<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="462748" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: FEATURE - Stone magic of Zimbabwe's art village.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Stone magic of Zimbabwe's art village.</headline>
<byline>Melanie Cheary</byline>
<dateline>TENGENENGE, Zimbabwe 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shadowy stone giants loom out of the morning mist before melting back into the thorny forest and shoulder-high African grass.</p>
<p>Thousands of silent sentinels line the muddy red road through green tobacco fields, welcoming visitors to Tengenenge -- &quot;The beginning of the beginning&quot;.</p>
<p>Here, 150 km (90 miles) north of the capital Harare, is the heart and soul of Zimbabwe's traditional stone sculpture and here the roads, electricity and telephone lines end.</p>
<p>The small African village lies in the foothills of the Great Dyke Mountains, which cut through Zimbabwe and are believed to be the stamping grounds for numerous ancestral spirits.</p>
<p>A scattering of mud and straw huts under twiggy trees, Tengenenge is home to 300 black artists, their families and about 20,000 stone sculptures.</p>
<p>Stylised birds stand three metres (10 feet) tall, flanked by smaller animals. Simple, fluid human figures stare out from between abstract, geometric renditions of trees and flowers.</p>
<p>Everywhere is the spirit of myth and magic that is at the root of Africa's traditional art.</p>
<p>&quot;Discussion about Zimbabwe's historical stone sculpture would not be complete without mentioning Tengenenge. It has become the biggest art community of its kind in Africa,&quot; said Matt Fischer, an African art dealer based in Harare.</p>
<p>Fischer added that Tengenenge had given birth to sculptors whose figures were found in museums and galleries worldwide.</p>
<p>WHITE AFRICAN ARTIST AND LIVING LEGEND</p>
<p>An old, bearded white man stoops out of a mud hut's opening, rubbing his large, dusty hands on faded khaki trousers.</p>
<p>This is 72-year-old Tom Blomefield, who came from South Africa to what was then Rhodesia in 1948 to farm tobacco and founded Tengenenge's sculpture community in 1965.</p>
<p>United Nations sanctions against the white-ruled country in the 1960s bankrupted his farm and, desperate to make a living, Blomefield and his black labourers by chance uncovered a vast deposit of dark serpentine stone on which Tengenenge lies.</p>
<p>They began to carve and almost immediate success and fame brought a rush of artists from Angola, Mozambique, Malawi and Zambia who have now lived here for more than 30 years.</p>
<p>&quot;I used to tell my sons, magic and superstition are tied by make-believe to coincidence and luck. The mountain showed me what to do. It was by luck that I found the stones. The mountain seems to have the answers,&quot; says Blomefield.</p>
<p>&quot;Mister Tom&quot; -- as he is called by the community -- tells his story, occasionally smoothing his long white hair.</p>
<p>&quot;I always wanted to be an artist. My mother was a painter and my father a carpenter. I wanted to use my hands, but my wife said she married a farmer,&quot; Blomefield chuckled.</p>
<p>Close by, two black women -- a mother and daughter -- stand patiently. They say they are &quot;the keepers of the old man&quot;.</p>
<p>They murmur gossip to him in their native Chinyanja language. He answers fluently.</p>
<p>&quot;The man is a living legend. When he dies, he will get a state funeral in this country like no one else before. He is Tengenenge and Tengenenge is him,&quot; Fischer said.</p>
<p>NATURAL AND SUPERNATURAL ART</p>
<p>Tengenenge's statues cast a gloomy mood, but bright clean clothes hanging on lines and noisy, barefoot children skipping by add life and temper the eeriness.</p>
<p>Edson Sedar is 20 years old and has lived in Tengenenge since he was 14. He is known for his elegant &quot;leaf-head&quot; statues -- fluid, tapered monoliths with a nose and mouth at the base.</p>
<p>&quot;I see the idea in the trees. Leaves breath. They live. They are life. They talk through the wind,&quot; Sedar says, while above him the mist wafts through rustling branches.</p>
<p>&quot;This is my work and this is my wife's. These are my children's,&quot; says 66-year-old Fred Masarakufa, showing off round spirits and all-knowing, ancient eyes.</p>
<p>Small carvings cost Z$100 ($9) and the giants about Z$1,600, but artists are open to &quot;negotiating&quot;.</p>
<p>SPIRITS GUARD AGAINST GUERRILLAS AND GUNS</p>
<p>&quot;When the war started the police came to us and said we'd have to defend ourselves,&quot; Blomefield says, describing how he and his artists, armed with two hunting rifles and a broken shotgun, were expected to fight trained cadres with automatic weapons.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe's guerrilla war for independence erupted in December 1972 and raged for seven years but Tengenenge, lying in one of the most troubled areas, survived unattacked.</p>
<p>&quot;When Chief Chimuwerere died (in 1970) I slaughtered an ox and we drank hundreds of litres of beer. The people say Rambanemuka, the spirit of death, came and said that no blood must ever fall on this land,&quot; Blomefield said.</p>
<p>None ever did and Tengenenge survives, a monument to ancient culture and peace.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TENGENENGE, Zimbabwe"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
