<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463385" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Raffles Medical to use IPO capital for expansion.</title>
<headline>Raffles Medical to use IPO capital for expansion.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Healthcare company Raffles Medical Group Ltd (RMG) will use proceeds from its share listing to buy new offices and to fund regional expansion, medical director and founder chairman Dr Loo Choon Yong said on Monday.</p>
<p>Its initial public offering (IPO) is expected this week, pending approval from the Stock Exchange of Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;Two-thirds of the proceeds will be used for local expansion in the form of acquiring premises, HDB (Housing and Development Board) shophouses for us to set up branches,&quot; Loo said at news conference.</p>
<p>He declined to disclose how many shares would be offered or how much the company hoped to raise but said RMG plans to offer only 15 percent of its capital in new shares.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel that with 15 percent we can raise adequate funds for our immediate requirements,&quot; Loo said, noting that control would be retained by doctors and the staff.</p>
<p>&quot;It is our policy to buy more of these rather than rent and in this way we can control rental costs,&quot; Loo said, adding that by controlling costs, RMG would pass on savings to patients.</p>
<p>The remaining proceeds will be used to expand existing operations in HongKong and for a joint venture project with U.S. healthcare giant Kaiser Permanente in Beijing.</p>
<p>The partners signed a memorandum of understanding with China to establish a specialist centre in Beijing.</p>
<p>Loo said phase one of the project would require Singapore $1 million, and capital requirements will be periodically reviewed.</p>
<p>Lead manager for the offering is DBS Bank.</p>
<p>RMG was established in 1976 and operates an integrated healthcare network offering primary care, specialists services, surgeons, and hospital facilities.</p>
<p>Asked if RMG would be setting up a full-fledged hospital with government-run Pidemco Land, Loo said a memorandum of understanding had been signed in December.</p>
<p>RMG currently runs a surgical-centre with 30 beds.</p>
<p>It runs 32 clinics in Singapore and is targetting to have 50 clinics by the end of next year.</p>
<p>Loo said it also hopes to expand its four clinics in HongKong and look for opportunities in Malaysia and Indonesia.</p>
<p>A large number of RMG's patients comes from these two countries, indicating good demand for such facilities, Loo said.</p>
<p>The group saw an increase in 1995 pre-tax profit to S$4.08 million from S$1.55 million in 1994 while turnover rose to S$25.45 million in 1995 from S$21.56 million in 1994.</p>
<p>--Jacqueline Wong, Singapore newsroom (65 870 3080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
