<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463317" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Business News - Mar 25.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Business News - Mar 25.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>In a move which signifies a major strategic shift for Colonial State Bank as its parent, the Colonial Group demutualises and prepares for a public share offering later this year, Colonial State Bank has announced plans to sell its branch businesses as seven-day-a-week retail franchises in a bid to cut costs and boost sales of its financial products. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The committal hearing for Macquarie Bank Ltd executive director Simon Hannes, who was arrested and charged in January as part of an investigation by the Australian Securities Commission into unusual trading in TNT Ltd's options before a takeover bid, is scheduled to open on Tuesday, June 10. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Woolworths has rejected a claim by Davids Ltd advisers, Beerworth &amp; Partners, that a group of 34 Canberra and New South Wales independent supermarkets had switched to Davids from Australian Independent Wholesalers - Woolworths' independent wholesaling divsion. AIW is seeking to become a major force in the A$6 billion-a-year independent wholesaling market which is currently dominated by Davids. Page 15.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Keith Gray, an executive vice-president of Canada's Toronto Dominion Bank, revealed yesterday the Bank has sealed a A$30 million takeover bid for Pont Securities, Australia's biggest discount stockbroking house. The offer was made through the Bank's subsiiary, Green Line Investor Services, as part of Green Line's plan to create a worldwide network of discount broking operations. Page 15.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Pacific Dunlop's share price has soared from a low of A$2.43 last September to A$3.30 yesterday as the market showed its support for a reconstruction plan developed by the company's new managing director, Rod Chadwick. The plan has already boosted the group's market capitalisation by A$880 million to A$3.4 billion in six months. Page 16.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A Shell Australia spokeswoman confirmed yesterday a review was underway which is likely to see the firm's parent company, the Royal Dutch/Shell group, reorganising the management of its global coal assets and creating a world coal headquarters in Sydney around Shell Coal Australia, the third largest coal miner in the country behind BHP and RTZ-CRA. Page 17.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>In what was described by one broker as &quot;Wallis fever&quot;, more than A$1.5 billion was added to the market value of Australia's banks yesterday as the banking index surged 97 points, or 2.4 per cent, to 4180.9 amid expectations the Wallis report, expected to be released within a week, will trigger a round of takeovers in the finance sector. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In what is the most radical response to the Wallis inquiry to date from within the financial services sector, Colonial State Bank, formerly the State Bank of New South Wales, plans to relocate or close up to 200 &quot;bricks and mortar&quot; branches as part of a srategic shift into franchise banking. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Robin Redfern, the managing director of leading mortgage originator RAMS Ltd, revealed yesterday the group has launched a new securitised company, Australian Securitised Funding Ltd, in an effort to place itself favourably for an anticipated liberalisation of the non-bank sector after the Wallis report is released. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>BHP's Canadian diamond subsidiary, BHP Diamonds Inc, and the Canadian Government are in talks over the company's distribution and marketing of its annual diamond output of 4.5 million carats from the Lac de Gras joint venture. BHP will either market the output itself, or move the diamonds through the De Beers Central Selling Organisation. The Government is pushing BHP to establish a local base. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Regional pay-TV group Austar, which took court action against the alliance between Optus Vision and Australis Media Ltd last year, alleging it breached its franchise agreement with Australis, may benefit from the expected settlement of Optus Vision's legal dispute with minority shareholder Seven Network. Vision is tipped to begin serious talks aimed at sharing programming with Austar. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Tensions between Woolworths Ltd and Davids Ltd intensified yesterday as Davids' corporate adviser, Beerworth and Partners, released a statement claiming the defection of all 34 independent retailers from Australian Independent Wholesalers, the Canberra-baed wholesaling unit that is to form the basis of Woolworths' assault on the A$10 billion-a-year wholesale grocery market. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>As investors speculated that the final report and findings of the Wallis inquiry into the Financial System will be delivered this week - heralding a merger free-for-all in the finance and banking sector - bank stocks rose almost 2.5 per cent yesterday. Naional Australia Bank also yesterday began its buyback of nearly six per cent of its ordinary shares. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Victorian Treasurer Alan Stockdale yesterday accused the New South Wales Government of subsidising its electricity industry by nearly $A500 million a year, causing the State battle over electricity reform to escalate. Stockdale asserted that by accepting ower-than-market dividends, the NSW Government was protecting its power generators. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Colonial State Bank managing director Stuart James said yesterday the Bank's plan for a reform of its branch network and the introduction of bank franchises was intended to cut its cost-to-income ratio in future years. The Bank's cost-to-income ratio is one of the industry's worse at nearly 72 per cent. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Macquarie Bank executive Simon Hannes was yesterday given a nine day committal hearing - to begin on June 10 in Downing Centre Local Court - after being charged with breaching laws governing large cash transactions. Hannes' lawyers have said he will plead not guilty to the charges. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>An independent economic study has found the West Australian Government's proposed 2.5 per cent gold tax would cause the loss of 1,500 jobs and effectively cost the State five times what it raised. Released yesterday by the Gold Industry Forum, the WA Gold Study was carried out by the University of Western Australia's Economic Research Centre. Page 31.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a bid to gain a foothold in the rapidly-growing local discount broking industry, Canadian-based stockbroker Green Line Holdings has made a $A29.8 million takeover grab for Pont Securities. Owned by the Toronto-Dominion Bank, and when combined with its North American business - Waterhouse Investor Service - Green Line is the world's third biggest discount broking company. Page 31.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>The Coalition of Small Business Organisations of Australia has welcomed the Howard Government's long-awaited plan for reducing red tape, which includes widespread changes to fringe benefits tax for small firms, exempting employers of less than 15 staff frm unfair dismissal provisions, and a new A$200 million capital venture scheme. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A decision is expected by the end of the week as to the winner of the three-way bidding battle between Prudential Corp plc, Abbey National plc and George Trumbull's AMP Society for Edinburgh-based company Scottish Amicable Life Assurance Society. AMP submitted a third bid for ScotAm last month, rumoured to have been as much as two billion pounds. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Talks between Optus Communications and its other partners in cable-TV company Optus Vision have failed to result in a final agreement for Optus Communications to buy out its fellow Vision shareholders, US West, Publishing and Broadcasting and the Seven Nework. Talks were again extended to 5pm tomorrow. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Announcing plans yesterday to sell 60 franchises to operate new outlets in its branch network, Colonial State Bank has launched an aggressive interstate expansion. The Bank will increase its representation in Victoria from 15 to more than 50 outlets by the end of next year, with nine franchises destined for the State. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Ross Mining has pulled in $A18.9 million from a share placement and has effectively ended the uncertainty surrounding the funding of its Golden Ridge gold project in the Solomon Islands. Clients of Porter Western were placed with 18 million shares at $A1.05 a share. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Independent wholesalers spokesman Peter Bunn claims that Woolworths switched allegiances to Davids has caused Woolworths to defend its supply arrangements with 34 independent supermarkets in Canberra and New South Wales. Bunn owns three Tempo supermarkets and chairs buying and marketing consultancy Retail Logistics. Page B3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
