<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463320" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-TIMELINES-Today in History - March 25.</title>
<headline>RTRS-TIMELINES-Today in History - March 25.</headline>
<text>
<p>** BIRTHDAYS **</p>
<p>Italian conductor ARTURO TOSCANINI was born on this day in 1867. He once said &quot;I kissed my first woman and smoked my first cigarette on the same day - I have never had time for tobacco since&quot;</p>
<p>GRACE MUNRO, who lived on a remote farm and after much hardship, became the founding President of the Country Women's Association, was born in 1879.  </p>
<p>British film director DAVID LEAN (&quot;Lawrence Of Arabia&quot;, &quot;Dr Zhivago&quot;, &quot;Bridge Over The River Kwai&quot;), was born in 1908.</p>
<p>Author BARBARA JEFFERIS (wife of ABC film buff JOHN HINDE), was born in 1917.</p>
<p>Author and chef BERNARD KING was born in 1934.  </p>
<p>American singer ARETHA FRANKLIN, dubbed &quot;the Queen of Soul&quot;, was born in 1942. She made her first recordings when she was 14. In 1960 she signed with Columbia Records and switched to Atlantic Records in 1967. Her hits included &quot;I Never Loved A Man (The Way I Love You) (1967), &quot;Since You've Been Gone&quot; (1968), &quot;I Say A Little Prayer&quot; (1968), &quot;Bridge Over Troubled Water&quot; (1971), &quot;Spanish Harlem&quot; (1971) and &quot;Until You Come Back To Me&quot; (1973). All of these and more were million sellers. In the eighties she returned with duets with the 'Eurythmics', KEITH RICHARDS and GEORGE MICHAEL.  </p>
<p>British songwriter/singer ELTON JOHN was born in 1947. He is also noted for his piano work. His real name is REGINALD KENNETH DWIGHT. His career started in 1961 with 'Bluesology' and he turned professional in 1965. In 1968 ELTON JOHN released his first single and in 1969 his first solo album came out. His first big hit was &quot;Your Song&quot; (1970). This was followed by others such as &quot;Crocodile Rock&quot; (1972), &quot;Goodbye Yellow Brick Road&quot; (1973), &quot;Benny And The Jets&quot; (1974), &quot;Don't Let The Sun Go Down On Me&quot; (1974), &quot;Someone Saved My Life Tonight&quot; (1975), &quot;Sorry Seems To Be The Hardest Word&quot; (1976) and &quot;Little Jeannie&quot; (1980). His first number one hit in Britain was his duet with KIKI DEE, &quot;Don't Go Breaking My Heart&quot; (1976). His more recent hits include &quot;Nikita&quot; (1985), &quot;I Don't Wanna Go On With You Like That&quot; (1988) and &quot;Sacrifice&quot; (1990). On Valentine's Day in 1984 in Australia ELTON JOHN married German sound technician RENATE BLAUEL. It was a short-lived marriage.</p>
<p>New Zealand singer JOHN ROWLES was born in 1947. He charted in 1968 with &quot;If I Only Had Time&quot; and &quot;Not A Word To Mary&quot;.  </p>
<p>				     ** EVENTS **</p>
<p>	   TODAY IS WAFFLE DAY IN SWEDEN !</p>
<p>1807 :    The British parliament abolished the slave trade.</p>
<p>1815 :    Britain, Austria, Prussia and Russia formed an</p>
<p>alliance against NAPOLEON BONAPARTE.  </p>
<p>1877 :    CAROLINE CHISHOLM (who appeared on the old $5</p>
<p>note), born CAROLINE JONES, died in Liverpool. She married an Indian army officer before coming to live in Australia in 1838 (at Windsor, north of Sydney), where she obtained Government backing to assist and provide shelter for distressed single women.</p>
<p>1949 :    British actor and director LAURENCE OLIVIER's film</p>
<p>version of &quot;Hamlet&quot; won 5 Oscars, including 'Best Picture', and 'Best Actor' for OLIVIER himself.  </p>
<p>1957 :    France, West Germany, Italy, the Netherlands,</p>
<p>Belgium and Luxembourg signed the 'Treaty of Rome' and formed the European Economic Community.</p>
<p>1958 :    American boxer SUGAR RAY ROBINSON won the world</p>
<p>middleweight title for an unprecedented 5th time, defeating CARMEN BASTILLO on points, over 15 rounds.  </p>
<p>1974 :    Australia's Prime Minister GOUGH WHITLAM was</p>
<p>showered with tomatoes, eggs, pies and rubbish during a demonstration in Perth. The demonstrators were mainly farmers objecting to the Federal Government's decision to end subsidies on farm fertiliser. The PM was rushed by the crowd, which was controlled by mounted police. Mr WHITLAM was hit on the neck by a full can of drink during the violent protest.</p>
<p>1975 :    Saudi Arabia's KING FAISAL was murdered by his</p>
<p>nephew.  </p>
<p>1989 :    Eleven million gallons of crude oil began leaking</p>
<p>from the tanker EXXON VALDEZ, after it ran aground yesterday on a reef in Prince William Sound, Alaska.</p>
<p>1990 :    87 people died in a disco fire in New York.</p>
<p>(Compiled from ABC ARCHIVES, ABC RADIO NATIONAL, &quot;On This Day&quot; published by REED INTERNATIONAL BOOKS LIMITED, &quot;The Chronicle Of The 20th Century&quot; published by PENGUIN BOOKS and &quot;Rock And Pop (Day By Day)&quot; published by BLANDFORD BOOKS.  </p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
