<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463556" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Economist delivers warning on U.S. card debt.</title>
<headline>Economist delivers warning on U.S. card debt.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lower-income Americans are more overextended on credit card debt than other groups, said economist Daid Wyss of DRI/McGraw Hill, who warned of the impact on bank reserves and the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;If this trend continues, banks will be forced to reevaluate loan loss reserves and utlimately it could have a profound economic impact,&quot; the economist said in prepared remarks for the National Collections and Credit Risk Conference sponsored by Faulkner &amp; Gray Inc.  </p>
<p>Wyss said 27 percent of families whose household income is below $10,000 now have credit card obligations exceeding 40 percent of their income. He said by comparison, fewer than five percent of families earning more than $50,000 are equally burdened.</p>
<p>He said households with incomes below $25,000 are bearing a disproportionate share of accelerating credit card debt, and this may be directly related to the record personal bankruptcies in the U.S. which topped one million last year.  </p>
<p>&quot;By extending too much credit to Americans who will have the most difficulty paying it back, banks are forgetting the basic principles of banking,&quot; Wyss said.</p>
<p>He said while consumer debt overall has stablized in the past year, outstanding consumer credit care debt as a percentage of disposable income among all Americans has risen to eight percent, which represents a 60 perrcent increase since 1989.</p>
<p>Wyss noted that 50 percent of the largest U.S. banks report they are tightening standards for credit card loans, and about 25 percent of smaller banks are doing the same.</p>
<p>Some participants in the credit card industry have recently argued that while the overall level of credit card debt has risen, many consumers use the cards as a convenience and pay their balances in full each month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150108">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
