<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463551" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Brent sellers target U.S. Gulf Coast, demand mixed.</title>
<headline>Brent sellers target U.S. Gulf Coast, demand mixed.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A growing list of companies holding North Sea Brent crude are targeting the U.S. Gulf Coast, but demand there is mixed as winter wanes and spring demand begins to flicker, trade sources said on Monday.</p>
<p>The transatlantic window has opened wide over the past week, encouraging sellers at a time when European demand remains sluggish.</p>
<p>The spread between benchmarks West Texas Intermediate/Cushing and Brent for May was around plus $1.48 a barrel Monday afternoon, up from below $1.00 a barrel some 10 days ago.</p>
<p>One seller is asking around May WTI minus 90 cents a barrel for Brent arriving April 20-30, trade sources said.</p>
<p>Compounding the supply situation on the U.S. Gulf Coast is a continued abundance of West African crude, notwithstanding a cutback of 100,000 barrels per day (bpd) in Royal Dutch/Shell's Nigerian production due to political turbulence.</p>
<p>Exports are not expected to be affected, at least for now, and traders seemed unconcerned.</p>
<p>Nigerian Bonny Light was pegged at an equivalent of dated Brent plus $1.75 a barrel for May 2-7 arrival on the Gulf Coast.</p>
<p>Still, Asian demand for West African cargoes is beginning to pick up as that region's refiners begin to emerge from turnarounds. Far East maintenance is expected to wind down at the end of April.</p>
<p>One refiner noted that several West African and Brent cargoes are already on the water looking for a home, underscoring the supply glut.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like your getting a build-up of crude globally,&quot; one refiner said.</p>
<p>Another suggested that supplies are far outpacing demand. &quot;I think people have their tanks full. Things are pretty well saturated.&quot;</p>
<p>The physical imbalance has prompted major regional sellers like Mexico to seek storage, if only on a spot basis.</p>
<p>State-owned Pemex recently leased storage on the Caribbean island of Aruba for about one million barrels of heavy sour Maya crude for about one month. The crude was subsequently pumped into Coastal's giant Aruba refinery for processing.</p>
<p>The Mexicans and short-haul competitor Venezuela are aggressively competing to maintain and expand market share in the U.S. for their mounting heavy sour flows.</p>
<p>--Patricia Garip-Bertuol NY Energy Desk ((+1 212 859 1620))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
