<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463500" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. helps fund nuclear safety in Cuba.</title>
<headline>U.S. helps fund nuclear safety in Cuba.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States has helped fund nuclear technical assistance to Cuba in 19 of the last 33 years, according to a Congressional watchdog agency report released on Monday.</p>
<p>Since 1963, the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) has spent about $12 million on nuclear assistance projects in Cuba, the General Accounting Office said in a report for the two authors of the Helms-Burton sanctions law against Cuba.</p>
<p>Most of the $12 million came out of a technical cooperation fund of voluntary contributions from IAEA members, including the United States.</p>
<p>In 1996, for example, Washington voluntarily gave $36 million to the United Nations agency, of which $16 million went to the technical cooperation fund.</p>
<p>But from 1981 through 1995 the United States withheld about $2 million that would have gone toward Cuban assistance.</p>
<p>The IAEA assistance is being used for 10 programs in Cuba, including atomic safety and atomic energy development at reactors that the United States does not want to see completed, and use of radiation in agriculture.</p>
<p>In January, Cuba shelved work on two half-built Soviet-designed reactors that Washington has opposed on the island's south coast about 180 miles (290 km) south of Florida.</p>
<p>Russian officials said in February they would help secure financing to resume construction of the reactors in 1998.</p>
<p>U.S. officials cited in the report said they &quot;did not object to IAEA'S providing nuclear safety assistance to Cuba's reactors&quot; since Cuba was a member of the agency.</p>
<p>But they said Washington would &quot;not provide extrabudgetary funds for IAEA's nuclear technical assistance projects with Cuba,&quot; or any other member state that had not signed onto the nuclear non-proliferation treaty.</p>
<p>U.S. experts are allowed to help on safety projects in Cuba, and the GAO said one expert had visited Cuba three times on a radiation project to help kill farm pests.</p>
<p>Senate Foreign Relations Committee chairman Jesse Helms of North Carolina and Rep. Dan Burton of Indiana, both Republicans, were not immediately available to comment on the report.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I1610109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
