<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463511" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hog futures soar on Taiwan news, grains and oil fall.</title>
<headline>Hog futures soar on Taiwan news, grains and oil fall.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hog futures prices soared the daily allowable limit for the third straight day on Monday as speculators and exporters continued to buy heavily on a belief that U.S. pork exports will jump with Taiwan exports halted.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Mercantile Exchange, lean hog futures for June delivery closed up the 2-cent per pound limit at 82.150 cents a pound, while May pork belly futures closed down 0.45 cent at 78.85 cents as speculators cashed in profits after two days of maximum gains.</p>
<p>Last Thursday Taiwanese authorities put a halt to pork exports due to an outbreak of foot and mouth disease that may take more than a year to eradicate.</p>
<p>Buyers of Taiwan's pork exports, inclucing Japan and South Korea, have been scrambling for other suppliers such as the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>Japan alone was importing more than 16,000 metric tons of Taiwanese pork each month.</p>
<p>Even with the sharp gains in hog prices -- up eight percent in three days -- analysts said the potential bonanza from new long-term sales could push pork prices higher.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the fundamentals we've probably got a ways to go, but they need some profit taking, they need some retracement,&quot; said Dale Benson, vice president and senior livestock analyst for Dean Witter, said of hog futures.</p>
<p>The lower close in pork bellies, the raw material to produce bacon, was less of a surprise after prices jumped 6 cents the prior two trading days, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;They are more sensitive to high prices shutting down demand,&quot; said Julia Bussie, livestock analyst for AG Edwards.</p>
<p>The futures rally was boosting movement of fresh bellies into cold storage. Bacon was also not one of the pork cuts that would be heavily in demand from Taiwan's customers.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not as bullish for pork bellies,&quot; said Jim Clarkson, analyst for A and A Inc.</p>
<p>Lumber prices soared, also driven by speculators betting that improving spring weather will spark higher demand that can absorb higher Canadian imports as well as U.S. production.</p>
<p>CME May lumber closed up the $10 daily limit at $373.70 per thousand board feet.</p>
<p>&quot;If retailers are truly in need of wood right now, we will find out in the next day or two,&quot; said Neil Schmaedick, Smith Barney Forest Products analyst.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Board of Trade, grain prices fell as traders said next Monday's first estimates for this year's corn and soybean crops by the Agriculture Department might come in higher than expected.</p>
<p>&quot;There are ideas the (soybean) acreage is edging higher from earlier expectations,&quot; said Robert Lekberg, analyst with Goldenberg Hehmeyer in Chicago. &quot;Sixty-seven million acres now is a pretty popular figure.&quot;</p>
<p>Last year U.S. farmers planted 64.2 million acres to soybeans, harvesting 2.382 billion bushels, and 79.5 million acres to corn, harvesting 9.293 billion bushels. Both crops were near the record crops produced in 1995 of 2.517 billion bushels of soybeans and 10.103 billion bushels of corn.</p>
<p>May soybeans closed down 10-3/4 cents a bushel at $8.31-3/4 and May corn down 1-1/4 cents a bushel at $2.99.</p>
<p>Improved weather in South American grain regions, where crops are now being harvested, also weighed on prices.</p>
<p>Grain markets also continued to be affected by the news from Taiwan, where past steady imports of corn and soybeans for animal feed were expected to fall off as much as 20 percent this year, Taiwanese traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>At the New York Mercantile Exchange, crude oil futures fell as heavy supplies from the North Sea outweighed worries about unrest in Nigeria and a strike at California refineries.</p>
<p>April crude oil fell 45 cents to close at $21.06 a barrel.</p>
<p>The disruption of production at one of Nigeria's main fields, as protesting villagers took Royal Dutch/Shell Group workers hostage, sent oil prices higher early in the day. But Shell later said it didn't expect any supply delays.</p>
<p>In California, union negotiators representing workers at refineries soon to be sold by Unocal to Tosco Corp went back to the table to discuss terms, easing supply concerns.</p>
<p>April unleaded gasoline closed 1.13 cents a gallon lower at 66.51 cents, and April heating oil fell 0.25 cent a gallon to 55.73 cents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
