<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463501" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Senator calls for U.S. aid suspension to Palestinians.</title>
<headline>Senator calls for U.S. aid suspension to Palestinians.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Republican senator on Monday called for suspension of U.S. aid to the Palestinian authority until determination of whether an indirect &quot;green light&quot; was given for last week's suicide bomb in Tel Aviv.</p>
<p>&quot;I would appreciate your advice, as promptly as possible, on your Department's conclusion as to whether Chairman (Yasser) Arafat and the Palestinian authority gave an indirect green light to the terrorists,&quot; Sen. Arlen Specter of Pennsylvania said in a letter to Secretary of State Madeleine Albright.</p>
<p>He also asked Albright to advise him on whether there was any U.S. aid in the pipeline which had not yet been turned over to the Palestinian authority. &quot;If so, I request that such payments be withheld until the determination as to whether the Palestinian authority is complying&quot; with its commitments under its peace accords with Israel.</p>
<p>A suicide bomber killed three women in a Tel Aviv cafe on Friday. The Islamic group Hamas threatened more suicide bombings if Israel pressed ahead with the construction of a Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has blamed Arafat for giving Islamic militants a &quot;green light&quot; to launch attacks against the Jewish state. Arafat denies the charge.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
