<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463541" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live cattle close higher but with pared gains.</title>
<headline>CME live cattle close higher but with pared gains.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME live cattle futures held gains at the close on support encouraged by a firm undertone to cash markets, though best levels were pared late. Feeder cattle futures also eased from best levels late following a late recovery in corn futures, traders said.</p>
<p>Live cattle closed 0.475 cent higher to unchanged with April up most at 68.625 cents. Feeder cattle ended 0.450 to 0.100 higher with May up 0.175 at 69.250 cents.</p>
<p>Paring of best levels in deferred hog futures and setbacks in pork belly futures despite the Taiwan situation prompted profit taking in cattle pits late, traders said.</p>
<p>Live cattle futures had run up early on the spillover from pork pits, with expectations of stronger cash beef and live markets adding to support. The boxed beef market has been strengthening and expectations are that packers will raise bids for fed cattle as some of them need cattle soon to meet slaughter requirements, they said.</p>
<p>The sharp rise in pork prices may also encourage retailers to feature beef more often. Export demand for beef may also rise as pork prices run up sharply in the Pacific rim due to Taiwan's pork export ban, they added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
