<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463544" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: California bill could clear way for tobacco suit.</title>
<headline>California bill could clear way for tobacco suit.</headline>
<dateline>SACRAMENTO, Calif.</dateline>
<text>
<p>A California lawmaker will introduce legislation to clear the way for the state to sue tobacco companies to recoup public health care costs related to smoking, aides said Monday.</p>
<p>If the legislature removes barriers to a state suit, California would likely join other states in suing the major tobacco companies, said a spokesman for California Attorney General Dan Lungren, a Republican.</p>
<p>Last week, Liggett Group, owned by Bennett LeBow's Brooke Group Ltd., broke ranks with other tobacco companies by agreeing to settle with 22 state attorneys general who sued the industry to recoup smoking-related Medicaid health care costs.</p>
<p>California, the most populous state, with potentially billions of dollars in claims, has so far not sued the tobacco industry. Lungren had said state litigation would likely fail because of a controversial 1987 state law shielding tobacco companies from product liability claims.</p>
<p>Assembly Speaker Cruz Bustamante, a Democrat, said he plans to sponsor a measure that would eliminate current barriers to California suing the tobacco companies.</p>
<p>&quot;If the legislature acts and changes the law, it is very likely that California will enter into the lawsuit against the tobacco manufacturers,&quot; Lungren spokesman Rob Stutzman said.</p>
<p>The language of the proposed legislation has not been finalised, but Bustamante's spokesman, Ron Gray, said the measure should be introduced into the state legislature next week.</p>
<p>The legislation would, if passed, take effect immediately. However, such bills, known as &quot;urgency bills,&quot; require two-thirds support to pass. Democrats control both houses of the legislature.</p>
<p>&quot;Assembly Democrats want to make sure California taxpayers get back some of the money they've spent on tobacco-related illnesses,&quot; Bustamante said in a statement. &quot;That won't happen if the attorney general doesn't act, so we're closing the tobacco loophole and taking away any possible excuse for not suing the tobacco companies.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman for Republican Gov. Pete Wilson had no immediate comment on Bustamante's proposal.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the state legislature passed non-binding resolutions calling on Lungren to sue major tobacco companies.</p>
<p>There are an estimated four million smokers in California. According to a recent study by the University of California, state taxpayers spent $4.1 billion in Medi-Cal expenses between 1980 and 1993 to treat smoking-related illnesses.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SACRAMENTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
