<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463684" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgians find female torso in bin-bag murders case.</title>
<headline>Belgians find female torso in bin-bag murders case.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian police found a female torso on Monday and were looking for a serial killer after the discovery of bin bags containing the surgically severed limbs of three other Caucasian women.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the torso of a woman aged between 35 and 40 years,&quot; a spokesman for the public prosecution service said. &quot;It looks like it is a fourth victim...and it is quite recent.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It could be the work a serial killer,&quot; he said in reply to a question.</p>
<p>The nine bags containing the arms and legs of the three other victims were found by chance in a ditch next to the Brussels-Paris railway line on Saturday by a mounted policeman in the town of Cuesmes near Mons in southern Belgium.</p>
<p>On Monday morning police found a 10th bag containing what media described as personal effects. The 11th bin-bag with the torso was found later near the Mons administrative centre.</p>
<p>All the remains have been transferred to Liege University hospital where forensic pathologists will have the task of piecing together the anatomical jigsaw.</p>
<p>But Mons Public Prosecutor Pierre Honore warned that identification of the victims could take some time.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be slow. At least 15 days,&quot; he told RTBF television.</p>
<p>Police said it was clear from the state of the ground under the bags containing the severed limbs that they had been left in the ditch at different times.</p>
<p>&quot;There are three different types of putrefaction,&quot; Honore said. &quot;One very advanced. One less so, and one quite recent.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Mons police had contacted forces in other areas of the country.</p>
<p>Five of the nine bags found at the weekend had the name of the Belgian beach resort of Knokke-Heist printed on them.</p>
<p>Police said they no clue as the identity of the killer or killers -- other than they appeared to have some surgical knowledge of anatonomy -- or the motives.</p>
<p>Police said the investigation into the origin of the limbs and the torso would focus on recent disappearances of women in Belgium, France and the Netherlands.</p>
<p>Newspapers said two of the dead had been adult women, and the third had been either an adolescent or a young woman.</p>
<p>They said the surgical nature of the dismemberment had prompted speculation of links with the discovery in July last year of the mutilated corpse of another woman in the same region.</p>
<p>Police officials said at the weekend there was no immediate reason to suspect a link with gruesome discoveries made in a paedophile scandal which has rocked the country in the past nine months.</p>
<p>The bodies of five young girls have been found since August.</p>
<p>Convicted child rapist Marc Dutroux has been charged with the murder of four of them. Another convicted paedophile, Patrick Derochette, has been charged with the illegal imprisonment and rape of a minor leading to death.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
