<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46363" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran says sheltering 39,000 Iraqi Kurd refugees.</title>
<headline>Iran says sheltering 39,000 Iraqi Kurd refugees.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran said on Wednesday it was sheltering 39,000 Kurdish refugees who fled the takeover this week of northern Iraq by a Baghdad-backed Kurdish faction.</p>
<p>Ahmad Hosseini, Iran's top official in charge of refugees, told the official news agency IRNA the refugees were given shelter outside the border towns of Baneh and Sardasht and the city of Kermanshah 125 km (80 miles) east of the border.</p>
<p>IRNA quoted him as saying Iran was also setting up camps for another 16O,OOO refugees on the Iraqi side of the border and providing aid.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands of refugees had fled toward Iran from advancing Iraqi-backed Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) forces who took Sulaimaniya, Iraq's biggest Kurdish city, on Monday from the rival Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK).</p>
<p>But, against the flow, hundreds of Kurdish refugees went back to their homes in northern Iraq. Some said they were returning because President Saddam Hussein's Iraqi troops had not entered Sulaimaniya.</p>
<p>&quot;People are still coming back. They continue to return. We've monitored a lot of trucks and cars coming back,&quot; Stafford Clarry, senior U.N. representative in Sulaimaniya, told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>Thousands of refugees set up camp on the Iranian side of the Bashmaq border crossing on Wednesday after they said KDP guerrillas killed four people on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>&quot;KDP men came and asked us first nicely to go back home, but when people confronted them, they started shooting. Four were killed,&quot; a refugee told Reuters.</p>
<p>Local Iranian authorities at the Bashmaq border crossing said four people were killed and about 100 wounded. The wounded were taken to hospitals in Iran, they said. State-run Tehran radio said Iraqi troops were also involved.</p>
<p>Tehran had said it would not admit refugees &quot;unless in an emergency&quot;. It said it would offer relief with the help of international organisations in camps on the Iraqi side of the border.</p>
<p>United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees official Laurens Jolles in Tehran said Iranian officials had decided to allow refugees facing grave danger into Iran.</p>
<p>&quot;Iranian officials said they were now admitting more refugees, including those whose lives were in danger and those who were in hard-to-reach border areas,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;They also repeated their request for urgent international action to bring aid to the refugees. They said food and medicines were in short supply,&quot; Jolles told Reuters.</p>
<p>Tehran this week appealed for international aid, saying nearly 200,000 refugees were approaching. UNHCR officials in Geneva said on Tuesday up to 75,000 people were on the move, although some were later reported returning home.</p>
<p>Iran already has more than two million refugees, including 1.5 million Afghans, making it the country hosting the largest number anywhere.</p>
<p>Tehran had feared a repeat of an exodus in 1991, when more than a million Iraqis, most of them Kurds, fled to Iran as Baghdad crushed uprisings that followed Iraq's defeat in the Gulf War. Most Kurds had since returned to northern Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;I would rather be a refugee than go back home to Sulaimaniya and live under the KDP and (Iraqi President) Saddam Hussein,&quot; a middle-aged man with his wife and daughter told Reuters earlier in Bashmaq.</p>
<p>He said he and many other refugees belonged to Kurdish clans opposed to the KDP.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
