<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463671" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Capsized barge still snarling Mississippi traffic.</title>
<headline>Capsized barge still snarling Mississippi traffic.</headline>
<byline>Jua Nyla Hutcheson</byline>
<dateline>BATON ROUGE, La. 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Federal and state officials struggled on Monday morning with plans to remove volatile cargo from a capsized barge in the flood-swollen Mississippi River, while marine traffic backed up near the accident site, the Coast Guard said.</p>
<p>Plans to unload the benzene and gasoline mix were scrapped on Saturday after officials with the Atchafalaya Basin Levee District won a temporary injunction in state court to prevent the barge owners from drilling holes in the hull.</p>
<p>Levee District officials maintained that any risk of explosion, which could knock out a section of the mainline levee protecting the west bank of river, was unacceptable. A full hearing on the injunction was to be held later Monday.</p>
<p>Other efforts to use existing but submerged valves were delayed on Sunday after a plume of the benzene mix leaked from a valve being replaced, Coast Guard spokesman Chris Haley told Reuters.</p>
<p>The next attempt to lighter the barge, owned by Ingram Barge Co. of Nashville, was expected about 10:30 a.m. EST, Haley said. Once lightering begins, it will take at least 24 hours to complete. Then cranes can be used to right the barge.</p>
<p>By daylight Monday, 27 tows, involving numerous barges, were backed up waiting to move downriver, Haley said. Nineteen barges moved upriver during the night.</p>
<p>Marine traffic in the area was restricted to one way, one vessel or tow at a time past the capsized barge. Southbound traffic was allowed only during daylight hours.</p>
<p>The Coast Guard reported just one minor incident of runaway barges on the river over the weekend near Convent, La., and said the barges were quickly corraled.</p>
<p>A mobile home spotted floating downriver toward Baton Rouge was pushed onto the bank by a tug to keep it away from vessel traffic, a spokesman said. &quot;We have no idea where it came from, but no one was inside.&quot;</p>
<p>In the past week several incidents blamed on the high water's swift current, have closed the river in sections from Baton Rouge to the mouth of the river at Southwest Pass.</p>
<p>River traffic at Baton Rouge has been hampered since a string of 25 barges under tow hit a bridge on March 17. Two rock barges sank, one is missing and the third capsized.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BATON ROUGE, La."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
