<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463702" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch soccer death looked like &quot;seal cull&quot; -wiitness.</title>
<headline>Dutch soccer death looked like &quot;seal cull&quot; -wiitness.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dutch soccer gang leader slain in a pre-arranged battle on Sunday was surrounded and clubbed to death by nearly 20 fans from a rival club, a witness told Dutch television on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;They clubbed him like it was some sort of seal cull,&quot; said the young man with close-cropped hair whose identity was concealed in the television report.</p>
<p>Gangs of Ajax Amsterdam and Feyenoord Rotterdam fans met and fought with knives and baseball bats on waste ground by a motorway 20 miles from Amsterdam on Sunday.</p>
<p>Carlo Picornie, who died surrounded by at least 18 Feyenoord fans, was well-known as a ringleader of an ultra-hard faction in Ajax's fanatical &quot;F-Side&quot; supporters gang, Dutch newspapers reported.</p>
<p>He was 35, had a girlfriend and two small children and owned a hotel in central Amsterdam.</p>
<p>&quot;He made a terrible mistake yesterday, one of his friends told a local newspaper. &quot;They called him out and Carlo went. A few of the old Feyenoorders must have known him very well.&quot;</p>
<p>His death was the first caused by the hooliganism that has blighted Dutch soccer for more than 20 years.</p>
<p>Dozens of police spent  Monday scouring the field where the gangs fought. Others questioned motorists who might have passed near the scene.</p>
<p>Twenty-eight people were arrested after the fight and police said they were scanning a video from a motorway surveillance camera hoping to identify the rioters.</p>
<p>The suspects were being held in police stations around the Kennemerland region west of Amsterdam. Police in Rotterdam and Amsterdam were also helping the investigation.</p>
<p>Ringleaders marshalled armed hooligans to the wasteground -- miles away from either team's ground on a day when their teams were not playing each other -- using mobile phones to outwit police attempts to keep them apart.</p>
<p>Chief superintendent Cees Bakker of the Netherlands' senior police officers' committee told television he feared the clash could herald further violence as gang members sought revenge.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm extremely concerned that this could be the start of a series of such incidents,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It has all the hallmarks of a gang war situation and we must be careful that we can free up more capacity to head off further such incidents,&quot; Bakker said.</p>
<p>Another senior policeman called for more extensive use of helicopters to follow aggressive football fans.</p>
<p>Justice Minister Winnie Sorgdrager and Home Affairs Minister Hans Dijkstal laid the groundwork for meetings with sporting and police bodies to discuss football violence, the Justice Ministry said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;These are gangs of hardened criminals, groups who seek each other out to fight,&quot; Dijkstal said, calling for tougher sentences. &quot;This is hard work for the police and judiciary. We must track down these groups and punish them.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
