<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463710" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain praises France for fighting Basque querrillas.</title>
<headline>Spain praises France for fighting Basque querrillas.</headline>
<byline>Marjorie Olster</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain praised France on Monday for its efforts to crush Basque guerrillas as the two countries prepared for talks on how to combat the separatist group ETA.</p>
<p>French Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre was to meet his Spanish counterpart Jaime Mayor Oreja on Monday evening to plan joint action against ETA, which in recent months has stepped up its deadly attacks on Spanish targets.</p>
<p>&quot;The entire leadership of ETA is in France, but not exactly intact. It is not exactly the same as it was six months ago,&quot; Mayor Oreja said in an interview published on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The cooperation with France is exemplary. The number of detentions produced in these months, thanks to measures we have taken together with France, has been most important,&quot; he told the Spanish magazine Tribuna.</p>
<p>ETA, which stands for Basque Homeland and Freedom, has killed more than 800 people in its 29-year fight for an independent Basque state encompassing parts of southern France and northern Spain.</p>
<p>In the past, Madrid had complained the guerrillas used the Basque region of southern France as a haven to orchestrate attacks by commandos in Spain.</p>
<p>But Spain's 10-month-old conservative government has repeatedly expressed its satisfaction with increasingly forceful French action against ETA's network in France. In recent months, France has arrested several activists considered among the group's top leaders.</p>
<p>The two ministers, who meet twice a year, were also expected to discuss cooperation to fight Islamic guerrillas and illegal immigration from Africa.</p>
<p>A Spanish interior ministry statement said the &quot;excellent cooperation&quot; between the two countries had paid off with the capture of senior ETA figures.</p>
<p>It cited the arrests in France of several suspected ETA leaders -- Julian &quot;Pototo&quot; Achurra Egurola, Juan Luis Aguirre Lete , known as &quot;Isuntza&quot;, and Jose Luis Urrusolo.</p>
<p>Egurola, arrested in July 1996, is wanted for the 1986 killing of a policeman in Bilbao. Lete is suspected of plotting to kill Spanish King Juan Carlos.</p>
<p>Lete was arrested in November 1996 in southern France when authorities found a cache of documents with a list of possible targets including senior French officials, among them Debre.</p>
<p>Spain has asked France to extradite Urrusolo, said to be the number three ETA leader and one of Spain's most wanted men.</p>
<p>The Spanish daily El Mundo said the government was seeking to secure international support for its policies in the aftermath of allegations that Spanish authorities tortured a suspected ETA guerrilla arrested two weeks ago.</p>
<p>The government said its own investigation found that the prisoner, Fernando Elejalde, was not mistreated, as Basque nationalist politicians alleged, after he was caught fleeing the site of a killing.</p>
<p>Spain has been criticised by international groups in the past for mistreating ETA inmates, allegations which may make neighbouring Portugal and France reluctant to extradite suspected guerrillas.</p>
<p>Spain has been pressing European Union member states to ratify an extradition treaty signed in Dublin last September under which countries would no longer be able to refuse to extradite a suspect in a politically motivated crime.</p>
<p>Madrid hopes the treaty will make it easier to prosecute ETA suspects caught abroad.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
