<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463851" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Krupp drops bid for Thyssen.</title>
<headline>Krupp drops bid for Thyssen.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Busvine</byline>
<dateline>BONN, Germany</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Krupp group withdrew its hostile $8 billion takeover bid for Thyssen AG Monday, but the companies said future cooperation could extend beyond a joint steel venture they plan to establish.</p>
<p>&quot;The previously announced takeover bid is void and no further offers to take over Thyssen will be made in future,&quot; Fried. Krupp AG Hoesch-Krupp said in a statement issued jointly with Thyssen.</p>
<p>Krupp originally launched a hostile bid for Thyssen but after heavy political pressure agreed to suspend it during talks between the two companies on an agreed merger of their steel operations.</p>
<p>After five days of talks, the two sides agreed to establish a steel venture to be run by Thyssen because its Thyssen Stahl unit has greater capacity and is more profitable than Krupp-Hoesch Stahl, a Thyssen spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;The negotiations between Thyssen and Krupp over a merger of steel operations are going well,&quot; the joint statement said. &quot;The participants agree that such a merger would enable Germany to survive as a steel production centre and make possible a strategy to move forward.&quot;</p>
<p>The two sides have been in talks since last Thursday after Krupp suspended its cash bid which valued Thyssen at 435 German marks ($257) a share, a 25 percent premium to the market when it was made at the beginning of last week.</p>
<p>Krupp said its decision to drop its hostile bid for Thyssen did not herald a friendly merger, but there was scope for joint ventures outside the steel production area.</p>
<p>&quot;This does not mean that there will be a merger between the two groups,&quot; a company spokesman said.</p>
<p>Thyssen had said earlier that it would not be possible for Krupp to finance its hostile bid, which valued Thyssen at 13.6 billion marks ($8 billion), without taking irresponsible risks and damaging the interests of Thyssen shareholders.</p>
<p>The Thyssen spokesman said the steel venture would offer &quot;the best concept&quot; for its workers and shareholders.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we have the time and calm to work out the details,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Despite news of the breakthrough, workers' representatives said a demonstration organised by the IG Metall union against the banks behind the defunct Krupp bid would still go ahead in Frankfurt Tuesday.</p>
<p>Workers fear that at least 7,000 jobs will go in any deal between Krupp and Thyssen.</p>
<p>The protest will take place in the heart of Frankfurt's financial district, where Krupp backers Deutsche Bank AG and Dresdner Bank AG are headquartered. Investment bank Goldman Sachs had also supported the Krupp bid.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
