<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463842" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: FEATURE - India Supreme Court creaking under backlog.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - India Supreme Court creaking under backlog.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Verma</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Chief Justice A.M. Ahmadi looks tired when he talks about his job -- he heads what is believed to be the world's most overworked Supreme Court.</p>
<p>&quot;The burden of work in this court is perhaps the maximum anywhere in the world. There are really very few courts where comparable pressure of work on judges can be found,&quot; Ahmadi told Reuters recently, shaking his head.</p>
<p>With a backlog of nearly 23,000 cases to clear and some 50,000 fresh cases to sift through every year, legal experts say Ahmadi is probably right.</p>
<p>The ultimate arbiter for 936 million Indians demanding justice, the Supreme Court stands at the pinnacle of a network of courts that is wrestling with some 35 million pending cases.</p>
<p>Ahmadi says the Supreme Court handles up to 100 cases every day. &quot;The U.S. Supreme Court takes about 150 cases in a year,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>SUPREME COURT ITSELF PARTY TO BLAME</p>
<p>Law Ministry officials say cases lodged with the 25-judge Supreme Court can take as long as 14 years to come up for hearing.</p>
<p>&quot;Part of the blame is to be attributed to the Supreme Court itself,&quot; says Soli Sorabjee, a prominent lawyer and former attorney-general.</p>
<p>&quot;It entertains many matters in its special leave jurisdiction which should not be touched at all and left at the high court stage.&quot;</p>
<p>When petitioners lose cases at any of India's 18 high courts, they have no right of appeal, but can plead with the Supreme Court to consider their cases. The court can then admit cases it considers important.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no consistent, coherent thinking of policy among the Supreme Court judges,&quot; Sorabjee said. &quot;If bench A is strict in admission, bench B will be very liberal. So the litigant decides to take a chance, and it becomes a lottery.&quot;</p>
<p>COURT WEIGHED DOWN BY PUBLIC INTEREST LITIGATION</p>
<p>Legal experts say the court is also weighed down by a spate of public interest litigation (PIL), often filed by social and environmental activists who say the government is not fulfilling its statutory duties.</p>
<p>Judges, known for sententious rulings that usually run into dozens of pages, have grumbled about the petitions.</p>
<p>&quot;An officious busybody picking up a stray dispute or idle pedlar of blackmail litigation, through abuse of the process of court, cannot be permitted to pollute the court instrumentality for private objectives,&quot; one judge said in a ruling.</p>
<p>To stem the stream of PILs swamping the Supreme Court, the government recently proposed a law that says petitioners must deposit 100,000 rupees ($2,800) along with their pleas.</p>
<p>Social activist H.D. Shourie, who heads a leading Delhi-based consumer rights group, said politicians hoped that the proposed law would shield them from the judiciary.</p>
<p>Last year a PIL unearthed a political corruption scandal that forced the resignation of seven ministers and helped to send the government hurtling to defeat in general elections.</p>
<p>&quot;By proposing a legislation to curb PIL, politicians are trying to cut at the very roots of the judiciary,&quot; Shourie said.</p>
<p>Law Ministry officials said the government also plans to introduce a bill that would give politicians the power to appoint judges.</p>
<p>&quot;People in general today are greatly aggrieved,&quot; Shourie said. &quot;They cannot secure redress from the political or the bureaucratic executive. They are therefore forced to turn to the courts.&quot;</p>
<p>COMPUTERISATION, CASE CLASSIFICATION HELP CUT WORKLOAD</p>
<p>Ahmadi says he has worked hard to overhaul the Supreme Court's creaking infrastructure since he took charge in 1994, when he inherited a backlog of more than 100,000 cases.</p>
<p>Apart from computerising the court's filing, he started a system through which similar matters were grouped together and disposed of in bunches, rather than being heard individually by separate benches.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be able to dispose of cases in a year's time if the ship is kept on even keel. The culture of computerisation has the capacity to revolutionise,&quot; Ahmadi said.</p>
<p>Sorabjee and Ahmadi say each Supreme Court judge spends weekends reading nearly 100 cases ahead of rulings on Monday.</p>
<p>But the job also comes with enviable perquisites -- a four-and-a-half-hour working day five days a week, and a two-month summer vacation. $1 = 35.8 rupees</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
