<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="464005" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain says vigilance foiled guerrilla jailbreak.</title>
<headline>Britain says vigilance foiled guerrilla jailbreak.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain said on Monday an alert prison officer had foiled a possible jail break by IRA guerrillas at Northern Ireland's maximum security Maze Prison.</p>
<p>The prison officer discovered a tunnel some 13 metres (40 feet) long during a routine patrol at a cell-block housing 95 Irish Republican Army (IRA) inmates convicted of waging war on British rule, security sources said.</p>
<p>The tunnel was around 30 metres (100 feet) short of the prison's perimeter wall, the sources said.</p>
<p>As a political row erupted over the security breach, Britain repudiated claims it had allowed guerrillas a free rein in running day-to-day life on the prison wings.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sure that is not right,&quot; Northern Ireland Secretary Sir Patrick Mayhew told reporters at Banbridge, County Down.</p>
<p>The tunnel reportedly had electric lighting. The Maze Prison is a heavily-fortified complex on flat open land beside a busy motorway, some eight miles (13 km) south of Belfast.</p>
<p>&quot;At no stage did any prisoners escape and all prisoners have been accounted for,&quot; said a spokesman for the province's prison service.</p>
<p>Mayhew praised officers' vigilance. &quot;I think it is genuinely recognised that the prison service at the Maze has a very difficult job to do.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we should concentrate on the fact that this was a foiled attempt by an alert patrol,&quot; Mayhew stressed.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't know who was involved at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>Prison sources said the tunnel led from the IRA prisoners' block, and a leading activist with Sinn Fein, the guerrillas' political arm, praised the escape effort.</p>
<p>But the security breach at the Maze, which is Britain's most heavily guarded jail complex and holds the biggest concentration of guerrilla prisoners in Western Europe, led to Protestant politicians' demands for a clampdown on IRA inmates.</p>
<p>However, Sinn Fein politician Gerry Kelly said the prisoners regarded themselves as prisoners of war.</p>
<p>&quot;They see it as their duty to escape. Fair play to them,&quot; said Kelly, one of 38 Republicans who broke out of the Maze in 1983 in the largest prison break-out in British history.</p>
<p>A senior Sinn Fein negotiator in talks in 1995 with Britain, Kelly is candidate for a Belfast seat in a national election to be held in Britain and Northern Ireland on May 1.</p>
<p>Finlay Spratt, leader of prison officers in the British province, blamed high-level managers in the prison service for the breach and said the governor should not be made a scapegoat.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a known fact that the prisoners run their own accommodation, (have) their own command structure within that and prison officers are not allowed into that unless they seek the approval of the paramilitary commanders,&quot; he told BBC radio.</p>
<p>The Maze holds 297 republican convicts and around 300 pro-British Protestant guerrillas, called Loyalists because of their allegiance to Britain. The rival inmates are segregated.</p>
<p>&quot;Serious sentences have got to be passed on those responsible for this escape attempt,&quot; Ulster Unionist Party security spokesman Ken Maginnis told BBC radio.</p>
<p>Peter Robinson, deputy leader of the Democratic Unionist Party, said guerrillas had been given too much freedom in their cell blocks. &quot;Prison officers do not believe the prison establishment will back them up. There needs to be a complete review of security,&quot; he told the BBC.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
