<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="464020" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold, under pressure, tries to hold $350.</title>
<headline>London gold, under pressure, tries to hold $350.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold struggled back above the psychological $350 an ounce level on Monday afternoon, after speculative selling had forced repeated downside tests.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been good speculative selling today, which was probably in anticipation of the fund selling we've seen in the market recently,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;So far gold hasn't been run down too far, but it's looking shaky.&quot;</p>
<p>Bullion hit a low bid of $348.55 before rebounding to fix at $350.20 an ounce compared to $350.65 in the morning. It had closed considerably firmer on Friday, at $352.40/$352.90.</p>
<p>The market was nervously focusing on Tuesday's over-the-counter options expiry and a possible U.S. interest rate hike by the Federal Open Market Committee, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Dealers are trying to position themselves ahead of the options expiry on Tuesday. It's also the end of the first quarter ahead of a long Easter weekend, so it's all happening,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Bullion has been trading in a narrow band in recent days, and analysts said that $350 and $355 were the most popular &quot;strike&quot; prices for the March options expiry.</p>
<p>&quot;The $350 level is very important in terms of the expiry and some people have a big stake in making sure it stays above here,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>But also at the forefront of the market's consciousness was Tuesday's FOMC meeting, which many dealers saw likely to raise interest rates by 25 basis points.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt in my mind that a hike of 25 basis points has been priced into the market. The question is whether it's going to be 25 or 50 basis points,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Silver saw some selling as well, although the $5.09 support level held firm, and prices rebounded.</p>
<p>Silver was last indicated at $5.14/$5.16 since, compared to $5.17/$5.19 at Friday's London close.</p>
<p>Platinum and palladium started the European trading day on a weaker note, casualties of overnight selling. But prices remained generally static throughout the day.</p>
<p>Platinum was last at $375.50/$376.50, down $2.25, while palladium was just off the day's lows at $148.25/$149.25, down $3.75.</p>
<p>Both platinum group metals were still watching for fresh news on delayed Russian supply contract talks with Japan and planned strikes at the Russian Norilsk complex.</p>
<p>--Lida Poletz, London newsroom +44 171 542 2936</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
