<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="464225" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Program helps mentally ill avoid homelessness.</title>
<headline>Program helps mentally ill avoid homelessness.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mentally ill people have a better chance of making the transition back into the community without ending up homeless if they have support programmes that intervene at the most critical times, public health and psychiatric researchers said on Sunday.</p>
<p>A study appearing in the American Journal of Public Health compared traditional support services with &quot;critical time intervention&quot; programmes for 96 male patients leaving institutions after being treated for severe mental illness.</p>
<p>It found that the patients in the intervention programmes had fewer nights of homelessness.</p>
<p>&quot;This study has positive implications for mental health services,&quot; the team led by Dr. Ezra Susser of Columbia University wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;The view that these patients suffer homelessness and other deprivations because they cannot be reached may be unwarranted,&quot; they said, adding that the techniques that proved effective were &quot;neither costly nor complex.&quot;</p>
<p>Over an 18 month period, those who got the intervention programme had an average 30 nights of homelessness, compared to 91 nights for the control group that got more typical follow-up services, including referrals to mental health and rehabilitation programmes.</p>
<p>The critical time intervention programme took a more active role in patient follow-up. For instance, the counsellors in those programmes may accompany patients to outpatient services, or track them down if they miss appointments. In more traditional follow-up services, there is less outreach.</p>
<p>&quot;Some clients needed only a few follow-up visits. At the other extreme, some clients needed frequent visits for emotional support over several months and help with practical matters such as obtaining a minimum of furniture and locating inexpensive stores,&quot; the authors wrote.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
