<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="464241" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Treasury's Anderson happy with index-linked bonds.</title>
<headline>Treasury's Anderson happy with index-linked bonds.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. government is pleased with the performance of the index-linked securities market and is looking for ways to make its appeal more widespread, said Roger Anderson, Deputy Assistant Secretary of Federal Finace at the U.S. Treasury Department.</p>
<p>Speaking at an index-linked bond conference, Anderson said that while institutional investors were active bidders at the Treasury's inagural index-linked auction in late January, he would like to see more retail investors.</p>
<p>The auction brought in $37 billion in institutional bids, but non-competitive bids totalled $150 million.  </p>
<p>Anderson acknowledged that retail typically starts off slow for the new products.  &quot;It's a long-term process,&quot; he said. &quot;We've made a good start but there is a lot more to do.&quot;</p>
<p>He reiterated the Treasury's desire to build up the market offering index-linked securities throughout the yield curve.</p>
<p>Anderson noted that the Treasury will announce details of the next index-linked auction on April 2 and said it will most likely be a reopening of the January 10-year note.</p>
<p>He said that the subsequent auction will not be a 10-year note, but it's not yet known if it would be a shorter or longer maturity than the 10-year note.  </p>
<p>He added that a third maturity will be issued in 1998 and that the Treasury hopes the additional maturities will boost liquidity in the market.</p>
<p>Anderson said the Treasury is still gathering information on the future of the market from traders and investors.</p>
<p>He also repeated earlier Treasury Department remarks that investors would still be fully compensated should the government make changes to the Consumer Price Index (CPI). Anderson said the government would assume all risks for any tehnical or quality changes in the CPI.  </p>
<p>Anderson said that there is no doubt that liquidity in the market will continue to rise.</p>
<p>He said that while the trading volume has not been very high, &quot;Bid-ask spreads are nararower than in other countries.&quot;</p>
<p>Anderson deemed the index-linked bond market a success, given that numerous mutual funds were based on index-linked bonds and with more than $2 billion in inflation protected corporate bond issuance.</p>
<p>He said the Treasury suspects there will be more new corporate bond issuance, as well as municipal and international.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
