<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="464348" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: U.N. clears $18 mln French sugar sale to Iraq.</title>
<headline>U.N. clears $18 mln French sugar sale to Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations has approved the sale of French sugar to Iraq worth some $18 million under a U.N.-monitored oil-for-food pact, a French diplomatic source said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;A sugar contract worth $18 million was approved on Friday,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>The source said the contract involved the sale of 50,000 tonnes of French sugar to Iraq.  </p>
<p>France submitted applications for the sale of 50,000 tonnes of French sugar to Iraq in December.</p>
<p>But the total amount of sugar Iraq purchased from international firms under the December tender remains unclear, though some traders put it at up to 150,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Earlier this month Iraq tapped world markets again for sugar under the U.N. deal and may have bought more French sugar, European traders said. But this could not be officially confirmed.</p>
<p>One French trade source said Iraq bought four cargoes of 14,000 tonnes each of French whites at $355 per tonne, including cost and freight.  </p>
<p>But another trader said Iraq may have bought only two cargoes of French whites.</p>
<p>Under the U.N. pact Iraq is allowed to sell oil worth up to $2 billion over six months to buy food and medicine. Each contract must be approved by the U.N. before the supplies can be delivered.</p>
<p>The United Nations recently approved a sale of 100,000 tonnes of French wheat to Iraq, bringing to 300,000 tonnes the volume of wheat sold to Iraq and subsequently cleared by the U.N.</p>
<p>International grain traders have sold a total of 600,000 tonnes of French wheat to Iraq since December.</p>
<p>France has also asked the U.N. to clear the remaining 300,000 tonnes of wheat sales.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5432</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
