<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="464471" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Kingspan sees reasonable demand in '97.</title>
<headline>Kingspan sees reasonable demand in '97.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish building products manufacturer Kingspan Group Plc said on Monday it is envisaged that demand for its products will remain reasonably strong for 1997 as a whole.</p>
<p>Kingspan said in its 1996 results statement the momentum of the second half of 1996 had carried through to the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;It is envisaged that demand for Kingspan products will remain reasonably strong for 1997 as a whole,&quot; Kingspan, who reported a rise of 117 percent in 1996 pre-tax profit to 13.3 million Irish pounds, said.  </p>
<p>Kingspan reported a 51.3 percent rise in turnover to 126.1 million Irish pounds while its gearing ratio at year-end was 98 percent compared to 0.6 the previous year.</p>
<p>It said the acquisitions made during the year continued to perform very well indeed.</p>
<p>&quot;Ward, the most recent acquisition is being bedded down in a satisfactory manner and is contributing to group profitability in line with expectation,&quot; Kingspan said.</p>
<p>&quot;The structural steel business of Ward has been hived off from the building components business and we are currently working towards a sale of the structural steel business to management,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Kingspan said the sequence of its various acquisitions had been very important, leading up to the acquisition of Kooltherm and finally Ward.</p>
<p>It said the product range and the geographical spread had been strengthened considerably without diluting the main focus of the group.</p>
<p>&quot;Where a business such as Ward, with a good market share, is merged with Kingspan there is clearly the potential for unlocking shareholder benefits,&quot; Kingspan said.</p>
<p>&quot;The achievement of adequate margins for the group's products is dependent upon Kingspan's market position and the dynamics within the markets it serves, such as barriers to entry and fragmentation,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Kingspan said through its investment and acquisition strategy, it had been attempting to address both of these issues.</p>
<p>&quot;The removal of fragmentation could provide scope for reducing costs and stabilising market conditions generally by creating one strong, resilient and focussed group,&quot; Kingspan said.</p>
<p>&quot;Regardless of such additional acquisition opportunities I am encouraged in the short term by the organic growth potential of the group,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Kingspan said 1996 had shown satisfactory growth over the previous year with the growth spread across Britain, Ireland and mainland Europe.</p>
<p>The company said it had consolidated its market position in the rigid insulation market and the intermediate bulk containers market through the acquisition of Kooltherm in September and S&amp;D Group (now Kingspan IBC) in March.</p>
<p>It said the Kooltherm technology for rigid insulation products was expected to make a considerable contribution to product development associated with composite panels and insulation boards.</p>
<p>&quot;This acquisition, coupled with the recently announced acquisition of Ward, puts Kingspan into a much stronger position in terms of market, product and process development,&quot; Kingspan said.</p>
<p>&quot;The group has in effect been assembling a regionally strong market position and would expect to see some benefits accrue from this position,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>It said a major investment programme was completed in its insulation division at Pembridge.</p>
<p>&quot;This investment, together with the Kooltherm acquisition, leaves the group well placed for any upturn in the UK market particularly in the area of domestic housing for which we have tailored a number of products,&quot; Kingspan said.</p>
<p>	 -- Dublin newsroom +353 1 676 9775</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
