<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="464637" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Stronger banks lead Australian stocks.</title>
<headline>Stronger banks lead Australian stocks.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank stocks led the way on Monday as the Australian share market closed firmer, seeing any U.S. rate hike as already factored in to the market.</p>
<p>Brokers said a recent local sell-off may have been overdone, while investors had readied themselves for a 25-basis point rate rise in the U.S. when the Federal Open Market Committee meets on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an air of relief that it is out of the way and life can go on as normal,&quot; said Andrew Sekely, head of equities at Intersuisse Ltd.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index closed up 15.7 points, or 0.66 percent, at 2,402.1 on moderate turnover of A$613 million.</p>
<p>Investors chased higher yielding stocks, with the banks well ahead of the pack, although gains were seen across the board. &quot;It was a yield play today,&quot; added Sekely.</p>
<p>Banks were also buoyed by speculation over the imminent release of a report into the financial sytem, which is expected to recommend the removal of barriers to mergers among the big banks.</p>
<p>The banking and finance index, which makes up almost 19 percent of the All Ordinaries index, rose almost 2.4 percent on the day.</p>
<p>National Australia Bank was also boosted by its announcement of the details of a share buyback of 5.97 percent of its ordinary shares.</p>
<p>News Corp led the turnover list, with nearly 12 million shares changing hands. The stock gained 13.2 cents to A$6.16 after its hammering in recent weeks following the decision to buy Heritage Media Corp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
