<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="464685" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian crude off, Oman drifts, Indo grades weak.</title>
<headline>Asian crude off, Oman drifts, Indo grades weak.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian crude prices were lower on Monday, and differentials seemed to be following a similar track as Oman edged down.</p>
<p>A European major sold a cargo of Oman to a Japanese refinery at MPM -5 cents and in exchange bought Lower Zakum at ADNOC +7 cents.</p>
<p>The Oman side of the deal was almost matched by another European major selling a cargo of Oman to a U.S. major at MPM -4 cents.</p>
<p>The U.S. major is normally a seller of Oman, but said it wanted the Oman for its own system.  </p>
<p>However, it did not discount the possibility of selling the Oman should it see a price advantage later in the month.</p>
<p>Previous deals have been done at discounts of two or three cents. One early deal was even done at a three-cent premium.</p>
<p>The regional market remained equally soft, with a U.S. major buying a Widuri at 20 cents under its ICP -- a further reflection of the weakness of the Minas grade.</p>
<p>Traders said Minas buyers and sellers were at a stand off, with sellers holding out for flat, while buyers were looking for a discount of 20 to 30 cents.</p>
<p>The last deal done was -15 cents, traders said.  </p>
<p>Traders said further details of West African imports were emerging.</p>
<p>They said 900,000 barrels of Bonny Light could be combined with Pennington for delivery by a western trader into Japan.</p>
<p>A VLCC of Cabinda was heard sold into China by a trader for April 15-17 loading. A trader said that would indicate China has now bought three VLCCs of April loading Cabinda.</p>
<p>--Singapore, N.Fullick (+65 870 3081), Tokyo, M.Yoshikawa (+813 5473 3706)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
