<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="464680" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAPUA NEW GUINEA: British mercenary leader pleads not guilty in PNG.</title>
<headline>British mercenary leader pleads not guilty in PNG.</headline>
<dateline>PORT MORESBY 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former British colonel who took 70 foreign mercenaries into Papua New Guinea pleaded not guilty to illegal firearm charges on Monday and defended the mercenary operation which has left the nation in crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;There is nothing wrong with the activities of Sandline,&quot; retired Colonel Tim Spicer told reporters as he left the court in Port Moresby.  </p>
<p>The magistrate ordered Spicer to stand trial on April 4 on a charge of possessing an unlicensed Russian pistol and 41 rounds of ammunition.</p>
<p>Magistrate Boio Kidu agreed to extend bail on the condition that Spicer remained at the British High Commission in the South Pacific nation. He rejected a request by Spicer's lawyer that Spicer's passport be returned.</p>
<p>&quot;Due to the seriousness of this case and what has happened in this country, the passport is to be withheld,&quot; Kidu told the court.</p>
<p>Spicer told reporters he would be happy to testify at an inquiry into the terms of PNG's US$36 million deal with his mercenary firm, Sandline International. The abortive mercenary operation against rebels on copper-rich Bougainville island has caused a week-long political crisis in PNG.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT MORESBY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAPUA NEW GUINEA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
