<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="464788" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Nikkei futures end sharply off on tax report.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Nikkei futures end sharply off on tax report.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Nikkei futures ended sharply lower on Monday after Jiji news agency quoted Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka saying Japan's consumption tax could be raised in the future after a scheduled rise on April 1.</p>
<p>The benchmark Nikkei 225 June contract lost 605 points to end below the psychologically important 18,000 level, at 17,950.</p>
<p>&quot;After the report about the consumption tax hike, the Nikkei started to come off like crazy. People feel the market is not strong and they're just trying to take profit from whatever news they can find,&quot; said a trader with a Japanese house.  </p>
<p>Dealers said stop-loss sales and bearish sentiment pulled the June Nikkei down, with a further drop seen just before the close as Tokyo players sold it on SIMEX after Osaka's close.</p>
<p>&quot;There was good size selling from Tokyo after the Osaka market closed,&quot; said the trader.</p>
<p>Early in the day, the market was lifted by a Japan newspaper report of a government plan to allow securitisation of collateralised land from April to boost property market liquidity.  </p>
<p>But dealers said this news had already been in the market for a few weeks and failed to provide any support after the consumption tax report appeared.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market should rebound tomorrow but I would want to sell if it reached 18,200,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>On the downside, he said the June Nikkei should be supported initially around 17,800, with a break below that level seen pushing it to 17,500.  </p>
<p>Taiwan stock index futures was pressured as Taipei stocks plunged 3.49 percent to close at 7,946.88 on a report that China planned to hold war games near the island, possibly to protest a visit by Tibet's exiled spiritual leader, the Dalai Lama.</p>
<p>The March MSCI Taiwan index contract ended at 330.2 against its opening 344.5 on volume of 838 lots.</p>
<p>April ended at 327.0 against 344.2 on 689 lots.</p>
<p>A report that U.S. investment bank Morgan Stanley had lowered its holding ratio on Taiwan stocks to four percent from six percent also weighed on the market, Refco (Singapore) Pte Ltd said in a daily commentary. -- Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
