<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="464967" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - March 24.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - March 24.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Thai press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>TOP STORIES</p>
<p>- The New Aspiration Party (NAP) has no vested interest in purchasing Bangkok Land Co's Muang Thong Thani housing estate as a site for the new parliament, NAP secretary-general Snoh Thienthong says. Interior Minister Snoh dismisses the opposition's allegation as mud-slinging and calls on the public to consider the issue on the grounds of appropriateness alone. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh denies that he has instructed the Interior Ministry to arrest Democrat Party deputy secretary-general Suthep Thaugsuban over charges of encroachment in Tha Chana forest. Chavalit says the pending arrest is only routine procedure after police have wrapped up their investigation. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>- Interior Minister Snoh Thienthong admits that he has been contacted by Rakesh Saxena, a key suspect in the Bangkok Bank of Commerce (BBC) loan scandal case, but appears surprised that reporters knew about sometihing he regarded as a secret. Deputy Interior Minister Chalerm Yoobamrung, who oversees the government's attempts to combat drugs and crime, reportedly said over the weekend that Saxena, formerly a financial adviser to the scandal-hit bank, had asked the Interior Minister to facilitate his return to Thailand so he could defend himself in court. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>	 + + + +</p>
<p>BUSINESS</p>
<p>- The government must accelerate the project to renovate and improve the former U-Tapao aircraft maintenance centre otherwise Thailand may lose the chance to become the aircraft maintenance hub for the East Asian region, the Board of Investment (BOI) says. The aircraft maintenance centre at U-Tapao airport, which served the U.S. Air Force during the Vietnam war, has been deserted for about two decades since the American military withdrew from the country. (BUSINESS DAY)</p>
<p>- Plasticware manufacturer Sri Thai Superware is close to clinching a deal to supply 1.2 million front and rear bumpers a year to the U.S. automobile giant General Motors (GM). GM has already sent a delegation to study the production process of the bumpers at Sri Thai's plants. (BUSINESS DAY)</p>
<p>- More than 150 leading international executives will today be given a pep talk on the state of the Thai economy. Amnuay Viravan, the Deputy Prime Minister and Finance Minister, will explain the government's steps to bolster what he believes are the already sound fundamentals of the economy. Corporate leaders, statesmen and academics will be among those attending the opening of the Fortune Global Forum in Bangkok. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
