<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46496" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Crude oil, gas prices rise on Iraq missile firings.</title>
<headline>Crude oil, gas prices rise on Iraq missile firings.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crude oil prices rose sharply for a second consecutive session Wednesday after Iraq fired missiles at U.S. warplanes, reviving fears that supplies will be curtailed.</p>
<p>Cotton prices rose the maximum 3-cents-per-pound daily limit after the Agriculture Department released a surprisingly low U.S. crop estimate. Wheat prices tumbled after the department forecast a large U.S. crop.</p>
<p>The Commodity Research Bureau's index of 17 commodities was down 0.92 at 247.22.</p>
<p>Iraq's launching of the missiles and news the United States ordered stealth fighters and B-52 bombers to the Gulf region indicated Mideast tensions may be escalating, which could jeopardise the flow of oil from that region.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is worried that the tension in Iraq could escalate even more every time the U.S. flies over the no-fly zone,&quot; said Ed Kevelson, director of refined products at Paribas Futures Inc.</p>
<p>At the New York Mercantile Exchange, October crude oil closed up 63 cents at $24.75 a barrel, after setting a contract high of $24.98 earlier.</p>
<p>October gasoline closed up 1.06 cents at 65.91 cents a gallon, and October heating oil rose 1.52 cents to 68.19 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>Traders bid cotton futures up the 3-cent daily limit at the New York Cotton Exchange after the Agriculture Department slashed nearly 700,000 bales from its previous U.S. crop estimate. NYCE October cotton closed up 3 cents at 74.90 cents per pound.</p>
<p>The Agriculture Department estimated this year's U.S. cotton crop at 17.900 million 480-pound bales, down from its August estimate of 18.577 million bales. The smaller estimate surprised analysts, especially those who expected a 100,000- to 200,000-bale increase from August.</p>
<p>&quot;We are surprised by the big decrease in three key states,&quot; said Sharon Johnson, analyst with Frank Schneider &amp; Co. &quot;It was very much in conflict with what we were hearing in yields.&quot;</p>
<p>In a summary accompanying the crop estimate, the department attributed the decline to harmful hot weather in California and dry conditions in Arkansas and Louisana.</p>
<p>Some analysts said the high prices will curb demand for cotton, especially exports.</p>
<p>Bearish Agriculture Department wheat production forecasts for the United States and other countries hit wheat futures prices at the three major U.S. futures exchanges.</p>
<p>&quot;The world has more wheat than anybody originally thought and the buyers' appetites aren't that big,&quot; said Skip Searcy, wheat trading specialist for FIMAT Futures USA Inc.</p>
<p>The department estimated this year's U.S. wheat crop at nearly 2.30 billion bushels, up from its August estimate of 2.25 billion.</p>
<p>It also increased its estimates for Australian and Canadian wheat crops.</p>
<p>&quot;Canada will under cut us, Australia will undersell us and the EU is cranking up their subsidies,&quot; Searcy said.</p>
<p>The Chicago Board of Trade's December soft red winter wheat contract fell 15-1/4 cents to $4.37-1/2. Kansas City Board of Trade December hard red winter wheat closed down 15-1/4 at $4.36-3/4 and Minneapolis Grain Exchange December spring wheat was down 14 cents at $4.20.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
