<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="465299" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: VF Corp. plans Maidenform acquisition.</title>
<headline>VF Corp. plans Maidenform acquisition.</headline>
<byline>Robin Sidel</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>VF Corp., the No. 3 maker of women's lingerie with brands Vanity Fair and Vassarette, said Tuesday it planned to buy Maidenform Worldwide Inc. in a deal that would expand its role in the booming market for body-slimming undergarments.</p>
<p>Terms of the potential transaction were not disclosed and company officials said a definitive agreement would not be reached for at least 30 days.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a done deal. It's a letter of intent,&quot; said VF spokeswoman Cindy Knoebel, adding that more due diligence will be conducted.</p>
<p>A merger of the two companies would make VF more competitive with market leaders Sara Lee Corp., which owns Playtex and Wonderbra, and Warnaco Group Inc., which has the Warner's and Olga brands.</p>
<p>The potential transaction also would include Maidenform's 92 percent stake in NCC Industries Inc., maker of full-figure intimate apparel.</p>
<p>VF has about 11 percent of the $9.8 billion intimate apparel industry, while privately-held Maidenform holds about 10 percent, according to company officials and industry experts.</p>
<p>&quot;We undertook this transaction because today's market does not stand still and demands greater and greater investments for success. VF Corp., with its proven leadership in the industry, is well-suited to be able to grow and develop the Maidenform business,&quot; a Maidenform spokesman said.</p>
<p>Industry experts said anti-trust issues may arise with government regulators, although they may not be severe enough to ruin the transaction.</p>
<p>&quot;From what we can see, there's not so much overlap,&quot; Knoebel said.</p>
<p>Maidenform generated sales of $400 million in 1996. Long known for its sexy ads, the company this month unveiled a &quot;Maidenform Unhooked&quot; advertising blitz that shows underwear-clad models interspersed with phrases like &quot;Sometimes I wear a bra just for fun&quot; and &quot;The way my husband still looks at me, you'd think I was twenty&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Maidenform is clearly one of the premier names in intimate apparel, and could be an excellent strategic fit with our existing intimate apparel brands,&quot; VF Corp. Chief Executive Officer Mackey McDonald said in a news release.</p>
<p>Wyomissing, Pa.-based VF, which posted sales of $5.13 billion in 1996, operates other apparel businesses under brands such as Lee, Wrangler, Healthtex and Jantzen. The firm has undergone a comprehensive restructuring, predicted record earnings and sales for 1997, and set a goal to add $2 billion in new sales by 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;They have been putting some meaningful effort into attracting Wall Street's attention and they seem to have accomplished that goal,&quot; said David Leibowitz of Burnham Securities.</p>
<p>Analaysts said a Maidenform acquisition would help VF build its presence in the &quot;shapewear&quot; market, which has become the industry's fastest-growing segment as Baby Boomers buy garments to help slim protruding tummies and rear-ends.</p>
<p>Though still far behind sales of bras and panties, shapewear sales reached $382 million in 1996, up from $339 million in 1995, according to the American Apparel Manufacturers Association.</p>
<p>New York-based Maidenform is considered a leader in the fast-growing shapewear segment with its &quot;Flexees&quot; and &quot;Subtract&quot; garments.</p>
<p>Experts also said VF would also benefit from Maidenform's high-margin Oscar de la Renta designer brand of intimate apparel.</p>
<p>VF stock was unchanged at $68 in afternoon trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
