<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="465465" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: OPPOSITION CALLS FOR FASTER S.AFRICA PRIVATISATION.</title>
<headline>OPPOSITION CALLS FOR FASTER S.AFRICA PRIVATISATION.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A vigorous privatisation programme was on Tuesday mooted in parliament by several speakers, including Inkatha Freedom Party leader Mangosutho Buthelezi, as the best way to reduce debt and boost growth.</p>
<p>Speaking during the debate on the 1997/98 budget, Buthelezi said that government had to adopt tough, courageous and principled policies.</p>
<p>&quot;When necessary we must also have the determination to propose and implement unpopular policies which might call for sacrifices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If government wants to achieve its six percent growth rate target by the end of the decade, we cannot just do more of the same. What is needed is a momentous impulse in three directions -- privatisation, deregulation and unemployment.&quot;</p>
<p>Privatisation would help reduce debt and increase the overall efficiency of the economic system. Deregulation should become a new culture of government. Taxation had to be lowered and tax collection could partly be privatised, he said.</p>
<p>Democratic Party finance spokesman Ken Andrew said that despite the commitment of President Nelson Mandela to privatisation, there had been &quot;clumsy and half-hearted attempts&quot; at selling off state assets.</p>
<p>These had cost South Africa dearly as it lost out on the benefits of debt reduction, greater efficiency, technology transfer and new investments as well as job creation.</p>
<p>Andrew estimated that a vigorous privatisation exercise could raise 20 billion rand in 1997/98. That would slash government's borrowing requirement from the 37 billion rand estimated in the budget to 17 billion rand which would push interest rates down significantly.</p>
<p>Growth would be boosted and exchange controls could be abolished altogether because of improved foreign reserves, he said.</p>
<p>Higher growth would, in turn, attract large sums of foreign investment. &quot;It sounds too good to be true, but it is not,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Parliamentary newsroom +27 21 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
