<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="465416" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-SAMPRAS ADVANCES AT LIPTON CHAMPIONSHIPS.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SAMPRAS ADVANCES AT LIPTON CHAMPIONSHIPS.</headline>
<dateline>KEY BISCAYNE, Florida 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top seed Pete Sampras showed winning form at the Lipton Championships Monday, and three Spaniards were sent packing.</p>
<p>Sampras was responsible for one Spanish departure, winning a 6-3 7-6 (7-3) third-round victory over 36th-ranked Francisco Clavet of Spain.</p>
<p>Early in the day, second seed Arantxa Sanchez Vicario looked pathetically placid during most of a 6-0 7-5 fourth-round loss to 29th-ranked Sadrine Testud of France.</p>
<p>Seventh seed Carlos Moya, who shocked the tennis world by reaching the Australian Open finals, where he promptly lost to the top-ranked Sampras, fell to 66th-ranked Mikael Tillstrom of Sweden 6-4 3-6 6-3 in another third-round match.</p>
<p>The lone Spaniard experiencing victory was Alex Corretja, who won a 6-1 7-5 third round decision over qualifier Sebastien Lareau of Canada.</p>
<p>Scoring a big win was 26th-ranked American Jim Courier, who rebounded from 4-1 down in the third set to defeat powerful left-handed Australian Scott Draper 4-6 6-1 6-4 in another third-round match.</p>
<p>The 79th-ranked Draper was responsible for upsetting defending champion Andre Agassi in the second round.</p>
<p>The women's quarter-final pairings were decided on Monday.</p>
<p>Top seed Martina Hingis of Switzerland plays 10th seed Mary Joe Fernandez of the United States, third-seeded Czech Jana Novotna plays eighth seed Iva Majoli of Croatia, fourth seed Monica Seles plays seventh seed Irina Spirlea of Romania, and 11th seed Barbara Paulus of Austria plays Sadrine Testud of France.</p>
<p>Sampras, who is 19-1 for the year, is the only seed left in the top half of the men's draw going into the fourth round.</p>
<p>The bottom half of the draw is strong with seeds. Second seed Thomas Muster, fourth seed Goran Ivanisevic and fifth seed Richard Krajicek still remain.</p>
<p>Sampras looked extremely comfortable during the first set, but let down his guard in the second set. After breaking Clavet to go up 3-2 in the second set, he let Clavet break right back in the sixth game.</p>
<p>&quot;I got a little careless,&quot; Sampras admitted. &quot;I was careless in that game at 3-2. He competes very well and is all around the court.&quot;</p>
<p>Sampras, who is nursing a sore right wrist, jumped to a 4-0 lead in the tiebreaker before Clavet was able to win a few points.</p>
<p>The first set was a nightmare for the third-ranked Sanchez Vicario.</p>
<p>A player long known as someone unwilling to capitulate, Sanchez Vicario seems quite willing to fold lately. With no career titles since last May in Hamburg, Sanchez Vicario won only three points in three service games in the opening set.</p>
<p>Down 5-2 in the second set, Sanchez Vicario valiantly tried a comeback. Although she won the next three games, it was too little, too late.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't play so good,&quot; Sanchez Vicario said. &quot;I was a little bit tired. I was a little bit late today into the ball. That is something you could see as the match was going on. At the end, I was too late to come back.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KEY BISCAYNE, Florida"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
