<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="465645" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bank Montreal sets small business loan plan.</title>
<headline>Bank Montreal sets small business loan plan.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of Montreal said on Tuesday it has set up a C$1 billion loan program to spur growth of Canadian small and medium-sized businesses by offering fixed-rate loans at lower interest rates.</p>
<p>Canada's third-largest bank said it will provide loans of between C$10,000 and C$250,000 for terms of three to five years and may be amortized for periods up to 15 years.</p>
<p>The loans are for credit-worthy small businesses to use for purposes such as buying new equipment or financing expansion plans, the bank said.</p>
<p>&quot;More than 95 per cent of our business customers are small to medium-sized companies with annual revenues of less than $10 million. As they grow, they reach a critical point where they need financing to seize current market opportunities,&quot; said Maurice Hudon, senior vice-president of Bank of Montreal's personal and commercial lending services.</p>
<p>The new loan funding will increase by 12 percent the C$8 billion in credit already outstanding to small business, the bank said.</p>
<p>Bank of Montreal has grown its share of the small business loan market by six percent in the past six years.</p>
<p>The new financing program allows borrowers to fix their interest rate for the full term of the loan, and receive a significant discount in the first year.</p>
<p>The rate of the first year is 4.90 percent, a rate which will apply to all loans made up to June 30, 1997. The rates thereafter will be set according to market conditions with the first year rate established at a discount. The program will be in effect until January 31, 1998.</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
