<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="465662" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Zaire rebels move towards talks - South Africa.</title>
<headline>Zaire rebels move towards talks - South Africa.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zairean rebel leader Laurent Kabila has dropped a demand for direct talks with Zaire's ailing president and will negotiate with a team appointed by him, South African sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The government sources told Reuters Kabila said he was only prepared to negotiate once and the outcome had to be conclusive.</p>
<p>There was no immediate rebel reaction to the report but both Kabila and Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko have come under heavy international pressure to negotiate in the face of the rebel war that is tearing apart Zaire.</p>
<p>The sources said South Africa put Kabila's points to Mobutu and expected a reply before Wednesday's special summit in Togo.</p>
<p>The sources confirmed that South African President Nelson Mandela had outlined Kabila's conditions in a letter carried to Mobutu in Kinshasa by Deputy President Thabo Mbeki on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;President Mobutu undertook to respond within 48 hours, which is by tonight. That will enable the deputy president to report to the Lome summit tomorrow,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>Mobutu and Kabila have sent teams to Lome, Togo, for a special Organisation of African Unity summit that starts on Wednesday and will address the six month war in Africa's third largest country.</p>
<p>A Zambian foreign ministry official said on Tuesday Zambia had evacuated the families of its diplomatic staff in Kinshasa and southeast mining centre of Lubumbashi because of the war.</p>
<p>In Cape Town, Sadako Ogata, head of the U.N. refugee agency, slammed the international community over Zaire and called for an African rapid intervention force to intervene in conflicts.</p>
<p>&quot;The absence of a convergence of interests and views among the major powers also results in preventing this drama from receiving the international attention and determination it deserves for solution,&quot; she told the South African parliament.</p>
<p>Analysts said she was referring to reported tension between the United States and France over diplomatic spoils in Zaire.</p>
<p>Some 400,000 Rwandan and Burundian refugees are unaccounted for in Zaire since fleeing when civil war began last October.</p>
<p>Kabila's supporters seized Zaire's embassy in the Ugandan capital Kampala on Monday, set ablaze a Zairean flag and broke a portrait of Mobutu before being expelled by police, diplomats said.</p>
<p>Kinshasa accuses Uganda, Rwanda and Burundi of sending in troops to fight alongside rebels. All three deny the charges.</p>
<p>On Monday, the rebel Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire claimed their biggest political victory by forcing the resignation of Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo.</p>
<p>South African sources said Kabila had since changed his conditions for talks, despite a statement earlier by the rebel information commissioner Raphael Nghenda, who said: &quot;Kengo's resignation changes nothing.&quot;</p>
<p>The rebels were not available for comment but the South African sources confirmed a report from Kinshasa by the CNN network, which said Kabila's conditions now included:</p>
<p>- Kabila will talk only to a delegation mandated by Mobutu and authorised to make decisions on his behalf;</p>
<p>- Kabila will not participate in a second round of talks if the first fail or are inconclusive;</p>
<p>- The talks must take place outside Zaire and preferably in South Africa, where Mandela and Mbeki recently anchored proximity talks between the two sides.</p>
<p>The sources said the sequence of events remained a key issue, with Mobutu formally insisting on a ceasefire as a condition for talks and Kabila demanding talks before a ceasefire.</p>
<p>One source said Mobutu was likely to make a concession on this deadlock on Tuesday, either agreeing to simultaneous talks and ceasefire or to talks before the fighting is halted.</p>
<p>Kengo's resignation plunged Kinshasa into uncertainty as hundreds of American, Belgian and French troops gathered across the mighty Zaire river in Congo to prepare to evacuate foreign nationals.</p>
<p>Mobutu, 66 and struggling against prostate cancer as well as Kabila's rebellion, accepted Kengo's letter of resignation but asked him to remain in office until a successor was found.</p>
<p>The rebels, now in control of about one quarter of the country, are advancing on the vital Shaba region in the south whose colossal resources of copper, cobalt and precious metals make Zaire one of Africa's potentially richest countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
