<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="465753" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - March 25.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - March 25.</headline>
<text>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - The trade deficit for the first two months of 1997 reached 27.2 billion crowns, up from the same period last year where the deficit was 16.2 billion. Experts fear that the trade deficit could exceed 200 billion in 1997.</p>
<p>- The finance ministry is planning on issuing retail bonds valued at 50 billion crowns. The bonds would be issued for a two year period and are intended to safeguard against the declining propensity to save.</p>
<p>- The finance ministry will increase household energy prices as of July 1 by 15 percent. In January 1998, energy will cease to be subsidised and VAT on electricity and gas will increase from 5 percent to 22 percent.</p>
<p>MLADA FRONTA DNES - Economists fear that if wage growth goes unchecked, and if the overall quality of work is not improved, the crown could be headed for trouble. Wages are currently rising at 18 percent while work productivity based on GDP has increased only by 12 percent. Experts say this is contributing to inflation and boosting the trade deficit.</p>
<p>- Industry and trade ministry officials are not concerned over remarks made by the Russian gas company, Gazprom, which threatened to increase gas prices if the Czechs sign an agreement with Norway to import gas as an alternative. Ministry officials say they believe the Russians are simply trying to establish a strong initial bargaining position for upcoming negotiations.</p>
<p>- Some observers are suggesting that the election of Michael Zantovsky as head of the Civic Democratic Alliance (ODA) could win the party votes in future elections. The reason for the prediction is Zantovsky's close freiendship with President, Vaclav Havel.</p>
<p>LIDOVE NOVINY - The association for wholesale distribution of pharmaceuticals (AVEL) continues to lobby the health ministry to put indebted hospitals on the auction block. AVEL is upset that it will receive 800 million crowns owed to it by 14 hospitals run by the ministry over a two year period, instead of one year.</p>
<p>PRAVO - Unisys says that it will file a complaint with the defence ministry protesting the victory of rival bidder EDS in the staff information system tender. Unisys says that it may also push for a police investigation into allegations that it was tied in with former Czech politicians that were to help the electronics giant win the competition. Unisys claims that the accusations of corruption hurt its chances of winning during this tender.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom 420-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
