<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="465778" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Merrill sees NFI units at PLN 151-243.</title>
<headline>Merrill sees NFI units at PLN 151-243.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Merrill Lynch in London said in a report dated March 17 that the Polish mass privatisation NFI units should trade at between 151 and 243 zlotys.</p>
<p>It also said Polish National Investment Funds (NFI), likely to start bourse trade, should appeal both to emerging European investors and close-end fund investors.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that the current price of the (NFI unit) offers significant upside, and implies similar potential for (NFI) share price appreciation, following the anticipated summer listing,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>NFI units traded at 156.5 zlotys on Tuesday and at 166 zlotys on the day the report was issued.</p>
<p>The report stressed, however, that each NFI represented different value because of its sector emphasis, approach to restructuring and fund objective.</p>
<p>&quot;Accordingly we believe careful stocks selection is of vital importance to NFI investors,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Under the government's NFI programme, shares in some 500 mid-sized companies are allocated to 15 NFIs run by foreign and domestic management firms.</p>
<p>The 26 million Poles who bought a participation unit in the scheme will have the opportunity to exchange it for 15 shares, one in each fund before they start bourse trade.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
