<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="465740" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELARUS: Russia criticises Belarus, U.S. recalls Minsk envoy.</title>
<headline>Russia criticises Belarus, U.S. recalls Minsk envoy.</headline>
<byline>Larisa Sayenko</byline>
<dateline>MINSK 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belarus's relations with Moscow and Washington came under strain on Tuesday as hardline President Alexander Lukashenko prepared to visit Russian President Boris Yeltsin and sign a deal on a union.</p>
<p>A week before Lukashenko's trip to Russia, the United States recalled its ambassador from Minsk for consultations and said it would announce further steps to protest at the expulsion from Belarus of a U.S. diplomat.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman John Dinger said ambassador Kenneth Yalowitz would arrive in Washington on Thursday to report to Secretary of State Madeleine Albright.</p>
<p>The Kremlin, rarely openly critical of its small  &quot;cousin&quot; to the west, criticised Belarus on Tuesday for cracking down on Russian journalists working there.</p>
<p>&quot;The very fact that Russian television channels have been denied the right to send information material from Minsk prompts deep concern in the Kremlin,&quot; spokesman Sergei Yastrzhembsky told a news briefing in Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the right to expect that the principles of freedom of information will be restored in full.&quot;</p>
<p>Belarus authorities began stopping Russian journalists from entering the main television centre in Minsk on Sunday and extended the restriction to other foreign broadcasters on Monday.</p>
<p>Lukashenko and Yeltsin agreed last April 2 to form a &quot;commonwealth&quot; of two states, and a new deal is due to be signed at a meeting next week marking the anniversary.</p>
<p>The agreement is expected to move towards closer economic union, but it is unclear how far it will go towards full merger.</p>
<p>Yeltsin has mooted union as a possibility while Lukashenko stresses any merger must be one between two sovereign states.</p>
<p>Opposition forces in Minsk plan to mark the meeting with the kind of big protests which have turned violent in the past, particularly last Sunday when a nationalist rally erupted in clashes.</p>
<p>Moscow's criticism came on the heels of a serious worsening in Belarus-U.S. relations, strained since Belarussian forces shot down a balloon in 1995, killing two American amateur pilots.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the U.S. embassy said first secretary Serzh Alexandrov, of Belarussian origin, had left the country late on Monday following an expulsion order on Sunday.</p>
<p>Lukashenko took a step back in the row on Monday, saying he wanted to strengthen relations with Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want people to say that there was an anti-American campaign in Belarus,&quot; Lukashenko was quoted by state television as saying during a meeting with the newly-appointed Belarussian ambassador to the United States, Valery Tsepkalo.</p>
<p>Alexandrov was arrested at Sunday's rally and accused of &quot;provocative&quot; actions but the embassy said he was carrying out his normal diplomatic duties by observing a political rally.</p>
<p>Last week Washington said it had cut off $40 million in aid to the former Soviet republic of 10 million because of its human rights record. U.S. officials have also criticised Belarussian authorities for media restrictions.</p>
<p>Alexander Stupnikov, a reporter for Russia's NTV channel, had his accreditation withdrawn for &quot;systematic distortion of information about our country&quot;, state television said on Monday.</p>
<p>On Tuesday evening, the Belarussian state channel said the authorities were considering deporting Stupnikov.</p>
<p>Journalists handed in a protest note at the foreign ministry about the move against the journalist, who has an Israeli passport.</p>
<p>The government announced on Monday it was banning the import and export of &quot;all audio, video and text material which could damage the political or economic interests of the country&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINSK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELARUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
