<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="465892" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Bogota jail convicts riot, win initial demands.</title>
<headline>Bogota jail convicts riot, win initial demands.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than 2,000 prisoners including convicted leftist guerrillas rioted and started fires in Bogota's La Modelo jail early on Tuesday to protest against cramped conditions, prison authorities said.</p>
<p>About 800 prison officers and police fired tear gas at the rioters and restored relative calm. The National Prisons Institute (INPEC) announced by early afternoon that it had bowed to the inmates' key demands by firing the prison director and agreeing to transfer 100 prisoners to less crowded facilities in the next few days.</p>
<p>But for most of the day police helicopters hovered overhead and the army set up a cordon around the prison in a west-central neighbourhood of the capital as inmates roamed the jail at will.</p>
<p>The riot flared in two prison wings shortly after midnight when guards confiscated liquor from a group of inmates. There were no reports of injuries, INPEC officer Col. Hugo Alfonso Cepeda told reporters.</p>
<p>A Reuters photographer outside the jail heard a burst of machine-gun fire, apparently shots fired into the air as one convict smashed windows in one of the guard posts. He also reported smoke hanging over the prison and said by mid-afternoon hundreds of masked prisoners were still on the roof, brandishing sticks and clubs and makeshift signs.</p>
<p>One sign read &quot;End prison overcrowding&quot; and another said &quot;ELN present,&quot; a reference to the National Liberation Army (ELN) rebel force, some of whose members were among the rioting convicts. A third sign read &quot;The FARC support you,&quot; a reference to Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) rebels also serving time in La Modelo.</p>
<p>An INPEC spokesman said at least 2,100 prisoners were housed in the two wings, which are designed for 1,200 convicts. He said all the prisoners had joined an initially small group of rioters, but stressed the problems had not spilled over to the high security wing.</p>
<p>Representatives of the public prosecutor's office, the Human Rights Ombudsman and the International Committee of the Red Cross were holding talks with prisoners to find out what other demands they were making.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
