<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="465852" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Reshuffled Russia still in DeBeers gem talks -govt.</title>
<headline>Reshuffled Russia still in DeBeers gem talks -govt.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Russian government, fresh from a major reshuffle and expecting more changes, continues to negotiate with diamond giant De Beers on a long-stalled gem export deal, a government spokesman said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;These negotiations have not been cut off,&quot; Igor Shabdurasulov told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;As you remember, there was a period of public difficulties in relations, when both sides made rather bitter delarations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But nonetheless some common ground has been found and the work continues. I think the work will be completed in a fairly short time.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the recent cabinet reshuffle had caused some difficulties in the talks but that he did not expect any principal changes in Moscow's position as a result.</p>
<p>He gave no further details.</p>
<p>De Beers said earlier this month that it hoped to complete a new deal in March and that it expected a resolution from Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin and a decree from President Boris Yeltsin to finalise a deal.</p>
<p>The South African gem group stopped purchases of diamonds from Russia at the end of last year after Moscow failed to approve a new trade deal.</p>
<p>--Adam Tanner, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
