<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="465938" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico blocks EU aid to election observers.</title>
<headline>Mexico blocks EU aid to election observers.</headline>
<byline>Henry Tricks</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's Foreign Ministry has blocked a European Union plan to fund observers for July elections in Mexico City, drawing widespread fire in a country with a history of electoral dirty tricks.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Jose Angel Gurria late on Monday rejected a plea by members of Mexico's supreme electoral authority to allow European Union funding for a human rights group that planned to monitor the July 6 vote. In a letter, Gurria argued that allowing Europe to back an election project in Mexico broke with protocol.</p>
<p>Members of the Federal Electoral Institute, an independent body that is increasingly flexing its muscles in in a country run for 68 years by a single party, said they would press the issue to ensure a fair vote.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe in the widest electoral observation possible and supported by all means available. The more observers there are, the more guarantees there are that we will have clean and transparent elections,&quot; Mauricio Merino, one of the nine civic councilors on the institute's board, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Last week he and six colleagues on the nine-member board wrote to Gurria expressing concern that the $400,000 for the private Mexican Academy of Human Rights had been vetoed. They urged the Foreign Ministry to permit more international funding for election watchdog groups.</p>
<p>With less than four months before Mexico City residents elect their governor, sometimes known as mayor, for the first time ever, Merino said there was a pressing need for more observers.</p>
<p>Until now, the Mexico City &quot;regent&quot; has been hand-picked by the president and has always come from the ruling Instutitional Revolutionary Party (PRI). The PRI has been accused of rigging votes and using other illicit means in the past to maintain its grip on power, although complaints have dwindled in recent years as opposition parties have won increasing success at the polls.</p>
<p>In the Mexico City race, recent opinion polls have favoured Cuauhtemoc Cardenas of the left-leaning Party of the Democratic Revolution.</p>
<p>Also up for grabs on July 6 are seats in the lower house of Congress, and some pundits predict the PRI's almost seven-decade-old majority is at risk.</p>
<p>Oscar Gonzalez, head of the human rights group that had sought the EU's support, said he feared the government's backing for observation projects, which was widely lauded in 1994 presidential elections, may be on the wane because of the PRI's potential problems at the polls.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to us that in 1994 there was a much clearer disposition on the part of the government concerning electoral observation,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>The academy also speculated that the Foreign Ministry opposed its project in part because it was aimed at monitoring campaign spending, plagued by widespread abuses in the past.</p>
<p>Members of the PRI, however, argue vehemently against allowing money from abroad into the electoral process, saying it smacks of foreign meddling in Mexican internal affairs.</p>
<p>In defending his decision, Gurria argued that the EU, in funding the project, was implicitly seeking to &quot;create the conditions to ensure that the elections ... are clean and trustworthy.&quot; He said that was not part of the established framework of Mexico-EU relations and he indirectly criticised Brussels for not consulting with the government on the project.</p>
<p>He also noted that Mexico has agreed with the United Nations Development Programme on a $469,000 scheme to fund observation projects. The money, he said, comes from Mexico and will be funnelled via the UNDP to the Federal Electoral Institute.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
