<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46596" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Los Angeles airport rules out runway on bay.</title>
<headline>Los Angeles airport rules out runway on bay.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Los Angeles airport officials on Wednesday said they have ruled out a controversial proposal to construct a runway in the Santa Monica Bay, adding that they would pursue other options to accommodate future growth at the international airport.</p>
<p>The proposal would have involved constructing a platform on the Bay for a runway that could have connected to existing Los Angeles International Airport facilities.</p>
<p>But several local environmental groups were opposed the proposal, warning of the plan's potential impact on the Bay.  </p>
<p>&quot;The technical team ... has carefully examined the ocean concept, and has determined that proposing a runway in the ocean is not feasible or practical at this time,&quot; said Department of Airports Executive Director John  Driscoll. &quot;It would take us more than 10 years to implement such a runway. That's too long.&quot;</p>
<p>Los Angeles City Councilwoman Ruth Galanter welcomed the Department of Airports' decision, saying, &quot;In abandoning the Bay option, the Department of Airports is demonstrating the kind of environmental sensitivity we need.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Santa Monica Bay runway option was proposed as a part of the Los Angeles International Airport's master plan process, which is now underway.</p>
<p>The master plan, the first of its kind conducted for the region's primary airport, will provide a 20-year blueprint for redevelopment and expansion of the airport.</p>
<p>A team of experts in aviation planning, economic forecasting, traffic, environmental protection and urban design has been working on the plan for the past 18 months.  </p>
<p>Expansion concepts for the airport are due to be completed and released for public comment in October, with the final plan due to be presented to the Los Angeles City Council in 1997, following extensive public review.</p>
<p>Daniel Garcia, president of the Board of Airport Commissioners, warned that by foregoing the ocean runway option, the master plan's ability to handle long-term growth in demand at the airport would be limited.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's not kid ourselves,&quot; Garcia said. &quot;This decision will have consequences for southern California, and should be taken by southern California as a wake-up call.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;We are facing a crisis in airport capacity for southern California, and if we don't deal with it, we will see the jobs that we owe our next generation moving to Colorado, Texas and Illinois,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Los Angeles International Airport currently contributes 393,000 jobs to the region and $43 billion in annual economic activity. These economic benefits are projected to increase to 470,000 jobs and $64 billion region-wide by the year 2015, airport officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Every effort to capture as much regional economic benefit as possible will be made, while ensuring protection of the environment,&quot; Garcia said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
