<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="466015" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News-Mar 26.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News-Mar 26.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Following a wave of sharemarket activity over the past two days surrounding ANZ and Westpac, the two banks tipped to be vulnerable if the Howard Government relaxes bank and merger rules, Federal Treasurer Peter Costello has signalled the Government will respond immediately to some of the more commercially sensitive recommendations of the Wallis report. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>George Trumbull, the managing director of Australia's largest insurance group, the AMP Society, revealed yesterday the company, which was one of three bidders left in the race for British insurer Scottish Amicable, has been out-bidded by a A$5.7 billion ofer from Prudential Corp plc. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Peter Bunn, a spokesman for 34 independent supermarkets, yesterday rejected statements made on Monday by Woolworths group managing director Reg Clairs that none of the independent supermarkets had withdrawn their business from Australian Independent Wholealers, Woolworth's independent grocery wholesaling division. Bunn revealed 30 of the independents had signed formal contracts with market leader Davids Ltd. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Hong Kong-controlled Downer group, a subsidiary of Paul Y-ITC Construction Holdings Ltd, yesterday raised its bid for Century Drilling Ltd, which recently reported a 131 per cent increase in net profit for the six months to December to A$3.47 million. The bid was raised from A$1.02-a-share to A$1.60-a-share, valuing the target at A$96 million, a figure still well below the company's valuation price of between A$1.86 and A$2.26. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Despite being criticised by investors earlier this month for its one-for-six rights issue to fund a buyout of HudCon's management contract, Crown Ltd revealed yesterday it had received unexpectedly strong institutional support for the A$180 million capital raising. The issue, Crown's tenth capital listing since raising, means sub-underwriting support of the major shareholders will not be required. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After embattled pipes and fittings producer Crevet Ltd posted a significant drop in interim pre-tax, pre-abnormals profit to A$16,000 from A$691,000 previously, the board fired chief executive Robert McAlister yesterday, saying it no longer had confidence in his abilities. McAlister is to be replaced by manufacturing manager Herb Foxlee until an executive search is complete. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>The announcement yesterday that the ANZ Bank is to axe a further 356 jobs in a major shake-up of its consumer banking operations was largely overlooked by the sharemarket. ANZ led a sell-off in bank stocks after Federal Treasurer Peter Costello revealed the Wallis report on the inquiry into the financial system would not be released until April 7. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After identifying itself as an all-Australian insurer for its operations in Asia and China, insurance giant National Mutual's local rival in China, Colonial Mutual, questioned whether NatMut is actually an Australian company after it was revealed it is controlled by France's AXA group. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The four partners in the massive Gorgon-Chryasor gas field off the West Australian coast - Mobil, Texaco, Shell and Chevron - are divided as to whether it is viable for the project to be a stand-alone development, with key partner Shell predicting it will become part of the A$12 billion North West Shelf facility, and Mobil and Texaco maintaining a separate liquefied natural gas project is viable. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a report on telecommunications to be released today, the Federal Government's economic think-tank, the Productivity Commission, has warned national carrier Telstra may have a conflict of interest in providing infrastructure to rivals when the industry s fully deregulated from July 1. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Federal Government has rejected claims from the Institute of Chartered Accountants that many Australian businesses with taxable fringe benefits of A$5,000 or less will still have to keep records for fringe benefits tax. Small Business Minister Geoff Posser insisted yesterday the threshold of A$5,000 in taxable fringe benefits would assist at least 50 per cent of the small firms already paying FBT. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Parties involved in the long-running settlement negotiations between Seven Network and its fellow Optus Vision shareholders have dismissed claims from Seven's legal counsel, Roger Gyles QC, that the talks have broken down, indicating a resolution is stillon the way. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Pressure from Opposition parties to protect business failed in the Senate on Monday when the Federal Government passed the Telecommunications Bill after extensive debate over more than 200 amendments. The Bill means business customers will face timed loca calls for all information sent over the telephone network, including Internet access. Page 33.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Sources have revealed settlement talks between Seven Network and its joint partners in cable-TV operation Optus Vision - Optus Communications, US West and Publishing &amp; Broadcasting - are currently in a no-win situation because of an argument over who willpay Seven's A$10 million legal bill. Seven has reportedly asked the other partners to pay the bill as part of the settlement. Page 33.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>AMP Society's London-based group development officer Jonathon Schwartz told the Herald AMP is bitterly disappointed at missing out on its bid for UK life office Scottish Amicable to Britain's Prudential Corp, but is planning to resume talks with four othe British life offices with a view to takeover or merger possibilities. Page 33.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After the Australian Securities Commission tried unsuccessfully last year to force Swiss financial corporation EBC Zurich to reveal the ultimate owner of a strategic parcel of Offset Alpine shares, which was the subject of a takeover bid, the ASC yesterday decided to abandon a case against EBC relating to its holding of shares in Dome Resources and Allegiance Mining. Page 35.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a deal described yesterday by Westfield Trust executive director Steven Lowy as a &quot;coming of age&quot;, Dutch group ABF, one of the world's largest institutional investors, has agreed to take up the majority of a A$250 million capital raising that will help fund Westfield's A$2 billion shopping centre expansion plan. Page 35.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a result blamed largely on a wider prudential margin on compulsory third-party business, insurer Sun Alliance has posted a 25.8 per cent drop in net profit to A$69 million for the year to December, with the general insurance result before tax falling to A$50 million from A$88 million previously. Page 35.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>The AMP Society is expected to continue searching for further acquisitions in Britain and the United States as part of its plans to expand outside its Australian base despite losing its bid for Scottish Amicable, which would have seen AMP become a major player in the British life insurance industry. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Peter Hawkins, a chief general manager at the ANZ Bank, which has closed 100 branches since September and axed more than 2,300 jobs, announced yesterday there is to be a new round of cost savings in ANZ's Australian retail banking operations, which will rsult in more job losses. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Roger Gyles QC, representing the Seven Network, told the New South Wales Supreme Court yesterday that the out-of-court negotiations between Seven and its fellow shareholders in embattled cable-TV group Optus Vision had broken down. The deadline to decide settlement on the issue had been extended from 5pm Monday to 5pm today. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>As Shadow Treasurer Gareth Evans and Democrats Leader Cheryl Kernot hardened their resolve against changes in the banking industry such as mergers, the Wallis report into the financial system will be released to Federal Treasurer Peter Costello in the week commencing April 7, somewhat later than the original March 31 release date. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After receiving authority in February last year to open a branch of Citibank NA to handle a significant portion of corporate banking operations, Citibank's Australian operation has recorded a 19.4 per cent rise in net profit to A$160.1 million on the back of a strong all-round performance. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Holders of Hudson Conway's exchangeable unsecured notes are now entitled to receive one new Crown casino share for every six HudCon notes as part of Crown's A$185 million one-for-six rights issue, after HudCon, which holds a combined 48 per cent stake in rown with Consolidated Press, extended its entitlement. Page B3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
