<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="466165" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta index ends 1.18 pct up on bargain hunting.</title>
<headline>Jakarta index ends 1.18 pct up on bargain hunting.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta share prices closed 1.18 percent higher on Tuesday after a spurt of late bargain-hunting mostly in the cigarette sector, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Jakarta composite index rose 7.67 points, or 1.18 percent, to close at 657.29 points after touching a day's low of 649.62 points.</p>
<p>Gainers led losers by 67 to 51 with 64 issues unchanged. Total volume was 336.27 billion rupiah with about 154 million shares changing hands.  </p>
<p>&quot;Bargain hunting in Sampoerna and Gudang Garam helped boost the index as well as overall sentiment after recent sharp falls,&quot; one broker from a foreign brokerage firm said.</p>
<p>He said most of the buying on tobacco counters Sampoerna and Gudang Garam originated from foreign brokerage houses, which ignited follow-up buying from the locals.</p>
<p>Gudang Garam and Sampoerna had been under strong pressure after reports of a new government regulation on cigarette sales.  </p>
<p>Cigarette makers, under the new scheme, are required to allocate 10 percent of their retail sales profits to distributors.</p>
<p>Gudang Garam ended 400 rupiah up at 10,500 rupiah, while Sampoerna rose 700 rupiah to close at 11,175 rupiah in active trading.</p>
<p>&quot;The falls were somewhat of an over-reaction, but it was understandable. Players prefered to sell their Indonesian blue chips stocks after the biggest blue chip Telkom came under heavy pressure (last week),&quot; another broker said.  </p>
<p>Telkom was under pressure on news reports that the government may end its monopoly over basic telephone services before the scheduled 2006 for domestic inter-city calls and 2011 for local calls, an analyst said.</p>
<p>He said the Tourism, Post and Telecommunications Ministry was expected to hold a press conference involving several senior government officials on Wednesday regarding Telkom's monopoly issue. Officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>The news reports had said the government was likely to allow a firm linked to President Suharto's brother-in-law Sudwikatmono to provide basic telecommunications services.  </p>
<p>Telkom had denied the rumours, but analysts said they were waiting for more details from the senior government officials.</p>
<p>Telkom was the second most actively traded stock. It rose 25 rupiah to 3,575 rupiah.</p>
<p>Plywood firm Daya Sakti Unggul, listed on Tuesday, was the most actively traded at a price of 1,125 rupiah compared with its initial offering price of 950 rupiah.</p>
<p>Brokers ascribed the encouraging debut to news reports that plywood prices in the international market had improved in the past few months. -- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
