<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="466150" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK's Tung to seek views on civil rights dilution.</title>
<headline>HK's Tung to seek views on civil rights dilution.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's future leader Tung Chee-hwa will tap public opinion on China's proposal to water down human rights laws after the British colony reverts to China on July 1.</p>
<p>Tung, who has endorsed China's proposals and seen his popularity slip as a result, has commissioned the survey to be carried out next month, a spokeswoman for Tung's office said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will launch a public consultation next month,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>China says the civil liberties laws breach the Basic Law, Hong Kong's post-1997 constitution, and that they need to be amended after the July 1 handover.</p>
<p>Tung's popularity has suffered a setback since throwing his weight behind Beijing in repealing the laws, opinion polls show.</p>
<p>A recent survey conducted by Hong Kong's Baptist University found only 53 percent of respondents said they were happy with his performance. British Governor Chris Patten polled 62 percent.</p>
<p>The poll also found 52 percent in Hong Kong opposed Beijing's plan, while only 20 percent supported it.</p>
<p>Tung's standing has suffered further in recent days after concerns about a possible conflict of interest mounted following his decision to appoint a prominent property surveyor as head of a committee to map out long-term housing policy.</p>
<p>Tung, chosen by a China-assembled caucus in December, will succeed from Patten in running Hong Kong after more than 150 years of colonial rule ends at midnight on June 30.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
