<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46617" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton says raising retirement age may be needed.</title>
<headline>Clinton says raising retirement age may be needed.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton said raising the retirement age for Social Security benefits would be one way to keep the programme solvent as the population ages, Money magazine reported Wednesday.</p>
<p>In an interview to appear in the October edition, Clinton also said he was open to a downward adjustment of the Consumer Price Index -- the government's official inflation gauge -- that would effectively reduce Social Security benefits paid out to retirees.</p>
<p>&quot;There might be some agreement on whether we could accelerate the (planned) increase in the retirement age a little, or whether it would be raised more for the people who are younger, like me,&quot; the 50-year-old Clinton told Money.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to have to do something,&quot; he said of Social Security reform in an interveiw conducted before the Democratic convention in the last week of August.</p>
<p>The eligibility age for Social Security old age cash benefits is 65 but it is scheduled to go up in gradual steps to 67 over a transition period from the year 2003 to 2027.</p>
<p>Some advocates of reforming Social Security say that to keep the programme solvent the eligibility age may need to go even higher by the time Clinton's generation, the so-called baby boomers, starts to retire 15 years from now.</p>
<p>Others urge an adjustment to the Consumer Price Index, which is used to index Social Security benefits for inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;We made a minor adjustment&quot; in the inflation gauge already this year, Clinton said. &quot;I was prepared to reduce it more this year if we could have gotten the Bureau of Labour Statistics to say that it was out of whack with the (true) cost of living.&quot;</p>
<p>The Bureau of Labour Statistics, part of the Labour Department, issues the inflation gauge monthly.</p>
<p>Many prominent economists, including Federal Reserve Board Chairman Alan Greenspan, charge that the CPI overstates inflation by as much as one percentage point annually.</p>
<p>Greenspan and others contend that if the overstatement could be fixed, it could save the federal government billions of dollars on cost-of-living adjusted programmes such as Social Security and federal pensions. But reforming Social Security is risky politically, and Clinton suggested that any dramatic changes would need the endorsement of a bipartisan commission.</p>
<p>Still another way to boost the pool of money available to retirees would be to allow workers to put some of their Social Security contributions in more risky but higher yielding private investments.</p>
<p>&quot;On privatisation, that's got to be reviewed and recommended by a bipartisan commission,&quot; he said. &quot;I wouldn't feel comfortable supporting (privatization) based on the evidence I have now.&quot;</p>
<p>He came out against raising Social Security payroll taxes. &quot;I do think that (a commission) can't recommend a substantial increase in the payroll tax because the tax is so high already,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
