<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="466383" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TALKING POINT/Pricing pressures dim paper outlook.</title>
<headline>TALKING POINT/Pricing pressures dim paper outlook.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investors battered paper company shares on Tuesday after a major brokerage focused attention on pricing pressures in the industry and lowered its near-term investment ratings on the group.</p>
<p>Before the market opened, Merrill Lynch &amp; Co. paper industry analyst Sherman Chao reduced his near-term ratings on several paper companies, forecasting lower prices for market pulp linerboard and uncoated freesheet in an environment of rising producer inventories.  </p>
<p>Chao also noted that the backdrop of low inflation that the Federal Reserve appears determined to preserve through tighter monetary policy meant that the U.S. economy was unlikely to accelerate and generate more demand.</p>
<p>The Merrill rating actions dovetailed with the views of some other Wall Street analysts who had contended that the industry faced a less buoyant recovery in 1998 than some investors had come to expect.</p>
<p>&quot;Instead of the recovery that people had expected to see going into the second quarter, pricing pressure remains very intense,&quot; said Dean Witter Reynolds analyst Evadna Lynn.  </p>
<p>Lynn said excess capacity was mainly responsible for producers' inability to raise prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Producers have not been disciplined in taking down time so inventories continue to be high,&quot; said Lynn. Under those circumstances, &quot;it's very difficult for producers to raise prices,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Paper stocks were among the weakest performers on the New York Stock Exchange on Tuesday. In afternoon trade, Georgia Pacific was down 2-1/8 to 74-1/4, nearly a three percent drop. Weyerhauser Co. was down 2 to 47, a four percent drop.  </p>
<p>Boise Cascade was off 1-7/8 to 31, a drop of almost six percent. Champion International was down 1-5/8 to 45-3/8, a three-and-a-half percent drop.</p>
<p>International Paper fell 1-5/8 to 41-1/4.</p>
<p>&quot;Pricing levels have reached new lows in the cycle after people thought they had been reached in the second quarter of 1996,&quot; said Lynn.</p>
<p>Lynn said some investors had counted on industry earnings would recover to levels achieved in 1995.</p>
<p>But those hopes have been dashed, she said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The price recovery that occurred from mid-1994 to mid-1995 was unprecedented in the paper industry, but investors remembered that and had expected earnings similar to 1995 by 1998 at the latest,&quot; said Lynn.</p>
<p>&quot;Now it looks as if the average paper company's 1998 earnings will be half of the 1995 levels,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Oppenheimer &amp; Co. analyst Peter Ruschmeier, who has held some of Wall Street's more bearish views of the paper industry, said persistent product oversupply means investors &quot;should not expect prices to recover anytime soon.&quot;  </p>
<p>Ruschmeier said the &quot;handwriting has been on the wall for some time&quot; and expressed some surprise that people &quot;are just now cutting estimates.&quot;</p>
<p>Global supply trends are aggravating the domestic supply issue, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;On a global scale, supply has come on at a faster rate than demand,&quot; said Ruschmeier. &quot;It's that simple. Brief periods of rising prices have not been sustainable.&quot;</p>
<p>Merrill's Chao cut ratings on Weyerhaueser Co, Boise Cascade Corp, Champion International Corp and Union Camp Corp to near-term neutral from near-term accumulate but retained its long-term accumulate rating  on the companies.</p>
<p>Stone Container Corp's near-term rating was cut to a neutral from a near-term accumulate. Its long-term rating was cut to accumulate from buy.</p>
<p>Chao cut Georgia-Pacific Corp to a near-term accumulate from a near-term buy but kept the long-term rating a buy.</p>
<p>Willamette Industries Inc's near-term rating was cut to accumulate from term buy, but the company remains a long-term buy, Merrill said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I46000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
