<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="466430" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed seen beginning new tightening cycle - US experts.</title>
<headline>Fed seen beginning new tightening cycle - US experts.</headline>
<byline>Jose Paulo Vicente</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A hike in the U.S. federal funds rate by the Federal Reserve on Tuesday marks the beginning of a new tightening cycle which is expected to last at least until May, former Fed officials and Wall Street experts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Usually they raise rates a number of times ... Normally when they start raising rates they end up raising them by at least 1.0 percent,&quot; said William Ford, a former President of the Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta.  </p>
<p>Expectations for a series of small incremental increases in the federal funds rate follow the notion that the Fed is perceived to be trying to bring economic growth down to more sustainable levels free of inflation pressures.</p>
<p>The Fed hiked the federal funds rate by 25 basis points to 5.50 percent on Tuesday. It was the central bank's first tightening move since February 1, 1995.</p>
<p>In a statement, the Fed called the rate rise a &quot;prudent step&quot; to extend the economic expansion, adding that it hiked interest rates in light of persisting strong U.S. demand.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Fed statement was a touch more hawkish than what might have been expected ... what that underscores is that as long as the economy stays strong this is not the last monetary policy tightening,&quot; said William Dudley, chief U.S. economist at Goldman, Sachs and Co Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;If you believe that monetary policy should be preemptive and if you believe that the policy tightening is necessary to slow the economy down, then you have to believe there is going to be more than one (tightening),&quot; added Dudley, who correctly predicted the Fed's rate hike on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>The central bank's decision to preemptively increase interest rates on Tuesday was perceived to be based mostly on long-term growth/inflation forecasts, pundits said.</p>
<p>The U.S. six-quarter Gross Domestic Product (GDP) average, for example, has consistently increased over the last 18 months, analysts said.</p>
<p>That average was 2.8 percent by the end of 1996 against a 2.3 percent rate by mid-1996 and a 2.0 percent pace by the end of the second half in 1995.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the jobless rate has been hoverning around the low 5.50 percent level for the past 12 months.  </p>
<p>Analysts said that if those economic conditions were maintained throughout the spring of 1997, further Fed tightening was perceived to be &quot;almost inevitable.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If between now and May 20, the economy performs strongly, housing starts continue to move up, GDP is up and unemployment is dropping ... I would expect the Fed to raise rates another one, two or three times,&quot; former Atlanta Fed chief Ford said.</p>
<p>The Fed will meet next to decide on policy on May 20. After that, the Federal Open Market Committee convenes on July 1 and 2 and then again on August 19.  </p>
<p>&quot;(Fed Chairman Alan) Greenspan has kind of a history of making small moves,&quot; said Steve McNees, a former economist at the Federal Reserve Bank of Boston.</p>
<p>&quot;You would have to argue that there would be more (tightenings) ... maybe two or three 25 basis-point hikes,&quot; McNees added.</p>
<p>Goldman's Dudley said he thinks the Fed is going to bring the federal funds rate back to 6.0 percent &quot;very quickly,&quot; adding that &quot;after that, they're going to think whether that is enough or not.&quot;  </p>
<p>Dudley said the answer to that question will depend on how strong the economy will be. He expects 1997 GDP to stay around 3.3 percent while consumer inflation is seen at 3.1 percent.</p>
<p>One other factor Fed policy makers are expected to consider over the coming months is the performance of the U.S. dollar against U.S. main trading partners' currencies.</p>
<p>Although the greenback has risen substantially since the beginning of the year, some analysts said they do not expect that dollar to appreaciate much further despite Tuesday's interest rate hike.  </p>
<p>&quot;We do not expect the dollar to be very strong over the next 12 months. We think it's going to peak relatively soon and we do expect recoveries in Europe and Japan,&quot; Dudley said.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as those assumptions are realized, we think the tightening is going to be bigger than what people expect,&quot; the Goldman, Sachs chief economist added.</p>
<p>Some analysts, however, took a more cautious approach to the dolar issue. James Glassman, senior economist at Chase Securities Inc, said the recent dollar rise should be a meaningful restraint on the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;So, my suspicion is over time, the dollar is starting to reinforce what the Fed is doing and the Fed will find it didn't have to tighten that much if the dollar remains strong,&quot; said Glassman, who in the past worked as an economist for the Federal Reserve Board.</p>
<p>(( -- 212-859-1676 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
