<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="466535" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Albright ventures into territory of Clinton foe.</title>
<headline>Albright ventures into territory of Clinton foe.</headline>
<byline>Carol Giacomo</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>After spending her first months in office meeting foreign leaders, Secretary of State Madeleine Albright on Tuesday ventured out on a domestic mission equally crucial and maybe even more delicate.</p>
<p>Albright had a day of engagements in North Carolina with Sen. Jesse Helms, Republican chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee and arch-conservative foe of the Clinton administration who is blocking key U.S. foreign initiatives.</p>
<p>The visit by the straight-talking Albright to the home state of the courteous but stubborn 75-year-old Helms was arranged at a time when two international treaties and critical U.N. and other funding hang in the balance.</p>
<p>Helms is largely responsible for preventing Senate ratification of the Chemical Weapons Convention, which faces an important deadline on April 29. If the Senate does not act by then, Washington loses clout and political face because it will not be allowed to help administer the pact.</p>
<p>He has been a major critic of the United Nations, insisting on reforms before the United States pays more than $1 billion in back dues, and has demanded restructuring of the State Department before supporting an administration request for a rise in more generalized foreign affairs funding.</p>
<p>Albright already has a cosy relationship with Helms, who is unabashed about his fondness for America's first female secretary of state. That affection contrasts with his public contempt for Democratic President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>Helms' committee gave Albright early and easy confirmation as the nation's top diplomat, sparing her the kind of grueling partisan treatment that forced Anthony Lake to bow out as Clinton's nominee to head the Central Intelligence Agency.</p>
<p>Although negotiations are under way, the administration has so far not reached a compromise with Senate Republicans to ratify the chemical pact -- which bans the production, stockpiling, sale or use of chemical weapons -- or to settle up its arrears with the United Nations.</p>
<p>Albright, who has declared both of those goals to be priorities, had an opportunity to address them with Helms and his constituents on visits to Charlotte, North Carolina, and nearby Wingate University, which Helms once attended.</p>
<p>&quot;She will raise the chemical weapons convention both in public and private,&quot; a U.S. official said beforehand. Besides discussing issues on which she and Helms disagree, he said, Albright would highlight subjects on which they are in accord, such as supporting tough sanctions against Cuba.</p>
<p>She was also expected to press for Senate ratification of the U.N. Convention on the Elimination of Discrimination Against Women, which Helms opposes.</p>
<p>More than past secretaries of state, Albright so far has made good on her promise to visit U.S., as well as foreign, ports-of-call and make the case for U.S. foreign policy to the American people.</p>
<p>Her first domestic trip was to Houston, where she won a re-affirmaiton of support for the chemical weapons treaty from two Republicans, former President George Bush and former Secretary of State James Baker. She plans trips to Cambridge, Massachussetts, and Alabama.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, she was lunching with community leaders in Charlotte and touring Sea-land Corp., a shipping company.</p>
<p>At Wingate, she was being escorted by Helms to a talk with students and on a tour of the Jesse Helms Centre, underwritten with a $225,000 donation from the government of Taiwan.</p>
<p>She planned a news conference with Helms and dinner with the senator and his family before making a speech at Wingate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
