<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46667" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mexico may make Brady payout if oil prices stay up.</title>
<headline>Mexico may make Brady payout if oil prices stay up.</headline>
<byline>George Lerner</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>If oil prices remain at current lofty levels, Mexico may be required to make supplemental payments to certain Brady bonds, several Wall Street analysts said this week.</p>
<p>Holders of Mexican par bonds and discount bonds may be entitled to payouts through an often overlooked warrant attached to the Brady restructuring accord.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe Mexico may have to make its first warrant payment to holders of par bonds and discount bonds on December 31,&quot; Smith Barney debt analyst James Barrineau said.  </p>
<p>Dan Peirce, chief strategist at Bank of Boston, said that if current oil prices persist through September then the warrants would be in-the-money.</p>
<p>The real question, however, is whether oil prices would remain high enough to drive the warrants in-the-money for the four quarters ending September 30, thereby requiring Mexico to make payments on the warrants on December 31.</p>
<p>Holders of Mexico's defaulted commercial bank debt who exchanged their paper for pars and discounts under the Brady agreement are entitled to oil warrants that provide payments linked to the value of Mexico's oil export revenues.  </p>
<p>A complex formula determines whether holders of Mexico Brady debt will receive payments under the warrants, called Value Recovery Rights (VRRs). The International Monetary Fund calculates the value of the warrants, using factors including the average price of oil exports, Mexico's production levels, a reference oil price adjusted to U.S. inflation, and the amount of eligible debt that was exchanged for par and discount bonds, which was about $47 billion.</p>
<p>An IMF official said he had no comment about whether the rights were in-the-money for the period from July 1, 1995 to June 30, 1996. If so, a payment would be due September 30.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the &quot;strike price,&quot; or reference point of inflation adjusted oil exports, will stand at about $17.25. That means the warrants would be in-the-money if the average oil export price rose above that level for the period covering the fourth quarter of 1995 through the third quarter of 1996, they said.</p>
<p>Barrineau said the payment was contingent on the average price of Mexico's exported oil remaining around the current $20.65 per barrel through the end of September, meaning the country would make a $62 million payment at year end.  </p>
<p>&quot;If Mexico's average oil price for August and September exceeds $18.25, then we're in the money,&quot; Peirce said. He forecast the total payment would amount to about $3.0 million on December 31, or around $100 per million discounts and $65 per million pars.</p>
<p>The initial warrant payment may be negligible, but that total would rise over the warrants' 20-plus year duration.</p>
<p>&quot;The story is the fact that they are going to pay, not what they are going to pay,&quot; Peirce said. &quot;Barring some cataclysmic decline in Mexico's exports and/or oil prices, it will be a decent payment in March.&quot;</p>
<p>Anna Titarchuk, quantitative analyst at ING Barings, said the average price from the third quarter for Mexico's oil should be in the order of $20.50- $21.00, so the warrants would be in-the-money for the December 31 payment.</p>
<p>Titarchuk estimated the December 31 payment would come to $0.03 for every $100 face value, but estimated the VRRs' value at $2.75 for $100 face value over the life of the warrants.</p>
<p>&quot;It's quite attractive for Mexican Bradies,&quot; Titarchuk said. &quot;Until recently Mexican Brady prices haven't reflected the oil warrants attached to them.&quot;</p>
<p>On Wednesday, pars traded 5/8 higher to a bid price of 67-3/8 and discounts rose 7/8 to 83-3/4.</p>
<p>-- 212 859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
