<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="466607" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Bruton says U.S. fed up with IRA violence.</title>
<headline>Bruton says U.S. fed up with IRA violence.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish Prime Minister John Bruton challenged IRA guerrillas on Tuesday to call off attacks in British Northern Ireland, saying they were being isolated on both sides of the Atlantic.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is fair to say that the patience of the U.S. administration is running out with the IRA (Irish Republican Army) and the fact that the IRA have not called a ceasefire,&quot; Bruton, who visited the United States last week, told parliament.</p>
<p>In Northern Ireland business leaders held talks with officials of the guerrillas' Sinn Fein political wing and urged an immediate end to violence which has intensified since December.</p>
<p>Bill Tosh, chairman of the regional section of the Confederation of British Industry, said it was the latest of a series of talks over 2-1/2 years.</p>
<p>The IRA called a truce in September 1994 but ended it in February 1996. It has killed two civilians in bomb attacks on mainland Britain and two soldiers in Northern Ireland since then.</p>
<p>&quot;It is appropriate that we relay directly to Sinn Fein our very grave concerns about the inhibitions that they create and the need to create stability by desisting from bombing, menacing and from issuing threats,&quot; Tosh told BBC radio.</p>
<p>IRA fighters trying to force an end to Britain's rule over Northern Ireland have turned down entreaties by the United States, Britain and Ireland to abandon a 28-year war. They blame Britain for keeping Sinn Fein from peace talks but Bruton said the fault lay with the guerrillas.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein had not been given a place in recently suspended multi-party talks because the IRA continued to wage an armed campaign, the Irish leader said.</p>
<p>Britain, backed by Ireland, says the guerrillas must end hostilities to prove a commitment to democracy.</p>
<p>Sources close to the guerrilla commanders said recently that a ceasefire is unlikely before a May 1 election in Britain. Sinn Fein says it hopes the election will create a new climate to end a three-year political logjam through &quot;inclusive talks&quot;, British concessions and a guerrilla truce.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
