<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="466963" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: THE PROTEUS COLUMN - Germany, Prudential.</title>
<headline>THE PROTEUS COLUMN - Germany, Prudential.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE PROTEUS COLUMN</p>
<p>Analysts, ratings agencies and researchers had already forecast ahead of this year's results season that for most German insurance sectors the era of steady and strong growth in premium income appeared to be over.</p>
<p>The weak economy has reduced consumer demand for insurance, especially for non-life cover. Uncertainty over future income levels is leading people to think very carefully about what insurance they should take out. News about industry growth tends to be dominated by headlines like &quot;Moody's - German insurers face collapse&quot; or &quot;The good years are over for insurers&quot;.</p>
<p>Statistics and forecasts released last week by the GDV industry association support this view. The Association reported that growth in premium income last year slowed to its lowest level since the war. This trend was echoed at the non-life arm of Allianz, Germany's largest insurer, which recently announced a drop in premium income for the first time since 1945.</p>
<p>The fact that insurers had strongly higher profits in 1996, despite falling premium income, was due to favourable claims ratios and cost cutting measures. Insurers cut their workforces by an average 1.3 percent last year, GDV President Bernd Michaels expects the rate of job losses to accelerate over the next few years.</p>
<p>CKAG Colonia for example was able to achieve a healthy increase in profits last year thanks to wide-ranging rationalisation and several years without a major natural catastrophe.</p>
<p>However, the question remains -- What will future results look like for German insurers once cost cutting has been exhausted and we have a year with high claims? Especially if people are still cautious about buying insurance and price competition becomes fiercer, as it has done in motor this year.</p>
<p>Neither the industry association nor management has any illusions about the outlook for 1997. Forecasts are uniformly cautious. The GDV expects no growth in property casualty insurance. Colonia, which relies on property casualty for more than half its premium income, expects its result to just about match last year's, while Allianz's non-life division expects a further fall in premium income.</p>
<p>			  oooo0000oooo</p>
<p>Prudential has finally made its long-trailed move and bought one of the larger British mutual insurers, as it said it planned to do more than a year ago.</p>
<p>While the purchase of Scottish Amicable is a giant stride for chief executive Peter Davis, it is a relatively small step in the long running consolidation of Britain's overcrowded life insurance industry.</p>
<p>As with the recent mega deals by insurance brokers Marsh &amp; McLennan and Aon, the outcome of the tussle for ScotAm answers one question, but raises several others.</p>
<p>Abbey National and AMP put a lot of work into their bids for ScotAm and raised many expectations. Along with several European insurers, such as Aegon and Allianz, they will continue looking for suitable bargains in Britain's life sector.</p>
<p>				--OO0OO--</p>
<p>THE PROTEUS COLUMN is an insight piece produced by Reuters journalists based on their own research and interpretations. While it aims to be as accurate and incisive as possible, it should not be taken to reflect the views of Reuters Ltd.</p>
<p>	   **************************************</p>
<p>THE PROTEUS COLUMN appears in the GLOBAL INSURANCE NEWS SUMMARY</p>
<p>every weekday on Reuters Insurance Briefing.</p>
<p>For enquiries, contact -</p>
<p>Gordon Mackenzie, Editor, London</p>
<p>Tel: 44 171 542 2770</p>
<p>Fax 44 171 542 2583</p>
<p>e-mail gordon.mackenzie@reuters.com</p>
<p>John Sanders, News Editor, London</p>
<p>Tel: 44 171 542 2769</p>
<p>e-mail john.sanders@reuters.com</p>
<p>****************************************</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
