<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="467251" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Juliette Binoche wins Oscar as best supporting actress.</title>
<headline>Juliette Binoche wins Oscar as best supporting actress.</headline>
<byline>Andrea Orr</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Juliette Binoche took the best supporting actress Oscar on Monday for her role as a Second World War nurse in &quot;The English Patient,&quot; but she wasn't acting when she voiced her shock at the upset victory.</p>
<p>Binoche's win stunned oddsmakers and almost everyone in Hollywood, who had cast legendary actress Lauren Bacall as the easy favourite for her role in &quot;The Mirror Has Two Faces.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I'm so surprised it's true. I didn't prepare anything,&quot; the French actress told the audience as she accepted the Oscar. &quot;I thought Lauren was going to get it and I think she deserves it.&quot;</p>
<p>Later, backstage, she said she had been nervous attending the ceremony only because she had to go up on stage to present an award, but had been certain the only Oscar she would go home with was a chocolate one.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not my fault,&quot; she said, offering a sort of apology to Bacall.</p>
<p>For the 72-year-old Bacall, her role as an ageing beauty and mother to plain daughter, played by Barbra Streisand, was regarded as the last chance she might have to win Hollywood's top honour.</p>
<p>&quot;The Mirror Has Two Faces&quot; was the first major performance in years for the sultry Bacall, who made her film debut 53 years ago opposite Humphrey Bogart in &quot;To Have and Have Not.&quot;</p>
<p>Bacall has won Tony Awards for her work on Broadway, Emmy nominations for her television performances, and even a National Book Award for her 1980 autobiography, but before this year had nover been nominated for an Oscar.</p>
<p>Most of her work in recent years has been limited to bit parts in films and the voice of a finicky feline in a cat food commercial.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope she gets an honour(ary) Oscar next year. She deserves it,&quot; Binoche told reporters.</p>
<p>At 32, Binoche has had her share of professional struggles. Born in Paris, she spent years learning English well enough to play in an English-language film. She has played several starring roles in both languages, including in the 1993 French film, &quot;Blue,&quot; as well as in &quot;The Unbearable Lightness of Being&quot; in 1986 and in &quot;Damage&quot; in 1993.</p>
<p>In &quot;The English Patient,&quot; Binoche played a young Canadian nurse during the Second World War who retreats into an Italian monastery to care for a grossly burned patient. With little personal experience to go on, Binoche met with women who had served as nurses during that war to prepare for the role.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
