<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="467302" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish shares rise, FOMC to set Wednesday's agenda.</title>
<headline>Danish shares rise, FOMC to set Wednesday's agenda.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish share prices closed higher on Tuesday buoyed by solid advances by FLS stock in an otherwise quiet, if occasionally volatile market up to FOMC, with dealers seeing more gains possible ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been a rather calm day ahead of FOMC with the FLS Industries share very much in the forefront after a very good 1996 result and potentially very likely to go on up,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The KFX top-20 index closed 0.46 point up at 153.30 while the KFX June future rose 0.80 point to 153.00 with 90 contracts each worth 100,000 crowns traded.</p>
<p>FLS closed 25 crowns higher at 845 after posting 1996 profits 68 percent up on the previous year and forecasting a still better 1997, having risen three percent on the result announcement.</p>
<p>Carlsberg bucked the trend, slipping three crowns to 385, while Sophus Berendsen put on 12 crowns to finish at 824. Dealers saw FOMC determining the opening level of Copenhagen stocks on a quiet Wednesday, the last day of trading before Denmark's five-day Easter break.</p>
<p>Overall turnover for the day was 1.053 billion crowns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
