<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="467614" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAPUA NEW GUINEA: PNG's Chan aloof from fray as MPs debate censure.</title>
<headline>PNG's Chan aloof from fray as MPs debate censure.</headline>
<byline>Michael Perry</byline>
<dateline>PORT MORESBY 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Politicians in Papua New Guinea held a rowdy debate on Tuesday over a parliamentary motion calling for the resignation of Prime Minister Sir Julius Chan for a $36 million mercenary fiasco.</p>
<p>But Chan himself, toughing it out after a week of crisis, stayed deliberately aloof from the fray.</p>
<p>As thousands of protesters gathered peacefully uutside parliament house, Port Moresby governor Bill Skate introduced a motion urging Chan to step aside during an inquiry into the mercenary affair.</p>
<p>Skate told the parliament that the South Pacific nation was divided and had its international credibility in tatters because Chan agreed a contract with British mercenary firm Sandline without consulting cabinet.</p>
<p>&quot;Our nation has been torn apart with division and more and more questions about corruption in high office,&quot; Skate told parliament as MPs from both sides shouted each other down.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the crisis today because of one man's ego -- it is madness, madness.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;Mr Speaker, this is a litany of lies, cover-ups, which have thrown our nation into turmoil. It makes President Nixon's Watergate scandal look like a leaking tap.&quot;</p>
<p>If passed the resolution would be non-binding but would nevertheless increase pressure on Chan to resign. Chan has come under pressure to step down from all sides and saw five ministers quit his cabinet late on Monday.</p>
<p>Officials close to Chan said the prime minister, first elected to parliament in 1968 and serving his second term as prime minister, was confident the vote would go his way.</p>
<p>Chan himself appeared at his urbane best. In a blue-grey suit and crisp blue shirt, he studiously polished his spectacles, rifled through papers on his desk and even spoke on a white telephone while MPs traded insults around him.</p>
<p>One senior member of parliament, Sir Pita Lus, rose to defend Chan against the army-driven challenge to his authority. The PNG crisis began eight days ago when army chief Jerry Singirok demanded that Chan, Deputy Prime Minister Chris Haiveta and Defence Minister Mathias Ijape resign over the plan to send mercenaries to Bougainville.</p>
<p>Speaking in pidgin, Lus said the army did not have the right to interfere in politics.</p>
<p>&quot;If you listen to the military now then it is the start to the country being ruined. We must protect the constitution of this country and we must abide by it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Across town at the Murray Barracks, the army's headquarters, a group of 80 soldiers prepared to become the first defence force members to join directly in the street protests.</p>
<p>A senior officer said the soldiers would be unarmed and spend only 10 to 15 minutes at the parliament. Other protesters would not be able to march with them.</p>
<p>&quot;We are doing this as a show of support for our cause, but we do not want the public to join us,&quot; chief of staff Alfred Renagi told Reuters.</p>
<p>The crisis, the worst in Papua New Guinea's 22 years of independence, began a week ago when army chief Singirok turned against Chan over plans for the mercenaries to lead an assault against a nine-year uprising on Bougainville island.</p>
<p>Chan sacked the general and tried to ride out the storm but Singirok, popular with his troops, has remained in effective control of the army and kept up the pressure on Chan.</p>
<p>Chief Emeka Anyaoku, the Commonwealth secretary-general, arrived in Port Moresby late on Monday on a mediation mission and held separate meetings with both rebel army leaders and government officals.</p>
<p>The eight-day crisis has preoccupied Papua New Guinea's Pacific neighbours.</p>
<p>Australia, PNG's former colonial power, has had troops on standby to help around 10,000 Australian nationals who live in the country if the situation deteriorates and New Zealand has also been drawing up contingency plans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT MORESBY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAPUA NEW GUINEA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
