<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46765" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Cr Foncier unions threaten legal action.</title>
<headline>Cr Foncier unions threaten legal action.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unions at troubled French property lender Credit Foncier warned on Wednesday they would take legal action if the government did not release more details regarding an offer for Foncier by state bank Caisse des Depots et Consignation (CDC).</p>
<p>At a news conference, the six main unions reaffirmed their judgement that the takeover plan was flawed and could be successfully challenged in court and said Credit Foncier should stay in business after turning in a first-half profit.</p>
<p>They said a note explaining the CDC offer left two essential questions open and that they had written to the finance ministry on the matter.</p>
<p>&quot;Is this a matter of holding shares for the state or is this a capitalistic takeover?&quot; the unions' letter said.</p>
<p>If the former, the plan would require a contract between between the government and the CDC, they said. If the latter, the plan would have required advance consultations with the CDC.</p>
<p>The government announced a &quot;managed wind down&quot; of Credit Foncier in July and said it would be initiated with a takeover by CDC on the state's behalf. The proposals foresaw spinning off its commercial activities and low-cost housing loan portfolio to another group called Credit Immobilier.</p>
<p>The rest of the company would be reduced to a shell company and placed in a state holding firm that would ensure billions of francs of bonds issued in its name were honoured.</p>
<p>On September 4, French stock markets authority CBV said CDC's 70 franc per share offer for Credit Foncier was acceptable.</p>
<p>The offer period opened on Monday and requires acceptances covering two-thirds of the shares in the group. The takeover is expected to cost about 2.5 billion francs and the offer closes on October 4.</p>
<p>The unions' threat came on top of earlier warnings by disgruntled shareholders that they too could challenge the takeover.</p>
<p>Credit Foncier ran up huge property loan and investment losses as the bottom fell out of the property market in the early 1990s. It reported losses of 10.8 billion francs for 1995 after provisions for property losses of 13.6 billion francs.</p>
<p>For the first half of 1996 the company posted a profit of 402 million francs compared with a 12 million franc loss in the year-earlier period.</p>
<p>-- William Emanuel, Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5071</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
