<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46807" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German Jewish leader slams Allies for looting gold.</title>
<headline>German Jewish leader slams Allies for looting gold.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leader of Germany's vestigial Jewish community sharply criticised World War Two allies on Wednesday for secretly holding on to vast amounts of gold looted by Nazi Germany.</p>
<p>Ignatz Bubis, the head of the Central Council of Jews in Germany, said the United States, Britain and France had apparently kept gold after World War Two that the Nazis had taken from victims of the Holocaust.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an absolute scandal and a crime if the three Western Allies wanted to divide up what the Nazis stole,&quot; Bubis said in an interview to be published in Thursday's edition of Berlin's Der Tagesspiegel newspaper.</p>
<p>Bubis singled out France for a special rebuke, saying that unlike the United States and Britain, France had failed to make public more details of what it knew about the post-war handling of the fortune.</p>
<p>&quot;The French are the only ones we haven't heard a thing from,&quot; Bubis said.</p>
<p>He also emphatically called upon Switzerland to open its banking records.</p>
<p>Britain's Foreign Office on Tuesday disclosed that Switzerland had only returned a fraction of Nazi gold to the Allies after World War Two.</p>
<p>The Foreign Office said in a report the sum of 250 million Swiss francs paid in 1946 to settle claims connected with Nazi gold was little more than a tenth of the gold thought to be in Swiss bank vaults at the end of the war.</p>
<p>It said the United States, Britain and France accepted the sum of 250 million Swiss francs because they felt they had little alternative.</p>
<p>Bubis told German television in a separate interview that revelations from Britain and the United States, which he said admitted several weeks ago it was willing to return its share of the gold, should have come years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe there was a lot more (gold involved),&quot; Bubis told the ARD network. &quot;We have seen the agreement in the meantime from 1946 and it shows that Switzerland was permitted to keep half for itself and the three western Allies divided up the rest among themselves.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
