<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468150" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan seen in deep trouble without IMF support.</title>
<headline>Pakistan seen in deep trouble without IMF support.</headline>
<byline>Ovais Subhani</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The suspension of an IMF standby loan is likely to deepen Pakistan's economic troubles and only implementation of major reforms is likely to tempt the Fund back, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This crisis is unlike others in the past: the IMF really has lost patience this time,&quot; said a research report of Credit Lyonnais Securities Asia.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Sartaj Aziz, acknowledging on Friday that the standby loan had been halted, said the International Monetary Fund had agreed to start negotiations on a medium-term loan once the government had implemented its economic reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;We doubt that the Fund will return to Pakistan until major domestic reforms are put in place and attempts to solve the budget deficit black hole are made seriously,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Aziz said the government plans bold reforms, including tax and tariff cuts, to revive growth and stimulate exports, which would form the basis of a transition to negotiations for an enhanced structural adjustment loan in the next few months .</p>
<p>However, Credit Lyonnais said the IMF's suspension of the standby loan should be seen as &quot;a clear rebuke of (Prime Minister) Nawaz Sharif's supply side strategy&quot;.</p>
<p>The IMF loan resumed in December after an interim government vowed to cut the budget gap to four percent of gross domestic product in 1996/97 (July-June) from 6.3 percent in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Kaleem Aziz, head of reasearch at ING Baring Securities, said it appeared that IMF inflexibility over the government's inability to meet agreed targets had convinced Islamabad to go its own way rather than pursue the standby facility.</p>
<p>&quot;We think the Fund is being extremely cautious this time around and has stated that full implementation of the structural reforms would form a basis for negotiations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the government's determination to press ahead with its radical supply side measures without IMF help might have its merits, but said they seriously doubted the measures could pull Pakistan out of its economic woes in the short term.</p>
<p>&quot;We doubt whether it (supply side strategy) can succeed, given the severe constraint imposed by (Pakistan's) short-term debt commitments,&quot; Credit Lyonnais said.</p>
<p>Pakistan, with liquid reserves of $1.15 billion, must make payments of about $1 billion in April-June on its $30 billion foreign debt, officials say.</p>
<p>Credit Lyonnais said Pakistan has rolled over some of its debt repayments falling in March but this merely meant shifting the burden to the next quarter and &quot;triggering the next crisis&quot;.</p>
<p>Kalim Aziz said Pakistan would be able to get by until June without IMF assistance. &quot;However, Pakistan will definitely need the Fund's support to pull it through the next financial year.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Pakistan would need $3 billion to tide over a possible funding crisis during July-December 1997.</p>
<p>Credit Lyonnais said withdrawal of the standby could prompt multilateral lending agencies and commercial banks to withhold funds and lead to a decline in foreign capital inflows.</p>
<p>&quot;Moreover any hopes that privatisation issues would be received at anything other than a deep discount will have to be abandoned,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>It said Pakistan would have to choose between staggering from one funding crisis to the next or &quot;take the radical, unpalatable step of open default&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The country needs a breathing space and a major restructuring of its international debt -- the quickest way to effect such a strategy is to default openly,&quot; it declared.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
