<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468182" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bre-X says Busang find possibly overstated.</title>
<headline>Bre-X says Busang find possibly overstated.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bre-X Minerals Ltd said on Wednesday there appears to be a &quot;strong possibility&quot; that the potential gold resources on the Busang project have been overstated due to invalid samples and assays of those samples.</p>
<p>Freeport-McMoRan Copper &amp; Gold Inc said earlier on Wednesday its tests of the Busang II site indicate insignificant gold amounts.</p>
<p>Bre-X said in a statement &quot;there appears to be a strong possibility that the potential gold resources on the Busang project in East Kalimantan, Indonesia have been overstated because of invalid samples and assaying of those samples.&quot;  </p>
<p>Bre-X said its statement was based on advice from Strathcona Mineral Services Ltd, an independent Canadian mining industry consultant.</p>
<p>Bre-X said its board of directors retained Strathcona last week to review, audit and comment on the technical programs carried out to date by Bre-X and the results of those programs on the Busang project and to review the due diligence program being conducted by Freeport-McMoRan.</p>
<p>&quot;Strathcona has recommended to Bre-X that an audit be conducted of the drilling and sampling programs done by both Bre-X and FCX (Freeport),&quot; the statement said.  </p>
<p>&quot;This audit will include the drilling of further core samples and will take approximately four weeks.  Bre-X has accepted Strathcona's recommendation and has advised Strathcona to immediately proceed with this audit program,&quot; Bre-X said. Shares in the Calgary-based gold prospector were halted before the start of trading on the Toronto Stock Exchange. Bre-X's stock has been under pressure since an Indonesian newspaper report last week questioned the size and viability of the Busang gold site. Investors have also been skittish over the mysterious death last week of a co-discoverer of the Busang site.  </p>
<p>Bre-X latest resource estimate for the Busang gold deposit was 71 million ounces of gold, but officials have speculated the site could contain up to 200 million ounces of gold.</p>
<p>Today's announcement came two days after Bre-X issued a statement on Monday saying its board of directors &quot;had &quot;absolute confidence in the integrity and accuracy of assay results and resource calculations.&quot;</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
