<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468111" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU says national troops might escort Albania aid.</title>
<headline>EU says national troops might escort Albania aid.</headline>
<byline>Ian Geoghegan</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union said on Monday that it would not object to individual countries sending troops to Albania to act as military escorts for humanitarian aid convoys.</p>
<p>But for the second time in eight days, the bloc shied away from organising its own multinational force to help restore order in the former communist state.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no need to deploy a major multinational force, but a 'coalition of the willing' exists and, on request from the Albanian government, we could investigate ways and means of operating,&quot; Dutch Foreign Minister Hans van Mierlo told a news conference after a General Affairs Council.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment this coalition looks like the most viable avenue.&quot;</p>
<p>EU foreign ministers in Brussels discussed a report from an exploratory mission to Tirana last week and decided the bloc had a &quot;very substantial&quot; role to play in helping Albania get back on its feet.</p>
<p>As a next step, the EU said it would send a second advisory mission to Albania to advise on humanitarian, economic, political and security-related developments.</p>
<p>Ministers said an advance team, including members from other international groups, would be sent to Albania this week with some 2 million Ecus ($2.3 million) worth of aid and would recommend who should be in the subsequent mission.</p>
<p>The Dutch EU presidency said the EU would combine its planned humanitarian aid with Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) efforts to help the Albanians prepare for free elections in the summer.</p>
<p>French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette told French radio that the EU also planned to appoint an administrator who would be sent to Tirana to help Albania recover.</p>
<p>It is estimated that $10 million in basic medical supplies and 10,000 tonnes of flour are urgently needed. EU Humanitarian Aid Commissioner Emma Bonino said last week aid was ready but that some form of security structure had to be put in place before it could be delivered.</p>
<p>Albania wants foreign police units to help secure ports, airports, roads and railways so that relief supplies can be distributed.</p>
<p>An Italian air force transport plane landed at Tirana airport on Monday with six tonnes of emergency medical aid for the northern part of the country, which is under government control. Italy sent in two tonnes of medical aid for the rebel-held south on the weekend.</p>
<p>French radio said France would send 40 tonnes of humanitarian aid on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Aid shipments are thought to need a protection force to prevent them ending up in the hands of armed bandits.</p>
<p>The EU earlier this month turned down Albanian requests for military intervention to help end disorder sparked by the collapse of savings schemes that bankrupted thousands.</p>
<p>British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind said it was premature to send troops to clear a path for humanitarian aid, given that key aid agencies fear troops could in fact jeopardise the safety of their workers by making them targets for bandits.</p>
<p>&quot;Some help may be useful to those providing aid, but our view is that we need further clarification from the aid agencies,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>But he confirmed that several EU members had prepared contingency plans to send troops and police to Albania if they were required to help aid get through.</p>
<p>Turkey earlier said it was ready to provide troops to any international effort to distribute aid in Albania.</p>
<p>EU foreign ministers were due to gather in Rome on Tuesday, when they will also meet Albanian Prime Minister Bashkim Fino.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
