<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468141" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish Ruch news-stand sale likely in H1 -minister.</title>
<headline>Polish Ruch news-stand sale likely in H1 -minister.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The privatisation of Poland's biggest news-stand chain  Ruch SA is likely to be finished in the first half of this year, the Nowa Europa daily on Tuesday quoted Treasury Minister Miroslaw Pietrewicz as saying.</p>
<p>The paper quoted Pietrewicz as telling trade unions at Ruch that he hoped the Polish-French consortium led by Hachette , which had already won a subsequently cancelled tender for the company, would again place an offer.</p>
<p>&quot;In my opinion the transaction can be concluded still in the first half of the year. We do not discriminate against anyone, all have equal chances, including Hachette,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Pietrewicz cancelled talks with Hachette and reopened the tender for Ruch after a Polish consortium which did not take part in the tender and including trader Universal, TV station Polsat and mineral water producer and newspaper owner Mulitico, said it could pay more than Hachette.</p>
<p>Last week Polish publishers from the Hachette consortium asked the French firm to consider building a separate news-stand network, competing with Ruch.</p>
<p>Last year, the Hachette-led consortium signed a preliminary agreement with the treasury ministry under which it had exclusive rights to carry out final negotiations on the sale.</p>
<p>The ministry is offering 75 percent of Ruch, which has a 65 percent share in the Polish press distribution market and 17,000 kiosks nationwide.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
