<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468160" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Gore meets China Premier, to witness business deals.</title>
<headline>Gore meets China Premier, to witness business deals.</headline>
<byline>Laurence McQuillan</byline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Vice President Al Gore met Chinese Premier Li Peng on Tuesday before witnessing a multi-million dollar deal with China to buy U.S. planes that set the seal on a major warming of battered Sino-U.S. ties.</p>
<p>&quot;Thank you for greeting me, welcoming me here,&quot; Gore said to his Chinese host as the two leaders sat down for talks after a glittering red-carpet welcoming ceremony in the cavernous Great Hall of the People.</p>
<p>The vice president stepped off Air Force Two on Monday to become the highest-ranking U.S. official to visit China since President George Bush in 1989.</p>
<p>In a sign of rapidly improving ties between the world's top superpower and its fastest-growing Pacific neighbour, Gore was to witness two multi-million dollar contracts for U.S. business in China that are to be signed during Tuesday's talks.</p>
<p>Boeing Co will sign a contract to sell five 777-200 jets worth $685 million to China's international carrier, Air China.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Chinese decision to buy the new-generation airliners now was almost certainly based not only on aviation needs but on a thaw in ties since Sino-U.S. relations chilled in 1995 and early 1996 amid disputes over human rights and Taiwan.</p>
<p>After relations soured, China's Li Peng visited France in April, 1996 and finalised the $1.5 billion purchase of 30 Airbus airliners in a sign business could become hostage to a nation's ties with China.</p>
<p>In the Boeing deal, five of the 777-200s are to be delivered to Air China by the end of 1998 and the other two in 1999.</p>
<p>Gore would also witness a formal agreement in which General Motors Corp will enter into a long-delayed joint venture with Shanghai Automotive Industry Corp to build medium-sized cars.</p>
<p>The $1.3 billion motor project, to be based in Shanghai, will be shared equally by the two corporations.</p>
<p>The project received an initial go-ahead in 1995 but final approval has been subject to lengthy delays.</p>
<p>&quot;These agreements... are proof positive that there is greater economic cooperation between the United States and China,&quot; said Ginny Terzano, Gore's press secretary.</p>
<p>She denied reports that Gore, whose trip to China is aimed at improving relations, had been uncertain as to whether he should witness the Boeing contract signing.</p>
<p>&quot;There was never any reluctance,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She was countering reports that Gore hesitated to attend the ceremony because of allegations that China had tried to influence last year's U.S. presidential election by illegally funnelling cash to support President Bill Clinton's campaign.</p>
<p>Under a third agreement to be signed on Tuesday, China will formally allow Washington to maintain a consulate in Hong Kong after 150 years of British rule ends at midnight on June 30.</p>
<p>Gore's meetings with Beijing leaders are aimed at strengthening a recent Sino-U.S. rapprochement, but his talks appeared likely to be darkened by the scandal over alleged Chinese funding of U.S. Democratic Party politicians.</p>
<p>The Washington Post has reported that the Federal Bureau of Investigation warned six members of Congress last year that they had been targeted by China to receive illegal campaign contributions from foreign corporations.</p>
<p>Gore has said he would raise the issue during his official talks in Beijing on a visit intended to pave the way for an exchange of visits by Chinese President Jiang Zemin and U.S. President Bill Clinton in the next two years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
