<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468398" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bears in majority at Gold Institute conference.</title>
<headline>Bears in majority at Gold Institute conference.</headline>
<byline>Clive McKeef</byline>
<dateline>LAGUNA NIGUEL, Calif. 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Views on the direction of gold prices were mixed among analysts at the Gold and Silver Institute's annual conference held this week in California, but on balance the bears appeared to predominate.</p>
<p>&quot;The trend toward more central bank gold sales probably means there's a cap on the market for now,&quot; Goldman Sach's vice president, Richard Hajdukiewicz, said when chairing a panel discussion on the likely future trend of gold prices.</p>
<p>The Belgian and Dutch central banks sold a combined 500 tonnes of gold from their reserves in 1996 and sales by governments and central banks have reduced official gold holdings by about five percent since 1989.</p>
<p>In addition, the IMF last year announced a plan to sell about five million ounces (155 tonnes) of its gold to finance a third world debt relief program.</p>
<p>Official holdings of gold by governments and international institutions are estimated at about 36,000 tonnes of gold, about a quarter of the world's estimated above-ground stocks of 129,000 tonnes at the end of 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;The gold price is driven by the price at the margins and by speculative investment activity, and currently the speculators remain biased to the short side with a number of very big bets still out there on the downside,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think gold could remain in a $370-340 an ounce range for some time, and any spike up will be brief,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Currently gold is trading around $350 an ounce, after a year-long slide to three year lows at $336 in January.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Switzerland also announced a plan to set up a fund to compensate Holocaust victims, financed by selling about 440 tonnes of gold over 10 years.</p>
<p>&quot;The Swiss move is a revolution,&quot; London based UBS analyst, Andy Smith, said. &quot;It's a bit like McDonald's getting out of the hamburger business.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Some people have argued gold sold by European central banks may be bought by Asian central banks which have a low ratio of gold to total foreign currency reserves, but if you net out their debt, the proportion of gold in Asian central bank reserve's is already large,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;And it's not enough to argue that the LBMA (London Bullion Market Association) data suggests the market is deep enough to sustain heavy central bank sales, as the LBMA data is for clearing members and is 'pass-the-parcel' data, not true turnover figures,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier this year the LBMA published data on turnover in the physical London gold market for the first time, which suggested average daily turnover was around 900 tonnes a day, more than many analysts expected.</p>
<p>&quot;Bank of England data suggests turnover is lower than that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result I think the spot gold/silver ratio could ultimately decline to as low as 30,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Currently the gold/silver ratio is around 69, after a decline recently to 22 month lows around 65.</p>
<p>However, Leanne Baker, a San Francisco based analyst in the equity research department of Salomon Brothers, was bullish about the prospect for gold prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The risk is to the upside now, as it's hard to see investors getting any more bearish, with inflation very low in the developed world, and confidence running high in central banks' ability to maintain low inflation,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's true there has been a trend toward more central bank sales, and a rise in gold mine production to over one million ounces a year by big gold mining houses, from around 400,000 ounces a few years ago, but probably about half of all gold miners are facing declining production in the next few years as current high levels of exploration spending are unlikely to be sustained and reserves need replacement.</p>
<p>&quot;The total amount of above ground stocks in the world is small at around 125,000 tonnes - that's less than one ounce per person in the world and rising discretionary income in both the developing and developed world is lifting demand,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's hard to be bearish as many gold mining companies have total costs, as opposed to cash operating costs, higher than the current price of gold around $350 an ounce,&quot; Baker said.</p>
<p>&quot;We think gold prices could rise to $375 an ounce in 1997 and to over $400 in 1998.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- New York Commodities Desk, 1-212-859-1641))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGUNA NIGUEL, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
