<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468462" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Beacon to buy buildings, offer 7 mln shrs.</title>
<headline>Beacon to buy buildings, offer 7 mln shrs.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Beacon Properties Corp said Wednesday it plans to buy eight office buildings totaling over two million square feet for an aggregate price of $339 million.</p>
<p>The company added in a release that it expects to begin a public offering of seven million shares of common stock in early April to help finance the acquisitions.  </p>
<p>Beacon said the eight buildings are located in suburban markets of Chicago, Los Angeles and northern Virginia, all areas previously targeted by the company for portfolio expansion.</p>
<p>Beacon said it expects $153 million of net proceeds from the public offering will be required for the $339 million in acquisitions, with the surplus applied to a reduction in the outstanding balance on the company's revolving credit line.</p>
<p>The remainder of the purchase price will be met by the issuance of $50 million in operating partnership units and the assumption by Beacon of $136 million in fixed-rate debt.</p>
<p>The acquisitions are expected to close during the second quarter of 1997, subject to the completion of due diligence and customary closing conditions, the company said.</p>
<p>The acquisitions will increase Beacon's total portfolio to 112 buildings encompassing 17.8 million square feet, and raise the proportion of the company's suburban office properties to 79 percent, Beacon added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
