<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468471" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Safety 1st restates Q3 due to re-pricing.</title>
<headline>Safety 1st restates Q3 due to re-pricing.</headline>
<dateline>CHESTNUT HILL, Mass. 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Safety 1st Inc said Wednesday it had restated its financial results for the 1996 third quarter to a net loss of $0.2 million, or $0.03 per share.</p>
<p>Originally it reported net income of $0.6 million, or $0.08 per share.</p>
<p>The company said the figures were restated as a result of the repricing of certain non-employee stock options during the quarter.  </p>
<p>The company said that during the 1996 second quarter it began a review of its product mix and took the first steps to refocus its business on its traditional, core product lines.</p>
<p>It said that in the fourth quarter it took additional steps to &quot;dramatically reduce the number of its product offerings by eliminating 350 juvenile and hardware products.&quot;</p>
<p>It said it had reduced planned sales of products introduced this year to about $20 million, concentrating on those products in the areas of its core development expertise. Sales of new products totaled $34 million in 1995 and $33 million in 1996, it said.  </p>
<p>As a result of these and other measures, Safety 1st said it expects to reduce its base level of operating expenses to about 30 percent of revenues in 1997.</p>
<p>Safety 1st reported a net loss of $38.1 million, or $5.33 per share, for the fourth quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>The company said it recorded a $32.7 million pretax charge in the fourth quarter associated with a redefining of its business strategy, particularly the previously announced realignment of the Safety 1st product mix, including a $10.2 million charge in connection with SFAS 121.</p>
<p>Excluding the pretax charges, the company would have recorded a fourth quarter pretax loss of $10.1 million, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHESTNUT HILL, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
