<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468541" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-COURIER REACHES EUROPEAN-DOMINATED QUARTERS AT LIPTON.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-COURIER REACHES EUROPEAN-DOMINATED QUARTERS AT LIPTON.</headline>
<dateline>KEY BISCAYNE, Florida 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former world number one Jim Courier Tuesday joined current number one Pete Sampras in the Lipton Championships quarter-final round, which took on a decidedly European flavor, save for the two American stars.</p>
<p>The top-seeded Sampras rolled on with a 56-minute, 6-2 6-0 annihilation of Magnus Larsson, giving the Swede plenty of time to go out and celebrate his 27th birthday.</p>
<p>&quot;I really played unbelievable tennis for the most part,&quot; said a very satisfied Sampras. &quot;I served well, got off to a good start. It was a smooth day, a real good day.&quot;</p>
<p>In the night match, local favourite Courier ousted fifth-seeded Wimbledon champion Richard Krajicek of the Netherlands 7-6 (8-6) 6-4.</p>
<p>&quot;Any time you get by a guy who's got a Grand Slam title under his belt, that's a great day at the office,&quot; said Courier.</p>
<p>The other six quarter-final slots up for grabs on Tuesday went to Europeans, including fourth-seeded Croatian Goran Ivanisevic, who advanced with a 6-4 6-4 victory over promising Slovakian Dominik Hrbaty.</p>
<p>Ivanisevic, a two-time Wimbledon runner-up and a finalist here last year, meets the resurgent Courier in the round of eight.</p>
<p>Australian Open champion Sampras, in the hunt for his fourth title of the year, next meets German Hendrik Dreekman, who ousted Sweden's Mikael Tillstrom 6-3 6-4.</p>
<p>Nicklas Kulti, another of the four Swedes to reach the fourth round, got no further after being stopped by Ukraine's Andrei Medvedev 4-6 6-3 7-5.</p>
<p>But Jonas Bjorkman kept Swedish hopes alive by fending off missile-serving Australian Mark Philippoussis 6-3 6-4.</p>
<p>Bjorkman next faces second-seeded Austrian Thomas Muster, who swiftly downed Spain's Alex Corretja 6-4 6-4.</p>
<p>Former two-time French Open winner Sergi Bruguera of Spain, who upset third seed Michael Chang in the third round, will face Medvedev in the quarter-finals. Bruguera beat Argentine qualifier Gaston Etlis 7-6 (7-0) 6-4 to take his place in the final eight.</p>
<p>The 26th-ranked Courier, who has a home nearby and the crowd in his back pocket, Tuesday showed some of the form that brought him the top ranking and four Grand Slam titles earlier in the decade.</p>
<p>Courier mixed a strong baseline attack with the occasional serve and volley to keep fifth seed Krajicek at bay.</p>
<p>The Dutchman, playing only his fourth tournament since knee surgery in December, was erratic on the forehand side and Courier took advantage of the mistakes.</p>
<p>The American failed on two chances to break Krajicek in the eighth game of the first set, but succeeded in the tight 8-6 tiebreaker, capitalising on a forehand error by the Wimbledon champion.</p>
<p>The second set was as hard fought as the first, with Courier gaining the first break for a 2-1 lead.</p>
<p>Courier survived break points in the next game with two service winners and an ace, then held onto the lead, dropping just two more points on serve to reach 5-4.</p>
<p>The local favourite completed his victory in the next game with a forehand winner down the line.</p>
<p>&quot;It was very satisfying to beat a top player,&quot; Courier said. &quot;It's a little pat on the back that all the work you've been doing is not for nothing.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KEY BISCAYNE, Florida"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
