<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468726" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE gasoline steady at the lower levels.</title>
<headline>NWE gasoline steady at the lower levels.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>NWE gasoline prices were holding steady at the lower levels supported by firmer crude and NYMEX unleaded futures in late trade on Wednesday, traders said .</p>
<p>The market weakened in early business after the American Petroleum Institute reported an unexpected 1.1 million barrel build in U.S gasoline inventories, but trade was thin with early selling finding few buyers.</p>
<p>Eurograde barges traded down at $208 a tonne for ARA, some $2-3 under Tuesday's late levels after being offered aggressively lower by one Rotterdam refiner in early business.</p>
<p>April swaps valued around $209.50 with the April/May spread trading a couple of times at 25 cents in backwardation.</p>
<p>The slack demand from the U.S. kept cargo trade subdued although light buying was seen for Eurograde into The U.K. and Germany at around $209-$211 a tonne, offers were $2 higher.</p>
<p>&quot;The (NWE) market's been quieter this week with most players squared ahead of the holiday, but prices could take a tumble early next week if fundamentals don't improve,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Tuesday's API figures also showed U.S. refinery usage rose 2.3 percentage points to 92.7 percent of capacity, supported by a surprise crude draw of 2.2 million barrels.</p>
<p>Many traders had expected the usage rate would edge up only half a percentage point as Gulf Coast refineries continued to come back from maintenance turnarounds.</p>
<p>The only bullish reports continued to come from the Mediterranean market where traders said they expect supplies to tighten further, they said refiners were mostly covered against term contracts but they expected warmer weather to create extra demand from drivers in addition to an anticipated increase in demand over the Easter holiday weekend.</p>
<p>-- Colin Wooster, London Newsroom, +44 171 542 7456</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
