<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468700" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - April 2.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - April 2.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the major events to have occurred on April 2 in history:</p>
<p>742 - Charlemagne, king of the Franks, born. King from 768, with his brother, he conquered most of Europe and was crowned Emperor in 800. His court became one of the most brilliant.</p>
<p>1792 - The Coinage Act passed by Congress and signed by George Washington established a mint and regulated the coins of the United States.</p>
<p>1801 - In the Napoleonic Wars, the Danish fleet was destroyed by the British under Admiral Nelson at the Battle of Copenhagen. Ordered to withdraw during the battle, Nelson put a telescope to his blind eye and said he could see no such order.</p>
<p>1805 - Hans Christian Andersen, Danish author, born. Famed for his childrens stories including, &quot;The Emperor's New Clothes&quot; and &quot;The Ugly Duckling&quot;.</p>
<p>1838 - Leon-Michel Gambetta, French statesman, born. One of the founders of the French Third Republic, he was also prime minister from 1881. As a delegate of the government during the Franco-Prussian war, he had to escape Paris which he did by balloon in October 1870.</p>
<p>1840 - Emile Zola, French writer, born. Founder of the Naturalist movement in literature, used notably in his novels &quot;Therese Raquin&quot; and &quot;Germinal&quot;. He was also author of the paper &quot;J'Accuse&quot; in defence of Alfred Dreyfus.</p>
<p>1860 - The first Italian Parliament met at Turin.</p>
<p>1891 - Max Ernst, German sculptor and painter and founder of the Dada movement, born. He was also involved in the Surrealist movement and invented the technique of frottage (pencil rubbings on canvas).</p>
<p>1905 - The Simplon rail tunnel under the Alps linking Switzerland with Italy officially opened.</p>
<p>1914 - Alec Guinness, British actor of stage and screen, born. Best known for his roles in &quot;Kind Hearts and Coronets&quot; and &quot;Bridge over River Kwai&quot;, for which he won an Oscar, and &quot;The Ladykillers&quot;.</p>
<p>1944 - It was announced in Moscow that Russian troops had crossed the River Pruth and entered Romania.</p>
<p>1947 - The U.N. Security Council voted to appoint the U.S. as trustee for former Japanese-held Pacific Islands.</p>
<p>1951 - General Dwight Eisenhower assumed command of all allied armies in Western Mediterranean area and Europe.</p>
<p>1960 - France signed an agreement with Madagascar which proclaimed the country an independent state within the French community.</p>
<p>1960 - France and the Soviet Union signed a protocol and agreement on scientific and technical co-operation.</p>
<p>1966 - Cecil Scott Forester, author of the Captain Hornblower novels, died. He also wrote &quot;The African Queen&quot;, which was made into a successful film.</p>
<p>1966 - South Vietnamese troops joined in demonstrations at Hue and Da Nang for an end to military rule.</p>
<p>1974 - Georges Pompidou, French statesman, prime minister and President from 1969, died in office.</p>
<p>1982 - Argentina invaded the Falkland Islands and overthrew the British administration. The protectorate had been held by Britain since 1832.</p>
<p>1992 - Mafia boss John Gotti, nicknamed &quot;Teflon Don&quot; after earlier attempts to try him, was convicted of murder and racketeering.</p>
<p>1996 - Russia and Belarus signed a treaty that created a tight-knit political and economic alliance within the Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS).</p>
<p>1996 - Lech Walesa, the former Solidarity union leader who became Poland's first post-war democratic president, resumed his old job as a $250-a-month electrician at the Gdansk shipyard.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
