<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468784" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Wal-Mart Canada starts union bargaining.</title>
<headline>Wal-Mart Canada starts union bargaining.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Canadian unit of Wal-Mart Stores Inc said on Wednesday it began bargaining with union members at the first-ever unionized store for the world's largest retailer.</p>
<p>Wal-Mart Canada Inc and the United Steelworkers of America began negotiations for a contract at its Windsor, Ontario, outlet on March 17 and plan to continue on April 29, 30 and May 12, 13.</p>
<p>Wal-Mart Canada, which quickly became Canada's largest discount chain since arriving in 1994, is wholly owned by the Bentonville, Ark.-based retailer. Windsor is on the Canada-U.S. border near Detroit.</p>
<p>Spokesman Ed Gould declined to disclose any of the issues on the table. &quot;We're continuing to bargain in good faith at the table to get a collective agreement, and that is where we're going to do the negotiations.&quot;</p>
<p>Wal-Mart Canada also reiterated it will appeal a mid-February decision by the Ontario Labor Relations Board to certify the union.</p>
<p>Gould said the retailers will file a notice of application at a division of Ontario's court.</p>
<p>&quot;We've said from the start that we felt that Wal-Mart acted fairly and that the decision did not reflect the true wishes of our people and our appeal will be based on those two levels,&quot; Gould said.</p>
<p>Wal-Mart Canada said the appeal will be heard by a panel of Ontario's Divisional Court within three to six months.</p>
<p>The ruling came despite a May 10, 1996 vote by Windsor store employees rejecting a union drive by 151-43.</p>
<p>The tribunal, which administers labor laws in Canada's most populous province, ruled Wal-Mart executives used unfair labor practices by refusing to tell employees whether they would shut the store if it became unionized.</p>
<p>((lydia.zajc@reuters.com, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8109))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
