<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468708" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Coffee, cocoa perk up in softs rise.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Coffee, cocoa perk up in softs rise.</headline>
<byline>Paul Carrel</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Soft commodities stole the limelight on Wednesday, coffee setting the pace with a near four percent gain and cocoa following up in its slip-stream.</p>
<p>The rise in the world coffee prices came after a bout of profit-taking earlier in the week as investment funds sought to cash in on a 50 percent increase in coffee futures prices since early 1997, caused by a shortage of premium arabica beans.</p>
<p>Benchmark robusta May coffee futures ended up $60 at $1,627 as investors looked at fundamentals as evidence that this year's staggering rally might still have some way to go.</p>
<p>Despite the recent fall, &quot;many analysts are not convinced that the party is over&quot;, German statistician F.O. Licht said in comments published recently.</p>
<p>&quot;They expect that the market will reassert itself as supplies could become extremely limited once again, possibly even tighter than they were recently,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Expectations of a much lower 1997/98 Brazilian crop and supply disruptions in Colombia due to strikes have compounded market worries about low consumer stocks.</p>
<p>After the markets closed, the Assocation of Coffee Producing Countries said it had lowered its estimate for the Central American 1996/97 crop by 400,000 bags to 15.4 million bags.</p>
<p>Cocoa put in a sparking performance in morning trade as investors marched up to the technically key 1,035 sterling level but the price later fell on news that forecast rain in the Ivory Coast looked less likely.</p>
<p>Cocoa May futures closed up 14 at 1,030 sterling.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, gold prices lost their shine as the market felt the impact of a 25 percent basis point rise in U.S. interest rates on Tuesday, the first rise in over two years.</p>
<p>Bullion tested techincal support levels at $346 before fixing at $346.05 an ounce in the afternoon and then later progressing back up towards $350.</p>
<p>Silver and palladium were both lifted from recent down spells to close in Europe at $5.14 and $147.25 respectively. Platinum edged back to $372.50 after fixing at $372 in the morning, its lowest level since February 21.</p>
<p>Aluminium received little support from news that workers at Russia's Bratsk smelter would protest on March 27 and ended $21 lower at $1,632.</p>
<p>News that a wage agreement had been struck at Poland's KGHM copper concern abated fears that the company's workers would begin strike action.</p>
<p>Copper made some gains in the morning but fell away in the afternoon to close at $2,352, down $25.</p>
<p>Ongoing fears about dryness in western sections of the HRW wheat belt sent wheat prices higher on the Chicago Board of Trade.</p>
<p>Wheat May futures rose 6-1/2 cents to $3.96 a bushel by 1830 GMT.</p>
<p>Some key prices at 1815 GMT on Wednesday</p>
<p>					     Wednesday   Tuesday</p>
<p>Ldn Spot Gold($ per ounce)		349.45     349.15</p>
<p>IPE Brent Crude Oil (May)		  19.72	19.65</p>
<p>Ldn Metal Exchange(3 mths delivery)</p>
<p>Copper ($ per tonne)		    2,352.00   2,377.00</p>
<p>Aluminium ($ per tonne)		 1,632.00   1,653.00</p>
<p>LIFFE Robusta Coffee ($/tonne) May) 1,627.00   1,567.00</p>
<p>Cocoa (Stg per tonne) (May)	   1,029.00   1,016.00</p>
<p>White Sugar ($ p/t May)		   306.00     306.10</p>
<p>Chicago Board of Trade Wheat</p>
<p>(Cents per bushel)(May)			396	  390</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
