<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468832" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa sells 30 percent of Telkom for $1.261 bln.</title>
<headline>S.Africa sells 30 percent of Telkom for $1.261 bln.</headline>
<byline>Ben Hirschler</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The South African government on Wednesday signed a landmark deal with a consortium of SBC Communications Inc and Telekom Malaysia Bhd, to sell a 30 percent stake in Telkom for $1.261 billion.</p>
<p>SBC and Telekom Malaysia have formed a new partnership called Thintana Communications in which the U.S. concern has 60 percent and the Malaysians have 40 percent.</p>
<p>The deal, the first major sell-off of state assets in South Africa and the largest direct investment to date, values the state-run telecommunications concern at around $4.2 billion, making it the biggest privatisation in Sub-Saharan Africa.</p>
<p>Posts, Telecommunications and Broadcasting Minister Jay Naidoo said the price received, translating to 5.58 billion rand, was within the government's expected range of five to six billion rand. The rand return was slightly less than expected at one stage, reflecting the recent strength of the currency.</p>
<p>Telkom's strategic equity partners will make a one-off payment in dollars at the close of the deal, which could be one week to 90 days from the signing, officials said.    Of the</p>
<p>proceeds, $1 billion will be injected into Telkom to help fund the company's infrastructure expansion programme and the balance will go to the state.</p>
<p>Naidoo said Telkom's partial privatisation would provide badly-needed capital, expertise and technology to enable it to overcome the legacy of the apartheid era which has left millions of mainly black South Africans without access to a telephone.</p>
<p>Telkom and its strategic equity partners -- who will enjoy a five-year exclusivity period in fixed line telephony -- have committed themselves to one of the fastest roll-out programmes in the world, promising to deliver 2.8 million new lines including 120,000 payphones over the next five years.</p>
<p>The company will also upgrade 1.25 million existing analogue lines with digital switch technology.</p>
<p>Telkom is committed to a $12 billion or 53 billion rand capital expenditure programme over a five-year period, almost doubling the current programme.</p>
<p>Announcing the long-awaited deal, Naidoo said the U.S-Malaysian bid -- the only one to make it to the final selection stage -- had exceeded the government's three key evaluation criteria of high roll-out, training and price.</p>
<p>The consortium has agreed to support a training budget of 2.315 billion rand over five years, 1.38 billion more than Telkom's current plan.</p>
<p>&quot;The restructuring of Telkom will provide universal access to telephony services and an information backbone for macroeconomic development,&quot; Naidoo said.</p>
<p>&quot;Telkom will at the same time be transformed into a world-class operator providing new and improved quality services with a trained and representative workforce.&quot;</p>
<p>The SBC-Telekom Malaysia consortium will have five of 15 board positions following the privatisation deal and 75 expatriate staff will take a hands-on role in managing the company during the five-year exclusivity period, Naidoo said.</p>
<p>Jim Myers, SBC regional officer, said his company believed strongly in the South African government's goals for extending services to its people.</p>
<p>&quot;We look forward to being an integral part of that process,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
