<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468914" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELARUS: Belarus leader vows to watch farms with eagle eye.</title>
<headline>Belarus leader vows to watch farms with eagle eye.</headline>
<byline>Larisa Sayenko</byline>
<dateline>MINSK 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Alexander Lukashenko on Wednesday vowed to ensure the spring grain sowing in Belarus goes to plan by making surprise flights over farms in his personal helicopter.</p>
<p>Lukashenko, a former state farm boss, made the promise in a three-hour programme broadcast live on television and radio, in which he discussed prospects for this year's grains crop with agricultural officials and regional leaders.</p>
<p>He said he would make good use of a present from Russian President Boris Yeltsin -- a helicopter -- to make sure the sowing of 2.70-2.75 million hectares with grains went smoothly.</p>
<p>&quot;The helicopter Yeltsin gave me will hover over the fields every day and I will land without warning to check how the sowing is going,&quot; Lukashenko said.</p>
<p>The sowing campaign, which usually starts in April, would last two weeks by order of the president, Agriculture Minister Vasily Leonov said, without giving details on the start date.</p>
<p>Belarus has targeted a grain harvest of 6.5 million tonnes, up from 5.8 million tonnes in 1996. Annual domestic demand is estimated at six million tonnes.</p>
<p>Leonov said the grain growing area would be increased by five percent and that Belarus needed 25 percent more feedgrains, 50 percent more fodder and 40 percent more fertiliser.</p>
<p>Sowing began in two southern regions during a thaw this month, and a senior ministry official said earlier.</p>
<p>Lukashenko, backed by much of the population who share the nostalgia he expresses for the Soviet past and his policy of rebuilding ties with Moscow, keeps a tight rein on industry and his opponents.</p>
<p>Last year he banned political protests during the harvest.</p>
<p>Farmers in Belarus, a largely agricultural nation of Slavs bordering Russia, Ukraine, Poland, Lithuania and Latvia, have an ally in the former farm boss but also a constant critic.</p>
<p>On Wednesday the 42-year-old president tongue-lashed Minsk region's governor, Pyotr Piotukh, accusing him of trying to deceive him by hastily cleaning up farms and livestock before a presidential visit.</p>
<p>&quot;Tell me how you tried to pull the wool over the president's eyes and washed cows with shampoo when I was planning to visit two districts of our region,&quot; Lukashenko said.</p>
<p>During the three-hour broadcast he frequently interrupted officials in the studio and those speaking through a special intercom system from their offices across the country.</p>
<p>But he vowed to lift some of the duties on 135,000 tonnes of nitrous fertiliser Leonov said were needed from Russia and Ukraine, saying: &quot;We will free them from part of the duties to support importers and producers of agricultural production.&quot;</p>
<p>Lukashenko has a history of making surprising statements about agriculture in Belarus.</p>
<p>On April 25 last year, the eve of the 10th anniversary of the Chernobyl nuclear disaster, he shocked liberals by declaring that people evacuated from areas contaminated by the blast would one day be able to return and produce radiation-free food.</p>
<p>&quot;We will return to our villages. I am certain of this. Through a series of agricultural, chemical and technical processes, we will be able to produce ecologically pure food on this land,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Belarus, downwind from the disaster, was worst affected by radioactivity from Chernobyl's ruined fourth reactor, receiving 70 percent of the total fallout.</p>
<p>Experts have said the territory should not be used, especially not for growing food, for an extended period of time.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINSK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELARUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
