<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46893" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India, recalling Gandhi, resists nuclear test pact.</title>
<headline>India, recalling Gandhi, resists nuclear test pact.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>India dug in its heels against a global nuclear test ban treaty on Wednesday, saying it would hold fast against the accord just as the nation's spiritual founder Mahatma Gandhi had stood up to British rule.</p>
<p>&quot;We shall not sign the treaty,&quot; Foreign Minister Inder Kumar Gujral told the upper house of parliament, where lawmakers expressed their approval with the loud thumping of desks.</p>
<p>India blocked adoption of the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT) by disarmament negotiators in Geneva last month.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, it was one of only three United Nations member states which voted against the accord banning nuclear explosions in the atmosphere, underground or in any other environment.</p>
<p>By a 158 to three vote, the U.N. General Assembly called for the accord to be open for signature by individual nations.</p>
<p>India has insisted the treaty commit the five declared nuclear powers -- Britain, China, France, Russia and the United States -- to a timetable for dismantling their arsenals.</p>
<p>But New Delhi has been especially piqued by a provision that would require it, along with 43 other countries, to ratify the accord before the pact could take effect.</p>
<p>India first raised its threat to veto the treaty when the entry-into-force provision was introduced in late June, and Gujral has said New Delhi would be willing to reconsider its stance if the measure was scrapped.</p>
<p>Backed by political parties and public opinion, the three-month old government seemed at ease in its lonesome stance.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been no pressure on India to sign the treaty but if there is any, this country has the national will to withstand pressure,&quot; United News of India quoted Gujral as saying.</p>
<p>The foreign minister, who has repeatedly called the CTBT a &quot;charade&quot;, said India had a longstanding history of withstanding pressure and had stood up to the British for its freedom.</p>
<p>&quot;We shall sustain the glorious path laid by Gandhi and Nehru,&quot; he said, referring to Mahatma Gandhi and the nation's first prime minister, Jawaharlal Nehru, who led the struggle against British colonial rule which came to an end in 1947.</p>
<p>India detonated a nuclear device in 1974 but says it has never built the bomb and has no plans to do so. Its strategic doctrine has been to keep the option to build nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot be at the mercy of the United States,&quot; said Jaswant Singh, deputy leader of the opposition Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) in parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;It is all the more necessary looking at the way our neighbouring country, Pakistan, is arming itself and is engaged in developing its nuclear capability.&quot;</p>
<p>Western diplomats took solace in the fact India did not try to block endorsement of the treaty in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;India saw fit to express its own position but not try to put any procedural roadblocks in the way,&quot; an envoy said.</p>
<p>Analysts predicted pressure would now grow on India to test and build a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p>In a recent poll by the Centre for the Study of Developing Societies published in India Today magazine, 36 percent of the respondents said India should build the atomic bomb while 26 percent were opposed. The rest had no opinion.</p>
<p>&quot;With Pakistan having been nuclear and China having been so for many years, India must go nuclear to defend its sovereignty,&quot; BJP national secretary Tapan Sikdar said.</p>
<p>Analysts scoffed at U.S. President Bill Clinton's remark that &quot;I believe we can find a way for the Indians to have their security concerns met&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Clinton cannot provide security to my country,&quot; said Brigadier Vijai Nair, executive director of the Forum for Strategic and Security Studies. &quot;Is this a new form of imperialism coming?&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
