<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46897" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Chidambaram defends minimum alternate tax.</title>
<headline>India's Chidambaram defends minimum alternate tax.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Finance Minister P. Chidambaram told parliament's lower house on Wednesday that the minimum alternate tax (MAT), a corporate tax he proposed in his budget for 1996/97 (April-March), was &quot;a justified levy.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;MAT is a justified levy,&quot; he said. &quot;It will not be more than 12.9 percent,&quot; he said while introducing for voting the fianace bill which would give effect to his budget proposals.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't propose to raise the tax,&quot; Chidambaram said of the tax which the government wants to impose on firms that earlier avoided tax payment by making use of a law that enabled tax exemptions on profits if they were ploughed back as investment.</p>
<p>But he announced that the tax will not be applicable to companies declared &quot;sick&quot; -- a reference in India to firms whose accummulated losses are more than their net worth.</p>
<p>The tax would also not apply to incomes from factories located in areas notified as &quot;backward,&quot; Chidambaram said.  </p>
<p>Chidambaram said the profits of industries located in districts or states declared as &quot;backward&quot; would be eligible for exemption from the tax during the period for which they can under the existing law claim overall income tax exemption.</p>
<p>&quot;Sick companies&quot; would enjoy the exemption as long as they fall within the official definition of a sick company, he said.</p>
<p>He proposed no other changes regarding the tax, which has adversely affected stock market sentiments since it was proposed in July.</p>
<p>--New Delhi newsroom, +91-11-3012024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
