<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="468966" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares rise, seen up on Thursday.</title>
<headline>Polish shares rise, seen up on Thursday.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares rebounded after Tuesday's dip and analysts said more rises were likely on Thursday, in part because Tuesday's Funds rate rise the United States had already been discounted by the market.</p>
<p>&quot;(U.S. Fed Chairman Alan) Greenspan did what he did and it (the rate rise) was already priced in,&quot; said Bogdan Kornacki, a trader at Wielkopolski Bank Kredytowy (WBK) brokerage.</p>
<p>Analysts said the market had put its recent deeper downward correction behind it and that some large-cap firms such as Elektrim might lead moderate market growth after recent falls.  </p>
<p>Elektrim rose 3.8 percent on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Blue chips that have become relatively cheap should gather in the portfolios of those with mid-term investment horizons,&quot; said Roman Sosnowski, an analyst at Bank Staropolski brokerage.</p>
<p>The main market's all-share WIG index rose 1.2 percent to 16,354.8 points and turnover rose 23 percent to 227.4 million zlotys on all three markets.</p>
<p>Four small-cap stocks rose between 8.7 and 9.9 percent on Wednesday, including debt-ridden Espebepe, which continued this week's speculative surge after last week's drop. The firm's creditors meet on April 14 to discuss a debt deal.  </p>
<p>Kable and Prochem were both up 9.9 percent, Mostostal Zabrze 8.7 percent, extending gains after news of a likely contract with Adam Opel AG.</p>
<p>Polifarb Cieszyn surged 9.5 percent and Polifarb Wroclaw fell 7.9 percent after the firms' shareholders agreed on a merger earlier this week, with Cieszyn shareholders approving a plan giving them 53.5 percent</p>
<p>Wroclaw officials have said a mutual shareholder, BIG, might dispute Cieszyn's version in court but that the merger was still likely to go through as a delay would cost both firms. -- Steven Silber +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
