<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="469096" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentina insists Galtieri cannot be tried in Spain.</title>
<headline>Argentina insists Galtieri cannot be tried in Spain.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Brown</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Argentine government on Wednesday rejected Spain's arrest warrant for former military President Leopoldo Galtieri but emphasised it was for legal reasons and not because it condoned his brutal regime.</p>
<p>A Spanish judge investigating the disappearance of 300 Spaniards in the Argentine military's &quot;Dirty War&quot; on leftists in the late 1970s issued an international arrest warrant for Galtieri for allegedly ordering the killing of three men.</p>
<p>Argentine human rights groups reacted with joy to the news on Tuesday, but the government says it cannot extradite anyone for crimes that they have already been tried for at home.</p>
<p>&quot;I share most people's opinion of Galtieri but the essence of the West, something that sets us apart from other cultures, is that we offer the protection of the law even to people we repudiate,&quot; Deputy Foreign Minister Andres Cisneros said.</p>
<p>&quot;Argentine courts have already made it clear a foreign judge cannot pass judgment on someone for crimes for which they have already been tried in this country,&quot; Interior Minister Carlos Corach agreed in a local radio interview.</p>
<p>Galtieri, 70, led the Argentine military junta from 1980 to 1982 and ordered the invasion of the Falkland Islands that led to a disastrous 10-week war with Britain.</p>
<p>Like all the leaders of the 1976-83 regime, which rights groups accuse of abducting and killing as many as 30,000 people, he was tried after democracy was restored in 1983 but was pardoned by President Carlos Menem in 1989.</p>
<p>Rights groups such as the Mothers of Plaza de Mayo, other relatives of &quot;disappeared&quot; people and Nobel Peace Prize winner Adolfo Perez Esquivel hailed Spanish High Court Judge Baltasar Garzon for helping their &quot;fight against impunity.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We think it's fantastic that the world is starting to prosecute these killers,&quot; Mothers' leader Hebe de Bonafini said.</p>
<p>&quot;This Deserves a Toast,&quot; declared the front page of the leftist daily Pagina 12, with a photo of a dejected Galtieri.</p>
<p>But as with other &quot;Dirty War&quot; criminals sought by foreign courts, Argentina is unlikely to let Spain try Galtieri for his alleged role in the abduction, torture and killings of Spaniard Victor Labrador and his two sons in 1976.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not really about Galtieri's rights but about the right of Argentine society to regulate itself and try crimes committed here on our territory,&quot; Cisneros said.</p>
<p>France has an arrest warrant out for Argentine Navy Capt. Alfredo Astiz, alias the &quot;Blond Angel,&quot; and sentenced him in absentia to life in jail for the murder of two French nuns. French President Jacques Chirac on a recent visit to Argentina urged that Astiz be tried in France but Justice Minister Elias Jassan insisted Dirty War crimes were &quot;a closed case.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
