<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="469047" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - March 26.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - March 26.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on Wednesday. Prepared for Reuters by the Co-operation Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- The candidate of Latvia's Way, Andris Berzinsh, was elected mayor of Riga by 32 votes in the third ballot.</p>
<p>- The management of Unibanka and Zemes Banka decided to cancel their planned merger.</p>
<p>- The privatisation agency decided that 4.7 million worth of Unibanka's state-owned shares should be put on the world's financial markets via a GDR issue. The agency's director general, Janis Naglis, said he was shocked by the two banks' decision not to merge without advising the agency, which owns 30 percent of Unibanka's shares.</p>
<p>- Andris Klavins was elected chairman of the Latvian shipping company. Ivars Godmanis was elected to the shipping company's board after being replaced by Arnolds Laksa as Savings Bank president. Godmanis was also elected the bank's chairman.</p>
<p>- Latvia commemorated the victims of the Communist-era deportations.</p>
<p>DIENA</p>
<p>- The Cabinet gave conceptual approval to the administrative reform, which envisages establishing four major districts and a special administrative unit for the capital, Riga.</p>
<p>NEATKARIGA RITA AVIZE</p>
<p>- After talks with the government, USAID decided to keep assisting Latvia until 1999 by providing $5-7 million in aid.</p>
<p>- The government approved the list of bills to be passed during parliament's spring recess.</p>
<p>BIZNES &amp; BALTIYA</p>
<p>- Representatives of Latvia and Sweden initialed an agreement on visa-free travel between the two countries.</p>
<p>- The U.S. is the first to recognise Latvia's non-citizen passports. Estonia and Lithuania are also ready to recognise the passports as legal travel documents.</p>
<p>SM</p>
<p>- Parliament finished its winter session.</p>
<p>DIENAS BIZNESS</p>
<p>- Nineteen companies from Riga and Ventspils have founded the Association of Latvia's Stevedoring Companies with the aim to promote stevedoring in Latvia and further co-operation with similar companies abroad.</p>
<p>- Parliament ratified the agreement on visa-free travel between Latvia and Denmark.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
