<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="469105" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Confab, Marubeni sign gas pipeline deal.</title>
<headline>Confab, Marubeni sign gas pipeline deal.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's Confab and Japan's Marubeni Corp on Wednesday signed a $628 million deal with Petrobras to supply steel pipes for the Brazil-Bolivia gas pipeline, a Petrobras official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have signed an agreement with Confab and Marubeni in which the companies will supply 540,000 tonnes of steel pipes from Santa Cruz, in Bolivia, to Porto Alegre (in Brazil),&quot; Petrobras president Joel Renno told a news conference.</p>
<p>The two companies were the winners of a contract to supply pipes which will extend over a distance of 3,150 kilometers, Renno added.  </p>
<p>The Brazil-Bolivia gas pipeline will cost $2 billion to be built and will be financed by the Bolivian and Brazilian governments, Petrobras, Brazil's National Development Bank (BNDES), the Interamerican Development Bank (IADB) and the World Bank.</p>
<p>The pipeline will allow Bolivia to sell 16 million cubic meters of natural gas daily to Brazil's southern states of Sao Paulo, Santa Catarina and Rio Grande do Sul.</p>
<p>Renno said the Sao Paulo state would buy 50 percent of all gas transported through the pipeline.  </p>
<p>The construction of the first part of the pipeline linking Santa Cruz fields to Sao Paulo city is expected to be ready by December next year, Renno added.</p>
<p>The second part linking Sao Paulo city to the capital of southern state of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, is expected to be completed in the second half of 1999, he said.</p>
<p>The Brazil-Bolivia gas pipeline is a part of a Brazilian government strategy to increase natural gas consumption in the country.</p>
<p>Brazil's Mines and Energy Minister Raimundo Britto said gas consumption in Brazil currently accounts for only 2.5 percent of total energy consumption.  He noted the government plans to increase natural gas' share to 12 percent by 2000.</p>
<p>((-- Romina Nicaretta, Sao Paulo newsroom, 5511 248 5415))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020043">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
