<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="469211" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK earnings, property seen riding out rate hike.</title>
<headline>HK earnings, property seen riding out rate hike.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Genevieve</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Hong Kong stock market took Tuesday's U.S. interest rate increase in its stride on Wednesday, with analysts expecting corporate earnings growth and property prices to remain strong.</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Reserve raised rates for the first time in more than two years on Tuesday, bringing the federal funds rate to 5.50 percent from 5.25 percent.</p>
<p>The Hong Kong Association of Banks followed the move by raising short-term deposit rates by 25 basis points and local commercial banks raised their prime rates by 25 basis points to 8.75 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;A quarter percentage point does not really have much impact on earnings and also we expect earnings growth will become faster on the back of improving economic activity,&quot; said Ben Kwong, director of research at Dharmala Securities.</p>
<p>Kwong expects earnings growth of about 15 percent in Hong Kong this year.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index closed the session down 56.14 points, or 0.44 percent, at 12,776.39 after gaining a total of 343.23 points during the two previous days.</p>
<p>The Hong Kong Monetary Authority also raised Liquidity Adjustment Facility rates by 25 basis points, bringing the LAF bid rate to 4.25 percent and the offer rate to 6.25 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said the property market was also likely to be unaffected by the move. Property stocks have a weighting of about 30 percent in the blue-chip Hang Seng Index.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we have sufficient genuine end-user demand to keep property prices pretty well-supported where they are,&quot; said Abhijit Chakrabortti, senior strategist at Lehman Brothers.</p>
<p>He said mortgage rates were below their historical average at prime plus 25 basis points to prime plus 50 compared with a past average of prime plus 125 basis points to prime plus 175.</p>
<p>&quot;The mortgage interest rate outlook is still reasonably supportive and given that we expect strong increases in wage growth, I don't think a 25 basis point move will do too much to the property sector,&quot; said Chakrabortti.</p>
<p>But analysts said there was some concern that the U.S. Federal Reserve had embarked on a series of tightenings which would impact corporate earnings growth.</p>
<p>Hong Kong Association of Banks chairman Chris Langley said he expected to see at least one more rate increase this year.</p>
<p>&quot;If we see continued increases in interest rates in the U.S. it will hurt Hong Kong, it will take the steam out of the Hong Kong market,&quot; said HG Asia investment strategist Jake van der Kamp.</p>
<p>Chakrabortti said a total 50 basis point rise would make the market vulnerable and 75 basis points &quot;very vulnerable&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Your fair value for the market would deteriorate, your earnings power would deteriorate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Alex Tang, head of research at Yamaichi International, said he expected an increase of 25 basis points in May and another 25 basis points during the second half of the year.</p>
<p>But he said companies exposed to the Chinese market should find themselves protected.</p>
<p>&quot;China does not have any inflationary pressure -- inflation keeps falling and interest rates are also coming down and the China market is still booming,&quot; said Tang.</p>
<p>&quot;The rate hike in the U.S. might affect some Hong Kong listed companies but it will not affect H-shares and some of the red chips since they rely on the China market,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>H-shares are stocks of Chinese incorporated companies listed in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
