<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="469279" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: South Korean bankers questioned over loans scandal.</title>
<headline>South Korean bankers questioned over loans scandal.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean state prosecutors on Wednesday questioned two bankers in connection with a loans-for-kickbacks scandal involving failed Hanbo Steel Co KS, a prosecution official said.</p>
<p>The official did not name the bankers, but said one was a branch manager of Korea First Bank, Hanbo's main creditor, and another an executive at the Commercial Bank of Korea.</p>
<p>State prosecutors last week reopened their enquiry into political influence-peddling that allowed Hanbo Steel to borrow $5.8 billion in largely unsecured loans.</p>
<p>The new probe is focusing on rumours that President Kim Young-sam's second son, Hyun-chul, received more than 200 billion won ($225 million) in kickbacks.</p>
<p>Three bankers are now on trial in the bribery scandal. They are Korea First Bank's former presidents Rhee Chul-soo and Sheen Kwang-shik and head of Chohung Bank Woo Chan-mok.</p>
<p>Seven other people including a former cabinet minister, Hanbo founder Chung Tae-soo and his chief accountant, three close aides to President Kim and an opposition lawmaker are also on trial.</p>
<p>President Kim apologised last month for the Hanbo furore and reshuffled his cabinet. Junior Kim issued a statement saying he was ready to receive punishment for any wrongdoings found.</p>
<p>The younger Kim was exonerated by prosecutors last month after being questioned in connection to the scandal.</p>
<p>The opposition has slammed the investigation as a white-wash. The government last week replaced Choi Byung-koog, who had led the Hanbo investigation, with Shim Je-ryoon.</p>
<p>Kim Hyun-chul is also due to testify before a National Assembly hearing on Hanbo in April which will be broadcast live. Parliament launch a 45-day special investigation on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
