<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="469241" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK's Hutchison 1996 net in line, outlook mixed.</title>
<headline>HK's Hutchison 1996 net in line, outlook mixed.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Davison</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong conglomerate Hutchison Whampoa Ltd reported healthy 1996 earnings in line with expectations on Wednesday, but analysts warned the outlook remains mixed despite upbeat comments from tycoon Li Ka-shing.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically it was in line with what the market was forecasting, propped up by the HK$4.1 billion exceptional from the Orange flotation earlier in the year,&quot; said ING Barings analyst Nam Park.</p>
<p>&quot;But the outlook is pretty mixed,&quot; he said. &quot;I think I'll be revising my numbers downwards.&quot;</p>
<p>Hutchison is 48.9 percent owned by Cheung Kong (Holdings) Ltd and has interests in property, energy, telecommunications, container terminal operations and retailing.</p>
<p>Despite weakness in most of its major divisions last year, Hutchison maintained earnings momentum by spinning off British mobile phone operator Orange Plc in April 1996.</p>
<p>The exceptional gain -- described by one analyst as recurrent income because Hutchison maintained its dividend payout ratio -- helped to boost 1996 net profit to HK$12.02 billion (US$1.55 billion) compared to HK$9.57 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>Although the company failed to give a detailed financial breakdown, analysts said the numbers suggested the company's telecoms and property divisions performed poorly last year while parts of the container business did reasonably well.</p>
<p>The outlook is slightly better in 1997 thanks to Orange, which has been performing better than expected, and the spin-off of a Hongkong Electric Holdings Ltd holding into subsidiary, Cheung Kong Infrastructure Holdings Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a pretty mixed outlook,&quot; said Park. &quot;But I think the real swing factor could be the telecoms side.&quot;</p>
<p>Hutchison chairman Li Ka-shing said the company's cellular telephone subscriber base is now about 340,000 and costs would plunge with the changeover from analogue to digital systems.</p>
<p>&quot;With its solid base of recurrent quality income, strong cash flow and financial position, the Group is well positioned to move forward to the next century with confidence,&quot; Li said.</p>
<p>But analysts said Hutchison faces an increasingly competitive telecoms market in Hong Kong, and 49-percent-held Orange remains a loss-making business despite early strength.</p>
<p>Analysts said the property division would continue to suffer from a lack of property developments, despite Li's comments that investment income offset any decline in property development income and rental income would remain strong this year.</p>
<p>&quot;It'll be 1998/99 before it's back to property being a source of significant growth,&quot; said John Hetherington, analyst at Asia Equity.</p>
<p>The container terminals division, however, seems set to improve. Analysts said Li suggested that Hongkong International Terminals Ltd (HIT) enjoyed double digit growth.</p>
<p>&quot;Given that other operators saw a three percent drop (in container traffic) HIT was obviously the other beneficiary,&quot; said Raymond Chong at Yaimichi Securities.</p>
<p>The medium-term outlook is much more positive, thanks to Hutchison's exposure to Chinese exports.</p>
<p>&quot;Medium term I'm very bullish. I'm bullish on China trade flows and Hutch is all up and down the coast of China,&quot; said Hetherington.</p>
<p>He is forecasting 1997 earnings of HK$3.60 per share, an estimate another analyst described as &quot;very aggressive&quot;.</p>
<p>Earnings per share in 1996 were HK$3.32.</p>
<p>(US$1 = HK$7.74)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
