<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="469317" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China's stock markets gain on good sentiment.</title>
<headline>China's stock markets gain on good sentiment.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's stock indices all ended higher on Wednesday led by Shanghai's B index, which closed at a 1997 high on news that General Motors Corp and a Shanghai firm had signed a production deal, brokers said.</p>
<p>Shanghai's foreign-currency B share index rose 1.318 points or 1.84 percent to 72.941 on volume of 21.4 million shares worth $10.7 million.</p>
<p>GM and state-owned Shanghai Automotive Industry Corp on Tuesday signed a $1.57 billion contract to produce cars in the Jinqiao Export Processing Zone in Shanghai's Pudong industrial zone.</p>
<p>Real estate developer Shanghai Jinqiao Export Processing Zone Development was another big winner on the news, rising $0.026, or 4.81 percent, to $0.566 on volume of 952,800 shares.</p>
<p>Brokers said a strong performance by Pudong shares boosted market confidence.</p>
<p>&quot;Market sentiment has improved and buying has focused on stocks with good records as most firms' 1996 results have yet to be released,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Shanghai Dazhong Taxi gained on expectations of good 1996 results and talk of an attractive bonus offer plan, soaring $0.102, or 10 percent, to its limit-up of $1.122 on volume of 444,000 shares.</p>
<p>Toy maker Shanghai Haixin benefitted from the same expectations, gaining $0.036 or 6.14 percent to $0.622 on volume of 2.2 million shares.</p>
<p>Shenzhen's B index gained 1.04 points or 0.64 percent to 163.12 on thin turnover of HK$85 million.</p>
<p>Strong performances by several stocks cheered the market, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Tellus, Wafangdian and Jiangling all boosted morale today,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Shenzhen Tellus Machinery &amp; Electronics surged to its 10 percent limit-up on expectations of good results, up HK$0.33 to HK$3.64 on volume of 1.3 million shares.</p>
<p>Wafangdian put on HK$0.14 or 2.79 percent to HK$5.16, on volume of 5.6 million shares. Its issue price was HK$2.66.</p>
<p>Jiangling Motors said it planned to issue 170 million new B shares, of which 120 million would be sold to Ford Motor Co. The counter rose HK$0.10 to HK$4.08.</p>
<p>Shanghai's A index of stocks reserved for domestic investors rose 18.172 points or 1.45 percent to 1,272.889 on volume of 839.6 million shares worth 9.5 billion yuan. The SSE 30 blue chip index gained 11.001 points or 0.32 percent to 3,493.479 points.</p>
<p>Tristar Petrochemical was the star on talk of a solid bonus offering plan, surging 1.89 yuan or 10 percent to limit-up of 20.77 yuan on volume of 1.8 million shares.</p>
<p>The Shenzhen A share index ended the day up at 451.81 points, gaining 6.65 points or 1.49 percent on turnover of 13.3 billion yuan against Tuesday's 13.8 billion yuan.</p>
<p>($1=8.3 yuan, $1=HK$7.8)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
