<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="469494" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Disabled New York man charged with molesting boys.</title>
<headline>Disabled New York man charged with molesting boys.</headline>
<dateline>HAUPPAUGE, N.Y. 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A wheelchair-bound New York man honoured for his athleticism despite a crippling disease, has been arrested and charged with sexually molesting two boys under 16 years old, police said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Tommy Lynch, 32, of Port Jefferson Station in Suffolk County, Long Island, allegedly lured boys to his house, plied them with wine and showed them pornographic videos, police said.</p>
<p>Suffolk County Detective Lieutenant Alan Rosenthal told a news conference that the alleged sexual molestation was revealed when parents of one of the victims questioned their son after his grades dropped from an A average to a C average.</p>
<p>Lynch, who was arrested on Tuesday, was already on probation for the 1992 sexual molestation of two boys ages 5 and 13, police said.</p>
<p>Lynch took part in wheelchair marathons for charity and could bench-press 400 pounds. In 1985 he was honoured as Suffolk County's citizen of the year and national athlete of the Spina Bifida Foundation. He was born with the crippling condition and was cited by the foundation as a &quot;role model&quot; for those suffering from the disease.</p>
<p>Rosenthal said Lynch offered $100 in cash to victims &quot;to stand with no clothes on outside his house&quot; and that the lure of wine and the videos came later.</p>
<p>He allegedly showed them a fake will in which he pretended to leave the boys his go-cart, VCR, and TV. One of the victims tried to escape but Lynch &quot;was so strong that he held onto him,&quot; Rosenthal said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAUPPAUGE, N.Y."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
