<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="469685" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida gator trappers rare but necessary.</title>
<headline>Florida gator trappers rare but necessary.</headline>
<byline>Brad Liston</byline>
<dateline>ASTOR, Fla. 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The death of a Florida boy in the jaws of a giant alligator has drawn attention to the alligator trapper, a rare and taciturn breed of man that has all but vanished from Southern U.S. backwaters.</p>
<p>When 3-year-old Adam Binford disappeared last Friday while picking water lilies at Lake Ashby, authorities immediately sent in helicopters with infrared scopes, scuba divers with search beams and sonar-equipped patrol boats.</p>
<p>But another group of men in faded jeans and soiled shirts waited on the shore, their hooks and gigs stowed in narrow boats. These were the trappers.</p>
<p>When authorities gave up the search, they took to the water, gliding quietly through the night, using skills passed from father to son since Seminole Indians first taught them to white settlers in this part of Florida in the 18th century.</p>
<p>That night on Lake Ashby, two gators were caught and killed but when they were cut open the trappers knew the one they wanted was still on the lake. Around dawn, trapper Curtis Lucas spotted the biggest gator of the night.</p>
<p>From years of watching alligators, he knew the creature was guarding something on the shore. As his boat approached, the gator took its prize into its massive jaws and Lucas could see it was Adam's tiny body.</p>
<p>Three blasts from his shotgun killed the beast and Lucas pried the boy's body from the 11-foot (3.3-metre) alligator's mouth.</p>
<p>&quot;It was horrible,&quot; Lucas told Reuters. &quot;It's just not something I can really talk about. I can't even imagine what that boy's family has been through.&quot;</p>
<p>Lucas is a soft-spoken man who gets no pleasure from the role he played even though he succeeded where several million dollars worth of high-tech gear failed.</p>
<p>&quot;It used to be all the men in Astor hunted gators,&quot; he said. &quot;My father and grandfather both hunted them and I suppose the men in my family hunted them before that. Hunting alligators was one of the only means of making cash money in Astor back then.&quot;</p>
<p>Those days are long gone. People still struggle to make a living in Florida's swampy interior but alligators were hunted nearly to extinction in the 1950s, victims of fashion's appetite for alligator handbags and shoes. That brought a total ban on hunting, which lasted until the late 1980s.</p>
<p>Then, with the gator population once again vigorous and Florida's swampy land being sold off for vacation and retirement homes, complaints about alligators rose. The central Florida region where Adam Binford died is one of the fastest growing areas in the United States.</p>
<p>About a million alligators live in Florida, most in lakes and waterways favoured by humans for recreation, Lt. Joy Hill of the Florida Game and Freshwater Fish Commission said. Attacks have risen from just two in 1976 to a high of 21 in 1994, though they are usually not fatal.</p>
<p>Now Florida's 67 counties each has at least one trapper. Lucas is the trapper for Volusia County, where complaints along the St. Johns River and lakes are common.</p>
<p>&quot;I grew up listening to all the stories,&quot; he said. &quot;I learned from a man who'd hunted gators with my father when they were both boys and he had to relearn everything he knew.&quot;</p>
<p>Usually Lucas works with a snatch hook and a harpoon. Although alligator attacks on humans are rare, larger animals can be extremely dangerous when the roles are reversed.</p>
<p>&quot;Shoot, those things can take you right out of the boat if you're not careful,&quot; said Brevard County trapper Bill Rob. &quot;They've got strong tails. You want to watch out for those tails. And alligators are built to roll. They take their prey into their jaws and roll in the water so the prey drowns.&quot;</p>
<p>The trappers receive no pay for their services. They sell the meat and hides, and sometimes the jawbones, prized by collectors. Lucas serves the meat at a restaurant he owns with his wife.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ASTOR, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
