<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46970" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gerber Products recalls baby rattles.</title>
<headline>Gerber Products recalls baby rattles.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gerber Products Co. said Wednesday it will recall about 60,000 baby rattles because they pose a choking and inhalation hazard to young children.</p>
<p>Gerber, a unit of Swiss drug and nutrition company Sandoz AG, said the recall involves red-handled versions of the Gerber Flip Fingers Rattle, but not green-handled versions.</p>
<p>Yellow spherical end caps attatched to the rattles' bright red, U-shaped handle may separate, Gerber said, releasing small parts, such as spinning plastic pieces and noise-making beads, which could present a choking hazard.</p>
<p>Gerber said it will offer consumers a full refund for the rattles, which were introduced in May at a retail price of $1.39 and sold in grocery stores and speciality stores.</p>
<p>The part number listed on the toy's clear plastic package on a blue card is 76250. The Fremont, Mich.-based baby food company said consumers should immediately take the rattles away from their children and call Gerber at 1-800-4-GERBER.</p>
<p>Gerber, which made the announcement in conjunction with the U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, said it has received reports five of the rattles breaking, but has not heard of any injuries.</p>
<p>Gerber spokesman Van Hindes said the company has not yet determined whether it will introduce a new version of the red-handled Flip Fingers rattle. The company, whose main business is baby food, buys the product under contract from a manufacturer in China, Hindes said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
