<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="469719" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN official resigns over Bosnian war victim probes.</title>
<headline>UN official resigns over Bosnian war victim probes.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.N. official in charge of probing the fate of missing persons in Bosnia and Croatia resigned in exasperation on Tuesday, saying he received little support for digging up mass graves of victims of ethnic cleansing.</p>
<p>Manfred Nowak, an Austrian law professor, told a U.N. commission in Geneva he received about 5 percent of the $6 million in funds needed, that NATO-led troops were reluctant to provide security for forensic experts and that Belgrade as well as the Bosnian Serbs frequently refused to cooperate.</p>
<p>&quot;If we wish to tell the women of Srebrenica or other families of missing persons the truth and facilitate a decent burial of their loved ones, then the international community should take the lead,&quot; he said, according to a statement delivered before the U.N. Commission on Human Rights.</p>
<p>&quot;Mere pressure on the Bosnia parties is in my opinion not sufficient,&quot; said Nowak, chairman of the U.N. Working Group on Enforced Disappearances.</p>
<p>He said most suspected mass graves are in Bosnian Serb areas and authorities there were not willing to open them unless there was some kind of reciprocity in other areas.</p>
<p>Nowak said about 20,000 people were still missing in Bosnia, most of them Moslem men who became victims of ethnic cleansing carried out by the Yugoslav army, Serb paramilitary groups and Bosnian Serb forces between May and September 1992 and after the 1995 fall of the enclaves of Srebenica and Zepa.</p>
<p>Other Moslems were most likely killed in operations carried out by Croats in 1993.</p>
<p>The missing, he said, also included:</p>
<p>-- 5,000 people in Croatia, including more than 2,500 who were victims of ethnic cleansing by the Yugslav Army and Serb paramilitary groups in late 1991;</p>
<p>-- 1,000 Yugoslav soldiers during Croatia's 1991 war of independence from Yugoslavia;</p>
<p>-- 2,000 Croatian Serb civilians who allegedly disappeared during Zagreb's military offensive in May and August 1995.</p>
<p>Nowak said several international groups were investigating the same incidents without proper coordination.</p>
<p>He suggested that the new international commission of missing persons established on the initiative of the United States and other governments might be more successful and should take the lead.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
