<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="469717" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss shares continue rise, ending one percent up.</title>
<headline>Swiss shares continue rise, ending one percent up.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss shares ended more than one percent higher for a second day as index heavyweights Roche, Novartis and Nestle helped the shares continue their recent recovery.</p>
<p>Traders said Tuesday's tightening of U.S. interest rates had been expected. Trade was likely to be quiet on Thursday ahead of Easter holiday and given the fact that the bourse close will be moved forward to 1300 GMT from 1530 GMT.</p>
<p>* Blue-chip Swiss Market Index (SMI) ended up 61.9 points or 1.36 percent to 4,620.5.</p>
<p>* All-share Swiss Performance Index (SPI) added 31.15 points to 2,919.11.  </p>
<p>* Stocks of food giant Nestle jumped 4.06 percent, or 64 francs, to 1,641, after it report a 16.6 percent increase in 1996 group net to 3,401 million francs. Nestle was the only SMI company so far to report 1996 results that were clearly above market expectations, one trader noted. Nestle had hit a year's high of 1,670 francs on March 11.</p>
<p>* Dealers said part of today's advance stemmed from short covering in recently pressured stocks. Thus, Roche certificates rebounded after Tuesday's weakness, adding 135 francs to end at 12,305, one dealers said.</p>
<p>* Novartis registered shares were up 20 to 1,780.  </p>
<p>* CS Group continued trading with a firmer bias, adding one franc to 174. UBS bears rose three francs to 12.85.</p>
<p>* The shares of temporary employment firm Adecco surged 18 francs to 454 after overcoming technical resistance.</p>
<p>* Surveillance jumped 115 francs to 3,065, in a rebound from a recent sharp fall.</p>
<p>* ABB and Electrowatt were flat at 1,700 francs and 533 francs, respectively.</p>
<p>* Ems Chemie lost 20 francs to end at 5,850.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
