<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="469815" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Basque guerrillas, French backers face prison.</title>
<headline>Basque guerrillas, French backers face prison.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A French anti-terrorism state prosecutor asked a court on Wednesday to jail 14 Spanish Basque ETA guerrillas and four French nationals who sheltered militants of the group.</p>
<p>Prosecutor Irene Stoller requested a maximum 10-year sentence against suspected ETA (Basque Homeland and Freedom) leader Pedro Pikabea Ugalde, and terms of six to seven years against four other guerrillas on charges of criminal conspiracy with terrorist aims.</p>
<p>She suggested sentences of 10 and seven years respectively against Jose Arizcuren Ruiz and Conchita Iglesias, who are being tried in absentia and are suspected of involvement in plans to kill King Juan Carlos of Spain during his summer holiday at Palma de Majorca.</p>
<p>Stoller asked the court to jail for under a year four people from Brittany in western France who invoked a local tradition of asylum to justify sheltering ETA militants.</p>
<p>&quot;They are using the wrong word; asylum is for the victims of violence while they knew these people were murderers,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Police rounded up the accused following Pikabea's detention in Bayonne in southwest France in July 1994. Spain has requested that he be handed over.</p>
<p>The court is to announce its verdict at a later date.</p>
<p>ETA has killed more than 800 people in a 29-year fight for an independent Basque state encompassing parts of southern France and northern Spain.</p>
<p>French Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre visited Madrid this week and pledged to increase cooperation with Spain against ETA rebels, saying it would aggressively pursue leaders of the group on its territory.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
