<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="469826" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French former CGE adviser in corruption probe.</title>
<headline>French former CGE adviser in corruption probe.</headline>
<dateline>NICE, France 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former adviser at giant French water utility Compagnie Generale des Eaux (CGE) was detained on Wednesday to be questioned on allegedly illicit payments to the Riviera resort of Cannes, justice sources said.</p>
<p>The unnamed aide to Jean-Marc Oury, former chairman of CGE subsidiary and real estate firm Phenix, was due to be brought before investigating magistrate Philippe Alenda in Nice, the sources said. He had previously been questioned in June as part of the investigation.</p>
<p>The CGE is France's biggest private employer, with 225,000 staff and a turnover of 164 billion francs ($30 billion).</p>
<p>Judicial sources said Oury was likely to be questioned by the judge next week.</p>
<p>The jailed former mayor of Cannes, Michel Mouillot, faces further questioning along with his wife as part of the corruption inquiry.</p>
<p>Mouillot, jailed since July in a separate sleaze probe, is suspected of illicitly receiving funds -- more than 10 million francs ($1.7 million) -- through a Phenix employee. Oury was an associate of Mouillot.</p>
<p>The employee, Oury's former secretary Micheline Clerq who now works for the chairman of the CGE, was this week ordered held in custody in Nice.</p>
<p>The investigation started when co-owners of part of the Croisette seafront boulevard appealed to magistrates in a tussle with the town hall which wanted to expropriate their property to build a hotel complex close to the Palm Beach casino.</p>
<p>The plaintiffs accused Mouillot of &quot;distorting a public procedure for the benefit of private interests&quot;.</p>
<p>Mouillot resigned in February after the Supreme Court threw out an appeal against his previous conviction for sleaze.</p>
<p>Once dubbed the &quot;Kennedy of the Croisette&quot;, the centre-right politician was barred from holding public office for five years as part of an 18-month suspended prison sentence and 200,000 franc ($37,000) fine for receiving a ficticious salary from a Lyon businessman.</p>
<p>He has been in pre-trial custody since last July for two other corruption cases in which he is accused of having solicited bribes in exchange for permits to install one-arm bandits in casinos.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICE, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
