<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46987" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Key U.S. corn crop seen improved from last month.</title>
<headline>Key U.S. corn crop seen improved from last month.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Agriculture Department on Wednesday estimated U.S. 1996 corn production at 8.804 billion bushels, up slightly from its August estimate and almost 20 percent more than last year's production.</p>
<p>In a closely watched report that came just as farmers begin to make harvest preparations, the Agriculture Department also pegged the U.S. soybean crop at 2.270 billion bushels, down slightly from last month's projections, but still the second largest soybean crop on record.  </p>
<p>The U.S. wheat crop was pegged at 2.30 billion bushels, up slightly from last month's estimate and 5 percent more than last year.</p>
<p>The new estimates, based on surveys of fields throughout the growing areas and interviews with about 16,000 farmers, could briefly calm global commodity markets, which have been roiled all year by a wide range and degree of crop problems, tight grain supplies and significantly strong demand.</p>
<p>Recently, concerns that maturity of the U.S. corn crop is lagging the average pace, that the condition of the soybean crop has deteriorated slightly and that an early frost in the midwest could damage the vulnerable crops have made the nervous markets even more tense.</p>
<p>The Agriculture Department said warmer weather in early August over most of the Corn Belt accelerated row-crop development, but not enough to reach normal levels. As of September 1, only 33 percent of the corn in the major producing states was in the so-called denting stage, compared to 49 percent last year and a five-year average of 51 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
