<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="470000" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Labour pledges tax cuts, fights union charges.</title>
<headline>UK's Labour pledges tax cuts, fights union charges.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The opposition Labour party on Wednesday agreed a tax-cutting manifesto which its leader Tony Blair said marked a new bond of trust with the British people and &quot;the burial of tax-and-spend politics from Labour&quot;.</p>
<p>Dismissing Conservative attacks on Labour's links with the unions as scare tactics, Blair told a news conference: &quot;The only weapon they have is fear, the weapon we have is hope.&quot;</p>
<p>Promising no surprises after the May 1 election, Blair said: &quot;What you see is what you will get. It says only what we know we can deliver. Nothing more. It guarantees that Labour will govern from the centre for all the people.&quot;</p>
<p>The hastily-called news conference came after what Labour's foreign affairs spokesman Robin Cook said was the shortest meeting in living memory of the party executive and a cabinet-in-waiting to decide an election manifesto.</p>
<p>Cook said the short meeting was a sign of party unity. But it was also a sign of the disciplined campaigning machine Blair has built up after taking charge of the party in 1994 and dragging it from the left to the political centre.</p>
<p>The key points of the manifesto, which Blair said would be available next week, are pledge not to increase income tax rates for the full five years of a Labour government and to cut Value Added Tax on heating from eight to five percent.</p>
<p>Blair said the manifesto, based on policies approved last year by rank-and-file party members, also included an &quot;ambition&quot; to cut the starting rate of income tax to 10 percent from 20.</p>
<p>He promised no &quot;unfunded spending commitments&quot;, saying: &quot;There is nothing in the manifesto that requires higher taxes other than the windfall levy on the excess profits of the privatised utilities to fund a jobs programme for young people.&quot;</p>
<p>But Blair's strongest language was reserved for the ruling party's charges that a Labour government would signal a return to the industrial strife of the 1970s over its plans to give union recognition where half the workforce voted for it.</p>
<p>The Conservative attacks, echoed in a Sun newspaper article on Wednesday which said Blair's deputy John Prescott had signed a deal with European unions which could lead to Britain being infected by European labour disputes, jolted Labour's campaign.</p>
<p>Economics spokesman Gordon Brown, thrown off balance, on Tuesday said details of Labour's plans had been misunderstood.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Major kept up the pressure on Wednesday, writing in The Birmingham Post newspaper: &quot;One Labour government could destroy our ability to attract massive investment from all over the world and put thousands of jobs at risk.</p>
<p>&quot;Eighteen years of progress surrendered in 18 months of Labour in power. Make no mistake. If Labour and the unions win, Britain loses,&quot; wrote Major before a campaign tour.</p>
<p>But Blair, who sent Brown off to a marginal constituency near London on Wednesday to explain his tax plans and took the news conference platform himself, went on the offensive.</p>
<p>Saying Labour had no plans to repeal tough anti-union laws introduced by the Conservatives during 18 years unbroken rule, Blair promised &quot;no favours&quot; for unions -- the party's historical power base and still the main single source of party funds.</p>
<p>The Conservatives, 25 points behind in polls, see reviving memories of the winter of 1978-9, when the last Labour government suffered bitter protests against attempts to control wage rises, as one of their best hopes of catching Labour.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course the Conservatives want to fight the 1997 election as if they were fighting the 1979 election but...there is no going back to the past, we are a party addressing the future,&quot; Blair said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
