<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="470090" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dollar seen buttressed by Fed rate rise - analysts.</title>
<headline>Dollar seen buttressed by Fed rate rise - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Astrid Zweynert</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The first U.S. rate rise in two years and the prospect of further hikes will bolster the dollar as interest rate differentials with Japan and Germany are expected to favour the currency in the foreseeable future, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The tone for the dollar after the rate rise is pretty positive, though the quarter point hike was already priced in,&quot; said Jeremy Hawkins at Bank of America. &quot;The fact we've had higher rates cemented now helps underline the divergence between the U.S. economic cycle and continental Europe.&quot;  </p>
<p>By the European midsession on Wednesday the dollar traded at 1.6900/05 marks, down from 1.6928/33 in late European trading on Tuesday. Against the yen, it was at 124.13/23, up from 123.91/96 after stalling around overnight peaks at 124.35 yen.</p>
<p>The dollar initially spiked higher to 1.6980 marks on Tuesday in response to an expected 25 basis point rise in the Federal funds target to 5.50 percent but profit-taking and weaker U.S. asset markets dragged it off its peaks, traders said.</p>
<p>Downward corrections in stocks and bonds amid fears in those markets that interest rates are set to rise further remain a risk to the positive dollar scenario.  </p>
<p>The dollar is vulnerable to asset market sell-offs because of the amount of foreign investment in dollar securities, which is needed to fund the large U.S. current account deficit.</p>
<p>Many in the market are now looking to the May 20 Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting for another 25 basis points rise in the Fed funds rate. Interest rate markets are already pricing in a Fed funds rate of 6.0 to 6.25 percent at the end of the year.</p>
<p>Thus, heavily discounted interest rate rises are unlikely to shake asset markets, and a 1994-style shake-out is unlikely given the different U.S. economic backdrop now, analyst said.  </p>
<p>The aggressive tightening in 1994/95 of three percentage points within a year led to a bond market meltdown and also hit stocks and the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will keep an eye on asset markets but the situation is different now, and there was no panic yesterday,&quot; said Teis Knuthsen, international economist at First Chicago.</p>
<p>There is still no clear sign of inflation in the economy despite robust economic growth. The release of U.S. jobs data for March next week will be eyed for signs of wage pressures.</p>
<p>Moreoever, real U.S. rates, adjusted for inflation, are over two percent higher now than when the Fed raised rates last time.  </p>
<p>With gloom and doom about the economy in Germany and Japan lifting only very gradually, interest rate differentials remain the key argument in favour of the dollar, analysts said.</p>
<p>This should bolster the dollar against the yen in particular as capital is expected to flow out of Japan into U.S. assets at the start of the new Japanese financial year next week.</p>
<p>However, a firm cap lurks at 125 yen, which is seen by many observers as a level Japanese and U.S. authorities are watching.</p>
<p>The dollar hit a high of 124.82 on February 28, its highest level in four years.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have had comments from Japan in particular saying it would not be acceptable for the dollar to break 125 yen,&quot; said Graham Cocks, vice-president at Bank of Boston. &quot;But as far as Japanese investors are concerned the (U.S.) bond markets are still attractive.&quot;</p>
<p>Concern that a further dollar rise will increase trade friction between Japan and the U.S. was highlighted on Wednesday by comments from Richard Medley, a U.S. investment advisor, who also advises the Democratic Party. Medley said the Treasury will not tolerate an increase in the structural trade deficit with Japan and was growing concerned about current dollar levels.  </p>
<p>Trade issues are likely to move to the top of the agenda again for the dollar when Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin visits Tokyo on April 4, dealers said.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom + 44 171 542 7792</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
