<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47009" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS - Most Germans accept need for cuts - poll.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Most Germans accept need for cuts - poll.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A growing majority of Germans accept Chancellor Helmut Kohl's argument that government spending cuts are needed to boost the economy's competitive position, an opinion poll published on Wednesday said.</p>
<p>The Allensbach research institute said, in a survey published in the daily Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung, that 64 percent of Germans now agree that Kohl's savings plan is necessary, up sharply from 44 percent in May.</p>
<p>Even though trade unions have staged massive demonstrations throughout the country in recent months to protest against the proposed cuts in sick pay and workers' rights, Allensbach found more and more people now accept the cuts as inevitable.</p>
<p>&quot;The population is anxious about the economy and is concerned it is not just a temporary downturn but rather a changing environment that requires sacrifice and change,&quot; pollster Renate Koecher wrote in the newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;The public is aware of the state's financial problems,&quot; she added. &quot;What frightens people is the thought that taxes and fees will continue in a permanent upward spiral.&quot;</p>
<p>Kohl's austerity package consists of a wide range of spending cuts and supply side reform measures, aimed both at cutting runaway budget deficits and reducing business costs to encourage firms to take on more workers.</p>
<p>The package aims to slash 50 billion marks ($33.03 billion) from public spending next year and 20 billion marks from social welfare fund to get the public deficit under the three percent of gross domestic product level required for joining the single European currency planned for 1999.</p>
<p>Kohl, citing the survey during a nationally televised debate in parliament on Wednesday, said: &quot;A large majority of our fellow citizens have recognised that changes are needed in order to secure the future.&quot;</p>
<p>Despite the growing acceptance, there was a sharp division between how east and west Germans viewed the spending cuts.</p>
<p>While acceptance in the west rose to 69 percent at the end of August from 46 percent in June, only 43 percent of those in the formerly communist east agreed with the austerity plans, up from 36 percent in June.</p>
<p>&quot;The savings programme has touched a more critical nerve in the east, where many doubt the need to save,&quot; Koecher said.</p>
<p>&quot;While a slowly growing majority in the west are convinced that even massive cuts in the social welfare system are unavoidable, the majority in the east want to maintain or even expand on the social security system.&quot;</p>
<p>A major part of the package, including pension and health reforms as well as cuts in sick pay and workers' protection from dismissal, is set to be voted through the lower house of parliament on Friday, overriding upper house objections.</p>
<p>Germany currently spends a trillion marks annually -- equivalent to a third of its GDP -- on welfare and social spending.</p>
<p>($1=1.5139 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
