<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="470038" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BAA to raise London airport fees April 1.</title>
<headline>BAA to raise London airport fees April 1.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>British airport operator BAA said it will increase from April 1 its average landing, passenger and parking charges in line with a formula laid down by its regulator, the Civil Aviation Authority (CAA).</p>
<p>Landing fees at Gatwick and Stansted have been increased by more than at London Heathrow which remains the most expensive of BAA's three London airports.</p>
<p>This is the first year of the five-year formula restricting the average rise in charges to three percent less than the UK retail price index.</p>
<p>Landing fees at Heathrow for planes over 50 tonnes are up by between five and seven stg with a top rate of 585 stg for peak time landing for noisy Chapter 2 planes which carry a 30 percent surcharge.</p>
<p>Fees at Gatwick for a Chapter 2 over 50 tonnes are 19.5 stg higher at 422.50 stg. At Stansted the charge structure has been altered so next week Chapter 2 planes over 250 tonnes will pay 195 stg plus 4.55 stg a tonne of the total weight of the aircraft. Previously the charge for ones over 50 tonnes was 111.80 stg plus 4.55 stg a tonne for each tonne above 50 tonnes.</p>
<p>- Reuters Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax+5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
