<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="470189" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Palestinian protesters burn Israeli, U.S. flags.</title>
<headline>Palestinian protesters burn Israeli, U.S. flags.</headline>
<dateline>BETHLEHEM, West Bank 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinians burned Israeli and American flags in the West Bank town of Bethlehem on Wednesday in a protest against Israel's settlement policy they perceive as supported by the U.S., witnesses said.</p>
<p>Palestinian protesters have clashed with Israeli troops in the West Bank for seven days straight since Israel broke ground on a new Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem. Israel has confronted the stone-throwing demonstrators with teargas and rubber bullets lightly wounding dozens of Palestinians.</p>
<p>The Palestinians and the Arab world have been angered by the Israeli settlement drive. They say it strengthens the Jewish state's hold on the East part of Jerusalem which Palestinians claim as the capital of a future state.</p>
<p>They have brought the matter to the United Nations where the United States twice vetoed decisions condemning the Israeli plan. The American flag burned in Bethlehem had the word &quot;veto&quot; scrawled on it.</p>
<p>The U.S. State Department said on Wednesday it was sending its chief Middle East peace broker to the region to try and defuse Arab-Israeli tensions.</p>
<p>An Israeli security source said troops had orders to exert restraint in dealing with Palestinian demonstrations and try to avoid casualties. Last September 61 Palestinians and 15 Israelis were killed in gunbattles during Palestinian protests against Israel's policy in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The Israeli security source said: &quot;The troops are trying not to fire at Palestinian police so as not to provoke them to fire back.&quot;</p>
<p>The Palestinian security chief in the West Bank, Jibril Rajoub, was in Bethlehem on Wednesday trying to keep the Palestinian protest from getting out of hand.</p>
<p>Relations between Israel and the PLO have been tense in recent weeks and Israeli security officials have been on high alert. On Friday an Islamic militant blew himself up in a Tel Aviv cafe, killing three women and wounding about 50 people.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BETHLEHEM, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
