<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="470228" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NOTICE OF SALE - Broome County, N.Y..</title>
<headline>NOTICE OF SALE - Broome County, N.Y..</headline>
<text>
<p>SUMMARY NOTICE OF BOND SALE</p>
<p>				  $28,875,000</p>
<p>			     County of Broome</p>
<p>				   New York</p>
<p>		Public Improvement (Serial) Bonds, 1997</p>
<p>			     (Book Entry Only)</p>
<p>Sealed proposals will  be received  and considered  by the undersigned Commissioner of Finance of the County of Broome, New York, at  the Office of  Willkie Farr  &amp; Gallagher,  900 Third Avenue, 17th  Floor, Conference Room  17-A, New  York, New York 10022, until  11:00 o'clock A.M., Prevailing  Time, on the</p>
<p>			  1st day of April, 1997,</p>
<p>at which time  and place the  bids will be  opened, for  the purchase INFEDERALFUNDS  at not  less than  par and  accrued interest of $28,875,000  Public Improvement (Serial)  Bonds, 1997, of said  County, dated  April 15,  1997, and  maturing April 15 as follows:</p>
<p>    Year  Amount   Year  Amount   Year  Amount</p>
<p>1998$3,200,000 2005$1,500,000 2011$1,000,000*</p>
<p>19992,500,000  20061,400,000  20121,000,000*</p>
<p>20002,400,000  20071,300,000* 2013900,000*</p>
<p>20012,000,000  20081,300,000* 2014900,000*</p>
<p>20022,000,000  20091,300,000* 2015675,000*</p>
<p>20032,000,000  20101,250,000* 2016500,000*</p>
<p>20041,750,000</p>
<p>*Bonds maturing on or after April  15, 2007 are subject to redemption, at the option of the County, prior to  maturity, in whole or  in part,  on any  interest payment  date on  or after April 15, 2006, at  redemption prices, expressed as  a percentage of par, plus  accrued interest to the  redemption date as follows: April 15, 2006 and October 15, 2006,  102%; April 15, 2007  and October 15,  2007, 101%;  and April  15, 2008 and thereafter, 100%.</p>
<p>THE COUNTY RESERVES  THE RIGHT  TO CHANGE THE  TIME AND/OR</p>
<p> DATE FOR THE  OPENING OF BIDS.   NOTICE OF  ANY SUCH  CHANGE</p>
<p>SHALL BE PROVIDED NOT LESS THAN  24 HOURS PRIOR TO THE  TIME</p>
<p>SET FORTH  ABOVE FOR  THE  OPENING OF  BIDS  BY MEANS  OF  A</p>
<p>SUPPLEMENTAL NOTICE  OF  SALE  TO BE  TRANSMITTED  OVER  THE</p>
<p>MUNIFACTS WIRE.</p>
<p>Each bid must be for all of said $28,875,000 bonds and may state a  single  rate  of interest  or  different  rates  of interest for different  maturities, provided, however,  that (i) only one rate  of interest may be  bid for bonds of  the same maturity,  (ii)  the  maximum  difference  between  the highest and lowest interest rate bid may not exceed one  and one-half per centum per annum, (iii) variations in rates  of interest so bid shall be  in ascending progression in  order of maturity  so that  the rate  of  interest on  any  single maturity of said bonds  shall not be less  than the rate  of interest applicable  to any  prior  maturity, and  (iv)  all rates of interest bid must be  stated in a multiple of  one- eighth or one-hundredth of one per centum per annum.  Unless all bids are rejected, the award will be made to the  bidder</p>
<p>complying with the  terms of sale  and offering to  pur said bonds at such rate or rates of interest as will produce the lowest net interest cost computed in accordance with the net interest cost method of calculation, that being the rate or rates of interest which  will produce the least  interest cost over the life  of the  Bonds, after accounting  for the premium offered, if any.  If two or more such bidders  offer  to purchase  the   Bonds at  the  same  net  interest  cost,</p>
<p>computed as described  above, the  Bonds will be  awarded to the bidder whose  bid offers to  purchase the  Bonds at the  highest premium dollar  amount.   The right  is reserved  to</p>
<p>reject any or all bids, and any bid not complying with  this  Notice  of  Sale  will  be  rejected.    Each  bid  must  be</p>
<p>accompanied by a good faith deposit  check in the amount  of $577,500.</p>
<p>If the  bonds  qualify  for  issuance  of  any  policy  of municipal bond  insurance  or  commitment  therefor  at  the option of  a  bidder, the  purchase  of any  such  insurance policy or the issuance of any such commitment therefor shall be at the  sole option and  expense of such  bidder and  any increased costs of issuance of the Bonds resulting by reason of the same, unless  otherwise paid, shall  be paid by  such bidder.  Any failure of the Bonds to be so insured or of any such policy of insurance to be issued, shall not  constitute cause for a failure or refusal by the purchaser of the Bonds to accept delivery of  and pay for  the Bonds in accordance with the terms of the purchase contract.</p>
<p>  The  purchaser  will   be  furnished  without   cost,  the</p>
<p>unqualified legal opinion as to the validity of the Bonds of Willkie Farr &amp; Gallagher, New York, New York, Bond Counsel. Bidders must refer to the complete  Notice of Sale for the terms and conditions of the sale.</p>
<p>For further information regarding the  Bonds and to obtain copies of the complete  Notice of Bond  Sale, Bid Form,  and the Official Statement of the County, please contact  Fiscal Advisors  &amp;  Marketing,  Inc.,  telephone:  (315)  699-7912, telecopier: (315) 699-8833.  Additional Official  Statements may be downloaded from  Fiscal Advisors &amp; Marketing,  Inc.'s Internet address: http://www.fiscaladvisors.com.</p>
<p>Dated: March 20, 1997.</p>
<p>						  Commissioner of Finance</p>
<p>			  (From The Bond Buyer)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
