<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47032" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EMU no threat to London's financial dominance -BOE.</title>
<headline>EMU no threat to London's financial dominance -BOE.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>London's status as Europe's number one financial centre will not be seriously threatened even if Britain opts out of a European single currency, Bank of England deputy governor Howard Davies said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;In many respects, the euro, if sterling remains outside it, would be just another foreign currency and London has operated extremely effectively in other peoples' currencies for many years,&quot; Davies told a German-British Chamber of Industry and Commerce gathering in London.</p>
<p>He added that British authorities will stick to an anti-inflation policy whether the country joins EMU or not.</p>
<p>&quot;In or out of Economic and Monetary Union, we would...argue that the UK should be aiming to achieve price stability, or at least an inflation rate as close as possible to that which obtains in our major markets in Continental Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>Davies said less than 10 percent of London's foreign exchange business was tied to those currencies likely to be in the first wave of European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>And anyway, there was much still to be decided about the relationships between EMU &quot;ins&quot; and &quot;outs&quot;.</p>
<p>But of most encouragement for the City of London was the attitude of European financial institutions to London.</p>
<p>The possibility of Britain not participating in EMU was not a new one, Davies said, yet foreign financial institutions have shown no signs of decamping from London.</p>
<p>&quot;On the whole, they have reacted by building up their operations in London, rather than scaling them down.</p>
<p>He noted German institutions such as Deutsche Bank and Dresdner Bank which have made acquisitions in London and moved in lock, stock and barrel. U.S. and other foreign banks have also tended to establish European headquarters in London.</p>
<p>&quot;They have done so, I think, because they calculate that the competitive advantage of London as a financial centre will not be negated by the arrival of EMU, whether or not Britain is immediately a member.&quot;</p>
<p>Turning to the potential loss of inward investment should Britain shun EMU, Davies noted an increase in European Union investment in Britain in recent years.</p>
<p>&quot;The scale of EU investment in British manufacturing is now quite dramatic. The number of big EU multinationals producing in Britain increased from 13 to to 27 between 1986 and 1993.&quot;</p>
<p>In terms of monetary and fiscal policy, Davies said Britain's three major political parties all now endorsed an anti-inflation policy and non-membership of EMU would not be seen as a licence to run a monetary policy at variance with its trading partners.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
