<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="470425" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: BA,Iberia talks on hold for American deal approval.</title>
<headline>BA,Iberia talks on hold for American deal approval.</headline>
<byline>Merissa Marr</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Airways is continuing talks with Spain's Iberia airline on a possible alliance, but cannot finalise a deal until after BA's link-up with American Airlines is approved, an Iberia source said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The European Commission is currently studying a proposed alliance between BA and American that would give the two airlines control of 61 percent of passenger traffic between Britain and the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;Iberia is in ongoing talks with BA, but BA can go no further until it finds out whether its alliance with American Airlines has been approved,&quot; the source told Reuters.</p>
<p>The source said BA has told Iberia that it cannot make a decision before April.</p>
<p>European Union sources predict, however, that the Commission will take no action on the BA-American deal until after the British general election on May 1. The proposed alliance has run into strong opposition from some commissioners who argue it would eliminate competition on a number of routes.</p>
<p>Spanish state holding company SEPI, Iberia's parent, is particularly eager for Iberia to join BA's proposed alliance with AMR Corp's American Airlines, the source said.</p>
<p>British Airways declined to comment on the talks.</p>
<p>&quot;We talk to a whole range of different airlines about a whole range of subjects and more often than not they come to nothing,&quot; a BA spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>British Airways has also shown interest in investing in Iberia when it is privatised, the Iberia source said.</p>
<p>&quot;BA is interested in taking a stake, which could mean one of two things: either it is interested in an alliance or a takeover considering the size of Iberia,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>However, the Spanish government is unlikely to allow foreign interests to take a large stake in the airline. &quot;BA's stake could be around 10 to 20 percent, but no more,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>BA again declined to comment.</p>
<p>KLM has also shown interest in investing in the Spanish airline after privatisation, the source added.</p>
<p>Iberia is eager to start its privatisation process so it can join in the wave of airline alliances.</p>
<p>Spanish law requires Iberia to earn a profit three years in a row before it can be privatised. The Iberia source said the government could therefore sell off the airline as early as July 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;Iberia also wants as much of the airline privatised as possible, but the government is likely to want to hold on to a sizeable share at the beginning,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>The airline could speed up the process with a capital increase that could then be issued to the public, the source said.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom + 34 1 585 2161</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
