<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="470690" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UNO makes offer for World of Leather.</title>
<headline>UNO makes offer for World of Leather.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>UNO Plc, the specialist retailer of upholstered furniture, said on Wednesday it had made a recommended offer for World of Leather Plc valuing the company at approximately 14.27 million stg.</p>
<p>World of Leather, one of the largest specialist leather upholstered furniture retailers in England and Wales, said it had recommended the offer.</p>
<p>The offer, on the basis of 0.43542 of a new UNO share for each World of Leather share, values each World of Leather share at 118 pence, the companies said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>This represents a premium of around 41.2 percent over the share price of 83.5 pence on Monday -- the day before World of Leather announced it was in talks over a possible offer.</p>
<p>The full cash alternative prices World of Leather at 108 pence per share.</p>
<p>The acquisition will help the enlarged group &quot;compete more effectively in the UK upholstered furniture market,&quot; said Paul Rosenblatt, chairman and chief executive of UNO.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the offer from UNO is fair and reasonable and consequently we are recommending our shareholders to accept the offer,&quot; said Richard Taylor, joint managing director and finance director of World of Leather.</p>
<p>World of Leather also reported annual results showing pretax profits for the year to December 31 of 1.03 million stg, against a loss of 517,000 stg the previous year. It proposed a total dividend of 2.0 pence per share, up from 1.6 pence.</p>
<p>World of Leather shares were trading 18-1/2 pence higher at 110 pence at 0830 GMT.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 4365</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
