<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="470750" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian dollar pulls back some pre-FOMC losses.</title>
<headline>Australian dollar pulls back some pre-FOMC losses.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar made a partial recovery of some heavy overnight losses on Wednesday but found itself wedged in by good two way trading after the U.S. FOMC meeting proved something of an anticlimax, traders said.</p>
<p>The dollar was sold down in New York to US$0.7800, its lowest level in a month, ahead of the meeting on rumours of an Australian credit downgrade and reports of a bearish assessment of the Australian dollar's prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;Either one of those sort of things is not necessarily enough to get the (Aussie) moving, but obviously all three of them last night gave it a bit of a push,&quot; one bank trader said.  </p>
<p>By 4.45 p.m. (0545 GMT) the dollar was at US$0.7822/32, down on an opening US$0.7825/35 and a Tuesday close of US$0.7887/92.</p>
<p>The dollar had traded to a low of US$0.7800 in the New York selloff, and was near US$0.7810 prior to the FOMC decision. On the day it traded to a high of US$0.7842/47, where it ran into some Asian selling, but on dips to around US$0.7820 it found good demand led by exporters.</p>
<p>The FOMC decision to lift the Fed Funds rate by 25 points to 5.50 percent had been widely anticipated, and was expected to lead to some short term weakness in the Australian dollar due to narrowing interest rate differentials.  </p>
<p>However, the market had already unwound long positions on the rumours, subsequently denied, that Australia's sovereign credit rating may be under examination by Moody's Investors Service, and also on an bearish newspaper report on the research paper on the Australian dollar by a research arm of Standard and Poor's, DRI/McGraw Hill.</p>
<p>A Moody's official said Australia was not on Creditwatch and did not have a negative outlook.</p>
<p>The newspaper article labelled the Australian dollar a high risk currency, but the research paper said the overall medium term assessment was one of very low risk.  </p>
<p>The report, using mid February as a reference point which was when the Australian dollar was in a downtrend at US$0.76, did increase the risk of a 25 percent depreciation in the dollar over the next year to 15 percent from 10 percent, and over a five year period to 45 percent from 43 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The risk of a currency decline large enough to meet our threshold is low, however,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Although subsquently discounted by local traders who saw the the New York selling as presenting a good buying opportunity, the report had affected offshore sentiment.  </p>
<p>&quot;I'm not totally bearish today, I think eventually we're going to recover a little bit, it's just a little bit overdone to me,&quot; the bank trader said. &quot;But longer term we may have seen a top put in place for the next month or so. Certainly US$0.7910, I think, looks a long way away now.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said the U.S. rate hike should have no impact on domestic policy settings, and the narrowing of the rate differential advantage should only be a short term negative.</p>
<p>Australia's official cash rate is seen as being on hold at 6.00 percent for at least most of this year, with a rise in rates is expected in late 1997 or the first half of 1998.  </p>
<p>&quot;Domestic cash rates will be determined by domestic factors,&quot; ANZ Securities chief economist Phil Graham said. &quot;Rate increases are still a long way off -- we think until 1998.&quot;</p>
<p>Treasurer Peter Costello told parliament that the inflation rate, which the Reserve Bank has indicated it expects to remain low for the foreseeable future, was the key to local rates.</p>
<p>Investors were also not expected to divest themselves of Australian dollar assets because of rising U.S. rates, particularly in Japan where Australia still held a sizeable yield advantage. As well, the prospects of stronger U.S. growth was a long term positive for the currency.  </p>
<p>&quot;To the extent to which the US tightening cycle points to stronger world growth...and higher commodity prices, well then I would certainly argue strongly against those who believe the Australian dollar's run of support has come to an end,&quot; Macquarie Bank senior economist Richard Gibbs said.</p>
<p>On the cross rates, the Australian dollar finished at 97.06/16 yen and 1.3202/23 marks, from an opening 96.82/92 and 1.3217/32 and local closes on Tuesday of 97.25/35 and 1.3301/11. In trade weighted terms, it ended at 60.4, up a notch on its opening 60.3, but down on Tuesday's closing 60.7.</p>
<p>-- John Mair Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
