<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="470738" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAPUA NEW GUINEA: PNG premier faces crunch vote in parliament.</title>
<headline>PNG premier faces crunch vote in parliament.</headline>
<byline>Michael Perry</byline>
<dateline>PORT MORESBY 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Embattled Papua New Guinea Prime Minister Sir Julius Chan faced a fresh challenge in parliament on Wednesday as armed soldiers and protesters blockaded the building.</p>
<p>Opposition leaders who failed on Tuesday to push through a parliamentary motion calling on Chan and two senior ministers to quit were pushing for another vote later on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The motion would not be binding on Chan because elections are due in three months, but it would increase pressure for him to quit over a failed plan to use mercenaries against rebels on Bougainville island.</p>
<p>&quot;He cannot escape,&quot; Port Moresby governor Bill Skate told Reuters. &quot;We will hound him until he resigns -- we're not going anywhere and those people out there will not go away until he quits.&quot;</p>
<p>The motion, slightly stronger than Tuesday's, called for Chan, Deputy Prime Minister Chris Haiveta and Defence Minister Mathias Ijape to resign &quot;to defuse the situation and so allow parliament and the people to return to normality&quot;.</p>
<p>Chan was nowhere to be seen. The embattled prime minister slipped out of parliament after Tuesday's vote although officials said he would return.</p>
<p>As PNG's 10-day crisis -- which has preoccupied its South Pacific neighbours -- intensified, Governor-General Sir Wiwa Korowi appealed for soldiers to return to barracks.</p>
<p>&quot;Let us not take to the streets to destroy the nation,&quot; Korowi said in a national radio address.</p>
<p>About 80 heavily armed soldiers and thousands of anti-government protestors beseiged the parliament building overnight, preventing politicans from leaving. By noon on Wednesday around 30 soldiers remained with some 2,000 protesters chanting &quot;resign Chan, resign&quot;.</p>
<p>Shops, banks and other businesses which were closed on Tuesday amid the political upheaval were reopening on Wednesday and public transport was returning to normal.</p>
<p>Korowi, who as the official representative of titular head of state Queen Elizabeth wields considerable influence, has already called on Chan to step aside.</p>
<p>In his national address, he said he understood that many people felt frustrated and wanted to take to the streets to burn cars, damage property and fight but the cost was too high.</p>
<p>&quot;No matter what amount of evil we think they have committed, your confrontation directly with the parliament and its members will not help and I appeal to the Papua New Guinea Defence Force as your commander-in-chief to move back to barracks this morning,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;What you have done overnight by holding the members of parliament under siege is dangerous, now get back to your barracks,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Korowi also appealed for sacked army commander, Jerry Singirok, to hand over control of the defence force to the new commander, Colonel Jack Tuat. He called on Singirok to &quot;hand over graciously command of the defence forces&quot;.</p>
<p>Singirok was dismissed last week after turning on Chan and demanding his resignation of the $36 million mercenary contract with Sandline International. The contract fell apart amid violent street protests and the mercenaries, except for their British commander, were expelled.</p>
<p>Singirok told Australian radio he did not take responsiblity for soldiers joining the protest and said troops had only been at parliament to assist police.</p>
<p>&quot;The demonstration that you have seen outside the parliament is the people's voice,&quot; he said. &quot;Politicians must now understand the reality: the people have the power.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT MORESBY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAPUA NEW GUINEA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
