<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47073" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Motorola says earnings may be below previous quarter.</title>
<headline>Motorola says earnings may be below previous quarter.</headline>
<dateline>SCHAUMBURG, Ill. 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Motorola Inc.'s stock was hammered Wednesday after the maker of electronic equipment and components said its quarterly earnings would be lower than the previous period.</p>
<p>Motorola, which makes cellular telephones and computer equipment such as semiconductors and integrated circuits, also said its earnings would be lower than Wall Street analysts had projected.</p>
<p>In early trading Wednesday on the Instanet system, Motorola fell to $46 a share, down from its close Tuesday at $50.75 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>In a news release, Motorola said its earnings in the third quarter, which ends Sept. 28, would likely lag the second quarter, when it earned $326 million, or 54 cents a share, on sales of $6.83 billion.</p>
<p>According to First Call, which tracks analysts' earnings estimates, Motorola had been expected to earn 50 cents a share in the current quarter.</p>
<p>Noting that the semiconductor industry remained in a &quot;down cycle,&quot; Motorola said the most significant factor affecting the results was poor demand and low prices in its semicondoctor division.</p>
<p>Price pressure also continued in the cellular telephone, paging and modem businesses, Motorola said, and in international markets, orders and sales have weakened.</p>
<p>Gary Tooker, vice chairman and chief executive officer, said many of Motorola's units have taken steps to reduce expenses, including hiring restrictions and reductions in work schedules and manufacturing run rates, and reducing capital expenditures, especially in the semiconductor products sector.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SCHAUMBURG, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
