<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="470724" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Blair promises no return to unionism of the 1970s.</title>
<headline>Blair promises no return to unionism of the 1970s.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Reaney</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>British opposition leader Tony Blair, ahead in opionion polls to win the country's May 1 election, promised on Wednesday there will be no return to the trade union problems of the 1970s if he is elected prime minister.</p>
<p>In an article in The Daily Mail newspaper, he refuted Prime Minister John Major's claims that a Labour government could lead to renewed powers of the &quot;overmighty&quot; trade unions that would threaten Britain's industrial prosperity.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no return to the trade union laws of the 1970s. Laws banning secondary and flying pickets, on secondary action, union elections -- on all the essential elements of the 1980s laws -- will stay,&quot; he wrote, referring to law introduced to curb the power of the unions.</p>
<p>&quot;The Conservatives have attacked this in the most hysterical terms,&quot; Blair added.</p>
<p>Major pushed the union issue to the top of the political agenda in the second week of campaigning, warning that a Labour government would threaten Britain's hard-won reputation.</p>
<p>&quot;One Labour government could destroy our ability to attract massive investment from all over the world and put thousands of jobs at risk: 18 years of progress surrendered in 18 months of Labour in power,&quot; Major wrote in The Birmingham Post on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Make no mistake. If Labour and the unions win, Britain loses.&quot;</p>
<p>Rekindling memories of the crippling public sector strikes in the late 1970s, Major said Britain had the best industrial relations for 100 years and warned it would all disappear under a a Labour government.</p>
<p>&quot;Every business would be a potential target for the union campaigns,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday Labour economics spokesman Gordon Brown revealed plans for a third party, or judge, to arbitrate in disputes between workers and management over how union recognition would work.</p>
<p>&quot;The management would, quite simply, have their hands tied. If they disagreed with the union, Labour would have an outsider resolve the situation,&quot; said Major.</p>
<p>But Blair dismissed the prime minister's predictions of doom, saying Labour's policy was broadly based on the U.S. example where 12 million new job have been created since President Bill Clinton took office.</p>
<p>Far from reverting back to the old bosses-and-workers conflicts, Blair said his party would &quot;concentrate on issues of the future -- education, skills, technology, science and innovation, the things that build jobs and industry we will need in the 21st century.&quot;</p>
<p>Labour also announced on Tuesday that it would postpone publishing its election manifesto so it will not clash with the release of the Conservatives' proposals.</p>
<p>Labour campaign manager Peter Mandelson said Labour will unveil their document one day later than planned. He claimed the Conservatives had wanted to use Labour's launch as a smokescreen for their manifesto.</p>
<p>&quot;So we are moving our manifesto launch to Thursday April 3,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
