<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="471093" id="root" date="1997-03-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul buses on strike; first stoppage under new law.</title>
<headline>Seoul buses on strike; first stoppage under new law.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Public bus drivers in Seoul and two other major South Korean cities went on strike on Wednesday to back demands for higher wages, leaving tens of thousands of commuters stranded.</p>
<p>Only about two percent of Seoul's 8,700 buses were operating, municipal officials said.</p>
<p>The cities of Inchon and Taejon were also hit by the first wildcat strikes since a new labour came into force this month.</p>
<p>South Korea was hit by a month of strikes following the passage of an earlier version of the labour law on December 26. The strikes forced President Kim Young-sam to return the bill to parliament for revision.</p>
<p>Wednesday's strikes were the first industrial action linked to this year's annual pay round, which kicked off this month and usually lasts until May.</p>
<p>Government officials said they would deal sternly with striking bus workers, saying the industrial action was illegal since it violated a provision calling for a mandatory two-week &quot;cooling off&quot; period.</p>
<p>The original labour bill allowed companies to lay off workers and banned a militant umbrella union group until 2000.</p>
<p>Its replacement delayed implementation of the controversial lay-off clause for two years. It also recognised immediately the formerly outlawed Korean Confederation of Trade Unions that organised the January strikes.</p>
<p>Government officials said Seoul bus unions were demanding a 13 percent wage increase and an additional half-month bonus payment a year.</p>
<p>Management wants to peg wage rises to fare hikes, which have yet to be fixed and require government approval.</p>
<p>Bus unions in three other cities were originally due to join the strike on Wednesday. But drivers in Pusan, the nation's second largest city, and Taegu reached settlements early in the day and union leaders in Kwangju agreed to continue negotiations.</p>
<p>Traffic snarled in Seoul as many citizens drove to work. Subway trains were overflowing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
