<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="471536" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Sudan rebels say aiming for key road in east Sudan.</title>
<headline>Sudan rebels say aiming for key road in east Sudan.</headline>
<byline>Peter Smerdon</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sudanese rebels said on Thursday they were on the offensive in the east of the vast African country to cut the main road from Khartoum to Port Sudan.</p>
<p>The Sudanese army earlier said Eritrean troops and Sudanese rebels were shelling Sudan army positions on Eritrea's border but the rebels denied any Eritrean forces were involved.</p>
<p>&quot;Our forces in the last 48 hours were ordered to start an operation with the aim of interrupting traffic on the Khartoum -Port Sudan road to make it unuseable,&quot; said Sampson Kwaje, a spokesman for the rebel Sudan People's Liberation Army (SPLA).</p>
<p>&quot;There are no Eritreans involved, absolutely none. The forces fighting there are 100 percent SPLA plus forces from the National Democratic Alliance (NDA), mainly the Beja Congress,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>SPLA commander John Garang told Reuters in January part of rebel strategy was to cut communications between Khartoum and Port Sudan on the Red Sea, Sudan's main commercial link with the rest of the world.</p>
<p>In Khartoum, army spokesman Lieutenant-General Mohamed al-Senoussi Ahmed said: &quot;Since the early hours of Wednesday the Eritrean forces and a group of the outlaws started shelling the army advance posts in Garoura and Itairba.&quot;</p>
<p>The general said the attackers planned to control border areas of eastern Sudan. &quot;Our troops are mounting a tough resistance to thwart the intentions of the enemy,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The exact location of the border posts was not immediately clear but the small town of Karora lies just inside Sudan and about 40 km (25 miles) from the Red Sea coast. Sudanese place names are often transliterated in many different ways.</p>
<p>The SPLA spokesman confirmed the fighting was in the Karora area.</p>
<p>Northern rebels of the opposition NDA opposition coalition attacked the army on the Sudanese side of the Eritrean border in January but the offensive failed to win much territory.</p>
<p>Rebel units further south, led by the southern-based SPLA, captured the Sudanese towns of Kurmuk and Qeissan on the Ethiopian border in an attack coordinated with the northerners.</p>
<p>The Sudanese government said Eritrean and Ethiopian forces did most of the fighting in both attacks but the two countries, despite poor relations with Khartoum, said their troops had no role.</p>
<p>The campaign against the Islamist government shifted this month to the far south, where the SPLA captured the town of Yei and began to advance towards the city of Juba, the capital of the south.</p>
<p>Khartoum says Ugandan troops are fighting in the south but the Ugandan government has denied this.</p>
<p>A Sudanese member of parliament from eastern Sudan was quoted on Thursday as saying that Eritrean forces had been massing east of Tokar, a town about 100 km (60 miles) northeast of Karora, with plans to open a new front on the Red Sea coast.</p>
<p>The SPLA has been fighting since 1983 for greater autonomy or independence for the Christian and animist south from the Moslem and Arabised north. It and its allies say they want a popular uprising in Khartoum against the Islamist government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ERTRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
