<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="471523" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Saudi bomb suspect has initial hearing in Canada.</title>
<headline>Saudi bomb suspect has initial hearing in Canada.</headline>
<byline>Randall Palmer</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Canadian judge held an initial hearing on Thursday into the case of a Saudi dissident wanted for questioning by the United States regarding last June's bombing in Saudi Arabia that killed 19 U.S. airmen.</p>
<p>A Federal Court spokeswoman said the results of the closed-door hearing regarding Hani Abdel-Rahim Hussein al-Sayegh were due to be made public in the late afternoon.</p>
<p>Authorities arrested Sayegh last week in Ottawa using a &quot;security certificate,&quot; a document signed by two government ministers saying he represented a security risk to Canada.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman said that unless the judge ruled Sayegh should be freed immediately, a further hearing would be required to determine whether he was a security risk.</p>
<p>Immigration Minister Lucienne Robillard made it clear last week that, given her priority of ensuring the safety of Canadians, she could deport those deemed to be security risks.</p>
<p>Sayegh, a Shi'ite Moslem who undertook religious studies in Iran, told reporters on Monday he was in self-imposed exile in Syria when the bomb went off outside a military housing complex near Dhahran, Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>He said he was scared to go back to Saudi Arabia because of the treatment of Shi'ites by its Sunni Moslem rulers but he denied involvement in the bombing or in any organisations. He was not present at the hearing on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Iranian Embassy in Ottawa issued a statement on Wednesday night denying any links with Sayegh or the bombing. It referred to a March 25 New York Times article that quoted a senior U.S. administration official who said part of the evidence against Sayegh was &quot;the contacts he apparently had with Iranian diplomats in Canada.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The embassy of the Islamic Republic of Iran in Ottawa finds those accusations totally baseless and categorically denies any contact under any circumstances between the Iranian diplomats in Canada and the said suspect,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;The embassy ... reiterates the position of its government in condemning all forms of terrorism by whoever and for whatever purposes, and further reiterates that it has not had any involvement in any sort or fashion with the bombing incident in Saudi Arabia.&quot;</p>
<p>Sayegh arrived on a flight that stopped in Boston. It was conceivable Canada could use that as a reason to deport him to the United States if he were found to be a security risk.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
