<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="471628" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bosnian Serb president critisised by colleagues.</title>
<headline>Bosnian Serb president critisised by colleagues.</headline>
<byline>Dan De Luce</byline>
<dateline>PALE, Bosnia 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bosnian Serb President Biljana Plavsic has come under attack from other Serb leaders after raising questions about war profiteering and criticising a cooperation pact between Bosnia's Serb entity and neighbouring Yugoslavia, diplomats say.</p>
<p>Leading members of the ruling Serb Democratic Party (SDS) are trying to rein in Plavsic, an academic who became president after indicted war criminal Radovan Karadzic was forced to step down in peacetime, and isolate her within the Bosnian Serb government.</p>
<p>A cabinet reshuffle this month removed two ministers who were based in the northern city of Banja Luka, where Plavsic's offices are also located.</p>
<p>The reshuffle meant the entire cabinet was now based in the government seat of Pale, outside Sarajevo. &quot;That leaves her all alone in Banja Luka,&quot; said one diplomat, who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>The Radical party, which is allied with the ruling SDS, has also called for the Bosnian Serb assembly to hold a recall vote against Plavsic.</p>
<p>Serb political sources described the proposal as a warning shot across Plavsic's bow to discourage her from stepping out of line with the SDS leadership.</p>
<p>Diplomats said they encountered a &quot;crisis atmosphere&quot; in Plavsic's offices last week, underscoring the power struggle.</p>
<p>Although Plavsic shares the ultra-nationalist sentiments of other party leaders, she ran into political trouble because she failed to submit completely to the authority of her associates in Pale, diplomats said.</p>
<p>The former biology professor has never been seen as a powerful figure in Serb territory. Her rival, Momcilo Krajisnik, the Serb member of the Bosnian inter-ethnic collective presidency, wields strong influence over the Serb police and state media.</p>
<p>Plavsic ran afoul of Bosnian Serb leaders when she publicly refused to support the cooperation agreement signed in Belgrade this month.</p>
<p>Plavsic, who was not invited to the signing ceremony, questioned its legality and told a newspaper there should have been a public debate before the signing.</p>
<p>But Western diplomats and political sources say her real complaint was that she should have signed the pact as the highest official in Serb territory. Krajisnik signed the agreement on behalf of Bosnia's Serb republic.</p>
<p>Plavsic, unlike Krajisnik, has also come out clearly in support of opposition parties in neighbouring Serbia who led a campaign of street protests demanding recognition of opposition victories in local elections.</p>
<p>Krajisnik has chosen to take a more cautious approach towards opponents of Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic, the longtime patron of the Bosnian Serbs who forced them to accept territorial concessions in a U.S.-brokered peace treaty.</p>
<p>Denying any disagreement inside the leadership, Krajisnik was quoted by Pale television on Wednesday as saying enemies of the Serb people were spreading propaganda to &quot;destabilise&quot; the Serb republic.</p>
<p>Plavsic first irritated Krajisnik when she called for an investigation into alleged corruption by two Serb companies suspected of avoiding taxes while reaping big profits on oil, cigarette, alcohol and coffee imports during the Bosnian war.</p>
<p>Political sources in the Serb government seat of Pale said they expected nothing to come from Plavsic's request. Such an investigation would have to be conducted by the same officials linked to the alleged corruption, analysts said.</p>
<p>Opposition political parties and officers in the Bosnian Serb army frequently accused Serb civilian leaders of growing rich from the spoils of war while ordinary people struggled to survive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALE, Bosnia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
