<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="471799" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>PUERTO RICO: Puerto Rico moves to ban bungee jumping.</title>
<headline>Puerto Rico moves to ban bungee jumping.</headline>
<dateline>SAN JUAN, Puerto Rico 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Engineers inspected bungee jumping operations and carnival rides in Puerto Rico on Thursday and lawmakers moved to ban the pastime after the death of a 17-year-old jumper last week.</p>
<p>Lawmakers have filed three separate bills in Puerto Rico's legislature this week that would make bungee jumping a crime. At this same time, the mayor of San Juan announced she was writing an ordinance to outlaw bungee jumping in the city.</p>
<p>The bills were spurred by the death on March 22 of Roberto Lopez Carrasquillo, who crashed to the ground while bungee jumping at the Ciudad Mecanica carnival in San Juan.</p>
<p>Carnival officials say the cord tied to Lopez Carrasquillo's leg apparently snapped during the 90-foot (27.43 metre) fall.</p>
<p>&quot;Bungee jumping is a high-risk activity and it isn't the first time that a tragedy occurred,&quot; said Senate president Charlie Rodriguez, who filed one of the bills. &quot;We can't allow in Puerto Rico that people keep on putting their lives at risk by flinging themselves into the air.&quot;</p>
<p>Rodriguez's bill proposed up to six months in jail and fines of up to $500 for operators of bungee jumping equipment. A tougher measure filed in the House would impose up to three years in jail for jump operators and fines of $10,000 for operators and $2,000 for jumpers.</p>
<p>The San Juan district attorney's office was investigating the fatal jump of Lopez Carrasquillo, who was buried on Monday.</p>
<p>Ciudad Mecanica promoter Carlos Garcia said the jump operator, Texas-based Bungee Plunge Inc., changed the rope after every 800 jumps. Lopez Carrasquillo's jump was number 722 for the rope, Garcia said.</p>
<p>San Juan Safety Commissioner Jorge Collazo, ordered the closure of seven bungee machines on the island.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt we will get this municipal ordinance approved (to ban bungee jumping),&quot; Collazo said. &quot;We've gotten a lot of support from all over the island.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PURI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN JUAN, Puerto Rico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PUERTO RICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
