<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="471705" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Poland to pick international bond leader in mid-Ap.</title>
<headline>Poland to pick international bond leader in mid-Ap.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland has started work on this year's first international bond issue and expects to pick a lead manager by mid-April, a senior finance ministry official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have started preparations for the first planned international treasury bond...and the choice of the lead manager should be expected in the first half of April,&quot; Wieslaw Szczuka told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;There are several banks we are negotiating with,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Szczuka said the issue was likely to take place in late June or early in July but the ministry has yet to decide where and how much of the bonds would be placed.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible that, the issue will be on the U.S. market but the final decision will depend on market conditions in a period shortly prior to the placement,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The 1997 budget set a $500 million limit on international bond issues this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue size is not determined...the budget sets the limit for all issues this year and we don't know yet how big this one will be,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier this year the ministry has said it was mulling yankee and samurai bond issues after two successful Eurobond issues in 1995 and 1996.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Belka last month said Poland would continue its strategy of placing limited international bond issues to continue its presence on international capital markets and maintain a benchmark for commercial borrowers.</p>
<p>Poland returned to the international capital market two years ago after striking a crucial debt restructuring deal with foreign commercial banks.</p>
<p>Poland's sovereign debt currently has a B-minus Standard &amp; Poor's rating, Baa3 from Moody's Investors Service and BBB from IBCA.</p>
<p>-- Jacek Ramotowski +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
