<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="471869" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: IDBI director positive on bank's outlook.</title>
<headline>IDBI director positive on bank's outlook.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The outlook for Industrial Development Bank of India is favourable despite recent softness in the Indian economy and increasing competition, executive director P.S. Subramanyam said Thursday.</p>
<p>He said IDBI should post slightly better results for the year ended March 1997 than for the prior year.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect that the results for the year ending 31 March 1997 would be a shade better, even though we passed through a year of slowing down of the economy that gets factored into all constituents, such as the financial institutions and the banks,&quot; Subramanyam told Reuters.</p>
<p>IDBI posted net profits of 10.07 billion rupees in the year ended March 1996.</p>
<p>The director said he was positive on the Indian economy going forward. He said the 1997/98 budget, with its combination of tax cuts and regulatory changes, set the stage for &quot;a major spurt in investments through appropriate increases in savings.&quot;</p>
<p>Subramanyam said he was not worried about competition to IDBI from India's commercial banks, partly because there is so much long-term investment that needs to be done in India.</p>
<p>&quot;The estimated funding requirements of (the industrial) sectors are so large that the government has stipulated that at least 60 percent of the funding requirements of these projects should be met by external sources and 40 percent by the Indian financial institutions and banks,&quot; said Subramanyam.</p>
<p>&quot;So for the next five to 10 years, I don't see any threat to coexistence of financial institutions and banks in the Indian scene,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Securities analysts have warned that India's development financial institutions could find their margins squeezed as they face increasing competition from the commercial bank sector.</p>
<p>Subramanyam pointed out that commercial banks are subjected to certain rules, such as reserve requirements and directed lending, which the development banks need not follow.</p>
<p>He also said the the development institutions are better placed to lend to industrial projects because they raise long-term funding, whereas the commercial banks rely on short-term deposits.</p>
<p>&quot;Typically, commercial banks would not like to borrow short and then lend to industrial investments when they do quite a bit more business...providing increasing requirements of working capital to industries,&quot; said Subramanyam.</p>
<p>IDBI recently launched a seven-year US$150 million floating rate note issue through lead manager Merrill Lynch International's Hong Kong office.</p>
<p>The notes pay a margin of 60 basis points over the six-month London Interbank Offered Rate and were launched and re-offered at 99.460 to give a fixed re-offer yield of 70 basis points.</p>
<p>Bankers in Hong Kong have been generally positive on the issue, saying the priced accurately reflected the market for Indian debt.</p>
<p>&quot;The deal was priced correctly. It wasn't a blow-out and there's still plenty left but it's the most realistically priced Indian deal we've seen in a while,&quot; remarked one banker.</p>
<p>&quot;We like it. I think we are going to take a piece,&quot; said another syndicate manager in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Subramanyam said he was pleased with the FRN's reception.</p>
<p>-- Andrea Ricci (852) 2843-6371</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
