<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47214" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: United TransNet sees Q3 profit below views.</title>
<headline>United TransNet sees Q3 profit below views.</headline>
<dateline>ROSWELL, Ga. 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>United TransNet Inc said Wednesday it expects earnings for the third quarter ending September 28 will be below analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>First Call estimates predict per-share net income of $0.15 per share. The company became publicly traded in December 1995, and no year-ago information was applicable.</p>
<p>The company said results for the quarter are expected to include losses from its South Central region where United TransNet is restructuring its operations and reducing personnel and facilities.</p>
<p>The company said operational problems identified in the second quarter have been met with &quot;a number of corrective measures,&quot; most notably a change in the management in the South Central region.</p>
<p>&quot;These measures have begun to produce the intended results, but progress has been slower than anticipated,&quot; said Philip Belyew, president and chief executive officer, in a statement accompanying the announcement.</p>
<p>&quot;We are working aggressively to reduce costs and we expect to see positive results by the end of this calendar year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Seperately, the company also announced it reached a definitive agreement to merge with Corporate Express Inc, which it expects to complete before the end of calendar 1996.</p>
<p>--New York Newsdesk  (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROSWELL, Ga."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
