<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="472423" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gore China trip vindicates U.S. policy - Clinton.</title>
<headline>Gore China trip vindicates U.S. policy - Clinton.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton said on Thursday he believed Vice President Al Gore's visit to China had gone well and validated his administration's policy of engagement with Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that the trip has been a real validation for our strategy of engagement with China, of taking our agreements, our disagreements ... directly to them,&quot; Clinton said in response to a question at a White House event on health care.</p>
<p>Clinton told reporters he had spoken to Gore on Thursday morning, adding: &quot;He is very pleased with the results so far and I certainly am very pleased with the work he's done.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I'm encouraged about it, I think the trip has been well worth making,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The most senior U.S. official to visit China since the crackdown on student demonstrations in Beijing in 1989, Gore's talks with Chinese leaders covered a wide range of tricky topics including human rights, trade disputes and Taiwan.</p>
<p>Gore also told the Chinese an investigation into reports China tried to make donations to U.S. politicians should not affect Sino-U.S. relations -- but would be a serious matter if such charges were proved. China has denied the allegations.</p>
<p>Clinton made no reference to the fund-raising controversy nor to Gore's public relations difficulties during the visit, which included one Gore aide contradicting another on what the vice president had told the Chinese on the controversy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
