<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="472467" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: N.Y. nursing aide jailed for rape of coma victim.</title>
<headline>N.Y. nursing aide jailed for rape of coma victim.</headline>
<dateline>ROCHESTER, N.Y. 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former nursing assistant convicted of raping a comatose patient who later gave birth to a baby boy was jailed on Thursday for the maximum term of up to 25 years.</p>
<p>Before sentencing, state prosecutor Jerry Solomon read a letter to the court from the victim's mother, who wrote: &quot;He needs to be bound and gagged and raped repeatedly ... please also make sure he can never make claim to my baby.&quot;</p>
<p>State Supreme Court Judge Donald Mark, calling John Horace &quot;a sexual predator,&quot; sentenced him to between eight years and four months and 25 years on his conviction for rape and two years and four months to seven years for sexual abuse.</p>
<p>The sentences would run concurrently but prosecutors vowed to petition the parole board to keep Horace, 53, jailed for the maximum time should he become eligible for parole.</p>
<p>A jury ruled in February that Horace raped the woman in August 1995 while working as a nursing assistant at the Westfall Health Care Facility in the Rochester suburb of Brighton, New York.</p>
<p>The woman, identified to the public only as Kathy, later gave birth to a baby boy, who is being raised by her mother. The woman, in a coma for 11 years after a car accident while a student at Cornell University, died 10 days ago, aged 30.</p>
<p>Horace's lawyer Yolanda Villa said her client would appeal the conviction and sentencing. &quot;It is my humble opinion that John Horace is not the monster he has been made out to be,&quot; she said, arguing, as she had done during the trial, that no proof was offered at the trial that a rape actually occurred.</p>
<p>&quot;Pregnancy does not equal sexual intercourse,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Prosecuting attorneys based their case on DNA evidence that showed more than 99 percent probability that Horace was the father of the child. Authorities collected blood and saliva samples from an envelope Horace licked and compared them with the baby's blood and amniotic fluid from the womb.</p>
<p>Horace, who worked at the nursing home for six weeks, has already served time for two other sex crimes. Last year he pleaded guilty to impersonating a physician at a &quot;sex therapy clinic&quot; and was convicted of fondling another Westfall patient, a 49-year-old suffering from multiple sclerosis.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROCHESTER, N.Y."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
