<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="472690" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Chronology of events in India-Pakistan relations.</title>
<headline>Chronology of events in India-Pakistan relations.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here is a chronology of major events involving arch-rivals India and Pakistan, which are due to resume talks in New Delhi on Friday after a three-year gap.</p>
<p>Oct 27, 1947: War breaks out between Indian and Pakistani troops in the disputed Himalayan region of Kashmir, barely two months after their independence from Britain.</p>
<p>January 1, 1949: Ceasefire, ordered by the United Nations Security Council, takes effect in Kashmir.</p>
<p>Sept 6-22, 1965: Full-scale India-Pakistan war over Kashmir, which ends after a U.N. call for ceasefire.</p>
<p>Jan 3, 1966: Indian Prime Minister Lal Bahadur Shastri and Pakistani President Ayub Khan sign a Soviet-mediated peace pact in Tashkent, then part of the Soviet Uzbek republic.</p>
<p>Dec 3-17, 1971: India-Pakistan war over East Pakistan (later Bangladesh) which ends after 90,000 Pakistani troops surrender.</p>
<p>July 2, 1972: Indian Prime Minister Indira Gandhi and counterpart Zulfikar Ali Bhutto sign a peace accord in Simla.</p>
<p>May 18, 1974: India holds an underground nuclear test which it says is for its atomic energy programme, not weapons.</p>
<p>Nov 1, 1982: Indira Gandhi and Pakistani President Mohammad Zia-ul-Haq agree to begin talks on a non-aggression treaty.</p>
<p>June 4, 1983: India-Pakistan Joint Commission meets for the first time to discuss bilateral cooperation.</p>
<p>Jan 20, 1986: Talks between the foreign secretaries of India and Pakistan end inconclusively in Islamabad. But both agree on &quot;desirability&quot; of peace treaty and non-aggression pact.</p>
<p>Dec 31, 1988: India and Pakistan sign agreement not to attack each other's nuclear facilities.</p>
<p>Feb 5, 1989: Pakistan army chief General Mirza Aslam Beg says Pakistan has successfully test-fired its first long-range surface-to-surface rockets, named Hatf-1 and Hatf-2.</p>
<p>July 16-17, 1989: Indian Prime Minister Rajiv Gandhi and counterpart Benazir Bhutto clash publicly on Kashmir and Pakistan's nuclear programme during a meeting of the South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation (SAARC) in Islamabad.</p>
<p>Feb 6, 1992: Pakistan says it has acquired know-how to make a nuclear bomb, but has decided not to do so.</p>
<p>March 28, 1993: India accuses Pakistan of plotting March 12 Bombay bombs that killed 260 people. Pakistan denies charges.</p>
<p>Oct 25, 1993: Foreign secretaries of Pakistan and India meet in Cyprus during Commonwealth Summit and agree to resume talks.</p>
<p>Jan 1-3, 1994: Foreign secretaries fail to narrow differences on Kashmir. Pakistan rules out more talks unless India stops alleged human rights violations in Kashmir.</p>
<p>Jan 26, 1994: India submits six &quot;non-papers&quot; proposing confidence-building measures, including a pledge it would not be the first to make a nuclear strike. Pakistan says the proposals fail to address the basic dispute over Kashmir.</p>
<p>Jan 26, 1994: India rolls out short-range Prithvi missile at Republic Day Parade in New Delhi.</p>
<p>Aug 23, 1994: Then former prime minister Nawaz Sharif tells a public rally in Pakistan-ruled Azad (free) Kashmir, forming a third of disputed Jammu and Kashmir, that Pakistan possesses an atomic bomb, but the government denies the claim.</p>
<p>Dec 26, 1994: Pakistan orders closure of Indian consulate-general in Karachi, accusing it of involvement in acts of terrorism. India rejects the charge.</p>
<p>Jan 4, 1995: India closes consulate-general in Karachi.</p>
<p>Jan 15, 1995: India asks Pakistan to reduce number of its diplomats from embassy in New Delhi.</p>
<p>Jan 30, 1996: Pakistani and Indian military officers meet on ceasefire line dividing Kashmir to ease tension after clashes.</p>
<p>June 4, 1996: Pakistani Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto urges new Indian Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda to resume dialogue. Deve Gowda responds positively, but Pakistan drops idea when India holds local elections in Jammu and Kashmir state.</p>
<p>Feb 17, 1997: Deve Gowda writes to Pakistan's new Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif, seeking &quot;comprehensive&quot; talks.</p>
<p>Feb 27, 1997: Sharif agrees to talks and proposes that officials meet to pave way for a prime ministerial meeting.</p>
<p>March 6, 1997: India and Pakistan set March 28-31 for talks between their foreign secretaries in New Delhi.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
