<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="472729" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: British Airways plans to expand JFK terminal.</title>
<headline>British Airways plans to expand JFK terminal.</headline>
<byline>Jessica Hall</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Airways Plc said Thursday it planned to invest $100 million to expand its terminal at New York's John F. Kennedy International Airport and improve roadway access.</p>
<p>The $100 million investment is in addition to the $17 billion in spending planned for the United States over the next five years, the airline said.</p>
<p>&quot;As our operations continue to grow in the U.S. and our alliance with American Airlines moves closer, so does our investment in America,&quot; said British Airways Chief Executive Robert Ayling.</p>
<p>Ayling said he remained confident a proposed trans-Atlantic alliance with American will be approved this summer, but British Air could reject the alliance if regulators required the airlines to pay a burdensome price, such as disposing of a large number of airport slots at London's Heathrow airport or some U.S. airports.</p>
<p>&quot;If the terms are so penal that they are not in our commercial interest, we will say no,&quot; Ayling said at a press conference here to announce the Kennedy expension project.</p>
<p>Construction on the Kennedy terminal expansion will begin this summer, with completion set for mid-1999. A new roadway connecting local expressways to the terminal's access roads will be finished by mid-2000, British Airways said.</p>
<p>The expanded terminal will feature larger check-in areas, new lounges and a shopping plaza and &quot;leisure centre.&quot; The design also includes a station for a proposed rail link to Manhattan.</p>
<p>British Airways said the expansion was not contingent on the approval of its proposed alliance with American. American Airlines, the No. 2 U.S. carrier, is a unit of Fort Worth, Texas-based AMR Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a happy coincidence that American's terminal is next to ours,&quot; Ayling said. If the proposed alliance is approved, British Airways said it will work with American to coordinate service between the two terminals.</p>
<p>Ayling said he did not know if American would move its facilities into the expanded British Airways building, since the space is now shared by United Airlines, a unit of Chicago-based UAL Corp. and the nation's largest carrier. United has been one of several competitors that have been critical of the proposed British Airways-American alliance.</p>
<p>British Airways said it was not aware if United planned to remain a tenant in the building. United representatives could not be immediately reached for comment.</p>
<p>&quot;If United remains as a tenant that of course would led to one set of conclusions. If they left as a tenant, then we could use the whole of our terminal with American for our trans-Atlantic routes,&quot; Ayling said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
