<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="472890" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. group slams lack of clean water enforcement.</title>
<headline>U.S. group slams lack of clean water enforcement.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Paul</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Federal and state agencies are failing to crack down on major water polluters, the U.S. Public Interest Research Group said Wednesday.</p>
<p>In a report on clean water violations across the nation in 1995 and early 1996, the group said industrial, municipal and federal plants illegally polluted surface water far more than Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) lists showed.</p>
<p>&quot;EPA and many of the 39 delegated state agencies charged with implementing the (Clean Water) Act have lacked both the resources and the political will to enforce the law aggressively,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>The criticism of the EPA was based on the group's finding that in the first quarter of 1996 32 percent of major industrial plants violated their permit limits. But for the same period, EPA targeted only 7 percent of major facilities.</p>
<p>A senior EPA enforcement official disputed the group's concerns, saying the agency concentrated on violations that posed the greatest threat to the environment or public health.</p>
<p>&quot;If we have knowledge of any facility where we think there's a serious environmental problem, whether it fits the definition (of significant violation) or not, we put them on our list to go after,&quot; the EPA official said.</p>
<p>By EPA criteria, Texas, Florida, Michigan, South Carolina and Ohio had the largest number of plants in &quot;significant noncompliance&quot; at least once from January 1995 to March 1996.</p>
<p>States such as California and Colorado, which had few violations on the EPA list, did not necessarily have water that was safe enough for swimming and fishing, said Todd Robins, the author of the report. He said the federal list understated the pollution problem partly because the agency's threshold for &quot;significant noncompliance&quot; was set very high.</p>
<p>Under EPA criteria, to be reported as not complying significantly a plant must exceed conventional pollutant limits by 40 percent or toxic pollutant limits by 20 percent in two months over a six-month period, or violate any limits for four months in a six-month period.</p>
<p>The list failed to reflect all problems, Robins said, because states often did not report violations to a national database and because industry was not being forced to report violations accurately. &quot;Very, very rarely do you see serious deterrent penalties being assessed against these companies for violations of their permits,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>The EPA enforcement official questioned the charge that the agency allowed companies to profit from polluting. &quot;We do not seek to penalize them but to make sure that any ill-gotten gains ... in terms of competitive advantage over those that are in compliance are taken back,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
