<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="472993" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: WEEK AHEAD-Searching for clues to Fed's next move.</title>
<headline>WEEK AHEAD-Searching for clues to Fed's next move.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Thorpe</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Financial markets will comb through several weighty data releases from the United States in the week ahead for indications of the Federal Reserve's next move on interest rates, analysts said.</p>
<p>The week will culminate in the most widely-watched data of them all -- U.S. payrolls. In Europe, Germany gives a reading of the health of its industry while Japan has its Tankan survey.</p>
<p>&quot;The initial dramatic reaction to the durable goods shows you how sensitive the market is right now to U.S. data,&quot; said David Coleman, chief economist at CIBC Investment Bank here.</p>
<p>U.S. debt markets tumbled, then partially recovered, after the Commerce Department reported on Wednesday that durable goods orders climbed 1.5 percent in February. Forecasts had been for a small drop.</p>
<p>Coleman said the reaction showed how vulnerable markets were to signs of growth and inflation after the Fed raised its interest rates for the first time in two years on Tuesday.</p>
<p>(The Fed increased its target for the federal funds rate that commercial banks charge each other for overnight loans to 5.50 from 5.25 percent. It left the discount rate unchanged at 5.0 percent.)</p>
<p>Next Friday's March employment report, including the average hourly earnings component, would provide clues to if and when the Fed would next raise the federal funds rate, Coleman said.</p>
<p>Stephen King, chief European economist at HSBC James Capel in London, said his firm expected a rise of 215,000 in payrolls, down from February's 339,000 increase. He said March data would not contain the same boost to construction employment that February had after harsh winter weather conditions abated.</p>
<p>Also due from the U.S. next week are the March Chicago Purchasing Managers Index on Monday and the National Association of Purchasing Management's (NAPM) March report on Tuesday.</p>
<p>HSBC James Capel has a forecast of 53.0 for NAPM, down slightly from 53.1 in February. &quot;It's still indicating a steady expansion in manufacturing activity,&quot; King said.</p>
<p>European data will be thin on the ground with financial centres closed on Monday for Easter and many investors taking advantage of school shut-downs to take extended breaks.</p>
<p>The highlight is likely to be German February industrial production data expected from Tuesday and manufacturing new orders data, due from Wednesday.</p>
<p>King expected industrial production to rise 1.0 percent in February, after a 1.7 percent weather-related drop in January.</p>
<p>But manufacturing new orders were expected to drop 0.5 percent in the month. The overall picture would be of a gradually improving German industrial base, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not as healthy as it could be from a structural point of view but the recovery has been coming through now for a number of months on a definitive basis,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;That will continue through this year because of the decline in the exchange rate combined with the looseness of monetary conditions.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain has its version of the U.S. NAPM out on Tuesday with the release of the Purchasing Mangers Index for March.</p>
<p>The PMI fell to 53.5 in February from 53.9, still showing expansion in manufacturing, while prices showed the largest drop since July 1996. Any evidence of further benign data could help cool interest rate speculation in Britain, analysts said.</p>
<p>In Japan, the main event will be the Tankan report on Wednesday. Analysts said forecasts would take into account a consumption tax rise on April 1.</p>
<p>IBJ International in London forecast some improvement in the manufacturing index to zero from minus three.</p>
<p>-- International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
