<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="473000" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - AMEC shares rise on 71 pct profit jump.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - AMEC shares rise on 71 pct profit jump.</headline>
<byline>Edna Fernandes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>British engineering and construction group AMEC Plc cheered investors on Thursday with a 71 percent rise in 1996 pretax profits and a one third hike in its dividend payout.</p>
<p>Pretax profits for 1996 rose to 27.2 million pounds ($44.3 million) from 15.9 million after taking a 10.5 million one-off charge. Stripping out exceptional charges, profits were 37.7 million against 24.7 million in 1995.</p>
<p>The dividend was raised to four pence a share from three in 1995, while sales swelled to 2.77 billion from 2.45 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;It's pleasing to announce pretax profits up 71 percent accompanied by further improvements in the group's cash position and a dividend increased by 33 percent,&quot; AMEC chief executive Peter Mason said.</p>
<p>&quot;This level of increase demonstrates our confidence going forward,&quot; he said. Net cash was up more than threefold to 63.4 million.</p>
<p>The market welcomed the news, pushing AMEC shares up 14-1/2 pence to 141-1/2 before it edged back.</p>
<p>&quot;The results were pretty encouraging and the shares have reacted accordingly,&quot; one market-maker said.</p>
<p>AMEC said its internal review was continuing and that further progress would be made this year.</p>
<p>Mason told Reuters he planned more small disposals in the current year, but declined to comment further.</p>
<p>He said there were signs of an uptick in British construction. The building and civil engineering division saw a positive performance last year in the U.S., with progress in British road projects.</p>
<p>Germany remained a difficult market, but Mason said it accounted for just three percent of turnover at 100 million pounds. A return to profitability in Germany was not envisaged until the market improves, despite cost cutting measures.</p>
<p>The mechanical and electrical unit saw a 17 percent rise in profit assisted by a contribution from the new AMEC Rail division. Process and energy returned to profit but AMEC said there was still further scope for improvement.</p>
<p>Housing saw a 13 percent rise in sales and operating margins up six percent. While the services business performed well across all divisions and remains an area for expansion.</p>
<p>The company said the May 1 British election had led to a delay in a number of private finance initiative (PFI) health projects under which the private sector will build infrastructure for public health services.</p>
<p>AMEC has been announced as preferred bidder for several PFI deals.</p>
<p>The 1996 exceptional charge related to a 25 million write-off for the housing division, a 2.7 million charge for German restructuring and 2.3 million write-off against investments which were partly offset by disposal gains of 19.5 million. ($ = 0.614 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
