<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="473095" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>QATAR: Qatar bourse off one pct in post dividend slip.</title>
<headline>Qatar bourse off one pct in post dividend slip.</headline>
<dateline>DOHA 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qatar's unofficial stock market ended over one percent lower as prices of some leading stocks were marked down after dividend announcements, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said some heavyweights, including market leader Qatar National Bank, were adjusted down by the extent of their recently-announced dividends.</p>
<p>The Commercial Bank of Qatar's 18-share index shed 1.48 points to 127.53 points from 129.01 the previous week, dragged down by a 135 riyal plunge in QNB shares, which account for a third of the total market capitalisation of $1.9 billion.</p>
<p>QNB closed at 525 riyals against 660 the previous week after it announced a cash dividend equal to 25 percent of capital and a one-for-four bonus issue.</p>
<p>The CBQ lost 30 riyals to 318 after a payout of a dividend equal to 30 percent of the capital and a rights issue of one share for every two held at a premium of 250 riyals.</p>
<p>Qatar Shipping shed 2.50 riyals to 45.50 after distributing that amount in a cash dividend.</p>
<p>Another loser was Qatar Navigation which gave up 20 riyals to 680 as demand dried up.</p>
<p>Gainers included Doha Bank Ltd, which advanced three riyals to 313, Al Khaleej Insurance, which rose five riyals to 250 and Qatar Cement, which gathered two riyal to 325.</p>
<p>Other shares were unchanged.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DOHA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="QATAR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
