<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="473162" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Apparent mass suicide in mansion outside San Diego.</title>
<headline>Apparent mass suicide in mansion outside San Diego.</headline>
<dateline>SAN DIEGO 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deputies found at least 10 bodies at the scene of an apparent mass suicide in a luxury mansion, the San Diego Sheriff's Department said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Sgt. Don Crist told Reuters the department received a call in the afternoon about bodies at a house in the exclusive community of Rancho Santa Fe, some 20 miles (32 km) north of San Diego.</p>
<p>Deputies who went to the house found at least 10 bodies, Crist said. &quot;They lost count at 10,&quot; he said. Homicide detectives were investigating.</p>
<p>Unconfirmed media reports put the number of dead higher.</p>
<p>Local TV station, KFMB, quoted a reporter at the scene as saying the bodies were in a &quot;multimillion-dollar house&quot; in Rancho Santa Fe.</p>
<p>The house, with a tennis court and swimming pool, and surrounded by horse ranches, had been rented by a group of people since October 1996, the reporter said, quoting neighbours.</p>
<p>The incident came after a cult suicide in Saint Casimir, Quebec last weekend.</p>
<p>Five members of a notorious doomsday cult died in a blazing house Saturday in an apparent ritual suicide pact, but spared three teenage children, Quebec police said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN DIEGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
