<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="473262" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Charity founder pleads no contest to fraud.</title>
<headline>Charity founder pleads no contest to fraud.</headline>
<dateline>PHILADELPHIA 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The founder of the bankrupt Foundation for New Era Philanthropy pleaded no contest Wednesday to fraud and other crimes in the collapse of his plan to double investments of nonprofit organisations.</p>
<p>John Bennett Jr., 59, entered the plea at a federal court hearing. He had been charged with 82 counts of fraud, money laundering, check kiting, tax evasion and other crimes.</p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Edmund Ludwig accepted the plea and said he would set a later date for sentencing.</p>
<p>Bennett and his attorneys, asked after the hearing whether there had been an agreement with prosecutors, declined to comment. Bennett faces a maxium prison sentence of 907 years and a fine of $28 million.</p>
<p>Bennett's foundation attracted more than $350 million in investments from major charities, nonprofit groups and others with a pledge to double their money with matching donations from anonymous investors who, according to prosecutors, never existed.</p>
<p>Investors included Harvard and Princeton Universities, the Philadelphia Orchestra, mutual fund guru Peter Lynch and numerous charitable organisations.</p>
<p>The charity collapsed in 1995 when Prudential Securities, the foundation's broker, called a credit line and began seizing New Era assets. A total of $107 million in claims was recognised by a federal bankruptcy trustee, and New Era had about $31 million in cash assets remaining.</p>
<p>Under a settlement last year, groups that profited in the scheme agreed to return about $39 million to groups that lost money, thus repaying their losses at about 65 cents to the dollar.</p>
<p>Bennett's plea followed a ruling last week by Ludwig which restricted Bennett's lawyers' ability  to use a defence that claimed mental illness and religious zeal made it impossible for him to act with criminal intent.</p>
<p>The federal criminal case was scheduled to go to trial April 7.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHILADELPHIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
