<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="473497" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Man shot and injured in N. Ireland incident.</title>
<headline>Man shot and injured in N. Ireland incident.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A 19-year-old man was shot and seriously injured in Northern Ireland late on Wednesday, shortly after an explosion was heard outside a police station.</p>
<p>Police said details about the incident were sketchy and they could not confirm reports of a bomb. They said a hostile crowd had gathered at the scene, a police station in Coalisland, County Tyrone.</p>
<p>Local people said they suspected the explosion, heard shortly before 1000 p.m. (2200 GMT), was caused by a stun grenade fired by security forces.</p>
<p>Councillor Jim Canning said he was at a function nearby in the town.</p>
<p>&quot;There was an explosion followed by a number of gunshots. Some of us went outside and there was a man lying on the ground surrounded by a number of men who appeared to be some form of undercover operation,&quot; Canning said.</p>
<p>He said the man had his hands tied behind his back and the &quot;undercover&quot; people appeared agitated.</p>
<p>&quot;They were concerned about the crowd that was gathering and they were shouting at the crowd to stand back and eventually plastic bullets were fired,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Hospital sources said the man was admitted with gunshot wounds to the stomach and was in a &quot;serious but stable&quot; condition.</p>
<p>Two women also suffered minor injuries in the melee around the police station, they said.</p>
<p>The incident came hours after two suspected IRA bombs exploded in north west England, damaging railway lines and signalling equipment.</p>
<p>Earlier the Irish Republican Army (IRA) said it would not relax its guerrilla war to end British rule of Northern Ireland and blamed Britain for the lack of progress in peace efforts for the province.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone should be assured that we are united, we are strong and we remain steadfast in our determination to achieve our objectives,&quot; the IRA said in a statement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
