<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="473491" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain's Conservatives admit sleaze is hurting.</title>
<headline>Britain's Conservatives admit sleaze is hurting.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Deputy Prime Minister Michael Heseltine admitted on Thursday a string of sleaze scandals were an embarrassment for his Conservative party in the runup to national elections on May 1.</p>
<p>But Heseltine, speaking the day after a Conservative member of parliament stood down as a candidate and a newspaper accused another of an affair with a teenager, blamed the media for trying to distract attention from Britain's booming economy.</p>
<p>&quot;These revelations, accusations, headlines are a damaging diversion in an election campaign,&quot; Heseltine told BBC radio.</p>
<p>&quot;I very much hope that the people will recognise that what we're talking about is the big issues, about the booming economy and the dangers of Labour blowing it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Heseltine, battling with Prime Minister John Major to give the Conservatives a record consecutive fifth term in office after 18 years in power, sent a strong hint to the latest MP embroiled in scandal that he should step down as a candidate.</p>
<p>&quot;I haven't the slightest doubt that Piers Merchant, his family and his association will want to consider very carefully the consequences of what has happened for the party at large.&quot;</p>
<p>When pressed whether this meant Merchant should stand down, he said: &quot;You must listen to what I have said very carefully.&quot;</p>
<p>The latest scandal broke in Thursday's edition of The Sun newspaper, which last week declared its support for the main opposition Labour Party.</p>
<p>The Sun covered its front page with a report that Merchant, a Conservative MP on the first rung of a ministerial career, was having an affair with a 17-year-old nightclub hostess. A series of colour pictures showed the married MP kissing and embracing the blonde teenager.</p>
<p>The Sun's revelations gave new life to Labour charges that the government was mired in sleaze, accusations highlighted by a series of articles in last week's Guardian newspaper alleging influence-peddling by Conservative MPs.</p>
<p>Heseltine immediately hinted at a conspiracy.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope to goodness there's not a sort of pattern emerging. The Labour Party were in deep trouble over the unemployment figures, which were so good, and the Guardian comes up with a sleaze story,&quot; he told his BBC interviewer.</p>
<p>&quot;Now the Labour party are in deep trouble over their relationships with the trade unions and The Sun comes up with this story... I hope this isn't going to be a pattern.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1992, the Sun -- owned by media baron Rupert Murdoch -- claimed it had won the election for the Conservatives. Its switch of allegiance was one of the many blows Major's party has suffered in the first 10 days of its campaign.</p>
<p>The MP at the heart of the latest row denied the story, telling The Sun: &quot;Anna is a dear friend of mine and has been helping my campaign. But there is no question of us having an affair. I have never made love to her.&quot;</p>
<p>But the row dominated media coverage of the election campaign on Thursday, throwing the Conservatives on the defensive just as they appeared to be making some headway with their attacks on Labour over its trade union links.</p>
<p>Tim Smith, a former junior Northern Ireland minister, said on Wednesday he was standing down as a candidate following a row over his acceptance of cash for asking questions in parliament.</p>
<p>A MORI poll in Thursday's Times newspaper gave the Conservatives 29 percent support compared to 50 percent for Labour. Both parties have dropped two points from the previous MORI poll in February as backing for the centre-left Liberal Democrats increased to 14 percent from 11 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
