<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="473535" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: STOCKS -- Closing stock market indices, March 26.</title>
<headline>STOCKS -- Closing stock market indices, March 26.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here is how major stock markets outside the United States ended on Wednesday.</p>
<p>LONDON - The leading FTSE 100 index held just above the 4,300 level at the close after a strong showing from retailers and relief that the Federal Reserve did not tighten U.S. credit more aggressively bolstered investor confidence.</p>
<p>The benchmark FTSE 100 index added 30.8 points to 4,301.5.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Germany's DAX share index closed bourse trade strongly after renewed takeover speculation in the banking sector drove shares there to sharp gains.</p>
<p>The DAX-30 index ended 68.98 points or 2.06 percent up at 3,418.12 after early pressure following the Dow's overnight losses. In post-bourse trade the DAX index stood at 3,439.22, up 64.29 points.</p>
<p>PARIS - French stocks finished higher due to the dollar's gains following a widely anticipated quarter-point rise in U.S. interest rates.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed up 24.48 points, or 0.93 percent, at 2,648.73.</p>
<p>ZURICH - Swiss shares ended more than one percent higher for a second day in a row as index heavyweights Roche, Novartis and Nestle helped the overall market continue its recovery. On Thursday the bourse close will be moved forward to 1300 GMT from 1530 GMT ahead of the Easter holiday.</p>
<p>The blue-chip Swiss Market Index closed 61.9 points, or 1.36 percent, higher at 4,620.5 and the all-share Swiss Performance Index added 31.15 points to finish at 2,919.11.</p>
<p>TOKYO - Tokyo stocks ended mostly steady after see-sawing throughout most of the session. Brokers said the market reacted little to the U.S. rate rise as it had already been factored in.</p>
<p>The 225-share Nikkei average ended 32.84 points or 0.18 percent higher at 18,472.45.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Hong Kong stocks largely ignored higher interest rates and strong property prices to limp to a slightly weaker close.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index closed at 12,776.39, down 56.14 points or 0.44 percent.</p>
<p>SYDNEY - Australian stocks closed virtually steady after the U.S. Federal Reserve lifted interest rates as expected and the Easter break loomed for traders.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index ended up 0.9 points, or 0.04 percent, at 2,404.3. .</p>
<p>JOHANNESBURG - A gloomy bullion price dragged South African gold shares down from the start of trade but dealers said their fall was lessened by some foreign buying at lower levels.</p>
<p>The market's downside was seen limited. Industrial shares ended 32.3 points down at 8,308.0 and the all-shares shed 29.9 points to 7,059.6 points.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
