<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="473581" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: BHP says it's not about to abandon PNG.</title>
<headline>BHP says it's not about to abandon PNG.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian resources giant The Broken Hill Co Pty Ltd (BHP) said on Thursday it was not considering abandoning crisis-hit Papua New Guinea as a place for future investment.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been in PNG for a long time and we have been there through thick and thin and I don't think this is going to change our particular view,&quot; BHP Copper chief executive Jim Lewis said.  </p>
<p>BHP shut down a steel processing plant in Papua New Guinea this week after a confrontation between the prime minister and sacked defence force commander plunged the nation into its worst political crisis.</p>
<p>The company also pulled staff and their families out of the capital, Port Moresby, and Lae to the north, but says its 52-percent owned Ok Tedi copper mine has been unaffected.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Sir Julius Chan and his finance and defence ministers stood down on Wednesday to defuse the crisis, which brought angry troops and rioters onto the capital's streets.  </p>
<p>Lewis told reporters in Melbourne he was pleased &quot;the matter&quot; seemed to have been resolved constitutionally but wanted to see a complete and swift end to the crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't see a problem with operating with whomever becomes the government in Papua New Guinea and I would certainly be pleased to see the matter resolved expeditiously,&quot; Lewis said.</p>
<p>Papua New Guinea will hold a general election in June.</p>
<p>BHP is not in the position now of having to make a decision on any major investments in Papua New Guinea, Lewis said. But he acknowledged concern among international investors.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Papua New Guinea situation has given rise to some uncertainty and I'm sure some nervousness eith international investors,&quot; Lewis said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our withdrawal of our people out of Port Moresby and Lae should not be misinterpreated as anything other than simply responding to the particular circumstances of the day.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 613-9286-1421</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
