<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47361" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iraqi Kurds enter Iran after KDP shooting.</title>
<headline>Iraqi Kurds enter Iran after KDP shooting.</headline>
<byline>Sharif Imam-Jomeh</byline>
<dateline>BASHMAQ, Iran 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>About 5,000 weary Iraqi Kurdish refugees set up camp on the Iranian side of the border on Wednesday after they said a Baghdad-backed Kurdish group killed four people.</p>
<p>&quot;On Tuesday night, KDP (Kurdistan Democratic Party) men came and asked us first nicely to go back home, but when people confronted them, they started shooting. Four were killed,&quot; a refugee told Reuters.</p>
<p>Local Iranian authorities at the Bashmaq border crossing said four people were killed and about 100 wounded. The wounded were taken to hospitals in Iran, they said. State-run Tehran radio said Iraqi troops were also involved.</p>
<p>Refugees said after the shooting some 5,000 people rushed toward a closed border crossing. Iranian border guards shot into the air but could not halt them, they said.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands of refugees had streamed toward Iran to escape advancing forces of the Iraqi-backed KDP who took Sulaimaniya, Iraq's biggest Kurdish city, on Monday from the rival Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK).</p>
<p>&quot;I would rather be a refugee than go back home to Sulaimaniya and live under the KDP and (Iraqi President) Saddam Hussein,&quot; said a middle-aged man standing next to a fire where his wife and daughter were cooking.</p>
<p>He said he and many other refugees belonged to Kurdish clans opposed to the KDP.</p>
<p>Iranian relief workers set up tents in a large field about 500 metres (yards) from a line of tress marking the border. The refugees had spent the night in cars or outside in the rugged mountainous region.</p>
<p>&quot;I left Sulaimaniya after my sister called me on Sunday to tell me that the Iraqis were coming,&quot; said Sirwan Rostam a 50-year-old school supervisor. &quot;I have been active with a Kurdish women's union and criticised Saddam publicly, so I had to leave.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Now I am here with a few clothes and some money I could bring. I have lost touch with my sister. I am finished. I am dead,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Two dozen women in colourful Kurdish dresses queued for water near a tanker sent by Iran's Red Crescent Society.</p>
<p>Tehran radio said Iran was housing &quot;thousands&quot; of refugees but named only the Bashmaq camp. United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees official Laurens Jolles in Tehran told Reuters that &quot;several thousand&quot; refugees had been admitted.</p>
<p>Tehran had said it would not admit refugees &quot;unless in an emergency&quot;. It said it would offer relief with the help of international organisations in camps on the Iraqi side of the border.</p>
<p>Iran already has more than two million refugees, including 1.5 million Afghans, making it the country hosting the largest number anywhere.</p>
<p>Tehran had appealed for international aid, saying nearly 200,000 refugees were approaching. UNHCR officials in Geneva said on Tuesday up to 75,000 people were on the move, although some were later reported returning home.</p>
<p>Tehran had feared a repeat of 1991 when more than a million Iraqis, most of them Kurds, fled to Iran as Baghdad crushed uprisings that followed Iraq's defeat in the Gulf War. Most Kurds had since returned to northern Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BASHMAQ, Iran"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
