<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="473607" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: PRESS DIGEST - Malaysia - March 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malaysia - March 27.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Thursday's Malaysian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>All dailies lead with Malaysian Cabinet decision to freeze all fresh bilateral dealings with Singapore following Singapore Senior Minister Lee Kuan Yew's derogatory remarks about a Malaysia state.</p>
<p>NEW STRAITS TIMES</p>
<p>-- The two Royal Malaysian Air Force helicopters which crashed in Sabah state last week, killing 11 crew members, were likely to have slammed into a hill, according to a preliminary investigation report.</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad calls for a re-evaluation and reconstruction of Malaysian-Japanese relations in the light of the rapidly changing world economy and technology development.</p>
<p>-- United Malays National Organisation's youth wing chief Ahmad Zahid Hamidi says Singapore should treat the freeze on bilateral dealings with them as a last warning never to look down upon Malaysia.</p>
<p>BUSINESS TIMES</p>
<p>-- Tourist arrivals in Malaysia between January and August 1996 declined 6.5 percent, Tourism Minister Sabbaruddin Chik says.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
