<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="473718" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Yaohan Japan to shift clerical staff to stores.</title>
<headline>Yaohan Japan to shift clerical staff to stores.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese retailer Yaohan Japan Corp said on Thursday that it would shift half of its administrative work force into store jobs by the end of 1997/98 as part of restructuring measures.</p>
<p>Yaohan currently employs about 400 workers for back-office operations at its headquarters and affiliate firms, half of which will be redeployed in its stores.</p>
<p>A Yaohan spokesman said the company's vice chairman Terumasa Wada will resign when the company holds a stockholders' meeting in June to take responsibility for a deterioration in the company's financial condition.</p>
<p>Yaohan Japan, the flagship firm of the Yaohan international retailing group, has been burdened with hefty borrowings after aggressive expansion overseas.</p>
<p>The company said in February that it plans to trim group debt subject to interest payments to 90 billion yen from 164.6 billion yen by the end of March 1999.</p>
<p>Yaohan also said in February that it has agreed with supermarket chain operator Daiei Inc to sell 16 of its outlets for 33 billion yen.</p>
<p>The two companies said in separate statements that the 16 outlets, all in central Japan, would be sold to Seifu Kabushiki Kaisha, a chainstore operator owned 89.8 percent by Daiei, in the middle of May.</p>
<p>The spokesman said that Yaohan's British subsidiary Yaohan Development U.K. Ltd may sell off its shopping centre located in a suburb of London as part of efforts to reduce the group's debts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
