<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="474042" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-UNBEATEN BORDEAUX FACE TRICKY FRENCH CUP CLASH.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-UNBEATEN BORDEAUX FACE TRICKY FRENCH CUP CLASH.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bordeaux host Montpellier in a French soccer Cup quarter-final on Saturday hoping not to stumble to their first defeat of 1997 as they bid for a European cup competition berth.</p>
<p>Unheralded at the start of the season, Bordeaux are now shining on all three domestic fronts.</p>
<p>Sixth in the league standings, four points short of the second place, the team coached by Rolland Courbis, who meet Strasbourg in the League Cup final on April 12, feel their clash against Montpellier could be their most decisive test to come.</p>
<p>&quot;If we lose this match, will we be able to react and get back on the right gear?&quot; Courbis asked.</p>
<p>&quot;We must make it to a European cup competition next season. There is still a possibility that we'll win the two cups and finish second in the league. But a loss against Montpellier could ruin it all.&quot;</p>
<p>Courbis is all the more cautious as Bordeaux had to go through a nailbiting penalty shootout to dismiss Montpellier in the League Cup semifinals last month.</p>
<p>Since then, Montpellier, like Bordeaux, have not lost a match and Saturday's clash pits two in-form sides against one another.</p>
<p>But Bordeaux may have an extra asset, as their former Montpellier player Michel Pavon explained.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the start of the year, we've played all our matches as if they were cup matches. In the League Cup, in the French cup as well as in the league, we've played as if qualification was at stake,&quot; he said. &quot;Saturday will be just another cup match.&quot;</p>
<p>Courbis can count on the whole of his squad for the tie, including defender Bernard Lambourde, who was missing in their goalless draw against Nantes in the league on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Montpellier may be without former internationals Franck Sauzee and Pascal Baills, who are both injured.</p>
<p>In the other quarter-finals, Nice hope to do better than Paris St Germain against fourth division Clermont-Ferrand, the sensations of the previous round while first division Guingamp, who have a lacklustre league season, travel to third division Creteil. Laval and Troyes battle it out in a clash between two average second division sides.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
