<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="474035" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: HORSE RACING-THE GREY MONK IN IRISH GRAND NATIONAL RAID.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-THE GREY MONK IN IRISH GRAND NATIONAL RAID.</headline>
<byline>Damien Lynch</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-03-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gordon Richards on Friday gave the all-clear for The Grey Monk to head an eight-strong British challenge for Monday's Irish Grand National at Fairyhouse.</p>
<p>Richards, who pulled The Grey Monk out of the Cheltenham Gold Cup earlier this month because the ground was too firm, welcomed news that the going at the County Meath racecourse had changed to good-to-yielding after rain on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Grey Monk, a faller on his last visit to Ireland for the Hennessy Gold Cup at Leopardstown in February, will have to shoulder top weight of 12 stone (76-kg) for the three miles and five furlongs (5.8-km) trip. Bookmakers rate him an 8-1 chance.</p>
<p>No less than 21 of the last 30 winners of the race have carried l1 stone (70-kg)  or under.</p>
<p>Another leading English trainer, David Nicholson, will saddle both Percy Smollett (8-1) and St.Mellion Fairway (20-1).</p>
<p>Jenny Pitman-trained Mudahim (8-1) and Graham McCourt's Sister Stephanie (12-1) will race at Fairyhouse despite the fact that they are also entered for the Aintree Grand National at Liverpool on Saturday week.</p>
<p>Ted Walsh-trained Papillon, now the 6-1 favourite after he was backed down from 10-1 this week, will head the 13-strong home defence.</p>
<p>Walsh, who saddled his first winner at the Cheltenham Festival when Commanche Court won the  Triumph Hurdle, has booked Ireland's champion jumps jockey Charlie Swan to ride his novice.</p>
<p>Arthur Moore, who sent out Feathered Gale to win the 1996 Irish National, will be represented this year by Amble Speedy and Fissure Seal. Both are quoted 16-1 chances.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
