<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="474130" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Poland - March 28.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Poland - March 28.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- Poland's per capita gross domestic product was between $6,300 and $6,350 in 1995, which was two times less than in the least developed countries of the EU and three time less than in Denmark, Austria, Germany and Belgium, the Central Statistical Office (GUS) said.</p>
<p>- The Polska Grupa Kapitalowa (PGK) capital group has formally confirmed its offer to buy a 40 percent stake in the Ruch press distribution chain to be privatised soon.</p>
<p>- The bankrupt Stocznia Gdansk (SG) shipyard's liabilities total more than 400 million zlotys, Poland's Finance Minister Marek Belka said. The co-owner of the all-national private Polsat television Zygmunt Solorz has offered to take over the yard, SG Solidarity trade union's Ryszard Walewski said.</p>
<p>- The rise of coke prices in the first qurter of 1997 will increase Huta Katowice steel mill's production costs by 80 million zlotys, the mill said. The economic ministers' committee KERM plans to correct coke price levels so as to fully utilise the coke  plants' output capacity, cut steel production costs and eliminate uneconomic coke exports at the same time, KERM said.</p>
<p>- Germany's Reemtsma Cigaretten Fabriken GmbH cigarette maker, which controls a 76 percent stake in the Wytwornia Wyrobow Tytoniowych WWT cigarette plant in Poznan, invested 61 million zlotys in the Poznan plant development last year. In 1997 it will invest 160 million zlotys with 120 million zlotys to be spent on a new plant construction in Jankowice, western Poland, the company said.</p>
<p>NOWA EUROPA</p>
<p>- The Polish-German Allianz BGZ Polska non-life insurance firm expects to generate losses in the next two years, while the Allianz BGZ Zycie life insurance firm it may take up to ten years to come out in the black, the Allianz AG board member Detlev Bremkamp said.</p>
<p>- The Dutch-British-Polish LDV commercial vehicle maker, which controls an assembly plant in Andrychow, sold 200 vans last year, which showed a significant growth compared with 104 cars sold the year before, the company said.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>- Fiat Auto Poland is planning to launch again its environment friendly marketing scheme, which gave buyers discounts for scrapping their old cars.</p>
<p>ZYCIE</p>
<p>- Poland's wheat and rye prices in the last week of March eased 0.4 percent and 0.2 percent respectively, the Polskie Zaklady Zbozowe grain processor said.</p>
<p>PARKIET</p>
<p>- The general shareholders meeting of the ZM Ropczyce magnesite plant, which is controlled by the Foksal National Investment Fund (NFI), is planning an up to 500,000 C-series share issue priced at 2.5 zlotys per share this year, Foksal NFI board member Piotr Wielowiejski said.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
