<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="474122" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Berisha renews pleas for foreign force in Albania.</title>
<headline>Berisha renews pleas for foreign force in Albania.</headline>
<byline>Alister Doyle</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-03-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanian President Sali Berisha renewed his calls on Friday for a U.N.-approved force to be sent to his anarchic Balkan state, saying foreign police or troops were essential to safeguard aid supplies.</p>
<p>In the countryside, a gun battle in which 20 people were killed and the looting of an arsenal contrasted starkly with signs of a return to calm with the arrival of a first Red Cross aid truck and plans for a soccer match in Tirana on Saturday.</p>
<p>Berisha met a European Union-led group in Tirana seeking ways to help to restore order after the U.N. Security Council began informal talks on Thursday on an Italian request for it to authorise sending a multinational force.</p>
<p>&quot;Berisha stressed that the escort of convoys of aid by police or military units of the countries Albania has asked aid from...is indispensable to provide the necessary security of this operation,&quot; an official statement said.</p>
<p>He said relief efforts in cooperation with Albanian police were &quot;very significant to pull the country back from the grave situation it is in,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Much of the south of the formerly communist country is controlled by rebels and armed gangs after protests against the collapse of savings schemes in January spilled over into insurrection in mid-March.</p>
<p>Greece, France, Spain, Portugal, Austria, Turkey and Romania have all expressed willingness to take part in a force to safeguard shipments of basic supplies like flour and medicines.</p>
<p>Italy has estimated that about 2,500 personnel would be deployed initially, with another 2,500 in reserve.</p>
<p>Dutch diplomat Jan de Marchant et d'Ansembourg, heading the EU delegation that included experts from the OSCE security group and the Council of Europe, told a news conference the Security Council might meet again on Friday or at the weekend.</p>
<p>He said relief efforts would be largely ineffective until Tirana's airport and the ports of Durres and Vlore were secured.</p>
<p>To illustrate the crisis, he said, &quot;the government is simply not able to feed its own army&quot; and food shortages would soon be a threat to the poorest people in Albania.</p>
<p>Police were investigating the deaths of 20 people in a shootout in the village of Frakull in central Albania on Thursday night, the highest toll in two months of crisis that have claimed well over 100 lives.</p>
<p>Villagers shot dead 17 gunmen who drove to the village and began firing weapons in the street. Three villagers were killed in the unexplained exchange, police said.</p>
<p>Radio Tirana said looters seized weapons from a military arsenal near the town of Gramsh after 10 hours of fighting with police. It said the attackers broke downb resistance by shielding themselves behind dozens of children.</p>
<p>But in a sign of hope, the first Red Cross relief truck since the crisis erupted crossed into southern Albania from Greece to test perilous road routes.</p>
<p>The truck, accompanied by two jeeps and carrying 10 tonnes of basic food like flour and sugar, dropped off supplies at hospitals, orphanages and old people's homes. The vehicles had turned back at the border on Thursday after an aborted first attempt.</p>
<p>In another sign of normality, the capital's two main soccer teams decided to play a friendly on Saturday, the first match between top teams since January. Several major banks planned to reopen on Tuesday after about two weeks' closure.</p>
<p>On the political front, Berisha faced a new challenge from some parties within his government of national reconciliation.</p>
<p>About 120 people, including leaders of several parties in the government, heads of self-styled national committees for public salvation and other opposition groups met in Vlore and urged Berisha's resignation.</p>
<p>In his statement, Berisha accused some parties in the new government of undermining its work by backing southern rebels.</p>
<p>He said rebel committees had a &quot;mediaeval feudal psychology&quot; and were &quot;completely discredited with citizens by breaking into banks with tanks, organising looting and killing.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
