<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="474177" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Budapest wheat futures rise, triggered by Chicago.</title>
<headline>Budapest wheat futures rise, triggered by Chicago.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-03-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A limit-up rise of milling wheat futures on the Budapest Commodity Exchange (BCE) on Friday was mainly triggered by Chicago prices, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;A six to eight cents per bushel price rise was enough for Budapest prices to go higher as well,&quot; said Istvan Markus of Swap.</p>
<p>He added that domestic factors could not have caused the rise.</p>
<p>&quot;On the basis of domestic news and crop forecasts prices should have gone down,&quot; Markus said.</p>
<p>Milling wheat futures rose by the daily allowed 400 forints per tonne limit for all maturities to finish at 24,830 forints for May, 22,300 for July and 23,970 for December.</p>
<p>The milling wheat price rise triggered an increase of 100 to 400 forints in feed wheat prices for the July to December maturities.</p>
<p>Old (1996) crop maize prices remained little changed in a fairly balanced market, Markus said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market had calmed down, panic position-closings are over,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>May maize rose 100 forints to close at 18,400 forints, July eased 50 forints to 17,700 forints.</p>
<p>Markus said that the overheated Hungarian grains futures market is ripe for a correction and it should happen by the second half of next week, unless international prices go in the opposite direction.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Chicago rise stops, a downward movement is likely to start here,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Total grains turnover was 394 million forints or 957 contracts, with milling wheat accounting for 472 and maize for 360 contracts.</p>
<p>Lot size= 20,000 kgs</p>
<p>($1=176.24 Hungarian forints)</p>
<p>-- Denes Albert, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
