<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="474261" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil bond fraud probe inches towards &quot;big fish&quot;.</title>
<headline>Brazil bond fraud probe inches towards &quot;big fish&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA, Brazil 1997-03-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A multi-million dollar municipal bond scandal threatens to ensnare one of Brazil's leading politicians after a principal players in the scam decided to kiss and tell, local media reported on Friday.</p>
<p>The Folha de Sao Paulo said former Sao Paulo mayor and presidential hopeful Paulo Maluf had close ties to Wagner Ramos, the architect of a scheme in which brokers allegedly skimmed millions off suspect state and municipal bond issues.</p>
<p>&quot;Wagner Ramos, the brain behind the bond scheme, was proud that he dealt directly with Maluf,&quot; wrote Folha columnist Luis Nass, who said the information was given to investigators by the owner of a bank implicated in the scheme, Fabio Nahoum.</p>
<p>Maluf could not be reached for comment. He has previously denied any wrongdoing.</p>
<p>The bond scandal, through which more than $400 million may have been deposited abroad in secret bank accounts in Paraguay and the Caribbean, has echoes of the corruption probe that toppled former president Fernando Collor de Mello in 1992.</p>
<p>Senators heading a parliamentary investigation say states and cities sold their debt at below market price to friendly brokerages, who in turn passed the securities on for a considerable profit to others involved in the scheme. The senators have vowed to get &quot;the big fish&quot; behind the scam.</p>
<p>So far in Sao Paulo, the country's biggest city, the finger of suspicion has pointed to current mayor and Maluf protege, Celso Pitta, who was the city's finance secretary.</p>
<p>Pitta has denied doing anything wrong.</p>
<p>The parliamentary investigation is also looking at the Central Bank, sparking speculation that heads may roll because of slack supervision of the financial sector.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA, Brazil"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
