<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="474373" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Orange County, Calif., CFO develops debt plan.</title>
<headline>Orange County, Calif., CFO develops debt plan.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA ANA, Calif. 1997-03-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Orange County's chief financial officer on Friday said he developed a plan to reduce the California county's debt levels to &quot;build trust&quot; on Wall Street in the wake of its bankruptcy.</p>
<p>County CFO Gary Burton said his so-called Credit and Debt Management Strategy calls for the defeasance and refinancing of county bonds, and for the county to build up its budget reserves.</p>
<p>&quot;We're trying to build trust with Wall Street, Main Street and Sacramento,&quot; Burton said in an interview. &quot;We want everybody to know we're on the right track.&quot;  </p>
<p>Burton said he hoped to bring his credit and debt management strategy before the county's Board of Supervisors in April. He said he expected the board to approve the plan.</p>
<p>Under Burton's plan, the county would build up its year-end balances, using a portion of the excess funds to defease or retire bonds before maturity.</p>
<p>Burton said the county should be able to build up a $140 million fund balance by fiscal 2001-2002. Those funds could be used to retire county bonds. The county could also defease bonds gradually, between now and 2002, Burton said.  </p>
<p>By refinancing its 1995 Teeter bonds, Burton said the county would free up reserves and could save about $5 million annually in the coming years.</p>
<p>Burton said his program could reduce county debt per capita to $482 from $572. General obligation and lease debt as a percentage of assessed valuation would drop to 0.70 percent from 0.85 percent, he said.</p>
<p>Even so, Burton said total general obligation and lease debt service as a percentage of governmental fund expenditures would increase to 5.2 percent from 2.4 percent because of deferred debt-service payments.  </p>
<p>Burton said his program could help the county attain single-A debt ratings and allow it to gain easier access to the capital markets with short- and long-term financings.</p>
<p>&quot;We know we defaulted at one time, but everyone has been made whole,&quot; Burton said. &quot;We're back on track with a financial plan to bring the debt levels down and hopefully get our credit ratings back.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We have to get the bankruptcy behind us,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Orange County filed for bankruptcy in December 1994 after sustaining losses of more than $1.6 billion on risky investments. It emerged from bankruptcy last June.</p>
<p>(( Adam Entous, 415-677-2511 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA ANA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
