<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="474475" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan sees export value doubled in three years.</title>
<headline>Pakistan sees export value doubled in three years.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-03-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's Finance Minister Sartaj Aziz said on Friday the government aimed to double the dollar value of exports over the next three years by strengthening the manufacturing sector and providing incentives.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is setting a target of doubling the total dollar value of exports in three years,&quot; Aziz told the National Assembly (lower house) as he announced an economic reform package that cut taxes and import duties.</p>
<p>He said a central pillar of the economic recovery programme of Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif's government was a strategy of growth led by exports, which were valued at $8.3 billion in fiscal 1995/96 (July-June).</p>
<p>&quot;Given the critical importance of export development in our economic revival, the prime minister will be personally monitoring the performance of exports and resolve any problems,&quot; Aziz said.</p>
<p>He said in order to ensure availability of machinery to exporters at international prices, the duty on imports of machinery was being reduced to 10 percent while raw materials for exportable goods would be exempt from duties.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
