<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="474647" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy should take genuine Albanian refugees -U.N.</title>
<headline>Italy should take genuine Albanian refugees -U.N.</headline>
<byline>Tom Wright</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-03-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.N. refugee agency expressed concern on Friday that Italy's use of its navy to halt an exodus to its shores from Albania might stop genuine refugees from fleeing the chaos-hit country.</p>
<p>The Rome office of the Geneva-based United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) said in a statement that it appreciated the &quot;humanitarian approach that the Italian government has taken so far&quot; to the Albanian crisis.</p>
<p>But it voiced concern about an Italian decision on Monday to turn away boats bringing Albanians to its ports from across the Adriatic, a journey already made by some 12,000 people since March 13 following an eruption of armed anarchy.</p>
<p>&quot;This kind of interdiction is not an appropriate way of handling a mass outflow of people, given that there may be some individuals who are leaving because of genuine concerns about their physical security,&quot; the UNHCR said.</p>
<p>Italy ordered its navy to conduct deterrence patrols of the Adriatic and advise Albanian boats to turn back after saying it was concerned that the most recent arrivals were not refugees but simply people looking for a better life abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;We agree with the Italian government's assessment that many of those involved in the later exodus may be motivated by the desire to leavce Albania for purely economic reasons,&quot; the UNHCR said.</p>
<p>But it added that the agency was &quot;anxious that those who may be in need of temporary refuge should be able to reach safety and have their protection needs assessed&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We are working with the Italian authorities to find ways of satisfactorily addressing this problem,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The Italian foreign ministry denied on Thursday that the restrictive measures amounted to a naval blockade.</p>
<p>It described the action in a statement as a patrolling exercise conducted &quot;at the request of and with the active cooperation of the Albanian government&quot;.</p>
<p>Thousands of Albanians fled the impoverished Balkan country in a flotilla of rusty and ancient boats after rebels seized towns in the south this month in an armed insurrection.</p>
<p>The uprising was unleashed by anger at the collapse of fraudulent savings schemes which wiped out many people's entire savings.</p>
<p>Italian coastguards said on Friday the exodus seemed to have dried up. Radar had detected only a single motorised dinghy approaching the southeast port of Brindisi which could be loaded with immigrants.</p>
<p>Italy has said it will grant temporary sanctuary to genuine refugees. It has repatriated some 1,000 Albanian &quot;undesirables&quot; since the crisis began, including 250 on Thursday.</p>
<p>All had broken the law since they arrived in Italy or were believed to have escaped from Albanian jails, officials said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
