<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="474786" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia palm oil prices seen up in 1997 - Negara.</title>
<headline>Malaysia palm oil prices seen up in 1997 - Negara.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-03-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's crude palm oil prices are forecast to pick up slightly this year, based on expectations of a lower supply of vegetable oils in the world market amid rising demand, Bank Negara said on Friday.</p>
<p>The central bank did not forecast any specific prices in its annual report for 1996.</p>
<p>A tonne of local crude palm oil is currently fetching about 1,285 ringgit.</p>
<p>The report said by end-1996, the total area planted with palm oil grew by 2.9 percent to 2.6 million hectares, while mature areas have expanded faster by 3.9 percent to 2.3 million hectares.</p>
<p>Bank Negara said output of crude palm oil in 1996 rose 7.4 percent to 8.4 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The bank said the upturn in the commodity's three-year biological yield cycle which started in 1995 had, to some extent, contributed to higher output.</p>
<p>The country's campaign to motivate collection of loose oil palm fruits also accounted for the higher output.</p>
<p>Bank Negara did not forecast 1997 output but traders estimated it would be 8.5 to 8.6 million tonnes.  </p>
<p>Malaysia accounted for 48.5 percent of world palm oil production in 1995, followed by Indonesia with a share of 29.6 percent, the report said.</p>
<p>The drawdown in stocks of palm oil to 0.79 million tonnes at end-1996 after a strong expansion in production during the year, was more than matched by equally strong growth in sales of the commodity, Bank Negara said.</p>
<p>It did not give a figure for end-1995 stocks but Malaysia's palm Oil Registration and Licensing Authority said it was 0.68 million tonnes. --Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230-7510)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
