<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="474778" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Property sector loans up by 22.9 pct-Negara.</title>
<headline>Property sector loans up by 22.9 pct-Negara.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-03-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Growth in loans to Malaysia's property sector rose 22.9 per cent in 1996 with demand for commercial and residential real estate firm despite official attempts to curb it, the central bank said on Friday.</p>
<p>Property loans added up to 22 billion ringgit in 1996, accounting for 30.5 percent of total lending, Bank Negara said in its 1996 report on the economy.</p>
<p>The growth in loans to the sector moderated slightly from 26 percent growth in 1995, it said.</p>
<p>The market for office space is expected to turn softer with nearly a doubling of space projected by 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;The office space market is envisaged to be highly competitive over the next few years, as tenants would have wider choices and possibly, more competitive terms, depending on the location and type of office buildings,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>The Bank said its forecast was also based on an estimate that an additional 3.5 million square metres of office space would be entering the market by 1999, bringing total supply to 7.0 million square metres.</p>
<p>The office market also secured good occupancy and rental rates, especially in and around the capital Kuala Lumpur, Bank Negara said.  </p>
<p>Average occupancy of office buildings rose to 97 percent from 93 percent. Average monthly rentals rose 5.0 percent to 50.45 ringgit a square metre, from 48.07 ringgit.</p>
<p>Reviewing the performance of the property market in 1996, Bank Negara said demand for residential and commercial space strengthened during the year.</p>
<p>It said the number of houses approved for building by the government remained high at 113,923 units, compared to 113,183 in 1995.</p>
<p>The central bank said 98,699 houses were completed last year, accounting for 12.3 percent of the 800,000 homes projected to be built between 1996 and 2000.</p>
<p>Foreign buying of residential property declined to 2.6 percent, from 10 percent after the government imposed restrictions in late 1995 on foreigners buying houses.</p>
<p>But demand for commercial properties continued to grow among foreigners, with 195 units worth 214 million ringgit transacted in 1996 from the 181 units valued at 112 million ringgit in 1995.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201-4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
