<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="474773" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan output falls in Feb, but outlook brightens.</title>
<headline>Japan output falls in Feb, but outlook brightens.</headline>
<byline>George Nishiyama</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A planned rise in the sales tax from April has clouded the outlook of the Japanese economy, but production data released on Friday showed signs that the economy may weather the tax rise after all, economists said.</p>
<p>Economists brushed aside the fall in Japanese industrial output in February and instead paid attention to the manufacturers' outlook, which pointed at production bouncing back in April.</p>
<p>&quot;The economic conditions are already firm now. People say the economy will slow down in the April to June period, but from the perspective of production, I don't think it will fall drastically,&quot; said Susumu Kato, chief economist at BZW Securities Japan.</p>
<p>Industrial production in February fell a preliminary 3.4 percent from month-on-month, following a hefty 5.6 percent rise in January, the trade ministry said on Friday. The figure was in line with economists' average forecast of a 3.3 percent fall.</p>
<p>A senior ministry official played down the month-on-month drop, saying that it was mainly due to a reaction to brisk production in January.</p>
<p>But economists' eyes were on the ministry's forecasts for manufacturers' output for the following two months, especially for April, when the government plans to raise the consumption tax to five percent from three.</p>
<p>The ministry said it expects output to decline 2.0 percent in March, but rise 1.0 percent in April.</p>
<p>&quot;A 1.0 plus (figure) is confirmation that the corporate sector is still positive about sales after April and is willing to increase production,&quot; said Takashi Kiuchi, chief economist at Long-Term Credit Bank of Japan.</p>
<p>But the forecast rise was not large enough to catch the attention of financial markets.</p>
<p>Yen bond dealers said the production data failed to have an impact on the market.</p>
<p>The yield on the benchmark 10-year Japanese government bond was standing at 2.290 percent in late Tokyo trade on Friday, little changed from its Thursday close of 2.300 percent.</p>
<p>But economists also said that despite the expected rise in production in April, there were doubts whether growth in output would be sustainable in the subsequent months.</p>
<p>&quot;(The tax increase) would cut down the disposable income of consumers and lead to a fall in demand. And that would invite a temporary drop in production from June,&quot; said Hisashi Yamada, an economist at the Japan Research Institute.</p>
<p>The expected positive figure for April is also unlikely to lead Japan's monetary authorities to alter their low interest rate policy, economists said.</p>
<p>The Bank of Japan (BOJ) has not changed its assessment that the economy is continuing its gradual recovery.</p>
<p>Although BOJ Governor Yasuo Matsushita said on Wednesday the trend of economic recovery was likely to continue after a temporarily slowdown following the tax rise, he added that it was still necessary to confirm the trend by looking at economic data, the views of the market and companies' business plans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
