<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="474702" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAPUA NEW GUINEA: Australia seizes military hardware bound for PNG.</title>
<headline>Australia seizes military hardware bound for PNG.</headline>
<byline>Terry Friel</byline>
<dateline>PORT MORESBY 1997-03-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia is holding a planeload of military hardware bound for Papua New Guinea, where plans to use mercenaries to quell a rebellion sparked a 10-day national crisis, an Australian official said on Friday.</p>
<p>An Antonov 124 carrying military supplies including helicopters was diverted to an airforce base near the northern city of Darwin on Thursday, a spokesman for Defence Minister Ian McLachlan told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;An AN 124 aircraft carrying defence materiel proposed to have been supplied to PNG under the Sandline (mercenary) contract has been diverted to Australia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The PNG government was concerned about the delivery of this material to PNG in the uncertain circumstances and asked Australia to receive it and store it. We have agreed to do so.&quot;</p>
<p>The spokesman said the load included several helicopters, but would not provide further details for security reasons.</p>
<p>But Australian government sources said the arsenal included two helicopter gunships, two transport helicopters, military vehicles, assault rifles, about 500 cases of ammunition and explosives, rockets and heat-seeking missiles.</p>
<p>Papua New Guinea's government and central bank sought to reassure foreign investors on Friday as Port Moresby enjoyed a relative calm following the crisis, which had wiped millions of dollars off the value of listed firms with exposure to PNG.</p>
<p>The central bank and the Commerce Department issued a statement saying the business climate was recovering from the recent political upheaval, which forced Prime Minister Sir Julius Chan to stand down on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;At least one leading commercial bank has reported that there has been no capital flight nor has there been any suggestion that investors and depositors were nervous,&quot; the Bank of Papua New Guinea and Commerce Department statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;The (local currency) kina's trading levels against all currencies has remained stable over the period of unrest.</p>
<p>&quot;The value of PNG stocks are recovering and financial analysts believe that they will return to their true value in the next week.&quot;</p>
<p>Papua New Guinea has no stock market, but some companies are listed in neighbouring Australia. Those stocks fell significantly when the crisis began.</p>
<p>Australian markets were closed on Friday for the Christian Easter holiday, but PNG's Australian-listed stocks rallied in active trade on Thursday on relief at the apparent peaceful resolution to the political crisis.</p>
<p>Chan suspended the A$46 million (US$36 million) contract with consultancy Sandline International last week in the face of civil and military opposition to the plan to use African mercenaries to help put down a secessionist rebellion on Bougainville island.</p>
<p>The contract included the provision of sophisicated weaponry to be used against the Bougainville Revolutionary Army on the resource-rich, jungle-clad island 800 km (500 miles) northeast of Port Moresby.</p>
<p>The mercenaries' leader, Tim Spicer, is currently awaiting trial in Port Moresby on illegal firearm charges.</p>
<p>Chan stepped aside pending the outcome of an inquiry into the awarding of the contract after a wave of unrest climaxed in rebel troops blockading parliament, trapping about 100 politicians inside on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>The streets of Port Moresby remained calm on Friday as the country closed down for the Christian Easter holiday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT MORESBY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAPUA NEW GUINEA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
