<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475071" id="root" date="1997-03-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Family and friends mourn Busang geologist.</title>
<headline>Family and friends mourn Busang geologist.</headline>
<byline>K.T. Arasu</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-03-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Friends and family members held a service in Jakarta on Friday for Filipino geologist Michael de Guzman, who fell out of a helicopter while flying to the Busang gold find he helped discover in Indonesia's East Kalimantan province.</p>
<p>His widow, Theresa Cruz, wept as she stood at the head of the carved wooden casket where a large portrait of de Guzman was placed alongside family photographs and a crucifix.</p>
<p>De Guzman's brother and two sisters were also present at the simple ceremony at the Gatot Subroto hospital in central Jakarta along with John Felderhof, the vice-president of Bre-X Minerals Ltd where de Guzman was chief geologist.</p>
<p>Bre-X shares plunged on Thursday on the Toronto Stock Exchange when trading in the stock reopened after being suspended when the company made a stunning admission there might be far less gold at the Busang property than previously estimated.</p>
<p>Bre-X chief executive David Walsh said in a statement on Wednesday that &quot;there appears a strong possibility that the potential gold resources on the Busang property...have been overstated&quot;.</p>
<p>The Calgary-based exploration company announced on February 17 the property contained about 71 million ounces of gold worth some $25 billion at current prices.</p>
<p>The penny-stock company became a darling of the Toronto Stock Exchange as it continued to raise the gold reserve estimate in the Busang property through 1996 and this year.</p>
<p>Bre-X shares were hit last week after news that de Guzman had fallen out of a helicopter while on his way to the Busang property, touted as the biggest single find since gold was discovered on South Africa's Witwatersrand late last century.</p>
<p>Some Indonesian officials have called it a suicide as the helicopter was in good condition and one of the letters de Guzman left behind said he was suffering from acute hepatitis B.</p>
<p>De Guzman's brother, who declined to give his name, said his brother had not given any indication that he had been ill with hepatitis B.</p>
<p>Felderhof, who had worked closely with de Guzman in discovering the Busang property, said his colleague's body would be flown to the Philippines on Saturday.</p>
<p>Reverand F. de van der Schueren, who conducted the prayers, told the small gathering that &quot;Michael had found what he was looking for...the treasure as the Lord would say&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;He went to look for new treasures...he was rewarded, he found it. But it seems God did not want to grant him this reward as better rewards await him,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Indonesian government has put the Busang gold find on hold after news that the property might contain much less than earlier reported.</p>
<p>The director-general of the mines and energy ministry, Kuntoro Mangkusubroto, said on Thursday he was putting aside applications for contracts of work by Bre-X to further explore and develop the property.</p>
<p>He said the latest turn of events in the long-running Busang saga could dent Indonesia's image and investor confidence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
