<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475155" id="root" date="1997-03-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BARBADOS: CRICKET-TENDULKAR AND DRAVID RAISE INDIAN HOPES.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-TENDULKAR AND DRAVID RAISE INDIAN HOPES.</headline>
<dateline>BRIDGETOWN, Barbados 1997-03-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sachin Tendulkar and Rahul Dravid transformed India's prospects with a mix of skill and courage on Saturday to seize the initiative from West Indies in a fluctuating third test.</p>
<p>Tendulkar led the way with 92 from 147 balls, again narrowly missing a first test hundred in the Caribbean, as India finished the second day at Kensington Oval on 249 for three, a mere 49 runs behind West Indies first innings of 298.</p>
<p>Dravid was still there after almost five hours on 71, providing the kind of support his captain's sublime afternoon strokeplay deserved as India fought their way into a position of strength from the shaky foundations of 42 for two.</p>
<p>Tendulkar, 23, made a superb 169 in a losing cause against South Africa in Cape Town at the start of the year and was run out for 88 in the drawn second test in Trinidad, but his latest effort could prove the most significant for his side as they seek to improve their disappointing overseas record.</p>
<p>The little genius had to work hard early on against some fine fast bowling from Curtly Ambrose and Ian Bishop on a pitch which offered encouragement to the quicker men, but survived to teach the less experienced Mervyn Dillon a few harsh lessons.</p>
<p>The rookie bowler conceded 33 in his first three overs and was hit for three more boundaries in the same over by Tendulkar as he progressed smoothly past 50 off just 75 balls.</p>
<p>He celebrated by hooking Franklyn Rose over square leg for six, followed by an exquisite back foot drive to the extra-cover boundary to reach the tea interval on 60 not out, but was unable to keep the same tempo going in the final session.</p>
<p>The third wicket stand was worth 170 by the time Tendulkar finally departed eight runs short of a well-deserved 12th test hundred, brilliantly caught by Sherwin Campbell in the gully off Bishop off what television replays suggested was a no-ball. He hit 14 fours and a six.</p>
<p>West Indies bowled 26 no-balls in all and stand-in West Indian captain Brian Lara was ultimately grateful to conclude a day which had started reasonably well.</p>
<p>Resuming on 240 for seven after Friday's rest day, West Indies added an additional 58 runs in 65 minutes in the morning with Shivnarine Chanderpaul once again immovable.</p>
<p>The Guyanese left-hander finally ran out of partners having advanced to a test-best unbeaten 137, including 13 fours, which almost single-handedly saved his team from unravelling at the seams.</p>
<p>Venkatesh Prasad finally trapped last man Dillon lbw for a duck to return figures of five for 82 in 31.4 overs, but his efforts looked in danger of being wasted when the Indian openers were sent back either side of lunch.</p>
<p>Enter Tendulkar and Dravid, whose efforts have given their side a fair chance of recording their first test win in the Caribbean for 21 years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BARB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WEIND">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRIDGETOWN, Barbados"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BARBADOS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
