<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475259" id="root" date="1997-03-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: Russian soldiers kill three on Tajik-Afghan border.</title>
<headline>Russian soldiers kill three on Tajik-Afghan border.</headline>
<dateline>ALMATY, Kazakhstan 1997-03-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three people trying to slip into Tajikistan from neighbouring Afghanistan were shot dead by Russian border guards late on Friday, a guards' spokesman said.</p>
<p>Speaking by phone on Saturday, he said the incident had taken place some 200 km (125 miles) south of Dushanbe.</p>
<p>The dead had been trying to carry 60 kg (132 lbs) of narcotics into Tajikistan, he added.</p>
<p>Russian border guards in Tajikistan say they have so far this year intercepted over 600 kg (1,320 lbs) of drugs coming into the former Soviet republic from Afghanistan.</p>
<p>The drugs -- opium and its derivatives -- make their way across Tajikistan to other republics of the former Soviet Union and into Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Around 20,000 Russian peacekeepers and border guards serve in Tajikistan -- a remote, mountainous Central Asian state which also borders China -- viewing themselves as a bulwark against a possible advent of militant Islam from Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Despite a ceasefire agreed last December between the secular government and the country's united Islamist opposition, which ended a four-year civil war, Tajikistan remains unsettled as groups of fighters with unclear loyalties and drug couriers continue to operate from bases in Afghanistan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TADZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY, Kazakhstan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
