<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475316" id="root" date="1997-03-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China firms will not exploit post-97 HK - businessman.</title>
<headline>China firms will not exploit post-97 HK - businessman.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-03-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>China-funded enterprises will not seek special treatment in Hong Kong after the British territory reverts to Beijing's control this year, a leading Chinese businessman was quoted as saying on Saturday.</p>
<p>The Chinese-backed newspaper Ta Kung Pao quoted China Merchant Holdings Co Ltd president Li Yinfei as saying his firm and other state-owned enterprises would continue to abide by Hong Kong's rules when doing business in the territory after the July 1 handover.</p>
<p>Li told a business seminar on Hong Kong in the Chinese capital that Beijing-funded companies would not try to seek special privileges.</p>
<p>Hong Kong, a British colony for over 150 years, reverts to China at midnight on June 30. China has pledged to grant Hong Kong a high degree of autonomy and to retain its capitalist system for 50 years after the handover. But some pro-democracy politicians in Hong Kong fear that Chinese companies will try to exploit the transition to gain an edge over their Hong Kong counterparts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
