<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475334" id="root" date="1997-03-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: First Palestinian fatality on day 10 of unrest.</title>
<headline>First Palestinian fatality on day 10 of unrest.</headline>
<byline>Hamouda Hassan</byline>
<dateline>RAMALLAH, West Bank 1997-03-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli soldiers killed a Palestinian in clashes at Ramallah on Saturday, the first fatality in 10 days of unrest sparked by Israel breaking ground for a Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Palestinian hospital officials said Abdullah Khalil Abdullah, 20, was shot in the back with live ammunition during clashes at the outskirts of Ramallah Palestinian self-rule enclave. He was a student at a nearby university.</p>
<p>&quot;This killing is a declaration of war,&quot; said Palestinian Authority Finance Minister Mohammed Nashashibi, as Palestinian ministers prepared for a cabinet meeting in self-rule Gaza.</p>
<p>After the meeting, Culture Minister Yasser Abed Rabbo slammed Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>
<p>&quot;Netanyahu is responsible for every drop of blood, Palestinian or Israeli, because of his policy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Abed Rabbo said the Authority saw no use in talks with Israel &quot;as long as the policy of expansion, confiscation of land and violation of the (peace) agreement continue&quot;.</p>
<p>Late on Saturday, a Palestinian security forces honour guard escorted Abdullah's body at his home village of Beit Sahour, beside the hilltop called Jabal Abu Ghneim in Arabic or Har Homa in Hebrew where the settlement is being built.</p>
<p>Witnesses said several thousand people turned out to receive the body. Abdullah is to be buried on Sunday.</p>
<p>The death increased fears of an upsurge violence at a time when peace moves are threatened by Palestinian outrage over the new settlement and Israeli anger over an Islamist suicide bomber who killed three women in a Tel Aviv cafe last week.</p>
<p>Thousands of Israeli police, backed by tanks and helicopters, were on high alert ahead of warnings unrest would peak on Sunday -- the annual &quot;Land Day&quot; when Israeli Arabs stage protests against government confiscation of lands.</p>
<p>On Saturday at least 24 Palestinians were wounded when Israeli troops fired rubber bullets at demonstrators stoning them at the outskirts of Bethlehem, Ramallah, and Bir Zeit in the West Bank. Two Arabs were also wounded by live ammunition.</p>
<p>There were also clashes at Qalandya refugee camp near Ramallah but no reports of Palestinian casualties.</p>
<p>The Israeli army confirmed a Palestinian was killed during clashes and said it was checking the circumstances in cooperation with Palestinian authorities.</p>
<p>It said two border policemen were injured by stones in Qalandya and an officer was injured by stones in Ramallah.</p>
<p>At Bethlehem, protesters burned an effigy of Netanyahu.</p>
<p>The Palestinian Authority on Saturday rejected Israel's conditions for resuming peace talks.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat told reporters in Gaza on his return from Cairo: &quot;Netanyahu's orders and decisions are escalating the situation in the whole area.&quot;</p>
<p>Arafat's adviser Nabil Abu Rdainah said: &quot;What is needed is the implementation of the agreements and the return to the negotiating table without any preconditions or restrictions.</p>
<p>&quot;The new Israeli conditions are not acceptable.&quot;</p>
<p>Netanyahu, after meeting U.S. peace envoy Dennis Ross on Friday, demanded Arafat arrest militants, dismantle guerrilla groups and tighten security cooperation. He denied Ross asked Israel to make any reciprocal gesture.</p>
<p>Arafat, asked by reporters if Ross in their meeting in Rabat on Thursday requested him to calm tensions in areas controlled by his Palestinian Authority that abut Israeli army positions where there have been clashes said:</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, they are against the violence, especially the violence of settlement and the Judaization of Jerusalem.&quot;</p>
<p>Israel says Arafat gave militants the impression they had a green light for attacks. The Authority denies the charge.</p>
<p>Abed Rabbo warned the United States against adopting what he said was Netanyahu's line against the Palestinians.</p>
<p>&quot;The main issue is the American administration should not go along with Netanyahu's propaganda about violence while Netanyahu himself brought violence to the region,&quot; Abed Rabbo said.</p>
<p>Palestinians say settlement building in Jerusalem preempts negotiations that are to be held on its status in final peace talks which have yet to resume. They demand it be halted.</p>
<p>Europe's Middle East envoy, Miguel Angel Moratinos, speaking to reporters after meeting Arafat in Gaza, said political issues should be the top priority in peace talks but that he would convey to Netanyahu that Arafat condemned terror.</p>
<p>The Israeli Foreign Ministry on Saturday slammed as an obstacle to peace a call by a committee headed by Morocco's King Hassan urging Arab and Moslem states to reconsider ties with Israel over the settlement building.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RAMALLAH, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
