<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475429" id="root" date="1997-03-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French doctors strike to go on, government firm.</title>
<headline>French doctors strike to go on, government firm.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>French junior hospital doctors vowed on Saturday to continue into next week a 17-day-old strike over the government's disputed plan to cap costs in the health service, a spokesman for the strikers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are determined, and we are calling for the protest to be toughened,&quot; the spokesman said. He said the strikers agreed at a meeting the stoppage would go on until at least Tuesday.</p>
<p>Six surgeons' unions have come out in support of the strike, saying on Friday evening they would join it next Thursday.</p>
<p>The junior doctors, on strike in 22 of the country's 26 teaching hospitals, are demanding the scrapping of automatic fines on doctors in regions which exceed government health spending targets.</p>
<p>The government looked no less determined to go ahead with the reform, which is part of its drive to bring down the welfare deficit and help France qualify for a single European currency in 1999.</p>
<p>It appeared to put the seal on the provisions disputed by the strikers by having them published on Saturday in the Official Gazette.</p>
<p>The provisions were agreed between the national health insurance fund and two health professionals' trade unions which support the reform.</p>
<p>Social Affairs Minister Jacques Barrot has said the measure was essential as a safeguard against overspending until new standard medical procedures take root.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
