<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475443" id="root" date="1997-03-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Delta hunger striker moved to Frankfurt hospital.</title>
<headline>Delta hunger striker moved to Frankfurt hospital.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-03-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Delta Air Lines staff member needed urgent medical attention on Saturday after six days on hunger strike at Frankfurt airport in protest over large-scale jobs cuts, a union official said.</p>
<p>Ibrahim Keklik, one of five Delta staff camping out in front of the airline's check-in desk, was taken to the airport clinic for a blood transfusion in the morning after he became weak and disoriented and lost feeling in his hands.</p>
<p>He was expected to return to his position in the afternoon, having agreed to treatment on condition that he continue his protest, Delta's works council chairman Walter Czogolla said.</p>
<p>&quot;It has made us very nervous,&quot; Czogolla told Reuters. &quot;But his condition does not seem to be as grave as we thought. The others seem to be holding up relatively well. They want to go on until we get an offer worth negotiating.&quot;</p>
<p>The conflict between the airline and its employees centres on Delta's plans to cut staff from 850 to 250 in Frankfurt and drop eight of its 14 daily flights.</p>
<p>The works council wants job guarantees for the 250 remaining staff and wants Delta to invest 180 million marks, or its expected financial improvement from the restructuring measures, in a social plan valid until 2003.</p>
<p>No immediate comment was available from Delta, which has said in the past that union demands were unrealistic but that it was ready to talk.</p>
<p>A meeting was scheduled between the works council and Delta on Saturday afternoon but may not go ahead because of Keklik's condition, Czogolla said.</p>
<p>Four men and a woman are involved in the protest. They are are mainly surviving on orange juice, coffee and vitamin pills, Czogolla said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am offering myself up for all the workers,&quot; said striker Ayhan Dagtekin, who appeared alert and robust. &quot;The health issue is not a factor for me. I will go on to the death.&quot;</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
