<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475666" id="root" date="1997-03-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Prisoner dies in explosion in Colombian jail.</title>
<headline>Prisoner dies in explosion in Colombian jail.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-03-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A prisoner in Bogota's high- security jail was killed when a bomb he was handling exploded, a prison spokesman said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Another inmate was seriously injured in the explosion.</p>
<p>The blast occurred late on Saturday in an area of the La Picota jail adjoining the wing where the Cali drug cartel bosses, the Rodriguez Orejuela brothers, are imprisoned.</p>
<p>The man who died was William Infante, 33, the contract killer who murdered the leader of the left-wing Patriotic Union (UP) party in 1987, the prison spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was an incident in which a prisoner was handling explosives. We do not yet know exactly what type of explosive it was. The prisoner died in the blast,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>He said it was not yet clear how Infante, serving a 24-year jail term, had obtained the explosives.</p>
<p>According to Colombia's leading El Tiempo newspaper, Infante murdered UP leader Jaime Pardo Leal on the orders of the late drug trafficker Gonzalo Rodriguez Gacha, a henchman of cocaine kingpin Pablo Escobar, former head of the Medellin cartel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
