<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475620" id="root" date="1997-03-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Foreign force for Albania despite anger over boat.</title>
<headline>Foreign force for Albania despite anger over boat.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Weeks</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-03-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania accepted deployment of an Italian-led multinational force to secure aid supplies but angry residents in the rebel-held port of Vlore warned Italian troops on Sunday to stay away.</p>
<p>Parliament, dominated by President Sali Berisha's rightist Democratic Party, voted 97 to one to accept the foreign security force, expected to number about 2,500 troops and police.</p>
<p>Italy, trying to head off a new wave of illegal Albanian immigrants, wants to the force to start work as soon as possible and diplomats said some advance units could arrive this week.</p>
<p>The force will secure the Adriatic ports of Durres and Vlore, where anti-Berisha rebels are in control, and Tirana airport as well as escorting humanitarian relief convoys.</p>
<p>In Vlore, about 7,000 people rallied to denounce Italy after one of its navy ships collided with a crowded Albanian refugee boat in the Adriatic on Friday.</p>
<p>The boat, which left Vlore with many locals aboard, sank after the Italian ship tried to intercept it. Tirana said at least 83 people died. Thirty-four were rescued.</p>
<p>Berisha ordered a day of national mourning on Monday, with flags at half mast. Parliament stood in silence for a minute on Sunday in respect for the dead.</p>
<p>Emotions ran especially high in Vlore and many people at the rally vowed to avenge the victims if Italian troops dared to deploy in the port as planned.</p>
<p>&quot;I warn Italian soldiers not to come to Vlore, otherwise they will be killed,&quot; said Aida, 35.</p>
<p>In a statement to the crowd, the self-styled Committee of Public Salvation called on Italy to compensate the families of the dead and do everything possible to recover the bodies.</p>
<p>&quot;We accuse the Italian government of intentionally sinking the Albanian patrol boat and call it an irresponsible killer,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Diplomats in Tirana said the might delay sending troops to Vlore because of the anger there.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation in Vlore was already fragile. This (the sinking) came at a very unfortunate time and has raised passions in the region. It might be better to deploy elsewhere first,&quot; a European Union diplomat said.</p>
<p>The force of troops and police is being put together after receiving approval from the United Nations on Friday. Among the countries expected to participate are Italy, France, Greece, Spain and Portugal.</p>
<p>Albania has been swept by violence since January when a string of popular, but bogus, investment schemes failed and wiped out millions of dollars in savings. Berisha is widely blamed for having let the unregulated schemes flourish.</p>
<p>A popular uprising swept the country in March, with army depots looted and thousands of automatic weapons seized. Much of southern Albania, including Vlore, remains outside of government control.</p>
<p>While rebels control main towns and villages in the south, scores of armed gangs have terrorised the countryside, robbing, looting and pillaging. There are daily reports of killing.</p>
<p>Italy and Greece fear the Albanian crisis on their borders could trigger another massive wave of illegal immigration, as happened in 1991 and 1992 after the ruthless Stalinist regime which ruled for 45 years collapsed.</p>
<p>More than 13,000 Albanians have risked the hazardous trip across the Adriatic to Italy since March 13.</p>
<p>Italy and Greece also hope the protection force will help to reassure the 3.4 million population and clear the way for planned early elections in June.</p>
<p>The multinational force commanders could find themselves facing other problems as well with deep divisions emerging in the all-party crisis government set up earlier this month.</p>
<p>Berisha's spokesman Genc Pollo said the unity government was &quot;in a new situation&quot; after several parties in the cabinet met the self-proclaimed committees of national salvation in Vlore last week.</p>
<p>&quot;Each party has certain public responsibilities and must decide either to be on the side of the legitimate government or on the side of the communist rebels that want to overthrow the government by force of arms,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
