<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475748" id="root" date="1997-03-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>YEMEN: Gunman shoots at Yemen pupils, two teachers dead.</title>
<headline>Gunman shoots at Yemen pupils, two teachers dead.</headline>
<dateline>SANAA 1997-03-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A man opened fire with a machinegun on hundreds of children at two schools in the Yemeni capital Sanaa on Sunday killing at least two teachers and wounding six pupils, witnesses said.</p>
<p>They said the man, believed to be a disgruntled former bus driver at one of the schools, opened fire at random as the children, aged between six and 18, lined up in the playgrounds before morning lessons.</p>
<p>Yemeni police arrested the man at the second school, but refused to comment on the shootings, which the witnesses said spread panic among the more than 1,000 students in the adjacent schools in the middle class suburb of Asbahi.</p>
<p>They said the headmistress, in her 40s, of the first school, Tala'eh, was killed in the shooting and a male teacher, in his 30s, was killed in the second school, Musa Ibn al-Naseer.</p>
<p>At least three children of unknown ages were wounded in each of the private schools. They were rushed to hospital, but there was no word on their condition.</p>
<p>Some of the panic-stricken children dived for cover while others ran away during the shooting sprees, the witnesses said.</p>
<p>The schools were closed after the shootings, which residents said were the first such incident in the capital of this impoverished Arab state.</p>
<p>The witnesses said they believed the gunman, who walked from the first school to the second, was angry over his sacking by the headmistress of the Tala'eh school.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANAA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YEMEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
