<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475736" id="root" date="1997-03-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Arab ministers recommend isolating Israel.</title>
<headline>Arab ministers recommend isolating Israel.</headline>
<byline>Miral Fahmy</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-03-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A draft resolution circulating at an Arab foreign ministers meeting in Cairo on Sunday recommended Arab states reactivate the Arab economic boycott of Israel.</p>
<p>It also suggested Arab states stop normalisation with the Jewish state, close Israeli offices and missions and pull out of multilateral talks on aspects of Middle East peace.</p>
<p>The measures are in response to the Israeli government's policy of settling Jews in disputed East Jerusalem, a policy Arab states says is in violation of commitments Israel made in earlier stages of Middle East peace talks.</p>
<p>Israel's decision to start breaking ground for a new Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem two weeks ago have sparked 11 days of clashes with Palestinians in the West Bank.</p>
<p>Arab and Islamic states have been hinting for more than a week at retaliation against Israel but they had not spelled out in detail the steps they were planning to take.</p>
<p>The draft resolution, confirmed in most details by a senior Arab League official, makes some specific recommendations.</p>
<p>The draft says: &quot;The council of the Arab League recommends stopping all normalisation steps which have been taken with Israel in the framework of the peace process and stopping to deal with it (Israel), including closing offices and missions.&quot;</p>
<p>These steps would remain in force &quot;until Israel obeys the Madrid frame of reference and the principle of land for peace, and carries out the agreements, undertaking and commitments which the parties concerned have reached on all tracks during peace talks,&quot; the resolution says.</p>
<p>It adds: &quot;(It recommends) suspending Arab participation in the multilateral talks and continuing to maintain the primary Arab boycott and reactivating it until just peace is achieved.&quot;</p>
<p>Said Kamal, an assistant secretary general of the Arab League, told reporters earlier that the ministers would suggest to their heads of state that their countries suspend dealings with Israel and close down any Israeli offices.</p>
<p>&quot;The council (of foreign ministers) recommended stopping the normalisation process...and stopping all dealings and offices and missions as well as suspending conferences called under the multilateral track,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a recommendation that will be submitted to the presidents and kings (of the Arab states),&quot; he added.</p>
<p>An Egyptian official said Egypt, the most populous and most influential Arab country, was fully behind the resolution, despite possible complications posed by its 1979 peace treaty with Israel.</p>
<p>The official said the ministers reached consensus on the resolution although two unnamed states had some reservations.</p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, blamed by Israel's partners in the Middle East peace talks for the current problems, said on Sunday he doubted Arab nations would cut ties with Israel.</p>
<p>&quot;I would urge the Arab countries to think of their larger interests, their longer interests, as I urge the Palestinians for the necessity of peace,&quot; Netanyahu told CBS television's &quot;Face the Nation&quot; programme.</p>
<p>Kamal said the ministerial recommendation would be based on the resolutions of the last Arab summit, which said Arab states would reconsider the gestures made towards Israel if the Jewish state does not fulfil its commitments.</p>
<p>The Arab summit took place in Cairo in June, at a time when Israel's neighbours were still waiting to see whether Netanyahu would try to carry out his hardline election pledges.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
