<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475723" id="root" date="1997-03-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore telecoms D-Day on April 1.</title>
<headline>Singapore telecoms D-Day on April 1.</headline>
<byline>Chris Johnson</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore's telecommunications industry takes a giant step into the free market on Tuesday, opening up domestic mobile phone and pager services to competition.</p>
<p>It may not be radical by Western or even Asian standards, but the change represents a significant shift away from the centralised direction of many key industries in the tiny city-state, analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;It is Deregulation Day. It will be the first time the local market has seen competition and it will be a better deal for consumers,&quot; said Gautam Kapoor, telecommunications analyst at ING-Baring. &quot;It is a new era for Singapore.&quot;</p>
<p>On April 1, Singapore Telecommunications Ltd (SingTel), 82 percent-owned by state investment company Temasek Holdings, will face the first challenge to its domestic services since it was privatised in 1992.</p>
<p>SingTel will have one new competitor, MobileOne (M1), in the mobile phone market and three new rival pager services as the door is opened to full competition across the board from 2000.</p>
<p>From then, several companies will vie for Singapore customers in all services.</p>
<p>British Telecommunications Plc, U.S. giant AT&amp;T Corp and several local companies say they may bid for the one or two basic telephone service licences on offer from 2000. Another one or two mobile phone operators will also be added.</p>
<p>How the cellular competition shapes up from Tuesday should be a good pointer to the eventual shape of the fully deregulated market, analysts say.</p>
<p>Mobile phones and pagers account for one-fifth of Singapore's telecommunications market, or more than S$800 million (US$555 million). It represents the fastest expanding telecommunications service and, with Internet and computer services, is considered the industry's future, telecommunications firms say.</p>
<p>But SingTel is expected to survive happily.</p>
<p>&quot;These reforms don't mean the end, or even the beginning of the end, for Singapore Telecom,&quot; Kapoor said. &quot;And the Singapore government looks set to retain its majority stake in SingTel.&quot;</p>
<p>However, competition means customers will see their bills drop even faster for better services. Charges for 100 minutes of mobile phone air time a month have already slid to S$46 a month from S$70 two years ago.</p>
<p>Over the same period, basic telephone charges have also dropped as SingTel prepared for opposition. Average IDD collection rates have fallen 20 percent to S$1.86 per minute.</p>
<p>In the S$200 million a year pager market, one new competitor, Hutchison Paging, is already threatening stiff price cuts to lure customers from SingTel.</p>
<p>Hutchison is a joint venture of Hutchison Whampoa Ltd, Intraco Ltd and Teledata. The other new paging firms are MobileOne and ST Messaging.</p>
<p>MobileOne is a joint venture of Britain's Cable &amp; Wireless, Hong Kong Telecommunications, Keppel Telecom and Singapore Press Holdings.</p>
<p>Analysts said competition will inevitably erode revenues for SingTel, which has recently enjoyed almost 50 percent margins.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen from other markets that when competition comes in, monopolies' profits come down,&quot; Kapoor said. &quot;But when competition comes in, the existing operators often find ways of improving efficiency significantly, which can improve margins.&quot;</p>
<p>Most analysts expect SingTel to report a 13 percent rise in net profit to around S$1.68 billion in its financial year to March 31, 1997, but say competition will push this growth down to 11 percent next year.</p>
<p>&quot;In the short term, the impact of competition will be to pare back slightly telecoms rates to customers. In the longer term it will help cut charges more dramatically,&quot; said John Chessher, telecoms analyst at Schroders in Bangkok.</p>
<p>($1 = S$1.44)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
