<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475883" id="root" date="1997-03-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Year of tumult in Indian politics.</title>
<headline>Year of tumult in Indian politics.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Congress Party's decision to withdraw support from Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's centre-left alliance casts doubt on the survival of the United Front government.</p>
<p>Following is a chronology since last year's general election.</p>
<p>April-May 1996 - General election held over several weeks defeats ruling Congress Party and makes Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) the largest single party in parliament.</p>
<p>May 16 - BJP leader Atal Bihari Vajpayee sworn in as prime minister without assurance of majority support in parliament.</p>
<p>May 28 - Vajpayee resigns as prime minister because of impeding defeat in parliamentary vote.</p>
<p>June 1 - H.D. Deve Gowda sworn in at head of United Front, a coalition of 13 parties which Congress supports but does not join.</p>
<p>June 28 - Communists join government for first time since independence from Britain in 1947.</p>
<p>July 11 - Delhi court summons Congress president P.V. Narasimha Rao to testify as co-accused in cheating case.</p>
<p>September 22 - Rao resigns as president of Congress Party.</p>
<p>September 23 - Sitaram Kesri elected Congress president.</p>
<p>October 11 - Uttar Pradesh state election returns a hung assembly; local power struggle sharpens conflicts between Congress and coalition parties at national level.</p>
<p>February 28 - Government strengthened by daring, market friendly budget.</p>
<p>March 19 -Bahujan Samaj Party (BSP), a powerful low-caste party, deserts alliance with Congress in Uttar Pradesh to form government with BJP.</p>
<p>March 30 - Congress withdraws support from United Front.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
