<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475824" id="root" date="1997-03-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Jim Carrey still lies in top spot at U.S. box office.</title>
<headline>Jim Carrey still lies in top spot at U.S. box office.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jim Carrey easily remained king of the box office as his latest comedy, &quot;Liar Liar,&quot; pulled in $24.2 million over the weekend, according to studio estimates released on Sunday.</p>
<p>Opening in second with $14.3 million was &quot;The Devil's Own,&quot; a $90 million thriller that its co-star, Brad Pitt, described as an &quot;irresponsible bit of filmmaking.&quot; &quot;The Devil's Own&quot; was the only strong performer among the four new entries in the top 10.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, &quot;The English Patient,&quot; which grabbed nine Oscars including best picture at the Academy Awards ceremony on Monday, rose two places to eighth with $3.0 million. Walt Disney Co.'s Miramax Films, which released the wartime romantic epic, capitalized on the Oscar publicity by boosting its screen total by 407 to 1,409. In its 20th week of release, the movie has earned $67.6 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Liar Liar,&quot; in which Carrey plays a lawyer who must tell the truth for one day, fell just 23 percent from its opening round, and its 10-day total stands at $69.8 million. Its per-screen average of $8,482 (from 2,853 screens) was the highest in the top 10. The movie is released by Universal Pictures, a unit of Seagram Co. Ltd..</p>
<p>&quot;The Devil's Own&quot; stars Pitt as an IRA gunrunner opposite Harrison Ford as a Boston policeman. Pitt had tried to quit the production until he was threatened with a hefty lawsuit. Script problems and reported disputes with Ford led him to tell Newsweek magazine recently that the film &quot;was the most irresponsible bit of filmmaking -- if you can call it that -- I've ever seen.&quot;</p>
<p>This caused a stir and his handlers forced him to clarify his comments by saying that they referred to his dilemma before shooting, not to the actual movie. Critics were generally mixed. A Variety poll of reviewers in New York, Los Angeles, Chicago and Washington showed that 10 liked it, 10 did not and 15 were mixed.</p>
<p>The movie, which is released by Sony Corp.'s Columbia Pictures, averaged $5,704 from 2,507 screens for the Friday to Sunday period. Its gross to date, after opening on Wednesday, stands at $18.1 million.</p>
<p>Last week's No. 2, &quot;Selena&quot; suffered the largest percentage drop in the top 10, 52 percent, as it slipped to third with $5.6 million in its second round. The biopic about the slain Tejano singer is released by Time Warner Inc.'s Warner Bros. It averaged $2,990 from 1,873 screens, and its 10-day total stands at $21.2 million.</p>
<p>Also down a notch, to fourth, was &quot;Return of the Jedi&quot; with $4.5 million. The third installment in the reissued &quot;Star Wars&quot; trilogy averaged $1,837 as its three-week total rose to $34.8 million. The lifetime domestic total for the 1983 movie stands at $298.5 million, which makes it the seventh-highest grossing picture in U.S. history. It is released by 20th Century Fox, a unit of News Corp..</p>
<p>Opening in fifth was Disney's basketball comedy &quot;The Sixth Man,&quot; which earned $4.3 million. It averaged a decent $3,504. The other new entries were Fox's seventh-placed &quot;Turbo: A Power Rangers Movie&quot; with $3.5 million ($1,656 average) and New Line Cinema's urban comedy &quot;B.A.P.S.&quot; with $2.8 million ($2,326 average) in ninth. New Line is owned by Time Warner.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
