<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475940" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: HORSE RACING-PITMAN COMPLETES STEEPLECHASE GRAND SLAM.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-PITMAN COMPLETES STEEPLECHASE GRAND SLAM.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>British trainer Jenny Pitman saddled her first winner of the Irish Grand National when Mudahim won at Fairyhouse on Monday to complete an impressive steeplechase grand slam.</p>
<p>Pitman's 13-2 chance, ridden by Ireland's Jason Titley, edged out Arthur Moore's 14-1 shot Amble Speedy by a short head after a dramatic finish to the three miles five furlongs (5.8 km) race.</p>
<p>&quot;I honestly thought we were beaten. I am a bit surprised to have won,&quot; said Pitman after the photo-finish result was announced.</p>
<p>&quot;I had already won the English, Welsh and Scottish Grand Nationals so this completes the collection nicely.&quot;</p>
<p>Fortune smiled on winning jockey Titley who was given the ride on Mudahim only after his regular partner Rodney Farrant was ruled out through injury.</p>
<p>Titley, who had already walked away from the unsaddling enclosure thinking he had lost the race before the official result was announced, had combined with Pitman to win the Aintree Grand National with Royal Athlete in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't believe it. I was sure we were beaten,&quot; Titley said. &quot;He (Mutahim) will stay all day.&quot;</p>
<p>Titley is booked to ride Nathen Lad for Pitman in next Saturday's Aintree Grand National.</p>
<p>Amble Speedy's jockey Francis Woods, who was looking for his third Irish Grand National win in four years, said he was disappointed not to have held on for victory after his mount edged ahead of Mudahim after jumping the last.</p>
<p>Gordon Richards-trained 9-2 favourite The Grey Monk finished a further 11 lengths further back in third place.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
