<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="476013" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER-LEVERKUSEN CAST OFF CAUTION, AIM FOR TITLE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-LEVERKUSEN CAST OFF CAUTION, AIM FOR TITLE.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Gray</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bayer Leverkusen, just two points behind Bundesliga leaders Bayern Munich, have finally cast off months of caution by staking their claim for the title.</p>
<p>The club, which escaped relegation by only two points last season, had set itself the modest goal of a UEFA Cup place.</p>
<p>After months of shadow boxing, when officials and players refused to discuss their title chances even though they had kept pace with the leaders from the start, the gloves are now off.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm only looking above us now. I can't do anything else any more,&quot; coach Christoph Daum said.</p>
<p>&quot;You can't just talk about the UEFA Cup when you're so close to the title,&quot; said former Germany striker Rudi Voeller, now Leverkusen's director of sport.</p>
<p>Leverkusen, chasing their first ever Bundesliga crown, notched up an important win on Saturday by beating UEFA Cup semifinalists Schalke 2-0 at home.</p>
<p>The unfashionable side have shown they can live with the best this season, thrashing Bayern 5-2 a few weeks ago and inflicting a 4-2 defeat on champions Borussia Dortmund on the opening day of the season.</p>
<p>&quot;The team's been fantastic. The way they've played is really impressive. Every player is ready to give everything in every game, even to go through the pain barrier,&quot; Daum said.</p>
<p>&quot;This final phase will be a game of nerves. Little things will make the difference. I've got a young team but they want to be involved when it comes to who wins the title.&quot;</p>
<p>But Daum, a master motivator and expert at putting pyschological pressure on his opponents, still insists his team are the outsiders in the four-way fight for the title.</p>
<p>Bayern lead the pack thanks to a 1-0 win over Bremen on Saturday. Dortmund are third, a point behind Leverkusen, while VfB Stuttgart are a further point behind in fourth place.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want to demand the title,&quot; Daum said. &quot;We're only the Davids in the fight with the Goliaths of Munich, Dortmund and Stuttgart.&quot;</p>
<p>But those who know their Bible will recall who won that particular fight.</p>
<p>And those who know their soccer will be well aware that Daum captured the league title in his first full season in charge at both VfB Stuttgart and Besiktas Istanbul. Few would bet against him completing the hat-trick.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
