<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="476060" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Rebels in Zaire rail hub of Kamina-sources.</title>
<headline>Rebels in Zaire rail hub of Kamina-sources.</headline>
<dateline>LUBUMBASGHI, Zaire 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rebels fighting to topple veteran President Mobutu Sese Seko have taken control of the rail hub of Kamina in Zaire's southern mining province of Shaba, expatriate sources said on Monday.</p>
<p>The rebels moved into town, which was once a major military base with an airfield, on Sunday or early Monday without a fight, the sources added.</p>
<p>Kamina is 600 km (400 miles) or a 24-hour rail journey north of the provincial capital Lubumbashi, a declared rebel target.</p>
<p>&quot;The railway line was cut at Kamina. The rebels are in Kamina,&quot; one expatriate source told Reuters.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear where the soldiers from the town had gone but the sources said that many had already pulled out, leaving just a handful of paramilitary gendarmes.</p>
<p>There were no reports of looting, the scourge of Zairean civilians in the path of retreating ill-disciplined Zairean soldiers.</p>
<p>The sources said that the rebels had advanced on foot along the railway line from Kalemie on Lake Tanganyika, a town they seized earlier in the conflict.</p>
<p>The sources had no details on numbers of rebels in Kamina.</p>
<p>The Sizarail Belgian and South African consortium operates the rail line, which supplies the diamond-mining province of Kasai with goods from Southern Africa. Before it took over the then dilapidated line two years ago, supplies were flown in.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUBUMBASGHI, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
