<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="476048" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Cricket-Waugh century gives Australian victory.</title>
<headline>Cricket-Waugh century gives Australian victory.</headline>
<dateline>PORT ELIZABETH, South Africa 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>A brilliant, unbeaten 115 from Mark Waugh led Australia to a crushing seven-wicket victory over South Africa in the second of seven one-day internationals on Monday.</p>
<p>Waugh's 10th one-day century levelled the series after South Africa's equally emphatic six-wicket win on Saturday and gave Australia a much needed boost after 13 defeats in their last 19 matches.</p>
<p>Needing 222 to win, Waugh added 107 with twin brother Steve (50 not out) after off-spinner Pat Symcox had taken two wickets in two balls.</p>
<p>Mark Waugh's innings spanned just 125 balls with eight boundaries and three sixes. His brother's half century came from 52 balls with five fours and a six.</p>
<p>Captain Mark Taylor's slump in form plumbed new depths in an innings of 17. His dismissal, caught at slip , was almost a relief.</p>
<p>Symcox then had Stuart Law (33) caught at mid-wicket and Shane Warne, put in at number four, was lbw to him first ball.</p>
<p>Mark Waugh made amends by walloping Symcox for 32 runs in his last two overs. He reached his century with two successive sixes over mid-wicket.</p>
<p>Taylor had put South Africa in on a green pitch under overcast skies and Queensland fast bowler Adam Dale, in only his second game, quickly reduced the home side to 16 for three in eight overs.</p>
<p>Dale had local debutant Louis Koen caught at second slip for a duck, Adam Bacher caught at mid-off for three and then bowled Daryll Cullinan for another duck.</p>
<p>But Jacques Kallis and Jonty Rhodes added 104 for the fourth wicket to rescue the innings before Rhodes drove a tame catch to mid-on to depart for 57 with seven fours. Kallis and Hansie Cronje (31) added another 61 for the fifth wicket to continue the recovery.</p>
<p>Cronje and Kallis were both bowled by Jason Gillespie in the 45th over. Kallis's 82 came from 118 balls with five fours and a six.</p>
<p>When the teams lined up for the national anthems before the start, Australia had to endure Waltzing Matilda and not Advance Australia Fair after a mix-up in tapes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT ELIZABETH, South Africa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
