<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="476291" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ashland, Marathon coy on downstream merger talks.</title>
<headline>Ashland, Marathon coy on downstream merger talks.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ashland Inc said Monday that it is still looking for a partner for its refining and marketing business, though the company would neither confirm nor deny a report that it is about to announce a deal with Marathon Oil Co.</p>
<p>&quot;We announced in December that we were going to aggressively seek a joint venture partnership or other strategic alliance and we are actively persuing that,&quot; said Chuck Rice, a spokesman at the company's Ashland, Kentucky head office.  </p>
<p>A report published last Thursday by Oil Price Information Service, an oil industry publication, said that an &quot;imminent&quot; deal would give Marathon 52 percent of Ashland's three U.S. refineries and retail network.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been linked with several companies&quot; since the December announcement, Rice noted.</p>
<p>Among those previously rumored are Amoco Corp and BP America, both companies which have a major presence in the middle of the U.S. where Ashland is concentrated.</p>
<p>Marathon also declined to comment on whether or not the two companies had a deal.  </p>
<p>&quot;That talk has been going on for months, but we do not have a comment on that issue,&quot; said John Farrell, a Marathon spokesman.</p>
<p>Ashland, under pressure last year from investor Providence Capital to improve its performance, announced a major restructuring in December. However, the main plank of the deal has yet to materialize and the company's shares have been underperforming.  </p>
<p>Under the restructuring, the largest section of Ashland Inc was bundled into the Ashland Petroleum Group, including the large Catlettsburg, Kentucky refinery and two smaller plants at St. Paul, Minnesota and Canton, Ohio which together have capacity to process slighly more than 350,000 barrels of crude a day.</p>
<p>Also in this group are 750 company-owned outlets (SuperAmerica, Ashland) plus a 523-store branded jobber network, the Valvoline motor oil business and pipeline and other distribution assets mainly grouped under Scurlock Permian interests.  </p>
<p>Ashland, after appointing CS First Boston advisor last December, said earlier this month that it is seeking an initial public offering (IPO) of 3.1 million shares in its exploration unit, Blazer Energy Inc. The company plans to offer 82.3 percent of the company to Ashland Inc shareholders after offering 17.7 percent in the IPO.</p>
<p>Blazer Energy consists of an Appalachian natural gas operation and about 20,000 barrels per day of crude oil production in Nigeria.  </p>
<p>Also, as part of the restructuring, Ashland said it will merge the coal businesses in which it holds controlling interests, Ashland Coal and Arch Mineral of St. Louis.</p>
<p>Ashland's chemical business, which had operating income of $169 million in 1996 and is the company's fastest growing sector, continued to make acquisitions in the first quarter.</p>
<p>The company also has an ongoing program to buy back up to a million common shares.  </p>
<p>Despite the company's efforts, however, its shares have performed badly since early December, dropping by about 15 percent to $40 3/8 on Friday and trailing the Dow Jones Inustrial average by the same amount over the period.</p>
<p>-- (( New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1623))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
