<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47666" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - BRITISH BUSINESS PRESS - SEPT 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - BRITISH BUSINESS PRESS - SEPT 11.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company.</p>
<p>-- LABOUR LEADERS CLASH WITH UNIONS OVER STRIKE CURBS</p>
<p>There is reported to be considerable confusion within Labour ranks over a change in party policy in the area of industrial relations and specific proposals relating to strike legislation. At the annual Trades Union Conference union leaders expressed concern with recent statements by party leader Tony Blair on the introduction of mandatory and binding arbitration between unions and employers. The strife comes in the wake of similar confusion within party ranks over the issue of Scottish devolution.</p>
<p>-- MATTHEW CLARK SHARES SLIDE 35 PER CENT</p>
<p>Drinks group Matthew Clark has seen its shares fall 35 per cent in value after the company announced a fall in profits resulting from competition presented by a new generation of alcoholic soft drinks. A number of the company's main brands had seen sales decline sharply during July and August as younger drinkers switched to 'alcopop' alternatives. The news has prompted analysts to revise downward profit forecasts for the year to next April from 50 million stg to 20 million stg.</p>
<p>-- 500 MILLION STG KLEINWORT FUND TO BE BROKEN UP</p>
<p>Kleinwort Benson has decided to break up its 500 million stg Kepit fund. M&amp;G has been awarded the task of liquidating the Kleinwort European Privatisation Investment Trust after a period of two years during which it produced disappointing returns for thousands of investors. The company has noted that high marketing costs as well as a demand for more rapid returns had led to the decision to wind-up the trust. 77,000 investors are to be offered the option of either accepting cash for their shares or alternative investments in other trusts.</p>
<p>-- SWISS BANKS FACE PRESSURE OVER 'NAZI GOLD' CLAIMS</p>
<p>A report from the British foreign office on the amounts of plundered gold placed in Swiss banks by the Nazi regime has increased pressure on the Swiss to reveal whether or not they are still holding assets. It has been revealed that after the Second World War the Swiss authorities handed back only a small proportion of the hundreds of millions of pounds worth of assets deposited in their vaults. There is particular concern that the banks have continued to prove reluctant to return funds to the families of Jewish people murdered by the Nazis.</p>
<p>-- COMPANIES FEAR MOVES TO CLOSE VAT LOOPHOLES</p>
<p>British companies are reported to be concerned that the government is planning to tighten rules relating to value added tax payments after discovering that businesses have become increasingly efficient at avoiding having to make such payments. Studies by the government have indicated that for the 1995-96 tax year revenues from this source were some 5 billion stg less than had been anticipated. It is now the belief that this situation has arisen as a result of increased use of tax planning in the corporate sector.</p>
<p>-- MERCURY PLANS BIG BOOST TO UK SPENDING</p>
<p>Mercury Communications is reported to be planning to increase its capital expenditure levels in the UK in an effort to enhance its ability to compete more effectively with rival British Telecom. The increase in investment to between 400 million stg and 450 million stg will principally go towards the development of local networks. The company also sees mainland Europe as another market in which it wishes to expand its operations.</p>
<p>-- BUNDESBANK MEMBER SEES FLEXIBLE EMU</p>
<p>Ernst Welteke, a member of the central council of the Bundesbank, is reported to have called on Germany to adopt a more flexible approach to the interpretation of Maastricht criteria for participation in the process of EMU. The call comes at a time when it appears increasingly likely that a number of key EU member states, including France and Germany, may encounter difficulties in qualifying for membership of the planned single currency.</p>
<p>-- US GROUP TO INVEST 68 MILLION STG IN N IRELAND</p>
<p>US electronics company Seagate Technology has announced that it intends to invest some 68 million stg in a production facility in Northern Ireland. The plant, which will eventually employ 759 people, will manufacture substrates for use in computer disk drives. A grant of 24.2 million stg is being made available by the local development authorities for the project, which is seen as a major vote of confidence in the local economy.</p>
<p>-- RETAILERS FIND LITTLE COMMERCIAL BENEFIT IN SUNDAY TRADING</p>
<p>A survey by property consultant Healey &amp; Baker has concluded that the introduction of Sunday trading in Britain has resulted in little commercial benefit for retailers. Instead the same level of trade which was carried out over five days has simply been extended to cover six. Those who have gained the most from the changes have been larger out-of-town multiple retailers, with town centres continuing to experience a decline in trade.</p>
<p>-- TUC GIVES BACKING TO MONETARY UNION</p>
<p>At the annual Trades Union Congress delegates have been told by the TUC's general council that Britain must join the planned single European currency. John Edmonds of the GMB union informed those gathered that the country had to play a more central role in EMU if it was to shape the final outcome of the process. The TUC has noted, however, that the timetable adopted for the creation of the euro is too rapid and that it is therefore essential that the country play a more prominent role in order to secure reform.</p>
<p>For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
