<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="476667" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Soy shipping conditions at key Brazilian ports.</title>
<headline>Soy shipping conditions at key Brazilian ports.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Key Brazilian ports reported the following conditions for shipments of soybeans and soy products:</p>
<p>PARANAGUA:</p>
<p>Vessels: Ocean Lady loading 47,000 tonnes soymeal. Cardamyla loading 53,831 tonnes soybeans. Flag Supplier loading 54,200 tonnes soybeans. Pioneer Star loading 55,000 mixed soybeans/soymeal. Waiting to load were 16 vessels for soybeans, 12 for soymeal and three for mixed cargo.</p>
<p>Trucks: 4,154 trucks unloaded soybeans, 1,197 trucks soymeal and 255 trucks soyoil between March 27 and 30.</p>
<p>Loading: 148,249 tonnes soybeans and 51,546 tonnes soymeal were loaded between March 27 and 30. In the month to March 30, 699,667 tonnes soybeans were loaded at Paranagua, 501,497 tonnes soymeal and 24,950 tonnes soyoil. In March 1996, 274,070 tonnes soybeans, 489,005 tonnes soymeal and 43,228 tonnes soyoil were loaded at the port.</p>
<p>Stocks: No figures available. NOTE: A conveyor belt at the port's export terminal which was damaged in a fire on March 24 has been repaired and resumed loading early Sunday. All five conveyor belts at the port terminal were operating normally Monday.</p>
<p>SANTOS:</p>
<p>Vessels: Mentese finished loading 45,300 tonnes soybeans and citrus pulp, due to leave at 6.00 a.m. local (0900 GMT) Tuesday. Hilon of Sparta waiting to dock, to load 55,000 soybeans. Aguiatrias loading 58,126 tonnes soybeans at Cargill private terminal.</p>
<p>Road: 198 trucks arrived between March 28 and 30 unloading 5,274 tonnes soybeans and 12 trucks arrived unloading 259 tonnes soymeal.</p>
<p>Rail: No arrivals.</p>
<p>Stocks: 71,281 tonnes soybeans, 3,355 tonnes soymeal.</p>
<p>Loading: The port recorded a new record daily loading total on March 27 of 40,700 tonnes soybeans, compared with a previous high of around 30,000 tonnes. Between March 28 and 30, 65 tonnes soybeans were loaded.</p>
<p>((--Joelle Diderich, Sao Paulo newsroom +248 5417))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
