<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="476707" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia Gas Oil/Jet - Gas oil steady at lower levels.</title>
<headline>Asia Gas Oil/Jet - Gas oil steady at lower levels.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore gas oil prices were holding steady at lower levels on Monday as sellers again offered their arbitrage cargoes which were all taken up by two Singapore traders, traders said.</p>
<p>Four cargoes were sold to the two related local traders--all of which were arbitrage cargoes, for end April lifting. Three cargoes were sold at $26.50 per barrel and one at $26.80 on a free-on-board basis from a US trader, a Swiss trader and a German trader.</p>
<p>One of the Singapore traders was still seeking prompt gas oil cargoes and were asking for offers, traders said.  </p>
<p>With today's purchases, the Singapore trader has bought a total of 6.8 million barrels since early March and again counfounding market speculation that they would soon stop buying, causing jitters in the swaps market earlier.</p>
<p>Traders said while gas oil prices were holding very well, the market remained nervous about the large volume of arbitrage cargoes in Asia which latest estimates placed at over 1.6 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Traders said Chinese enquiries remained low at around $200 per tonne, cost-and-freight basis.  </p>
<p>Swaps gas oil was unchanged in late trading at $25.85/$26.00 for April.</p>
<p>Traders said jet fuel demand for April remained muted, forcing the swaps jet-gas oil regrade to trade lower at minus 40 cents per barrel.</p>
<p>But physical regional demand is picking up for May with import tenders from Taiwan and Nepal, while India was expected to take at least two cargoes in its May tender which closes on Thursday.</p>
<p>(Prices in dollars per barrel)</p>
<p> MTH FOB SIN		     BUY/SELL     PREV BUY/SELL</p>
<p> MAR JET KEROSENE/KERO     25.30/25.60	 25.30/25.60</p>
<p> MAR GAS OIL 0.5% S	  26.50/26.90	 26.50/27.30</p>
<p> APR JET/GAS OIL SWAPS	-0.50/-0.30	-0.35/0.20</p>
<p> APR GAS OIL SWAPS	   25.85/26.00	 25.85/26.05</p>
<p> MAY GAS OIL SWAPS	   25.00/25.20	 24.90/25.05</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (+65-870 3084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
