<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47682" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: German TV network gearing up for mid-1997 float.</title>
<headline>German TV network gearing up for mid-1997 float.</headline>
<byline>Keith Weir</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pro Sieben Television AG, set to become the first German television station with a stock exchange listing, is gearing up for a mid-1997 flotation, chairman Georg Kofler said on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>The company, which has two national television stations in Germany, has previously said that the initial public offering would take place in the first half of 1997, having shelved earlier plans for a 1996 flotation.</p>
<p>Speaking in an interview with Reuters, Kofler said that the most likely date was now &quot;the summer of 1997, around June&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I proposed &quot;let's wait for mid 1997' because then we can show another successful year, 96, which will be a successful year,&quot; said Kofler.</p>
<p>Kofler said that the delay would also allow Germany's third largest commercial TV network to highlight its diversification into other areas of the audiovisual sector.</p>
<p>The company's main shareholders are Cologne-based retail group Rewe, which has 40 percent, and Thomas Kirch, son of Bavarian media mogul Leo Kirch, who has 24.5 percent.</p>
<p>The remaining 35.5 percent of ordinary stock is held by a group of banks and it is this portion which will be floated.</p>
<p>Kofler said that the company would be listed solely in Germany after its flotation.</p>
<p>&quot;We are a German company and we will be listed in Germany and for the moment we think that is enough,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>However, Pro Sieben also plans to place shares in the United States under U.S. securities rule 144A, which allows them to be distributed to qualified institutional investors.</p>
<p>Kofler said that Pro Sieben would launch a digital pay television service in November, offering near-video-on demand, a cartoon channel, a games show channel and &quot;an erotic channel&quot;.</p>
<p>Leo Kirch has pioneered digital television in Germany with the launch in July this year of DF1, a service in which British pay television operator BSKyB is a major partner.</p>
<p>The Pro Sieben digital package will use the same decoder technology as DF1 and the possibilites for joint marketing are being examined, Kofler said.</p>
<p>Pro Sieben's net profit fell by a third to 96.4 million marks ($64.13 million) in 1995 as start-up losses at its Kabel 1 station and investments in multimedia weighed on results.</p>
<p>Pro Sieben increased its stake in Kabel 1 from 45 percent to 100 percent last November. Kabel 1 boosted its market share to three percent of all viewers in 1995, its third year of operation.</p>
<p>The core Pro Sieben channel, which began broadcasting in 1989, has a share of just under 10 percent of viewing. It has a young audience attracted by a heavy diet of U.S. programming.</p>
<p>Kofler said that Pro Sieben could increase its audience share to around 12 percent in the next few years and would continue to focus on the under-50s.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to keep our branding as a young, quality TV,&quot; he said, adding this was the key market for advertisers. ($1=1.5032 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
