<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="476984" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soybeans end mostly down, acres hit new crop.</title>
<headline>CBOT soybeans end mostly down, acres hit new crop.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT soybean futures ended mostly lower on Monday, led by new crop November after USDA shocked the market by forecasting 1997 planted acreage at 68.8 million acres, traders said.</p>
<p>That acreage figure was well above analysts' expectations for 65.85 million acres and if realized, would be the highest acreage since 1980, USDA said.</p>
<p>Old crop months escaped relatively unscathed, supported by lower-than-expected quarterly stocks figures. USDA on Monday put quarterly stocks at 1.078 billion bushels, below trade expectations for 1.093 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The market seemed to react more toward the prospects of very large supplies come fall than the very strong demand pace evidenced by the stocks figure,&quot; said Joel Karlin, analyst with Everen Securities in Chicago.</p>
<p>&quot;We're talking about exceptionally large, perhaps record corn and soybean crops,&quot; he added. &quot;But demand for U.S. beans continues to be very strong. Even at these prices, it does not appear to have stifled even domestic demand.&quot;</p>
<p>Soybeans closed 20-1/2 cents per bushel lower to 3/4 cent higher with November down 20-1/2 cents at $6.99 a bushel and nearby May up 3/4 cent at $8.55-3/4.  </p>
<p>USDA analysts said the surge in soybean acreage was aided by larger plantings in &quot;fringe&quot; areas. North Dakota's planted acreage was estimated to rise 35 percent, or 250,000 acres, for a total of 1.15 million acres of soybeans.</p>
<p>Bulls pointed to ideas acreage figures were not set in stone as most farmers had not begun planting and wet weather had delayed pesticide applications in some areas.</p>
<p>&quot;Farmers can change acreage and they will do so depending on weather,&quot; said Terry Francl, economist with the American Farm Bureau Federation.</p>
<p>News that a Brazilian company was negotiating to ship soybeans and soymeal to the United States came out too late to move the market significantly but traders said they would closely watch developments.</p>
<p>Ceval Alimentos said it was in talks to sell 150,000 tonnes soymeal and 230,000 tonnes soybeans to two separate U.S. firms for April 15-May 30 shipment, a company official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Traders shrugged off news a conveyor belt at Brazil's Paranagua port had been repaired and exports were set to return to full steam.</p>
<p>On the day, Refco Inc sold 8.0 million bushels May, 1.5 million July and 1.0 million November, traders said, and Refco also bought two million bushels May and one million July. Tenco Inc sold four million May and bought two million May and 1.5 million July.</p>
<p>ADM sold 2.0 million May and 2.5 million July, floor sources said.</p>
<p>In options trade, Tenco Inc sold 300 May $9.00 calls at eight cents.</p>
<p>Soybean volume was estimated by CBOT at 60,000 contracts, compared with Thursday's actual volume of 51,709 contracts.</p>
<p>((Emily Kaiser 312-408-8749))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
