<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="476963" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dynamics says directors call bid inadequate.</title>
<headline>Dynamics says directors call bid inadequate.</headline>
<dateline>GREENWICH, Conn. 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dynamics Corp of America said Monday the &quot;unanimous initial reaction&quot; of its directors to WHX Corp's $40 a share cash merger offer, except for one who could not be reached, was that it was &quot;totally inadequate.&quot;</p>
<p>In a statement, Dynamics confirmed it received the unsolicited offer on March 27.  It said it acknowledged receipt of WHX's letter-offer on the same day and advised WHX it would inform its directors and respond this week.</p>
<p>Dynamics said it was suggesting to its shareholders that they withhold taking any action on the offer pending further developments.</p>
<p>WHX, a holding company whose principal subsidiary is Wheeling-Pittsburgh Steel Corp, publicly announced its unsolicited offer earlier Monday.  It valued the offer at $160 million, but said it was prepared to raise the price if it got data from Dynamics that warranted a higher bid.</p>
<p>Dynamics makes electronic components, mobile vans and transportable shelters for specialized electronic and medical diagnostic equipment.  It also makes portable electric housewares and commercial appliances, air distribution equipment, specialized air-conditioning equipment and generator sets.</p>
<p>It holds a 44.1 percent stake in CTS Corp, which makes electronic and electromechanical components.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GREENWICH, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
