<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477012" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ascend stock falls on plan to buy Cascade.</title>
<headline>Ascend stock falls on plan to buy Cascade.</headline>
<byline>Michael Ellis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ascend Communications Inc. stock tumbled Monday following its announcement that it was aquiring Cascade Communications Corp. in an effort to broaden its share of the computer networking marketplace.</p>
<p>Ascend plunged by $10.50, or about 20 percent, to $41.50 in heavy trading on the Nasdaq market, where it and Cascade were the two most actively traded issues.</p>
<p>The descent on Ascend's stock knocked about $650 million from the original value of the stock transaction, which Ascend said was worth about $3.7 billion, based on its stock's closing price of $52 last Thursday.</p>
<p>Cascade lost $1.375 to $27 -- well below the $36.40 a share that its shareholders were to have received under Ascend's offer, which was announced late Sunday.</p>
<p>Under terms of the definitive agreement, Cascade stockholders were to receive 0.7 of a share of Ascend stock for each Cascade share they own.</p>
<p>Alameda, Calif.-based Ascend, which is chasing industry leader Cisco Systems Inc., is seeking to acquire Cascade to offer customers a full range of products for linking computer systems.</p>
<p>&quot;Our products are highly complementary,&quot; Ascend Chief Executive Mory Ejabat told analysts during a conferennce call on Monday. &quot;In addition to an excellent technology and product fit, Ascend and Cascade possess complemetary distribution channels,&quot; which could expand sales across accounts, he said.</p>
<p>The combined company, which will keep the Ascend name, also will be able to offer a number of products to companies that provide access to the Internet, the global computer network whose popularity is growing at dazzling speed.</p>
<p>Ascend said it would take an unspecified one-time charge in its third quarter for costs related to the merger, which will be accounted for as a pooling of interests to qualify as a tax-free reorganization.</p>
<p>&quot;Assuming a third-quarter close to the transaction, we expect the transaction to have a slightly dilutive effect on Ascend's earnings for the remainder of 1997 and we expect that it will be accretive to our earnings in fiscal 1998,&quot; Ascend Chief Financial Officier Bob Dahl told analysts.</p>
<p>When pressed to be more specific, he indicated that 1997 earnings could be hurt by about 5 cents to 10 cents a share but the deal would add more than that to 1998 earnings. In 1996, Ascend earned $113.1 million, or 89 cents per share.</p>
<p>Ascend shareholders will own about 65 percent and Cascade shareholders about 35 percent of the combined company.</p>
<p>In a separate announcement, Cascade, based in Westford, Mass., said it expected its earnings and revenues for its first quarter, which ended March 29, to be below analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>Cascade said that, based on available information, it estimated first-quarter revenues would be around $90 million and earnings, excluding a one-time charge associated with its acquisition of Sahara Networks Inc., would be in the range of 14 cents to 15 cents per share.</p>
<p>In the first quarter of 1996, Cascade earned $11.3 million, or 24 cents a share.</p>
<p>Once the acquisition is completed, Ascend said, the company will reorganize into four business units -- multimedia access products, remote products, access and concentrator products and core switching systems.</p>
<p>Cascade Chief Executive Dan Smith, who will join Ascend as executive vice president of the core switching systems unit, said the company experienced uneven sales of telecommunications equipment.</p>
<p>&quot;While the timing of customer commitments has been delayed, we have not lost any key customer accounts,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Both Cascade and Ascend will announce first-quarter earnings on April 10.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34440">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
