<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477052" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US High Court rules against judge on sex assaults.</title>
<headline>US High Court rules against judge on sex assaults.</headline>
<byline>James Vicini</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Supreme Court ruled unanimously on Monday that the wrong standard was used to overturn a civil rights conviction of a former Tennessee state judge for sexually assaulting five women in his chambers.</p>
<p>They said a U.S. appeals court used an improper gauge by ruling that a 19th century federal civil rights law did not expressly criminalize sexual assaults committed by a state judge.</p>
<p>The appeals court had said a defendant may not be convicted under the 1874 law for a wilful violation of a constitutional right unless that right has been made specific by a Supreme Court decision involving similar factual circumstances.</p>
<p>&quot;The question is whether this standard of notice is higher than the Constitution requires, and we hold that it is,&quot; Justice David Souter wrote for the court.</p>
<p>Souter said the key determining factor was whether law made it reasonably clear at the time of the conduct that the activity was criminal. He said there had been &quot;fair warning&quot; criminal liability may be imposed for the assaults.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court sent the case of former Tennessee judge David Lanier, 62, the scion of a politically powerful family, back to the appeals court to use the proper standard. But it stopped short of reinstating his conviction.</p>
<p>The decision marked a victory for the Justice Department's civil rights division, which had prosecuted the case and had urged the Supreme Court to overturn the earlier ruling.</p>
<p>Lanier, a former Tennessee Chancery Court judge, was convicted on seven counts of wilfully depriving a person of rights protected under the Constitution.</p>
<p>The convictions stemmed from sexual assaults in 1989 to 1991 on victims who were in his chambers in connection with their official court jobs or prospective employment, including one woman who had a child custody case before Lanier.</p>
<p>Lanier committed one of the assaults while wearing his judicial robe, according to court records.</p>
<p>The law at issue was adopted after the Civil War to protect the civil rights of blacks. It has been used by prosecutors to protect against local government brutality by police or other officials and was used in the conviction of two Los Angeles police officers in the beating of black motorist Rodney King.</p>
<p>The Justice Department said the law &quot;has been the primary tool for bringing to justice state officials who engage in the most egregious abuses of official power, including rapes, beatings and other unjustified assaults.&quot;</p>
<p>It said the five women in the Lanier case had a constitutional right to be free from unwanted sexual abuse.</p>
<p>The Justice Department argued that the right to be free from rape or other assault by government officials already has been made specific by numerous court decisions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
