<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477175" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian metals ranged on low demand, stock shortage.</title>
<headline>Indian metals ranged on low demand, stock shortage.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Base metals were steady in a narrow price band on the local market on Monday, dealers said.</p>
<p>Demand from industrial consumers was at low ebb but limited arrivals and shortage of ready stock kept prices firm.</p>
<p>&quot;Arrivals of imported metals from the port to the market remained low following a strike called by the transport operators as they were protesting against service tax and hike in the insurance premium,&quot; one dealer added.</p>
<p>Copper ready was steady at 13,525 rupees per quintal as was zinc at 7,800 rupees and lead at 4,550 rupees per quintal in limited activity.</p>
<p>On Saturday copper was up by 25 rupees and zinc by 50 rupees per quintal.</p>
<p>Nickel remained steady at the reduced level of 36,800 rupees per quintal amid limited inflow. It was down by 200 rupees per quintal on Saturday and by 500 rupees last week on setbacks in the world market. Tin was available at the previous level of 31,600 rupees as was aluminium at 7,425 rupees in nominal trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Trading volume and price fluctuation in the world market remained low due to different festivals which in turn also kept price range narrow in the Bombay market,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay Commodities +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
