<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477240" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bre-X mystery deepens suspicions about Busang.</title>
<headline>Bre-X mystery deepens suspicions about Busang.</headline>
<byline>Cynthia Osterman</byline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>As investigators tried to unravel what happened at Bre-X Minerals Ltd.'s controversial Indonesian gold property, analysts outlined on Monday a number of scenarios including the possibility that drill results from the Busang discovery were rigged on a massive scale.</p>
<p>An audit of the project now under way will seek to determine exactly went awry.</p>
<p>But even before the release of the findings, several analysts contended that the discrepancies uncovered so far were almost impossible to explain as the result of technical problems, mistakes or a fluke.</p>
<p>In just one week, the Busang saga has gone from being a success story of almost mythic proportions to a fable of shattered hopes and confusion.</p>
<p>John Kaiser, a well-respected independent mining analyst in California, suspects Bre-X's rock samples were &quot;salted&quot; with gold to make them look richer than they were. &quot;The only explanation is that the the gold in the Bre-X samples came from somewhere else,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Bre-X denies there was any tampering at Busang. &quot;We've done over 100 miles of core and the assays have been consistent all the way through. So questioning the work we've done to date...it's physically impossible in our mind that the core could have been tampered with,&quot; Bre-X Chief Executive David Walsh said last week.</p>
<p>Some defenders of the company even speculated that the whole episode was manufactured to depress Bre-X's share price so a bigger mining company could buy it on the cheap. Walsh himself referred vaguely to a belief that forces with a &quot;hidden agenda&quot; were at work.</p>
<p>While other analysts also considered the situation suspicious, they found it hard to believe that a hoax of such huge proportions could have been kept up for three years without word leaking out.</p>
<p>Analysts estimated that Bre-X drilled 250 holes at Busang, yielding roughly 100,000 samples that were tested to come up with its reserve estimates.</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers indicate a fraud has been performed, but it's mind-boggling to think they could have salted all those thousands and thousands of samples. There has never been anything on this scale in the history of mining if it is proven to be a hoax,&quot; said one Canadian mining analyst who did not want to be identified.</p>
<p>Busang had been heralded as the biggest gold find of the century, worth at least $20 billion. Then came last week's stunning news that the deposit might instead contain only an &quot;insignificant&quot; amount of the precious metal.</p>
<p>The announcement came from Bre-X's prospective partner in the project, Freeport-McMoRan Copper &amp; Gold Inc. of New Orleans. The U.S. mining company had conducted tests intended to check Bre-X's results and instead found there may not even be enough gold to make a mine worthwhile.</p>
<p>Bre-X insisted again on Monday that its earlier estimates would be vindicated. But the assertion came on the heels of the company's own admission last week that there was &quot;a strong possibility&quot; its exploration results were overstated.</p>
<p>Bre-X previously claimed that the Busang deposit contained 71 million ounces of gold and some officials said publicly it could hold up to 200 million ounces.</p>
<p>Whether anything of value lies beneath the jungle mud of Busang is now the subject of intense debate. Freeport sought to duplicate Bre-X's results, in part by drilling alongside the Calgary-based company's own test holes.</p>
<p>Those checks should have produced almost identical results. Instead, Freeport often found barely a trace of gold in spots where Bre-X had reported hitting rich veins.</p>
<p>Alarm bells also rang when Freeport said gold particles in its samples showed &quot;visual differences&quot; -- a phrase well known in the mining industry to indicate salting.</p>
<p>Analysts said Freeport's use of the phrase suggested gold dust had been introduced into the Bre-X samples because otherwise the gold particles would have looked the same.</p>
<p>In the hunt for answers, investigators must cut through a thicket of intrigue. Many of Bre-X's geological records were destroyed earlier this year in a mysterious fire in a hut where geological samples were kept at Busang. In addition, Bre-X did not hold half its drill core samples for safekeeping as is the usual mining practice.</p>
<p>The man who could have provided many answers is now dead, deepening the mystery. Michael de Guzman, chief geologist at Busang, plunged from a helicopter in the Indonesian jungle in an apparent suicide.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
