<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477207" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India Congress power gambit seen falling short.</title>
<headline>India Congress power gambit seen falling short.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leader of India's Congress party has taken a political gamble that may topple Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda but leave the ruling coalition in power and economic reforms intact, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>Congress president Sitaram Kesri's surprise decision on Sunday to withdraw support for Deve Gowda's minority government provoked political confusion that sent share prices tumbling.</p>
<p>The Congress move opened a bewildering array of possibilities ranging from a parliamentary vote of confidence in Deve Gowda's 10-month-old government to snap general elections.</p>
<p>President Shankar Dayal Sharma was consulting constitutional experts following Kesri's decision to stake a claim to rule.</p>
<p>But analysts predicted the Congress leader, undercut by divisions in his own party and reluctant to face the electorate, would be unable to thrust himself into power and might have to settle for a revamped centre-left coalition.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a blind gamble by Kesri,&quot; said Pran Chopra of the Centre for Policy Research, an independent think-tank. &quot;He has propelled himself into a situation from which he is unlikely to derive any benefit.&quot;</p>
<p>Kesri's gambit sparked a selloff on Indian bourses as investors worried that the bout of political uncertainty would delay passage of the government's business-friendly budget for the 1997/98 fiscal year starting on April 1 and derail reforms.</p>
<p>At 0614 GMT, the Bombay Stock Exchange's benchmark index was down 291.46 points, or 7.96 percent, to 3,372.07.</p>
<p>Political leaders sought to assuage financial markets' fears. &quot;Political stability and economic reform are not interlinked,&quot; said Jaipal Reddy, spokesman for Deve Gowda's Janata Dal party. &quot;Reforms will go on irrespective of who will be in power.&quot;</p>
<p>Kesri, who was thrust to the head of India's oldest party last September after former prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao resigned over corruption charges, drew stinging criticism from newspapers which accused him of political expediency.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision smacks of a desperation that comes from deep political and personal paranoia,&quot; the Indian Express said.</p>
<p>Kesri's timing -- with the budget still before parliament and sensitive talks with Pakistan underway in the capital -- was shocking, the newspaper said in a front-page editorial.</p>
<p>In a letter to President Sharma on Sunday, the Congress leader cited lawlessness, a drift in the economy and a growing communal menace for his decision to revoke support.</p>
<p>Deve Gowda's 15-party United Front coalition has 178 votes in the 545-seat lower house of parliament. It depends on Congress, which has 140 deputies, to survive against the biggest single party, the rightwing Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), which controls 194 votes.</p>
<p>Analysts said Kesri appeared fed up with the United Front's unwillingness to cooperate in the key northern state of Uttar Pradesh, a former Congress stronghold where the BJP recently succeeded in installing a coalition government.</p>
<p>They said Kesri was also concerned over a spate of corruption investigations into Congress leaders close to him.</p>
<p>Analysts said the absence of several powerful Congress leaders from a strategy meeting on Sunday indicated Kesri had not mustered undivided support for his move to oust Deve Gowda.</p>
<p>Given Congress's unwillingness to go to the polls after finishing a humiliating second in elections last year, the United Front appeared well placed to fend off Kesri's challenge.</p>
<p>But the price it may have to pay for the support of enough Congress deputies needed to survive a confidence vote could be the replacement of Deve Gowda with a new United Front leader.</p>
<p>&quot;The chances of Congress being able to form a government are more meagre than the United Front surviving,&quot; Chopra said. &quot;Despite considerable drama, the chances of smaller changes are greater than drastic changes.&quot;</p>
<p>Ashis Nandy of the Centre for the Study of Developing Societies said Congress could decide to support another United Front nominee in hopes of ruling from behind the scenes, and the political turmoil could be over in a matter of days.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel Deve Gowda may resign,&quot; Nandy said. &quot;A new political configuration will be known in few days.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
