<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47723" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ shares close lower led down by Telecom.</title>
<headline>NZ shares close lower led down by Telecom.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>* New Zealand closes lower on 8 cent Telecom fall</p>
<p>* Turnover boosted by seven million BIL</p>
<p>* Buyers run out of steam</p>
<p>---------------------------(Sept 11)---------------------------</p>
<p>Price movements at close</p>
<p>	    LAST CHG</p>
<p>  143   -1  * NZSE-40 cap index -8.37  at 2,235.25</p>
<p>  329   -2  * NZSC cap index -5.69 at 4,487.04</p>
<p>  276   -1  * NZSE-10 cap index -6.85  at 1,122.83</p>
<p>  362   -5  * Volume NZ$71 million. Futures -9 at 1,121</p>
<p>  695   -8  * Other movers - +15  -10</p>
<p>The New Zealand bourse closed lower on Wednesday thanks mainly to an eight cent slide in market heavyweight Telecom.</p>
<p>The NZSE-40 capital index closed 8.37 points lower at 2,235.25 on tunover of NZ$71 million.</p>
<p>Paul Davenport of brokers Doyle Paterson Brown said turnover was boosted by four million Telecom and seven million Brierley Investment shares crossing. He said profit taking was not an influence.</p>
<p>&quot;You can't go on for ever. Buyers just ran out of steam.&quot;  </p>
<p>He attributed a slight rise of three points in the index towards the close as buyers cleaning out their orders.</p>
<p>Tim Koller of brokers Hendry Hay McIntosh said Telecom was the standout stock closing at 695c.</p>
<p>He said concerns about market share in Australia continued to press down on brewer Lion Nathan, of five cents at $3.62.</p>
<p>&quot;The market did not have such a strong tone today as yesterday after a good run of late. A little profit taking and interest rates going higher as well as the election drawing closer&quot; affected sentiment, Koller said.  </p>
<p>Utilities were still well-bought with Energy Direct up another nine cents to $3.34 while gas distributor Enerco gained 10 cents to $6.20.</p>
<p>Koller said TransAlta NZ's A/A1 credit rating by Standard &amp; Poor's had helped Energy Direct. TransAlta NZ is the company to be formed from the proposed merger of Energy Direct and neighbouring energy company Capital Power.</p>
<p>Among secondliners, plastics and electrical supplier PDL Holdings rose 15 cents to $7.15 on the back of a forecast increase in profit to $12.4 million for the March 1997 year.</p>
<p>-- Vernon Small 64 4 4714 278.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
