<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477397" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel shares end higher in quiet trading.</title>
<headline>Israel shares end higher in quiet trading.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli shares closed higher on Monday in very quiet trading, with traders saying the market was awaiting fresh news.</p>
<p>The benchmark Mishtanim index of the top 100 shares rose 1.32 percent, or 3.21 points, to 245.64 on low all-share turnover of 76 million shekels against 53 million shekels on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Maof 25 blue chip index closed 1.53 percent higher at 253.98.</p>
<p>&quot;Turnover was very low. Today's rise was meaningless. Many shares rose sharply on very low volume. The only positive thing is that there are no sellers in the market,&quot; said Amir Eyal of Epsilon Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems that the market wants to rise and investors are only awaiting fresh news to start buying,&quot; Eyal added.</p>
<p>&quot;Fourth-quarter earnings reports were above expectations, which is a positive factor that needs to be reflected in share prices,&quot; added Michael Weiss of Evergreen Capital Markets.</p>
<p>Bank Leumi gained 0.75 percent to 535 agorot. The bank said fourth-quarter 1996 net profit rose to 164.9 million shekels from 90.3 million a year earlier. Leumi also said it would pay an aggregate dividend 650 million shekels to shareholders most of it coming from the forced sale of non-bank holdings last year.</p>
<p>IDB Development Corp rose 2.5 percent to 6,734 agorot. The company reported that net profit fell in the fourth-quarter of 1997 to 16 million shekels from 53 million shekels a year earlier.</p>
<p>Elco Holdings surged 5.0 percent to 2,326 agorot on volume of only 41,868 shekels. Elco reported a fourth-quarter net loss of 3.5 million shekels compared with a 14.4 million net profit of 14.4 million shekels a year ago.</p>
<p>The most active shares were Bank Hapoalim, which rose 2.75 percent to 661 agorot on volume of 5.5 million shekels; Koor Industries, which gained 2.75 percent to 30,849 agorot on turnover of 4.5 million shekels; and Teva Pharmaceutical Industries, which rose 0.5 percent to 18,850 agorot on volume of 4.3 million shekels.</p>
<p>- Dan Gerstenfeld, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
