<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477367" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain's Labour Party promises positive campaign.</title>
<headline>Britain's Labour Party promises positive campaign.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Reaney</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tony Blair vowed on Monday to rise above the sleaze that has dominated Britain's election campaign and said the country deserves better than the ruling Conservatives have given it for nearly 18 years.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not want this election fought on negative issues. I want it fought on the policies that we offer to the people of our country,&quot; the Labour Party leader told supporters as he launched a new poster campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;Britain deserves better,&quot; he said, echoing the slogan with which Labour will fight the May 1 poll.</p>
<p>While the Conservatives took the day off at the end of a long Easter weekend dominated by the resignation of Sir Michael Hirst, chairman of the Scottish Conservatives, over claims he had had a homosexual lover, and calls for two other members of parliament to step down, Labour pounded home their message.</p>
<p>With his party enjoying a 20-point lead in opinion polls, Blair said Labour would divert 100 million pounds ($163 million) in the country's national health service from administration costs to patient care.</p>
<p>He promised safer streets, smaller classes in schools, low interest and mortgage rates and no income tax increases for the life of the next parliament.</p>
<p>Earlier on Monday, Blair dismissed Conservative allegations that a Labour government would dismantle trade union laws and said &quot;strikes without ballots, the closed shop and all the rest&quot; were things of the past.</p>
<p>&quot;The essential trade elements of the trade union legislation of the 1980s will remain,&quot; he wrote in The Times newspaper.</p>
<p>Blair was not alone in his quest for more positive issues. The Conservatives were also trying to change tracks and refocus their campaign.</p>
<p>After party members' failure to convince former minister Neil Hamilton and MP Piers Merchant that it was time to go, there were signs on Monday of a party climbdown after both insisted on staying.</p>
<p>Hamilton is at the centre of allegations that Harrods store owner Mohammed Al-Fayed paid several MPs generously to ask parliamentary questions, and photographs of the married Merchant kissing a 17-year-old nightclub hostess in a park were splashed across the front pages of most of the country's newspapers.</p>
<p>Major had hinted in a letter commending Hirst for stepping down for the good of the party that Hamilton and Merchant should do the same.</p>
<p>But after it seemed unlikely that either would, Dame Jill Knight, the vice-chairwoman of the powerful Conservative backbench 1922 Committee, softened the party's position.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a far better story to tell in the long run. Mr Jones in the High Street is far more interested in the economy and education for his children than who is having an affair,&quot; she told BBC radio.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not going to fly in the face of British justice and say a man is guilty because allegations have been made against him,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Ever since Major announced the election date on March 15, the Conservatives have been hit by a series of publicity disasters.</p>
<p>As well as Hirst, one of their Scottish MPs has stepped down as a candidate amid rumours about his private life while former minister Tim Smith, implicated in the &quot;cash for questions&quot; affair, was disowned by his local party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
