<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477365" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: SHORTER WORK WEEK TO HARM EMPLOYMENT, RAISE COST - IOBE.</title>
<headline>SHORTER WORK WEEK TO HARM EMPLOYMENT, RAISE COST - IOBE.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The reduction of working week hours will not generally boost employment and will adversely affect workers' real income, the balance of payments and the budget, said the private Foundation for Economic and Industrial Research (IOBE).</p>
<p>&quot;Even in cases where the effect on employment is positive, the effects on production, exports and investments are shown to be negative,&quot; said IOBE. &quot;.. even when there is full compensation (nominal wage is kept steady), the real income per worker drops.&quot;</p>
<p>The international experience from the implementation of a shorter work week in various countries showed that negative effects outweighted positive ones, the IOBE study titled &quot;The effects of the reduction in conventional work hours.&quot;</p>
<p>In France, the number of new jobs that created were less than projected by econometric simulations and were concentrated in large corporations employing more than 500 people, it said.</p>
<p>A decrease in working hours during 1979-1982 led to negative developments on unemployment, employment and production, it said.</p>
<p>Data on OECD countries points to a positive correlation between reductions in work hours and an increase in the level of unemployment, the study said.</p>
<p>The decrease in weekly work hours raises hourly labour cost per employee by up to 14.29 percent assuming full compensation and no overtime and even up to 17.64 percent in the case of a 25 percent rise in overtime compensation, it added.</p>
<p>The IOBE study was written by Peter Nicholaidis. --Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
