<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477488" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: WMX to start $1-bln Dutch auction April 1.</title>
<headline>WMX to start $1-bln Dutch auction April 1.</headline>
<dateline>OAK BROOK, Ill. 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>WMX Technologies Inc said it will start a $1 billion Dutch auction tender offer on April 1 for up to 30 million WMX common shares, or about 6.2 percent of its outstanding common shares.</p>
<p>The price range for the offer will be $30 to $35 per share and the offer will expire at 2400 EST April 28/0500 GMT April 29, said the largest U.S. garbage hauler and handler.</p>
<p>WMX shares closed Thursday at 31 on the New York Stock Exchange.  </p>
<p>Under the Dutch auction rules, stockholders specify a price at which they are willing to sell their shares to WMX within the company's price range. At the conclusion of the offer and receipt of tenders, the company determines the lowest price, or clearing price, within its price range that will enable it to purchase up to 30 million WMX shares.</p>
<p>All shares acquired in the offer will be acquired at the specified clearing price, the company said.</p>
<p>Shares tendered at prices exceeding the clearing price anmd shares not purchased due to proration or conditional tender will be returned, the company said.  </p>
<p>The offer is part of a sweeping restructuring plan announced by WMX in February.</p>
<p>The company said it expects to generate $3 billion in owners' cash flow after capital expenditures and dividends by the end of 1998 from combined asset-monetization efforts and operations.  WMX said it will use a combination of cash from operations, proceeds of asset dispositions and borrowings to fund the purchase of the shares.</p>
<p>The board has authorized the repurchase of up to 50 million shares of WMX stock by the end of 1998, including the shares to be purchased in the Dutch auction.  </p>
<p>Wheelabrator Technologies Inc, a majority-owned subsidiary of WMX, said last week it had indefinitely deferred a similar, $350-million Dutch auction share repurchase plan. The move was read by some analysts as a sign that WMX's restructuring might face delays due to the company's continuing search for a new chief executive.</p>
<p>Wheelabrator's chief financial officer said the unit deferred its Dutch auction because of the vacancy in WMX's head office but added he was not aware of any other changes in the WMX shake-up plan.</p>
<p>As part of its restructuring, WMX is also divesting $1.5 billion in assets, searching for a new chief executive and cutting 3,000 jobs.  The company has been under pressure for months from dissatisfied shareholders who are demanding improved performance.</p>
<p>((--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I92110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OAK BROOK, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
