<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477447" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NOTICE OF SALE -- Georgia $307 mln GO bonds.</title>
<headline>NOTICE OF SALE -- Georgia $307 mln GO bonds.</headline>
<text>
<p>OFFICIAL NOTICE OF SALE</p>
<p>				 $307,195,000</p>
<p>			     STATE OF GEORGIA</p>
<p>		    GENERAL OBLIGATION BONDS, 1997A</p>
<p>SEALED BIDS will  be received  and publicly opened  by the undersigned at Suite  214, 254  Washington Street,  Atlanta, Georgia, at 11:00 o'clock A.M. on Tuesday,</p>
<p>				 April 8, 1997</p>
<p>for all  but no  part of  the above  captioned bonds,  dated April 1,  1997. The  bonds will  be  issued only  as  fully- registered bonds  in denominations  of  $5,000 each  or  any whole multiple thereof. Both principal and semiannual (April 1 and October  1) interest are  payable at The  Bank of  New York. The bonds mature on April 1 as follows:</p>
<p>$8,130,000 _ 1998$12,430,000 _ 2005$19,000,000 _ 2012</p>
<p>8,640,000 _ 199913,200,000 _ 200620,180,000 _ 2013</p>
<p>9,180,000 _ 200014,030,000 _ 200721,440,000 _ 2014</p>
<p>9,750,000 _ 200114,900,000 _ 200822,780,000 _ 2015</p>
<p>10,360,000 _ 200215,840,000 _ 200924,210,000 _ 2016</p>
<p>11,010,000 _ 200316,830,000 _ 201025,705,000 _ 2017</p>
<p>11,700,000 _ 200417,880,000 _ 2011</p>
<p>THE BONDS OF THIS ISSUE ARE NONCALLABLE.</p>
<p>The bonds are  issued by  the Georgia State  Financing and Investment Commission  for and  on behalf  of the  State  of Georgia pursuant to powers granted to the Commission in  the Constitution of the State of  Georgia, the Act creating  the Commission and an authorizing resolution of the  Commission.  The  bonds   so  issued   constitute  direct   and   general</p>
<p>obligations of the State of Georgia for the payment of which the full faith,  credit and taxing  power of  the State  are pledged.</p>
<p>Delivery of the bonds  will be made in  New York, New York as soon as the bonds can be validated and prepared, which is estimated to be April 24, 1997. However, the purchaser shall allow 50 days for delivery. Payment  for the bonds shall  be made in federal funds.</p>
<p>The  bonds  are  offered  subject  to  validation  by  the Superior Court of Fulton County, Georgia, and delivery  will be accompanied by an execution, signature and  no-litigation certificate and non-arbitrage  certificate. The legality  of  the  proceedings  and   the  bonds  will   be  approved   by</p>
<p>Sutherland, Asbill &amp; Brennan, L.L.P., Atlanta, Georgia,  the cost of whose approving opinion shall be paid by the  State. The legal opinion  of Sutherland, Asbill  &amp; Brennan,  L.L.P. will be printed on the bonds.</p>
<p>Bidders may name the  rate or rates of  interest the bonds are to bear in  multiples of 1/20th of  1%, with no  greater difference than  4% between  the  highest and  lowest  rates named and no interest rate shall exceed 6.25% per annum. All bonds of each maturity must bear  a single rate. No bid  for less than par and accrued interest will be considered.</p>
<p>	 Any bid  providing for  supplemental coupons  will  no</p>
<p>considered, and all bonds must bear interest to maturity. The lowest and best bid will  be determined by calculating the total interest on all bonds  from April 1, 1997 to  date of maturity, less any premium.</p>
<p>Instructions  relating  to  certificate  registration  and denominations must be forwarded so as to be received by  the Registrar Bank no later than April 18, 1997.</p>
<p>Within  48  hours  after  the  award  of  the  bonds,  the  successful  bidder  shall   submit  to   the  Commission   a</p>
<p>certificate, in  form  and substance  satisfactory  to  Bond Counsel, specifying for each maturity the expected bona fide reoffering price of the  bonds of each  maturity, as of  the date of  the award  of the  bid. Prior  to delivery  of  the bonds, the successful bidder must submit to the Commission a certificate, in  form  and substance  satisfactory  to  Bond Counsel, stating that a bona fide offering of the bonds  was made to  the public  at the  prices indicated  in the  first certificate, certifying the actual  re-offering price of  at least 10% of the bonds of each maturity, and identifying the amounts, maturities,  and prices  at  which any  bonds  were actually sold  to  institutions  or  other  investors  at  a discount  from  the  offering  prices  to  the  public.  For  purposes  of  this  paragraph,  sales  of  bonds  to   other</p>
<p>securities brokers or dealers will  not be counted as  sales to the public.</p>
<p>A Preliminary Official  Statement for  the bonds  has been  prepared  by  the   Commission.  The  Preliminary   Official</p>
<p>Statement is deemed by  the Commission to  be final for  the purposes of compliance with  Rule 15c2-12 of the  Securities and Exchange  Commission.  In  order to  assist  bidders  in complying with Securities and Exchange Commission Rule 15c2- 12(b)(5) (the Rule''), the State will undertake,  pursuant to the resolution authorizing the issuance of the bonds  and a  Continuing  Disclosure  Certificate,  to  provide  annual reports and notices  of material events  in accordance  with  the  provisions  of   the  Rule.  A   description  of   this</p>
<p>undertaking is set  forth in Appendix  E of the  Preliminary Official Statement  and  will  be set  forth  in  the  final Official Statement.  The  State's  failure  to  deliver  the Continuing Disclosure Certificate  on the  date of  issuance and delivery  of  the  bonds shall  relieve  the  successful bidder of its obligation to purchase the bonds.</p>
<p>The Commission designates the  senior managing underwriter of the  syndicate  to  which  the  bonds  are  awarded  (the Purchaser'') as  its agent  for  purposes of  distributing copies of the final Official Statement to each participating underwriter. Any underwriter executing and delivering a  Bid Form with respect to this issue  agrees that, if its bid  is accepted by the Commission: (1) to accept such  designation; (2)  to  contact  all  participating  underwriters  for  the purpose  of  assuring  proper  dissemination  of  the  final Official Statement; and  (3) to provide  to the  Commission, within two  (2)  days  after  the  date  of  the  sale,  all</p>
<p>necessary pricing information and underwriter identific needed to complete the final Official Statement.</p>
<p>Upon receipt  of  this  information,  the Commission  will prepare and  provide  to  the Purchaser,  within  seven  (7) business days after the sale, a sufficient number of  copies  of  the  final  Official   Statement.  The  final   Official</p>
<p>Statement will  be in  substantially the  same form  as  the preliminary document, subject  to any additions,  deletions, or revisions that the Commission believes are necessary.</p>
<p>The right is reserved to reject any and all bids, and bids shall be  submitted  upon  the Bid  Form  furnished  by  the  Georgia  State  Financing  and  Investment  Commission   and</p>
<p> enclosed  in  a  sealed  envelope  marked  on  the   outside</p>
<p>PROPOSAL FOR  1997A BONDS.'' The  Commission reserves  the right to waive informalities in any and all bids.</p>
<p>A good faith deposit in the  amount of $3,071,950 shall be made by each bidder in the form of a certified, treasurer's, or cashier's check payable to the order of the Georgia State Financing and  Investment  Commission. The  deposit  of  the successful bidder will be applied  on the purchase price  of the bonds  or  retained  by  the  Commission  as  liquidated damages to  it should  the bidder  fail to  comply with  the terms of the bid. All checks of unsuccessful bidders will be returned upon  the  acceptance  of the  successful  bid,  or within 24 hours. No interest will be paid on any good  faith deposit.</p>
<p>Preliminary Official Statements, including  Notice of Sale and Bid  Form, have  been mailed  to a  list of  prospective bidders and institutional investors. Further information and details are available  upon request from  the Georgia  State Financing and Investment Commission, 254 Washington  Street, Suite 214, Atlanta, Georgia 30334 (telephone 404-656-2174).</p>
<p>	  Georgia State Financing and Investment Commission</p>
<p>			   254 Washington Street</p>
<p>				   Suite 214</p>
<p>			  Atlanta, Georgia 30334</p>
<p>March 26, 1997</p>
<p>			  (From The Bond Buyer)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
