<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477536" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek stocks gain 2.25pct on drachma rate cuts.</title>
<headline>Greek stocks gain 2.25pct on drachma rate cuts.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Athens bourse gained 2.25 percent in the last trading session of March, extending Friday's 3.35 percent gains which were the result of changes in money market operations recently announced by Greece's central bank.</p>
<p>The bourse's general share index finished at 1,368.82, up by 30.56 points on Friday's close, having reached an intra-day high of 1,391.42 in early trading when buying momentum on Alpha Credit was carried over from the previous week.</p>
<p>Market participants attributed fresh buying interest on falling interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is entering a new round of appreciation which is fueled by cuts in money-market rates and Treasury paper&quot;, said Yiannis Kalogerakis, broker with ABN-Amro Axias Securities.</p>
<p>A common view among market participants is that the banking sector will continue to pull the broader market higher. Banks' profitability this year will be boosted by gains in their government bond portfolios.</p>
<p>The market appears to be easily digesting oncoming large capital increases such as Alpha Credit Bank's 72 billion rights issue, while scrip issues and sizeable dividends are prompting investors to widen their stock positions.</p>
<p>&quot;Buying interest stems mostly from domestic investors. Momentum is expected to be maintained over the coming two weeks or so, in anticipation of fresh positive input from the macroeconomic front&quot;, Kalogerakis added.</p>
<p>Turnover jumped to 22.8 billion drachmas with nearly 5.1 million shares changing hands, in a session which was shortened by 15 minutes as trading was delayed in excess of an hour due to technical problems.</p>
<p>Gainers led losers 153 to 75, with 23 stocks remaining unchanged out of a total of 251 shares traded. Ten new year highs were recorded today, while Halyps Cement's common and preferred stock provided a contrasting view, respectively leading the gainers and losers lists. -- Angelos Kiosklis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
