<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477617" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China open market operations see little progress.</title>
<headline>China open market operations see little progress.</headline>
<byline>Graham Earnshaw</byline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>China has made only symbolic progress in establishing central bank open market operations in the past year, and the signs of concrete progress in the next few months are at best mixed, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>The central bank launched open market operations, trading short-term treasury bills with major state banks, on April 1 last year in what was seen as a major step towards making China's financial system more responsive to market forces.</p>
<p>But last year the bank traded only a miniscule four billion yuan ($482 million) worth of treasury bills in open market operations, and it appears that no trades have been done at all so far this year, bankers and analysts said.</p>
<p>As a result, the original aim of making the operations a bell-wether of monetary policy and a sophisticated means of controlling money supply has so far remained unrealised.</p>
<p>&quot;Trading has so far been symbolic,&quot; said one Beijing-based banker with a major Chinese bank reached by telephone. &quot;There were a number of transactions done last year but it would appear nothing has been traded since the end of last year.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;A four-billion yuan turnover is only a fraction of one day's trading volume on the Shanghai stock market,&quot; said a Shanghai-based securities analyst with a big Chinese brokerage.</p>
<p>The central bank has indicated it wants to expand the open market operations this year.</p>
<p>Chen Yuan, the central bank's deputy governor said earlier this year that the bank had made expansion of the operations one of the major financial tasks this year, but he gave no details.</p>
<p>The main problem standing in the way of the development of the operations is a shortage of the key tradeable item -- short-term treasury bills.</p>
<p>Analysts said there were indications of differences between the Finance Ministry and the central bank about the issue of more treasury bills.</p>
<p>&quot;For further development, they need to issue large amounts of short-term bills within one year and below,&quot; said a second Beijing-based banker.</p>
<p>&quot;But this needs time and a good coordination with other government departments in particular the Finance Ministry,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>China's Finance Ministry is responsible for the issue of all state debt, including short-term treasury bills.</p>
<p>A central bank official in Beijing said that preparations for the expansion of open market operations was underway.</p>
<p>&quot;We are collecting more information and working on a whole package for development,&quot; he said, but declined to give any details.</p>
<p>Another problem is the small number of banks currently allowed to participate in the open operations.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect the central government to shortly add more banks and securities houses onto the trading list,&quot; said a third banker. &quot;The prospect for development this year is much better than 1996. But we are in the dark the same as you about the central bank's intentions on this.&quot;</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
