<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47766" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Good rain could boost Australian barley - AWF.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Good rain could boost Australian barley - AWF.</headline>
<byline>Marie McInerney</byline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Good rains particularly in southern Australia in the next week could add substantially to forecast barley yields for 1996/97, Brian Bailey, managing director of Australian Wheat Forecasters Pty Ltd, told Reuters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If we got something significant, an inch and a half (of rain) or better, it would really add a significant amount on to the barley production in southern Australia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bailey said his latest forecast was for a national barley yield of 5.96 million tonnes, which he would update next week.  </p>
<p>&quot;If we got two inches of rain between now and when I report, we would put the barley yields up substantially because the timing would be absolutely magnificent if a heavy rain fell now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Heavy rains earlier last week in north-western New South Wales had had no downside because of their timing, he said.</p>
<p>The Australian Bureau of Agricultural and Resource Economics (ABARE) last week forecast a national barley crop of 5.69 million tonnes.  </p>
<p>The Australian Barley Board (ABB), which represents growers in South Australia and Victoria, has estimated areas sown with barley for 1996/97 at 950,000 hectares for SA, compared with 955,000 ha last year, and 595,000 ha for Victoria, a six percent reduction on last year's 636,000 ha.</p>
<p>&quot;As it stands in South Australia at the moment, we are probably looking at an average to above average sort of season and in Victoria, not dissimilar,&quot; ABB corporate relations manager, Ian Desborough told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;No-one is really talking about a bumper season at this time...,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;If you now go through with a normal spring, (with) reasonable rains in the next few weeks, I think people would be confident in the above average result, but if we got a very, very wet spring ... that certainly would not help the estimates,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The ABB earlier on Tuesday announced a A$10 a tonne reduction in its barley pool prices, to A$220 for malting and to A$167 for feed barley in Victoria, because of big crops around the world.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800 mmc reuters</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
