<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477752" id="root" date="1997-03-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Rubber - prices seen easier on rising stocks.</title>
<headline>Rubber - prices seen easier on rising stocks.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese rubber futures are likely to tread easier for most of this week, as the prospect that domestic rubber stocks will climb further has cast a shadow over the markets, traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Sentiment remains bearish. Rubber prices are more likely to go down than up even after a decline in prices last week,&quot; an analyst at a commodity broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;With few bullish factors in sight, rising domestic rubber stocks are likely to weigh on prices and local investors may be quick to sell on any technical price rebound,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The benchmark September contract on the Tokyo Commodity Exchange (TOCOM) ended the morning session at 149.4 yen per kg, against 149.5 yen last Friday.</p>
<p>Similarly, the benchmark September contract on the Kobe Rubber Exchange was quoted at 150.00 yen per kg, compared with 149.8 yen last Friday.</p>
<p>Natural rubber stocks at designated warehouses as of March 20 amounted to 35,972 tonnes, up 1,131 tonnes from March 10, according to the Rubber Trade Association of Japan.</p>
<p>Sources said the gains represented an end to the downward trend in rubber stocks since last October.</p>
<p>A Tokyo-based technical analyst at a commodity broker said that the TOCOM benchmark September contract may probe the downside at 147 yen this week.</p>
<p>Industry sources said the rise in stocks resulted from the fact that Japanese traders actively bought Thai rubber in mid-February, taking advantage of relatively low rubber prices in Thailand, compared with domestic futures.</p>
<p>&quot;Rubber stocks are expected to rise to above 40,000 tonnes by the end of April, and the ample stocks may flow into the market as deliveries when the spot contract expires,&quot; the technical analyst said.</p>
<p>Although tyre demand ahead of an increase in the consumption tax from April has been robust, a view that tyre demand will slow in April may lead domestic rubber inventories to accumulate, the sources said.</p>
<p>They said the appropriate level for natural rubber stocks is about 25,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>The offer price for Thai rubber to Japan was quoted lower at 122 U.S. cents per kg, against 124 U.S. cents last Monday.</p>
<p>Slack rubber demand from the United States and European countries, especially for Technically Specified Rubber (TSR), and weaker Tokyo rubber prices in recent days have caused a decline in Thai rubber offer prices to Japan, they said.</p>
<p>In the local physical market, benchmark Thai rubber for large-lot end-users was quoted at 164 yen per kg on Monday, compared with 170 yen on March 24.</p>
<p>--Keiko Takagi, Tokyo Commodity Desk, +81-3-3432-7431</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
