<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47872" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Tamara Bank plans rights, bond issue.</title>
<headline>Tamara Bank plans rights, bond issue.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's Tamara Bank said on Wednesday it will float a rights and a bond issue later this year to raise 142.83 billion rupiah.</p>
<p>The bank said in an announcement that 41.4 million shares would be offered to existing shareholders on a one-for-two basis at a price of 1,250 rupiah each.</p>
<p>Shareholders would also be eligible to apply for convertible bonds at a price of 2,200 rupiah on the basis of one bond for every two existing shares, the bank said.</p>
<p>The bonds, which pay interest of 15 percent annually, can be converted into one share starting from 1999, the bank said.</p>
<p>The rights issue ex-date would be on November 16, 1996, while the last day of registration would be on November 4, 1996.</p>
<p>Both plans were approved by an extraordinary shareholders' meeting on Tuesday, the bank said.</p>
<p>Twenty percent of the rights issue proceeds of about 51.75 billion rupiah would be used to finance an expansion programme while the remainder will go towards enhancing the bank's portfolio fund, Tamara said.</p>
<p>Funds raised from the bond issue, estimated at 91.08 billion rupiah, will be used to finance operational activity, it said.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
