<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47875" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: NYMEX aims to launch Asia-specific energy futures.</title>
<headline>NYMEX aims to launch Asia-specific energy futures.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Mercantile Exchange (NYMEX) said on Wednesday it was working to launch an Asia-specific futures energy contract to be traded on its ACCESS screen-based system.</p>
<p>NYMEX President Patrick Thompson said research was at an early stage and he did not expect a proposal on a specific futures product to emerge for another year.</p>
<p>NYMEX has set up an advisory panel of traders to help mould the new product.  </p>
<p>Speaking to reporters at the Asia-Pacific Petroleum Conference in Singapore, Thompson said the contract would probably be crude or gas oil based, with a cash, rather than delivery, settlement.</p>
<p>He said the discussions with the advisory group so far indicated the market for the new product should reach three to six months forward.</p>
<p>The Singapore International Monetary Exchange (SIMEX) has a dormant fuel oil futures contract, which it is revamping to increase trader interest.  </p>
<p>A gas oil futures contract on SIMEX, launched in 1991, was delisted in 1993 because it was not being activiely traded.</p>
<p>&quot;The biggest worrying factor is that there has been some failures in the past in the midst of a very growing market,&quot; Thompson said.</p>
<p>But he said he was confident futures markets were needed in the Asian energy sector because of its ballooning growth, increasing energy price volatility and worries about price manipulation.  </p>
<p>&quot;All of that would imply that the industry itself has a desire to create some vehicle which would be able to provide, on the one hand risk management and on the other hand price transparency,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65 870 3081)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
