<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47889" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs end up, but well off peaks on corrective sales.</title>
<headline>JGBs end up, but well off peaks on corrective sales.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key December Japanese Government Bond (JGB) contract ended higher, but well off the day's peaks as corrective sales slowed its advance, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>December hit the year's high of 121.60 in mid-afternoon trade. It ended at 121.44, up from Tuesday's 121.27.</p>
<p>&quot;Many traders rushed to cover short positions in December, driving it up to the year's high. But, nobody was sure why they had to do so, bringing it down to the level they were comfortable with by the close,&quot; said a city bank trader.  </p>
<p>Bullish bond sentiment was underscored by news quoting Ministry of Finance sources as saying that if the government is dissolved later this month, a supplementary budget, if any, would not be adopted until the end of the year.</p>
<p>The yield of the benchmark 182nd JGB was at 2.910 percent at 0638 GMT, down from 2.935 percent on Tuesday. It moved in a 2.890-2.945 percent range.</p>
<p>Cash bonds were supported by the prospect that some players may fail to deliver bonds at settlement of the September contract because some U.S. hedge funds are squeezing the cheapest deliverable cash bonds, traders said.  </p>
<p>A record 2.3519 trillion yen worth of the September contract is due for settlement through delivery of cash JGBs, the Tokyo Stock Exchange (TSE) said.</p>
<p>In the corporate bond market, strong investor demand was detected on bonds launched today by NKK Corp and KDD, totalling 115 billion yen.</p>
<p>&quot;Good investor demand on the NKK and KDD issued urged traders to cover hedge selling positions in the JGB futures market,&quot; said a brokerage trader.</p>
<p>There were unconfirmed rumours that large lot investor bids were placed by life insurers on the cash JGBs.  </p>
<p>The government's Economic Planning Agency said that Japan will announce its gross domestic product (GDP) data for the April-June quarter on September 13 at 3.30 p.m. (0630 GMT).</p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters expect a quarter-on-quarter fall of between 0.3 and 1.8 percent in the April to June period, mainly due to a drop in consumer spending.</p>
<p>The economists' predictions would translate to a fall of between 1.0 percent and 6.6 percent on an annualised basis.</p>
<p>---Yoshiko Mori, Tokyo Treasury Desk 813-3432-8676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
