<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47944" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta seeks to phase out traffic dinosaurs.</title>
<headline>Jakarta seeks to phase out traffic dinosaurs.</headline>
<byline>Tom Wright</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Si Doel&quot;, a popular Indonesian television comedy, tells a story of two likeable rogues from Jakarta's suburbs who ferry people illegally in their rusty and smoke-belching bemo -- a three-wheeled motorised minibus.</p>
<p>But some people are not amused.</p>
<p>Jakarta's city council, which has the unenviable job of trying to solve the horrendous traffic jams that plague this city of 10 million people, are trying to get rid of the vehicle.</p>
<p>Officials want to phase out 1,800 bemos by 1998. Sometime after that the city's 14,000 bajajs, a three-wheeled motorised rickshaw named after Indian manufacturer Bajaj Auto Ltd, will also be junked, they say.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to educate our people here to get used to a modern bus service,&quot; an official from the town planning department told Reuters. The bajaj -- which has no specific route and carries only two people -- does not maximise road capacity, she said.</p>
<p>Jakarta's traffic jams are legion. With around 1.5 million vehicles on the streets (86 percent of which are private cars), many journeys of only a few kilometres can take up to an hour in rush-hour traffic.</p>
<p>Many people set off from home before dawn to reach offices on time and leave well after dark, when they expect traffic to be lighter. Others have been known to finish a paperback novel in the time taken on the two journeys.</p>
<p>Things are set to get worse. In a recent study, the city administration predicted that by the year 2010 Jakarta will have a population close to 12 million and about one-third of them will own a car.</p>
<p>To cope with this unbridled growth, officials want to beef up the public transport system.</p>
<p>Until recently the council's main focus had been on reducing the number of cars in the city.</p>
<p>In 1992 they introduced a &quot;three-in-one&quot; policy, under which there had to be a minimum of three people in a car entering the central business district at specified times in the morning and evening.</p>
<p>But people got around the law by paying street children to make up the required number. Groups of young boys gather near the arterial road into the city each morning and climb in for the short ride past the video cameras strung up a little further on.</p>
<p>They charge as little as 1,000 rupiah (less than 50 U.S. cents) per trip and quickly sprint back to find another commuter.</p>
<p>With that scheme largely proving useless, officials are trying to revive the city's moribund public transport service and rid the city of bemos and bajajs.</p>
<p>&quot;Public transport should be the backbone of our city,&quot; the planning official said.</p>
<p>But many fear that the council's plans will lead to job losses.</p>
<p>&quot;My drivers have to live...think of their families,&quot; said Tasripah, a woman who owns a fleet of 50 bajajs.</p>
<p>Around 30,000 drivers depend on the bajaj to make a living, taking home about 10,000 rupiah ($5) a day after paying 20,000 ($10) to the owner.</p>
<p>Tasripah -- who says she makes about 60 million rupiah ($25,800) a year from her business -- said that the ban will not only affect owners and drivers but also millions of people who rely on the vehicles for quick short trips.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't have to change. There's no problem as there is,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Still, officials are plugging the scheme as part of a drive to turn Jakarta into a symbol of Indonesia's economic growth.</p>
<p>New toll roads have recently been built, by a company owned by President Suharto's daughter Siti Hardianti Rukmana. The same company has plans to build a $800 million elevated railway track next year and begin work on a subway in 2001.</p>
<p>In contrast, the bemo and the bajaj are slow, polluting and ecologically unfriendly. The city administration wants to replace them with bigger minivans which, officials said, will maximise road efficiency and be cleaner and safer.</p>
<p>Early attempts to get bemo drivers to switch to minivans by the 1998-deadline have been a failure with only 100 drivers signing up to the scheme. Officials said this is because around 750 of Jakarta's 1,800 bemos already operate without permits.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
