<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="47963" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: PRESS DIGEST - Vietnam - Sept 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Vietnam - Sept 11.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the official Vietnamese press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>VIETNAM NEWS</p>
<p>-- The Ministry of Planning and Investment licensed 192 joint ventures and wholly foreign investment projects in the first eight months of this year, with registered capital of over $3 billion. Companies from Taiwan, South Korea and Singapore continued to top the list of investors.</p>
<p>-- Twenty thousand tonnes of Vietnamese rice has arrived in the Cuban port of Havana as a gift from the Vietnamese people. -- A delegation from Vietnam's National Assembly, led by Chairman Nong Duc Manh, yesterday began an official visit to Malaysia.</p>
<p>-- Quebec's Minister for International Affairs, Sylvain Simard, will leave today after a three-day visit to Hanoi.</p>
<p>-- The overseas arm of Pacific Power, the Australian state of New South Wales' largest government enterprise, has won a $579.68 million dollar contract to design and supervise the construction of an electricity station in Pha Lai. NSW Premier Bob Carr and Pacific Power Chairman Fred Hilmer said in Sydney that Pacific Poiwer International and a Japanese development company would provide project supervision for the power station.</p>
<p>-- More than a dozen car makers and parts and accessories suppliers will display their latest models and technology at a show in Ho Chi Minh City October 3-7.</p>
<p>-- The State Bank of Vietnam will auction 50 billion dong ($4.54 million) of one-year Treasury bills today. - - - -</p>
<p>LE COURRIER DU VIETNAM</p>
<p>-- Bidding will open in April 1997 for the construction of a 300-km (188-mile) stretch of road between Vinh, Nghe An province, and Dong Ha, Quang Tri province. The World Bank is helping finance the $200-million project.</p>
<p>-- More than 165 foreign and local companies have signed up for an October 22-26 exhibition on Telecommunications, Computers, Radio and Television in Ho Chi Minh City. - - - -</p>
<p>NHAN DAN</p>
<p>-- Vietnam's army took part in a reforestration and protection project on 50,000 ha of forest area.</p>
<p>-- A $300-million shipbuilding project has been submitted to the government for official approval by the Ministry of Planning and Investment. The project is a joint-venture between four companies of the Hyundai group and Vietnam Shipbuilding Corp.</p>
<p>-- Minister of Science, Technology and Envronment Dang Huu said in an interview that government and Communist Party policies have not yet created a favourable environment for the development of science and technology. He said that in the near future, two percent of the state budget would be spent on scientific and technological development. - - - -</p>
<p>QUAN DOI NHAN DAN</p>
<p>-- The number of HIV carriers in Vietnam had reached 4,209 by the end of August. Three hundred and fifty-three were suffering from AIDS and 184 have died from the disease.</p>
<p>-- A conference was held in Hanoi on Tuesday by the central anti-flood and natural calamity committee and the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural development to discuss measures for storm and flood control in the country's central provinces. - - - -</p>
<p>HA NOI MOI</p>
<p>-- A ground breaking ceremony for a $12 million electrical conductors factory was held in Hanoi's Gia Lam district on Tuesday. The plant is joint-venture between Japan's Sumi Co. and Vietnam's Hanel.</p>
<p>-- Vietnam Central State Bank Deputy Governor Le Van Chau wrote in the newspaper that Asian countries are still Vietnam's biggest and most important partners. He said one of the ways to overcome backwardness was strong and fast development of the financial and monetary environment, a high savings rate and stronger domestic investment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
