<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48027" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel opens new Gaza crossing for Arab workers.</title>
<headline>Israel opens new Gaza crossing for Arab workers.</headline>
<dateline>GAZA 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel opened a second crossing point for Palestinian workers along its border with Gaza on Wednesday, a Palestinian official said.</p>
<p>The Sova checkpoint in the southern Gaza Strip will cut commuting time for between 800 and 900 Palestinians who have travelled to jobs in southern Israel through the northern Erez crossing.</p>
<p>&quot;It will lessen the pressure on Erez and ease the way for workers to get into Israel,&quot; Said al-Mudalal, a Palestinian labour ministry official, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Witnesses said some 700 Palestinians passed through Sova, previously used only for the transit of cargo, on Wednesday. The workers underwent Palestinian and Israeli security checks before being allowed into the Jewish state.</p>
<p>About 19,500 Gazans and 15,500 residents of the West Bank work in Israel.</p>
<p>Palestinian officials have urged Israel to allow in more workers by lifting a closure imposed on the West Bank and Gaza after suicide bombings by Moslem militants killed 59 people in the Jewish state in February and March.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GAZA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
