<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48051" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Sept 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Sept 11.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in the Swedish papers this morning. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAGENS NYHETER</p>
<p>- Unemployment among Swedish construction workers is set to rise as Norway reduces its demand for workers from neighbouring countries.</p>
<p>- The strong Swedish crown is keeping the Swedish debt down, helping the government to save over 40 billion crowns so far this year.</p>
<p>SVENSKA DAGBLADET</p>
<p>- Swedish electricity agency Nutek said it is possible that there will be insufficient electricity this winter in Sweden, leading to rationing and increased electricity prices.</p>
<p>- The Swedish government and parliament want better control over Swedish spies after a scandal erupted over the expulsion of a Swedish engineer from Russia. The defence minister is holding a press conference on Wednesday about a review of Sweden's intelligence sector.</p>
<p>- Sweden has isolated 50 HIV-infected patients, mostly drug addicts, under the infection protection law because they are judged to be in danger of spreading the illness.</p>
<p>DAGENS INDUSTRI</p>
<p>- The former board of Frigoscandia may be personally liable for 250 million crowns in damages for allegedly not mentioning a potential legal case against the refrigerated-transport and equipment company when it was sold to ASG.</p>
<p>- A Dagens Industri survey showed that companies, including Scandinavian Airlines System and Skanska, plan to continue providing employees with cars, as it appears new tax changes will not be as unfavourable as first imagined.</p>
<p>- Swedish engine part manufacturer Opcon has come under the shadow of the Morgan Grenfell investment funds investigation. Opcon is half owned by foreign interest including Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>-- Paul de Bendern, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1006</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
