<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="480758" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-ENGLISH CRICKET AT CRISIS POINT, WARNS WISDEN.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-ENGLISH CRICKET AT CRISIS POINT, WARNS WISDEN.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kitson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>English cricket has received a double blow to its self-esteem on the eve of the new season from the unexpected direction of Wisden, the sport's peerless reference book.</p>
<p>The 134th edition of the Almanack, published on Wednesday, warns that the game in England is in a &quot;potentially catastrophic&quot; state and nominates only overseas players as its Five Cricketers of the Year.</p>
<p>Pakistan's Saeed Anwar and Mushtaq Ahmed, India's Sachin Tendulkar, West Indian Phil Simmons and Sri Lanka's Sanath Jayasuriya, the first man to win the accolade without having played in the previous English season, make it a completely non-English list for the first time in 15 years.</p>
<p>But the most significant pages are the ones written by editor Matthew Engel and new England supremo Lord MacLaurin, who paint an alarming picture on the eve of a full-scale Ashes tour.</p>
<p>In his editorial, Engel describes the 1996 season as &quot;in some respects the most depressing in memory&quot; and does not mince words on the subject of the England team and those who run it.</p>
<p>&quot;Amid the general global mood of cricketing expansionism, England is a spectacular and potentially catastrophic exception.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1996-97 the national team reached a point where even the good days were bad. It felt as though the English, who were once presumed to have won first prize in the lottery of life, were now on the receiving end of some cosmic practical joke.</p>
<p>&quot;At the World Cup the England squad resembled a bad-tempered grandmother attending a teenage rave...unable to comprehend what was happening - on the field or off it - the players just lingered, looking sullen as well as incompetent.</p>
<p>&quot;They conveyed as bad an impression in Zimbabwe at the end of the year. The captain, Mike Atherton, and the coach, David Lloyd, were culpable in failing to understand the importance of their roles as public figures.&quot;</p>
<p>Former England captain Ray Illingworth's spell in charge of the national team will also &quot;not be remembered kindly&quot;, according to Engel.</p>
<p>&quot;It was sad to watch a man whose career embodied so many of the strengths of English cricket flail around and have his failings exposed so hopelessly in the World Cup. He had no long-term strategy, merely faith in his own instincts. It was not enough.&quot;</p>
<p>Engel is equally unimpressed by the lack of initiative shown from Lord's, claiming &quot;cricket in the UK has become unattractive to the vast majority of the population. The game is widely perceived as elitist, exclusionist and dull.&quot;</p>
<p>His views are endorsed by MacLaurin, the new chairman of the England Cricket Board, who warns that &quot;amber lights are flashing over our game.&quot;</p>
<p>In an article entitled English cricket: a manifesto' MacLaurin writes: &quot;It's been so rare for England to win Test matches that people can almost remember where they were when it happened.</p>
<p>&quot;To maintain the support of TV, sponsors and the public, the flagship - the England team - has to be successful. People want to be associated with winners.&quot;</p>
<p>Jayasuriya, whose batting heroics helped Sri Lanka win the 1996 World Cup, certainly comes under that heading and becomes only the third player from his country to be named as a Cricketer of the Year.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in its 1,440 pages, Wisden has a satisfying number of oddities from around the cricketing world as well as its first 'gossip column.'</p>
<p>&quot;We don't actually reveal who cricketers are sleeping with, but there are a lot of interesting personality stories that were a bit too informal for Wisden in the old days,&quot; said Engel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
