<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="480971" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Most UK finance bosses favour tax rises - survey.</title>
<headline>Most UK finance bosses favour tax rises - survey.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than half of Britain's finance directors think the next government should raise taxes to fund election commitments, a survey out on Thursday showed.</p>
<p>Some 55 percent of the 200 finance directors polled by Accountancy/Reed Accountancy Personnel said the next government should raise taxes to pay for improvements in education, the health service, law and order and other commitments.</p>
<p>And 58 percent of them believe it will do so.</p>
<p>An election is due on May 1 and the opposition Labour Party is riding high in the polls although the latest suggests the gap might be closing.</p>
<p>&quot;While more than half of those surveyed can see the benefit of raising additional revenue through increased taxation, many are adamant that taxes should not be raised,&quot; said David Callaghan, director of Reed Accountancy Personnel.</p>
<p>Only 37 percent of the directors surveyed were against tax inreases but most of those were resigned to the fact that taxes would rise regardless of who takes power.</p>
<p>&quot;Whilst most agree that any political party would be foolish to fight the election on a tax-raising policy, by far the majority of financial directors believe that taxes will rise after the election has been won, no matter who come out the winners,&quot; Callaghan said.</p>
<p>-- Mike Peacock, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
