<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="480970" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Labour's Blair pledges &quot;contract&quot; with UK voters.</title>
<headline>Labour's Blair pledges &quot;contract&quot; with UK voters.</headline>
<byline>Giles Elgood</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>British opposition Labour Party leader Tony Blair launches his election manifesto on Thursday, offering voters a new &quot;contract&quot; in an attempt to convince them he will keep his promises if he becomes prime minister.</p>
<p>Blair will be buoyed by an opinion poll showing that his party's commanding lead over Prime Minister John Major's Conservatives has stretched to 27 points ahead of the May 1 election.</p>
<p>A MORI poll in The Times newspaper gave Labour 55 percent against 28 percent for the Conservatives, suggesting that the ruling party has paid a price for persistent allegations of sex and money scandals in its ranks.</p>
<p>But a Conservative member of parliament whose resignation had been demanded by the party leadership following a newspaper report that he had a fling with a 17-year-old nightclub hostess was endorsed by local party officials.</p>
<p>Piers Merchant, who denies he had sex with hostess Anna Cox, was re-selected as a parliamentary candidate after a meeting of the Beckenham Conservative Association, who apparently accepted his contention that he was set up by tabloid journalists.</p>
<p>Blair meanwhile released a handwritten &quot;contract&quot; listing the 10 key promises he wants to form the centrepiece of the manifesto he will unveil at 0930 GMT on Thursday.</p>
<p>Blair is said by aides to be convinced that Britons are tired of politicians making election promises which they do not keep when they get into power and will restrict himself to pledges he is convinced he can honour.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a What-You-See-Is-What-You-Get manifesto,&quot; one aide said. &quot;John Major breaks promises, Tony Blair keeps promises. Tony Blair can be trusted to deliver.&quot;</p>
<p>In the contract, Blair says Labour will not raise income tax rates and will provide stable non-inflationary economic growth.</p>
<p>He says education will be his government's number one priority, and spending on it will rise.</p>
<p>And he repeats a promise to take 250,000 young people out of the dole queues, using proceeds of a windfall tax on surplus profits of water, gas, electricity and other firms privatised by the Conservatives.</p>
<p>Other pledges include more money for National Health Service patient care, the safeguarding of Britain's environment, a cleanup of politics following a bout of sleaze and to &quot;give Britain the leadership in Europe which Britain and Europe need.&quot;</p>
<p>Labour's manifesto launch follows the same exercise on Wednesday by the Conservatives, who promised low taxes as part of a 25-point programme that Major said would help make Britain the best place in the world to live.</p>
<p>Describing the manifesto as the boldest any party had published since the Conservatives took power in 1979, Major tackled head on Blair's argument that it was time for a change after 18 unbroken years of Conservative rule.</p>
<p>&quot;It is time for a change. Time for a change to the next phase of Conservative prosperity that will give everyone -- no matter who they are, where they live -- more choice and more control over their lives,&quot; Major told a news conference.</p>
<p>The Conservatives also plan to tackle Blair over his refusal to honour a pledge to hold a televised debate with Major.</p>
<p>A man dressed in a large yellow chicken suit will follow Blair around in an attempt to goad him into agreeing to appear in a television debate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
