<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="481021" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Iraq April Kirkuk exports seen up, May price lower.</title>
<headline>Iraq April Kirkuk exports seen up, May price lower.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prices for Iraqi Kirkuk crude oil exports will fall in May in line with Saudi price cuts announced on Wednesday but Baghdad's customers will have little opportunity to defer liftings given thin exports in late March, traders said.</p>
<p>With Iraq's State Oil Marketing Organisation (SOMO) keen to complete term exports for the second 90-day period of the U.N. oil-for-food deal by early June, traders think most barrels nominated April loading dates at the Turkish port of Ceyhan will be lifted.</p>
<p>&quot;In April SOMO is trying to catch up with March and in May they will be catching up with April,&quot; said a senior trader for a European refiner lifting Kirkuk this month.</p>
<p>State Saudi Aramco told European customers it was reducing the May crude price formula for Arab Light by 30 cents to Dated Brent less $2.25 a barrel and for U.S. customers by 15 cents to WTI less $3.60 a barrel.</p>
<p>Kirkuk Blend, which is linked on a cent-for-cent basis with Arab Light under arrangements established by the United Nations, will be priced for May 30 cents lower at Dated Brent less $2.20 a barrel into Europe and down 15 cents to WTI less $3.65 a barrel into the U.S.</p>
<p>But traders say they do not expect a repeat of the rash of deferrals last month, when several customers successfully delayed loadings into April to take advantage of the one-off 25-cent reduction in the Kirkuk formula confirmed in mid-March on top of a 10 cent cut in Arab Light.</p>
<p>&quot;In the first few days of March there were reasonable liftings from Ceyhan but after March 10, the second quarter of the U.N. deal got off to a pretty slow start,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Traders said the preliminary April loading programme for Kirkuk Blend scheduled 10 or 11 cargoes totalling about 13 million barrels or about 430,000 barrels per day (bpd).</p>
<p>By comparison, February loadings were pegged around 335,000 bpd. Some said the April total could turn out to be even higher.</p>
<p>&quot;The full volume is not there. Only the term contracts have been nominated and that is not going to be enough to meet the $1 billion target,&quot; said a trader predicting further spot sales by SOMO.</p>
<p>Traders were offering Kirkuk Blend on the spot market at premiums to the April OSP of Dated Brent less $1.90 a barrel, a level which was attracting little interest in the face of fierce competition from rival Russian Urals.</p>
<p>Russian Urals was valued around Dated Brent less $1.40 a barrel basis cif Augusta.</p>
<p>&quot;At these kind of levels Urals makes more sense than Kirkuk,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Following the release by Saudi Arabia of May price formulas Iraqi prices for the month, in dollars a barrel, are as follows:</p>
<p> Basrah Light			MAY     APR</p>
<p>    Far East	Oman/Dubai -$0.05  +$0.05</p>
<p>    U.S.	 2nd month WTI -$4.20  -$4.05</p>
<p>    Kirkuk Blend</p>
<p>    Europe	 Dated Brent -$2.20  -$1.90</p>
<p>    U.S.		     WTI -$3.65  -$3.50</p>
<p>-- Mark Thompson, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7930</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
