<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="481040" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: One 2 one connects 75,000 more in Q1.</title>
<headline>One 2 one connects 75,000 more in Q1.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>One 2 One, the British mobile telephone business jointly-owned by Cable and Wireless Plc and U S West Inc, on Wednesday reported record new connections with 75,000 subscribers added in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>Net growth in the quarter jumped a hefty 114 percent against the comparable period in 1996, the company said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Although the new subscription figure outstrips that of market leader Vodafone Group Plc, which reported net new UK subscribers of 67,000 on Tuesday, it lags that of Britain's youngest mobile operator -- Orange Plc.</p>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday, Orange reported 109,000 new subscribers over the past three months and a customer base of 894,000.</p>
<p>One 2 One's share of the total UK market for mobile phones has risen to 8.5 percent from 7.1 percent as its customer base at March 31, 1997, grew 51 percent over the year to 620,000, the group said.</p>
<p>&quot;For the second consecutive quarter, One 2 One has broken records, achieving 114 percent net growth against the comparable period and the best ever January to March quarter for gross sales,&quot; said Jan Peters, One 2 One's managing director.</p>
<p>Peters said a wide-ranging television and press advertising campaign and new consumer promotions had helped the figures and made a &quot;positive impact&quot; on churn levels -- the number of people ending subscriptions. It declined to reveal what churn levels were.</p>
<p>The company's service now reaches about 80 percent of the population and by this December should be available to 95 percent.</p>
<p>The fourth mobile operator in Britain, Cellnet, is also expected to reveal subscriber figures on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Analysts expect Cellnet, Britain's second biggest mobile phone company that is majority owned by British Telecommunications Plc, to report sharply lower new subscriber numbers after recent problems that include the departure of its managing director.</p>
<p>BT, which is openly interested in -- but currently restricted by regulators from -- buying out the remaining 40 percent stake owned by Securicor Group Plc, may use the disappointing figures to barter a bargain price for the stake that analysts value at between 1.2 and 1.6 billion stg.</p>
<p>Analysts expect the restriction on BT buying out Securicor to be lifted in due course.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 4017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
