<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="481072" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ETHIOPIA: African ministers say World Bank debt plan inflexible.</title>
<headline>African ministers say World Bank debt plan inflexible.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>ADDIS ABABA 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The World Bank on Wednesday said a debt relief plan for the world's poorest countries was meant to ensure governments pursued reforms, but African ministers said its rigid criteria meant few could benefit.</p>
<p>African ministers of finance ended a conference in the Ethiopian capital Addis Ababa on Wednesday saying the plan was a partial solution to the continent's debt crisis and would fail if the World Bank criteria were not more flexible.</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to be concerned that the magnitudes of debt are unsustainable,&quot; they said in a statement. &quot;African countries devote a large proportion of their resources to servicing external debt when their social sectors and infrastructures are in dire need of rehabilitation and reform.&quot;</p>
<p>Jean-Louis Sarbib and Callisto Madavo, World Bank vice presidents for the African region, told Reuters that the ministers' concerns were real but it was up to them to take steps that would ensure growth of their economies.</p>
<p>&quot;We see the debt problem as real and this should be a real opportunity to make a difference,&quot; Sarbib said. &quot;We are not in the business of forcing a country to do something that is not in its interest. We are not police. We have travelled a long distance over this.&quot;</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the World Bank last month approved a debt relief plan for Uganda, making it the first candidate of the Debt Initiative for Heavily Indebted Countries (HIPC).</p>
<p>Sarbib and Madavo said Ivory Coast, Burkina Faso and Bolivia were other immediate candidates for the plan. Later in the year, Madavo said, the World Bank would also look at Ethiopia, Mozambique, Mali, Guinea Bissau and Sao Tome.</p>
<p>African ministers said 33 of 41 so-called HIPC countries were in Africa but the rigidity of criteria and eligibility meant few could benefit.</p>
<p>Africa's international debt stands at around $340 billion and Africans spend $24 billion annually on debt servicing.</p>
<p>The World Bank has put a $500 million contribution to a HIPC Trust Fund. Bilateral contributions stand at $43 million.</p>
<p>In general, a country is required under the initiative to establish a six-year record with IMF tutorship that shows strong economic reform efforts. Debt relief aims at improving living conditions by a sustained level of economic growth.</p>
<p>The initiative was undertaken when it became clear that the repayment of old loans to lending agencies such as the World Bank and IMF were draining some of the poorest countries, making it impossible for them to get on their feet no matter what reforms they made.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFRICA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ETHPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADDIS ABABA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ETHIOPIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
