<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="481063" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Storage buying propels Canada spot natgas prices.</title>
<headline>Storage buying propels Canada spot natgas prices.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian spot natural gas prices continued their climb on Wednesday as players in the west scrambled to buy supply for storage injection.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole western part of North America is strong and I think it's going to stay up there,&quot; said a Calgary-based marketer. &quot;We only had 140 million (cubic feet per day) of injections yesterday in Alberta and people felt very uncomfortable with that.&quot;</p>
<p>Spot gas at the AECO storage hub was quoted at C$1.73 per gigajoule, up from C$1.65 on Tuesday and C$1.475 last week. May AECO was quoted at C$1.68 in Wednesday trade.  </p>
<p>The Canadian Gas Association said on Friday that western Canadian natural gas storage facilities were 16.80 percent full at March 21, down by more than 10 percentage points from the same time last year.</p>
<p>Stronger prices were also quoted at Sumas, Wash., where storoage concerns combined with cooler weather in the U.S. Pacific Northwest and higher electricity prices to boost demand, traders said.</p>
<p>In eastern Canada, where gas storage levels were about the same as last year, prices at Niagara and Dawn were off about US5 cents per million British thermal units from Tuesday's and last week's levels.</p>
<p>((Reuters Calgary Bureau (403) 531-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
