<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="481039" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: ACI sets provisional programme for Toronto Forex.</title>
<headline>ACI sets provisional programme for Toronto Forex.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Association Cambiste Internationale (ACI) has set out the provisional programme for its 39th annual congress in Toronto on May 29-31.</p>
<p>The planned keynote speaker is Bank of Canada Governor Gordon Thiessen, who on Friday May 30 will deliver a speech, &quot;How well are exchange rates working? A Canadian perspective&quot; which will be followed by a question and answer session.</p>
<p>Following Thiessen, Bill McDonough, President of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York will present &quot;The case for price stability,&quot; also followed by a Q and A.</p>
<p>South African Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals will speak on &quot;South Africa - Opportunities and Concerns&quot;</p>
<p>Other planned speakers include Mikio Wakatshuki, Chairman of the Board of Counsellors at the Japan Research Institute, Rudi Dornbusch, Professor of Economics at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and Jean Monty, President and CEO of Northern Telecom Limited.</p>
<p>Other speakers are detailed in the full listing of the provisional programme below ---</p>
<p>Friday May 30 09:00 - 09:10</p>
<p>Welcoming Remarks</p>
<p>Rob Wittmann, President, Financial Markets Association of Canada (FMAC) 09:10 - 09:20</p>
<p>Welcoming Remarks</p>
<p>Eugne Prim, President, ACI - The Financial Markets Association 09:20 - 09:45</p>
<p>How Well are Exchange Rates Working? (A Canadian Perspective)</p>
<p>Gordon Thiessen, Governor, Bank of Canada 09:45 - 10:30</p>
<p>The Case for Price Stability</p>
<p>Bill McDonough, President, Federal Reserve Bank of New York 11:00 - 11:40</p>
<p>Financial Reform in Japan and its Implications</p>
<p>Mikio Wakatshuki, Chairman, Board of Counselors, Japan</p>
<p>Research Institute 11:40 - 12:30</p>
<p>EMU Update</p>
<p>Dr. Rudi Dornbusch, Professor of Economics, MIT 14:00 - 14:45</p>
<p>South Africa - Opportunities and Concerns</p>
<p>Dr. C.L. Stals, Governor, Reserve Bank of South Africa 15:15 - 15:50</p>
<p>Competing Globally in the High Technology Industry</p>
<p>Jean Monty, President and CEO, Northern Telecom Ltd. 15:50 - 16:00</p>
<p>Closing Remarks</p>
<p>Barry Wainstein, Chair, FOREX 97 Organizing Committee Saturday May 31 10:00 - 10:40</p>
<p>Asia in the 21st Century</p>
<p>Toyoo Gyohten, President, Institute for International Monetary</p>
<p>Affairs, Tokyo 10:40 - 11:15</p>
<p>Opportunities &amp; Risks in Hong Kong and China</p>
<p>Richard Li, Chairman and Chief Executive, Pacific Century Group 11:15 - 11:45</p>
<p>The Outlook for Chile and Latin America</p>
<p>Dr. Eduardo Aninat, Minister of Finance, Chile 11:45 - 12:15</p>
<p>Political Risk in Financial Markets</p>
<p>Dr. John M. Deutch, former Director, Central Intelligence Agency,</p>
<p>currently Professor, MIT 12:15 - 12:30</p>
<p>Wrap-Up and Closing Remarks</p>
<p>Barry Wainstein, Chair, FOREX 97 Organizing Committee</p>
<p>Phil Smith, London Forex desk +44-171-542-6284</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
