<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48117" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOZAMBIQUE: FEATURE-Mozambique economy stirs from sick bed.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Mozambique economy stirs from sick bed.</headline>
<byline>Michael Rudolph</byline>
<dateline>MAPUTO 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mozambique is shrugging off its reputation as one of the world's poorest countries, helped by five years of impressive economic growth.</p>
<p>New preliminary data from the World Bank suggests the country, devastated by a 16-year civil war which ended only in 1992, is doing better than many economists thought.</p>
<p>The Bank's 1996 World Development Report said the average gross national product (GNP) in 1994 was just $90 a head. But chief representative in Mozambique Roberto Chavez told Reuters Television he believes this is an underestimate.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in the process of revising the GNP per capita figures and it is safe to assume that we can no longer speak of Mozambique as the poorest country in the world, but having a GNP that is perhaps as high as $120 to $150,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Figures from the Harvard Institute for International Development show Mozambique was the fastest-growing economy in sub-Saharan Africa betwen 1990 and 1995, registering average annual growth of over eight percent.</p>
<p>The 1994 multi-party elections have given Mozambique its greatest measure of political stability since independence from Portugal in 1975.</p>
<p>President Joaquim Chissano's government is also starting to deliver economic stability with the currency having held steady for nearly a year and inflation on the decline.</p>
<p>Together, these factors have encouraged international investors back, lured in particular by the promise of cheap energy in the form of natural gas and hydro-electricity.</p>
<p>&quot;After many years of hesitation, investors have started coming in force,&quot; Chissano said in an interview</p>
<p>&quot;There is more confidence in Mozambique nowadays...we are confident that our country will come out from this classification as the poorest in the world.&quot;</p>
<p>Despite a rising middle class, boasting new private cars, poverty remains widespread. But Chissano hopes some major projects now in the works will have a dramatic impact on Mozambique's modest economy and its 15 million people.</p>
<p>The government has signed an outline agreement with U.S. company Enron Corp to extract and market gas from the Pande field, including construction of a pipeline from Inhambane province northeast of Maputo to South Africa.</p>
<p>At the same time South Africa's Gencor Ltd is studying the feasibility of establishing an aluminium smelter, with an initial capacity of 245,000 tonnes a year, near Maputo. Power could come from a new hydro-electric scheme on the Zambezi downstream from the existing Cahora Bassa dam.</p>
<p>Chissano said a second aluminium project, backed by a U.S. company, was also under consideration for the north of the country.</p>
<p>And Mozambique is expecting an economic fillip from the &quot;Maputo Corridor&quot; which will link the country's main port with South Africa's industrial heartland around Johannesburg.</p>
<p>The scheme, which won enthusiastic support from both governments earlier this year, should boost Mozambique's nascent manufacturing and service sectors, while offering South African firms access to Maputo port, nearer to Johannesburg than Durban.</p>
<p>In the last year the farming sector, still the bedrock of the economy, has enjoyed bumper crops following excellent rains.</p>
<p>Chissano believes a planned migration of South African farmers will provide a badly needed injection of capital and know-how.</p>
<p>Chavez said he was also encouraged by progress on privatisation.</p>
<p>Earlier this year Chissano's government sold off the country's largest bank, state-run BCM with a 70 percent market share, and recently signed up a deal for a private company to take over administration of the customs service.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of the economic indicators are very positive and the trend seems good,&quot; Chavez said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAPUTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOZAMBIQUE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
