<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48123" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton lashes Dole in ads, Perot selects VP.</title>
<headline>Clinton lashes Dole in ads, Perot selects VP.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, U.S. Political Correspondent</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton on Tuesday lashed out at Bob Dole in two television commercials, while Texas billionaire Ross Perot introduced a little-known anti-free trade economist as his running mate.</p>
<p>Perot said during a half-hour television campaign ad that Choate, an academic and determined critic of the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), was an expert on economic policy and would play a key role in his campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;He knows the system. He knows what's wrong with it. We agree what's wrong with it. His views are your views out there across America,&quot; said Perot, who is running for the fledgling Reform Party he founded and financed from his own pocket.</p>
<p>With Perot trailing in the polls at around five percent, his failure to persuade a national figure to run with him on his ticket unlikely to revitalise his prospects.</p>
<p>In other developments, Dole, who is also looking for a shot in the arm, arranged a meeting with Republican members of Congress on Wednesday to steady nerves about his and their election prospects.</p>
<p>The latest CNN/USA tracking poll showed Clinton's lead over Dole unchanged at a substantial 21 percentage points.</p>
<p>But Clinton is not sitting on his lead. He stayed on the offensive with a new advertisement attacked Dole for opposing the popular Family and Medical Leave Act, which allows employees to take unpaid time off for family emergencies.</p>
<p>&quot;Bob Dole led a six-year fight against Family Leave. Twelve million have used leave but Dole's still against it,&quot; the commercial says.</p>
<p>Dole campaign spokeswoman Christina Martin reacted indignantly, calling the advertisement a &quot;moral outrage ... nasty and spiteful.&quot;</p>
<p>A second advertisement decried Dole for raising taxes throughout his career. &quot;Bob Dole: 35 years in Washington, 35 years of higher taxes,&quot; an announcer declares.</p>
<p>Dole last weekend denounced the Family Leave Act as unwarranted government intrusion and said the federal government should leave such matters to states and local communities to regulate.</p>
<p>Campaigning in Kansas City on Tuesday, Clinton rejected Dole's criticism. &quot;I just respectfully disagree. I think we were right to do it. ... It's not a big radical step. It's pro-family and pro-work,&quot; the president said.</p>
<p>Dole's meeting with congressional Republicans was clearly designed to to calm fears that the Nov. 5 election in shaping up as a disaster for the party.</p>
<p>Republican leaders put a positive spin on the meeting. Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott said its purpose was to discuss the legislative agenda and receive a briefing on the presidential campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there's plenty of time for them to get their message of economic growth out to the public .... I think there's a long way between now and the election in November and I'm counting on a very competitive campaign,&quot; Lott said.</p>
<p>Perot got 19 percent of the vote in 1992 but is currently trailing with about five percent in the polls, making his participation in upcoming presidential debates open to doubt.</p>
<p>Dole and Clinton campaign officials plan to hold their first negotiating session on Thursday to discuss the rules of the debates, the first of which is tentatively scheduled for Sept. 25 in St Louis, Missouri.</p>
<p>Meanwhile the independent Commission on Presidential Debates will announce next Monday whether it believes Perot should take part. Its recommendations, while not binding on the campaigns, will carry substantial weight.</p>
<p>The commission is proposing three presidential debates and one between vice presidential candidates on four successive Wednesdays starting on Sept. 25.</p>
<p>Dole spent the day in Louisiana trying to shore up his southern Republican base. He pushed his 15 percent income tax cut and blamed Clinton for increased drug use by teenagers.</p>
<p>At a rally in the small Louisiana town of Baker, Dole derided Clinton's claim that another four years of his Democratic administration would be a bridge to a brighter American future.</p>
<p>&quot;Which bridge to the future is right for America? My opponent would build a bridge of higher taxes and more teenagers using drugs, of a government-run health care system, more liberal judges, an economy producing fewer jobs and more and more and more government,&quot; Dole said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
