<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="481365" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil coffee council members to meet April 8.</title>
<headline>Brazil coffee council members to meet April 8.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Members of Brazil's joint private and public coffee council are to meet at 1500 local/1800 GMT on April 8 in Brasilia, private sector representatives said.</p>
<p>The meeting will be to hold preliminary talks ahead of the next official session of the council, known as the CDPC, now take place on May 5 in Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais state.</p>
<p>Previously the CDPC had been scheduled for April 28.</p>
<p>Private sector representatives said they also expected to discuss any proposals Brazil may wish to submit to the Association of Coffee Producing Countries (ACPC) on coffee market stabilisation plans from July 1997.</p>
<p>The ACPC secretariat has asked members to send any suggestions to London by April 15.</p>
<p>Private sector officials have also been invited to a lunch on April 4 at the Fundacao Getulio Vargas (FGV) in Rio de Janeiro to be attended by Mauricio Assis, the head of the Industry and Commerce Ministry's primary commodities department.</p>
<p>The FGV has been contracted by the CDPC to prepare a document putting forward future strategies for the coffee sector while taking into consideration issues such as producer debts.</p>
<p>A preliminary draft of the document should be ready by the end of this month ahead of the May 5 CDPC meeting while a final version is expected by the end of May, a FGV official said.</p>
<p>((-Caroline Bulloch, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 5074151))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
