<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48154" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Motorola passing through rough patch, seen recovering.</title>
<headline>Motorola passing through rough patch, seen recovering.</headline>
<byline>Susan Nadeau</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Telecommunications giant Motorola Inc., whose corporate culture strives for as few as three mistakes for every one million tasks, is passing through a difficult time but is not in serious trouble, industry experts said Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;My perspective is this is a rough patch, but not serious trouble,&quot; said Russell Roberts, director of the Management Centre at the John M. Olin School of Business at Washington University in St. Louis.</p>
<p>&quot;They're still a strong, robust company,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Schaumburg, Ill.-based Motorola said it would not meet third-quarter earnings expectations, and that earnings might be more than 25 percent lower than second quarter's $326 million, or 54 cents a share. First- and second-quarter earnings fell far below Wall Street estimates as well.</p>
<p>Motorola's stock fell $1.50 to $47.75 Thursday on the New York Stock Exchange, where it was again one of the most active shares. On Wednesday the stock fell $1.375.</p>
<p>By contrast, last year Motorola grew some 22 percent and ended the year generating over $27 billion in revenues selling semiconductors, pagers, cell phones and infrastructure.</p>
<p>&quot;No company is going to grow 22 percent for very long,&quot; said Jim Buckman, co-director of the Quality Leadership Centre at the Carlson School of Management, the University of Minnesota. &quot;My suspicion is that it is not a long-term problem and that Motorola continues to be one of the best-managed companies on the planet.&quot;</p>
<p>The industry experts agreed Motorola is a company that pushes itself to perform.</p>
<p>In the 1980s it adopted the Malcolm Baldrige business management model and is famous for &quot;Six Sigma&quot; quality -- in reference to a statistical term -- striving for as few as three errors per one million tasks, in the factories all the way to office work.</p>
<p>This quarter's hurdle is caused by an oversupply of semiconductors and stiff international competition in the cellular phone and pager business, Motorola said.</p>
<p>Cellular phones, for example, are being mass-produced internationally and Motorola's market share, estimated as high as 40 percent worldwide, is diminishing.</p>
<p>Roberts, who in 1994 published a novel based on Motorola in the 1960s when it was faced with increasing competition in manufacturing television sets, said the situation in some ways parallels that of Motorola now. At that point, the company thrived after taking a risk and selling its TV business.</p>
<p>&quot;It may be that cellular phones are best produced in the United States, and it may turn out that the best idea is to license them and spend your creative efforts and limited amounts of focus on a new product,&quot; Roberts said. He said Motorola was still investing heavily in research and development.</p>
<p>&quot;A very pessimistic forecast in the 1960s that they would lose their business turned out to be totally wrong,&quot; he said, adding that at the time the company had 15,000 employees, which grew to 100,000 by the early 1990s.</p>
<p>Despite market speculation, analysts tracking the company said they were sure Motorola has a plan -- and it probably at this point does not include unloading the cellular phone business.</p>
<p>&quot;They are driven by their own vision and only modestly affected by Wall Street,&quot; Buckman said.</p>
<p>But one thing is for sure, despite winning the prestigious Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award, in 1988, there is always room for improvement, especially when projecting earnings in a volatile market.</p>
<p>&quot;Their forecasting process is probably not as perfect as Six Sigma,&quot; said Roger Schroeder, a professor at the Carlson School of Management at the University of Minnesota.</p>
<p>The company is expected to report its third-quarter results on Oct. 7.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
