<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="481621" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Istanbul gold exchange volume hits new record.</title>
<headline>Istanbul gold exchange volume hits new record.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Traded volume on the Istanbul gold exchange hit a new record on Wednesday of 3,870 kilos after the previous record of 2,950 kilos on Monday.</p>
<p>Dealers said trading was heavily based on banks' arbitrage deals and registering imported gold on the exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact there was a small amount of real trade which will cause gold to go out of the bourse. Most of the trading was based on arbitrage deals between banks and registering gold,&quot; said a bank dealer.</p>
<p>Gold closed higher at $352.00 an ounce and 1,446,500 lira per gram, up from Tuesday's $351.00 and 1,439,800 lira in line with firmer world prices. The lira closed easier at 127,850 to the dollar versus 127,650 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Bourse members must register imported gold on the exchange by selling and buying the gold themselves before they can sell it to non-member third parties in the free market.</p>
<p>Most of the day's trade took place in the morning session with only 205 kilos changing hands in the afternoon. 50.9 percent of the total turnover was conducted in dollar terms. --Istanbul newsroom +90-212-2750875.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
