<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48177" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British Aerospace 1st half profits take off.</title>
<headline>British Aerospace 1st half profits take off.</headline>
<byline>Greg Mahlich</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Aerospace Plc announced a near 75 percent jump in headline first-half profits on Thursday which it said testified to the success of its radical restructuring in recent years.</p>
<p>&quot;We have got real growth, margins improving, a very strong order book and we are generating cash,&quot; finance director Richard Lapthorne told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Pretax profits for the six months to end-June leapt to 199 million pounds ($309.5 million) from 114 million pounds last year with underlying profits before exceptional charges rising 38 percent to 215 million pounds from 156 million last time.</p>
<p>The interim dividend was raised 25 percent to 6.25 pence a share on earnings up 58 percent at 34.9 pence.</p>
<p>Investors greeted the news by marking up the shares 11p to 10.235 pounds. &quot;The figures did come in above forecasts, said industry analyst Paul Pickford at brokers Panmure Gordon in London. &quot;There was an upbeat statement and better cash position than expected,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lapthorne said the company was also pleased with the net cash position of 511 million pounds at the end of June &quot;because we have managed it very well.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the company feared there could have been a stronger draw on cash now BAe is building another batch of Tornado fighter bombers for Saudi Arabia but working capital was contained to 50 million pounds in the first half.</p>
<p>Meanwhile chief executive Sir Richard Evans said the group's strong performance was set to continue thanks to increased productivity and a 13 billion pound order book, including defence orders worth 9.2 billion pounds.</p>
<p>&quot;The measures taken, and continuing, to improve productivity are driving the strong performance now becoming evident from these results and will ensure tha maximum value is derived from delivering the substantial forward order book,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>BAe's defence business increased its first half operating profits to 255 million pounds from 240 million a year ago on sales of 2,174 million pounds.</p>
<p>Evans said the defence order book of 9.2 billion pounds will get a further boost in the second half of the year from the recent award of two British orders for Nimrod maritime patrol aircraft and for air-launched cruise missiles which together are worth over two billion pounds.</p>
<p>BAe's commercial aerospace division turned in another loss in the half year with continuing problems with BAe's Jetstream turboprop regional passenger aircraft business swallowing up profits from BAe's work making wings for the four-nation Airbus Industrie consortium.</p>
<p>Increased work for Airbus helped cut the commercial aerospace division's overall losses to 33 million pounds from 59 million on sales up at 754 million pounds from 678 million.</p>
<p>BAe said strong sales at Airbus has left it with outstanding orders worth three billion pounds for Airbus wings and it planned to increase production rates from 125 wings this year to 190 in 1997 and over 220 in 1998.</p>
<p>The company does not disclose its profits from Airbus, which are disguised by the unspecified level of losses at Jetstream.</p>
<p>It is no secret that Jetstream is suffering from too much competition in a limited market for passenger turboprops, and remains BAe's biggest remaining headache. But Evans declined to say whether they were contemplating closing the operation down.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the weakness in the portfolio,&quot; Evans told Reuters in the same interview on Thursday. &quot;We have taken a further cut in the production rate...from 30 aircraft to 20 (a year) and will continue to review that rate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have clearly got to review the way the market is beginning to move but we are prepared for any eventuality. At the present time 20 aircraft a year is relatively modest number.&quot;</p>
<p>($1=.6430 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
