<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="481980" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RESEARCH ALERT - Semiconductor industry seen strong.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Semiconductor industry seen strong.</headline>
<text>
<p>-- Prudential Securities said it expects semiconductor companies to post March-quarter earnings that reflect continued strengthening of the overall industry and individual company fundamentals.</p>
<p>-- said it expects relatively few negative earnings surprises and expects most companies to meet or slightly exceed consensus earnings estimates.  </p>
<p>-- said expects firmer dynamic random-access memory (DRAM) chip prices, low inventories at original equipment manufacturers and distributors and expanding lead times in selected products &quot;will allow most management teams to suggest that near-term visibility has improved.&quot;</p>
<p>-- said Xilinx Inc and Altera Corp will benefit from better-than-expected revenue growth within the programmable logic devices market and the weaker yen. Said these companies should show slight improvement in gross margins and positive earnings surprises.  </p>
<p>-- said LSI Logic Corp and Vitesse Semiconductor Corp should benefit from solid bookings and increasing capacity utilization levels.</p>
<p>-- said believes demand in the personal computer sector can be categorized as &quot;falling within the normal expectations for seasonal weakness in the first quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>-- said the lack of price cuts on high-end microprocessors will lead to expanding gross margins and positive earnings for Intel Corp.</p>
<p>-- said it expects the above companies to post positive earnings surprises, but they will not exceed consensus estimates by more than five percent.</p>
<p>-- said certain pricing weakness and seasonally weak PC demand will cause Advanced Micro Devices to fall slightly short of its expectations for break-even earnings.</p>
<p>-- said expects the loss to be minimal and not &quot;meaningfully&quot;below the consensus estimate of a $0.03 per share loss.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
