<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48195" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Baffling Australian jobs data confuses rate outlook.</title>
<headline>Baffling Australian jobs data confuses rate outlook.</headline>
<byline>John Mair</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian employment climbed in August, official data released on Thursday showed, but the news was tempered by a rise in the unemployment rate.</p>
<p>The result baffled economists and prompted contradicting forecasts for the next move in official interest rates. Some said the data showed the economy gathering further strength while others said it revealed nagging weakness.</p>
<p>Employment rose by 37,900 in the month, well above market expectations for a rise of 11,000, the Australian Bureau of Statistics said.</p>
<p>But the figure was boosted by the inclusion of 10,000 temporary workers hired for the national census held in August.</p>
<p>Despite the robust employment figures, the unemployment rate jumped to 8.8 percent from 8.5 percent in July. Most economists had expected the August rate to remain unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a bit baffling. There is very strong employment growth and a higher unemployment rate,&quot; Bankers Trust Australia chief economist Chris Caton said.</p>
<p>&quot;In a sense, you can read what you like into the August labour force data as to the relative strength or weakness of the labour market,&quot; Citibank chief economist Grant Bailey said.</p>
<p>Most economists did just that.</p>
<p>Those who said the data showed the economy was stronger and reduced the chance of a rate cut pointed to the fact that the increase was above expectations and marked the fifth consecutive monthly employment rise.</p>
<p>&quot;In the face of today's employment number, the case for a rate cut crumbles,&quot; Societe Generale economists said.</p>
<p>Bain and Co associate director Ivan Colhoun added that even excluding the effect of the census workers, August jobs growth still approached 28,000.</p>
<p>&quot;This is another strong number among a string of strong numbers recently,&quot; Colhoun said, noting it followed strong retail sales, housing finance and credit data.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of this data precedes or is coincident with the last rate cut which the RBA described as a confidence booster,&quot; Colhoun said. &quot;It would seem the chances of another cut are somewhat less than some people are saying,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>However, those factoring in another rate cut in 1996 said the reasons behind a reduction of 0.5 percentage points to 7.0 percent in official rates on July 31 -- a moderating wages and inflation outlook and an unemployment rate stalled at 8.5 percent -- were still present in the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;If wages are under control, inflation is low and the unemployment rate is high, a strong case can be made for lower interest rates this year,&quot; State Bank of New South Wales chief economist Hans Kunnen said.</p>
<p>Caton at Bankers Trust added: &quot;Today's figures somewhat increase the likelihood that the economy will eventually need a further interest rate cut.&quot;</p>
<p>In Canberra, Reserve Bank of Australia Governor (RBA) Bernie Fraser, who retires next week, reiterated that the RBA was comfortable with inflation but concerned about unemployment.</p>
<p>&quot;On inflation, we're a bit more confident about what might happen over the next six or 12 months than we are about what might happen to growth and employment,&quot; Fraser told a parliamentary committee.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
