<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="482044" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Crude oil prices drop sharply, gold and coffee fall.</title>
<headline>Crude oil prices drop sharply, gold and coffee fall.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crude oil prices dropped to their lowest level in months on Wednesday as news of growing supplies and the end of the winter heating season fueled selling by speculators.</p>
<p>At the New York Mercantile Exchange, crude oil for delivery in May closed at $19.47 a barrel, down 81 cents and its lowest closing price since August 30, 1996.</p>
<p>That price was also the lowest for a spot or first month delivery of crude oil on the exchange since March 4, 1996, when oil closed at $19.20 a barrel.</p>
<p>Pressured by the selling in crude oil, May delivery gasoline closed 2.06 cents lower at 60.61 cents a gallon and May heating oil down 1.43 cents at 52.52 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>Gasoline prices typically rise in the spring ahead of the summer driving season, when gasoline demand peaks.</p>
<p>However, the American Petroleum Institute's weekly oil inventory data for the week ended March 28 showed U.S. refineries working at a strong 93.6 percent of capacity.</p>
<p>While gasoline and heating oil stocks fell slightly last week, stocks of crude oil grew 6.4 million barrels compared to the one to three million barrel rise expected by traders.</p>
<p>Imports rose sharply to 7.7 million barrels a day from 6.8 million due to an influx of West African crude oil.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this was a recognition of the bearish API numbers which indicated the market is well supplied. We have known this for some time, though,&quot; said Prudential Securities analyst Richard Redash in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;With gasoline falling with crude, we have removed from the market one bullish underpinning that the market has been relying on to take us higher,&quot; Redash said.</p>
<p>Precious metals prices also slipped as speculators sold, with gold for June delivery at the Commodity Exchange in New York closing down $2.60 an ounce at $352.10.</p>
<p>May silver ended down 13.5 cents at $4.87 an ounce.</p>
<p>Traders cited selling by commodity investment funds as the cause of the weakness and said precious metals were likely to steady after those professional investors eased up.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, though, the precious metals complex still looks to be consolidating the gains made earlier this year, helped perhaps by a weakening equities market,&quot; said Andre Dimino, New Jersey based fund manager with Apostle Capital Management.</p>
<p>Treasury bond yields were little changed Wednesday, but stock market values continued to slide following last week's monetary policy tightening by the U.S. Federal Reserve.</p>
<p>&quot;If (U.S. Federal Reserve Chairman Alan) Greenspan thinks inflation is rising, you would think gold prices would rise,&quot; said Hans Kashyap, president of Analytics Research Corp of Maryland. &quot;But gold is not much of an inflation hedge anymore, only perhaps a catastrophe hedge.&quot;</p>
<p>At the Coffee Sugar and Cocoa Exchange in New York, coffee futures closed lower despite a strike by stevedores on Wednesday at Santos port in Brazil, the top coffee exporter.</p>
<p>May delivery coffee closed at 193.15 cents a pound, down 1.15 cents.</p>
<p>The strike in Santos was scheduled to last 48 hours and could spread to national level on Friday if the dispute is not resolved, the stevedores' union said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The strike does not look to be a serious situation and I'm not sure how much it will impact coffee shipments,&quot; said Dean Witter analyst Steve Platt. &quot;Typically, these strikes do not last that long.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Board of Trade, soybean futures rose to new 8-1/2 year highs on fears that the strike by Brazilian stevedores would go national on Friday.</p>
<p>May soybeans closed up eight cents a bushel at $8.83-1/2, the highest closing price since September 1988.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be some strikes in Brazil,&quot; said Bob Lekberg, analyst with Goldenberg-Hehmeyer. &quot;Whether that impacts the port of Paranagua is uncertain but that was still a sustaining factor.&quot;</p>
<p>Paranagua handles the bulk of soybean exports from Brazil, which ranks second to the United States as a soy exporter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
