<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48200" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian rupiah returns to favour with investors.</title>
<headline>Indonesian rupiah returns to favour with investors.</headline>
<byline>Raju Gopalakrishnan</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The high-yielding Indonesian rupiah is once again returning to favour among emerging market currencies after the central bank's loosening of intervention controls, foreign exchange analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The rupiah, which surged sharply against the dollar on Wednesday after Bank Indonesia widened the intervention band to eight percent from five percent, ticked up slowly on Thursday and analysts saw more rises in coming months.</p>
<p>The rupiah jumped to 2,326 against the dollar on the central bank announcement on Wednesday from an opening of 2,349 before settling back at about 2,330. On Thursday, it was trading at about 2,325.50/6.00 in the late afternoon.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of people are establishing outright positions,&quot; said Edwin Png, country treasurer at Bank of America. &quot;A lot of hot money is coming in. Look at the problems in Thailand. Where else can you put your money?</p>
<p>&quot;I thing the rupiah is still very attractive to foreign investors.&quot;</p>
<p>The central bank's new band, which marks the perimeters outside of which it will intervene in the market, was set at 2,309/2,501 on Wednesday and analysts said they saw the rate creeping to the lower end of the band by the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now, the market has room to play,&quot; said Jimmy Koh of the I.D.E.A. economic consultancy. &quot;In the longer term, we see the rate heading back toward the lower end of the band. Perhaps by the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;Further measures to liberalise rupiah movement and introduce a managed float can be expected over the medium term to avoid the problem of the spot rate converging with the lower end of the intervention band,&quot; Koh added.</p>
<p>&quot;This merely reaffirms our preference for long rupiah positions, which now offer capital gains on top of a highly attractive (yield).&quot;</p>
<p>Bank Indonesia said it widened the intervention band to contain the overheating economy and control capital inflows.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an open question whether a wider band will be any more effective at slowing inflows (or curbing their effect) this time than in the past,&quot; said Peregrine Fixed Income in a commentary received by Reuters. &quot;Unless the band is continuously widened, it has only a temporary effect. Nor have past band widenings appeared to have struck much fear into the hearts of foreign investors.&quot;</p>
<p>The rupiah has been in a continuous uptrend since the beginning of the year except for slight hiccups in June on unfounded rumours that President Suharto had suffered a heart attack and again in July when riots broke out in Jakarta.</p>
<p>But sentiment on the currency has been restored after Suharto made a trip to Germany where doctors gave him a clean bill of health and the crackdown in the aftermath of the riots.</p>
<p>The strengthening, however, appears to have scuppered Bank Indonesia's stated target of depreciating the rupiah by five percent annually to help exports, analysts said.</p>
<p>Peregrine estimated that the rupiah would need to depreciate at an annual rate of 8.15 percent from now until April 1 to achieve a four percent depreciation over the 1996-97 (April-March) fiscal year.</p>
<p>Koh said Indonesian authorities needed to look to other measures to boost exports.</p>
<p>&quot;For the export side we believe the government will probably (need to) introduce more deregulation&quot;, he said. &quot;Export competitiveness needs more than just a weakened rupiah. They've got to deal with the structural problem.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
