<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="482022" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Conn. lawmaker seeks more money from NHL Whalers.</title>
<headline>Conn. lawmaker seeks more money from NHL Whalers.</headline>
<dateline>HARTFORD 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Connecticut House of Representatives Speaker Tom Ritter said Wednesday the state should demand a much higher exit fee from the Hartford Whalers than the $20.5 million arranged last week.</p>
<p>Peter Karmanos, who owns the National Hockey League (NHL) franchise, last week rejected Connecticut Governor John Rowland's proposal to build a $147 million arena and said the team would leave the state at the end of this season.</p>
<p>Rowland, a Republican, said last week the team agreed to pay $20.5 million as an exit fee, because under their contract with the state, they were to stay for at least one more season.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's go back to the table and tell them that we're going to put the hammer to their heads,&quot; Ritter said in an interview broadcast on local radio.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to force our rights under the contract to make them stay here next year, unless they make it so inviting by the payment they're going to give us...&quot;</p>
<p>Ritter, a Democrat, said the exit fee should be increased at least two-fold.</p>
<p>He also said the state should wait until the last possible moment to agree on an exit fee.</p>
<p>A group of Hartford business and political leaders are still trying to broker a last-ditch deal to keep the team -- Connecticut's only major league sports franchise -- in the capital city.</p>
<p>Hartford Mayor Mike Peters said Tuesday the city was considering a lawsuit to keep the team here for the final season of its Civic Center lease.</p>
<p>Hartford owns the Civic Center and leases it to the Connecticut Development Authority.</p>
<p>But analysts point out that a lawsuit would not endear the capital city to Rowland as budget season approaches. The state funds nearly half of Hartford's $414 million budget.</p>
<p>Karmanos has not said where the Whalers, who came to Hartford in 1975, will relocate. Among the cities seen as contenders are Minneapolis/St. Paul, Minn.; Columbus, Ohio; Nashville, and Oklahoma City.</p>
<p>--Hartford newsroom (860) 727-0224</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARTFORD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
