<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="482138" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Venture-backed IPOs slow down in '97 first quarter.</title>
<headline>Venture-backed IPOs slow down in '97 first quarter.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The number of venture-backed initial public offerings in the first quarter of 1997 was well below last year's first quarter, according to data released by research and consulting firm Venture Economics Information Services, a division of Securities Data Company Inc.</p>
<p>Thirty two companies that had venture capital firms listed as principal shareholders went public during the first three months of 1997, raising $960 million, compared with 61 companies raising $2.33 billion in the first quarter of 1996.  </p>
<p>The first quarter of 1997 did, however, boast the largest post-offering valuation of a venture-backed IPO ever. Ciena Corp, which went public in February, was valued at $2.14 billion upon completion of its public offering, according to Venture Economics.</p>
<p>The data also showed that the average offering size decreased to $30 million this year from $38.2 million in last year's first quarter. Venture-backed IPOs as a percentage of overall IPOs slipped to 23 percent, compared with 36 percent for the first quarter of 1996 and 31 percent for the year.  </p>
<p>In the face of current market volatility and the battering suffered by hi-tech stocks, venture capitalists' &quot;appetites have slackened a bit,&quot; Jesse Reyes, Director of Venture Economics Information Services, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Roughly two-thirds of all venture-backed IPOs tend to be in the hi-tech arena, said Reyes. This fraction was even higher in 1995 and 1996.</p>
<p>Reyes also said that the IPO boom in the last couple of years was characterized by companies, particularly hi-tech ones, rushing to market &quot;much sooner than they might have ordinarily done in a less robust market&quot;.  </p>
<p>That was no longer the case. The market had reached a saturation point and investors, as well as financial backers, were being far more selective, analysts have said.</p>
<p>&quot;Venture capitalists are still very interested in technology companies but I think they're looking for ...more experience based on the management team and a much more solid foundation for growth,&quot; said Robert Fish, partner in charge of Coopers &amp; Lybrand's venture capital and hi-tech practice in New York.</p>
<p>He said venture capital firms were taking a longer-term view on companies they backed, committing to a more traditional three to five year time horizon, as opposed to hurrying the deal to the marketplace and then beating a hasty retreat after cashing in the gains.</p>
<p>---K. Mehta, New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150203">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
