<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="482121" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr/Dow link overshadowed by Rubin, Japan trade.</title>
<headline>Dlr/Dow link overshadowed by Rubin, Japan trade.</headline>
<byline>Alden Bentley</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar's tie to the slumping U.S. stock market is flimsy, and weakness in the U.S. unit this week is more closely tied to trade jitters in advance of U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin's arrival in Japan on Friday, currency analysts said.</p>
<p>Wall Street's shakeout in the wake of the Federal Reserve's first interest rate increase in two years last week was a handy excuse for currency traders to exit dollars as the 1997 rally increasingly showed signs of faltering.  </p>
<p>But the connection between the dollar and U.S. stock prices is hard to confirm, especially in terms of actual capital flows, experts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Naturally, people link the two but I think it's pretty tenuous. I don't think people who play the currency market are putting their money into the equity market,&quot; said David Gilmore, partner at consulting firm Foreign Exchange Analytics.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd prefer to emphasize a tougher U.S. position on Japan, which, I think, is becoming more evident in recent weeks.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average plummeted nearly 300 points in the Thursday and Monday sessions straddling the U.S. Easter market holiday -- one of the most harrowing retreats since the crash of 1987.</p>
<p>Yet the greenback held relatively steady verus the yen on Monday, although its sharp drop against the mark seemed to occur in tandem with the gut wrenching drop in the Dow.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, after Secretary Rubin hinted at mounting concern over a widening U.S. trade gap with Japan, the dollar flopped more than two yen, even though the Dow recovered from early losses to close the day up 28 points.  </p>
<p>By Wednesday, the dollar had recovered some of its losses against the yen while the Dow skidded again.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see it that closely linked to the stock market on a continuing basis or necessarily going to keep going down in a sort of stock-and-dollar spiral,&quot; said Andrew Hodge, financial strategist at Bank Brussels Lambert.</p>
<p>The Treasury chief departs on Thursday for a six-day jaunt to Asia. He meets with Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto on Friday where he is expected to convey the administration's concern that Japan will try to cure its economic ills by boosting exports.  </p>
<p>Washington is particularly concerned about Tokyo's plan to sharply tighten budget policy, fearing that a rise in consumption taxes that took effect on Tuesday will sap demand at home and force Japanese firms to look for growth abroad.</p>
<p>Rubin persistently has articulated as policy his belief that a strong dollar is good for the U.S. economy.</p>
<p>But the dollar's strength against the yen seems now to be taking a toll on the U.S. trade balance.</p>
<p>The Treasury Secretary repeated his mantra to reporters after giving a speech in Washington on Wednesday, adding that the U.S. currency has been strong for some time now.  </p>
<p>The weak yen has evidently boosted Japanese exports as Japan's trade surplus widened on a year-over-year basis for the first time in two years last month.</p>
<p>&quot;That's the real problem Secretary Rubin has, that he wants to be tough with Japan to encourage renewed fiscal stimulus, yet at the same time he doesn't want the markets to think he has abandoned his strong-dollar policy,&quot; Gilmore of Foreign Exchange Analytics said. &quot;But you can't have your cake and eat it, too.&quot;  </p>
<p>The U.S. trade deficit ballooned 21 percent to $12.7 billion in January, its highest in almost a decade. The bilateral gap with Japan widened for the first time in recent months.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the U.S. current account deficit, the broadest measure of trade, hit another record of almost $47 billion in the third quarter, spotlighting the dollar's more important bond with the bond market.</p>
<p>If the Fed continues to raise interest rates, experts said the yawning current account gap could finally trigger alarm in the bond markets, which have been buoyed by huge purchases of T-bonds, as foreigners willingly have recycled dollars earned by exports to the U.S.</p>
<p>&quot;The interesting thing is foreigners have not been aggressive purhasers of stocks,&quot; said Earl Johnson, foreign exchange economist at Bank of Montreal.</p>
<p>&quot;It is much more important to see what the impact on the bond market is going to be and are private investors and central banks going to keep cycling dollars into Treasuries.&quot;</p>
<p>(( -- 212 859 1667 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
