<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="482275" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Scattered showers may hamper US Midwest fieldwork.</title>
<headline>Scattered showers may hamper US Midwest fieldwork.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scattered showers forecast for late this week and again the middle of next week may interrupt Midwest fieldwork, but meteorologists doubt wet conditions will seriously delay spring planting.</p>
<p>&quot;We really have never seen three consecutive very wet springs,&quot; said Craig Solberg, meteorologist with Freese-Notis Weather. &quot;It is very difficult for us to believe there will be significant planting delay problems in the Cornbelt this spring.&quot;  </p>
<p>Solberg said scattered showers the next few days may produce up to 0.5 inch of rain in Midwest areas west of the Mississippi River, while east of there should be dry.</p>
<p>Weather Services Corp meteorologist, Joel Burgio, expects scattered showers in the Midwest this week, plus possibly four to eight inches of snow in the Dakotas and Minnesota.</p>
<p>Next week, overnight lows in the teens Fahrenheit were likely in the Midwest along with scattered showers, he said.</p>
<p>Burgio also said he doubts there will be excessive rain this spring, but if this week's storms produce a large amount of rain, that could hint of wet conditions later this spring.  </p>
<p>&quot;I would say basically it will be normal to above normal rainfall this spring,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Burgio said an El Nino pattern is developing in the equatoral Pacific Ocean which could produce steady rain showers this month across the southern U.S.</p>
<p>Central Illinois fieldwork has been under way for at least two weeks, grain dealers there said. It involved applying anhydrous ammonia and herbicides and ground preparation.</p>
<p>Wet fields in southern Illinois interrupted fieldwork and fertilizer application, said Gary Prosis, manager of the Irvington (Ill.) Elevator.</p>
<p>In northern Iowa, widespread fieldwork may begin soon, once the ground warms.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in good shape. There is still frost in the ground,&quot; said Bob Sienknecht, a corn and soybean farmer in northwest Iowa. He said fieldwork should start late this week if it does not rain.</p>
<p>In the northeastern Corn Belt, there is little fieldwork being done because the soil is still too wet and cold.</p>
<p>However, several more days of dry and warm weather would enable farmers to get in their fields this weekend, one Ohio dealer speculated.</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
