<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="482260" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. must be able to fight two wars-Pentagon report.</title>
<headline>U.S. must be able to fight two wars-Pentagon report.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>A draft report prepared by senior Pentagon officials has determined that the U.S. military must remain ready to fight two regional wars virtually at once despite painful budget cuts after the Cold War, defence officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The officials stressed the preliminary draft was not ready for scheduled submission to Congress by mid-May and had not yet concluded how forces should be reshaped to address both conflict and increasing non-combat missions such as peacekeeping and humanitarian assistance.</p>
<p>One of the officials, who asked not to be identified, told Reuters that the final report would be written personally by Defence Secretary William Cohen and was expected to retain both the current two-conflict policy and the costly deployment of U.S. troops in Europe and Asia by the world's sole remaining superpower.</p>
<p>The Washington Post reported on Wednesday that the preliminary draft, part of a major quadrennial defence review (QDR) by the Pentagon, stressed that American forces must remain capable of fighting two regional wars &quot;in close succession.&quot;</p>
<p>Reflecting continued tension in such areas as the Middle East and the Korean Peninsula, the military supports a U.S. policy of being prepared to fight two major regional conflicts virtually at once even as demands have grown for costly operations such as Bosnia peacekeeping.</p>
<p>The draft report did not change that policy or the policy that has 100,000 U.S. troops in Europe and another 100,000 in Asia and the Pacific, one defence official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Another confirmed the Post report that the document predicted a &quot;period of strategic pause&quot; between now and 2010 during which no new superpower is likely to emerge to challenge the United States as the Soviet Union did over more than four decades.</p>
<p>&quot;One major conclusion so far is that, despite China's potential, no superpower is likely to challenge us for at least a decade. That will be a breather, but we'll still be in a major financial crunch,&quot; the official told Reuters.</p>
<p>U.S. military forces have been cut sharply to a total 1.4 million troops since the end of the Cold War with reduced defence budgets but remain on duty around the world.</p>
<p>Officials said that when the final version of the QDR is sent to Congress it will include more precise recommendations on whether and how the U.S. military might be further cut in order to save money for costly and needed modernisation of weapons.</p>
<p>The Defence Department anticipates budgets in the coming years averaging about $250 billion. Unless significant further savings are found in troop strength, base closings and acquisition, that money will not be adequate for such major projects as the military's new F-22 stealth fighter, the Joint Strike Fighter and other weaponry.</p>
<p>The QDR is being done against a background of loud objections by Republicans in Congress to recent defence cuts and calls by Republicans and Democrats to balance the U.S. budget after the turn of the century.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
