<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="482361" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Cocoa rallies fail to motivate German buyers.</title>
<headline>Cocoa rallies fail to motivate German buyers.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>German chocolate manufacturers shrugged off Tuesday's rally in cocoa futures to new 2-1/2 year highs in New York and further London highs earlier on Wednesday, cocoa traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The industry needs cover throughout 1997 but is not prepared to follow the futures market,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rallies are viewed as purely technical and perhaps come in sympathy with coffee's strong performance and with speculative money flowing into commodities.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said comfortable supply news should in theory be bearish for prices and origin selling from Latin America, Indonesia and West Africa should also weigh on prices.</p>
<p>Cocoa butter sellers were offering a ratio of 2.54 with the implied second quarter price at 7.30 marks/kg versus 6.92 marks early last week.</p>
<p>Second quarter cif Ivorian bean sellers were at 2.82 marks/kg versus 2.67 marks last week.</p>
<p>Sterling was at 2.7470 marks at the Frankfurt Exchange Fixing at midday.</p>
<p>Traders said the first quarter 1997 German cocoa grind should be well below the 69,520 tonnes in the same 1996 quarter, perhaps as low as 60,000 tonnes. The fourth quarter 1996 grind was 56,255 tonnes.</p>
<p>Confectionery industry association BDS plans to release the result on April 7 or 8.</p>
<p>-Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
