<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="482392" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek archaeology watchdog slams Virgin hotel plan.</title>
<headline>Greek archaeology watchdog slams Virgin hotel plan.</headline>
<byline>Dina Kyriakidou</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greece's top archaeology watchdog on Wednesday rejected plans by British entrepreneur Richard Branson's Virgin Group to build a hotel resort on the historic island of Hydra where no cars are allowed.</p>
<p>The powerful Central Archaeological Council (KAS) said in a decision issued on Wednesday the hotel complex would alter the character of the Hydra village of Kaminia.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the positioning and construction of buildings would cause immediate damage to the historic, preserved settlement by altering its perimeter and character,&quot; KAS said.</p>
<p>Although its role technically is only advisory, KAS decisions are never contradicted by the culture minister, who has the final say.</p>
<p>Branson's Virgin Hellas Hotel company envisioned a romantic complex of buildings, with winding paths, swimming pools and tennis courts on the island, which is a 90-minute hovercraft ride from the main Greek port of Piraeus.</p>
<p>Environmentalists and cultural preservation societies campained against the proposed 5,000 square-metre project, but islanders appeared before KAS to support the plan, saying it would create more than 100 permanent and 300 seasonal jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;The island's 2,600 remaining residents are distressed at the decision. They feel the state wants to turn the island into a deserted archaeological site,&quot; Hydra mayor Constantine Anastopoulos was quoted as saying by the semi-official Athens News Agency.</p>
<p>Kaminia, a small village west of Hydra's port town can only be reached by mule path. Hydra is popular with Greeks but has been spared a mass onslaught of back-packers because of its rocky beaches.</p>
<p>KAS did not totally shut the door in Branson's face, saying it would consider a new proposal for a much smaller hotel complex within the perimeter of the village, provided it did not include new roads, swimming pools, or sports facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;Within the limits of the Kamini settlement and especially in the southern section of his property, a study on facilities for similar use may possibly be seen positively,&quot; KAS said after a six-hour meeting to consider Branson's proposal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
