<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="482399" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU smooths ruffled feathers in US meat trade row.</title>
<headline>EU smooths ruffled feathers in US meat trade row.</headline>
<byline>Peter Blackburn</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union said on Wednesday it had no plans to escalate a trade war with the United States over meat imports, at least for the moment, but warned it could make few concessions.</p>
<p>The row blew up into a fully fledged trade fight on Tuesday after Washington warned it would cut off imports of European Union meat, and the EU effectively halted incoming shipments of U.S. poultry.</p>
<p>&quot;We are prepared to continue the negotiations. Contacts at senior official level will be taking place today,&quot; the European Commission's chief spokesman Nikolaus van der Pas said.</p>
<p>Asked specifically if the Commission was considering counter measures following the U.S. action, agriculture spokesman Gerard Kiely earlier told reporters &quot;No. We are still negotiating. The U.S. has not introduced the measures yet.&quot;</p>
<p>The Commission's chief negotiator, Lars Hoelgaard, is due to meet his U.S. counterpart Paul Drazek, senior trade adviser to USDA Secretary Dan Glickman, on Wednesday to see if progress can be made.</p>
<p>&quot;Room for manoeuvre is very limited indeed,&quot; Van der Pas said, briefing on a report by EU Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler to the rest of the Commission on difficulties in the talks on mutual recognition of veterinary standards.</p>
<p>The Commission, which negotiates for the EU, has to respect a tight mandate given by the 15 member states for the talks which cover three billion dollars a year in trade.</p>
<p>The U.S. measures, announced on Tuesday, would block an estimated $300 million of imports of EU meat, mainly Danish ham, but are only due to come into force on April 15.</p>
<p>But Kiely called the planned American action &quot;totally disproportionate&quot; as EU curbs on imports of U.S. chicken meat and dairy products would only affect an estimated $100 million dollars of exports annually.</p>
<p>The aim of the negotiations is to allow each side to accept meat, poultry, pet food and fish products from the other side even if their inspection methods differ.</p>
<p>The EU has strict rules at each stage of production whereas U.S. food safety standards apply to the final product.</p>
<p>The main dispute is over hygiene standards in U.S. poultry slaughter houses with the EU saying that decontamination of chicken carcasses, involving use of recycled chlorinated water, is totally unacceptable.</p>
<p>&quot;(Commissioner) Fischler cannot see how he can accept such a system and the Commission agrees with him,&quot; Van der Pas said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a question of protection of consumer health, not a trade question, nor is it a protectionist measure in disguise.&quot;</p>
<p>Following criticism during the mad cow crisis that the EU gave priority to protecting beef industry earnings instead of public health, Fischler is now determined to be seen to be doing everything possible to safeguard consumers.</p>
<p>Industry sources said that U.S. poultry producers were worried that EU curbs might trigger similar moves from Russian, east European, Chinese and middle Eastern importers.</p>
<p>U.S. poultry exports to Russia -- the main U.S. export market worth some $500 million annually -- were temporarily halted last spring due to Russian concern about the hygiene of the U.S. products. China, another huge market, also banned imports of some U.S. poultry products last December.</p>
<p>Although the U.S. has objections, other countries -- New Zealand, Canada and the Czech Republic -- have already concluded similar veterinary inspection agreements with the EU.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
