<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="482496" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India, Oman sign fertiliser, taxation pacts.</title>
<headline>India, Oman sign fertiliser, taxation pacts.</headline>
<byline>Hari Ramachandran</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>India and Oman on Wednesday signed seven agreements, including one forming a joint venture company for a $1.1 billion fertiliser complex in the Gulf state.</p>
<p>The agreements were signed after Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda and the visiting Sultan Qaboos Bin Said of Oman held talks on regional and international issues.</p>
<p>Qaboos, accompanied by 14 ministers, arrived on Tuesday on a four-day visit, his first to a South Asian country.</p>
<p>The other agreements signed on Wednesday related to the avoidance of double taxation, investment protection and cooperation in civil aviation, information, agriculture and fisheries.</p>
<p>The Fertiliser Ministry said the Oman-India Fertiliser Project (OIFP) would be among the biggest overseas ventures by Indian companies.</p>
<p>The joint venture agreement for setting up the Oman India Fertiliser Company was signed by Maqbool bin Ali bin Sultan, chairman of the Oman Oil Company, D.K. Verma, chairman of the state-run Rashtriya Chemicals and Fertilisers Limited (RCF), and S. Kabilan, managing director of Krishak Bharati Cooperative Limited (KRIBHCO).</p>
<p>The project envisages the setting up of a world class ammonia-urea complex with annual production capacity of 1.45 million tonnes of granulated urea and 330,000 tonnes of merchant ammonia at an estimated cost of $1.11 billion.</p>
<p>The project is expected to be financed through debt and equity in a ratio of three to one. Out of total equity of $277 million, RCF and KRIBHCO will contribute $69.25 million each, while Oman oil will contribute the remaining $138.50 million.</p>
<p>Oman would provide natural gas on a long-term basis and land for the project.</p>
<p>The entire quantity of urea will be purchased by India for 20 years under a buy-back arrangement at prices lower than international levels.</p>
<p>The agreement on the avoidance of double taxation provides for lower rates of taxation as compared with domestic rates on income such as dividends, interest, royalties and fees for technical services.</p>
<p>Qaboos was scheduled on Thursday to meet Indian Foreign Minister Inder Kumar Gujral and address the Federation of Indian Chambers of Commerce and Industry. He was due to return to Oman on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25130">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
