<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48263" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. signs bank contract for &quot;oil-for-food&quot; funds.</title>
<headline>U.N. signs bank contract for &quot;oil-for-food&quot; funds.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations and the Banque Nationale de Paris signed an agreement on Thursday under which the bank will handle funds resulting from a planned &quot;oil-for-food&quot; deal with Iraq, a U.N. spokesman said.</p>
<p>The bank will apply to the U.S. Treasury Department for an exemption to sanctions against Iraq in order to open an escrow account in the United States to handle the funds generated once the &quot;oil-for-food&quot; plan is actually implemented.</p>
<p>It is now on hold after Iraqi President Saddam Hussein sent troops into Kurdish-populated northern Iraq at the end of August to back one faction in an inter-Kurdish struggle.</p>
<p>This prompted Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali to announce on Sept. 1 that he was postponing the dispatch to Iraq of U.N. monitors to oversee the plan because of a lack of security. It will be up to him to decide when conditions permit it to go ahead.</p>
<p>Under Security Council resolution 986 of April 1995, the basis for the oil-for-food deal signed this May,  Iraq would be able to sell $2 billion worth of oil over six months, on a renewable basis, to buy food, medicine and other civilian necessities. The aim is to help mitigate the effect on ordinary Iraqis of economic sanctions imposed since Baghdad's 1990 invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>A U.N. spokesman said the contract with the Banque Nationale de Paris was signed by Under-Secretary-General Joseph Connor, a U.S. citizen who heads the U.N. department of administration and management, and by the bank's general manager in New York, Pierre Schneider.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
