<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48277" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU denies getting French bid to change CL bailout.</title>
<headline>EU denies getting French bid to change CL bailout.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission denied on Thursday a newspaper report that it had received a letter from the French government outlining plans to soften the terms of last year's state rescue of Credit Lyonnais.</p>
<p>A spokesman said that the Commission had received a letter from Finance Minister Jean Arthuis about the troubled state-controlled bank.</p>
<p>&quot;But nowhere in the letter does Mr Jean Arthuis make any reference to a new recovery plan for Credit Lyonnais,&quot; the EC spokesman said.</p>
<p>The Commission spokesman said that the letter from Arthuis was a response to a request for certain &quot;clarifications&quot; sought by European Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert in a letter to the French government on July 12.</p>
<p>La Tribune reported on Thursday that the letter from Arthuis outlined measures the French government planned to take to &quot;lift the financial burden that is strangling the state-owned bank&quot;.</p>
<p>The French finance ministry was unavailable for comment.</p>
<p>The bank lost 21 billion francs between 1992 and 1994 as the result of a reckless expansion binge before eking out a slim 13 million franc profit in 1995.</p>
<p>The bank, whose downfall was the biggest banking scandal in recent French history, has been in negotiations with the government to revise last year's bailout before Credit Lyonnais releases its half year results on September 26.</p>
<p>There have been a raft of reports suggesting the government intends to ease the rescue conditions to prevent the bank plunging back into the red.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
