<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48309" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wholesale prices rise 0.3 percent in August.</title>
<headline>Wholesale prices rise 0.3 percent in August.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kelley</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wholesale prices rose moderately in August, the government said Thursday, offering evidence that inflation remains under control for now despite strong economic growth.</p>
<p>The Labour Department said the Producer Price Index edged up 0.3 percent last month, after showing no change in July. The monthly increase was the biggest since March, when the index rose 0.5 percent.</p>
<p>After factoring out volatile food and energy costs, the closely watched &quot;core&quot; PPI fell 0.1 percent in August after rising 0.1 percent in July.</p>
<p>&quot;It confirms that inflation (at the producer level) is very well-contained,&quot; said Marilyn Schaja, money market economist at Donaldson, Lufkin &amp; Jenrette.</p>
<p>The report helped to comfort Wall Street, which had anxiously awaited the data amid fears that a stong economy could prompt the Federal Reserve to boost interest rates to contain inflation pressures.</p>
<p>Stock prices rallied on the report, with the Dow Jones industrial average jumping 24.42 points to 5,779.34 in afternoon trading, surpassing its record close of 5,778.00 set in May. It later eased somewhat to close at 5,771.94, up 17.02 points.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond 14/32 of a point, or $4.375 per $1,000 face value, pulling its yield down to 7.08 percent from 7.11 percent Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The inflation news continues to be positive,&quot; said Sung Won Sohn of Norwest Corp. in Minneapolis.</p>
<p>But Sohn and others expressed concern that rising labour costs in a tightening job market would begin to push up prices in coming months.</p>
<p>&quot;It's pretty clear that we are going to see wage pressures,&quot; Sohn said.</p>
<p>Labour costs have a far bigger impact on the Consumer Price Index, which is due out Friday, and economists will look to those figures for another reading on inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;That's really the hurdle that the market has to pass right now,&quot; Donaldson's Schaja said.</p>
<p>Despite the restrained inflation news, some economists predicted that the Federal Reserve would decide to move sooner rather than later to combat future price pressures.</p>
<p>Recent data suggest the economy has a considerable head of steam as it approaches the end of the third quarter. The government said last week the unemployment rate in August fell to a seven-year low of 5.1 percent from 5.4 percent in July, while wages climbed.</p>
<p>The Federal Reserve, in its regular &quot;Beige Book&quot; economic report, said Wednesday that the economy appears to be expanding moderately but without a clear sign of higher inflation.</p>
<p>The central bank's top policy-makers are scheduled to meet Sept. 24 to decide whether to raise interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the Fed will take the first step toward a tighter monetary policy,&quot; said Richard Berner, chief economist at Mellon Bank.</p>
<p>Added Norwest's Sohn, &quot;They can't wait until the last minute. I think they should begin to raise interest rates.&quot;</p>
<p>The August PPI exceeded Wall Street forecasts of a 0.1 percent increase in the overall PPI. Economists, however, had expected the core rate to rise by 0.1 percent. Since January, the PPI has risen at a 2.1 percent annual rate.</p>
<p>Thursday's report showed that food prices rose 1.0 percent in August, paced by gains in fruit and meat, while poultry, fish and vegetable prices fell. Economists had anticipated higher food costs, saying that steeper grain prices were filtering through to food prices.</p>
<p>Energy costs rose 0.7 percent in August after falling 0.9 percent in July. The increases were fuelled by gains in gasoline and heating oil.</p>
<p>Prices of intermediate goods -- those that require further processing, such as flour, synthetic fibers and leather -- rose 0.2 percent last month after falling 0.1 percent in July.</p>
<p>In a separate report issued Thursday, the Labour Department said that new applications for unemployment benefits rose by 21,000 last week. New filings jumped to 338,000 in the week ended Sept. 7 from 317,000 in the previous week, the Department said.</p>
<p>The 4-week moving average, which smoothes out the often-volatile weekly figures, was 327,750, up 4,250 from the prior week's 323,500. The average is considered a more accurate measure of jobless trends than the weekly data.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
