<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="483059" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Dairygold says '96 operating profits slips two pct.</title>
<headline>Dairygold says '96 operating profits slips two pct.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dairygold Co-Operative Society said on Wednesday that operating profits slipped to 17.7 million Irish pounds last year from 18.1 million in 1995.</p>
<p>Turnover was down 2.2 percent at 621.4 million but each division contributed positively, Ireland's largest farmers' co-operative said in a statement.</p>
<p>Dairy product sales totalled 320.8 million, down from 324.5 million a year earlier. The company said that milk prices paid to suppliers were maintained at high levels for all of 1996 despite the fact that international market returns decreased, particularly in the last three months of the year.</p>
<p>Turnover in the agri-trading division slipped by 1.8 percent to 138.8 million due to a 14 percent reduction in sales of animal feedstuff, a direct result of good grass growing conditions and the impact of BSE or madcow disease.</p>
<p>In the meat division, the BSE crisis impacted heavily on sales which fell to 161.8 million from 169.4 million.</p>
<p>But Dairygold, whose three meat plants process 10 percent of all Irish beef exports, said it remained committed to the beef industry.</p>
<p>&quot;We will play our part in the development of a Beef Quality Assurance Scheme and the re-establishment of Irish beef as a major force in the EU and third country markets,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Dairygold said net borrowings were reduced by 2.4 million Irish pounds to 36 million last year and gearing stands at 17.9 percent, allowing ample capacity for growth and development.</p>
<p>&quot;Dairygold remains in a very strong financial position and our balance sheet is on a very sound footing,&quot; chairman Denis Cronin said.</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom +353 1 676 9779</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
