<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48316" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian steel firm Cockerill falls into loss.</title>
<headline>Belgian steel firm Cockerill falls into loss.</headline>
<byline>Lorrayne Smith</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgium's biggest steel maker, Cockerill Sambre said on Thursday it fell into the red in first half 1996, and that the company was more likely to make a loss than a profit for the year as a whole.</p>
<p>&quot;Today I cannot say what the full-year results will be. We will probably make a loss but it would not be very heavy for a company of our size,&quot; Gandois told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;If by good fortune we make a profit, it would not be very great,&quot; Gandois added. Cockerill made a full-year 1995 group net profit of 3.2 billion Belgian francs ($102.7 million), up from 800 million in 1994.</p>
<p>The first-half 1996 group net loss amounted to 180 million francs, after a 3.1 billion profit in first half 1995.</p>
<p>Consolidated turnover rose to 103 billion francs from 95 billion in the year ago period. But excluding German unit Eko Stahl -  not consolidated in first-half 1995 figures - first half 1996 turnover was only 88 billion francs.</p>
<p>Liquid steel production was 3.2 million tonnes in the first six months, boosted by the growth of production at Eko Stahl.</p>
<p>Cockerill said the steel making industry had worsened in Western Europe during the first six months of 1996, particularly in its major markets - France, Germany and Benelux.</p>
<p>The situation was made more difficult by clients holding high stock levels, by rising imports and intensified competition among producers. Like others, Cockerill had to reduce steel prices considerably compared with 1995.</p>
<p>Also weighing on results were first-half losses at both its its engineering subsidiary Cockerill Mechanical Industries (CMI) and at German unit Ymos.</p>
<p>CMI made a net loss of 368 million francs, although orders placed during the first six months of 1996 showed strong growth. It aimed to return to breakeven in 1998 as the result of a relaunch plan.</p>
<p>Cockerill's group share of the losses at German car components unit Ymos AG was 502 million francs.</p>
<p>Despite weak European steel markets, the integrated steel, distribution and construction divisions - which form the group's core business with 87 percent of consolidated sales - were all profitable in terms of current results, the group noted.</p>
<p>Gandois said that in the second half operating profits for the distribution, building divisions and services divisions should show an improvement. However operating profits for integrated steel were likely to be worse than the first half.</p>
<p>The company said it expected both steel volumes and demand to increase in the second half of 1996, as a result of de-stocking among customers and at distribution centres.</p>
<p>&quot;Stocks are being exhausted and we are feeding real consumption,&quot; Gandois said.</p>
<p>&quot;The upward demand trend continues and 1997 should provide a more favourable economic environment for steelmaking.&quot;</p>
<p>Cockerill said orders for the fourth quarter had seen the end of a fall in prices for all products, and some prices were showing the first signs of rising.</p>
<p>It said less pressure from imports coming into the European Union should sustain the trend.</p>
<p>The average workforce, which was 28,635 in the first half of 1996, is expected to be reduced by about 2,000 over four years. ($1=31.15 Belgian Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
