<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48332" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Iraq says fires at U.S. planes, U.S. reinforces.</title>
<headline>Iraq says fires at U.S. planes, U.S. reinforces.</headline>
<byline>Barry May</byline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Thursday ordered bombers to deploy for possible air strikes against Iraq but an unbowed Baghdad replied by announcing it had fired three more missiles at Western air patrols.</p>
<p>Ignoring U.S. threats of a &quot;disproportionate&quot; response to any attacks, Iraqi President Saddam Hussein's forces said they had fired for a second straight day on the Western aircraft that have enforced a &quot;no-fly zone&quot; for Iraqi aircraft in the north and south of Iraq since the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>&quot;Iraq will continue defending its national air space,&quot; Iraqi Information Minister Abd-al-Ghani Abd-al-Ghafur said before the latest missile firings. &quot;Iraqis and the Iraqi armed forces will meet any aggression.&quot;</p>
<p>Washington said it had no information on the latest reported Iraqi attack, but in response to a confirmed attack on Wednesday the United States announced it was readying F-117A stealth bombers and B-52 long-range bombers for retaliation.</p>
<p>&quot;The determination of the United States in dealing with the problem of Iraq should not be underestimated,&quot; President Bill Clinton said.</p>
<p>The United States was assembling a stronger force than used last week to hit Iraq with 44 cruise missiles in retaliation for Baghdad's military involvement in northern Iraq, an area out-of-bounds to Iraqi forces for the last five years.</p>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry said in Washington the U.S. forces building in the Gulf would use &quot;robust&quot; action to protect American interests.</p>
<p>U.S. officials said eight U.S. F-117A &quot;stealth&quot; fighters -- accompanied by aerial refueling tankers -- were leaving New Mexico later in the day on a non-stop 20-hour flight that would land them in Kuwait on Friday.</p>
<p>The radar-evading jets carry laser-guided 2,000-pound (908 kg) bombs that can hit targets such as concrete air defence command-and-control centres with extreme accuracy.</p>
<p>Four U.S. B-52 bombers, like those used in last week's cruise missile attacks on Iraqi air defences, were flown to a British base on the Indian Ocean island of Diego Garcia.</p>
<p>News that the &quot;stealth&quot; jets would operate from Kuwait -- the only Arab country to endorse U.S. missile attacks on Iraq -- drew a warning from Iraqi Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz.</p>
<p>&quot;We consider this conduct on the part of the Kuwaiti regime a flagrant aggression against Iraq and an act of war against the state of Iraq,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The rising tension sent crude oil prices jumping to levels unseen since January 1991, the eve of the Gulf War when a U.S.-led coalition drove Saddam's forces from Kuwait. Prices later eased but brokers said they would be strong throughout the crisis.</p>
<p>An increasingly confident Iraq on Thursday rejected some of the restrictions it had endured since losing the Gulf War.</p>
<p>Saddam's forces are banned from Kurdish north Iraq and Iraqi aircraft are not allowed into &quot;no-fly zones&quot; over both the north and south of the country. U.S., British and French aircraft enforced the policies.</p>
<p>&quot;There are new facts in the north of Iraq. That area is no longer free for all,&quot; Iraqi presidential adviser Hamed Youssef Hummadi said in Ankara after the capture of the area this week by an Iraqi-backed Kurdish faction.</p>
<p>Hummadi urged Ankara to throw out the Western forces that had been using Turkish air bases to shield the Kurds: &quot;The Kurds are now protected by their legitimate government in Baghdad.&quot;</p>
<p>Baghdad has revelled in the disarray in the Western alliance enforcing the post-Gulf War policies. France would not endorse the U.S. attacks last week and called for consultation before Washington takes any further retaliation.</p>
<p>Although Sami Abderrahman, number two in the Iraqi-backed Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP), denied Saddam would extract a price for his support, Baghdad said northern Iraq was being quickly integrated back into the national economy.</p>
<p>Iraqi state-run media hailed the KDP victory as a prelude to the end of U.S. influence in northern Iraq. Saddam has signed decrees for Kurdish areas that had been under Western protection for the past five years.</p>
<p>People in Baghdad said people and goods were flowing to the north without restriction, but fear of U.S. attacks sent their currency plunging from 1,000 to 1,300 dinars to the dollar.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
