<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="483458" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: BOJ seen unlikely to tighten credit in near-term.</title>
<headline>BOJ seen unlikely to tighten credit in near-term.</headline>
<byline>Kanta Watanabe</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Japan's (BOJ) March &quot;tankan&quot; corporate survey released on Wednesday is unlikely to spur a near-term credit tightening, economists said.</p>
<p>Some economists see the risk of a change in monetary policy after the release of the June tankan, but others do not expect the BOJ to raise its official discount rate until next year.</p>
<p>The yield of the benchmark 10-year Japanese government bond (JGB) is expected to be stable between 2.1 and 2.5 percent in the April-June period, but may edge up in the second half of this calendar year, economists said.</p>
<p>The BOJ's March tankan showed an improvement in the closely watched diffusion index (DI) for major manufacturers to plus two, compared with minus three in November. Forecasts had ranged from minus two to plus two.</p>
<p>However, the DI for major non-manufacturers fell to minus six from zero in the previous survey. The DI represents the percentage of firms which see business conditions as favourable minus those which see conditions as unfavourable.</p>
<p>&quot;The March DI for non-manufacturers was a lot worse that expected. Also, the forecast for June DI shows a deterioration. So this tankan does not suggest the likelihood of a near-term change in monetary policy,&quot; said Mamoru Yamasaki, a senior economist at Paribas Capital Markets Ltd in Tokyo.</p>
<p>The June DI forecast was minus one for major manufacturers and minus seven for major non-manufacturers.</p>
<p>&quot;Among non-manufacturers, the construction sector was most severely hit due to the expected decrease in public works spending. The retail sector was also sluggish due to worries about the impact of the sales tax rise,&quot; said Tetsufumi Yamakawa, director of Japan economic research at Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>Japan's consumption tax was raised to five percent from three percent on April 1.</p>
<p>&quot;The decline in the June DI forecast suggests that corporate earnings will be on a declining trend. Under such a condition, a credit tightening is unlikely,&quot; Yamakawa said.</p>
<p>Economists were divided on the timing of a possible credit tightening.</p>
<p>&quot;Due to the consumption tax rise, a lot of people think Japan's economy will remain sluggish. Most market participants seem to be trying to believe that the BOJ will stay on hold. But I don't think this is right,&quot; said Takashi Ueno, senior manager at Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi.</p>
<p>&quot;There may be a possible monetary policy change by the BOJ by the July-September quarter this year,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>If the June tankan shows that the negative impact of the tax rise on the economy is less severe than expected, that could lead to a 50 basis point tightening during the July-September period, Ueno said.</p>
<p>But Goldman's Yamakawa said a credit tightening during 1997 looks unlikely at this stage, judging from the March tankan.</p>
<p>However, if the yen falls sharply, that could prompt the BOJ to alter its current policy of targeting the key unsecured overnight call rate at slightly below the 0.5 percent official discount rate during the July-September period, Yamakawa said.</p>
<p>Paribas's Yamasaki said it would take about six months to assess how the economy will recover from the negative impact of the consumption tax rise.</p>
<p>&quot;Any change in monetary policy is more likely to come after the release of the December tankan,&quot; Yamasaki said.</p>
<p>As for long-term interest rates, economists agreed that they are likely to remain stable at the current low levels in the April-June period, but could creep higher in the latter half of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The benchmark 182nd JGB yield is likely to move between 2.1 and 2.5 percent in the next three months. However, it could rise to near 3.0 percent by the end of this year,&quot; Paribas's Yamasaki said. The yield of the 182nd JGB fell to a record low of 2.150 percent on Wednesday afternoon.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-9780</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
