<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="483413" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs higher, off new highs, on late profit-taking.</title>
<headline>JGBs higher, off new highs, on late profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cash yen bonds and futures stayed above the previous day's finish in late Tokyo on Wednesday but slipped back from new highs on aggressive profit-taking.</p>
<p>Key June 10-year Japanese government bond (JGB) futures closed offer-only after being last traded at 126.62, up 0.67 from Tuesday's finish. The June's session low was 126.32.</p>
<p>Turnover was 48,761 contracts.</p>
<p>The June hit a new high for any benchmark contract at 126.92 in the afternoon, buoyed by a continued buying spree in long-term cash bonds after the release of the Bank of Japan's (BOJ) key &quot;tankan&quot; corporate survey in the morning.  </p>
<p>The survey revealed weak sentiment at non-manufacturing and smaller firms. The June diffusion index was also weak.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who had sold cash bonds on speculation of a strong tankan bought back quickly, while those who had failed to buy during the recent rallies also joined in a buying spree this afternoon,&quot; said a dealer at a trust bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>Before the tankan's release, rumours emerged that the June diffusion index might be plus one, a strong figure, prompting cash bond sales that lifted the key JGB yield to 2.285 percent.</p>
<p>The yield of the benchmark 182nd 10-year cash JGB later fell to 2.140 percent, a record low for any benchmark JGB.  </p>
<p>The yield stood at 2.175 percent at 0712 GMT, still sharply down from Tuesday's 2.255 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The tankan gave mixed signals on Japan's economy as business sentiment at big manufacturers' was good, while small businesses and non-manufacturers were not doing well,&quot; said a senior dealer at a city bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>&quot;But given the recent buoyant tone in JGBs, the neutral result was a buy signal for many investors,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The diffusion index for big manufacturers for June was minus one, while the June index for big non-manufacturers was minus seven, the BOJ said.  </p>
<p>The diffusion index for June was minus 13 for small manufacturers and minus 14 for small non-manufacturers, the BOJ said.</p>
<p>The March diffusion index for big manufacturers was plus two, up from minus three in the November survey, the BOJ said.</p>
<p>The market, buoyed by strong demand for JGBs from life insurers and other investors, ignored moderately optimistic remarks on the tankan survey by a senior BOJ official.</p>
<p>Masayuki Matsushima, director of the BOJ's Research and Statistics Department, said Japan's economy is continuing its gradual recovery, with private demand becoming firmer.  </p>
<p>Traders said the cash bond buying spree was later fuelled by a report that MOF's Trust Fund Bureau will shift its investment focus to holding JGBs for five years and longer.</p>
<p>A MOF official told Reuters that the bureau has now more freedom to invest than in the past. The bureau's plan to buy 2.4 trillion yen worth of long-term JGBs in fiscal 1997/98 was approved by the parliament last month, enabling the bureau to hold long-term JGBs for five years and longer.</p>
<p>&quot;MOF's regular buying is usually too small to have a strong impact. But many bought on the news as the market was bullish,&quot; said a dealer at a Big-Four brokerage. -- Risa Maeda</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
