<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="483559" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Morocco spends $61.3 mln on industrial zones.</title>
<headline>Morocco spends $61.3 mln on industrial zones.</headline>
<dateline>RABAT 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Morocco is spending $61.3 million to build infrastructure in two industrial zones to lure investors and expand local industry, Khalid Kadiri, head of state-run Caisse de Depot et Gestion (CDG) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>One zone is in the northern city of Tangier and the other in Bouznika on the Atlantic coast near Morocco's fianancial centre of Casablanca, Kadiri said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect Tangier and Bouznika areas to be among Morocco's leading industrial zones in future...The land will be sold at between 250 dirhams ($27.2) and 400 dirhams per square metre,&quot; Kadiri told a news conference held at CDG headquarters in Rabat.</p>
<p>Established in 1959, the CDG fund is mainly involved in banking and construction sectors, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The fund devoted 490 million dirhams to Tangier's Gzenaya indistrial zone and 74 million dirhams to Bouznika region,&quot; Kadiri said.</p>
<p>Bouznika area is now operational while Tangier zone will be ready for industrial projects in 1999, Kadiri said.</p>
<p>Future business and industry projects, including the Tangier area, &quot;should comply with international environment rules...because we want a clean indutrial areas,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tangier, which is the main financial and industrial zone of a region with five million people, is expected to attract more investors mainly from Spain and southern Europe, officials said.</p>
<p>The European Union plans to invest up to $1.0 billion per year in northern Morocco to upgrade local infrastructure and create new jobs to halt clandestine immigration to Europe.</p>
<p>Morocco, in the early 1960s, built an industrial zone near Tangier's port but its infrastructure failed to meet the increasing demand of industrial investments, official added.</p>
<p>($1= 9.2 dirhams)</p>
<p>- Rabat newsroom +212-7 72 65 18</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
