<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="483675" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: VW still tops Fiat in Cen. Europe.</title>
<headline>VW still tops Fiat in Cen. Europe.</headline>
<byline>Ryan Tutak</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Volkswagen AG hung onto a narrow lead in January over Fiat SPA in central Europe's booming market for new autos, according to a monthly Reuters survey.</p>
<p>VW outsold its Italian rival 14,797 units to 14,408 units in the Central European Free Trade Agreement (CEFTA) countries -- the Czech Republic, Hungary, Poland, Slovakia and Slovenia.</p>
<p>South Korean conglomerate Daewoo Group, the region's clear third power, moved within striking distance of the lead, selling 11,598 units in January.</p>
<p>&quot;It's difficult to forecast who will emerge on top in the long term, but it's clear that Daewoo is determined to have a big presence in the region,&quot; Philip Wade, a partner in British automotive consultancy Harbour Wade Brown, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Daewoo outperformed market growth to gain ground on its European competitors, who lagged behind the rate of increase in demand.</p>
<p>The Korean company boosted sales 25.5 percent, as the market expanded 19.7 percent to 66,679 units in January 1997 from 55,728 units in January 1996.</p>
<p>In comparison, sales rose only 15.1 percent for VW and 11.1 percent for Fiat.</p>
<p>The data, based on provisional information from various sources, include new cars, minibuses, off-road vehicles, pickups, vans and other four-wheeled motor vehicles up to five tonnes gross weight.</p>
<p>Overall, the market slowed from its all-time peak in 1996, when sales soared 39.5 percent to 842,577 units.</p>
<p>But CEFTA still looked dynamic compared to western Europe, where year-on-year sales fell 2.9 percent in January 1997, according to the European Automobile Manufacturers Association, known by its French acronym ACEA.</p>
<p>Daewoo, which plans to build over 500,000 vehicles a year in central Europe by 2000, has bolstered sales largely by buying state-owned automakers in the Czech Republic and Poland.</p>
<p>VW, second to Fiat in CEFTA from 1993 to 1995, took the lead in 1996, outselling its Italian rival 197,887 units to 192,318.</p>
<p>The German automotive group -- including the Audi, SEAT, Skoda and VW brands -- kept its lead in January because of its diverse manufacturing presence in the region, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;VW has an advantage over Fiat because of the diversity of its brands that appeal to these markets, but Daewoo will become a serious challenger to both automakers,&quot; Maxwell Pemberton, a British auto analyst, told Reuters.</p>
<p>VW has continued to centre its CEFTA strategy upon Czech brand Skoda, but it also plans to assemble models from each of its brands throughout central Europe.</p>
<p>The German automaker assembles SEATs and Skodas in Poland as well as VWs in Poland and Slovakia. By mid-1998, it plans to start assembling Audis in Hungary.</p>
<p>Fiat has focused more narrowly on CEFTA. It owns the region's biggest car factory in Poland but it builds no vehicles elsewhere in central Europe.</p>
<p>The Italian conglomerate markets twice as many brands in CEFTA as VW, including Alfa Romeo, Autobianchi, Ferrari, Fiat, Innocenti, Iveco, Lancia and Maserati. But many of the brands offer only high-priced specialty cars sold in low volumes.</p>
<p>As a result, Fiats accounted for 98.7 percent of the Italian group's sales in central Europe in January, while Skodas represented only 54.1 percent of VW's sales.</p>
<p>Daewoo, Fiat and VW were the only automakers with CEFTA sales topping 10,000 units in January. The closest challenger, French automotive group PSA Peugeot Citroen, sold 5,407 units.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
