<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48373" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British Aerospace first-half profits rise.</title>
<headline>British Aerospace first-half profits rise.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pre-tax profits at British Aerospace Plc, a manufacturer of commercial and military aircraft, jumped nearly 75 percent to 199 million pounds ($309 million) during the first six months of 1996, reflecting strong orders and better profitability.</p>
<p>&quot;We have got real growth, margins improving, a very strong order book and we are generating cash,&quot; said finance director Richard Lapthorne in an interview Thursday.</p>
<p>Underlying profits, before exceptional charges, rose 38 percent to 215 million pounds ($334 million) for the first half of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;The figures did come in above forecasts,&quot; said industry analyst Paul Pickford at Panmure Gordon, brokers in London. &quot;There was an upbeat statement and better cash position than expected,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lapthorne said the company was also pleased with the net cash position of 511 million pounds ($795 million) at the end of June. He said the company had feared a stronger draw on cash now it is building another batch of Tornado fighter bombers for Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, chief executive Sir Richard Evans said the group's strong performance was set to continue, thanks to increased productivity and a 13 billion pound ($20 billion) order book, including defence orders worth 9.2 billion pounds ($14 billion).</p>
<p>The defence business increased its first half profits to 255 million pounds ($397 million) from 240 million ($373 million) a year ago on sales of 2.2 billion pounds ($3.4 billion).</p>
<p>The company's commercial aerospace division turned in another loss in the first half, with continuing problems at its Jetstream turboprop aircraft business taking profits from making wings for the four-nation Airbus Industrie consortium.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
