<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="483751" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-FRENCH MANAGER WORRIED ABOUT FOREIGN LEGION.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-FRENCH MANAGER WORRIED ABOUT FOREIGN LEGION.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>French manager Aime Jacquet, concerned by France's lacklustre 1-0 win over Sweden in a soccer friendly on Wednesday, warned on Thursday the exodus of some of the country's most gifted players may be to blame.</p>
<p>Jacquet singled out three who play in Italy, hinting that their careers in Europe's strongest domestic league had harmed France's preparations for next year's World Cup.</p>
<p>The manager said the absence of Didier Deschamps of Juventus, who also missed France's previous match against the Netherlands, had seriously hurt the French.</p>
<p>&quot;In the European championship semifinal, Deschamps was not there and we were ousted. Didier is a guy who has a real power over the rest of the team,&quot; Jacquet said.</p>
<p>&quot;He is capable of putting the team back in place. Patrick Vieira and Claude Makelele played a decent match against Sweden but with Deschamps, they would not have been the same,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Deschamps missed the Netherlands match last month with a knee injury and the Sweden game with dental problems.</p>
<p>Jacquet even said he may be forced to change the team dramatically were Deschamps to miss next June's Tournoi de France with England, Italy and Brazil.</p>
<p>Jacquet also admitted he had not found the right way to pair Zinedine Zidane of Juventus and Youri Djorkaeff of Internazionale.</p>
<p>&quot;To do without one or the other would be a waste. There must be a solution,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The French manager added he was worried about striker Christophe Dugarry, who has not played often since he left Bordeaux for AC Milan at the end of last season.</p>
<p>&quot;I keep him alive because of his qualities. It's only a matter of playing. I have faith in him but I hope he'll find a club in which he plays regularly. Otherwise...&quot;</p>
<p>Otherwise Jacquet made it clear that players who are not first choice players in their clubs would not be called up by France for the World Cup.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
