<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="483868" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: WORKERS TO MARCH, RENAULT STANDS BY BELGIAN CLOSURE.</title>
<headline>WORKERS TO MARCH, RENAULT STANDS BY BELGIAN CLOSURE.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of employees of French carmaker Renault will march through Brussels on Friday as part of a day of coordinated protests against the loss-making firm's restructuring plans, union leaders said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Organisers said they believed up to 5,000 workers from Belgium, France and Spain would take part in the march which is mainly targeted against Renault's plans to close its profitable plant at Vilvoorde near Brussels with the loss of 3,100 jobs.</p>
<p>However, Renault -- which lost 5.2 billion French francs ($923.4 million) in 1996 -- has also announced plans to cut nearly 3,000 jobs in France.</p>
<p>Belgian Renault workers got a morale boost on Thursday when the Belgian Labour Court backed a union complaint and said the firm broke the rules on worker consultation with the unexpected announcement on February 27 that Vilvoorde would close in July.</p>
<p>The court, which called on both sides to try to find a way to avoid or reduce the collective sackings, can fine Renault if it fails to hold full worker consultations.</p>
<p>But Renault, whose shares fell briefly on news of the ruling, said in Paris the fact that it failed to follow procedure would not alter its decision to close Vilvoorde.</p>
<p>Friday's march, due to start near Brussels North Station and end about three hours later next to the European Commission's headquarters, will be followed by press conferences in Brussels, Paris and Madrid.</p>
<p>Renault unions have also called for stoppages on Friday at all the company's European plants.</p>
<p>On Thursday the Vilvoorde unions met Renault management and a mediator to table their plans to keep the plant open at least until 2002.</p>
<p>The meeting followed what was termed &quot;a dialogue of the deaf&quot; between the unions and management on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Renault has said it is looking for alternative uses for the site.</p>
<p>The closure announcement sparked a backlash against the firm in Belgium.</p>
<p>Several regional authorities and government ministries have cancelled purchase orders for Renault vehicles. On Wednesday FEBIAC, the Belgian automobile manufacturers federation, said Renault sales in March fell 43 percent to 2,861 units compared to 4,983 in the same month last year.</p>
<p>At the same time overall car sales in Belgium dropped 13.3 percent to 39,329 units from 45,352 in March 1995, FEBIAC said.</p>
<p>Vilvoorde workers have been occupying the factory since the closure announcement, and have joined in protest actions with their colleagues from Renault plants in France and Spain.</p>
<p>Renault workers in Belgium have the backing of their colleagues at bankrupt steelmaker Forges de Clabecq who are also fighting to keep their jobs.</p>
<p>Some steelworkers are likely to take part in Friday's march, with Renault workers also expected to support their Clabecq colleagues at another march in the central city of Namur on Saturday.</p>
<p>Steel unions have said they expect tens of thousands of people at Saturday's march.</p>
<p>On Friday last week 25 people -- 17 gendarmes and eight steelworkers -- were injured when police prevented Clabecq workers blocking the Brussels to Paris motorway.</p>
<p>The steelworkers, brandishing iron bars and driving two bulldozers wrecked several gendarmerie vehicles including two water cannon. ($ = 5.631 French Francs)</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
