<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484010" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Power firm lifts Nairobi bourse index.</title>
<headline>Power firm lifts Nairobi bourse index.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A deal for power monopoly Kenya Power &amp; Lighting helped to lift the Nairobi Stock Exchange 20-share index marginally on Thursday.</p>
<p>The index gained 16.43 points to close at 3327.35 points.</p>
<p>Turnover was 22.860 million shillings on 438,270 shares compared to 28.034 million shillings on 568,161 shares on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices today recovered marginally from last week's dips,&quot; a bourse official said.</p>
<p>A total of 57,200 Kenya Power shares were dealt at a reserve price of 120.00 from 117.00 on the one-hour special board.</p>
<p>Brokers said a lot of the optimism surrounding the share was centred on the intended separation of the power generation and supply functions of the firm.</p>
<p>&quot;It is bound to reduce operating costs,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Foreign interest in Kakuzi, Kenya Commercial Bank and Sasini Tea &amp; Coffee remained -- holding prices stable.</p>
<p>Kakuzi closed at 101.00 unchanged, while Sasini Tea &amp; Coffee eased to 76.00 from 77.00. Kenya Commercial Bank closed at 95.00 from 96.00.</p>
<p>Standard Chartered Bank eased to 46.00 from 46.25 while Uchumi Supermarket edged to 37.00 from 36.50.</p>
<p>Rea Vipingo Plantations was unchanged at 9.00 while Total Kenya shed a shilling to close at 62.50.</p>
<p>Barclays Bank was unchanged at 100.00 while National Bank of Kenya closed at 15.60 from 15.55.</p>
<p>--Wambui Chege, Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
