<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484016" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FORECAST - Engen H1 shr up, but recovery slow.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Engen H1 shr up, but recovery slow.</headline>
<byline>Nicole Mordant</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Last year's strong recovery in annual earnings at South African oil and fuels firm, Engen Ltd, is seen slowing at the halfway stage hobbled by weak global refining margins and operational problems.</p>
<p>Analysts said on Thursday that although interim earnings would be higher than last year, they were rising off a very low base after a major earnings slide in 1995, which has weighed heavily on Engen ever since.</p>
<p>&quot;The earnings will be up, but last year's interims were pretty close to the bottom of the barrel,&quot; said an analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>A Reuters poll of chemicals and oils analysts forecast earnings for the half year to February 28 rising to between 90 cents and 108 cents with consensus at 103.2 cents -- 17 percent above last year's interim 88 cents.</p>
<p>This compares with a 199 percent improvement in earnings per share to 218 cents for the year ended August 31, 1996.</p>
<p>The first half dividend was seen rising to within a range of 36 and 50 cents with consensus at 44 cents. The dividend at the halfway stage in 1996 was 36 cents.</p>
<p>Engen is due to release results on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Refining margins have been relatively weak in dollar terms during the period, although in rand terms they were stronger. That's really the main driving force for the first half,&quot; said Themis Themistocleous, an analyst at SBC Warburg.</p>
<p>But another analyst said continued troubles at Engen's crude oil refinery in the port town of Durban, which pummelled earnings two years ago, would continue to hamper a return to profit levels seen pre-1995.</p>
<p>&quot;They are running a lot of crude through the refinery but they are not getting the white oil yields that they need...It is really a technical refinery management issue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said it was a &quot;disappointment&quot; that operational efficiencies had not improved following the purchase by Malaysian state-owned oil firm, Petronas, of a 30 percent stake in Engen last June.</p>
<p>In earnings per share terms, the Petronas deal was also not yet seen benefitting Engen's bottomline.</p>
<p>&quot;It will bring their interest expense down quite considerably but at the same time there are a lot more shares in issue so there would be a dilution effect as well,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Another factor bringing pressure to bear on Engen, along with all South African oil companies, was government's delay in raising the wholesale fuel margin, which has not been increased for over three and a half years.</p>
<p>&quot;Costs have gone up, but their wholesale margin is remaining static,&quot; said Mark Ingham, an analyst at Societe Generale Frankel Pollak.</p>
<p>The industry has long been lobbying for at least a three cents a litre increase, but government action has been stalled for a number of reasons including the appointment of a new mineral and energy affairs minister.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
