<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484050" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Private farmers rare birds in Russian countryside.</title>
<headline>Private farmers rare birds in Russian countryside.</headline>
<byline>Adam Tanner</byline>
<dateline>ZHURAVSKY, Russia</dateline>
<text>
<p>Both the burly private farmer and the unabashed pro-communist governor say recent trips to the United States revealed underlying truths about successful farming, but they drew opposite conclusions from what they saw.</p>
<p>Alexei Storozhenko, a pioneering private farmer in southern Russia's Kuban region adjacent to the Black Sea, says a visit to Texas convinced him that technology can make an individual farmer competitive on the world food market.</p>
<p>&quot;In America, they work five times less than we do because of all the technology,&quot; said Storozhenko, who left a collective farm in 1991 to set up his own farm. &quot;If Americans worked as hard as we do, they'd be a million years ahead!&quot;</p>
<p>Governor Nikolai Kondratenko, who opposes a rapid growth in private farming, says his America trip showed him that collective farms forcibly set up in the 1930s are the best way to manage agriculture.</p>
<p>&quot;I was in Nebraska and asked to meet a private farmer, but they couldn't find one. They brought me to two brothers who raise bulls, 4,000 of them, and 23 people work with them,&quot; he said. &quot;I said 'that's no private farm, that's a kolkhoz!'&quot;</p>
<p>Agricultural experts say faith in collective farms, combined with problems such as the difficulty in getting loans, help explain why the number of private farmers nationwide fell to 279,000 by January 1997, down 1,000 from the year before.</p>
<p>Private farmers, who many foreign experts see as the long-term solution to Russia's farm problems, make up only about three percent of all agriculture workers.</p>
<p>PRIVATE FARMER ALEXEI, CHAPTER THREE</p>
<p>To chart the progress of private farming since the collapse of the Soviet Union in 1991, Reuters has visited Storozhenko, 47, every two years since he established his Zhuravsky farm.</p>
<p>In 1993, he was bitter and frustrated by the difficulties he had endured to leave the kolkhoz. By mid 1995, he was beginning to enjoy the fruits of his labours and saw a $16,000 profit for the year before that, including his son's earnings.</p>
<p>Today, as before, Storozhenko, whose weathered, thick fingers and soil lodged in his fingernails suggest a lifetime in the fields, works with five partners from his old collective farm, one of whom is his son.</p>
<p>The group still takes turns spending the night in their warehouse, weapons nearby, to deter thieves envious of their aging Soviet-era tractors and machines, kept running by a winter of creative repairs.</p>
<p>They have leased some additional land of late, giving them more than 500 hectres (1,250 acres), but grumble that their land is in two different areas 60 km (38 miles) apart, and that they must pay the government no less than 17 different taxes.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an economically difficult time now,&quot; Storozhenko said. &quot;Prices for foodstuffs has stabilised, but our costs in fertiliser, fuel, parts and other materials have gone up.&quot;</p>
<p>As across the region, Storozhenko's output in wheat has fallen steadily over the past two years, and his corn crop failed completely last year. Excluding his son's earnings, he says he made a profit of about $13,600 last year and $5,000 in 1995.</p>
<p>But he has bought a used BMW car, a new Japanese television set, and a few other perks. His decade-old tractors and sunflower oil processor are the envy of would-be private farmers who cannot get loans to break free of their collective farms.</p>
<p>Storozhenko now hopes to leave a legacy to his grandchildren to continue farming, and points to a 50-year lease on some new land he recently signed.</p>
<p>DUELING VISIONS OF THE FARM'S FUTURE</p>
<p>Ivan Petrenko, the Krasnodar region's deputy governor overseeing agriculture, says about a third of Russia's private farmers are profitable and successful like Storozhenko. But most got their start in 1991-92, when cheap credits were available.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who set up farms then work well, have technology, produce crops and pay taxes,&quot; he said. &quot;But more than half of all private farmers, especially those set up after 1992, are in a difficult situation.&quot;</p>
<p>The AKKOR association of private farmers blames the regional government for blocking their progress with red tape, and says collective farm officials prevent others starting their own farms. They say inefficiency and ineptitude of collective farms threaten all Russian agriculture unless private farms develop.</p>
<p>Kondratenko said he saw a role for private farmers, but mostly in specialised roles such as growing flowers and fruit, with collective farms providing the backbone of food production.</p>
<p>He also says mass effort to break up collective farms would be a tragedy on par with Stalin's collectivisation that led to widespread famine and the deaths of millions.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't have enough fingers to count how many of my relatives died during collectivisation in the 1930s,&quot; he said. &quot;But we're about to commit a second crime: the first was forced collectivisation, the second is the destruction of agricultural technology...unified in the collective farm.&quot;</p>
<p>Storozhenko, however, hopes the government will just step back and let private farming develop without interference.</p>
<p>&quot;In principal, we don't need any help from the government,&quot; he said. &quot;We just need them to supply social stability, and the market will do the rest.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;That way, among our grandchildren, at least some will remain on the farm.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZHURAVSKY, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
