<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484198" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONDURAS: Honduras cites pilot error in U.S. military crash.</title>
<headline>Honduras cites pilot error in U.S. military crash.</headline>
<dateline>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A deadly crash of a U.S. military cargo plane in Honduras this week may have been caused by pilot error, Honduran officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Transport and Communications Minister Luis Zelaya met with members of the congressional transport commission and told them the pilots apparently overshot the runway in Tuesday's accident, legislators said.</p>
<p>&quot;The minister told us it was human error. The pilots landed the plane more than halfway down the runway,&quot; Jack Arevalo, a member of the commission, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The C-130 Hercules crashed upon landing and slid off the end of the Tegucigalpa airport runway onto a nearby avenue, bursting into flames. Three U.S. soldiers died in the crash and seven others were injured, two of them critically.</p>
<p>The crash renewed debate in Honduras about the safety of Toncontin airport, which has a short runway and is considered the most dangerous in Central America.</p>
<p>Despite claims of pilot error by Honduran officials, U.S. officials maintained Thursday that it was too early to tell what caused the crash and said an investigation had just begun. &quot;It is far too early to tell what caused the crash. The investigation is going to be a long and slow process,&quot; Marti Estell, a U.S. Embassy spokesperson in Honduras, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Estell said a second team of military investigators had arrived in Tegucigalpa to help in the probe. The first team, which arrived on  Tuesday, used work crews on  Thursday to take pieces of the wreckage away from the airport for analysis, Estell said.</p>
<p>Two of the injured soldiers had been flown to a military hospital in San Antonio, Texas, on Tuesday while the five other injured men and the three bodies were returned to U.S. soil on Thursday, Estell said.</p>
<p>The plane was making a stopover on its way to Palmerola military base in central Honduras from Howard Air Force base in Panama to deliver supplies to U.S. soldiers in Honduras.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONDURAS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
