<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484204" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru fails to find breathrough in crisis talks.</title>
<headline>Peru fails to find breathrough in crisis talks.</headline>
<byline>Paul Hughes</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediators in Peru's hostage crisis spent another apparently fruitless day talking to Marxist rebels holding 72 hostages in Lima on Wednesday as a police chief celebrated his 55th birthday in captivity.</p>
<p>Canadian Ambassador Anthony Vincent and Vatican representative Juan Luis Cipriani met for several hours inside the Japanese ambassador's home in the leafy San Isidro district trying to persuade the guerrillas to end their 106-day stand.</p>
<p>But the two men made no comments to reporters when they emerged and gave no indication that formal negotiations with the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels would resume any time soon.</p>
<p>President Alberto Fujimori, who has steadfastly refused to meet MRTA demands that about 400 jailed comrades be freed, announced Wednesday he would travel to Bolivia to discuss the crisis with Bolivian President Gonzalo Sanchez de Lozada.</p>
<p>Bolivian ambassador Jorge Gumucio is being held by the MRTA to pressure for the release of four members held in Bolivia.</p>
<p>After a telephone call with Fujimori Monday, Sanchez de Lozada said the Peruvian leader did not believe there would be a rapid solution to the standoff due to &quot;new disagreements&quot; with the MRTA.</p>
<p>Fujimori told reporters in the southern city of Arequipa he would meet Sanchez de Lozada in Bolivia's third city Cochabamba Saturday.</p>
<p>As Peru looked for new ways to break the deadlock, Congress President Victor Joy Way said he will go to Tokyo early next week to meet Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto.</p>
<p>Talks will focus on the government's negotiation strategy, about which &quot;there is full agreement not only at a national but at an international level,&quot; Joy Way told reporters.</p>
<p>Japan's ambassador Morihisa Aoki was hosting a reception when Marxist guerrillas stormed the house on Dec. 17, taking 500 VIPs captive. Most were soon freed. The remaining hostages include Fujimori's brother Pedro, two Peruvian cabinet ministers and two dozen Japanese diplomats and businessmen.</p>
<p>Cuban Foreign Minister Roberto Robaina, whose country has offered asylum to the 20-odd hostage-takers to help end the standoff, is also expected to visit Japan in the coming days.</p>
<p>Japan's news agency Jiji Press quoted a government source in Tokyo as saying Robaina is expected to exchange views on the hostage crisis with his counterpart Yukihiko Ikeda and other Japanese government officials on April 17.</p>
<p>The agency said Tokyo was studying economic cooperation and aid for Cuba in return for accepting the MRTA rebels.</p>
<p>With a general sense of gloom surrounding the 15-week-long crisis, one of the hostages, national police Col. Francisco Salinas, was cheered by birthday greetings from outside the residence Wednesday evening.</p>
<p>&quot;Happy birthday dad,&quot; one young girl shouted through a megaphone after family and friends sang happy birthday accompanied by a guitar. A man, presumed to be Salinas, appeared in silhouette at an upper window and applause could be heard from inside the residence after the singing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
