<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484369" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: GS Capital Corporation rated &quot;A&quot; by TRIS.</title>
<headline>GS Capital Corporation rated &quot;A&quot; by TRIS.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai Rating and Information Services (TRIS) gave an &quot;A&quot; rating on Friday to GS Capital Corporation Plc (GSCC).</p>
<p>TRIS said the rating reflected the 80 percent ownership of its parent, General Electric Capital Asia Investment (GECI) which has strong implicit support from GE Capital Corp (GECC), a $160.8 billion asset-diversified US-based finance company with solid credit risk.</p>
<p>GSCC was formed in 1993 to engage in auto hire purchase, auto related financing and commercial leasing.</p>
<p>In late 1996, GECC increased its ownership in GSCC to 80 percent through buying out shares of its other two partners, including the General Finance and Securities which currently holds the remaining 20 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Through GECC's manangement control, GSCC should benefit from stronger operational and financial supports,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>However, TRIS noted that GSCC is vulnerable to interest-sensitive auto hire purchase earning and asset quality development.</p>
<p>&quot;Given GSCC's relatively young profile and the highly competitive auto hire purchase and leasing market, it remains to be seen to what extent the company can solidify its market position and operating performance,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The company's rapid loan growth, intense competition within the auto hire purchase business and less favourable local economy resulted in higher overdue loans, TRIS said, adding that GSCC's non-accrual loans increased to represent 3.1 percent of total loans.</p>
<p>&quot;(But) GSCC's cautious control system and adequate provisions should mitigate significant loss risk,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>GSCC's net income in 1996 rose sharply to 86 million baht due to larger interest rate spreads allowed by lower funding cost and the implementation of its policy to substantially hedge interest rate risk.</p>
<p>But the earnings remain under some pressure of adequate spread sustainability and market competition, TRIS said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
