<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484351" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAPUA NEW GUINEA: PNG mercenaries planned copper mine venture-letter.</title>
<headline>PNG mercenaries planned copper mine venture-letter.</headline>
<dateline>PORT MORESBY 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mercenaries hired by Papua New Guinea to end a rebellion proposed a venture with the government and an Australian miner to run the Panguna copper mine at the centre of the dispute, an inquiry panel heard on Thursday.</p>
<p>British-based Sandline International, which arranged to bring in the mercenaries, had proposed the deal to the Papua defence minister in a letter dated August 1, 1996, the panel heard.</p>
<p>The letter carried the company name Plaza 107 Ltd, the London address of Sandline and the holding company used by Sandline before it changed its name in late 1996.</p>
<p>The letter, signed by Sandline chief executive Tim Spicer, suggested a &quot;joint venture with your government, ourselves and RTZ-CRA to reopen and operate the Bougainville mine once recovered&quot;, said Ian Molloy, counsel assisting the inquiry.</p>
<p>But retired British colonel Tim Spicer, who led the aborted US$37 million mercenary mission, told the panel the proposal had eventually been rejected by both the government and Sandline.</p>
<p>Australian mining giant RTZ-CRA was forced in May 1989 to close the Panguna copper mine in central Bougainville, an island 800 km (500 miles) northeast of Port Moresby, after rebels staged a series of sabotage attacks.</p>
<p>At the time Panguna, operated by RTZ-CRA's 53.6 percent owned Bougainville Copper Ltd, generated a third of Papua New Guinea's foreign exchange.</p>
<p>Under Sandline's contract with PNG the mercenaries were to engage in offensive operations alongside troops on Bougainville and retake the mine.</p>
<p>Executive Outcomes, a Pretoria-based group which hires out former South African Defence Force soldiers to foreign governments, supplied Sandline with the mercenaries.</p>
<p>It is Africa's best known private army and is widely believed to have been partly paid for its adventures in Africa through mining concessions.</p>
<p>Papua New Guinea's plan to use 70 African mercenaries to end the nine-year Bougainville secessionist conflict fell apart last month when the army revolted, throwing out the mercenaries and forcing Prime Minister Sir Julius Chan to step aside.</p>
<p>Opposition to the foreign soldiers and claims by army officers that the deal was corrupt sparked two days of protests and looting in Port Moresby, culminating in the country's parliament being blockaded by troops and protesters.</p>
<p>Chan, Deputy Prime Minister Chris Haiveta and Defence Minister Mathias Ijape stepped aside last week pending an inquiry into the mercenary deal, ending the South Pacific's worst political crisis since independence in 1975.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT MORESBY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAPUA NEW GUINEA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
