<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484338" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: HKSBC seeks more NZ retail customers.</title>
<headline>HKSBC seeks more NZ retail customers.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand division of the Hongkong and Shanghai Banking Corporation plans to expand in Auckland this year, after nearly doubling after-tax profits to NZ$8.14 million in 1996.</p>
<p>The tax-paid result compares with earnings of $4.29 million in 1995. The rise in earnings coincided with the bank's New Zealand asset base expanding 17 percent to $4.16 billion.</p>
<p>Its residential mortgage portfolio nearly doubled, to $447.5 million while corporate lending rose 15 percent to $2.39 billion.  </p>
<p>The total amount of money Hongkong Bank lent to customers and other banks in New Zealand rose 24 percent to $2.96 billion.</p>
<p>John Blanthorne, chief executive of the New Zealand branch, noted Hongkong Bank is perceived in this country as a bank only for wealthy individuals. But the bank wants to dispel that image and expand its customer base.</p>
<p>&quot;We will still be a niche player but certainly we want to attract more retail customers,&quot; Blanthorne said.  </p>
<p>The bank has been operating in New Zealand for 12 years, and has a strong presence in the corporate finance area. But currently it only has about 4000 retail customers, with around 2000 residential mortgage holders.</p>
<p>Blanthorne told Reuters the bank was gleaning business from a wider cross-section of the retail banking market than it had originally targeted.</p>
<p>&quot;We still, though, have a minimum loan of $125,000, which obviously in itself shows which end of the market we're trying to concentrate on,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The bank has only two retail branch offices in the country, in central Auckland and at Howick. It will open an office in Takapuna in June, but Blanthorne said the bank had no expansion plans beyond that.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not see the future of our business really being in bricks and mortar. We're never going to be able to compete with some of the branch networks here. We did want to have a North Shore branch just to complement and Eastern Suburbs and central city branch, but that's really about it,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;If it turned out there was a concentration of our customers in a particular area who needed a particular service, we would consider opening a small branch to look after them, but it's just not part of our strategy.</p>
<p>&quot;Our strategy in the future would be very much more technology driven, and delivery of services through the phone, through PCs, the internet and so on.&quot;</p>
<p>Blanthorne said the bank will look at launching new products. It does not have a credit card here, and it may also consider moving into the insurance area.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
