<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484333" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia defense spending 'inefficient'- comptroller.</title>
<headline>Colombia defense spending 'inefficient'- comptroller.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's defence spending is inefficient and has failed to stop the country's leftist guerrillas from gaining fresh ground, the government's public spending watchdog said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>There have been sharp increases in the defence budget in last decade, the Comptroller General's office said, but the money has been inappropriately allocated. It said there have been large increases in manpower and not enough spent on essential equipment.</p>
<p>&quot;Against the backdrop of the domestic fiscal crisis and decreasing international military budgets, spending on Colombia's armed forces is inefficient and unproductive,&quot; the office said in a highly critical report.</p>
<p>Levels of common crime and political violence have boomed to the point where the state has a lost a grip on law and order, the report said.</p>
<p>The Comptroller General's office said that in the last 10 years the military budget grew an average 12 percent per year.</p>
<p>This year the armed forces will receive about 800 billion pesos (about $800 million), although half that will be made up of proceeds from the mandatory purchase of war bonds by wealthy Colombians.</p>
<p>The spending rise served to swell the ranks of the armed forces to the point where more than 85 percent of the budget was being spent on personnel and decreasing amounts on equipment and logistical support, the report stated.</p>
<p>Between 1985 and 1995, the size of the army has swelled from 12,000 men to more than 170,000 at present. In the same period the police force has grown from 67,000 men to 97,000.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite all this, subversion has gained geographical, economic, logistical and probably social ground,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Colombia currently has the highest rate of abductions in the world, with more than 1,400 last year, and has the highest per capita murder rate in Latin America.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
