<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484496" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Six inmates die in van fire in Tennessee.</title>
<headline>Six inmates die in van fire in Tennessee.</headline>
<dateline>DICKSON, Tenn. 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A van transporting six shackled prisoners caught fire Thursday on a Tennessee highway, killing the trapped inmates before guards could free them, police said.</p>
<p>One of two guards who escaped the van suffered burns on his arms and hands as he tried to open the rear door as flames from a ruptured gas tank engulfed the vehicle.</p>
<p>&quot;They either burned to death or died from smoke inhalation,&quot; Dickson police spokesman Kevin Heely said of the prisoners.</p>
<p>The driver apparently pulled the van over to the side of Interstate Highway 40 when the vehicle began smoking with some type of mechanical problem while travelling eastbound about seven miles east of Dickson in central Tennessee.</p>
<p>Anthony Kimbrough of Tennessee's Department of Public Safety said the vehicle's drive shaft may have broken and pierced the gas tank, triggering the blaze that was hot enough to melt metal.</p>
<p>The inmates were shackled, but were not manacled either to each other or to the van, Kimbrough said.</p>
<p>Kimbrough said the prisoners may have been on their way to Georgia, but both Tennessee and federal prison authorities denied the inmates were from their prison systems. A private company in Memphis contracted to transport the inmates said it could not offer any information on the accident.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DICKSON, Tenn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
