<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484419" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: C/A deficits high in some APEC economies - IMF.</title>
<headline>C/A deficits high in some APEC economies - IMF.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The sharp fluctuations in the yen/dollar rate has affected some APEC economies by leading to a worsening of their current account deficits, the International Monetary Fund (IMF) said.</p>
<p>&quot;The large change in the yen/dollar rate has accentuated the real effective exchange rate appreciation for several APEC economies that maintain relatively close links to the U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;This appreciation has helped restrain demand pressures, but it has exacerbated current account deficits in some countries,&quot; the IMF said in a paper to be presented to ministers of the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum at the weekend.</p>
<p>The paper, a copy of which was obtained by Reuters on Thursday, suggested the ministers should discuss the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;Do ministers agree that current account deficits in some APEC emerging market economies are excessive ?</p>
<p>&quot;In addition to considering further exchange rate flexibility, do ministers see a role for additional fiscal consolidation in addressing demand pressures?&quot; the IMF said.</p>
<p>It said the real exchange rate appreciation of several APEC economies had helped reduce overheating pressures, although in some cases it had contributed to a deterioration in the current account.</p>
<p>The IMF said greater exchange rate facility vis-a-vis the U.S. dollar could be helpful.</p>
<p>With the Thai baht closely linked to the dollar, the real effective exchange rate has appreciated strongly since 1995 at a time when the current account deficit remains large, at eight percent of GDP, the IMF said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
