<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484499" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Blue-chip stocks come under fresh selling pressure.</title>
<headline>Blue-chip stocks come under fresh selling pressure.</headline>
<byline>Richard Jacobsen</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue-chip stocks racked up big losses again Thursday, boosting the Dow's losses to more than 400 points since the rout started a week ago on concern over further interest-rate hikes by the Federal Reserve.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average fell 39.66 points to end at 6,477.35, standing just above its 1997 start of 6,448.27.</p>
<p>In the broader market, declining issues beat advances 1,516 to 894 on active volume of 495 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>A rally in battered technology stocks buoyed the Nasdaq Composite index, which ended 12.76 points higher at 1,213.76.</p>
<p>All eyes were on Friday's report on the payrolls, wages and unemployment numbers for March, and the possible impact that the data might have on whether the Fed again raises interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be a killer if it goes the wrong way,&quot; said Jim Benning, a trader at BT Brokerage.</p>
<p>Economists surveyed by Reuters expected the jobless rate to show a 0.1 percent drop to 5.2 percent and non-farm payrolls to rise by 196,000.</p>
<p>The focus also will be on possible upward pressures on wages.</p>
<p>Last week, the central bank raised interest rates for the first time in more than two years in a politically controversial move to stay a step ahead of inflation and keep the economic expansion on track.</p>
<p>If the jobs report shows a more robust-than-expected economy, it will add to growing fears among investors that the Fed will have to further raise interest rates in order to cool the economy, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears that the market's already anticipating a number that's going to cause further indigestion,&quot; said Charlie Crane, chief market strategist at Key Asset Management.</p>
<p>With the day's losses, the Dow has shed more than 400 points since its steep downturn began last Thursday. The closely watched gauge of 30 blue-chip stocks has fallen 8.6 percent since its record closing high of 7,085.16 on March 11.</p>
<p>But while blue chips floundered, the technology stocks that led the downturn found some buyers.</p>
<p>Among leading technology issues, Intel Corp. rose 3-5/8 to 140-5/8, Microsoft Corp. gained 3-1/8 to 95-1/8 and Oracle Corp. added 1-7/8 to 38-5/8.</p>
<p>Battered financial stocks also attracted buyers. Morgan Stanley Group Inc. jumped 2-3/8 to 59-7/8, Citicorp rose 1-3/4 to 111-5/8 and BankAmerica Corp. added 1 to 101-1/8.</p>
<p>Despite the rebound in some sectors, market watchers said further selling could be in store.</p>
<p>James Melcher, president of Balestra Capital, said he has moved the firm's investment portfolio 50 percent into cash, the first time at that level since shortly before the 1987 stock market crash.</p>
<p>Melcher said he would not be surprised to see the Dow drop &quot;a couple of thousand points&quot; as money flowing into equity mutual funds dries up.</p>
<p>International Business Machines Corp. did not take part in the technology-stock rebound. The computer giant's stock tumbled 2-5/8 to 131-1/8 on renewed fears that a stronger dollar and a mainframe product transition will hurt its first quarter earnings.</p>
<p>Lucent Technologies Inc. jumped 1-3/4 to 52 after the company told analysts it has cut internal costs and expected strong second-quarter sales in its software and wireless divisions.</p>
<p>Pharmaceutical company Rhone-Poulenc Rorer Inc. lost 2-3/4 to 69-3/4 after a Salomon Brothers analyst downgraded his rating on the stock and cut his 1997 earnings per share forecast on the company.</p>
<p>Microchip Technology Inc. gained 1-13/16 to 31-1/8 after saying it expected its revenues and earnings for its fourth fiscal quarter, ended March 31, to reach record levels.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks rose 0.21 of a point to 750.32. The American Stock Exchange index lost 3.37 to 557.82.</p>
<p>The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks fell 0.97 to 394.40. The average share was down 10 cents.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 7,137.612 down 3.060 or 0.04 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
