<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484415" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia palm olein stable in late trade.</title>
<headline>Indonesia palm olein stable in late trade.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian palm olein prices were generally stable in late trading on Thursday, with buyers taking to the sidelines amid falls in Malaysia, traders said.</p>
<p>They said palm olein was quoted at 1,405 rupiah/kg in Jakarta, unchanged from the opening, but credit offers were heard at 1,410-15 rupiah. The traders said crude palm oil was on offer at 1,230-35 rupiah/kg in the North Sumatran city of Medan, compared with last done 1,231 rupiah.</p>
<p>&quot;The market turned quiet following the declines in Malaysia,&quot; one trader said. &quot;Local buyers are waiting to see how the falls in Malaysia affect the local market.&quot;  </p>
<p>The traders said the export taxes on crude palm oil and its products as announced by the government on Thursday were in line with expectations, and added that the lower taxes in April were expected to boost export competitiveness.</p>
<p>The finance ministry said the export tax on crude palm oil was reduced to $41.08 a tonne in April from $52.52 in March. The tax on palm olein was cut to $54.60 a tonne from $65.10, while that on RBD palm oil was lowered to $43.68 in April from $55.64. The tax on crude olein was reduced to $58.10 from $63.70.</p>
<p>&quot;The taxes are what the market have been expecting,&quot; one trader said. &quot;The reductions will be good for exports.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
