<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484682" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton seeks chemical weapons pact ratification.</title>
<headline>Clinton seeks chemical weapons pact ratification.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton will host Republicans at a White House event on Friday to advance his effort to win Senate ratification of the Chemical Weapons Convention by an April 29 deadline, the White House said on Thursday.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry said the event was intended to demonstrate &quot;the wide-ranging and bipartisan support that exists for the Chemical Weapons Convention and has existed through a number of administrations.&quot;</p>
<p>He said former officials involved in negotiating the treaty, hammered out under Republican President George Bush, would attend the event, scheduled to take place at 10:30 a.m. EST (1530 GMT).</p>
<p>&quot;The president in very strong terms will call upon the Senate to ratify the Chemical Weapons Convention by the end of April, when the deadline for regional adherence ... expires,&quot; he said, adding the U.S. role in treaty enforcement would be &quot;severely restricted&quot; if it is not ratified by the April 29 deadline.</p>
<p>Last week Sen. Jesse Helms, the North Carolina Republican who chairs the influential Senate Foreign Relations Committee, said there was a good chance for ratification of the treaty, which bans the production, stockpiling and use of chemical weapons.</p>
<p>The treaty was signed by the United States and 129 other countries in Paris on Jan. 12, 1993. Although at last count 161 countries had signed and about 70 had ratified the treaty, it has languished in the U.S. Senate since 1993.</p>
<p>Helms, appearing in North Carolina with Secretary of State Madeleine Albright on March 25, told reporters he and the Democratic Clinton administration had been negotiating over the treaty and had managed to resolve a number of differences.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
