<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48470" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Senior IMF official expects gold sales agreement.</title>
<headline>Senior IMF official expects gold sales agreement.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior International Monetary Fund official said he expects the organization's board to back the sale of IMF gold if needed to help aid poor nations.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to get an agreement that in the event of need the board will be willing to sell gold,&quot; he told a news conference unveiling the IMF's 1996 annual report.</p>
<p>Speaking to Reuters Financial Television later, Fischer said that an agreement was &quot;not totally in the bag&quot; but looked very likely.  </p>
<p>The IMF's board is scheduled to meet on Friday to discuss the possible sale of some five million ounces of the IMF's gold. A handful of nations -- led by Germany -- have opposed the proposal, although most back it.</p>
<p>Fischer said that the IMF was concerned about Germany's objections and was working with it to try to fashion an agreement.</p>
<p>But, he said, &quot;I'm not sure in the end we will be able to fully agree with them,&quot; indicating a willingness to go ahead with the proposal without German support.</p>
<p>Asked about rumors that the IMF was negotiating with some central banks about purchasing the gold directly so as not to upset the market, Fischer replied, &quot;There have been early discussions on how to sell the gold.&quot;But he added, &quot;I'm not aware that we've come anywhere close to deciding.&quot;</p>
<p>The IMF in the past has sold gold through public auction.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
