<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484724" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORECAST-Experts boost US March payrolls estimates.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Experts boost US March payrolls estimates.</headline>
<byline>Donna Sells</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A survey of Wall Street pundits on Thursday indicated a vibrant U.S. economy may have added more non-farm payroll jobs in March than was previously expected.</p>
<p>The poll of 21 economists produced a consensus forecast calling for an increase of 196,000 jobs in March, up from a prior estimate of 186,000.</p>
<p>Potentially market moving employment data for March are due out on Friday at 0830 EST/1330 GMT. In February, the economy created a solid 339,00 non-farm payroll jobs.  </p>
<p>Five economists revised their forecasts higher, one estimate was cut and the remaining 15 were left unchanged.</p>
<p>Among those survey participants who increased their forecasts was John Ryding, senior economist at Bear, Stearns &amp; Co Inc. &quot;We bumped our forecast (from 185,000) up to 200,000 after the NAPM,&quot; said Ryding. &quot;We took our manufacturing number from plus 10 (thousand) to plus 25 (thousand).&quot;</p>
<p>The NAPM, or National Association of Purchasing Management, released its monthly report on manufacturing activity on Tuesday. The NAPM employment component jumped to 51.6 in March from 45.4 in February.  </p>
<p>The strong manufacturing employment figure also played a role in prompting HSBC Markets economist Jonathan Basile to revise his payrolls forecast to a 250,000 gain from a previous 180,000.</p>
<p>&quot;We were looking for something a little bit weaker and it came in a lot stronger,&quot; said Basile, referring to the NAPM employment index. &quot;Yes, it's a volatile series (and) month-to-month movements don't correlate perfectly (with monthly jobs data); but we think there's going to be more strength in manufacturing, probably.&quot;  </p>
<p>Even some economists who did not revise their forecasts warned the closely watched payrolls figure could surprise financial markets.</p>
<p>&quot;There's room for almost any kind of number here,&quot; said Carol Stone, a senior economist at Nomura Securities International Inc. &quot;There are risks in this employment report in a couple of directions.&quot;</p>
<p>Payrolls could be a lot weaker than analysts expect because construction employment could fall as much as it rose last month, but there are some other areas that could be stronger than analysts expect, Stone said.  </p>
<p>A 109,000 increase in construction jobs helped boost non-farm payrolls in February.</p>
<p>Nomura Securities still expected payrolls to post a 205,000 gain in March.</p>
<p>On the other hand, Morgan Stanley and Co Inc lowered its forecast to a 185,000 increase from a 205,000 rise.</p>
<p>&quot;(Payrolls) were revised down this morning to 185 (thousand). That was on the basis of the surprising upward revision to continuing claims in the survey week,&quot; said David Greenlaw, senior economist at Morgan Stanley.</p>
<p>In the week ended March 15, the Labor Department reported that continued claims were revised higher to 2,310,000 from a previously reported 2,281,000.</p>
<p>Another key component of the employment report to be released on Friday is the jobless rate, which is seen edging down to 5.2 percent from 5.3 percent.</p>
<p>((-- 212-859-1668))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
