<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484803" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oklahoma City trial judge refuses media request.</title>
<headline>Oklahoma City trial judge refuses media request.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Oklahoma City bombing case judge on Thursday denied a request from news organisations that he stop holding closed conferences with attorneys to decide which jurors to dismiss.</p>
<p>U.S. District Court Judge Richard Matsch said that other potential jurors might be influenced by news reports disclosing the reasons why members of the jury panel were excused.  </p>
<p>So far 20 prospective jurors have been questioned by the judge, prosecutors and attorneys for defendant Timothy McVeigh on their attitudes toward the death penalty and on how much exposure they have had to pre-trial publicity about the April 19, 1995, bombing which killed 168 people.</p>
<p>The potential jurors' identity has been keep secret, they are seated behind a wooden panel and kept out of view of spectators in the courtroom.</p>
<p>Each morning the judge and the lawyers meet in closed session to review the prior day's jurors. At that time lawyers challenge certain potential jurors, citing specific reasons why those people should be dismissed.</p>
<p>Media lawyer Tom Kelley told the judge that high public interest in the case requires these meetings be done in open court. But the judge disagreed, saying he would unseal those proceedings at a later date.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
