<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484912" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital markets closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital markets closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bond futures suffered with Bund futures amid continued uncertainty ahead of key US jobs figures due Friday, strong German data and an ongoing reluctance on the part of French investors to take new positions.</p>
<p>Traders said although a sale of French government bonds had gone better than expected in the current environment the closer 10-year yields get to six percent the more nervous the market would become.</p>
<p>Traders and analysts said despite a relatively favourable European fundamental situation, the bond market had become fixated by the US and was looking to the US bonds for direction.  </p>
<p>The June bond future settled down 0.22 at 127.18 after trading between 127.46 and 127.06. Most of the action took place in the morning ahead of the OAT auction.</p>
<p>After a tentative start, stronger than expected German industrial production figures, covering ahead of the auction and the liquidation of positions by a non-resident investor sent the contract tumbling to the day's low.</p>
<p>Traders said while French insurance companies, the main source of demand in the domestic cash market, were not big players in the auction, other fund managers snapped up much of the paper to cover short positions ahead of the US jobs figures.  </p>
<p>The Treasury sold 21.84 billion francs of OATs with an overall bid to cover ratio of 1.8, the benchmark 5.5 percent 2007 OAT making up nearly three-quarters of the bonds sold.</p>
<p>The 10-year spread between French and German yields narrowed as low as minus seven basis points ahead of the sale from minus 10 on Wednesday. It had returned to minus nine by the end of the session.</p>
<p>&quot;People seemed pretty happy,&quot; said a trader at a French bank. &quot;It will be very quiet now, with no moves ahead of tomorrow afternoon.&quot;  </p>
<p>According to a Reuter poll of economists a US non-farm payrolls report for March due for release at 1330 GMT on Friday was expected to show a 182,000 increase in jobs.</p>
<p>Traders said it would be watched closely for clues as to when and by how much the U.S. Federal Reserve would next raise US short-term interest rates.</p>
<p>One trader said even though the current obsession with moves in the US bond market was not really justified a US-driven rise in French 10-year yields to six percent could spark panic selling. He said the spread between French and US yields seemed unable to widen beyond 100 basis points at the moment.  </p>
<p>Valerie Plagnol, economist at Credit Commercial de France said news that German Chancellor Helmut Kohl, a driving force behind the move towards European monetary union, would be running for re-election in 1998 was positive for convergence.</p>
<p>&quot;It supports the pro-European move,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The franc remained steady below 3.37 per mark, close to the 45-month high of 3.3654 it hit late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>As expected the Bank of France left the intervention rate unchanged at 3.10 percent at Thursday's regular money market tender.</p>
<p>-- David Clarke, Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5542</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
