<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484947" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's rulers say Congress will bow in crisis.</title>
<headline>India's rulers say Congress will bow in crisis.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Congress party said on Thursday it would press ahead with its effort to topple Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda, but the ruling coalition predicted its rival would opt for a face-saving bargain to avert elections.</p>
<p>Congress and Deve Gowda's United Front ruling coalition pursued their war of nerves ahead of a vote of confidence in parliament set for April 11.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question of our entertaining the United Front request for reconsidering our decision on withdrawal of support,&quot; Congress leader K. Karunakaran said.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Deve Gowda will be prime minister until April 11 only.&quot;</p>
<p>But United Front leaders said talks were under way to explore a possible settlement to the crisis, which has held hostage the path-breaking, tax-cutting budget for the 1997/98 fiscal year that started on April 1.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sure that the reality is such that Congress will realise that the step they have taken is a hasty one and that some solution will be worked out,&quot; Harkishan Singh Surjeet, general secretary of the Communist Party of India (Marxist), told reporters.</p>
<p>The party of Mahatma Gandhi and Jawaharlal Nehru triggered the political crisis on Sunday when its leader, Sitaram Kesri, abruptly announced that Congress was withdrawing its vital support for Deve Gowda's 10-month-old government.</p>
<p>United Front leaders predicted Congress would eventually withdraw its threat to bring down the government because it was reluctant to face mid-term polls after suffering its worst defeat last year in general elections.</p>
<p>&quot;Congressmen think Kesri is heading them towards a snap poll, and a snap poll is the last thing the Congress party can afford,&quot; United Front spokesman Jaipal Reddy said.</p>
<p>A recent opinion poll showed that the right-wing Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) would stand to gain at Congress's expense if elections were held now.</p>
<p>The BJP and its allies control 193 votes in the 542-member lower house. The United Front has 180 votes and Congress 140. Deve Gowda would need a simple majority of members present and voting to win the confidence motion.</p>
<p>Another United Front leader said: &quot;We expect Congressmen will in due course revolt against Mr Kesri.&quot;</p>
<p>The ruling coalition drew confidence from its relatively strong regional base, which contrasted with Congress's dismal performance in recent polls in the major states of Uttar Pradesh, Bihar and Tamil Nadu.</p>
<p>United Front leaders said Kesri had already started beating a retreat by saying he was prepared to accept another candidate from the United Front to replace Deve Gowda.</p>
<p>&quot;From making a claim to form the government they have come down to demanding a change in the leadership of the United Front,&quot; communist leader Surjeet said.</p>
<p>&quot;That is why I say something can be worked out.&quot;</p>
<p>Deve Gowda appeared unfazed by the turmoil. &quot;The people who are anxious to be nearer to power will always worry,&quot; he said. &quot;I used to worry. I know the taste (of power).&quot;</p>
<p>Independent political analyst Rasheed Talib said the crisis could deepen but there was pressure on Congress to reach a solution. &quot;I have a feeling it will be defused,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Congress could agree to enter the United Front government in exchange for private assurances that Deve Gowda would be replaced at a later date by a compromise leader, Talib said.</p>
<p>In that case, parliament would pass the budget next week and refrain from a confidence vote.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
