<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48503" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Argentina, Nicaragua show August price declines.</title>
<headline>Argentina, Nicaragua show August price declines.</headline>
<byline>Dario Tonelli</byline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina and Nicaragua posted negative inflation in August, while Mexico recorded its smallest price increases since its 1994 devaluation, official figures showed.</p>
<p>In its fourth monthly deflation since January, Argentina showed a 0.10 percent decrease in consumer prices for an accumulated drop of 0.3 percent in the first eight months of 1996 -- by far the lowest figure in Latin America.  </p>
<p>To be sure, Argentina's performance not only reflects the success of its stabilization plan, but also the country's stubborn economic stagnation. Nine out of ten Argentines think the economy will not emerge from the slump any time soon, according to a poll published this week.</p>
<p>The decline in Nicaraguan prices was even steeper, with a 0.79 percent drop led by food and clothing. That brought the total increase to 4.84 percent in the last eight months.</p>
<p>Brazil is another country that might soon experience falling prices. Only two years ago it was struggling to overcome hyperinflation.  </p>
<p>Brazil registered a 0.50 percent increase in its national consumer price index, while the Getulio Vargas Foundation's IGP-M index fell by 0.40 percent in the last 10 days of August. That might herald an overall decline in September.</p>
<p>Still, most analysts say falling prices are not a sign of things to come.</p>
<p>&quot;This number was really surprising, but the index is very volatile. It does not mean we will be in a period of deflation,&quot; said Marcelo Carvalho, chief economist at J.P. Morgan in Brazil.  </p>
<p>Mexico also had good news as inflation fell to 1.33 percent, its lowest since the financial crisis that erupted in December 1994.</p>
<p>But the impact of the peso devaluation, which sent prices spiralling, is still evident in an 18.50 percent accumulated rise for the January-August period, the second highest in Latin America.</p>
<p>Venezuela held the top place, with a 4.1 percent rise in consumer prices in August, an increase that pushed eight-month inflation to 70.4 percent.  </p>
<p>Following are the official inflation figures announced as of Thursday in Latin America:</p>
<p>    Country	August    July     8 months    12 months</p>
<p>    ARGENTINA    -0.10	0.50     -0.30	    0.20</p>
<p>    BOLIVIA	 1.04	1.13	7.13	   13.68</p>
<p>    BRAZIL	  0.50	1.20	7.96	   14.28</p>
<p>    COLOMBIA	1.03	1.51     16.96	   21.05</p>
<p>    COSTA RICA    0.96	1.17	9.10	   18.51</p>
<p>    CHILE	   0.40	0.30	4.60	    6.40</p>
<p>    ECUADOR	 1.99	1.70     16.60	   25.14</p>
<p>    EL SALVADOR   1.50	1.60	8.30	   10.80</p>
<p>    GUATEMALA     0.98	1.37	7.90	   12.03</p>
<p>    MEXICO	  1.33	1.43     18.50	   30.60</p>
<p>    NICARAGUA    -0.79	0.09	4.84	   11.49</p>
<p>    PARAGUAY	0.40	0.40	7.20	    9.70</p>
<p>    PERU	    0.92	1.37	8.84	   11.77</p>
<p>    URUGUAY	 2.15	1.67     16.60	   25.60</p>
<p>    VENEZUELA     4.10	5.00     70.40	  112.60</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
