<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="485017" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka expects showers by next week.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka expects showers by next week.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lanka's Meteorology Department said on Thursday there were signs intermonsoon thunderstorms could break over the island in a week's time, helping to fill depleted hydropower reservoirs.</p>
<p>&quot;The lower part of the atmosphere is favourable for rain although there is still a slight dryness prevailing,&quot; said deputy director P.M. Jayatilaka Banda.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope the situation will ease in a week's time and that the normal intermonsoon thunderstorms will arrive,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka is experiencing a drought for the second consecutive year, lowering water levels in reservoirs to dangerous levels and threatening power cuts.</p>
<p>The Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) state power utility said water levels in hydropower reservoirs had fallen to about 21 percent of capacity because of the failure of the northeast monsoon and the delayed onset of intermonsoon showers.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment there are no plans for power cuts given the additions we have made to the grid,&quot; a CEB official said. &quot;But we are asking consumers to conserve energy.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the power supply was slightly better than around the same time last year when the island was forced to impose lengthy power cuts, sometimes of up to eight hours a day.</p>
<p>The CEB has said it plans to reduce dependence on hydropower to about 57 percent, from almost 84 percent, by mid-1997 by building more thermal power plants.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka's total power generating capacity of about 1,250 megawatts has been boosted by the addition of 70 MW from new small thermal power plants, CEB officials said.</p>
<p>A further 40 MW is to be added in April, they said.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka has two rainy seasons. The southwest monsoon, the most important for hydroelectric plants, usually starts around the third week of May.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1610107">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
