<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="485142" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dow could rally on weak March jobs report - analysts.</title>
<headline>Dow could rally on weak March jobs report - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Westhoven</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The besieged Dow Jones industrial average could rally on Friday if a key report on March employment shows no signs of a tightening labor market.</p>
<p>The report is expected to show the U.S. economy created 196,000 new nonfarm jobs in March, compared with 339,000 in February, according to a Reuters survey.</p>
<p>The data will be dissected for any signs of mounting labor-cost pressures, which could increase the risk of the Federal Reserve moving to raise interest rates at its May 20 policy-making meeting or its next session in June.  </p>
<p>&quot;If the numbers are weak and shift the entrenched thought process that there will be a hike at the May meeting ... we could have a great rebound day. We could have a 100-point-up day,&quot; said John Ryding, senior economist at Bear Stearns.</p>
<p>The report also includes average hourly earnings, the unemployment rate and the length of the average work week.</p>
<p>&quot;Wages are what the Fed is paying attention to, so the market is focused on that,&quot; said Jennifer Moran, associate to the chief economist at Donaldson Lufkin &amp; Jenrette.  </p>
<p>U.S. economists polled by Reuters forecast average hourly wages climbed 0.4 percent in March compared with a 0.2 percent rise in February.</p>
<p>Heightened concern about rising rates have helped push the Dow industrials down 608 points, or 8.5 percent, from its March 11 high of 7085. The index closed Thursday at 6477.</p>
<p>The Fed moved to raise interest rates for the first time in two years on March 25, when it lifted the key federal funds short-term rate by 0.25 percentage point.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
