<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="485232" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY precious metals end lower led by silver.</title>
<headline>NY precious metals end lower led by silver.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX and NYMEX precious metals futures ended lower for a second day Thursday, led again by fund liquidation of long silver positions, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Funds continued to bail out of silver positions after silver broke support around $5.00 an ounce this week and the move just accelerated from there, with the help of some unwinding of gold/silver ratio plays also,&quot; said, Chris Foster, fund manager of Toronto based Friedberg Mercantile Group.  </p>
<p>&quot;But silver is probably very close to a level at which some serious support from the trade is likely,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>COMEX May silver ended down 13.0 cents at $4.740 an ounce, after seeing a new contract low at $4.655. Estimated total volume in silver was a high 51,000 contracts.</p>
<p>In the bullion market, spot silver ended quoted around $4.74 an ounce, after seeing a low around $4.67, the lowest level since mid-January.</p>
<p>In the latest CFTC data for March 25, funds were net long 10,871 contracts in COMEX silver and the residual &quot;non-reportable&quot; category, representing small traders, were net long 8,979 lots.</p>
<p>But open interest has since been rising quickly, reaching 94,216 contracts Wednesday, the highest level in a month, suggesting short positions may now be being put on, analysts said.</p>
<p>Daily momentum oscillators now look oversold though, analysts noted, suggesting a near term bottom may not be far away.</p>
<p>A standard five-day slow stochastic indicator stood at 17 percent and a nine-day relative strength indicator (RSI) at 17 percent also Thursday.</p>
<p>Gold held up better than silver again, with the spot gold/silver ratio recovering further to 73.5, from 71.7 Wednesday, after seeing a 22-month low at 65.6 in mid-February.</p>
<p>A weaker U.S. dollar and slipping stock market values are helping to provide some support for gold, but open interest in COMEX gold futures remains at its lowest levels since last September, suggesting no great rush into the asset-of-last-resort is occurring yet, analysts said.</p>
<p>U.S. bond and stocks remained weak Thursday, after U.S. February housing completions rose 10.8 percent to 1.404 million units at annual rate, the highest since January 1990.</p>
<p>Gold equities were little changed though, with the Philadelphia Stock Exchange's gold and silver sector (.XAU) index of North American mining stocks only slightly weaker around 103.92.</p>
<p>COMEX June gold ended down 70 cents at $351.60 an ounce, after trading a $352.50-350.00 range.</p>
<p>In the bullion market, spot gold ended quoted $348.50/00, compared to the London Thursday afternoon fix at $348.75, and the New York close Wednesday around $348.80/30.</p>
<p>Implied gold lease rates remained low also, with the one month rate still below 1.00 percent, suggesting little new speculative shorting activity, analysts said.</p>
<p>In the platinum metals group, NYMEX July platinum lost $2.80 to 369.50, but NYMEX June palladium ended unchanged at $147.50.</p>
<p>-email: clive.mckeef@reuters.com</p>
<p>((Clive McKeef, New York Commodities Desk, +1-212-859-1641))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
