<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="485357" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American pilots' board to discuss proposal.</title>
<headline>American pilots' board to discuss proposal.</headline>
<dateline>ARLINGTON HEIGHTS, Ill. 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The board of American Airlines pilots union said it might vote Thursday afternoon on a labour contract proposed by the nation's second largest carrier.</p>
<p>&quot;After the working lunch, the board will begin its debate and they could vote mid-afternoon,&quot; said Wally Pitts, a spokesman for the Allied Pilots Association, which represents 9,300 American Airlines pilots.</p>
<p>The 18-member board of the Allied Pilots Association, which represents 9,300 pilots at American, was meeting here in the suburban Chicago area to vote on the airline's contract proposal.</p>
<p>The pilots reached an agreement in principle with American last week, although the issue of who will fly small jets at the American Eagle regional division has yet to be settled.</p>
<p>American Airlines, a subsidiary of AMR Corp., wants American Eagle pilots, who are paid less than APA members, to fly smaller jets so the company can remain competitive with low-cost commuter carriers. The APA pilots, however, are concerned that American Eagle pilots will eventually take over their current routes.</p>
<p>Under a proposed five-year deal, American pilots would receive pay increases of 9 percent and options on 5.75 million shares of AMR common stock at $10 below market price.</p>
<p>American Airlines also would be able to add 50- and 70-seat commuter jets at American Eagle, but the APA in return would win a guarantee that any furloughed American pilots would be moved to fly the regional commuter jets.</p>
<p>A two-tier B-scale pay structure also will be phased out by the end of the contract.</p>
<p>If the board approves the pact, it would set up a ratification vote by the rank-and-file. If the board rejects the proposal, another 30-day cooling off period would be launched.</p>
<p>James Sovich, president of the APA, said late Wednesday there was no indication in either direction on the board's stance on the proposal.</p>
<p>The APA went on strike on Feb. 15 but a Presidential Emergency Board sent pilots back to work just minutes later.</p>
<p>The rank-and-file has rejected board-approved agreements before. Last fall, the board accepted a proposal by American, but union members rejected it in early January.</p>
<p>However, rejecting the latest proposal would allow Congress to impose a contract, a prospect that some pilots have said is more onerous than any offer from American.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ARLINGTON HEIGHTS, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
