<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="485369" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Japan pans U.S., sees win in photofilm trade dispute.</title>
<headline>Japan pans U.S., sees win in photofilm trade dispute.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan told a World Trade Organisation dispute panel Thursday that U.S. charges it deliberately skews its domestic market to limit sales of foreign photo-film products are untrue.</p>
<p>The Japanese company involved in the dispute, Fuji Photo Film Co. Ltd, said it was convinced that U.S. claims on behalf of Eastman Kodak Co. would be &quot;totally and decisively refuted&quot; by the neutral three-man group.</p>
<p>Tokyo's position was set out in a formal submission to the panel at the WTO's Geneva headquarters.</p>
<p>&quot;The Japanese film and paper markets are open to imports,&quot; said a document delivered to the panel by Japanese officials. &quot;Success in the Japanese market depends simply upon the efforts of private companies.&quot;</p>
<p>Fuji has consistently argued that Kodak has failed to win more customers in Japan through lack of attention to pricing policy and to what Japanese consumers want.</p>
<p>In Tokyo, a senior Trade Ministry official, in remarks echoed by Japanese diplomats in Geneva, said the U.S. argument set out in a 200-page submission on Feb. 20 &quot;is both factually baseless and legally groundless.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Japan had never taken any action that violated world trade accords supervised by the WTO or that nullified agreements on lowering tariff barriers by creating other obstacles to open commerce.</p>
<p>The WTO action was launched by Washington in June last year after years of complaint by Kodak.</p>
<p>The panel, whose members were appointed last December, would normally be expected to deliver its findings by the middle of June. But diplomats say the complicated nature of the case could cause a delay of several weeks or even months.</p>
<p>Whatever the outcome, an appeal is almost certain and under WTO procedures a final ruling by the trade watchdog's Dispute Settlement Body -- on which all 130 member countries can sit -- might not come until well into 1998.</p>
<p>In a comment issued from its Rochester, N.Y., headquarters Thursday, Kodak said it hoped the filing of the Japanese submission would enable the panel to press ahead on judging the merits of the U.S. case.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect that upon consideration of the evidence, the WTO will move to reverse the covert measures undertaken by the Japanese government to restrict import competition,&quot; Chief Executive Officer George Fisher said.</p>
<p>Kodak, which holds 70 percent of the U.S. domestic market but only 9 percent in Japan, says that for two decades it has lost up to $5.6 billion annually in potential sales to Japanese consumers because of unfair marketing rules.</p>
<p>Fuji, which has around 67 percent of its home market, counters that it faces distribution barriers in the United States, where it holds 12 percent of the market.</p>
<p>In a statement issued in Geneva, Fuji Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Minoru Ohnishi said the arguments presented by Japanese officials to the panel amounted to an &quot;overwhelming case&quot; against the U.S. complaint.</p>
<p>Washington, Ohnishi said, was aiming &quot;to impose its distorted views on the Japanese photographic market to force a greater market share for Kodak.&quot; Fuji, he added, was confident that the panel would find in Japan's favour.</p>
<p>The United States argues that the dispute is not a fight between two competitor companies but a normal trade dispute between two countries.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a case about classic protectionism accomplished through novel means,&quot; U.S. Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky said in February.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
