<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="485455" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasury mulls 5-yr inflation-protected notes.</title>
<headline>US Treasury mulls 5-yr inflation-protected notes.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>While the U.S. Treasury has not yet decided what maturity it will offer at either of its two inflation-protected securities auctions in the second half of the year, a five-year issue is getting consideration, suggested Roger Anderson, Treasury's Deputy Assistant Secretary of Federal Finance.</p>
<p>Anderson, in an interview with Reuters, reiterated that there will be a second mauturity offered at Treasury's quarterly index-lined bond auctions in July and October, but whether it will be longer or shorter than a 10-year note was not yet decided.  </p>
<p>&quot;Over the long run, we're going to set aside both interests,&quot; Anderson said.</p>
<p>A third maturity will be offered in 1998, he said.</p>
<p>Anderson noted that it's possible the 10-year index-linked note could be re-opened again later in the year, but the Treasury is also looking at a five-year note and 30-year bond.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of market people have said there is substantial interest in the five-year sector,&quot; Anderson said. &quot;A lot of the corporate issuance that has been done are fairly short. A lot of them have been five-years and one of them was even three years.  </p>
<p>&quot;There's more retail interest in the shorter end and therefore there is more mutual fund interest,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Wednesday, Treasury announced it will sell $8 billion of 10-year inflation-indexed notes on April 8, in a reopening of the note sold in late January.</p>
<p>Anderson said the re-opening was to build up the size of the issue and give it more liquidity. &quot;We have talked to a lot of market participants before we made a decision and almost all of them recomended a reopening,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As for whether the eventual longer-term offering will be a 20-year or 30-year bond, Anderson said that most market participants prefer a 30-year, but no decision has been made yet.</p>
<p>Anderson also noted the 10-year index-linked bond has traded quite well the past six weeks. Since mid-February, the nominal 10-year note has gained 58 basis points in yield (to 6.86 percent from 6.28 percent), whereas its index-linked companion was up only about 33 basis points (to 3.58 percent).</p>
<p>&quot;It is a little early to read a whole lot of meaning into these numbers,&quot; Anderson said. &quot;But they are interesting.&quot;</p>
<p>(( -- Steven Scheer, N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1867 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
