<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48559" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: KC Power says Utilicorp vote not majority.</title>
<headline>KC Power says Utilicorp vote not majority.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kansas City Power &amp; Light Co said on Thursday that just under one half of the shareholder votes on its proposed merger with UtiliCorp were affirmative.</p>
<p>The company also said in a statement that its board had rejected Western Resources' hostile exchange offer and continued to recommend that shareholders not tender shares to Western.  </p>
<p>The company said the count was preliminary and proxies remained subject to review and challenge by both Kansas City Power and Western Resources. Shareholders voted on a proposed merger with UtiliCorp United on August 16.</p>
<p>&quot;In the event that it is confirmed that a majority of shares voting at the special meeting did not vote in favor of the KCPL/UtiliCorp merger proposal, we will review our alternatives and pursue options which the Board believes are in the best interests of KCPL, its shareholders and other constituencies it serves,&quot; KCPL Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer Drue Jennings said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Jennings said the board rejected Western Resource's hostile exchange offer and was telling shareholders not to tender.</p>
<p>&quot;Given that nearly one-half of the shares voting at the August 16 special meeting clearly preferred the KCPL/UtiliCorp merger, it is difficult to see how Western could possibly get close to satisfying the conditions to its tender offer, which requires acceptance of the offer by the owners of 90 percent of KCPL's shares,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Western Resources has bid $31 per share in Western shares in a $1.9 billion offer for Kansas City Power.</p>
<p>On August 30, Western said it was extending its exchange offer for Kansas City Power to October 25 from September 20.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 859 1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
