<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="485525" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold fixes marginally lower, silver also off.</title>
<headline>London gold fixes marginally lower, silver also off.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Silver looked steadier after a fall in London on Thursday while gold reflected the move by being a touch easier. One dealer said a wave of fund selling of silver in New York had apparently dried up although further fund pressure could not be ruled out for gold.</p>
<p>Bullion fixed at $348.75 an ounce in the afternoon versus $349.10 earlier and against Wednesday's close of $351.10/$351.60.</p>
<p>In New York, the Comex June futures contract was off earlier lows, but still 70 cents down at $351.40.</p>
<p>On Wednesday it came under pressure from several factors including the sell-off in silver.</p>
<p>A slump in crude oil futures as the winter heating season ended and weakening stock market values undermined sentiment in other markets and put pressure on gold.</p>
<p>But gold seemed to be wedged in a tight range and was likely to receive good support at $345.00 if $348.00 fell, analysts added.</p>
<p>Silver shed 17 cents on the day in London and was indicated at $4.82/$4.84 at 1515 GMT. Comex May futures lost four cents to $4.83 after an intraday low of 481.50 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;There was good two-way business in silver today,&quot; said one dealer, referring to silver's ability to remain within a 2-3 cent range between $4.82-$4.85 bid after falling from a close of $4.99/$5.01 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Traders cited heavy selling in New York by disillusioned funds as the reason silver had dropped to its seven-week low.</p>
<p>&quot;The funds may have been motivated to sell silver by the threat of higher interest rates in the US,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The gold-silver price ratio has also &quot;had a good correction&quot; a dealer said as it expanded from around 65 in mid February to above 72 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Silver prices have been under some pressure since repeated attempts to push it through $5.30 failed in February and March, dealers said, adding that the break of $4.85 could have made the market vulnerable to a move towards $4.60.</p>
<p>Platinum and palladium were both marked lower in tandem with silver but their downside has been limited by continuing silence on the start this year of Russian exports to leading consumer Japan.</p>
<p>Both platinum and palladium pared earlier losses and were $3.00 down at $367.00/$368.00 and $146.50/$147.50 respectively.</p>
<p>--Clelia Oziel, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8058</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
