<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="485793" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O.Licht - Daily sugar report.</title>
<headline>F.O.Licht - Daily sugar report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from commodity statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>SUGAR: World market for April 2, 1997</p>
<p>White sugar futures in London ended weaker in uneventful trading. The most active May contract finished 90 cents softer at $308.20 per tonne, while August gave up $2.0 to close at $306.40 per tonne. In New York raw sugar futures ended weaker after failing to pierce resistance at 11.00 cents/lb despite steady speculative buying throughout the day. However, the market remains near the top of its trading range. Traders said speculative buying could hold prices steady but liquidation ahead of the May expiry could prompt further losses. The last trading day for the spot month is April 30. May gave up 4 points to close at 10.96 cents/lb, while July ended 2 points lower at 10.70 cents/lb.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>YUGOSLAVIA - Sugar beet and sugar production are expected to decline in 1997/98 primarily due to serious payment problems experienced by the Yugoslav sugar beet growers in 1996. As of mid-March sugar producers still owed farmers about 200 mn dinars for delivered beets in 1996, which has repercussions on this year's crop.</p>
<p>The government's target for sugar beet sowings this year is 100,000 ha, while industry sources said that the total will be not more than 50,000 to 60,000 ha, down from 70,000 ha last season. The government's target is based on the total processing capacity of the Yugoslav sugar industry put at around 4.5 mn tonnes of sugar beet.</p>
<p>However, industry sources said actual production will be not more than 2.0 mn tonnes, down from 2.5 mn tonnes the previous year. Excessive imports in 1995/96 are another reason for the difficulties experienced by the Yugoslav sugar industry. Total imports in 1995/96 (September/August) are estimated at 180,000 tonnes, raw value, most of which from Cuba and Brazil. Only small quantities are expected to be imported in 1996/97 because of improved domestic production, reduced consumption and the large 1995/96 sugar imports. However, the projected decline in production in 1997/98 is expected to necessitate imports of about 100,000 tonnes of sugar, raw value, in 1997/98.</p>
<p>BELGIUM - Sugar imports in December 1996 amounted to 176,662 tonnes, raw value, up from last year's 153,479 tonnes. This brought cumulative imports in the first quarter of 1996/97 (October/December) up to 320,822 tonnes compared to 319,631 tonnes in the like period the previous year. Total imports in 1995/96 reached 711,840 tonnes, down from 1.139 mn tonnes in 1994/95. Major countries of origin in October/December 1996 were France with 208,810 tonnes whites against 241,592 tonnes and Germany with 82,557 tonnes, up from 20,876 tonnes. Sugar exports in December 1996 amounted to 206,760 tonnes, up from 148,169 tonnes exported in December 1995. This brought cumulative exports in October/December 1996 up to 409,542 tonnes compared to 495,832 tonnes in the corresponding period the previous year. Total exports in 1995/96 reached 988,722 tonnes, down from 1.566 mn tonnes in 1994/95. Major countries of destination in October/December 1996 were Syria with 103,966 tonnes whites against 109,749 tonnes, Turkey with 2</p>
<p>NEW ZEALAND - Sugar imports in February 1997 jumped to 29,341 tonnes, up from 19,261 tonnes in February 1996. This brought cumulative imports in January/February 1997 up to 29,561 tonnes, down from 32,769 tonnes in January/February 1996. Total imports in 1996 amounted to 263,747 tonnes against 210,379 tonnes in 1995. The major country of origin in January/February 1997 was Australia with 19,843 tonnes raws against 18,548 tonnes and 8,856 tonnes whites, down from 13,053 tonnes.</p>
<p>TENDERS</p>
<p>The European Union awarded 54,500 tonnes of white sugar at a maximum refund of ECU 44.329 per 100 kg at its weekly tender on April 2. Cumulative awards so far made under the 1996/97 series of tenders for the period up to April 2 reached 1,734,450 tonnes, which compares to 1,833,448 tonnes last year.</p>
<p>The Turkish company Besler said that it was selling 5,500 tonnes of Icumsa-45 white sugar to various buyers in northern Iraq at prices between $410 and $430 per tonne. A spokesman for the company said that 3,000 tonnes of sugar were received from local suppliers and 2,500 tonnes of imported sugar from the free trade zone in Mersin port.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
