<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="485951" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy privatisations good for stock market - Consob.</title>
<headline>Italy privatisations good for stock market - Consob.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's privatisation process has so far had a positive effect on the development of the country's stock market, Enzo Berlanda, chairman of bourse regulator Consob, said in the supervisory body's annual report.</p>
<p>&quot;The weight of the main companies privatised is considerable,&quot; Consob said. &quot;Capitalisation at end-1996 is equal to some 23 percent of the total and overall share trading equals around 22 percent of total bourse capitalisation.</p>
<p>&quot;The value of shares floated of companies privatised or being privatised is equal to 41.8 percent of the overall capitalisation of the same stocks,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Operations carried out via public and institutional offers between end-1993 and the end of 1996 were worth a total 27.28 trillion lire ($16.4 billion), Consob said.</p>
<p>In this period the Treasury sold off stakes worth over 24.50 trillion lire. At the same time, privately negotiated sales of quoted companies totalled 5.65 trillion lire.</p>
<p>In 1996, Consob noted that institutional investors had played a major role in privatisation share placements, with over 90 percent of operations carried out, including a private placement aimed at institutionals as well as a public offer.</p>
<p>Demand largely exceeded offers last year and the stock market was boosted by the listing of new companies &quot;as also confirmed by the performance of such stocks which was well above that of the bourse index,&quot; Consob said.</p>
<p>-- Rome newsroom +396 6782501</p>
<p>($ = 1661 Italian Lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
