<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="486087" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Idiosyncratic British economy bars EMU membership.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Idiosyncratic British economy bars EMU membership.</headline>
<byline>Cheryl Juckes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>While politicians wrangle over the principle of European monetary union, the real obstacle to Britain's chances of ever being a successful member -- its idiosyncratic economic cycle -- is being ignored.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a dearth of serious academic study on the lack of convergence between the UK economic cycle and that of continental Europe,&quot; said Barclays group chief executive Martin Taylor, who is keen to stir up debate on the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;But that phenomenon is absolutely crucial if we're going to join a single currency,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The difference between the two economic environments could not be starker than it is at present.</p>
<p>Britain is enjoying a mini-boom with strong domestic demand and falling unemployment.</p>
<p>Continental Europe is struggling with sluggish growth and soaring joblessness.</p>
<p>Britain faces imminent interest rate rises to rein in rampant consumer spending.</p>
<p>Continental European rates are set to remain at historically low levels to allow flagging economies to gather pace.</p>
<p>Nor is there much chance the situation will be any better in 1998, when economists expect the British economy to start slowing down.</p>
<p>This is because whichever political party wins the May 1 election will be forced to raise official interest rates -- now at six percent -- to subdue inflation. In contrast, continental European economic growth should be just starting to show signs of life.</p>
<p>It is difficult to see how a single monetary policy -- a pre-requisite of monetary union -- could reconcile the demands of such diverse economic circumstances. The danger is that the needs of Britain, as the smaller economy, would be sacrificed to those of the rest of the European bloc.</p>
<p>BRITAIN'S PAINFUL EURO-CURRENCY PAST</p>
<p>Britain's past flirtations with a Eurocentric monetary policy have ended in acrimonious divorce for precisely that reason.</p>
<p>&quot;In the 1980s we tracked the Deutschemark and imported too accommodating a monetary policy. In the 1990s we had the opposite problem, when we were forced into too tight a monetary policy,&quot; Taylor said.</p>
<p>Former Conservative finance minister Nigel Lawson's attempt to make sterling adhere to a specific range against the mark meant he failed to raise interest rates in time to prevent the consumer borrowing orgy of the late 1980s.</p>
<p>Later, when the pound joined the precursor to a single currency -- the exchange rate mechanism -- the high interest rates needed across Europe to choke back the German economy after reunification in 1990 suffocated the ailing British economy.</p>
<p>Sterling beat an ignominious retreat from the ERM in September 1992 once financial markets concluded the feebleness of the British economy meant the government could not keep interest rates high enough for the pound to stay within a required 6.0 percent band around its 2.95 mark central rate.</p>
<p>Sterling's ejection from the ERM, accompanied by a 10 percent devaluation of the pound, boosted international competitiveness of British goods at a fell swoop. Surging export orders led the economy out of recession.</p>
<p>Ironically the ERM might have delivered pan-European economic synchronisation if Britain could have weathered the September 1992 onslaught.</p>
<p>&quot;Had sterling not left, we might have been forced into the European cycle,&quot; said Yamaichi chief economist John Shepperd.</p>
<p>&quot;As it was we shrugged off the downturn in Europe and were locked into the U.S. cycle rather than the European.&quot;</p>
<p>NO CONVERGENCE WITHOUT MORE SUFFERING</p>
<p>Financial experts say there is almost no chance of the British economic cycle moving spontaneously into kilter with that of Europe, and the political stomach to manufacture this is vanishing.</p>
<p>&quot;Convergence simply isn't going to happen unless you are going to be very brutal,&quot; said Ruth Lea, head of the policy unit at the Institute of Directors and an outspoken critic of the concept of EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;You would have to keep the economy in pseudo-recession for at least two years until the European economy catches up. We would have to adjust to higher unemployment,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;It knocks it completely off the agenda.&quot;</p>
<p>With the May 1 election looming, neither the Conservative government nor the opposition Labour Party -- which is widely expected to sweep to power -- can afford anything which might damage their popularity.</p>
<p>Many Conservatives blame the ERM debacle for the party's historically low poll ratings. Both parties are making increasingly anti-European comments, seeing this as a way of boosting votes.</p>
<p>Labour leader Tony Blair, who is expected to be the next prime minister, said on Tuesday that there were formidable objections to any British bid to join EMU on its expected start date of 1999.</p>
<p>BRITAIN HAS COMPANION IN U.S.</p>
<p>Although the British economy is the odd one out in Europe, it does have a companion in the United States -- U.S. interest rates are moving up now just as British rates are expected to rise and the pound's recent appreciation to more than 2.70 marks has followed a rise in the dollar.</p>
<p>Britain's link with the United States is based on the large proportion of British dollar-related trade, high market capitalisation and the deregulated nature of the economy.</p>
<p>But the bond, which is unique in Europe, is another factor standing in the way of a happy British experience in a single Euro currency.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a much higher proportion of our trade with the U.S. than the rest of Europe does. If the Euro appreciates by 13 or 14 percent against the dollar, it hits us disproportionately harder,&quot; Lea said.</p>
<p>Yamaichi's Shepperd issued a similar warning.</p>
<p>&quot;If the UK economy tracks the U.S. economy rather than the European, and if the currency moves in line with the U.S. dollar rather than European currencies, then there is a structural problem in forcing the UK into a European straitjacket&quot;.</p>
<p>But non-participation in EMU is also fraught with danger because most of Britain's trade is with the EU.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of our geographical location we have to be aligned with Europe, that trades off into late entry,&quot; Shepperd said.</p>
<p>PREMATURE BRITISH EMU MOVE COULD JEOPARDISE EURO</p>
<p>Premature British membership of EMU poses huge risks for the system as a whole as well as the domestic economy.</p>
<p>Trying to force a square British pound into a round Euro hole could tear EMU apart just as sterling's rout foreshadowed the demise of the ERM itself a year later. The pound still shows no sign of establishing a natural, stable rate against the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;In the end, I believe that Europe will get monetary union and that -- if properly managed it will prove a great boon,&quot; Barclays' Taylor told businesses in a speech last week.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time we should recognise that the formation of a monetary union is extremely risky, and that a bad one will blow Europe apart.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
