<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="486429" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: FEATURE - Cyprus bourse hopes for better year.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Cyprus bourse hopes for better year.</headline>
<byline>Michele Kambas</byline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Traders and officials of the Cyprus Stock Exchange expect a boost in the second year of operations after a turbulent year for the island, analysts say.</p>
<p>The exchange, which began formal operations in March 1996 after years of unofficial trading supervised by the Cyprus Chamber of Commerce and Industry, had a bumpy ride last year.</p>
<p>With record gains in the first two months of 1996 under the unofficial trading framework, trading volumes fell after the formal opening, and by the end of 1996 stocks of the 41 listed companies had declined by an average 17.75 percent.</p>
<p>A prices correction, liquidity squeeze, political tension, and a troublesome year for tourism, the island's principal money spinner which contributes 21 percent to gross national product, were all blamed for the decline.</p>
<p>&quot;There are better signs coming in this year,&quot; said Stavros Agrotis, a senior trader with CISCO, the Cyprus Investment and Securities Corporation.</p>
<p>&quot;There are expectations of a better tourism year, the interest rates, even the rain, all put together makes a better climate,&quot; he explained, making a reference to increased water supplies for the drought-stricken tourist industry.</p>
<p>Bourse chairman Dinos Papadopoulos is satisfied the bourse achieved what it set out to do -- install an official framework, enforce it and make sure everyone abides by the rules.</p>
<p>&quot;We should not forget that the (exchange) started out on a zero base,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;There was nothing but the legal framework...in the first year things worked extremely satisfactorily for us.&quot;</p>
<p>BAD TIMING?</p>
<p>But last year was a bit of an &quot;annus horribilis&quot; for Cyprus. It saw tourism arrivals drop, with unofficial estimates putting the decline anywhere between four and six percent. There was violence along the ceasefire line dividing the Greek and Turkish sides of the island since 1974, and to cap it all, an earthquake.</p>
<p>And it did not start 1997 on the right foot either. Disclosures that the Greek Cypriots were buying anti-aircraft missiles from Russia, Turkish threats to use military force to block missile deployment, and a protracted drought further depressed sentiment.</p>
<p>&quot;Two months ago I was searching around for something positive to say about the exchange and I couldn't find anything,&quot; one broker said wryly.</p>
<p>&quot;Life goes on regardless. We have short memories.&quot;</p>
<p>Now tourism is looking up, the climate on the political front appears significantly improved, interest rates have fallen which could encourage a switch to equities and the central bank has taken significant steps in encouraging foreign investment -- in some cases total ownership of Cyprus-based businesses.</p>
<p>And the weather has taken a turn for the worse, or better, if you are a Cypriot.</p>
<p>LOOKING TO A BETTER FUTURE</p>
<p>The bourse is pressing ahead with its target of full paperless trading in the next 15 months. The existing T+9 settlement requirement, under which transactions must be completed within nine working days of a deal, will remain in place until computerisation is completed.</p>
<p>Trading is still in open outcry, but it will give way to an automated electronic screen-based system.</p>
<p>The exchange is currently preparing to move the floor from a building owned by the Cyprus Chamber of Commerce and Industry to another building in the business district of the capital Nicosia.</p>
<p>The move should be completed by mid-May, said Papadopoulos.</p>
<p>In late March parliament approved a long-awaited mergers and acquisitions bill which guarantees equal treatment for all shareholders in bid situations.</p>
<p>&quot;It is sound legislation based on European Union directives and gives a feeling of fair treatment to investors,&quot; said Papadopoulos.</p>
<p>&quot;The insider trading bill will also do its own good in creating a fair environment and we hope this will be approved as soon as possible,&quot; he added, referring to legislation making insider trading a criminal offence.</p>
<p>Draft legislation has been pending in parliament since April 1995.</p>
<p>NEW LISTINGS ARE EXPECTED</p>
<p>The CSE currently trades 91 securities and expects to list government debt paper by mid-April. It has a daily volatility limit of 15 percent.</p>
<p>Market capitalisation was 1.06 billion pounds at the end of February ($2.11 billion) compared with 1.04 billion at the end of January, showing a rise of 1.94 percent.</p>
<p>Nicos Severis, an economist and chairman of Sigma-Severis and Athienitis Securities in Nicosia, sees an upward trend on the market in the next few months.</p>
<p>&quot;New liquidity is being injected,&quot; he said. &quot;We are definitely seeing inquiries (from foreigners) and we expect some interest.&quot;</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry is currently working on changes to taxation laws which could encourage the listing of more Cypriot companies. The changes could be announced in early April.</p>
<p>The CSE is planning a promotional roadshow in Greece in May.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a friendly environment for the Cypriots and interest has been shown there in the exchange&quot; explained Papadopoulos.</p>
<p>&quot;We shall take things from there.&quot;</p>
<p>($1 = 0.501 pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
