<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="486566" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GM March sales up 4.2 percent, other results mixed.</title>
<headline>GM March sales up 4.2 percent, other results mixed.</headline>
<byline>David Lawder</byline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Motors Corp., ending 10 consecutive monthly sales declines, said Wednesday its March U.S. car and truck sales rose 4.2 percent over weak year-ago results that were dragged down by a costly strike.</p>
<p>The world's largest automaker said it sold 432,805 vehicles in the United States during March, compared with 415,328 a year earlier, an increase that analysts said showed some promise for GM's new car models.</p>
<p>&quot;There seems to be a small recovery going on in their market share, if you look out the contribution of their new models,&quot; said Burnham Securities analyst David Healy. &quot;Their new models are helping.&quot;</p>
<p>The gains were led by GM's truck sales, which rose 9.2 percent over March 1996 to 190,445 units. GM's car sales, which exclude results from Saab Automobile AB, increased 0.6 percent to 242,359.</p>
<p>March was turning out to be a mixed bag for automakers, as Nissan Motor Co. Ltd., reported an 18.8 percent U.S. sales increase to 90,356 vehicles that was attributable to strong truck and imported car sales.</p>
<p>Mazda Motor Corp. reported a 23.2 percent decline for the month to 21,257 units, but several German automakers made impressive gains, including Volkswagen's Audi AG, which sold 2,863 cars in its best March since 1986, a 28.4 percent increase.</p>
<p>Mercedes-Benz AG topped that with a 30.4 percent increase to 9,642 cars, while Bayerische Motoren-Werke AG weighed in with a 40.6 percent increase to 11,578.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Chrysler Corp.  reported a 3.4 percent sales decline, while Honda Motor Co. Ltd reported a 6.6 percent sales drop. Ford Motor Co.  and Toyota Motor Corp are scheduled to report their sales on Thursday, and analysts expect a 3 percent decline from Ford and strong gains from Toyota.</p>
<p>Despite the disparities, analysts expect industry totals for March to reach a healthy annualized rate of 15 million to 15.5 million units, indicating a steady market.</p>
<p>GM's March 1996 sales were affected by a brake plant strike that paralyzed most of GM's North American production, significantly reducing the availability of GM truck models.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, GM spokesman Dean Rotondo said the automaker's March 1997 sales would have been up slightly even with normal production in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Truck sales would have been up about 1.5 percent over last year, he said, while car sales would still have been up about 0.6 percent, since the strike had little effect on car availability.</p>
<p>&quot;March sales continue a trend of outstanding performance by our new-for-'97 cars and trucks,&quot; GM North American marketing Vice President Ronald Zarrella said in a statement. &quot;Clearly, we see the pattern of sales increases, share gains and improved retail sales continuing as more of these new products hit the market.&quot;</p>
<p>GM is estimating that it will capture about 32 percent of the overall U.S. car and light truck market in March, compared with just over 30 percent in the first two months of 1997.</p>
<p>Among GM divisions, only Chevrolet, Pontiac and GMC posted overall sales increases. Buick, Cadillac, Oldsmobile and Saturn showed declines, as did Saab, which is half-owned by GM and Sweden's AB Investor   .</p>
<p>GM's all-new lineup of minivans sold considerably better than their plastic-bodied predecessors, with combined sales up 61.4 percent.</p>
<p>Sales of GM's Chevrolet full-size pickups were up 12.2 percent, while sales of its S-10 pickups were up 17.7 percent. Both vehicles were severely affected by last year's strike.</p>
<p>GM stock closed off 75 cents at $54.375 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
