<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="486536" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian rupiah volatile on succession issue.</title>
<headline>Indonesian rupiah volatile on succession issue.</headline>
<byline>Ian MacKenzie</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's rupiah, hit this week by renewed speculation about President Suharto's health, is likely to remain volatile until the question of his successor is settled, economists said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The rupiah plunged in London and New York on Wednesday on a media report that Suharto, 75, one of the world's longest-serving rulers, was suffering from a minor heart ailment.</p>
<p>The currency slid to 2420 to the dollar before recovering on Thursday to around 2,403.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Ali Alatas said after meeting Suharto on Thursday that rumours about the president's health were not true. &quot;You can see yourself the president is performing his full duties,&quot; he told reporters at the presidential palace.</p>
<p>Suharto came to power 30 years ago and is the architect of Indonesia's economic success.</p>
<p>But economic analysts said that when the president sneezed, the rupiah caught a chill.</p>
<p>&quot;There are definite worries over the succession issue. I think that is the major concern,&quot; a senior banker said.</p>
<p>The local currency has reacted over the past year to intermittent rumours on Suharto's health, and also to several riots in the country. It took a major plunge against the dollar in July last year before the president flew to Germany for medical checks which gave him a clean bill of health.</p>
<p>Economists said a lot of overseas money had poured into Indonesia in recent weeks, particularly after the recent battering in Thailand's economy.</p>
<p>&quot;A certain portion of that money is of a fairly limited tenure for short term speculation, primarily from speculative hedge funds,&quot; Nicholas Evans, head of treasury at American Express Bank Ltd in Jakarta, told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the overseas reaction to the rumour on Suharto's health &quot;shows how much or how little is needed to get that short-term money back out&quot;.</p>
<p>Suharto is widely expected to run for a seventh term as president in a March 1998 election ifollowing general polls due next May 29.</p>
<p>He said earlier this week that people wishing to nominate him should take into account that he would be 77 next year. But political analysts dismissed the idea he would not run.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no second thoughts about going for another term,&quot; a diplomat quoted well-placed Indonesians as saying.</p>
<p>But the question of the vice-presidential candidate is the key political issue, analysts say. Given Suharto's age, the next vice-president could move into the presidential seat.</p>
<p>Suharto himself, however, has given no indication of who he might favour, either for the vice-presidency or as successor. A number of names have come up, but no favourite has emerged.</p>
<p>The present vice-president, Try Sutrisno, has won high marks during his incumbency, but Suharto has so far never allowed his number two a second term of office. Thus the uncertainty is likely to continue for some months at least.</p>
<p>&quot;The political issue really is the key risk in Indonesia. Taking the economy as a whole, things are actually looking good,&quot; said Desmond Supple, head of research for Asian currencies at BZW Barclays in Singapore.</p>
<p>He said there was a potential vacuum post-Suharto and the political risk climate remained &quot;extremely worrying&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;No matter what improvements we get in economic fundamentals, until the issue of the succession is addressed you are still going to have the rupiah subjected to periodic bouts of weakness because of political concerns,&quot; Supple said.</p>
<p>But he added that despite the political factor, the rupiah still looked attractive.</p>
<p>&quot;The yield is very attractive, the economy itself is performing well, it's a good buy...but you can never take your eye off the political issues,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The central Bank Indonesia has been depreciating the rupiah against the dollar at a steadily managed rate of about two-to-three rupiah a week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
