<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="486592" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIAN MILITANTS TURN IRE ON SOCCER CHIEFS.</title>
<headline>BULGARIAN MILITANTS TURN IRE ON SOCCER CHIEFS.</headline>
<byline>Thalia Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>DUPNITSA, Bulgaria 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The most implacable protesters in the campaign which toppled Bulgaria's Socialist government have turned their attention to the soccer union, which they say is another hangover from the communist past.</p>
<p>At the height of the January protests, the people of Dupnitsa kept up a week-long round the clock blockade of the main road south from Sofia to the Greek border.</p>
<p>Now they threaten to go back on the barricades unless the football chiefs are replaced.</p>
<p>Dupnitsa's maverick mayor, who brought some 300 people to Sofia in buses on Thursday to protest outside the Football Union headquarters, wants a referendum of fans on whether they will let President Petar Stoyanov appoint new directors.</p>
<p>Mayor Pancho Panayotov said on Friday that if his demands for a new football union management were not met, he would organise a blockade of the railway line on Thursday night.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to make it clear that we are not against the president or the interim government but this communist organisation, the football union,&quot; he said, adding that they had chosen a time which would keep disruption to a minimum.</p>
<p>The head of the Bulgarian Football Union is Ivan Slavkov, son in law of former communist leader Todor Zhivkov.</p>
<p>If the campaign succeeds, it could bring back Bulgarian star striker Hristo Stoichkov to the national side for the remaining World Cup qualifying matches. He has vowed not to play for Bulgaria unless the present football chiefs go.</p>
<p>Panayotov and Thursday's protesters complained that the union did nothing to stop the practice of bribing referees.</p>
<p>&quot;We managed to topple a government, so the football union is a much easier task,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;Now that Stoyanov and the caretaker government have started to work in a transparent way, I think other institutions should do the same.&quot;</p>
<p>The ex-communist Socialists won parliamentary elections in 1994 but their support evaporated as the economy collapsed.</p>
<p>A swing to the Union of Democratic Forces (UDF) began with Stoyanov's election last November, and street protests began in January when the Socialists insisted on trying to form a new cabinet after Zhan Videnov resigned as prime minister.</p>
<p>Panayotov is running for the UDF in Dupnitsa and is certain to be elected.</p>
<p>Signs in UDF blue on the main road announce &quot;Dupnitsa: independent town&quot; and while support for the soccer campaign is limited to fans of Dupnitsa's third division Marek club, many people are proud of their contribution to the January protests.</p>
<p>&quot;The entire town was on the barricades, old people, families with children, everyone,&quot; said Annie, owner of Annie's Cafe in Dupnitsa's main street.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the spirit of the town. If the new government doesn't make things better we'll go out there again.&quot;</p>
<p>One of her clients, Boris Atanasov, said there were already signs of economic recovery under the interim cabinet appointed by Stoyanov and he hoped to reopen his own cafe, which he was forced to close in January as the lev currency collapsed.</p>
<p>Local Socialist leader Valery Starchilov, whose party office still bravely flies a faded red flag though no one in Dupnitsa will admit to knowing where it is, said there had been an element of manipulation.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of gypsies in this area who have been hard hit by the crisis and are ready to follow any politician who will offer them bread and slogans,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he said he was relieved on February 4 when Stoyanov persuaded the Socialist party leaders to give up trying to form a new government and agree to early elections on April 19.</p>
<p>&quot;It's high time Bulgarian politicians from all parties decided that consensus is needed to solve the crisis as no one party can get the country out of this mess,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUPNITSA, Bulgaria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
