<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48666" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-ALOU'S TWO-RUN SHOT TAKES EXPOS PAST CUBS.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-ALOU'S TWO-RUN SHOT TAKES EXPOS PAST CUBS.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moises Alou's two-run homer in the eighth inning lifted the Montreal Expos to a 2-1 victory over the Chicago Cubs, salvaging the final game of a three-game series on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Montreal pulled within 1-1/2 games of the Los Angeles Dodgers and San Diego Padres for the National League wild-card berth.</p>
<p>With the Cubs trailing 1-0 in the eighth, David Segui drew a one-out walk from Terry Adams (2-6) and Alou hit the ball over the left-centre field fence four pitches later for his 19th homer.</p>
<p>At Colorado, Ellis Burks and Steve Decker had two-run singles in a five-run third inning, and Andres Galarraga added his league-leading 43rd home run as the Colorado Rockies held off the Atlanta Braves 6-5 for their fourth straight win.</p>
<p>The Rockies broke the game open with five runs in the third off starter Denny Neagle (14-8).</p>
<p>Wright (4-2) allowed three runs and six hits over seven innings. He walked five.</p>
<p>In Houston, Mickey Morandini had four hits, including an RBI double that snapped a tie and sparked a four-run fourth inning, as the Philadelphia Phillies outslugged the Houston Astros 10-8.</p>
<p>The Astros remained 2-1/2 games behind first-place St. Louis in the National League Central. Houston, which has lost seven of 10, fell 4 1/2 games back in the race for the NL wild-card berth.</p>
<p>Morandini, Kevin Stocker and Jon Zuber each had two doubles for the Phillies, who won for just the sixth time in 17 games.</p>
<p>In Los Angeles, Ismael Valdes allowed two runs over seven innings and Mark Guthrie pitched out of a jam in the eighth as the Los Angeles Dodgers completed a three-game sweep of the Cincinnati Reds with a 3-2 victory.</p>
<p>Valdes (13-7) allowed five hits, walked three and struck out eight before tiring in the eighth. Guthrie relieved with runners at second and third and none out and protected the one-run lead by stranding both men.</p>
<p>In New York, Lance Johnson had three hits and drove in a run to back Jason Isringhausen, who threw 6-2/3 scoreless innings and helped the New York Mets to a 3-1 win over the Florida Marlins.</p>
<p>The 204 hits by Johnson, who went 3-for-4 and is hitting .333, are the most in the National League since Tony Gwynn had 218 in 1987 for the San Diego Padres. It was his 19th three-hit game of the season.</p>
<p>In San Francisco, Barry Bonds' second homer of the game, a two-run shot in the bottom of the eighth inning, lifted the San Francisco Giants to a 4-2 victory over the St. Louis Cardinals and avoided a three-game sweep.</p>
<p>Bill Mueller walked on a 3-2 pitch from Alan Benes (13-9) to open the Giants' eighth before Bonds lined a 3-2 pitch over the right-field fence for his 39th homer.  It was his third multi-homer game of the season and 30th of his career.</p>
<p>&quot;It's nice they had to pitch to me in those situations,&quot; Bonds said.  &quot;I thought Benes might go around me on the 3-2, but he threw a pitch that was a little up and I was able to handle it. I thought he'd walk me, he didn't, they lose.&quot;</p>
<p>In San Diego, Chris Gomez singled home Greg Vaughn with two outs in the bottom of the ninth inning, lifting the San Diego Padres to an 8-7 victory over the Pittsburgh Pirates.</p>
<p>San Diego, which is tied with Los Angeles for first place in the NL West, has won four in a row overall and nine of 10 at home.</p>
<p>Ken Caminiti's 34th home run, his second of the game, in the seventh off reliever Matt Ruebel brought the Padres within 7-6.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
