<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="486634" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: TENNIS-AUSTRALIA TAKE CHARGE OVER CZECHS IN DAVIS CUP.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-AUSTRALIA TAKE CHARGE OVER CZECHS IN DAVIS CUP.</headline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia took a commanding 2-0 lead over the Czech Republic in their Davis Cup quarter-final tie on Friday after the Czechs lost a player due to illness.</p>
<p>Pat Rafter and Mark Philippoussis both won in four sets against lower-ranked opponents in the opening round of singles on the grass centre court at Memorial Drive.</p>
<p>With world number one pairing of Todd Woodbridge and Mark Woodforde to contest the doubles rubber on Saturday, Australia looked set to secure a winning 3-0 lead and a semifinal meeting with either the United States or the Netherlands.</p>
<p>The Czechs, already weakened by the absence of four top players, suffered a setback before the start of play on Friday when Jiri Novak was forced to withdraw from his singles clash with Philippoussis because of a virus.</p>
<p>His late replacement, lowly-ranked left-hander David Rikl, proved no match for the big-serving Philippoussis and was beaten 6-1 6-4 2-6 6-4 in a match lasting one hour and 47 minutes.</p>
<p>Rafter earlier claimed the opening rubber by beating Martin Damm 6-1 7-6 (9-7) 4-6 6-4 in another lop-sided contest that occupied a near-capacity crowd for two hours and 41 minutes.</p>
<p>The Czech Republic's campaign has been hit by the refusal of Petr Korda, Daniel Vacek, Bohdan Ulihrach and Slava Dosedel to play in the tie.</p>
<p>Novak, ranked 60 in the world, complained of a high temperature on Friday and was ruled out on medical advice.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like an influenza virus. He wanted to play but physically he was not able to,&quot; Dr Andrew Potter told reporters. &quot;It may take two or three days for him to recover.&quot;</p>
<p>Rikl, ranked 179, was scheduled to sit out Friday's matches before partnering Pavel Vizner in an unproven combination in the doubles but Novak's sudden illness upset the team's plans.</p>
<p>It was not clear whether Rikl or Damm would back up Vizner in Saturday's doubles.</p>
<p>Rafter, the world number 43, took advantage of his greater experience on grass to dominate an opponent who is ranked one place below him.</p>
<p>Damm gradually settled into the match but his failure to convert a set point during the second set tie-break eventually proved decisive.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a fantastic feeling to win in a Davis Cup rubber at home. I started really well in the first and second sets but then Martin started putting some more pressure on me,&quot; Rafter said afterwards.</p>
<p>Philippoussis cruised to victory against Rikl although the powerful Australian showed only glimpses of the form that took him to victory in the Arizona ATP tournament last month. A brief lapse of concentration in the third set was quickly overcome.</p>
<p>Boasting the fastest serve in the world and a world ranking of 24, Philippoussis served 15 aces to subdue his left-handed opponent. Rikl was making his Davis Cup debut.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
