<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="486625" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: DARTS-PUB GAME TARGETS THE TOWNSHIPS.</title>
<headline>DARTS-PUB GAME TARGETS THE TOWNSHIPS.</headline>
<byline>Andy Colquhoun</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The idea of the likes of Eric Bristow and Jocky Wilson taking their ample frames and darts expertise into South Africa's townships may be bizarre but it could be about to come to pass.</p>
<p>The former world darts champions are being encouraged to abandon their fans in the smoke-filled public bars of Britain and instead become icons for would-be darts players in the townships of South Africa.</p>
<p>In a country where sports &quot;development&quot; is a hot political topic, the unified darts authority -- Darts South Africa (DSA) -- are launching their own development initiative. And they are already negotiating to bring British stars to the Republic's dusty, ramshackle townships.</p>
<p>Mervyn Johnson, general secretary of DSA, said: &quot;The image of the game is undergoing a change, not just in South Africa but worldwide, taking it away from the stigma of being associated with liquor.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe darts could be a way of helping combat the crime and drug problems we have in our communities.&quot;</p>
<p>While higher profile sports such as cricket and rugby are under pressure to take their sport to all sections of the community, darts can already claim to be some way along the road.</p>
<p>It is already a popular sport among South Africa's coloured community whose organising body, the South African Darts Board of Control (SADBOC) united with the white South African Darts Association (SADA), to form DSA.</p>
<p>Its leader Johnson has a missionary's zeal to spread the game throughout his country as well as the rest of Africa and is launching a pilot development scheme in the coloured Cape Town suburb of Retreat.</p>
<p>&quot;We are aiming at children between the ages of 13 and 18,&quot; he said. &quot;We want to fit in with the sports policy of South Africa which is to spread sport across the nation irrespective of the so-called racial classifications.&quot;</p>
<p>DSA are also the driving force behind plans to create the first African Darts Council. Delegates from all over the continent met in Johannesburg last week to discuss the plan.</p>
<p>The sport has 30,000 organised players in South Africa and is played at national representative level in Botswana, Lesotho, Malawi, Namibia, Swaziland, Zambia, Zimbabwe, Kenya, Seychelles and Uganda.</p>
<p>Johnson hopes to establish an African Cup, have darts included as a sport in the African Games and launch African players on to the world stage.</p>
<p>As the excitable TV darts commentator Sid Waddell once famously said: &quot;There may be Shakespeare on the other channel but there's real drama here.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
