<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="486657" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-MCCARRON IN THREE-WAY TIE FOR FREEPORT-MCDERMOTT LEAD.</title>
<headline>GOLF-MCCARRON IN THREE-WAY TIE FOR FREEPORT-MCDERMOTT LEAD.</headline>
<dateline>NEW ORLEANS 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scott McCarron began defence of his Freeport-McDermott Classic title exactly as he hoped, by grabbing a share of the first-round lead with a seven-under-par 65 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Sharing the top of the leaderboard after equalling McCarron's 65 on the English Turn Golf Club layout were Larry Rinker and David Toms.</p>
<p>Hideki Kase, a 14-year veteran of the Japanese tour playing his first year on the U.S. PGA Tour, was a stroke off the lead with a 66.</p>
<p>Australian star Greg Norman, a three-time runner-up here, was two strokes off the pace at 67 as he began his final tune-up for next week's Masters. Tied with Norman at 67 was qualifying school graduate Larry Silveira.</p>
<p>McCarron arrived at English Turn eager to get off to a good start in defence of his first PGA Tour title. He was also anxious to try out a new weapon -- Biggest Big Bertha, a 46-inch titanium driver he just acquired.</p>
<p>&quot;It got me excited to come out here and play because I had a new toy,&quot; McCarron said.</p>
<p>McCarron is one of 20 players in the field using this event as a warm-up for the year's first major championship. That number was down from 22 after Seve Ballesteros withdrew Wednesday with a bad cold and Sam Torrance pulled out Thursday suffering from tendinitis.</p>
<p>McCarron earned the last 1996 Masters invitation when he beat Tommy Tolles and Tom Watson here. He secured his 1997 Masters berth by finishing 10th at Augusta last year.</p>
<p>Of the 20 players who broke 70 in the first round, however, only four are already in the Masters field.</p>
<p>The other 16 are vying for a victory Sunday that will bring a ticket to Augusta. Prominent among those hoping to win that final Masters spot are Payne Stewart and Lanny Wadkins, who each shot 69.</p>
<p>The players here seem to agree that this event makes for a fine Masters preparation.</p>
<p>&quot;Of all the tournaments we could possibly play (ahead of the Masters), this is by far the best,&quot; said Billy Mayfair, who carded a 68.</p>
<p>&quot;The greens here are fast and in perfect condition,&quot; said Norman, who is hoping to erase the memory of his staggering final-round collapse at Augusta last year.</p>
<p>&quot;It's also a second shot golf course that requires precise positioning with your irons, which are the skills you need for Augusta,&quot; Norman said.</p>
<p>Norman was encouraged by improved putting Thursday with his score 12 strokes better than his final round last week at the Players Championship.</p>
<p>&quot;I still need to do a little more work, but last week I made none, today I made five, and maybe next week I'll make all the putts,&quot; Norman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW ORLEANS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
