<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48671" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BOXING-FOREMAN USES &quot;INTEGRITY&quot; TO HYPE A FIGHT.</title>
<headline>BOXING-FOREMAN USES &quot;INTEGRITY&quot; TO HYPE A FIGHT.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON, Texas 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>George Foreman, one of the greatest self-promoters in sports, pounced on the debacle of the Mike Tyson-Bruce Seldon fight last weekend to hype his next bout against a former kick-boxer in Tokyo.</p>
<p>The punching preacher insisted like a broken record that his fight against someone named Crawford Grimsley November 9 in Tokyo would help restore integrity to boxing.</p>
<p>But he apparently forgot to tell Grimsley, whom it seems would have difficulty spelling integrity.</p>
<p>Foreman ranted and raved about Tyson stopping Seldon at one minute, 49 seconds of the first round after some dubious punches, one of which appeared to have existed only in Seldon's imagination.</p>
<p>Foreman, 48, said he will fight Grimsley for the little-known and little-respected World Boxing Union heavyweight title.</p>
<p>Grimsley at first insisted he was 29 years old. When confronted with a newspaper article reporting he was born in 1961, he still insisted on his age. But then said he definitely was not born in 1961.</p>
<p>Only when pressed did he finally admit he was 34.</p>
<p>The reason he lied on Foreman's integrity show?</p>
<p>&quot;I told everybody I was 29 is to avoid these type of questions,&quot; Grimsley said. &quot;Age is a perception of the public. I perceive myself as a very young 34.&quot;</p>
<p>But Foreman, who said it was okay if anyone wanted to say he was 34, said, &quot;if there's gonna be integrity in boxing it depends on me.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a fight for integrity. Win, lose or draw I'm gonna leave some integrity. People are gonna say you gotta be a man to get into boxing.&quot;</p>
<p>The former heavyweight champion of the world took shots at all four of the opponents Tyson has faced since his parole from prison in March, 1995, after serving three years on a rape conviction.</p>
<p>&quot;I know why I can't get a fight with Mike Tyson,&quot; Foreman said.</p>
<p>&quot;They want someone to fall down -- the other fellow made the sign of the cross so much they thought it was a funeral, the guy from England,&quot; said Foreman, referring to Frank Bruno, who repeatedly crossed himself as he was entering the MGM Grand Arena last March to fight Tyson.</p>
<p>Bruno offered little resistance to Tyson, opting to throw futile punches and then hug him, until Tyson finally avoided his clutches and stopped him in the third round to win the World Boxing Council title.</p>
<p>&quot;A big old boy like that boy from England afraid of Tyson,&quot; Foreman said. &quot;These guys have disgraced my beloved sport ... They don't even say 'I'm sorry about it.'&quot;</p>
<p>Referring to Seldon falling down from a phantom punch and going on to lose his World Boxing Association title, Foreman said: &quot;If someone were to fall because of a scraped elbow, I'm gonna fall and fight him on the canvas.</p>
<p>&quot;I guarantee no young people gonna see someone swing and fall down without being hit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Foreman said he would tell Tyson to his face that &quot;he should call a halt to (fighting inferior fighters). If you want to be champ of the world and you fight like that you gotta get outta there.</p>
<p>&quot;These guys don't care. I'd tell him in the room right now, 'grow up, be a man. Stop acting like a sissy,'&quot; Foreman said.</p>
<p>Foreman said he plans to fight in Tokyo and somewhere in Europe and then in Houston. He did not name any of his projected opponents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
