<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="486967" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wall Street stock outlook turns murky.</title>
<headline>Wall Street stock outlook turns murky.</headline>
<byline>Cal Mankowski</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The outlook for Wall Street stocks has grown difficult to decipher, with analysts trying to figure how much higher interest rates will climb, how corporate profits will fare and whether ordinary Americans will turn more cautious with their retirement accounts.</p>
<p>The Dow industrials rose 49 points, or about 0.75 percent, to 6526 Friday afternoon. Since making an all-time closing high of 7085.16 March 11, the Dow has fallen 560 points or 7.9 percent. The Nasdaq composite index closed up about 23 points on Friday to about 1237.  </p>
<p>&quot;Some people may take advantage of the weakness to buy in,&quot; said Smith Barney strategist Marshall Acuff, noting that investors are well aware that since the crash of 1987 it has just been a matter of time before stocks resumed the upward path.</p>
<p>The trigger for the 1997 slump has been the Federal Reserve's March 25 increase in short-term interest rates to 5.50 percent from 5.25 percent. The Fed's move has been interpreted as a pre-emptive move to keep inflation from surfacing in a stronger-than-expected economy.  </p>
<p>In 1994, the Fed began moving short term rates up in a series of steps and the U.S. stock market was essentially flat that year. Acuff said a key difference between now and 1994 is the rate of growth in corporate profits.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1994 profits were up over 20 percent and in 1995 they were just shy of 20 percent,&quot; said Acuff. &quot;I don't think we're going to see profits up more than a couple percent this year and they may be flat next year.&quot;  </p>
<p>A trader on the desk of a mid-sized asset management firm said there seems to be more than the usual amount of uncertainty in the market. For example she said with stocks in a sharp retreat early Friday after the March payroll report, there were widely different interpretatons of what the figures meant. The jobless rate slipped to 5.2 percent from 5.3 percent and hourly wages rose. Non-farm payrolls rose by 175,000, slightly less than the average forecast.  </p>
<p>The trader said something else that is difficult to gauge is how the millions of Americans who have been increasingly socking their retirement savings into mutual funds will react when they get first-quarter statements in a few weeks and see negative returns. &quot;There is a lot of anecdotal evidence of poeple saying this presents a buying opportunity, but what people say and what they do can be very different,&quot; the trader said.  </p>
<p>She said the approach at her firm, a value-oriented manager, has been to keep a relatively high level of cash and stick with, but not add to holdings that it likes including money center banks and real estate investment trusts.</p>
<p>Sam Stovall, sector strategist at Standard &amp; Poor's Corp, said research shows that &quot;defensive&quot; plays are probably the best way to go right now although that often means that an investor buys stocks that then have a smaller decline than the overall market.  </p>
<p>Stovall said said investors could find defensive stocks among the beverages, foods, tobaccos, household products and utilities, among others. He said with electric utilities now yielding on average more than six percent, investors could comb through those stocks and pick some with the higher yields. He added that investors should check research reports to see if there is any risk of a dividend being cut. On the other hand, he said, some of the lower-yielding utilities have better growth prospects so a longer-term investor might want to pick from that tier.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't believe the market is going down a whole lot more but the problem is the market is not going up either,&quot; said Peter Canelo, strategist at Dean Witter Reynolds. He said stocks could be bound in a 6400-6800 trading range on the Dow for some time. &quot;The interest rate clouds have to clear up,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The declines he has studied last an average of 11 months, Stovall said. Although he did not predict the length of the current decline, he did say that two or three more increases in short term rates may be in the offing.  </p>
<p>Acuff, who emphasizes that the current pullback is not the end of the long-term bull market, said the current investment climate is &quot;a time to reconsider one's portfolio, and think in terms of trying to build as much quality and strength into the portfolio taking advantage of the volatility that we will likely continue to see.&quot;</p>
<p>He cited the drugs and oil service stocks as areas with good fundamentals. But he said there are a variety of places to look and named four of Smith Barney's buy-rated stocks, specifically Williams Cos Inc, Intel Corp Corp, Pfizer Inc and Citicorp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
