<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="486921" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dry Dairy to expand bread business.</title>
<headline>Dry Dairy to expand bread business.</headline>
<dateline>FORT MYERS, Fla. 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dry Dairy International Inc, a maker of pasta and breads, said on Friday it negotiated agreements that will allow the company to enter the specialty bread business at the supermarket retail level.</p>
<p>Tulip Bakery, a new company subsidiary, agreed to buy the production line for the making of pita bread and sweet bread loaves from Tulip Pita Bread Center II and the distribution rights for Tulip products, Dry Dairy said.</p>
<p>Dry Dairy said it formed NGU Distribution Inc to manage the distribution business.</p>
<p>The agreement to purchase the equipment line calls for the company to pay $165,000 and 1,600,000 shares of its restricted common stock to the owners of equipment line, Dry Dairy said.</p>
<p>In a separate purchase agreement, &quot;Tulip's&quot; distribution rights and delivery system were purchased for 1,200,000 restricted shares and Dry Dairy's assumption of $112,000 of existing Tulip debt, Dry Dairy said.</p>
<p>The company expects to close the transaction and begin booking revenues from the the deals by the end of April 1997. Tulip products are distributed via direct store delivery to approximately 300 supermarkets in Florida with plans to expand into Georgia in 1997, Dry Dairy said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FORT MYERS, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
