<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="486927" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Goldman reshapes units, to phase out J.Aron name.</title>
<headline>Goldman reshapes units, to phase out J.Aron name.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Goldman Sachs said Friday that it will merge three of its divisions into one which will be run by a three-man management team.</p>
<p>As part of the restructuring, the J. Aron trading name will be phased out, Goldman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have essentially consolidated, merged the fixed income divsion, the currency and commodities division into a single operating unit,&quot; said a Goldman spokesman.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a ratification of what's been happening over the past few years as there has been more synergy between the units,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Richard Garonzik and Michael Mortara are currently co-heads of the fixed income division, while Lloyd Blankfein is head of the J. Aron currency and commodities trading unit.</p>
<p>Under the new structure, the three become joint heads of the merged division and Blankfein moves to London, while the other two remain New York-based.</p>
<p>The J. Aron name will remain for certain entities for legal reasons but will be phased out over time, the Goldman spokesman said. Goldman acquired J. Aron, then primarily a commodities trading house, in the early 1980s.</p>
<p>The spokesman said that though there may be a few more changes within the management group of the divisions, &quot;it will not be resulting in layoffs or mass movements of personnel. J. Aron currency and commodities has been performing at a record pace this year.&quot;</p>
<p>--((New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1623))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
