<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487154" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Nairobi bourse index climbs in mixed market.</title>
<headline>Nairobi bourse index climbs in mixed market.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Nairobi Stock Exchange 20-share index gained marginally in Friday trading on modest demand for key shares, bourse officials said.</p>
<p>The index rose 17.79 points to close at 3345.14.</p>
<p>Turnover was posted at 16.686 million shillings on 430,410 shares compared to 22.860 million shillings on 438,270 shares on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're probably going to see more fluctuations, especially if these small purchases remain consistent, because the shares in demand are scarce,&quot; a senior broker said.</p>
<p>Another dealer observed that because demand was for specific shares, the rise in the index could not be seen as a long-term trend.</p>
<p>Publishing group Nation Printers &amp; Publishers gained 8.00 shillings to close at 126.00 on speculative buying in hopes of an expected bonus issue to be released with year-end results.</p>
<p>&quot;For the kind of assets they are carrying, the company is not adequately capitalized,&quot; a financial analyst said.</p>
<p>The group recently completed a printing plant estimated to raise total fixed assets to one billion shillings.</p>
<p>Dealers said that with 11 million shares at a face value of 5.00 shillings, the group was heavily under-capitalized.</p>
<p>Other climbers were Kenya Airways at 8.20 from 8.05, Uchumi Supermarket at 38.00 from 37.00 and Total Kenya at 64.00 from 62.50.</p>
<p>Barclays Bank eased to 99.00 from 100.00 while Standard Chartered Bank closed at 44.75 from 46.00.</p>
<p>Kenya Commercial Bank was unchanged at 95.00 while Kenya Power &amp; Lighting closed unchanged at 120.00.</p>
<p>Brooke Bond lost five shillings to close at 127.00 while Rea Vipingo Plantations was unchanged at 9.00.</p>
<p>--Wambui Chege, Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
