<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487198" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian Duma challenges Yeltsin over arts bill.</title>
<headline>Russian Duma challenges Yeltsin over arts bill.</headline>
<byline>Anatoly Verbin</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Parliament, in a move sure to enrage Germany, on Friday overruled President Boris Yeltsin's veto on a bill asserting Russian ownership of art treasures seized from Nazi Germany during World War Two.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's representative in the communist-dominated State Duma lower house, Alexander Kotenkov, called the law &quot;absurd&quot; and told Interfax news agency the Kremlin would appeal against it to Russia's Constitutional Court.</p>
<p>Germany has demanded the return of the artefacts, which include priceless paintings by French impressionists Monet and Matisse, as well as golden treasures from Heinrich Schliemann's excavations at Troy in the 19th century.</p>
<p>On March 18 Yeltsin vetoed the bill, passed by the Duma two months ago, saying in a letter to the Federation Council upper chamber that the document breached international law.</p>
<p>He also said the draft could damage Russia's position in talks with Germany, France, Poland, Hungary, the Netherlands and Liechtenstein -- countries from which the works of art came.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's foreign affairs adviser, Dmitry Ryurikov, told Interfax Friday's decision by the Duma would complicate Russia's relations with a number of countries.</p>
<p>The head of the German parliament's foreign affairs committee, Karl-Heinz Hornhues, said in a statement that the Duma was using the issue as a stick to beat Yeltsin.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Russian parliament, contrary to all agreements, declares the works of art to be Russian property, it doesn't exactly support the German government's international efforts to present Russia as a reliable partner and friend for the West...,&quot; Hornhues said.</p>
<p>In all 308 deputies in the Duma voted for the motion, just above the 300 votes -- or a two-thirds majority of the house -- needed to override a presidential veto. Fifteen voted against.</p>
<p>The motion now passes to the Federation Council, where a two-thirds majority is also needed to overturn the veto.</p>
<p>If the Council, which also heavily backed the original bill, overrides the veto as well, Yeltsin will have to sign the law, making all art treasures brought to the Soviet Union as a result of World War Two the inalienable property of the Russian state.</p>
<p>Many Russians view the treasures, seized from museums and homes in Nazi Germany, its allies and occupied countries, as compensation for the wartime suffering of the Soviet people and for the many Russian treasures destroyed in the German invasion.</p>
<p>But Yeltsin said the bill did not distinguish between Moscow's wartime enemies, allies and neutral countries, or between various categories of private individuals with rights to claim objects back.</p>
<p>The Duma's move may reflect a growing legal confrontation between Yeltsin and the Duma, which the 66-year-old Kremlin leader has already warned not to risk fighting him.</p>
<p>&quot;They shouldn't attack me too hard because I can hit back,&quot; Yeltsin warned his political foes in February as he was returning to active polical life after eight months of illness.</p>
<p>In a separate move on Friday, Yeltsin rejected over a dozen draft laws approved by parliament.</p>
<p>The Duma has so far failed to take any action against Yeltsin's latest government reshuffle which brought into top cabinet positions youthful reformers, including Anatoly Chubais, public enemy number one for the opposition.</p>
<p>But it has taken a series of decisions lately which will not be welcome to the Kremlin leader.</p>
<p>The most notable of them was on Wednesday. The Duma passed a non-binding resolution which was entitled &quot;Prevent an Act of Vandalism!&quot; and condemned Yeltsin's suggestion that Bolshevik leader Vladimir Lenin's embalmed body could be removed from a mausoleum on Red Square and buried.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
