<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487160" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FORECAST-Loss seen for Sentrachem H1 shr.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Loss seen for Sentrachem H1 shr.</headline>
<byline>Charles Phahlane</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African chemicals firm Sentrachem Ltd's half-year earnings are seen plunging into loss, weighed by its struggling Sanachem unit which recently opted to take once-off charges of 261 million rand on the chin.</p>
<p>Sentrachem issued a profit warning last month in which it said that restructuring at Sanachem would result in a 144 million rand after tax and provisions charge. The money would be used to reduce the firm's product range and cancel registrations of uneconomic products.</p>
<p>It said a further 117 million rand charge would be borne after &quot;unrealistic&quot; forward exchange contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;Results will be bad because of Sanachem...It has been a poor performer so far but that was understandable seeing that they were growing so rapidly,&quot; said an analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Analysts polled by Reuters forecast Sentrachem's loss ranging between 60.0 and 80.0 cents a share with consensus at 68.3 cents for the six months ended February 28, 1997. This compared with a 55 cents profit in the same period last year.</p>
<p>The company was not expected to declare a dividend in the interim period.</p>
<p>But analysts said Sentrachem would claw its way back into profit for the full year with a total recovery envisaged for the next financial year.</p>
<p>&quot;The market, as I understand it, is looking for about 15 to 20 cents (earnings per share) for the whole year, they are not looking for a loss,&quot; another analyst said.</p>
<p>Aside from Sanachem, most of Sentrachem's other businesses were seen performing well.</p>
<p>&quot;The other operations have not been really affected that much by problems from Sanachem. They are performing basically according to the markets where they operate,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>For the full year, dollar-based earner Hampshire Chemical Corporation was seen posting earnings up some 70 percent helped by a weaker rand. NCP was expected to post gains of about 20 percent.</p>
<p>However, Safripol, a joint venture with Hoechst South Africa Ltd, was seen hurt by poor prices for plastics, analysts said.</p>
<p>Following the shock Sanachem announcement, Sentrachem's share price last month plunged to a year low of 720 cents. On Friday the stock was trading at 810 cents, well below a year high of 996 cents posted on January 20 this year.</p>
<p>&quot;I see very little movement (in the price) for at least another six months so that we can become convinced that the problems at Sanachem are being sorted out...that they are once-off and not recurring,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
