<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487133" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GHANA: Ivory Coast streamlines mine permit approvals.</title>
<headline>Ivory Coast streamlines mine permit approvals.</headline>
<byline>Vincent t'Sas</byline>
<dateline>ACCRA 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ivory Coast has set up a National Mining Commission (COMINE) to speed up mining permit approvals and handle environmental impact studies, Ivory Coast's mines minister said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;For investors it is a one-stop contact point grouping together concerned ministries,&quot; Minister of Mines and Energy Mohammed Lamine Fadika told Reuters. &quot;The first files will be handled from Monday.&quot;</p>
<p>Exploration permit requests would be processed in 45 days or less, Fadika said at the sidelines of Oil and Gas Africa 1997, a three day forum in Accra ending on Friday.</p>
<p>COMINE had been loosely modelled on neighbouring Ghana's Mines Commission and would also handle other matters including duty-free imports of equipment, said Fadika.</p>
<p>Mining policy has up until now been handled mainly by the Direction des Mines, with decisions passed up to the Ministry of Mines and Energy.</p>
<p>Gold exploration companies in Ivory Coast welcomed the move.</p>
<p>&quot;Anything that cuts red tape is welcome,&quot; said one exploration geologist based in Abidjan. &quot;They say at the moment permits take six weeks to approve but it is usually longer than that.&quot;</p>
<p>Ivory Coast has only two operating gold mines with a third due to open in 1997. A wave of prospectors have arrived since the introduction of a new mining code in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Ghana (mining sector policy) is far more streamlined so the Mines Commission is a good model,&quot; said the geologist.</p>
<p>Others said customs agents had refused to grant waivers on equipment, despite industry complaints to government officials.</p>
<p>&quot;There are rules on duty-free imports in the (mining) code but when you apply to customs for rebates they just say any items had to be declared at the time of permit approval,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Foreign advisers in Abidjan last week told Reuters Ivorian mine policy management was about to be tightened up after industry complaints about red-tape slowing exploration efforts.</p>
<p>Existing rules and regulations stemming from the Mining Code would not be changed but management procedures would be tightened up, government advisers in Abidjan told Reuters.</p>
<p>About 24 companies, holding over 55 exploration permits are now operating in Ivory Coast, which shares Ghana's Birimian greenstone gold bearing geology.</p>
<p>Ivory Coast produces less than three tonnes of gold a year. Ghana, the regions largest producer, produces around 40 tonnes a year.</p>
<p>Gold exploration in West Africa has picked up sharply in the 1990s.</p>
<p>Prospectors are also busy in Mali, Guinea and Burkina Faso.</p>
<p>-- Matthew Bunce, Abidjan newsroom + 225 21 90 90</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ACCRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GHANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
