<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487140" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Ex-Nigerian oil minister decamps to winning party.</title>
<headline>Ex-Nigerian oil minister decamps to winning party.</headline>
<dateline>ABUJA 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Nigerian oil minister Don Etiebet on Friday quit the political party he has built up since a ban on politics was lifted last year and declared for the one that wants military ruler General Sani Abacha as a presidential candidate.</p>
<p>&quot;It is necessary for me to be seen to be participating in nation building,&quot; Etiebet told a news conference in the capital Abuja. &quot;I have therefore decided and it is my pleasure to declare for the United Nigeria Congress Party (UNCP).&quot;</p>
<p>UNCP says it wants Abacha as its presidential candidate in an election next year to restore democracy and swept a March 15 poll contested by the five political parties registered last year.</p>
<p>Etiebet previously belonged to and was the main financier of the National Centre Party of Nigeria (NCPN), which has been rocked by internal squabbling since the March polls.</p>
<p>He was alledged by opposition newspapers to have been detained by the military authorities immediately after the coucil poll. His news conference was his first public appearance since the election but he declined to answer questions.</p>
<p>&quot;I have reflected very thoughtfully&quot; since the election, he said, adding his decision was in &quot;Nigeria's interest.&quot;</p>
<p>Political analysts said Etiebet, who had made it clear he wanted the presidency, had probably realised it would be difficult to win if Abacha were to contest.</p>
<p>The Nigerian general seized power in the chaos that followed the annulment of a 1993 presidential vote but has not ruled himself out of next year's poll to elect a president.</p>
<p>His aides say several military officers have seized power elsewhere and gone on to win popular mandate through the ballot box.</p>
<p>Etiebet said he believed in Abacha's on-going transition to civil rule programme by which an elected president is due to take over from October 1, 1998.</p>
<p>Most members of the floundering NCPN are now expected to join him in the UNCP, bolstering the party which looks likely to present the next president.</p>
<p>A wealthy businessman, Etiebet was oil minister when Abacha seized power. He was initially retained but dropped in a cabinet shake-up in 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABUJA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
