<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487206" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin sacks top foreign aide.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin sacks top foreign aide.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian leader Boris Yeltsin relieved his long-term top foreign policy aide of his duties on Friday, the Kremlin said, without elaborating on what was behind the move.</p>
<p>&quot;President Boris Yeltsin on Friday issued a decree relieving Dmitry Ryurikov of his duties in connection with his taking up other work,&quot; said a brief statement.</p>
<p>Such phrasing has been used in the past when an official is dismissed, but a Kremlin official declined to give further details.</p>
<p>Russian Public Television said Kremlin spokesman Sergei Yastrzhembsky would coordinate foreign policy in the presidential administration from now on.</p>
<p>The report did not make clear whether Yastrzhemsky, 42, would keep the job as spokesman he has held since Yeltsin's re-election in July.</p>
<p>Yastrzhembsky, who speaks several European languages and has brought a slick touch to the Kremlin, was previously ambassador to Slovakia and head of the Foreign Ministry's press and information department.</p>
<p>Ryurikov, 50, had been Yeltsin's foreign policy aide since the president's election in 1991 and was also made an extraordinary plenipontentiary in 1993.</p>
<p>He kept a low public profile but played a key behind-the-scenes role planning Yeltsin's negotiations over NATO expansion plans, arms control and other controversial post-Cold War issues as well as preparing for summit meetings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
