<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48731" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK needs more export mkts after bumper cereal crop.</title>
<headline>UK needs more export mkts after bumper cereal crop.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain will need more export markets outside the European Union (EU) for its bumper 1996 cereals crop, especially as weather conditions have produced quality variations, a leading grains trader said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Total 1996 cereals output was expected to reach 24.57 million tonnes, the highest since 1986/87 before the introduction of set-aside, said Andrew Barnard, UK arable crop marketing manager for Dalgety Agriculture, at a news conference.</p>
<p>Dalgety Agriculture is the agribusiness arm of Dalgety plc.</p>
<p>&quot;The marketing of this increased crop will now present some major challenges during this year as the trends towards higher yields are reflected across the EU, requiring new third country export destinations to be developed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wheat production would reach 15.90 million tonnes, barley 7.98 million and oats 690,000 tonnes, leaving exportable surpluses of 4.65 million and 2.11 million tonnes respectively.</p>
<p>He said that it was estimated that UK exports would result in the EU getting 2.0 million tonnes of wheat, with 600,000 tonnes going to third countries and 2.05 million tonnes remaining as surplus after exports.</p>
<p>For barley, the EU was expected to take 850,000 tonnes, third countries 350,000 tonnes with the after-export surplus estimated at 910,000 tonnes. Dalgety estimated that the trend of exporting increased tonnages of British wheat and barley outside the EU to third countries would continue from 1995.</p>
<p>But another company official said geographic differences in quality between the autumn and spring crops could also cause marketing problems.</p>
<p>&quot;As our quality is variable, we will have to work hard as a trade to dispose of this crop,&quot; said Trevor Harriman, Dalgety Agriculture's commercial manager. &quot;Unlike last year, it is difficult to see where the surplus will go, without the (European) Commission granting restitutions.&quot; He added that wheat proteins were variable but bushel weights remained high with no screening problems.</p>
<p>This year's barley harvest provided a big variation and was probably a below average year in quality but not in yield.</p>
<p>-- Jeremy Smith, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8064</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
