<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487343" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>colombia: Japanese Red Army rebels said working in Colombia.</title>
<headline>Japanese Red Army rebels said working in Colombia.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A commando of Japanese Red Army guerrillas is operating in Colombia and may be training Colombian Marxist rebels, intelligence sources said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Japanese diplomats in Bogota met Gen. Luis Enrique Montenegro, the head of the national security department DAS, Thursday morning to warn him of the likely presence of the group in Colombia, a DAS spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>The security service initially said 15 Red Army members, four women and 11 men, were operating in Colombia but at least five of those named on a list issued by Interpol were arrested earlier this year and last in the Mideast and Peru.</p>
<p>The DAS spokeswoman declined to give details of the meeting between the Japanese delegation, including the Japanese ambassador in Bogota.</p>
<p>But she said there were &quot;strong grounds&quot; to suggest the Red Army task force was based in the violence-torn, banana-growing region of Uraba in northwest Colombia, training Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia FARC guerrillas in &quot;terror tactics.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The information of the presence of Red Army members in Colombia was supplied by the Japanese ambassador this morning ... We imagine they are being protected and hidden in the hills of Uraba,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>The ambassador was unavailable for comment.</p>
<p>The Japanese Red Army, founded in 1971, has links with Libya and is allied to hardline anti-Israeli Palestinian factions.</p>
<p>The guerrilla force's maximum leader, a 51-year-old woman named Fusako Shigenobu, is said to be among the group now in Colombia.</p>
<p>Information issued by Interpol indicated most have experience in conflicts in Southeast Asia and the Mideast and have carried out a range of bombings, hijacks and kidnappings.</p>
<p>But a Japanese reporter familiar with the history of the Red Army said four of those now said to be in Colombia had in fact been arrested in Beirut in February and a fifth had been seized in Peru last year and deported to Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible that some of these people may have come to Colombia or South America because the situation in the Mideast has completely changed and they are looking to build up ties with guerrilla groups elsewhere,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The army, police and military intelligence have joined the hunt for the international rebels and posters of the 15 alleged Japanese guerrillas are being distributed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
