<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487548" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Filipino who found Busang gold site buried.</title>
<headline>Filipino who found Busang gold site buried.</headline>
<byline>Ruben Alabastro</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Filipino geologist who helped discover what had been touted as the world's greatest gold find this century was buried on Friday, and his family said they would probably never fully know the circumstances of his death.</p>
<p>Michael de Guzman, chief geologist for Bre-X Minerals Ltd, was buried in a gold-coloured casket 17 days after he fell to his death from a helicopter taking him to the Busang gold site in the jungles of Indonesia.</p>
<p>At an emotionally charged funeral, de Guzman's mother collapsed wailing in her seat as a younger brother, holding back his own tears, sang the late geologist's favourite song, &quot;My Way&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Probably we will never know what actually happened, we are hoping against hope,&quot; de Guzman's brother, Simplicio Jr, told reporters.</p>
<p>The funeral took place a day after the Philippines' top civilian investigating agency, the National Bureau of Investigation, carried out a second autopsy on de Guzman's remains. Results were expected to be announced next week.</p>
<p>A week after his death on March 19, Bre-X stunned the international mining community and the capital markets when it said the Busang property that de Guzman helped discover might hold less than the 71 million ounces of gold it had announced previously.</p>
<p>The original amount, worth some $25 billion at current gold prices, would make it the gold find of the century.</p>
<p>&quot;No, absolutely not,&quot; Simplicio de Guzman said when asked if his brother was the kind of person who might commit suicide.</p>
<p>&quot;There are other things going for him,&quot; he said, adding that his brother had plans to build a school in Busang as well as in Manila.</p>
<p>An Indonesian official had said the geologist might have committed suicide, saying a letter from de Guzman found in the helicopter he was riding stated he was suffering from acute Hepatitis B.</p>
<p>Simplicio said he had seen the letter but refused to talk about its contents pending the outcome of investigation.</p>
<p>But he insisted that, &quot;my brother did not have Hepatitis B&quot;.</p>
<p>Asked about the controversy over the extent of gold deposits in Busang, Simplicio said: &quot;My brother is one person who will never ever say anything which is not there and I am pretty sure, pretty confident, 101 percent, that they'll prove that my brother was right from the very start.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the family requested another autopsy &quot;to double check,&quot; even though Indonesian authorities had already performed one.</p>
<p>&quot;We probably would never forgive ourselves if we would not do that. Just for the peace of mind of the family,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We know the justice of God is still there,&quot; the geologist's sister, Diana, said in brief remarks at the service.</p>
<p>Many of the 80-odd mourners broke into tears towards the end of the service when Simplicio, his voice echoing through the small chapel at the Holy Cross Memorial Park, sang &quot;My Way&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;He died, a geologist, in his field of dreams, till the end,&quot; the priest said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
