<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487525" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thailand to help brokerages with margin loan woes.</title>
<headline>Thailand to help brokerages with margin loan woes.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Thai Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) said on Friday it planned measures to help brokerages hit by high levels of outstanding margin loans from clients due to a prolonged stock market slump.</p>
<p>&quot;The margin loan problem has to be resolved as quickly as possible, otherwise it will harm the stability of securities companies,&quot; SEC chief Pakorn Malakul Na Ayudhya told reporters.</p>
<p>He said the Securities Finance Corp (SFC) would purchase the margin loans from securities companies on the condition they bought the loans back within five years.</p>
<p>The SFC, which was established last year as a lending centre for Thai securities companies, would raise funds through the issue of bonds, he added.</p>
<p>Total outstanding margin loans of all securities amounted to about 120 billion baht ($4.6 billion) of which 90 billion baht were unresolved, he said.</p>
<p>The margin loans which would be bought by the SFC must be loans granted for the purchase of blue-chip and highly-liquid shares, Pakorn said.</p>
<p>Other details would be disclosed after the finance ministry approved the planned measures.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
