<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487536" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks end up 1.14 pct on foreign buying.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks end up 1.14 pct on foreign buying.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks rallied 1.14 percent on speculative foreign buying of major bank and energy issues ahead of long weekend holidays, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreigners bought discounted banks and energy issues, reasoning their business would be less affected by the prevailing economic slump,&quot; said Somchai Trairattanapirom of SITCA Investment.</p>
<p>The composite SET index closed rising 8.08 points to 714.09 on 3.4 billion baht turnover.  </p>
<p>The SET-50 index gained 0.87 point to 53.55.</p>
<p>Advances edged declines 150 to 137 with 97 issues ending unchanged.</p>
<p>Brokers said foreigners continued accumulating stocks while local investors were sidelined by the upcoming long weekend.</p>
<p>Foreigners were net buyers by 875 million baht on Thursday.</p>
<p>The market will be closed on Monday for a public holiday.  </p>
<p>Brokers said an announcement by three finance firms to merge and apply for a new commercial banking licence on Thursday would benefit the market.</p>
<p>The firms planning to form an alliance are Nava Finance and Securities Plc, Thaimex Finance and Securities Plc, and CMIC Finance and Securities.</p>
<p>Bangkok Bank topped the active list, gaining two baht to 189, and PTT Exploration rose 18 to 340.</p>
<p>-- Suthep Chawla (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
