<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487810" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Renault workers clash with police, vow to go on.</title>
<headline>Renault workers clash with police, vow to go on.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian riot police clashed on Friday with angry and frustrated Renault workers who marched through Brussels in a bid to save their own jobs and force European Union governments to beef up employment protection.</p>
<p>Police turned water cannon on the demonstrators who, clad in the green, red and blue colours of their unions, hurled stones, eggs and firecrackers, brandished wooden and steel staves and tried to tear down barbed wire barricades in several places.</p>
<p>The ranks of Belgian Renault workers were swelled by delegations from France and Spain and from bankrupt Belgian steel firm Forges de Clabecq. Police put the total at 1,000.</p>
<p>&quot;Renault and Clabecq. The same fight. All together. All together,&quot; the demonstrators chanted as they moved from the Flemish Regional government buildings to the Belgian parliament and then on to the European Commission's headquarters.</p>
<p>The marchers also taunted the riot police with chants of &quot;bulldozer, bulldozer&quot; in a reference to a clash a week ago when steelworkers wrecked 10 police vehicles as they used bulldozers to try to block the Brussels to Paris motorway.</p>
<p>&quot;Renault's fight is exactly the same as Clabecq's,&quot; a steelworkers union representative said.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene, on a visit to Uruguay, told Belga news agency he regretted the clashes. &quot;Violence does not solve anything,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>There has been a rash of protests in Belgium and France since the French carmaker unexpectedly announced at the end of February that it would close its profitable plant at Vilvoorde near Brussels in July with the loss of 3,100 jobs.</p>
<p>The workers, who have occupied the plant since the decision and held billions of francs worth of cars for ransom, got a morale boost on Thursday when a Brussels court ruled that Renault had broken the law by failing to consult its employees.</p>
<p>However, Renault hit back, insisting the closure would go ahead regardless and saying it would appeal the ruling which forces it to start the consultation process from scratch.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be difficult to save Vilvoorde. But we will continue our actions and try to force them to change their minds,&quot; one union spokesman said at the barricades before going to see European Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert.</p>
<p>Van Miert, a Belgian, told the union delegation he was powerless to stop the Vilvoorde closure but would write to Renault chairman Louis Schweitzer asking him to reconsider.</p>
<p>In an interview published on Friday in the French newspaper La Liberation, Schweitzer said the car maker might close the Vilvoorde plant earlier if workers did not resume production.</p>
<p>&quot;The cars which have been blocked remain blocked. We won't give up our weapon to the management and start back at the beginning again,&quot; union representative Georges Jacqmijn said.</p>
<p>Van Miert also told the unions he would write to all European Union governments asking them to agree stronger rules for companies with plants in several countries.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not give up the fight,&quot; a member of the delegation told reporters after the meeting.</p>
<p>The Renault union later urged European Union social affairs ministers to agree the the new rules when they meet on April 17.</p>
<p>The march in Brussels on Friday was part of a coordinated day of action by Renault workers in Belgium, France and Spain.</p>
<p>Renault, which lost 5.2 billion French francs ($923.4 million) in 1996, has also announced plans to cut nearly 3,000 jobs in France.</p>
<p>Clabecq workers have organised a national march for work in the central Belgian city of Namur on Saturday. They expect tens of thousands of people to attend.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
