<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487972" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India Congress says ready for talks with rulers.</title>
<headline>India Congress says ready for talks with rulers.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Congress party, which withdrew make-or-break support to the ruling minority coalition this week, said on Friday it was open for talks with Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's United Front alliance.</p>
<p>Congress spokesman Vithal Gadgil told Reuters that the party was strongly behind Congress president Sitaram Kesri but ready for talks to end a political crisis if the United Front made the first move. &quot;Let the proposal come,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Asked if Congress was open for talks to end the political crisis, Gadgil said: &quot;Yes, yes.&quot;</p>
<p>Congress withdrew its support to the 10-month-old government on Sunday, citing what it said was the government's inability to tackle economic drift and combat communalism, a reference to Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP).</p>
<p>Analysts say the Congress, which has staked a claim to form a fresh coalition with support from the United Front or some of its constituents, has faltered in its bid for power ahead of a vote of confidence in Deve Gowda set for April 11.</p>
<p>The BJP and its allies control 193 votes in the 542-member lower house. The United Front has 180 votes and Congress 140. Deve Gowda would need a simple majority of members present and voting to win the confidence motion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
