<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487974" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian gilts soar on good liquidity, low interest.</title>
<headline>Indian gilts soar on good liquidity, low interest.</headline>
<byline>Giri Venkatesan</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A sharp surge in liquidity held by banks and expectations of a fall in interest rates have triggered a bull run in Indian government securities, dealers and analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices have shot up by 30-40 paise in stocks across all maturities since last week,&quot; said Aashish Pitale, manager debt research at ICICI Securities and Finance Company (I-Sec), the Indian affiliate of J.P. Morgan.</p>
<p>&quot;In the long bond, the 13.65 percent 2007, the yield has dropped by 20 basis points or an increase in price of at least 60 paise,&quot; Pitale said.</p>
<p>Dealers said a variety of factors had contributed to the current buoyancy in the government securities market.</p>
<p>&quot;One (factor) is the current liquidity position,&quot; said the chief dealer at the Bombay branch of an European bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The system is so flush with funds that call money rates are at ridiculously low levels,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Call money was traded below 1.0 percent on Thursday. Dealers said there were few takers for funds even at 0.25 percent in early Friday trade. It was trading at an average 4.5-5 percent in the first week of March.</p>
<p>Pitale said the current liquidity could be traced to a number of reasons, including the Reserve Bank of India's (RBI) dollar purchases, interest payments credited to banks on their holdings of government securities and lower participation by market players in repo auctions.</p>
<p>Surging foreign dollar inflows in recent weeks have forced the RBI to buy the U.S currency to prevent the rupee from appreciating which could hurt Indian exports.</p>
<p>India's foreign currency reserves stood at an all-time high of $21.16 billion on March 21, an increase of $1.46 billion over the February 28 figure.</p>
<p>&quot;In March alone, there has been an infusion of around 85 billion rupees ($2.37 billion) into the banking system,&quot; Pitale said.</p>
<p>&quot;Besides the dollar purchases which put in around 53 billion rupees, interest payments on government securities were around 17 billion rupees,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Reduced participation at repo auctions also added to the liquidity, Pitale said.</p>
<p>&quot;From an average participation of around 25 billion rupees at the beginning of the month, the last auction attracted less than 10 billion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Pitale said banks had kept away from repo auctions at the end of the month, anticipating a rise in call money rates at the year-end (financial year ending March 31).</p>
<p>&quot;This added a further 15 billion rupees,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another factor contributing to the buying frenzy which had gripped the gilts market was an expectation that interest rates would fall in the future, money market dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;A number of banks have built up speculative positions anticipating a fall in interest rates after the credit policy is announced,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>The RBI unveils its credit and monetary policy for the first half of 1997/98 (April-March) on April 15. Analysts and bankers expect announcements in the policy that generally lead to a fall in interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The market expects the interest rate cap for deposits with maturity to one year to be reduced from the current 10 percent,&quot; said a bank treasury head.</p>
<p>At present the RBI determines the maximum interest rates banks can offer for deposits up to one year. Banks are free to determine their own rates for higher maturities.</p>
<p>&quot;If the cap comes down, then we could see a drop in the yield on the 364-day treasury bill,&quot; Pitale said.</p>
<p>&quot;This would reshape the yield curve.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Banks are building positions on this expectation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay money desk +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
