<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48790" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE gas oil presses higher, demand firm.</title>
<headline>NWE gas oil presses higher, demand firm.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>NWE gas oil rose on Thursday as benchmark IPE futures firmed on mounting tension between Iraq and the U.S. and underlying physical demand remained strong, traders said.</p>
<p>The October IPE contract closed $3 up at $219.50 a tonne. September hit a post-Gulf War high of $226.75 before expiry.</p>
<p>Despite a relatively modest IPE delivery of 155,300 tonnes, the heating oil barge market remained firm with activity picking up in the afternoon. Barges traded at Oct IPE +$8.0 to +$8.50 a tonne fob ARA for second half September delivery, but traders said premiums were very volatile.  </p>
<p>Traders said Dutch barge buyers were fairly inactive but German demand was strong despite high freight rates -- which they said have nearly doubled due to low Rhine levels.</p>
<p>Low sulphur material continued to be in demand with premiums talked at Oct IPE +$16/+$17, cif Le Havre. Traders noted that a number of cargoes were due to be offered at the end of the month which could soften current differentials.</p>
<p>There was also talk, that Petrobras had fixed a vessel, the SKS Banner, to carry 80,000 tonnes of gas oil from Le Havre, but this was not confirmed.</p>
<p>-- Melanie Goodfellow, London Newsroom, +44 171 542 7714</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
