<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="487960" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan president signs bill clipping his powers.</title>
<headline>Pakistan president signs bill clipping his powers.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani President Farooq Leghari has signed a constitutional amendment bill that clips his powers to sack governments and appoint military chiefs and provincial governors, a spokesman for him said on Friday.</p>
<p>The spokesman told Reuters the president had signed the bill on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Senate (upper house) and the National Assembly (lower house) unanimously passed the bill on Tuesday, giving Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif the upper hand in Pakistan's power structure.</p>
<p>The bill has undone clauses of the Eighth Amendment, a relic from the military rule of late president General Mohammad Zia-ul-Haq from 1977 to 1988, and used by three presidents to sack four prime ministers in the past eight years.</p>
<p>Under the amendments, a dissolution of the National Assembly and subsequent sacking of a prime minister, and the appointment of armed forces chiefs and provincial governors by the president, will be subject to binding prime ministerial advice.</p>
<p>With presidential assent the amendment bill has become law with effect from Thursday, legal sources said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
