<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="488004" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S./EU meat talks to resume Tuesday in Washington.</title>
<headline>U.S./EU meat talks to resume Tuesday in Washington.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Key negotiations between the United States and the European Union to avert a trade war that threatens hundreds of millions of dollars worth of meat and poultry trade will resume Tuesday, April 8, in Washington, a senior Agriculture Department official said Friday.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters, Paul Drazek, senior trade adviser to Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman, said that the &quot;complexion of the negotiations&quot; had changed since this week's moves by each side to stop meat and poultry shipments from the other. Drazek said the U.S. side is hoping it can now wrap up an agreement &quot;fairly quickly.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;My hope is that we can wrap up something fairly quickly,&quot; said Drazek. &quot;From our point of view, there's no reason why we shouldn't be able to do that ... it just depends on how much flexibility the Europeans bring with them.&quot;</p>
<p>EU and U.S. negotiators were unable to successfully conclude talks on meat inspection regulations this week by an April 1 deadline, which set into motion moves by both sides that would stop U.S. poultry shipments from entering Europe and halt imports of European meat into the United States.</p>
<p>Drazek said the action taken this week has already disrupted trade, and is bound to have an impact on the talks.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the situation is substantially different than it has been in the past, because we are facing and are already suffering from trade disruptions on both sides ... and that does change the complexion of the negotiations,&quot; said Drazek.</p>
<p>U.S. inspectors will no longer issue export certificates for up to $100 million worth of U.S. poultry and dairy exports due to new EU rules adopted April 1.</p>
<p>As of April 15, European meat and poultry plants will not be able to export some $300 million worth of products, mostly Danish pork products and Italian hams, to the United States if they cannot comply with U.S. standards.  </p>
<p>According to officials on both sides, only a handful of technical issues are blocking an agreement in the &quot;veterinary equivalency&quot; talks. Drazek said this is down from thousands of differences a few years ago.</p>
<p>The USDA official said that despite EU statements that they were &quot;not just going to sit back and let the United States roll over us,&quot; he doubted if the EU would want to escalate the issue any further. &quot;It would only make the situation worse,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>EU and U.S. officials have said that taking the issue to the World Trade Organization is an option if it cannot be settled bilaterally.</p>
<p>Drazek denied that Washington's aggressive action this week was related to the administration's desire to get farm group support for fast-track trade authority and an expansion of the North American Free Trade Agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it would have mattered if there was a fast track bill on its way or not. we would have taken the same steps,&quot; said Drazek.</p>
<p>-- Maggie McNeil, Washington commodities, ((202-898-8300))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
