<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="488022" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: INSTANT VIEW - Canada unemployment.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - Canada unemployment.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are reactions to March unemployment data released by Statistics Canada on Friday. Statistics Canada said on Friday the unemployment rate fell to 9.3 percent in March from 9.7 percent in February. The March unemployment rate is the lowest since November 1995.</p>
<p>Economists in a Reuters survey had forecast, on average, that unemployment would fall to 9.6 percent from 9.7 percent the month before.  </p>
<p>Michael Gregory, economist, Lehman Brothers - &quot;(It was a) good solid number -- Full-time jobs, good distribution in the economy. I think virtually every indicator of labor market conditions was solid except for the labor force survey.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Bank of Canada was looking for reasons to be a little hestitant about raising rates to ratify the market-led increase we've seen, I think this is one less reason.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly what we have seen here is that the Canadian economy is indeed performing very well and it doesn't need any further stimulus. They could (follow the U.S. Federal Reserve rate moves).  </p>
<p>Mullins - &quot;I guess I'm still not convinced that we have got a good (enough) quality report here.</p>
<p>&quot;Help wanted has been picking up since the fourth quarter...I may change my mind a bit if we continue to see good strong gains over the next couple of months, maybe three...But the kind of leading indications we are getting from other reports and the general state of the economy, it's telling you that you should be getting a year even in excess of 1994 in terms of job creation.</p>
<p>&quot;I think rates have to go up, for a whole variety of reasons.&quot;  </p>
<p>Paul Ferley, assistant chief economist, Bank of Montreal - &quot;Very encouraging. It's showing broad-based gains in the month and clearly reversing some of the weakness we've seen in the last couple of months. So I think it's a very strong indication that the strength in expenditure that we have seen is starting to translate into stronger employment growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The drop in the unemployment rate was also encouraging. That was helped by steady labor force growth. That may reverse a bit in April, but generally I think the downtrend in the unemployment rate has been established here.</p>
<p>&quot;The (Canadian) dollar strengthened a bit on this report. If that's sustained, I think it's an environment where the Bank (of Canada) remains on the sidelines.&quot;</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
