<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="488000" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Don't call it cognac.</title>
<headline>Don't call it cognac.</headline>
<byline>Michael Christie</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Having already sparred with Chile over whisky, European Union Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan on Friday continued a Latin American tour by taking on Brazil over cognac.</p>
<p>Brittan told reporters in the capital Brasilia that Brussels strongly objected to spirits on sale in Brazilian supermarkets that called themselves &quot;cognac.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;In Europe, cognac is a sprit produced in a part of France and you can't call something cognac that doesn't come from there,&quot; Brittan said. &quot;Cognac is cognac. Products which are not cognac you can call whatever you like, but not cognac.&quot;</p>
<p>The EU's top trade negotiator was in Brazil to hold talks with government officials on a diverse range of trade issues, including controversial Brazilian car import rules and EU tariffs on Brazilian coffee exports.</p>
<p>On Thursday, he met with President Fernando Henrique Cardoso and on Friday with Foreign Minister Luiz Felipe Lampreia.</p>
<p>Brittan said he had not &quot;threatened&quot; Brazil over the cognac dispute but had made it clear the European Union expected Brasilia to do something about it.</p>
<p>In Chile this week, the European Commission vice president was more forthright, warning Santiago the EU might turn to the World Trade Organization if a spat over whisky taxes was not resolved.</p>
<p>Chile imposed a 70 percent tax on whisky in 1979, much to the chagrin of whisky producers but to the delight of distillers of pisco, a popular Chilean brandy.</p>
<p>Brittan was more aggressive when it came to disagreements between Brussels and Brasilia over a Car Industry Regime that allows car makers with Brazilian factories to import at half the usual tariff.</p>
<p>The measure has resulted in about $20 billion in pledged investment by major international automobile manufacturers but has angered some trading partners, mainly the United States, Japan and the European Union. After Brazil introduced a low-tariff quota system for EU, South Korean and Japanese car makers, the anger died down.</p>
<p>Brazil, meanwhile, reiterated long-standing complaints about EU farm subsidies and &quot;barriers&quot; that limit Brazilian agricultural exports, in particular of coffee and chicken.</p>
<p>As for coffee, he criticized EU rules that give preferential treatment to coffee from countries afflicted by the drugs trade, like main coffee competitor Colombia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
