<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="488141" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bomb hunt snarls British motorways, hits industry.</title>
<headline>Bomb hunt snarls British motorways, hits industry.</headline>
<byline>Tony Roddam</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Key sections of two British motorways were closed on Friday, costing industry millions of pounds and snarling traffic in central England, after police received coded bomb warnings thought to be from the IRA.</p>
<p>Even longer stretches of motorway, the spinal cord of British transport, were shut down on Thursday after bomb warnings, and a massive police search uncovered two bombs believed to have been planted by (IRA) Irish Republican Army guerrillas.</p>
<p>The M1 north-south artery reopened on Thursday night but the M6 and part of the M5 remained closed on Friday morning as police hunted for more bombs on roads crucial to the country's freight hauliers.</p>
<p>The threat to economic links is likely to intensify the business community's concern about the cost of deadlock in the Northern Ireland peace process.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein, political wing of the IRA, has been excluded from talks about bringing peace to Northern Ireland until the guerrilla group, fighting to end British rule in the province, calls a truce.</p>
<p>The British government pumps 4 billion pounds ($6.56 billion) net into Northern Ireland every year. One third goes on security measures and the conflict has hampered business expansion and investment.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Major, campaigning for general elections on May 1, said the IRA appeared to be responsible for the two bombs that police discovered.</p>
<p>&quot;It was intended deliberately to cause trouble...It looks as though it was the IRA playing silly games,&quot; Major told reporters. The opposition Labour party, tipped by pollsters to win the election, joined Major in his condemnation.</p>
<p>No group has yet claimed responsibility for the bombs but coded telephone calls are the standard warning from the IRA. The movement ended a 17-month ceasefire in February last year and has since detonated several bombs on the mainland.</p>
<p>Last week the IRA caused major disruption to rail services after they set off two bombs at an important rail junction in the northwestern town of Wilmslow.</p>
<p>Transport industry officials said the closure of two of Britain's most critical arteries between the south-east and the industrial northwest were costing the haulage industry around 2.3 million pounds an hour and snarling up central England's minor roads with heavy trucks.</p>
<p>&quot;This is serious. We estimate 77,000 vehicles traverse those motorways between eight and six o'clock. We can cater for everyday congestion by altering schedules but bomb alerts or sudden interruptions cannot be mopped up,&quot; said Geoff Dossetter, spokesman for the Freight Transport Association.</p>
<p>&quot;Something like this means complete re-routings through minor non-motorway roads and you get tremendous backwashes. Many companies depend on just-in-time deliveries, particularly in the auto industry and supermarkets, especially for fresh food and chilled lines,&quot; said Dave Norris, head of risk and insurance at NFC UK and Ireland, one of Britain's largest hauliers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
