<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="488173" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK Liberals pledge to tax smokers, wealthy.</title>
<headline>UK Liberals pledge to tax smokers, wealthy.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The minority Liberal Democrats, struggling to make an impact in Britain's election race, on Friday rejected the consensus view of their Conservative and Labour rivals that Britons will not vote for higher taxes.</p>
<p>Launching the party manifesto, leader Paddy Ashdown attacked his opponents for offering puny solutions to the immense challenges faced by Britain, and pledged to make high earners and smokers pay for education and healthcare improvements.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't wish people to pay one penny more in tax than is necessary, but there is no choice,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>With polls showing support at between 11 and 17 percent, the Liberals, always the victims of the first-past-the-post voting system, cannot aspire to victory in more than 40 of the 659 seats at stake in the May 1 election.</p>
<p>Party strategists hope that an anti-Conservative mood in the country will persuade voters in these key seats to vote tactically and back their candidate as the one most likely to beat the nominee of Prime Minister John Major.</p>
<p>The party, a 2,000-1 shot at the betting shops to win the election outright, at present has 26 MPs.</p>
<p>If the opposition Labour Party's 20-point opinion poll lead slips, Ashdown could yet find himself holding the balance of power after election day. He has made it clear he would then favour a Labour government rather than keep Major in office.</p>
<p>But in an even-handed attack, Ashdown said in the manifesto: &quot;A terrible fatalism seems to grip (British) politicians. Though the challenges are immense, the solutions we are offered are all too often puny...the Liberal Democrats reject this timidity.&quot;</p>
<p>He proposed a penny in the pound income tax hike to improve Britain's rundown schools, extra cigarette tax to pay for free eye and dental check-ups for all, and more expensive motoring for drivers of large cars to protect the environment.</p>
<p>The pledges were in stark contrast to Labour's caution on tax. Its economic spokesman Gordon Brown has promised to keep income tax rates where they are for the next five years, and has even accepted the Conservatives' 1997 and 1998 spending plans.</p>
<p>The Conservatives promise further income tax cuts in the future and a tax break for couples where one spouse gives up work to look after children or elderly relatives.</p>
<p>Ashdown said the changes he proposed were &quot;the minimum we believe needs to be done to begin the process of putting this country right after 18 years of Conservative government&quot;.</p>
<p>The Conservatives would suffer most, especially in seats they hold in the west of England where the Liberals are strong, if Ashdown's proposals catch voters' imaginations.</p>
<p>The Liberals have already overtaken the governing party in local government, where Ashdown's party traditionally polls well, both in terms of councils controlled and seats held.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
