<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="488218" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: U.S. stocks in London on hold ahead of jobs data.</title>
<headline>U.S. stocks in London on hold ahead of jobs data.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. shares were little changed on Friday as participants awaited key U.S. unemployment figures, due at 1330 GMT.</p>
<p>Dealers expect the Dow Industrials, which has dropped around eight percent in a little over three weeks, to push higher later today if the U.S. March jobless numbers are in-line with expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;We could see a bit of a technical rally if the figures meet forecasts,&quot; one market maker said. &quot;But I doubt any rally will be sustained. The market still looks like it needs more of a shake-out.</p>
<p>The U.S. non-farm payroll total is forecast to show an increase of 196,000 in March after rising by 339,000 the previous month, according to a Reuters poll of economists.</p>
<p>U.S. average hourly earnings, used by many participants as a guide to inflationary pressures, are expected to rise by 0.4 percent in March, after a 0.2 percent increase in February.</p>
<p>The Dow finished 39.66 points lower to 6,477.35 on Thursday, after trading nearly 100 points easier during the session.</p>
<p>The high-technology laden Nasdaq Composite rose 12.76 points or 1.06 percent to 1,213.76, helped by a firm showing in computer stocks.</p>
<p>Intel Corp, which rose $3-5/8 in New York on Thursday, was up $1/4 to $140-7/8, while Texas Instruments added $1/4 to $78-1/8.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Philip Morris was down $3/8 to $114.</p>
<p>U.S. treasuries were also in a wait-and-see mood, with the June T-bond up 2/32 to 107-22/32 by 1005 GMT. The yield on the cash 30-year long bond was standing at 7.07 percent.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
