<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="488295" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dalai Lama sets Washington visit.</title>
<headline>Dalai Lama sets Washington visit.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tibet's exiled political and spiritual leader, the Dalai Lama, will visit Washington this month in search of support for self-rule talks with China, sponsors of his trip said on Friday.</p>
<p>The White House welcomed the scheduled April 21-24 visit, but said no decision had been made on a possible meeting between President Bill Clinton and the monk who has led a government-in-exile in India since a failed anti-Chinese uprising in Tibet in 1959.</p>
<p>&quot;The administration welcomes the Dalai Lama's visit and looks forward to discussions with him,&quot; Eric Rubin, a White House spokesman, said. &quot;He will definitely be meeting members of the administration, but at what level and with whom has not been decided.&quot;</p>
<p>The Dalai Lama's visit poses political and diplomatic challenges for Clinton, who has been engineering a rapprochement with China. Beijing denounces the Buddhist leader as a &quot;splittist&quot; seeking to foment revolt against Chinese rule in his Himalayan homeland and has threatened to downgrade relations with countries whose leaders meet him.</p>
<p>Organisers of the visit said the Dalai Lama, winner of the 1989 Nobel peace prize, planned to ask President Clinton to nudge China toward the negotiating table to discuss a measure of autonomy for Tibet.</p>
<p>&quot;The Dalai Lama is seeking some genuine support for a negotiated settlement,&quot; said John Ackerly, director of the International Campaign for Tibet, which is sponsoring the visit.</p>
<p>The Dalai Lama will be the keynote speaker at a convention on Tibet that will bring together parliament members from more than 50 countries in a House of Representatives' office building. He will also take part in interfaith prayer gatherings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
