<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="488298" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSTANT VIEW - U.S. March payrolls jump 175,000.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - U.S. March payrolls jump 175,000.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are comments from U.S. experts after the Labor Department said the economy added 175,000 new jobs in the month and the jobless rate fell to 5.2 percent. Jobs growth in February was revised downward to show a 293,000 increase compared to 339,000 originally.</p>
<p>Economists in a Reuters survey had expected 196,000 new jobs in the month and an unemployment rate of 5.2 percent.</p>
<p>AUDREY FREEDMAN, PRESIDENT, AUDREY FREEDMAN &amp; ASSOCIATES,</p>
<p>INC: &quot;We just can't keep up the very fast pace (of jobs growth) of last month.&quot;  </p>
<p>Speaking on Reuters Financial Television, Freedman appeared encouraged that jobs growth was not as strong as some economists had expected.</p>
<p>KEVIN FLANAGAN, VICE PRESIDENT, DEAN WITTER REYNOLDS INC:</p>
<p>&quot;These are not the kinds of figures to spur a rally (in Treasuries); you can paint a negative side (for bonds). There was definitive momentum in wages with the highest year-over-year level gains in seven years. Overtime levels are at their highest in 41 years, so it keeps alive and well the notion the Federal Reserve can tighten again on May 20.&quot;  </p>
<p>JOSEPH LIRO, CHIEF ECONOMIST, CIBC WOOD GUNDY SECURITIES CORP:</p>
<p>&quot;They're strong numbers. The big thing is the workweek only dropped 0.1 after being up 2.6 percent in the prior month and that's telling. The big jump in the earnings number is a negative and the drop in the unemployment rate is a negative.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The household survey has shown 745,000 more people with jobs, so overall a very strong report. The other components (besides the headline) are pretty strong right across the board.&quot;  </p>
<p>NICHOLAS PERNA, CHIEF ECONOMIST, FLEET FINANCIAL GROUP:</p>
<p>&quot;(The) unemployment rate being lower than expected, average hourly earnings rose fairly strongly -- a nickel was a fairly substantial rise ... that's a pretty zippy increase. All in all, I would say that the report is on the strong side and that means to me whatever the Fed was going to do at the next FMOC meeting it's going to do. And I think they're going to raise rates another quarter point at that meeting ...&quot;  </p>
<p>Perna continued: &quot;Remember though, before the next FMOC meeting ... we get yet another employment report just like this one for the month of April. And, perhaps as at least as important, we also get the Employment Cost Index ...</p>
<p>&quot;But given what we've got today, I think it's bumped up the Treasury yields a little bit ... and my guess is that you'll see a further small rise in long rates today as this report is viewed as being on the strong side ...</p>
<p>&quot;Normally, under current conditions, any feeling of rising interest rates has not been good for the stock market,&quot; Perna added.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1660 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
