<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="488390" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Analysts expect rise in German jobless to reverse.</title>
<headline>Analysts expect rise in German jobless to reverse.</headline>
<byline>Clifford Coonan</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The rise in German unemployment could be reversed when March jobless data is published next Tuesday, but it would be too early to say if this signals a long-awaited turnaround in the German labour market, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>The sluggish pace of economic growth in Germany has stymied any chance of a meaningful upturn in the labour market so far this year. Levels of GDP growth in the early part of the year fall far short of Government forecasts of 2.5 percent growth for 1997.</p>
<p>The harsh winter has contributed to deep recession in the building industry, compounding woes in the labour market. Construction is a major employer in Germany, and The sector has accounted for the lion's share of job losses in the country since late 1996.</p>
<p>February figures gave the first indication that the country may be emerging from the mire, as unemployment rose by only 5,000 to a seasonally adjusted 4.316 million. The Bundesbank said the unemployment rate that month was unchanged at 11.3 percent.</p>
<p>Labour Office President Bernhard Jagoda said the worst of Germany's jobs crisis may be over as the rise in jobless slowed sharply in February.</p>
<p>The unadjusted total number of unemployed was 4.672 million, up from 4.658 million in January, while the unadjusted rate was also unchanged at 12.2 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;If our prognoses are correct, we are forecasting some cheer in the market, a kind of spring awakening, a small turnaround,&quot; Rolf Schneider, analyst at Dresdner Bank, Frankfurt, said</p>
<p>&quot;January and February were heavily influenced by the extreme cold and new rules for paying employees during bad-weather. We are confident on the development in the economy and are looking for growth of 2.6 percent in the economy in 1997,&quot; said Schneider.</p>
<p>Not all analysts are quite so upbeat. Holger Schmieding, analyst at Merrill Lynch in Frankfurt, said: &quot;The big jump in January was based on extraordinary factors and we see a slight improvement in March, because the extraordinary factors are no longer an issue.</p>
<p>&quot;In the rest of the economy there is further rationalisation going on, and the construction industry should bottom out, but will stay weak,&quot; Schmieding said.</p>
<p>He forecasts an average jobless figure for 1997 of 4.25 million and sees a fall of only 10,000 in the seasonally adjusted number for March.</p>
<p>Ralph Sueppel of J.P. Morgan in Frankfurt, is forecasting a strong fall in seasonally-adjusted jobless numbers.</p>
<p>&quot;For the whole early part of the year from March to June we are expecting a fall in seasonally adjusted terms of between 150,000 and 200,000,&quot; said Sueppel.</p>
<p>His counterpart at Bayerische Vereinsbank in Munich reckons it is still too early to tell whether the fall in jobless numbers has bottomed out or not.</p>
<p>&quot;The new appointments are in the construction sector and are seasonally affected. This is no more than a correction at the moment. In the second quarter we expect better figures in absolute terms, a rebound led by growth in the economy,&quot; Nikolaus Keis at Bayerische Vereinsbank in Munich said.</p>
<p>Ulrike Kastens, Trinkaus Capital Management in Duesseldorf, is forecasting a fall in seasonally adjusted unemployment of 85,000, the highest drop among those polled. At the same time, she is still cautious in her overall outlook.</p>
<p>&quot;February was disappointing. We should see a slight recovery in March because of the improved weather.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The construction industry is in recession and not everyone who was let go will be taken on again. Ultimately this is not a turnaround. The labour market remains a problem child,&quot; said Kastens.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
