<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="488803" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: S&amp;P says Thailand has no competitiveness problem.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P says Thailand has no competitiveness problem.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard and Poor's Corp believes that Thailand has no fundamental problem in its export competitiveness, S&amp;P said in a conference call on Friday.</p>
<p>S&amp;P also said it expects Thailand's exports to start to pick up later this year.  </p>
<p>&quot;Thailand does not have a fundamental export competitiveness problem,&quot; said Cem Karacadag, S&amp;P sovereign analyst in New York.</p>
<p>He said that while Thailand has lost some edge in lower value-added exports, it is making strides in the shift toward higher value-added goods.</p>
<p>Because of the economy's openness and flexibility, it can respond to competitive challenges, Karacadag said.</p>
<p>&quot;Usually at this time in an economic cycle we would start to see signs on an export pick-up and we are starting to see evidence of that in Thailand,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Thailand is well-placed for its export sector to pick up in the second half of 1997 and into 1998,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>S&amp;P expects Thailand's current account deficit to shrink to five percent of gross domestic product by next year, a forecast it deemed conservative.</p>
<p>The rating agency also expects Thailand's gross domestic product to grow roughly 5.0 percent in 1997 and in 1998 after an estimated growth rate of 6.7 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>S&amp;P affirmed Thailand's sovereign ratings and stable outlook last month. S&amp;P rates Thailand's long-term foreign currency debt at Single-A and its long-term local currency debt at AA.</p>
<p>S&amp;P reiterated in the conference call held earlier today that it does not believe that the troubles plaguing Thailand's financial sector will adversely affect the country's long-term sovereign rating because the problems are manageable.</p>
<p>-- Andrea Ricci (852) 2843 6371</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
