<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48898" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GHANA: Ghana to cut cocoa export duty, boost farm price.</title>
<headline>Ghana to cut cocoa export duty, boost farm price.</headline>
<dateline>ACCRA 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ghana plans to reduce export duty on cocoa so it can raise farmgate prices and encourage farmers to maintain production at current record levels, Finance Minister Richard Kwame Peprah said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Peprah, addressing the Ghana Cocoa Marketing Board (COCOBOD) Board of Directors, said the plan would require sacrifices from other players but was necessary for the industry.</p>
<p>The aim was to raise farmgate prices from their present level of 52 percent of FOB prices to 60 percent by 2000 -- in line with a pre-election pledge from the ruling National Democratic Congress.</p>
<p>&quot;The Board must take notice of the NDC Manifesto -- which was approved last week -- of paying the cocoa farmer at least 60 percent of the FOB by the year 2000 and stabilising (annual) production at around 400,000 metric tonnes,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Peprah was speaking at the inauguration of the new board of directors, which was reconstituted by President Jerry Rawlings last week. Rawlings and his party face elections in December.</p>
<p>He said improved efficiency had enabled COCOBOD to raise the farmgate price from 20 to 30 percent of FOB in the early 1980s to 52 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The payment of the 60 percent FOB to farmers will require sacrifices from the other stakeholders namely government, Cocobod, buyers and transporters,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;The government's sacrifice will come in the form of reduced export duty whereas the others will have to improve efficiency through cost cutting measures without affecting the quality of cocoa and services rendered,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We think we can make these sacrifices at an affordable cost to all of us and the farmers will appreciate this effort and will reward us with increased production.&quot;</p>
<p>Peprah urged the board to look at cost cuts such as privatising cocoa research and limiting the activities of Cocobod head office largely to policy planning, research and treasury functions.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen the success of the private sector companies in the internal marketing of cocoa. We think that the more we can encourage to enter this business, the more pressure we can take from Cocobod and therefore make it leaner,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation where we spend annually 15 billion cedis on Cocoa Extension (education and farming inputs) as against 4.6 billion on other agricultural extension services cannot be sustained,&quot; he said, adding that the solution was to create one efficient agricultural extension service.</p>
<p>Peprah did not mention privatisation of the export of cocoa, now the monopoly of Cocobod. He told Reuters a ministry task force was studying a private consultant's report about this.</p>
<p>The task force was expected to be ready with its study by the end of the week, he said. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Board chairman Odeneho Gyapong Ababio II, said privatisation of exports would be in line with the government's general economic policy but it was too early to make a definite statement.</p>
<p>The newly appointed chief-executive of COCOBOD, John Henri Newman, travels to London on Friday but gave no details of the reason for his visit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100144">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ACCRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GHANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
