<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="488956" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Kohl candidacy seen turning spotlight on SPD.</title>
<headline>Kohl candidacy seen turning spotlight on SPD.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>German press commentators on Friday praised Chancellor Helmut Kohl's decision to stand for a record fifth term of office, describing it as an admirable but risky move aimed at raising the pressure on the opposition Social Democrats.</p>
<p>The SPD leads in opinion polls but is undecided on whether its candidate should be left-leaning party leader Oskar Lafontaine or the more business-friendly Lower Saxony premier Gerhard Schroeder, who polls say has a much better chance against Kohl.</p>
<p>&quot;The fight has begun!&quot; the popular Bild daily proclaimed. &quot;SPD voters also have the right to demand clarity -- Schroeder or Lafontaine.&quot;</p>
<p>But although Bild said clarity was a good thing for Germany it said it would not be good if the country was plunged into a year and a half of campaigning before the general election.</p>
<p>The Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung said Kohl had considered waiting until the summer to make a decision, but had seized the moment to intensify pressure on the SPD.</p>
<p>&quot;Either it (the SPD) puts off the decision and causes bitterness in its own ranks and accusations that it cannot field a candidate to rival Kohl, or it gets on with it and thereby traps itself in fetters and snares,&quot; it said in a commentary.</p>
<p>The paper said younger members of Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU) and sister party the Christian Social Union (CSU) were probably happy to wait their turn because the next year and a half would undoubtedly be difficult for the union and ruling coalition. &quot;Kohl has never personally risked so much,&quot; it wrote.</p>
<p>The Sueddeutsche Zeitung said Kohl deserved respect for staying on board as the going got tough rather than retiring to his unquestioned place in history.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision... deserves respect because Kohl has not pushed the responsibility (for unemployment, the government deficit and the tax burden) onto others, but has put himself before the electorate.&quot;</p>
<p>The Berliner Zeitung said his decision was &quot;both the best thing and the worst thing that could happen to his party&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;With Kohl, it has a good chance of election success and forces the SPD to make radical leadership choices. But Kohl's new candidacy will prevent overdue reforms taking place...&quot;</p>
<p>Die Welt daily said Kohl had an obligation to stand again.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear that there is no one else there (in the CDU) who would have had a chance of victory.</p>
<p>&quot;Kohl's decision will stabilise the coalition for the time being. A refusal by the chancellor would have led to thoughts of a grand coalition.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
