<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="488996" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippines to highlight successes at APEC meet.</title>
<headline>Philippines to highlight successes at APEC meet.</headline>
<byline>Ramoncito dela Cruz</byline>
<dateline>CEBU, Philippines 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippines, once viewed as the sick man of Asia, will highlight its economic successes at a meeting this weekend that will draw finance ministers of the Pacific Rim region.</p>
<p>Jeremias Paul, director of the International Finance Policy Office of the finance department, told Reuters the Philippines would share its experiences in tapping private funds to bankroll infrastructure projects at the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an entirely different ballgame,&quot; said Paul, referring to a scheme used in the Philippines to build large infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>The build-operate-transfer (BOT) approach allows the private sector to finance, build and manage such projects as water systems, toll roads and power plants, which after a time are transferred to government ownership.</p>
<p>The Philippines has been cited by the World Bank for successfully embarking on massive infrastructure projects through privatisation and the BOT scheme.</p>
<p>The influx of foreign capital in past years has helped the country boost its gross national product, which grew by 6.8 percent last year.</p>
<p>Paul added the APEC meeting in the central province of Cebu would put the spotlight on the thriving economy of the island.</p>
<p>&quot;This will give Cebu ... the chance to take the centre stage. Cebu has been the forerunner in accepting the challenges of globalisation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The entrepreneurial spirits of the locals coupled with a steady stream of foreign investments have kept Cebu afloat even when the national economy was experiencing a deep economic slump in the past decade.</p>
<p>APEC groups 18 economies in the world's most vibrant region. These include Australia, Brunei, Canada, Chile, China, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Japan, South Korea, Malaysia, Mexico, New Zealand, Papua New Guinea, Philippines, Singapore, Taiwan, Thailand and the United States.</p>
<p>The APEC finance ministers' meeting will tackle a wide array of issues which include collaborative initiatives on free flow of capital, private sector participation in infrastructure development and capital market development.</p>
<p>The Philippines hosted the fourth leaders' summit last November in Manila and the nearby Subic freeport zone. Subic, devastated in 1991 by a volcanic eruption, has been transformed into a fledging investment hub.</p>
<p>These economies have pledged to open up their trade and investment regimes by year 2010 for developed economies and 2020 for developing economies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CEBU, Philippines"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
