<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489147" id="root" date="1997-04-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-BIERHOFF DOUBTS HE WILL PLAY IN GERMANY AGAIN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BIERHOFF DOUBTS HE WILL PLAY IN GERMANY AGAIN.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-04-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Udinese's struggling German international striker Oliver Bierhoff said on Saturday he doubted he would play in Germany again because not many clubs wanted him there and life was tough.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a 99 per cent chance I won't return home,&quot; he told Italy's Gazzetta dello Sport newspaper.</p>
<p>Bierhoff has not played in Germany since 1990, when he left Borussia Moenchengladbach for Austria's Salzburg. He has been in Italy since 1991, first at Ascoli then Udinese.</p>
<p>&quot;There are not many clubs that want me there and for a national team player life in Germany is not easy. (Juergen) Klinsmann scored 16 league goals and 14 UEFA Cup goals last season and yet now he is being slaughtered,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Germany's 32-year-old captain Klinsmann is giving up a lucrative contract at Bayern Munich at the end of the season because he is unhappy with the atmosphere at the club. He has said he plans to move abroad.</p>
<p>Bierhoff, who scored the two goals in the European championship final last summer to give Germany a 2-1 victory over the Czech Republic, has also suffered recently.</p>
<p>He injured an ankle in Italy on December 1 after scoring twice against Parma and was out until mid-February when he returned against Cagliari. He scored the winner again in that match but the goals have since dried up.</p>
<p>Bierhoff, 28, said he was happy to stay at Udinese. &quot;There's the World Cup next year and playing at Udinese I will be able to make the most of my chances,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
