<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489188" id="root" date="1997-04-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Rebels enter Zaire diamond capital- mining sources.</title>
<headline>Rebels enter Zaire diamond capital- mining sources.</headline>
<byline>Richard Meares</byline>
<dateline>LUBUMBASHI, Zaire 1997-04-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rebel forces entered Zaire's diamond capital of Mbuji-Mayi early on Saturday, mining sources in the town said.</p>
<p>Speaking to Reuters from the centre of the town, they said rebels had streamed in across a bridge during the morning.</p>
<p>&quot;People are cheering in the streets, there's a heck of a lot of noise. They are treating this as very good news,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>The mining sources also said that illegal diggers, profiting from the chaos, had invaded the mines to grab what they could before order was restored.</p>
<p>The main force of rebels entered Mbuji-Mayi, one of their most prized conquests to date, just as peace talks between rebels and President Mobutu Sese Seko's representatives were due to begin in South Africa.</p>
<p>Scouts on motorbikes had paved the way on Friday after Zairean soldiers fled in stolen vehicles, the sources said.</p>
<p>As in other cities taken by rebel leader Laurent Kabila's forces, the only reports of combat were between rival factions of Zaire's disintegrating army and not between army and rebels.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people wounded by the military were brought in from the bush this morning,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>He said rebel leaders were meeting the governor of Mbuji-Mayi and Mukamba Kadiata Nzemba, president of the MIBA diamond mining company which dominates the local economy and is Zaire's biggest foreign exchange earner.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope that when the negotiations are over the rebels will go in and clear the areas of the mines which have been invaded by illegal diggers,&quot; the mining source said.</p>
<p>Hundreds of people try to scrape a living out of the soil around Mbuji-Mayi, which is rich in industrial-quality diamonds. The best veins are inside MIBA's mining area, on the outskirts of the town, which is usually heavily guarded.</p>
<p>Inside the compound are mounds of gravel awaiting processing to extract remaining diamonds.</p>
<p>The sources said the town, some 1,000 km (600 miles) east of the capital Kinshasa and just as far west of the second city Lubumbashi, was calm on Saturday and overnight.</p>
<p>Early on Friday trouble started when soldiers set up roadblocks and robbed people of vehicles, watches and money.</p>
<p>They started firing around town, shooting locks off houses, shops, MIBA installations and the premises of Lebanese diamond buyers in the city -- many of whom had earlier fled.</p>
<p>&quot;Some soldiers took off their uniforms, shot their way in here and robbed us,&quot; said one source.</p>
<p>&quot;There was looting and shooting, they took all they could and then suddenly, at around 2 p.m., the soldiers left town. They made their escape in MIBA vehicles.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Then local people, mostly youths, started to pillage. We were attacked with stones by a crowd of hooligans, I was hit on the head,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>There was no immediate official word on what would be by far the biggest blow so far to the purse of the ailing Mobutu's authorities.</p>
<p>With the potentially rich copper and cobalt mines of Lubumbashi's Shaba province in disrepair, the diamonds of neighbouring Kasai province are Zaire's main earner.</p>
<p>Mobutu's opponents say much of the wealth went into the pockets of his officials or of diamond smugglers.</p>
<p>Rebels have taken about a quarter of Zaire since October and the fall of Mbuji-Mayi would be certain to raise tension in Lubumbashi, which Kabila has vowed to take and which looks increasingly likely to be next.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUBUMBASHI, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
