<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489277" id="root" date="1997-04-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Universal 1997 net seen at 1.025 bln pesos.</title>
<headline>Universal 1997 net seen at 1.025 bln pesos.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-04-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Universal Rightfield Property Holdings Inc said on Saturday it expected its net income to hit 1.025 billion pesos from 414 million last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Income growth this year will be propelled by the launching of (the company's) innovative leisure product, Universal Leisure Club,&quot; the firm said in a statement.</p>
<p>Universal Leisure Corp, a subsidiary of Universal Rightfield, has started selling an additional 1,000 &quot;membership shares&quot; in Universal Leisure Club Inc after it completed an initial offer of 1,000 shares.</p>
<p>Universal Rightfield said Universal Leisure Club's initial offer of 1,000 shares was underwritten on a firm basis by a group of investment banks that include Abacus Capital and Investment Corp and Keppel IVI Investments Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;Tenders for the membership shares of Universal Leisure Club ... exceeded the volume of the offering which started March 4, 1997,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Universal Leisure Club is a unit of Universal Leisure Corp.</p>
<p>Buyers of the shares are given the right to use Universal Leisure Club's facilities composed of a sports club and another business club in the city, two mountain resorts with an 18-hole golf course each, and one beach club.</p>
<p>--Manila newsroom (632) 841-89-36, fax 817-62-67</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
