<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489215" id="root" date="1997-04-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania reassures Italy over security force.</title>
<headline>Albania reassures Italy over security force.</headline>
<byline>Alister Doyle</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-04-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania sought on Saturday to reassure Rome about deployment of an Italian-led force to protect aid to anarchic Albania, saying troops will have maximum security and full backing from Tirana's government.</p>
<p>The Albanian state news agency ATA said that Prime Minister Bashkim Fino had spoken by telephone with Italian Foreign Minister Lamberto Dini to stress that Albanians wanted the 6,000-strong multinational force to help ease their crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;The Italian troops will have maximum security and complete support from the Albanian government and public opinion,&quot; Fino told Dini on Friday night, according to an official statement quoted by ATA.</p>
<p>Rome says deployment should start in the week starting on April 14.</p>
<p>&quot;The Prime Minister said that he was attentively following the debate in the Italian parliament on the problems and gave assurances that the concern expressed by some forces in (Italy's) parliamentary majority is exaggerated,&quot; ATA said.</p>
<p>Albania, racked by weeks of banditry, looting and insurrection in which scores of people have died, has been urging the fastest possible action since the U.N. Security Council approved the force a week ago.</p>
<p>Italy's parliament is to vote next week on deployment of the force to protect deliveries of food and medicines. Prime Minister Romano Prodi has enough opposition backing to win approval despite some dissent in his coalition.</p>
<p>Fausto Bertinotti, leader of the hard-left Communist Refoundation party that gives Prodi's centre-left government a parliamentary majority, has said he will vote against the mission.</p>
<p>Debate about deployment has been overshadowed by the sinking of a packed Albanian refugee vessel off Italy on March 28 in a collision with an Italian navy corvette, causing Albanian anger with Rome and raising extra worries for the troops' safety.</p>
<p>Many of the 34 survivors accused Italy of ramming the boat, something Italy denies. Tirana says that at least 80 people from the former communist country drowned but insists that anti-Italian passions have calmed since the sinking.</p>
<p>Italy is expected to provide between 2,000 and 2,500 troops, France 1,000, Greece 700, Turkey 500, Romania 400 and Spain 300. Austria and Denmark say they are also considering participation.</p>
<p>Many southern towns have been controlled by rebel councils since central government authority collapsed last month amid an armed uprising triggered by anger over the collapse of fraudulent savings schemes.</p>
<p>Apart from sporadic shooting and an overnight curfew, Tirana has been calm for days. Markets and shops are open, although prices have risen sharply.</p>
<p>President Sali Berisha faces new political headaches alongside the unrest after a group of 20 parliamentarians from his right-wing Democratic party said on Friday they would no longer &quot;accept the diktat of the president&quot;.</p>
<p>Accusing Berisha of amassing too much power, their criticism of the former heart surgeon was the strongest from his own ranks since Albania plunged close to anarchy last month. The disaffected deputies stopped short of a formal break with the party that won 122 of 140 seats in parliament last year.</p>
<p>The Albanian navy warned people against using dynamite for fishing near the rebel-held port of Vlore, saying that refugees who seized a military vessel had thrown mines and torpedoes overboard near a naval base to lighten the ship.</p>
<p>&quot;We recommend the population not to use dynamite for fishing...the consequences of an explosion may be catastrophic for the environment but also for the users themselves,&quot; Captain Vladimir Beja told Albanian television.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
