<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489263" id="root" date="1997-04-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Asian ministers to raise profile with forex views. [CORRECTED 10:02 GMT 06/04]</title>
<headline>Asian ministers to raise profile with forex views. [CORRECTED 10:02 GMT 06/04]</headline>
<dateline>CEBU, Philippines 1997-04-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>In a bid to pair their policy statements with their economic prominence, Asia-Pacific finance ministers are set for the first time to explicitly refer to the Group of Seven (G7) industrialised nations' view of current foreign exchange rates in a communique after their annual meeting (corrects by adding the reference to G7 and clarifying that such reference will be for the first time).</p>
<p>&quot;The finance ministers will make note of the fact that currency misalignments, as noted at the Group of Seven (G7) summit in Berlin in February, have been corrected,&quot; a Japanese delegation official said.</p>
<p>The 18-member Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) finance ministers forum ended its first full day of discussions on Saturday, working out proposals to be adopted at the finale on Sunday.</p>
<p>The other main thrust of the statement is the push to lure private cash into the region through efforts to standarise financial, corporate and legal terms within APEC's wildly diverse economies, which stretch from China to Chile, and Australia to Canada.</p>
<p>APEC members, which account for half the world's population and more than 40 percent of global trade, kept a characteristically low profile during the currency volatility around the spring of 1995, when the yen hit a low of 80 yen to the dollar.</p>
<p>The G7, which includes the three APEC members of the United States, Canada and Japan, and also Germany, Britain, France and Italy, called for a correction of the misalignment in currency levels at that time.</p>
<p>&quot;Given their relative size in the world economy, it's important for Asian countries to reach a common understanding over foreign exchange rates,&quot; a Japanese official said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CEBU, Philippines"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
