<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489211" id="root" date="1997-04-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin chides Belarus on reforms, human rights.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin chides Belarus on reforms, human rights.</headline>
<byline>Philippa Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-04-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin told Russians on Saturday not to worry about a controversial Union Treaty signed with Belarus last week and said he would try to bring reforms and human rights there up to scratch.</p>
<p>Blaming unnamed politicians for trying to force the pace of Russia's integration with its backward western neighbour, Yeltsin said that the treaty, scaled back at the last minute, allowed the people to decide how far and fast to go.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia will not sacrifice what we have achieved during the difficult times of reforms. We will not step back in order to be on a level with our ally and partner,&quot; Yeltsin said in an address broadcast nationwide on Radio Russia.</p>
<p>&quot;I will not hide that some politicians thought it would be possible...to present our peoples with a fait accompli. That is wrong. Russians should all get the chance to have their say in the making of such an important decision,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, keen to capitalise on widespread nostalgia in Russia for the former Soviet Union, signed the treaty with hardline Belarus President Alexander Lukashenko on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Lukashenko is unique among leaders of ex-Soviet republics in pressing for reunification with Russia, but his communist-style rule has proved an embarrassment to the Kremlin.</p>
<p>Moscow made 11th hour changes to the document after liberals in the government expressed fears it might make integration too fast and give Lukashenko a say in decisions affecting Russia.</p>
<p>On Friday Yeltsin, clearly embarrassed at having to get himself out of a diplomatic corner so publicly, sacked his top foreign policy adviser Dmitry Ryurikov, said by Kremlin sources to have tried to push integration too fast.</p>
<p>The treaty as signed was largely symbolic, Yeltsin said. &quot;It is the beginning of the path to unity, and not its end.&quot;</p>
<p>In a diplomatically worded swipe at Lukashenko, the Kremlin leader said that Russia was clearly ahead of Belarus in terms of its economic and political transition from communism.</p>
<p>&quot;Reforms are proceeding at differing paces in our countries...We have also advanced much further in building a law-governed state. We have succeeded more in providing democratic rights and civil liberties,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will do everything to make democratic values, freedom of speech and the media a common achievement of the Union.&quot;</p>
<p>Yeltsin also said he would not ignore Russian media organisations' concerns about their freedom to work in Belarus.</p>
<p>Minsk has expelled one Russian television correspondent for what it called biased reporting and threatened similar moves against other journalists working in Belarus.</p>
<p>The Russian foreign ministry expressed concern on Saturday that Russian journalists were among several people hurt in clashes between police and protesters in Minsk last week.</p>
<p>Asked to comment on Yeltsin's address, a senior Belarussian official said it was not a question of being behind but of having a different view on what progress meant.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, Yeltsin says that Russia has stepped ahead, but we simply understand differently what freedom is,&quot; Ivan Pashkevich, deputy head of Lukashenko's administration, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Boris Yeltsin was expressing not his own concern but that of a certain circle of society. We think the media should express objective reality and not subjective views,&quot; he said, adding that the opposition provoked last week's violence.</p>
<p>In the latest manifestation of his tough attitude toward officials, Lukashenko was reported to have sacked the mayor and senior officials of the city Borisov for allegedly hosting a drunken party on the day of the Union Treaty signing.</p>
<p>Lukashenko, who made a public dig at another local official last month for shampooing cows ahead of a presidential visit, plans a decree demanding more &quot;discipline&quot; throughout society.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
