<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489375" id="root" date="1997-04-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. prosecutors bring prison tax-scheme charges.</title>
<headline>U.S. prosecutors bring prison tax-scheme charges.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Federal prosecutors unveiled Friday an investigation dubbed operation &quot;Easy Money&quot; involving tax fraud charges against seven prisoners and two guards at Virginia's Lorton correctional facility.</p>
<p>U.S. Attorney Helen Fahey said the indictment alleged the inmates conspired to file false tax returns in 1994 that claimed the incarcerated prisoners actually were self-employed in various occupations and due a refund.</p>
<p>According to the indictment returned by a federal grand jury in Alexandria, Virginia, each inmate claimed exactly $6,950 in income, $5,600 in deductions, a self-employment tax of $981 and a $722 tax refund.</p>
<p>The Internal Revenue Service mailed refund checks to the Lorton post office box address used by the prisoners to get mail or to an address outside the prison, Fahey said.</p>
<p>She said a Lorton prison guard was charged in a separate indictment with filing false tax reports for 1992 through 1995, overstating his deductions, understating taxable income and improperly claiming refunds.</p>
<p>Last, Fahey said another correctional officer, who also prepared taxes, pleaded guilty to assisting in preparing false federal income tax returns for his clients, who included other guards and Washington, D.C., police officers.</p>
<p>She said the officer, William Jenkins, faces up to three years in prison at his sentencing in June. His scheme resulted in an estimated $71,000 tax loss for the government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
