<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48932" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAfrica banking shares rise after prime rate cuts.</title>
<headline>SAfrica banking shares rise after prime rate cuts.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in South Africa's &quot;Big Four&quot; banks rose on Thursday after First National Bank Holdings Ltd followed its rival Standard Bank Investment Corp Ltd in knocking a quarter point off its prime lending rate.</p>
<p>At 0930 GMT First National stock had jumped 25 cents to 27.80, Standard was up 250 cents to 175.25 rand, Nedcor was up 25 cents to 61.25 and Amalgamated Bank of South Africa (ABSA) was up five points to 22.65 rand.</p>
<p>Analysts said the move, which has brought Standard's and First National's prime rate down to 19.25 percent, was a sign the South African banking industry's margins were turning the corner.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is taking the view that things are a little bit more comfortable for the banks and there is a bit less pressure on margins now,&quot; said Doug Ellish, banking analyst at Standard Equities.</p>
<p>But Ellish warned the industry had not yet fully emerged from its difficult recent past. &quot;The pressure is off a little bit, but we are not out of the woods yet,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Standard said its rate cut reflected the government's decision to scrap the Financial Services Levy (FSL) and replace it with value added tax (VAT) on financial services from next month.</p>
<p>FSL was first introduced by the South African government in 1991, when banks increased prime by 0.25 percent to recover the cost.</p>
<p>Analysts said the move by First National and Standard should see Nedcor follow suit. &quot;(It) is going to have little choice but to do so,&quot; said one analyst who declined to be named.</p>
<p>Absa cut its prime rate by the same margin shortly before 1000 GMT.</p>
<p>The cuts could also pave the way for further decreases over the coming year with one analyst predicting 200 basis points could come off the rate by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>But analysts added that major cuts were unlikely during the rest of 1996.</p>
<p>-- Paul Harris, Johannesburg newsroom + 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
