<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489426" id="root" date="1997-04-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greece and Italy at odds over force in Albania.</title>
<headline>Greece and Italy at odds over force in Albania.</headline>
<byline>Costas Paris</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-04-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greece and Italy are at odds over the deployment of an Italian-led multinational force in lawless Albania with both sides pushing to deploy their troops in Tirana, key ports and road junctions, Greek officials said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;Every country (in the force) has its own preferences and there are different views from the ones proposed (by Italy),&quot; Defence Minister Akis Tsohatzopoulos, told reporters. &quot;In any case nothing will be valid if the governments involved don't agree.&quot;</p>
<p>Government officials said Athens was angry with a proposal by the force's Italian command that Greek troops should be stationed in Lezhe, about 90 km (55 miles) northwest of Tirana, while Italians would be in Tirana and the Adriatic port of Vlore.</p>
<p>&quot;Greece believes that the Albanian crisis can't be resolved by dividing the country in zones of influence,&quot; a senior government official told Reuters. &quot;Greek troops must be part of the force in Tirana and in other main towns.&quot;</p>
<p>Rome has said the 6,000-strong, United Nation-approved force should start deployment in the week starting on April 14.</p>
<p>Albania, rocked by weeks of chaos during which scores of people were killed, has urged the fastest possible deployment to secure the transport and distribution of humanitarian and technical aid.</p>
<p>Italy was expected to provide between 2,000 and 2,500 troops, France 1,000, Greece 700, Turkey 500, Romania 400 and Spain 300. Austria and Denmark said they may also paricipate.</p>
<p>Deployment plans have been overshadowed by the sinking of a packed Albanian refugee vessel off Italy on March 28 in a collision with an Italian navy corvette, causing Albanian anger with Rome and raising extra concern about the troops' safety.</p>
<p>Survivors accused the Italian captain of ramming the boat, something Rome denies. Tirana says that at least 80 people drowned but insists that anti-Italian passions have eased since the sinking.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Costas Simitis on Friday criticised Italy's handling of the refugee wave and urged robust European Union economic and techinical support for Albania and other poor Balkan nations.</p>
<p>&quot;When there is hunger and misery the solution is not one ship sinking another,&quot; Simitis said in a speech to a European socialist parties meeting. &quot;The solution is to prevent the mass exodus brought by hunger and misery. To make sure other (Balkan) countries don't face misery.&quot;</p>
<p>Thousands of Albanian refugees packed ships heading for Italy in the past weeks. Some 350,000 Albanians already live in Greece and Athens has increased patrols across the border with Albania to prevent another mass wave of refugees.</p>
<p>Analysts said Simitis' comments would fuel Greek-Italian antagonism before the final decision on the troops' deployment, expected on Monday.</p>
<p>Simitis said the EU and NATO should move faster in integrating Balkan nations and that the &quot;immediate response of the Union to the recent crisis in Albania was correct, but not sufficient&quot;.</p>
<p>State control has collapsed in Albania for the past month with many southern towns controlled by rebel councils. Army and police forces fled amid an armed uprising triggered by anger over the collapse of pyramid savings schemes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
