<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48959" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>Bosnia: EU official warns Mostar tensions getting worse.</title>
<headline>EU official warns Mostar tensions getting worse.</headline>
<dateline>MOSTAR, Bosnia 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union administrator of Mostar said on Thursday tensions in the divided Bosnian city were getting worse because of a sit-in by Moslems in the Croat-controlled western sector.</p>
<p>A standoff began on Wednesday when up to 200 people from Moslem east Mostar crossed into the west, saying they wanted to repair homes they had been forced to leave in 1993 during fighting between Moslems and Croats.</p>
<p>Last year's U.S.-brokered Dayton peace agreement guarantees all Bosnian refugees the right to return home.</p>
<p>But the Moslem action stoked tension. It began only three days before nationwide elections and the day the main party in west Mostar, the Croatian Democratic Union, staged a rally at a sports stadium in the city.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is serious and is becoming worse every moment,&quot; the head of the EU administration in Mostar, Sir Martin Garrod, told reporters.</p>
<p>Despite efforts by the EU, which is trying to unify the city, many of the Moslems camped out all night and were still there on Thursday afternoon.</p>
<p>Garrod defended the right of all refugees or displaced persons in the area to return home. &quot;I am one hundred percent for all the (displaced persons) returning to their homes in the whole of Mostar,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;The correct time and place must be chosen for that and it must be done according to arranged plans. Otherwise the situation becomes ten times worse than it was and we get the situation like we have now in Mostar.&quot;</p>
<p>Garrod held negotiations with the city's Croat mayor Ivan Prskalo and Moslem deputy mayor Safet Orucevic on Thursday, first separately and later together.</p>
<p>EU spokesman Dragan Gasic said the mayor had promised the houses would not be further damaged if the Moslems returned to east Mostar. Failing that, the Croat side would repair any new damage.</p>
<p>&quot;There is also a clear agreement in principle that they want and have to speak about return of refugees but they should start only after the elections,&quot; said Gasic.</p>
<p>Requests to return home should be made in writing and all deals should involve people from both communities. Before 1993 the city was ethnically mixed but the fighting forced all Moslems to the east and Croats to the west.</p>
<p>Gasic said the mayor and deputy mayor still had to sell the agreement to their own communities.</p>
<p>An official at east Mostar television, which has covered the sit-in since the start, questioned whether the Moslems would ever go back to the east.</p>
<p>&quot;They are repairing and cleaning their houses...They are not going back, they will stay there permanently,&quot; said tv bureau chief Emir Koso. &quot;Now they are working in shifts... They are just rebuilding the houses they own and that's all.&quot;</p>
<p>The Moslems spent the night in their homes, damaged in the war, or sleeping on the street. They seemed to be well organised -- power lines for lighting were laid from the Moslem east within an hour of their arrival.</p>
<p>Croat and Moslem police looked on from their sectors, along with officers of an international police force run by the Western European Union (WEU).</p>
<p>In a statement carried by the Croatian news agency HINA, Prskalo promised to try to defuse the situation.</p>
<p>The EU peace efforts have included municipal elections in June when a mayor and deputy for the whole city were elected. Before then, the Croat west and the Moslem east had separate mayors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSTAR, Bosnia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
