<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48956" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Mostar Croats, Moslems end 30-hour confrontation.</title>
<headline>Mostar Croats, Moslems end 30-hour confrontation.</headline>
<dateline>MOSTAR, Bosnia 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rival communities in the divided city of Mostar have ended a 30-hour confrontation which stoked tensions ahead of this weekend's post-war Bosnian elections.</p>
<p>Trouble began on Wednesday when up to 200 people from Moslem east Mostar crossed into the Croat-controlled west, saying they wanted to repair homes they had been forced to leave in 1993 during fighting between Moslems and Croats.</p>
<p>After refusing to move for more than a day, the Moslems returned to the eastern sector on Thursday under an agreement brokered by Sir Martin Garrod, who heads a European Union administration trying to unify the city.</p>
<p>&quot;People went back... and (agreed that) rebuilding of houses will be made by mutual agreement between east and west Mostar, authorised by the EU,&quot; said Wolfgang Odendahl, local head of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE).</p>
<p>Garrod had expressed deep concern about the standoff, when Moslem and Croat police faced each other near the &quot;confrontation line&quot; dividing the two communities.</p>
<p>Some officials said the action, which began as the main party in the west, the Croatian Democratic Union, held an election rally, had seemed well prepared.</p>
<p>But Odendahl said he believed it had nothing to do with the elections which the OSCE is organising.</p>
<p>&quot;That was a group of refugees who are frustrated and who decided to take the matter into their own hands,&quot; he said. Odendahl said he had been reassured that deputy Mostar mayor Safet Orucevic had not condoned the action.</p>
<p>&quot;We have agreed, having in mind the upcoming elections, that we want to soothe all tensions,&quot; Orucevic told Bosnian state radio.</p>
<p>Under the agreement with Garrod and mayor Ivan Prskalo, a Croat, a pilot project will be staged under which refugees from both communities could return to their homes in the district of Podhum, where the confrontation took place.</p>
<p>The project would involve the EU and United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees. &quot;The UNHCR and the EU will repair these houses for those people and enable them to return to their homes,&quot; said Orucevic.</p>
<p>&quot;Mayor Prskalo guaranteed there would be no destruction of the houses in their part of Mostar and we have given guarantees there will be no destruction of Croats' houses.&quot;</p>
<p>Moslems and Croats are officially allied in a federation and in some parts of Bosnia work well together. But Mostar has long been a flashpoint and violence flared there early this year.</p>
<p>Garrod was not available for comment but earlier he had expressed concern. &quot;The situation is serious and is becoming worse every moment,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Garrod defended the right of all refugees or displaced persons in the area to return home. &quot;I am 100 percent for all the (displaced persons) returning to their homes in the whole of Mostar,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;The correct time and place must be chosen for that and it must be done according to arranged plans. Otherwise the situation becomes 10 times worse than it was and we get the situation like we have now in Mostar.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSTAR, Bosnia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
