<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489673" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Tight security for Britain's postponed &quot;National&quot;.</title>
<headline>Tight security for Britain's postponed &quot;National&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Dave Thompson</byline>
<text>
<p>LIVERPOOL, England, April 7 - Britain's most famous horse race, the Grand National steeplechase, is to be run amid a security &quot;ring of steel&quot; on Monday, 48 hours after a bomb alert blamed on the IRA forced it to be postponed.</p>
<p>Organisers hope 10,000 spectators, defying the Irish Republican Army's bomb threats, will turn up at Aintree racecourse near Liverpool for the 150th Grand National.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to put a ring of steel around this race course,&quot; said Mark Sutcliffe of Merseyside police.</p>
<p>As Britain's May 1 general election approaches, the IRA has stepped up its campaign of violence against British rule in Northern Ireland in a clear attempt to force the issue on to the political agenda.</p>
<p>Police received two coded bomb warnings just 30 minutes before the race was due to start on Saturday. They mounted a massive security sweep, carrying out three controlled explosions on suspect packages but finding no bombs.</p>
<p>Nearly 70,000 people were evacuated from the course after the race was postponed and thousands of racegoers were stranded overnight in Liverpool while police checked 7,000 cars and coaches in the Aintree carparks.</p>
<p>Drivers were allowed to retrieve their vehicles on Sunday after police using sniffer dogs trained to detect explosives gave the all clear.</p>
<p>Owners, jockeys and trainers were adamant that the race should be run on Monday and it is now scheduled to start at 1700 (1600 GMT).</p>
<p>&quot;We're not going to be put off by a bit of aggro (trouble),&quot; said Charlie Brooks, trainer of Suny Bay, one of the favourites.</p>
<p>Fellow trainer Jenny Pitman, who burst into tears when the race was called off, said: &quot;It must go ahead for the sake of racing and the whole country. Otherwise there will be calls from terrorists to every big sporting event.&quot;</p>
<p>Fears that Sunday's soccer league cup final between Leicester City and Middlesbrough at London's Wembley stadium could also fall victim to bomb threats proved unfounded. The match, a 1-1 draw, was played without incident amid heavy security.</p>
<p>At Aintree, staff worked flat out to prepare the track as police searched the sprawling racecourse complex in an operation expected to continue until Monday afternoon.</p>
<p>Deputy police chief Paul Stephenson said: &quot;No one has yet claimed responsibility for the bomb threats and we can all draw our own conclusions from that.&quot;</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Major said he had no doubt that the IRA was to blame for the bomb scare, which he said could only hinder peace efforts in Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>&quot;These people are murderers. They have murdered before. They will murder again, and people ought not to take these threats lightly,&quot; Major told BBC television.</p>
<p>He said the Aintree bomb threat, which came after IRA bombs were found at major road and railway points in England, would only hurt prospects that the IRA's political allies, Sinn Fein, could take part in peace talks.</p>
<p>In Liverpool more than 2,000 people were forced to spend Saturday night wherever they could find an empty corner out of the blustery weather. One couple slept in a hotel sauna, another racegoer in the stable lads' hostel on the course.</p>
<p>&quot;The public were ringing in with offers,&quot; said an employee at Liverpool's social services department. &quot;I think some pubs and clubs were open all night to try and help out.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
