<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489793" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: APEC says region must keep developing-voluntarily.</title>
<headline>APEC says region must keep developing-voluntarily.</headline>
<byline>Abi Sekimitsu</byline>
<dateline>CEBU, Philippines</dateline>
<text>
<p>APEC finance ministers sent out a call Sunday for more private cash to keep developing the world's fastest growing area and pointed the region toward freer, more open financial and capital markets.</p>
<p>In a weekend gathering devoid of drama and high on &quot;voluntary&quot; action, the ministers also judged current exchange rates acceptable and patted themselves on the back for keeping the &quot;Asian miracle&quot; going.</p>
<p>But their final communique strongly hinted that the time had come for all countries to make their financial and capital markets more credible so that private investors would feel safe enough to put up the money needed to upgrade infrastructure like roads and communications.</p>
<p>Economists estimate that $1.5 trillion is needed for infrastructure work to cope with the growth in goods and services in the region covered by the 18-member Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum.</p>
<p>APEC comprises Australia, Brunei, Canada, China, Chile, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Japan, South Korea, Malaysia, Mexico, New Zealand, Papua New Guinea, the Philippines, Singapore, Taiwan, Thailand and the United States.</p>
<p>APEC has set as its goal the removal of barriers to free trade and investment by 2010 for developed countries like the United States and Japan and by 2020 for developing nations.</p>
<p>Sunday's final communique recommmended more uniform regulation among members, increased transparency and availability of information, making international investment easier, and liberalising markets.</p>
<p>However, the finance ministers set no specific time frames for the initiatives.</p>
<p>&quot;As with previous meetings, our discussions were conducted in the spirit of cooperation, consensus-building and collegiality,&quot; the communique said.</p>
<p>The ministers also agreed to closer cooperation among export financing banks, as proposed by Japan, the strengthening of financial market supervision, a U.S. proposal, and developing domestic rating agencies, put forward by the Philippines, who chaired the meeting.</p>
<p>They also called for the prompt resumption of the World Trade Organisation's financial services talks, urging WTO members to agree to commitments on improving market access.</p>
<p>The economically diverse region, which accounts for half the world's population and 40 percent of its trade, &quot;continued to expand more rapidly than the rest of the world in 1996,&quot; the communique said, despite a slowdown in some members' economies.</p>
<p>An APEC advisory group of private financiers recommended steps to nurture fully fledged capital markets throughout the region and a standardisation of accounting principles so that member economies can draw on private money to invest in much-needed infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>The ministers said major currency misalignments, which could have negative effects on members' trade and economies, had been corrected.</p>
<p>That is something the powerful Group of Seven (G7) nations -- Britain, Japan, Canada, Italy, France, Germany and the United States -- have been saying, and could be seen as an endorsement of current exchange rates.</p>
<p>Malaysian Finance Minister Anwar Ibrahim said the currency comment in the communique was partly in response to the G7.</p>
<p>&quot;We think that any intervention or various expressions on the issue should take into consideration all of the international community and not be confined to the established group,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the comment was not a sign of APEC aggressiveness, but a question of gaining confidence and having APEC's own mechanism to cope with unpredictable developments.</p>
<p>But unlike more formal counterparts such as the G7 or European Union, APEC in its declaration remained resolutely Asian, favouring consensus over any confrontational tactics.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a consensus that the idea of opening up, liberalisation, private-sector participation is the way to go,&quot; Philippine Finance Secretary Roberto de Ocampo, chairman of the meeting, said.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;Nobody is forcing anybody to do it along any particular timing. Everybody has his own timing and it is recognised by everybody.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CEBU, Philippines"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
