<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489738" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Fujimori back in Lima to seek peaceful crisis end.</title>
<headline>Fujimori back in Lima to seek peaceful crisis end.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-04-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peru's Alberto Fujimri returned from a 24-hour visit to Bolivia on Saturday after pledging not to use force to secure the freedom of 72 hostages held by Marxist rebels in Lima for 109 days.</p>
<p>Fujimori arrived in Lima on Saturday evening amid intense speculation that one of the crisis mediators had taken negotiations directly to the hostage-taker leadership.</p>
<p>Roman Catholic Bishop Juan Luis Cipriani, a member of a three-man mediation team in the 15-week standoff, visited a naval base in the port of Callao where Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) leader Victor Polay and other MRTA prisoners were serving life sentences.</p>
<p>Cipriani spoke to Polay during the hour-long visit to the prison on Friday evening, local radio said, though Cipriani had no comment.</p>
<p>Fujimori told reporters he had not talked to Cipriani about the visit but would be in contact with him soon after arriving in Lima.</p>
<p>Local newspapers speculated on Saturday that Cipriani hoped Polay would convince Nestor Cerpa Cartolini, leader of the 20-odd MRTA guerrillas holed up in the Japanese ambassador's residence in Lima, to give up his struggle.</p>
<p>&quot;Bishop tries to make Polay release Cerpa from his main demand: the release of MRTA prisoners,&quot; La Republica newspaper said.</p>
<p>A serious-looking Fujimori gave little away during his brief trip to Bolivia where he met with Bolivian President Gonzalo Sanchez de Losada.</p>
<p>In a joint news conference the two leaders stressed that every effort was being made to secure a peaceful end to the crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;The use of force is a move which would become the last (resource), in case of an incontrollable emergency which we hope will not come about,&quot; Fujimori said.</p>
<p>The Bolivian leader said his government could not bow to MRTA rebels' demands for freedom for their four comrades in Bolivia, echoing Fujimori's own stand on the 450 MRTA prisoners in Peruvian jails.</p>
<p>The MRTA has been holding Bolivian ambassador Jorge Gumucio, Japanese ambassador Morihisa Aoki, two Peruvian government ministers and scores of dignitaries, including two dozen Japanese diplomats and businessmen, at Aoki's residence in Lima since Dec. 17, 1996.</p>
<p>The rebels offered to free Gumucio in exchange for the release of four comrades jailed in Bolivia. But Sanchez de Lozada said the rebels were in the hands of Bolivian judges and outside his jurisdiction.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no way that under our legal system the executive branch can take a decision about it.&quot;</p>
<p>Sanchez de Lozada said he was concerned by the deadlock in talks to solve Latin America's longest hostage siege, but he trusted Lima and Tokyo would find a peaceful way out.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a delicate situation, anything can happen,&quot; he told reporters. &quot;But we are encouraged by the positions of Japan and Peru.&quot;</p>
<p>Cipriani and fellow mediators Canadian Ambassador Anthony Vincent and Red Cross representative Michel Minnig spent an hour inside the diplomatic mansion in the wealthy San Isidro district of Lima on Saturday afternoon.</p>
<p>The three men have visited the residence virtually every day since formal negotiations between the government and the MRTA broke down March 12.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
