<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489719" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania urges looters to hand in radioactive parts.</title>
<headline>Albania urges looters to hand in radioactive parts.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-04-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania urged looters on Sunday to return lethal chemicals and radioactive materials, some of them used in radars, that were seized from military bases during an insurrection last month.</p>
<p>&quot;They can kill...please hand them back,&quot; Colonel Asllan Bushati, head of the army chemistry unit, told Albanian television.</p>
<p>He said the materials were stolen from four depots during an armed rebellion in March triggered by protests at the collapse of popular savings schemes. Bushati said the objects had no value or use for civilians.</p>
<p>The radioactive objects, some looking like square tiles and others tiny capsules, contained strontium or cobalt, he said. Some parts were used in radars and remained radioactive for up to 30 years.</p>
<p>Barrels containing chemicals that could sting eyes or skin and make breathing difficult had also been stolen, he said.</p>
<p>Bushati also urged people not to abandon the radioactive objects in fields. &quot;They pass from grass to livestock,&quot; he said, warning that the radiation could then end up in beef and pass to humans.</p>
<p>British-based defence experts Jane's Information Group says in a 1996 report that Albania has chemicals, like tear gas, for riot control but has no programmes for developing chemical weapons.</p>
<p>It also says there is no evidence that Albania's former communist rulers, who ruled until 1990, ever sought to develop biological weapons. Albania has no nuclear weapons.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
