<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489762" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News - April 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News - April 7.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>In a move which comes amid signs of another possible delay in the release of the long-awaited report of the Wallis inquiry into the financial system, Federal Treasurer Peter Costello yesterday rejected criticism that the inquiry would recommend a relaxation of bank merger rules, saying the main issue in the report was the regulation of electronic commerce. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to AIDC Mortgage Finance head John Rowe, non-bank lenders will have to increase their variable home loan interest rates following the Commonwealth Bank's announcement in mid-February that it had cut its rates by 0.7 per cent, which triggered a rise in the benchmark 90-day bank bill rate to 6.1 per cent and rising. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following the commitment of most State Governments to increasingly privatise their public hospital systems, private hospital operators, including Ramsay Healthcare - Australia's third-largest private hospital operator, are becoming locked in an intense battle to win a bigger share of the A$10 billion spent on public hospitals per annum. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Ernst &amp; Young's Noelle Kelleher has warned a loophole in last year's Budget concerning maximum deductible contribution limits has created uncertainty over tax deductions for superannuation contributions for employers with defined benefit funds. Kelleher aso said changes to the rules for the contribution limits may encourage small businesses to switch from accumulation funds to defined benefit funds to claim higher levels of deductions. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>In a bid to exploit Labor's leniency with Queensland Senator Mal Colston, the Federal Government is re-examining 14-year-old fraud allegations against the Senate deputy president and Prime Minister John Howard has indicated he will call in Federal Police to examine discrepancies in Colston's travel expenses if there was any evidence of a breach of the law. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Indy Carnival Classic at Surfers Paradise was abandoned and restarted after nearly an hour's delay yesterday after young Brazilian racing driver Christian Fittipaldi, 26, rammed a concrete safety barrier in the main straight in a horrific 290 kilometre-an-hour crash, suffering multiple fractures to his lower right leg. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a move which has embarrassed Prime Minister John Howard and has reopened deep wounds within the West Australian Liberal Party, Ross Lightfoot, has been secured as the State's next Liberal Senator with the help of disgraced former senator Noel Crichton-Browne. Lightfoot has been criticised for his strong views on Aboriginal culture. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In an article in the Medical Journal of Australia today, in-vitro fertilisation pioneer Professor Carl Wood, the head of IVF research at Monash University, indicated women facing the loss of their ovaries will be able to freeze and store small segments of their ovarian tissue under new Australian research which could restore their menstrual cycle and allow natural conception. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>In a surprise turnaround aimed at avoiding United States-style managed care and ownership by foreign multinationals, the Australian Medical Association has dropped its long-held opposition to medical ownership of private hospitals and is predicting many more private hospitals could soon be owned and managed by the same doctors who refer patients to them. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Responding to comments last week that Pierre Botte, chief executive officer of the owner of the main East Circular Quay site, Hong Kong Shanghai Hotels Ltd, had denied any interest in a compromise, architect Neville Gruzman, an organiser of a mass rally opposed to the plans, told the rally of about 3,500 people yesterday there is still a &quot;tiny crack&quot; through which Botte might be persuaded to change his mind. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a revelation that provides an insight into one of the many missing links in the Bougainville missionaries saga, it has been revealed that mining magnate Robert Friedland, a part-time Australian resident who bought one of Sydney's most expensive harbouride mansions in 1996, has links to the Sandline mercenaries through a deal he brokered last year. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a move which comes as the Coalition tries to shift the focus to the Federal Opposition for its failure to act over controversial Senator Mal Colston when Labor was in office, Prime Minister John Howard vowed yesterday he would see that police investigate Colston if his Government learned the senator had broken the law. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Following its forward estimates for the ABC's budget, the Finance Department is pushing for further cuts of up to A$14 million - beyond the A$55 million announced by the Howard Government in 1996. The Department has allegedly allocated A$486 million for the national broadcaster in the coming year, compared to A$500 million proposed in the Mansfield review of the ABC. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to a letter dated November 17, 1995 from the Victorian Justice Department, obtained under the Freedom of Information Act, in the same month that the State Police were brought on to the controversial A$170 million Intergraph dispatch system, currently under investigation by the Auditor-General, the Victorian Government withheld part of its monthly payments to Intergraph because of a &quot;major fault&quot;. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Canadian-based television broadcaster CanWest Global Communications Corporation has rejected a claim from the Australian Broadcast Authority that CanWest breached foreign ownership regulations by increasing its stake in the Ten Group. CanWest chairman Israel Asper said the company believes the ABA erred both in law and in its interpretation of the transaction and said the broadcaster may resort to legal action over the ruling. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Police ethical standards department Commander Tom McGrath said Victorian Police have seized computer disks and sound equipment linked to the break-in at the St Kilda Road drug squad offices, from two properties at Mount Cottrell. A gun and drug-related substances were also seized from the two properties during the week. The stolen equipment contained sensitive information concerning a five-year undercover drug operation. Page 3.</p>
<p>Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
