<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489836" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai state enterprises face privatisation.</title>
<headline>Thai state enterprises face privatisation.</headline>
<byline>Vithoon Amorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-04-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's slow privatisation of bureaucratic-rooted state enterprises got a boost this week from a cabinet plan to permit majority private equity participation.</p>
<p>The cabinet this week instructed ministries to produce detailed plans for trimming government ownership in 29 state enterprises to less than 50 percent. It sought more private roles in the agencies to help ease public sector financing.</p>
<p>&quot;Our target is for various ministries to come up with privatisation master plans in a few months. The idea is to see concrete changes within the term of this government,&quot; said Suriyon Thankijjanukij of the National Economic and Social Development Board (NESDB), a government think-tank.</p>
<p>He said eight state enterprises, including major companies in the transport and communications sector, would receive high priority because their privatisation would produce economic benefits for the public.</p>
<p>The eight included the Telephone Organisation of Thailand (TOT) and the Communications Authority of Thailand (CAT), whose privatisation had been eagerly awaited by investors -- especially foreign telecom companies dealing with the two agencies.</p>
<p>TOT and CAT, operating mostly telecom monopolies, boast a combined annual profit of 30 billion baht ($1.15 billion).</p>
<p>Government planners and private analysts have debated in the past year on whether TOT and CAT should first be merged before they are privatised, in line with Thailand's commitment to the World Trade Organisation (WTO) to open up its telecom industry by 2006.</p>
<p>TOT executives have said since mid-1996 that the monopoly aimed to cut its current 100 percent government ownership to 49 percent within two years, but future foreign equity participation would be limited to 20 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;I think foreign participation would benefit the two agencies, which need technology modernisation to cope with rapid expansion,&quot; said Khanchit Assavasamrarn of Vickers Ballas Co.</p>
<p>He said another lucrative business on the speedy privatisation list that should attract investors was the Liquor Distillery Organisation, a whisky monopoly.</p>
<p>Past attempts to privatise some of Thailand's 83 state enterprises, either through direct equity sales or granting concessions on expansion projects, met stiff resistance from unionised workers fearful of losing employment benefits because of management changes.</p>
<p>More than 1,000 air cargo workers of Thai Airways International Plc went on strike for several days last November to stop the government from spinning off the carrier's profitable ground air cargo handling operation to a private company.</p>
<p>Thai Airways went public in 1992 but only seven percent of its state-owned equity had been divested. The airline was among those slated for adopting a more corporate management style with majority private ownership.</p>
<p>The 33-member State Enterprise Relations Association had threatened to stage a mass protest rally later this month if the government refused to scrap a plan to sell off power plants of the Electricity Generating Authority of Thailand (EGAT).</p>
<p>But Suriyon of the NESDB said: &quot;It would be easier than people think. Employees in these agencies realise that they could not remain dead wood by refusing to accept changes. They agree that their future has come to a dead-end under current bureaucracy.&quot;</p>
<p>Other enterprises that the government sought to reduce its majority holding were the Port Authority of Thailand, Transport Co, Thai Maritime Navigation Co and the Playing Cards Factory.</p>
<p>(US$1 = 26 baht)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
