<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489886" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: UAE oil storage project in Fujairah launched.</title>
<headline>UAE oil storage project in Fujairah launched.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-04-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shipping and tank storage firm Van Ommeren Tank Terminal (VOTT) and the Emirates National Oil Company (ENOC) on Sunday announced the start of an $85 million oil product storage project.</p>
<p>ENOC chief executive and chairman of the new company, Van Ommeren Tank Terminal Fujairah Limited, Hussain Sultan, announced construction of the facility which will take 18 months to complete.</p>
<p>He said the first contract for dredging and reclamation was awarded about ten days ago and other deals including mechanical and piping works, storage tanks and an offshore marine terminal are due to be awarded in the next few weeks, according to a press statement.</p>
<p>Sultan did not say which companies won the contracts.</p>
<p>Total tankage of the facility, the first independent terminal for petroleum products in Fujairah, will amount to 479,000 cubic metres to handle gasoline, naphtha, condensate, jet fuel, gasoil, kerosene, MTBE, methanol and fuel oil.</p>
<p>The storage and product blending facilities would allow oil trading firms to capitalise on supply opportunities in the Middle East, Indian subcontinent and Asian product markets.</p>
<p>India, Pakistan, Sri Lanka and Nepal are already important and regular refined product buyers from the Gulf and Singapore spot markets, and demand is set to grow strongly.</p>
<p>ENOC and VOTT each hold 30 percent of the new terminal in Fujairah, one of seven emirates in the United Arab Emirates and a major Gulf bunkering port. The Fujairah government has a 20 percent share through its Fujairah Petroleum Investment Establishment.</p>
<p>ENOC is wholly-owned by the government of Dubai.</p>
<p>VOTT operates 1.9 million cubic metres of storage terminals in Asia and 13.4 million worldwide. The terminals are used by traders in oil imports, breaking bulk, blending, redistribution and bunkering.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
