<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489813" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Rubin nudges world fin'l services talks forward.</title>
<headline>Rubin nudges world fin'l services talks forward.</headline>
<byline>Rich Miller</byline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-04-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin gave the soon-to-be-restarted global negotiations on financial market liberalization a gentle nudge forward at a meeting of Asia-Pacific finance ministers on Sunday.</p>
<p>Rubin, who came here after attending the weekend meeting in the Philippines, told reporters that he raised the issue, even though it was not on the formal agenda.  </p>
<p>&quot;The United States very much wants to reach a financial services agreement this year,&quot; Rubin said he told his fellow ministers from the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) group. &quot;But it has obviously got to be a good agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>In its final communique, the 18-member APEC voiced support for the resumption of the financial services talks and said it was aiming for a broad-based, significant pact &quot;in the agreed time frame&quot; -- meaning, U.S. officials said, by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The APEC nations are a very important part of whether we get a good agreement,&quot;Rubin said.  </p>
<p>The negotiations are scheduled to resume later this week in Geneva under the auspices of the World Trade Organization. The talks broke down in 1995 after the United States decided that some developing countries had not offered to do enough to liberalize their markets.</p>
<p>Those developing nations were wary about doing more in part because of fears that their markets would end up being dominated by foreign financial firms and subject to the whims of foreign investors.  </p>
<p>Rubin though argued that developing countries had much to gain from the expertise and capital of international financial firms.</p>
<p>He also said that developing countries could cope with the ebbs and flows of portfolio investment if they pressed ahead with some of the reforms discussed at the APEC meeting.</p>
<p>They include improved clearing and settlement procedures and the creation of bond rating agencies.</p>
<p>&quot;There was permeating all of this some uneasiness about these large flows of portfolio capital,&quot; Rubin said of the APEC discussions.  </p>
<p>&quot;What we were trying to say is that you have all of these reforms in place, then you have effective capital markets that can easily handle the ebbs and flows of portfolio (investment),&quot; he added.</p>
<p>U.S. officials have also made clear to developing countries that they can phase in their financial sector reforms over a number of years, provided they make a firm commitment to carry them out.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
