<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489979" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Former Norwegian premier to seek top job at WHO.</title>
<headline>Former Norwegian premier to seek top job at WHO.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-04-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Norwegian prime minister Gro Harlem Brundtland has agreed to stand as a candidate for the top job at the United Nations World Health Organisation (WHO), the Norwegian Foreign Ministry said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Brundtland, 57, a medical doctor by training, resigned as prime minister last October after dominating Norwegian politics for more than a decade. She subsequently declared she would also quit parliament this year.</p>
<p>&quot;She has said 'yes' to be at the disposal (of the WHO) if there is broad support for her candidacy by the member countries of the WHO,&quot; Geir Pedersen, spokesman at the Foreign Ministry, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Pedersen said Brundtland had received requests from several WHO-members to give a positive signal to the agency's board and had now delivered her intention before the May deadline.</p>
<p>The national NTB news agency reported on Sunday that both Britain and the United States were among those who had asked her to stand as a candidate.</p>
<p>The three-time Norwegian premier has long been muted as a favourite to head the Geneva-based WHO although Brundtland herself has always refused to comment on speculation that she might leave Norway for an international position.</p>
<p>The leading international health institution has come under increasing criticism both from within and outside the agency for mismanagement. The authority is expected to announce in May, 1998 a new director general, who will take over from incumbent Dr Hiroshi Nakajima of Japan the following July.</p>
<p>Brundtland has enjoyed international recognition since 1983 as chairwoman of the U.N. World Commission on Environment and Development and is also known as a champion of women's issues.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
