<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="490011" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Non-aligned to demand economic, political equality.</title>
<headline>Non-aligned to demand economic, political equality.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Verma</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign ministers from more than 70 developing nations will press to be treated as equals in the global economy and demand more power in the United Nations when they meet in New Delhi this week.</p>
<p>The Non-Aligned Movement (NAM) conference, starting on Monday, will tackle the problems of patchy economic development, nuclear arms control, environmental damage and growing poverty, according to a draft of the two-day meeting's conclusions.</p>
<p>&quot;What the Movement has always stood for is self-reliance; what it expects from its partners in the developed world...is the cooperation of equals,&quot; says the draft final document, obtained by Reuters and due to be adopted on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Countries and regions still recovering from the ravages of colonialism and tackling problems which had in part been a residue of alien rule, should not again be subjected to solutions, no matter how well meant, that ignore their wishes and the unique features of each problem.&quot;</p>
<p>The movement, created in 1961 as a platform for countries that wanted to remain neutral during the Cold War, groups 113 nations, most of them developing, post-colonial nations.</p>
<p>The impact of global economic forces on weaker developing countries has been much greater in the 1990s than ever before, the document says.</p>
<p>&quot;At a time when attention to development and enhancement of the quality of life in poorer societies should be the highest priority, international commitment to supporting development has been weakening,&quot; it says.</p>
<p>The statement attributes environmental damage in developing countries to the constraints of poverty rather than unsustainable over-consumption, and says rooting out poverty is therefore vital to &quot;sustainable development&quot;.</p>
<p>The movement will urge the World Trade Organisation to ensure that poorer countries' trade opportunities are not hurt by protectionist measures &quot;in the guise of technical standards, environmental, social and human rights-related concerns&quot;.</p>
<p>The non-aligned countries, which form the largest grouping within the U.N., will also demand that the powerful Security Council be expanded to include developing nations.</p>
<p>&quot;Attempts to exclude NAM from any enlargement in the membership of the Council are unacceptable,&quot; the document says. &quot;Expansion of permanent membership only to accommodate industrialised countries is unacceptable.&quot;</p>
<p>The panel's five permanent members -- Britain, China, France, Russia and the United States -- are also the five declared nuclear powers. Germany and Japan are the leading candidates to become new permanent members, but India and Brazil are pressing their cases.</p>
<p>The draft document accuses the nuclear powers of lacking the political will to dismantle their arsenals.</p>
<p>&quot;They expressed their concern at measures aimed at blocking, for political ends, the transfer of technology to developing countries...for peaceful developmental purposes.&quot;</p>
<p>Commenting on violence in the Middle East, the movement's members say ministers &quot;reaffirmed their full support for the legitimate struggle of the Palestinian people...and reiterated their demand for the withdrawal of Israel from all occupied Palestinian and other Arab lands,&quot; including Lebanon.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat was scheduled to address the meeting on Monday morning.</p>
<p>The ministers also urged the Security Council to review an air embargo imposed on Libya, and called on the United States to end all economic and commercial action against Cuba.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
