<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="490016" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India crisis deepens as war of words escalates.</title>
<headline>India crisis deepens as war of words escalates.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>War of nerves or game of chicken, India's ruling coalition and its rival Congress party have set themselves on a collision course which has raised Hindu nationalists' hopes of seizing power.</p>
<p>The harsh rhetoric heated up at the weekend, overshadowing efforts by leaders of Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's United Front (UF) alliance and Congress to strike a bargain before a vote of confidence in parliament set for April 11.</p>
<p>Congress president Sitaram Kesri, who sparked the crisis on March 30 when he unexpectedly announced his party was revoking its vital support for Deve Gowda, stepped up his attacks on the prime minister.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not have any grudge against the United Front, but this man -- the prime minister -- is not only inefficient but communal,&quot; Kesri told supporters on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;Communal&quot; is a code word in Indian politics for the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), which its opponents accuse of fanning communal tensions by favouring India's Hindu majority at the expense of minority Moslems.</p>
<p>The BJP, which held power for 12 days in May, is the single biggest party in the 542-member lower house of parliament with 162 seats. The United Front has 180 and Congress 140.</p>
<p>Bitter electoral opponents, the United Front and Congress were driven together after inconclusive general elections last year by fear of the BJP.</p>
<p>But Kesri's deep animosity towards Deve Gowda, apparently fuelled in part by a string of court cases involving Congress leaders, has nearly torn the tenuous alliance apart.</p>
<p>Two dozen Congress deputies signed a letter to President Shankar Dayal Sharma on Saturday accusing the Deve Gowda government of &quot;unprincipled politics of vendetta and vengeance through fabrication of false cases against top leaders&quot;.</p>
<p>In response, the United Front accused Kesri of &quot;abusive personal attacks&quot; on Deve Gowda which a coalition spokesman said were at odds with the dignity of the Congress chief's office.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Kesri) has no people's issues to raise but only personal attacks to embark upon,&quot; United Front spokesman Jaipal Reddy said.</p>
<p>Newspapers said the two sides had dug in their heels, apparently undermining hopes of a quick settlement that would avert snap polls. &quot;Stalemate as Congress Hardens Stand&quot;, &quot;UF, Congress Heading for Showdown&quot;, &quot;Voices Turn Sour, Bitter&quot; were some headlines.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a war of nerves,&quot; columnist Hari Shankar Vyas wrote in The Pioneer on Sunday. &quot;The one who retreats or fumbles, defeat is in store for him.&quot;</p>
<p>Ashis Nandy of the Centre for the Study of Developing Societies said: &quot;Both are playing chicken.&quot;</p>
<p>The BJP waited gleefully on the sidelines. &quot;Let us be ready for governance,&quot; BJP president L.K. Advani told the party's national executive meeting on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very unstable, short-lived experiment which will collapse soon,&quot; Advani said in an interview published in The Pioneer on Sunday.</p>
<p>United Front and Congress leaders were pursuing informal talks to try to defuse the mounting tension. Kesri met former prime minister V.P. Singh, a front stalwart who has been negotiating from a Delhi hospital bed, late on Saturday and emerged, saying: &quot;The talks were good.&quot;</p>
<p>While there was no sign of a breakthrough, analysts said the two sides, driven together by fear of fresh polls which could propel the BJP into power, could still patch up differences.</p>
<p>&quot;It is rhetoric, but geared to bargaining,&quot; Nandy said. &quot;They are working towards a climbdown on both sides.&quot;</p>
<p>A compromise position would keep Deve Gowda in power for now with Congress taking on some key ministerial portfolios and the two sides forming a coordination committee to smooth ties.</p>
<p>But eventually Deve Gowda might have to go, Nandy said. &quot;Ultimately the United Front doesn't care a bit if Deve Gowda goes or not,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
