<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="490051" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks end mixed despite key index gains.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks end mixed despite key index gains.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>CHANGE				    CHANGE</p>
<p>TSE	  5840.78    +23.49   HI 5851.76	    LO  5831.25</p>
<p>DJI	  6555.91    +29.84   GOLD (LONDON)   US$349.00 +1.60</p>
<p>FTSE100    4271.70    +35.10   GOLD (NY-COMEX) US$351.40 -0.30</p>
<p>NIKKEI    17715.67   -144.92   LME CASH NICKEL US$7190  -350.0</p>
<p>CANDLR	1.3869		 LME CASH ALUM   US$1550.0 -33.0</p>
<p>CAN 30-YR   107.30     +0.85   BRENT CRUDE     US$17.78  +0.08</p>
<p>--------------------MARKET COMMENT----------------------------</p>
<p>* Toronto's key index closed higher on Monday but the broader market ended mixed, dragged down by a sell-off in golds and base metals. * 83 million shares traded worth C$1.3 billion.  </p>
<p>Toronto's key equities index closed higher on Monday, aided by Friday's strength, but the broader market closed mixed as investors sold off Bre-X Minerals Ltd and other mining issues.</p>
<p>The Toronto Stock Exchange's 300 Composite Index rose 23.49 points to 5840.78. Trading was moderate at 82.9 million shares worth C$1.34 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we carried over from the rally we got late on Friday in New York,&quot; said ScotiaMcLeod senior vice-president Fred Ketchen. The Dow Jones Industrial Average soared 48 points in late trading.  </p>
<p>Big mutual fund managers decided Toronto fell far enough last week and re-entered the market, snapping up bank stocks and conglomerates, Ketchen said.</p>
<p>Despite that optimism, investors still see &quot;a negative side surrounding the gold sector,&quot; Ketchen said.</p>
<p>Of Toronto's 14 sub-indices, only golds and base metals tumbled, while the rest soared. Heavyweight conglomerates rose most, followed by financial institutions, media and forestry.</p>
<p>Declines edged out advances 456 to 452, while 170 issues traded flat.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Bre-X Minerals Ltd topped Toronto actives, dropping 0.66 to 2.52 on 15 million shares. Institutional investors were spooked by media reports that appeared to put the gold prospector in a more negative light.</p>
<p>* Bank of Nova Scotia gained 0.90 to reach 51.75.</p>
<p>((Lydia Zajc, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8109))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
