<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="490123" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: CRICKET-KENYA BEAT IRELAND BY SEVEN RUNS. [CORRECTED 09:00 GMT]</title>
<headline>CRICKET-KENYA BEAT IRELAND BY SEVEN RUNS. [CORRECTED 09:00 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenya beat Ireland by seven runs in a thrilling match on Monday, booking their place in the finals of the International Cricket Council (ICC) Trophy as well as the 1999 World Cup.</p>
<p>(Corrects to make clear Kenya not ICC Trophy defending champions).</p>
<p>Ireland scored 208 runs for the loss of nine wickets in 50 overs when play resumed on Monday after Kenya's 215 for eight on Sunday before the match was suspended due to rain delays.</p>
<p>Kenyan team manager Jamer Singh said the match was under control the whole way despite the close score.</p>
<p>&quot;We were never threatened at any time and knew that Ireland would not match our total,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>It was not that clear-cut down on the pitch, however.</p>
<p>The Irish were spurred by Derek Heasley who hit four sixes and two fours. Their cause suffered a big blow when he departed with the score at 178.</p>
<p>The Kenyans bowled tightly and fielded well to keep the Irish on the defensive.</p>
<p>Ireland made their task more difficult by allowing the Kenyans to score 50 runs in their last five overs on Sunday.</p>
<p>Ireland still have a chance of making it to the 1999 World Cup finals in England, as three of the top four from the ICC Trophy tournament are guaranteed places.</p>
<p>Scotland, who barely lost to tournament favourite Kenya by run rate in a quarter-final match on Friday, play Bangladesh in the second semi-final on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Bangladesh are under huge pressure at home to qualify for the World Cup. When they failed to do so in the last ICC Trophy in Kenya in 1994, fans burnt down the Bangladesh Cricket Board building in Dhaka.</p>
<p>Kenya, Bangladesh, Canada and Scotland have also qualified for the Kuala Lumpur Commonwealth Games next year.They earned the right by being the top four Commonwealth nations in the ICC Trophy.</p>
<p>Malaysia automatically qualify for the 16-team cricket competition as hosts. Cricket is being played for the first time at the 1998 Commonwealth Games.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
