<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="490220" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: INTERVIEW-RIGAS KOMMERCBANKA EYES RIGA, TALLINN LISTING.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-RIGAS KOMMERCBANKA EYES RIGA, TALLINN LISTING.</headline>
<byline>Martinsh Gravitis</byline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rigas Komercbanka, the third largest Latvian bank, said on Monday it will list its shares on the Riga stock exchange in the middle of this year and also wants a listing in Tallinn and on a Scandinavian bourse.</p>
<p>&quot;The main issue for our bank this year is to enter the stock market. To be more exact, in the middle of this year we have to enter the Riga bourse,&quot; Vladimir Kulik, Rigas komercbanka president, told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Komercbanka said last year it was eyeing the Riga bourse but Kulik said the bank also wants to be present on two Baltic bourses this year.</p>
<p>It also sees itself joining a Scandinavian or a continental European stock exchange within a year.</p>
<p>&quot;The planned chain of events is very simple. First Latvia's bourse and after that Tallinn, later a Scandinavian or a continental exchange and then one in the U.S.,&quot; Kulik said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a programme which will be implemented in stages. Two bourses this year and either early next year or late this year - Scandinavia or continental Europe,&quot; Kulik added.</p>
<p>He named Luxembourg and Frankfurt as a possibility, depending on the conditions.  </p>
<p>&quot;One has to be realistic, we are not an issuer which would attract enormous interest but at the same time we understand that it is necessary to be present there,&quot; Kulik added.</p>
<p>The European Bank for Reconstruction and Devlopment (EBRD), which last autumn took a stake in RKB, backs its aspirations.</p>
<p>&quot;During the annual meeting of the EBRD, to which we have been invited, we will have more talks on the issue,&quot; Kulik said.</p>
<p>&quot;They encourage us to do that but we have to plan everything very carefully,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We are working on technicalities at the moment,&quot; Kulik said.</p>
<p>-- Martinsh Gravitis, Riga Newsroom +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SCAND">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
