<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="490443" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE cocoa tumbles 5 percent on fund liquidation.</title>
<headline>CSCE cocoa tumbles 5 percent on fund liquidation.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE cocoa futures finished lower for the fourth consecutive session Monday, plummeting five percent on heavy fund long liquidation amid bearish technical indicators and a lackluster German grind, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a combination of technical and fundamental factors,&quot; said Prudential Securities analyst Arthur Stevenson. &quot;The German grind was roughly 12 percent lower and obviously not encouraging. It was a contributing factor, but I do not think it alone justified this kind of selloff.&quot;</p>
<p>Cocoa prices headed lower at the outset, gapping down $25 at the opening bell after heavy losses in London overnight. Traders said downward momentum accelerated after a series of technical sell-stops were triggered below $1,450 a tonne in CSCE May.</p>
<p>May delivery tumbled $103 to a low of $1,370 -- filling in a chart gap between $1,403 and $1,395 -- before light trade buying and bottom-picking by speculators helped the market to regain some ground.</p>
<p>By the close, most-active May delivery stood $75 lower at a five-week low of $1,398 after ranging from $1,452 to $1,370. Second-month July plunged $68 to $1,436, while the outer months ended $58 to $68 lower.</p>
<p>Although the German grind was within expectations -- analysts had estimated the first quarter data to be down after extremely high year-ago figures -- traders said it weighed on market sentiment.</p>
<p>German Confectionery Industry Association BDS said Monday German cocoa grindings fell by 11.71 percent to 61,379.3 tonnes in the first quarter of 1997 from 69,520.3 tonnes in the same 1996 period.</p>
<p>&quot;The German grind was as expected. As major importers get product at origin, you're going to see declines,&quot; said Dean Witter analyst Corey Bell. &quot;Still, lower grinds are psychologically negative.&quot;</p>
<p>New that heavy late-March rains in the Ivory Coast have improved the mid-crop cocoa harvest after a February drought also contributed the market's downfall, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>Ivorian crop analysts said in early March that regular showers up to April would determine how close this year's mid-crop would be to the bumper 200,000 tonnes in the record 1.2 million tonnes 1995/96 (Oct-Sept) harvest season.</p>
<p>&quot;It confirms the fact that there is going to be a pretty decent Ivory crop and that's bearish for the market,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>In the near-term, traders said nearby cocoa was likely to continue to come under pressure as speculators liquidate or roll spot positions into July before May's first notice day on April 17.</p>
<p>May open interest remained hefty at 30,385 lots as of April 4, up 131 lots from the previous session.</p>
<p>On the charts, one trader said May would need to hold above $1,395 and get back above $1,400 to shore up its stance. Today's low of $1,370 would provide some support, with the next level seen around $1,350.</p>
<p>Volume on the exchange was extremely heavy at an estimated 30,288 lots, nearly double Friday's official tally of 17,471 lots.</p>
<p>((--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
