<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49047" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares rise, seen extending gains.</title>
<headline>Polish shares rise, seen extending gains.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares rose after Wednesday's fall and analysts said the higher turnover and stronger buying after price fixing suggested that the market's three-week flat trend might be turning upwards.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems there's now a preponderance of investors who don't fear a fall,&quot; said Krzysztof Rogalski, an analyst at Bank Staropolski brokerage.</p>
<p>Analysts said players might be buying before mid-September, when some technical analysts expect a rise, and before the release of firms' August earnings next week, expected, as in July, to beat the first half's mediocre results.  </p>
<p>Analysts did not expect steep growth but said the market could soon beat its July 5, 27-month high at 14,282.2 points.</p>
<p>&quot;If company results are similar to July's we can beat the high,&quot; said Tomasz Berent, an analyst at IB Austria Securities.</p>
<p>The main market's all-share WIG index rose 1.4 percent to 14,010.4 points and turnover rose 28.8 percent to 103.5 million zlotys on both markets.</p>
<p>Analysts said a good sign for stocks was that NFI units were flat in lower turnover, suggesting that the units may be hitting a correction after their surge by 44 percent since late August, with some capital flowing to stocks.  </p>
<p>The units fell 7.5 percent in continuous trade.</p>
<p>Analysts said Stalexport, whose 75-million-zloty claim on overpaid tax interest was rejected by the Supreme Administrative Court on Thursday, should fall on Friday. Before the tax news the stock fell 1.9 percent in heavy trade.</p>
<p>Analysts were surprised by the scale of Zywiec's 10-percent rise in heavy trade, but said garment makers Vistula, Prochnik and Wolczanka were underpriced after recent steep falls.</p>
<p>The three stocks rose 6.1 percent, 5.6 percent and 5.4 percent respectively. -- Steven Silber +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
