<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="490799" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian Socialists withdraw backing for cabinet.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian Socialists withdraw backing for cabinet.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's former ruling Socialists have withdrawn their support from the interim cabinet, complaining of a lack of transparency over a new IMF accord and politically-motivated sackings of state employees.</p>
<p>In an open letter to President Petar Stoyanov published by Bulgarian newspapers on Monday, Bulgarian Socialist Party (BSP) leader Georgi Parvanov said an all-party agreement which ended a month of street protests led by the Union of Democratic Forces (UDF) was not being respected.</p>
<p>&quot;The UDF betrayed the principles agreed to lead the country out of crisis. The caretaker cabinet and yourself openly ignored those principles in your activity,&quot; Parvanov said.</p>
<p>The Socialists agreed on February 4 to abandon attempts to form a new government. Stoyanov appointed a caretaker cabinet, which contains many UDF members, to rule until elections on April 19 and to negotiate with the IMF.</p>
<p>&quot;At this stage the BSP still has not received the text of the accord between the interim government and the IMF,&quot; Parvanov said.</p>
<p>He said details of the accord, which will include a tough fixed exchange rate regime, were unclear, and Bulgarians did not realise the high social cost of the reforms.</p>
<p>Countries of the G-24 industrialised nations meet in Brussels on Tuesday and Wednesday to discuss additional support for Bulgaria, and the IMF board is expected to approve the standby accord on Friday.</p>
<p>He said sackings of directors of companies and government departments had been politically motivated.</p>
<p>&quot;We are worried by the fact that in some spheres, especially in the tourist business, we have new faces connected to strong-arm (criminal) groups, which is maybe an attempt to reward their efforts in the January unrest,&quot; Parvanov said.</p>
<p>Parvanov met Stoyanov last month to express his concern, and Stoyanov said that in his view the reforms by the new cabinet did not go far enough.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
