<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="490876" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexican tortilla makers threaten govt office block.</title>
<headline>Mexican tortilla makers threaten govt office block.</headline>
<dateline>MONTERREY, Mexico 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leader of 1,125 corn flour dough and tortilla makers in the northern state of Tamaulipas threatened Monday to block government Trade Ministry offices in protest at not being able to buy subsidized corn.</p>
<p>Mario Moreno, chairman of the Northeast Union of Corn Flour Dough and Tortilla Makers, said the lack of response on the part of the federal authorities could force them to take over government offices in seven state cities on May 18.</p>
<p>Moreno told Reuters that his members are arguing for equal access to subsidized corn.</p>
<p>He alleged that large corn flour industrialists have unfair price access to corn through the national staples agency Conasupo and his members are forced to pay higher prices.</p>
<p>Moreno said if they did not gain an audience with federal authorities on April 18 to put forward their views his members would take over Trade Ministry offices on state-wide basis.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not let anyone in the offices of Tampico, Victoria, Mante, Laredo, Matamoros and Reynosa,&quot; Moreno said, citing the state's seven ministerial centers.</p>
<p>Moreno said Conasupo is selling his members corn at 1,350 pesos per tonne when the maximum price should be 940 pesos. He claimed larger corn flour producers have access to subsidised corn at 425 pesos per tonne from Conasupo.</p>
<p>Tortilla makers throughout Mexico are demanding that the government raises prices for the corn flour pancakes that are eaten more widely than bread. Tortillas are one of the last surviving food products that have set prices. Producers either want prices to be hiked or controls to be lifted totally.</p>
<p>Government officials, from the Conasupo agency or Trade Ministry in Mexico City, were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>((--Jacqueline Lerma, Monterrey bureau +528 -3457677))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTERREY, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
