<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="490989" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SembCorp eyes power plant project.</title>
<headline>SembCorp eyes power plant project.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>SembCorp Ltd's plans to build a 600-megawatt power plant in Singapore through joint venture Sembawang Utilities and Terminals Pte Ltd (SUT) are expected to be finalised this year, company officials said on Monday.</p>
<p>SUT is building a Singapore $250 million utilities centre on Pulau Sakra, one of seven islands to be merged to form Jurong island for the site of a large petrochemical centre.</p>
<p>&quot;SUT still intends to build a cogeneration plant with 600 megawatt power generating capacity for the phase two of the utilities centre development,&quot; said Tan Mong Seng, chairman and president of SembEC.  </p>
<p>&quot;We hope to make a decision within this year,&quot; Tan said. Industry sources said the company was talking to Indonesia and Malaysia for possible natural gas supplies.</p>
<p>SUT is a joint venture between SembCorp's engineering and construction unit, SembEC, Belgium's Powerfin S.A., JTC International Pte Ltd and EDB Investments Pte Ltd.</p>
<p>Tan said SUT was awaiting details of the Singapore government's plans to deregulate the power supply market in 1998. The government is expected to make an announcement this year.  </p>
<p>SUT has been in negotitations with the Public Utilities Board as well as PowerGrid, the Singapore Power subsidiary which will manage electricity distribution, on the cogeneration plant's potential supplies to users.</p>
<p>The project would make SUT one of the first independent power prducers in Singapore.</p>
<p>The plant is expected to take about 27-28 months to complete once approvals are given, Tan said.</p>
<p>-- Angela Tan, Singapore newsroom (65 8703083)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020044">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
