<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49099" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - September 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - September 12.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on Thursday, prepared for Reuters by the Co-operation Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- The chief of the Latvian Privatisation Agency, Janis Naglis, said the agency had received an application from Germany's Preussen Elektra to purchase Latvia's state-run energy company Latvenergo. Final date for applications is October 15.</p>
<p>- Latvian Minister of Transportation Vilis Kristopans met unofficially with his Russian counterpart Anatoly Zaitsev to discuss abolition of tariffs on goods transported by rail to Latvian ports. They agreed to form a group to try to attempt to resolve rail-related issues between the two countries.</p>
<p>- Five customs officers have been sentenced by District Court in Valmiera to imprisonment for bribery and abuse of power.</p>
<p>- Ukrainian Parliament has decided to postpone ratification of free trade agreement with Latvia. Left-wing factions in Ukrainian Parliament said they would not vote for the agreement because of the imprisonment of former Latvian Communist chief, serving an eight-year sentence for his participation in the botched coup of August 1991.</p>
<p>DIENA</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Valdis Birkavs announced on his return from Denmark that visa regulations between the two countries may be abolished before Christmas.</p>
<p>NEATKARIGA RITA AVIZE</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Valdis Birkavs has begun discussing with two high-ranking U.S. State Department officials the so-called American plan for cooperation with the Baltics. Latvia fears the plan may be offered as an alternative to NATO membership.</p>
<p>- After his visit to Iceland, scheduled for September 18, Prime Minister Andris Shkele is to go to the United States to deleiver a speech to the United Nations.</p>
<p>SM</p>
<p>- Latvian government is planning to impose taxes on pensions received from abroad.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7226693</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
