<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="490982" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Rubin lectures Hanoi on labour, sidesteps Nike row.</title>
<headline>Rubin lectures Hanoi on labour, sidesteps Nike row.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin said on Monday Hanoi needed to establish &quot;fair labour&quot; standards, but sidestepped a row over alleged worker abuse at factories which make Nike Inc. shoes in Vietnam.</p>
<p>Spelling out the hurdles still in the way of closer economic ties, Rubin said that if Vietnam wanted access to Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) loans and insurance it would have to meet certain labour standards.</p>
<p>&quot;Vietnamese access to OPIC loans insurance programmes requires Vietnam satisfying fair labour standards,&quot; he said in a speech to a conference on U.S.-Vietnam economic normalisation in Hanoi.</p>
<p>OPIC is a U.S. government agency whose primary mission is to insure or guarantee American private capital investments in developing countries.</p>
<p>It is prohibited from supporting activity in nations that fail to meet international labour standards by guaranteeing the right of association, the right to organise and bargain collectively, a minimum age for child labour, prohibition of forced labour and certain wage, health and safety standards.</p>
<p>Asked about allegations of worker abuse at factories in Vietnam which are subcontracted by America's Nike Inc to produce recreational shoes, Rubin said he understood that the company was checking the situation out.</p>
<p>&quot;Fair labour standards are an issue we take with all seriousness,&quot; he said, adding that it was up to U.S. companies around the world to set a good example.</p>
<p>Three South Korean and two Taiwanese factories producing Nike shoes in Vietnam were named last month by Vietnam Labour Watch for abuse of their workers.</p>
<p>The labour activist group's Thuyen Nguyen said he had found workers at factories contracted by Nike earning less than the minimum wage in the first three months of employment.</p>
<p>Some were limited to one trip to the lavatory and two drinks of water per shift, and verbal abuse, sexual harassment and corporal punishment were common, he told a news conference in New York.</p>
<p>Nike has said it cannot confirm Nguyen's findings, but has stressed that it welcomes and works with independent observers to monitor, train and improve working conditions overseas.</p>
<p>A Labour Department offficial in southern Vietnam said last week that a Taiwanese supervisor at a factory which makes Nike shoes will stand trial for alleged abuse of her employees.</p>
<p>He said the woman was accused of forcing 56 workers to jog twice around the two-km (1.2-mile) factory perimeter for failing to wear regulation workshoes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
