<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="491073" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr ends higher in US, near new 50-mth peak vs yen.</title>
<headline>Dlr ends higher in US, near new 50-mth peak vs yen.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>*Dlr ends by new 50-mth peak ag yen, nearly one-month mark high on Rubin's benign dollar/trade remarks after Japan visit. *Dlr eyes Jan '93 126.21 high on break of Mon's 125.81 yen high; 1.7210 marks in focus. Bid dollar helped support bonds. *Waigel denies reports he softened ERM stand, but mark heavy. *Stg/mark well bid after scaling old ERM floor of 2.7780.</p>
<p>Subsiding fears that U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin would use the dollar as an instrument of trade policy carried the greenback to a higher close, but the rally fizzled after dollar/yen touched a new 50-month peak in the U.S., currency experts said.</p>
<p>Before the rally ran out of steam, the dollar advanced broadly on Monday, vaulting over 125 yen to hit 125.81 yen, its highest since January 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/yen has been a little more quiet in terms of our session,&quot; said Bob Lynch, senior foreign exchange analyst at MMS International.</p>
<p>Although Rubin urged Japan to guard against widening trade surpluses, his relatively benign trade rhetoric in the wake of a meeting with Japanese officials in Tokyo on Friday stoked dollar bulls, who feared he could have threatened to use a lower dollar as a weapon against rising Japanese exports.</p>
<p>On Monday, while in Hanoi on a six-day tour of Asia, Rubin said the recent strength of the dollar has been good for the U.S. economy. He declined to express a view on the dollar's direction even though Japan reported that its February current account surplus -- the broadest measure of trade -- widened 15.4 percent to 865.2 billion yen in the previous 12 months.</p>
<p>&quot;The lack of strong rhetoric from him (Rubin) is telling us that the U.S. won't use the dollar as a trade tool and there doesn't seem to be any problems with the Japanese trade surplus numbers that came out,&quot; said Dennis Pettit, foreign exchange manager at Long-Term Credit Bank of Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;Last week, those numbers would have caused the dollar to have sold off a little bit, but I think, with the background of Rubin saying that the exchange rate won't be used as a trade tool, the market has been less responsive to the numbers,&quot; Pettit said.</p>
<p>The dollar closed at 125.60/65 yen, up from 125.50/55 at the open, and at 1.7119/24 marks, up from 1.7030/35.</p>
<p>The dollar also benefitted from speculation that the Federal Reserve will raise interest rates another notch in May, which would make dollar-denominated investments relatively more alluring to foreigners, experts said.</p>
<p>The notion that the Fed rate hike on March 25 was likely the first in a series of tightenings to ward off inflation gained ground on Friday, when U.S. employment data hinted that tight labor markets are starting to generate worrisome wage rises.</p>
<p>&quot;It's keeping U.S./Japan rate spreads favorable (for the dollar) and keeping the idea that Japanese investors will continue to look offshore for investments because returns at home are very low,&quot; Lynch said.</p>
<p>The dollar was also lifted when the mark fell after the British press reported that Bonn had softened its position that countries wishing to qualify for European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) must cut government deficits to no more than 3.0 percent of economic output.</p>
<p>The weak mark helped sterling, which soared to 2.7870 marks, its highest since September 1992.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel denied reports in Monday's Financial Times and Guardian that he had relaxed his hardline stance on entry conditions for joining the euro, planned for 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;You now have the possibility of a soft euro, a soft EMU and spreads are wider now between U.S. and European rates,&quot; said Stephen Jury, chief dealer at Union Bank of Switzerland, explaining the mark's slide.</p>
<p>The dollar ended at 1.4685/90 Swiss francs, up from 1.4642/52 at the open. It fell to Canadian $1.3869/74 from C$1.3912/17, and the pound rose to $1.6273/83 from $1.6258/68. The Australian dollar slid to $0.7763/68 from $0.7782/87.</p>
<p>((-- Alden Bentley 212 859 1667))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
