<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="491250" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYC and firefighters reach tentative 5-year pact.</title>
<headline>NYC and firefighters reach tentative 5-year pact.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mayor Rudolph Giuliani and the firefighters union Monday reached a tentative, five-year contract raising wages and benefits by 15.63 percent, which the city hopes will set a pattern for other uniformed unions.</p>
<p>The agreement follows a pattern set in contracts with civilian workers, as there are no raises in the first two years.  </p>
<p>Starting in 1997, the third year of the contract, annual raises would be three percent, three percent and six percent. The civilian United Federation of Teachers and the Municipal Labor Coalition both have agreed contracts that offer no raises in the first two years.</p>
<p>Kevin Gallagher, president of the Uniformed Firefighters Association, at a City Hall news conference, said the proposed pact would return to union workers 39 hours of vacation time lost in a 1988 arbitration and improve longevity pay and annuity.</p>
<p>&quot;We felt it was important for us to be the first uniformed force to achieve an agreement so that we can set a pattern that will best serve the interests of our members,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Giuliani, city labor officials and the union declined to give out further details about the contract, saying they wanted to let the union explain it directly to its 8,800 members before they vote. The approval process was expected to take as long as two months.</p>
<p>The leaders of the Patrolmen's Benevolent Association rejected a similar offer from the Giuliani Administration and now are in arbitration. Many police officers have been bitter about the city's proposal and some have avoided issuing parking tickets as a protest.</p>
<p>((--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
