<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="491409" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: G7 urges small businesses to get cyber savvy.</title>
<headline>G7 urges small businesses to get cyber savvy.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Small and mid-sized businesses throughout the Group of Seven richest industrialised nations are far behind large corporations in getting hooked up to the global Internet, G7 trade politicians and technocrats said on Monday.</p>
<p>Kicking off a three-day conference on opportunities in cyberspace for small and mid-sized enterprises, dubbed SMEs in techno-jargon, officials warned that many small businesses were still unable to cash in on the boom in electronic commerce.</p>
<p>A combination of confusing and contradictory government regulations and slow investment by small companies in the know-how and technology to do business online threatens to hold back economies and thwart opportunities to create new jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;All of the G7 ministers believe that it is of the utmost importance for our economies that particularly small and mid-sized companies find their way in the Information Society,&quot; said conference host German Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt.</p>
<p>The three-day conference in Bonn is the first to be held as a result of a G7 project launched two years ago that aims to come up with international measures to promote the development of electronic trade on networks like the global Internet.</p>
<p>Mario Monti, EU commissioner for the single market and taxation, said while 98 percent of large European corporations were hooked up to the Internet this was true for just four percent of small and mid-sized enterprises (SMEs).</p>
<p>At the same time, the global electronic marketplace was growing 60 percent a year and elecrtonic trade volume could reach some 1.5 trillion ecus ($1.7 trillion) in the European Union alone by the turn of the century, he said.</p>
<p>This number of people with Internet access is estimated to rise to 250 million in the year 2000 from around 86 million at the end of last year.</p>
<p>&quot;SMEs can only realise their full potential in the cyber-economy if they are fully aware of the opportunities,&quot; Monti said.</p>
<p>Hirobumi Kawano, director general for machinery and information industry policies for Japan's MITI, forecast that electronic trade volume could reach $10 billion by 2005. He said MITI would present a report on cyber trade this month.</p>
<p>&quot;One point that cannot be too emphasised is the global nature of electronic commerce. It will require an unprecedented level of uniformity and international cooperation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While small companies have been slow to adopt new information technologies, they are picking up the pace and in the coming digital economy they could be the biggest winners.</p>
<p>William Etherington, general manager of computer maker IBM Europe, said in a speech prepared for delivery at the conference that as big business downsized, small business was creating jobs.</p>
<p>IBM used to employ some 100,000 people in Europe, the Middle East and Africa and relied on 50,000 others at SMEs. Now IBM employs just 70,000 but relies on a network of 120,000 SME employees, a net increase of between 30,000 and 40,000 people.</p>
<p>&quot;SMEs in Europe -- and worldwide -- are growing faster and generating more jobs than large enterprises,&quot; Etherington said.</p>
<p>That is why creating a reliable international regulatory environment that protects individual privacy, copyright and intellectual property, but also allows for safe transactions to be done online, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;The priority is for industry to regulate itself, not for state regulation,&quot; said Rexrodt.</p>
<p>But EU Commissioner Monti said there must be a secure European regulatory framework for electronic commerce based on the principles of the European single market.</p>
<p>Differing national regulations could inhibit firms seeking to engage in cross-border electronic trade, he said, adding that contract regulations in some EU countries were &quot;not appropriate for an electronic commerce environment.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There is no need to introduce new forms of tax, such as a 'bit tax', within the EU,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The G7 comprises the United States, Japan, Germany, France, Italy, Britain and Canada.</p>
<p>($ = 0.865 European Currency Unit ECUs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
