<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="491428" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Food-borne infectious diseases on the rise - WHO.</title>
<headline>Food-borne infectious diseases on the rise - WHO.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>More and more people are becoming sick from what they eat because of changing eating habits in favour of pre-prepared food from the supermarket or takeaways, the World Health Organisation said on Monday.</p>
<p>WHO also said at least 30 new infectious diseases with no known treatment, cure or vaccine had emerged in the past two decades and blamed the rapid increase in air travel, growth of mega-cities and inadequate safe water and sanitation.</p>
<p>It said smallpox had been eradicated but that diseases such as malaria, diptheria and yellow fever were making a comeback in the age of jet travel, slum cities and big population movements.</p>
<p>In a message to mark Monday's World health Day, WHO said humanity's ancient battle with microbes had yet to be won with diseases of the past such as pneumonic plague reemerging and new bacteria and viruses eluding modern medicine.</p>
<p>AIDS emerged as a global disaster in the early 1980s and could affect nearly 30 million adults by 2000, WHO said. Mad cow disease may be another in the making, and also its incurable human form, the brain-wasting Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease.</p>
<p>WHO doctors also noted an increase in food-borne emerging infectious diseases such as salmonella and enterohaemorrhagic E-coli, which causes bloody diarrhoea, can be fatal especially in children and cause abortions in pregnant women in some cases.</p>
<p>&quot;Bacterial and food-borne emerging infectious diseases are on the increase,&quot; Klaus Stohr, a doctor at WHO's emergency diseases unit, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;People don't have much time to cook their own food anymore,&quot; Stohr lamented. &quot;We are changing our eating habits. There is increased demand for pre-prepared food because we are getting more mobile and eating on the run.&quot;</p>
<p>Stohr said global statistics for outbreaks of food-borne infectious diseases were not available because very few countries had successful surveillance systems.</p>
<p>The health food craze was also a factor to blame for the increase in food-borne diseases because unprocessed food contained less preservatives, Stohr said.</p>
<p>&quot;People are turning to uncooked food, believing it's more healthy. But this is wrong,&quot; he said. &quot;There is a reason why we pasteurise our milk -- because raw milk can be contaminated if not treated properly.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1996, 2.5 billion people crossed international borders aboard commercial flights. Another 25 million people have become refugees and millions more are migrant workers living abroad.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
