<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="491523" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Arafat says Israel in war on peace process.</title>
<headline>Arafat says Israel in war on peace process.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat said on Monday that Israel had declared &quot;war against the peace process&quot; in the Middle East and violated written agreements with the Palestinians.</p>
<p>&quot;The Israeli government is going through a war of aggression against our people,&quot; Arafat told a meeting of foreign ministers of the Non-Aligned Movement (NAM) in the Indian capital.</p>
<p>&quot;It is regrettable that the Israeli government should take advantage of the United States veto twice in 10 days to continue on the path of aggression and challenge international legitimacy,&quot; Arafat said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a declaration of war against the peace process.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. vetoes on March 7 and March 21 prevented action by the U.N. Security Council on Israel's plan to build 6,500 homes for Jews on land captured during the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>Ties between the Palestinians and Israelis plunged into crisis after the Israeli government broke ground on the settlement.</p>
<p>&quot;The Israeli government is constantly violating promises of the agreements signed between us. The annexation of land is going on,&quot; Arafat said.</p>
<p>&quot;Israel is striving to establish relations with Arab nations, non-aligned countries and the entire world at our expense, at the expense of the Palestinian people and Palestinian land, at the expense of everything we hold sacred.&quot;</p>
<p>Arafat demanded that Jerusalem be handed over to Palestinians.</p>
<p>&quot;To save Jerusalem from occupation is indeed a duty,&quot; Arafat said, adding that there could be no peace unless Jerusalem was returned to &quot;its owners&quot;.</p>
<p>Arafat placed the blame for the present crisis in the Middle East on the Israeli government, and appealed to the Non-Aligned Movement to support the Palestinians.</p>
<p>&quot;Indeed no one else has brought about this crisis but the present Israeli government,&quot; Arafat said. &quot;To save the peace process, we appeal to all of you, one by one, to stand by us at this critical stage.&quot;</p>
<p>Countries establishing relations with Israel should make it clear that the renewal of ties was linked to Israel's honouring United Nations resolutions, Arafat said.</p>
<p>&quot;The resolutions and recommendations call upon all the sister and friendly countries that have started to establish relations with Israel to link such relations to Israel's respect for resolutions of the U.N.,&quot; Arafat said.</p>
<p>The Palestinian leader appealed for a special session of the U.N. General Assembly to discuss the Middle East.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of the two vetos within 10 days, we have no other option but to go the general assembly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Later on Monday, Arafat was scheduled to meet Indian President Shankar Dayal Sharma and Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda during his one-day visit to New Delhi.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
