<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="491869" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Moody's sees ratings uncertainty in Austrian banks.</title>
<headline>Moody's sees ratings uncertainty in Austrian banks.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moody's Investors Service said on Monday it expected further consolidation of the Austrian banking system and some rating instability in the near to medium-term, following Bank Austria AG's recent acquisition of Creditanstalt.</p>
<p>The expected instability was due to acceleration of change of the operating environment and the fact this consolidation will not necessarily lead to correspondingly greater efficiency, it said in its annual report on the outlook for the Austrian banking system.</p>
<p>The report, which was written by Tobias Gruen (a vice president - senior analyst in London) also notes that despite banking overcapacity, a number of barriers to rationalisation either remain or have been erected, Moody's said.</p>
<p>&quot;Furthermore, the franchise value of some banks may become more vulnerable as a result of such consolidation and the potential for greater long-term rationalisation,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Forthcoming shareholder realignments amongst the banks could presage in some cases bank mergers, and thus also lead to rating reviews.</p>
<p>&quot;Austrian banks' interest margins remain narrow by global and European standards as a result of aggresive retail fund pricing and banking overcapacity,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Recurring earnings power, after falling in recent years, has stabilised due to a modest recovery in interest-earning assets, higher profits from trading activities and a more diversified source of earnings resulting from expansion into neighbouring Central and East European markets.</p>
<p>&quot;To date, the major Austrian banks have retained a fairly high degree of domestic bank intermediation and although disintermediation is expected to rise, this is unlikely to exert immediate pressure on earnings,&quot; Moody's said.</p>
<p>Moody's added that key asset quality indicators are only moderate following the Austrian recession and that loan loss provisioning will need to remain at relatively high levels for most banks.  </p>
<p>&quot;Although loan losses will continue to impact reserves for the immediate future, domestic asset quality is expected to improve for the majority of rated banks,&quot; Moody's said.</p>
<p>&quot;Most Austrian banks are well capitalised and are starting to improve internal capital generation rates, helped by a low effective tax rate that enhances their capital generation capabilities.</p>
<p>Moody's rates the following Austrian banks</p>
<p>(long term/short term/financial strength)</p>
<p>Bank Austria:Aaa/P-1/C+</p>
<p>Creditanstalt-Bankverein:A1/P-1/C</p>
<p>Die Erste Oest. Spar-Casse Bank:A1/P-1/C+</p>
<p>GiroCredit Bank AG der Sparkassen:A2/P-1/D+</p>
<p>Oesterreichische Investitionskredit:Aa3/P-1/D+</p>
<p>Oesterreichische Kommunalkredit:Aa3/P-1/C</p>
<p>Oesterreichische Kontrollbank:Aaa/P-1/-</p>
<p>Oesterreichische Postsparkasse:Aaa/P-1/-</p>
<p>Raiffeisen Zentralbank Oesterreich:Aa3/P-1/C+</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 6176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
