<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="491851" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: POLL - UK Labour leads by 21 points - Reuters/NOP.</title>
<headline>POLL - UK Labour leads by 21 points - Reuters/NOP.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's opposition Labour Party has a massive 21-point lead over the ruling Conservatives with less than four weeks to go to the May 1 election, an NOP poll conducted for Reuters showed on Monday.</p>
<p>The lead is down from 25 points in the previous Reuters poll conducted three weeks earlier, and just below the level shown in two other polls published in newspapers on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;The key thing is that although the lead has narrowed, the change is not statistically significant,&quot; said Nick Moon, head of political research at polling organisation NOP.</p>
<p>&quot;This sort of change will not do the Conservatives any good. It's just tinkering a bit at the edges,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>NOP questioned a representative sample of 1,088 voters last Friday. It gave Labour 51 percent of the vote, down from 54 percent in a poll conducted on March 14, the day the election was called.</p>
<p>The Conservatives were on 30 percent, against 29, and the minority Liberal Democrats were unchanged on 11 percent.</p>
<p>Despite the narrowing margin between the two main parties, the poll indicates that Labour leader Tony Blair is on course for a huge overall majority under Britain's first-past-the-post electoral system in the next parliament.</p>
<p>If the electorate cast its votes in line with this poll, Labour would have 440 members in the 659-seat lower House of Commons. The Conservatives would have 169 seats and the Liberals 24, according to calculations by election experts Colin Rallings and Michael Thrasher.</p>
<p>The poll shows that 64 percent of voters, regardless of their own preferences, believe Blair will replace John Major as prime minister.</p>
<p>Only 18 percent think the Conservatives can score a fifth successive election victory, while four percent predict a &quot;hung parliament&quot; in which minor parties hold the balance of power.</p>
<p>Major's task in overturning the huge Labour lead is made more difficult by allegations of sleaze against some of his members of parliament, notably former trade minister Neil Hamilton.</p>
<p>Six percent of voters told NOP that their voting decision would be influenced &quot;a lot&quot; by the allegations and eight percent said they would be swayed &quot;a little&quot;.</p>
<p>Hamilton, accused of taking cash from Harrods department store owner Mohamed Al-Fayed to ask Commons questions, faces a challenge from BBC war correspondent Martin Bell, backed by both Labour and the Liberals, unless he stands down in his northwest England seat.</p>
<p>On some key economic and political issues, the gap between the parties was much narrower than voting intentions indicate.</p>
<p>Labour led the Conservatives by just 34 points to 29 when people were asked which party they would trust most to manage the economy. And 35 percent said they believed they would be better off under Labour against 28 percent for the Conservatives.</p>
<p>Labour led by 33 percent to 29 when people were asked which party they most trusted to manage Britain's relations with Europe.</p>
<p>--London Polling Unit tel: +44 171 542 5223</p>
<p>			    e-mail: polling.unit@rtrlondon.co.uk</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
