<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="491935" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey rejects Dutch Liberals' EU comments.</title>
<headline>Turkey rejects Dutch Liberals' EU comments.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey said on Monday that a Dutch political party's rejection of its bid to join the European Union was not compatible with the views of EU governments and modern European civilisation.</p>
<p>Frits Bolkestein, outspoken chief of the conservative Dutch Liberal Party, told a party meeting on Saturday that Turkey did not fit the traditional profile of the 15-member western bloc.</p>
<p>&quot;If what we have seen in the press is true, I do not think that such thoughts and ideas can be considered as compatible with contemporary European civilisation,&quot; foreign ministry spokesman Omer Akbel told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Up to now no European government has assumed an identical posture, identical to the ideas that have been attributed to the Liberal Party chairman,&quot; Akbel said.</p>
<p>Bolkestein said Turkey, Ukraine and Russia, all potential candidates for EU membership, were too far removed from the bloc's historical traditions -- feudalism, the Renaissance, the Age of Reason and the development of democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;The EU should only offer a place to those countries that share in the great formative events that shaped European history,&quot; Bolkestein said.</p>
<p>The Liberal Party, currently the most popular political group in the Netherlands with a general election due in May of next year, is one of three in the right-left ruling coalition. The Netherlands holds the rotating EU presidency until June 30.</p>
<p>Leaders of the EU's Christian Democrat governments, including German Chancellor Helmut Kohl, in February cast serious doubt on Ankara's application for EU membership.</p>
<p>Their comments put further pressure on Turkey-EU relations, already strained by the suspension of financial aid to Ankara under a customs union with the bloc set up last year.</p>
<p>But EU foreign ministers at a meeting in the Dutch town of Apeldoorn last month signalled that Turkey could one day join the Western club.</p>
<p>The foreign ministers of Germany and France have since visited Ankara, where they sought to smooth relations between Turkey and the EU.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
