<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="492047" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IBM introduces LogiCast broadcast package.</title>
<headline>IBM introduces LogiCast broadcast package.</headline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>International Business Machines Corp said Monday it had introduced LogiCast, its package of digital broadcasting technologies and services for both video and data.</p>
<p>LogiCast allows viewers to enjoy much of digital television without having to buy a new digital TV and could serve as a transition product as the television industry moves to High Definition Television (HDTV), IBM said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The conversion of video from analog to digital formats is accelerating around the world, enabling new revenue-generating broadcast services through greater channel capacity, as well as improving video and audio quality,&quot; said William Beckmann, vice president of IBM Video Enabled Solutions.</p>
<p>&quot;Our approach gives customers the flexibility to deliver their services to either TVs or personal computers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>IBM, which made the announcement at the National Association of Broadcasters convention in Las Vegas, said LogiCast includes a video server as well as storage and networking products.  </p>
<p>An industry team led by IBM already has installed an end-to-end digital broadcast solution in Italy for STET, the Italian telecommunications holding company.</p>
<p>The cable-based system has been serving customers of Stream, the multimedia group formed by STET to implement the new services, since last September, IBM said.</p>
<p>It said digital broadcasting allows for the transmission of up to 10 compressed digital programs on the same bandwidth taken up by one analog program.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
