<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="492040" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Culligan buys interest in Argentine water bottler.</title>
<headline>Culligan buys interest in Argentine water bottler.</headline>
<dateline>NORTHBROOK, Ill. 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Culligan Water Technologies Inc said Monday it acquired a 51 percent interest in  Sparkling SA, a bottled water company based in Buenos Aires, Argentina, for about $19.5 million.</p>
<p>Culligan said it also agreed to purchase the remaining 49 percent over a two-year period at a purchase price based on Sparkling's earnings.  </p>
<p>Doug Pertz, Culligan president, said the acquisition is expected to be accretive to earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition, we anticipate further activity in this market as we continue to look for opportunities to expand Culligan's presence in South America and other areas of the world,&quot; Pertz said.</p>
<p>Sparkling is Argentina's leading five-gallon bottled water company with 44 percent of the market. Sparkling expects to report net sales of over $15 million for the year ended March 31, Culligan said.</p>
<p>&quot;The acquisition of Sparkling is the first step in Culligan's expansion efforts in Latin America,&quot; Kenneth Wellings, Culligan Group President - International, said in a statement. &quot;We see significant growth opportunities in this market for the full line of Culligan products as economies have stabilized and a pattern of strong growth has been achieved.&quot;</p>
<p>Culligan manufactures and distributes water purification and treatment products for retail, household, bottled water, commercial and industrial applications.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NORTHBROOK, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
