<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="492019" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Netanyahu vows to hold &quot;united&quot; Jerusalem.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu vows to hold &quot;united&quot; Jerusalem.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu defended Israel's right to build Jewish housing in East Jerusalem on Monday and vowed, to thunderous applause, that Israel would never yield sway over Jerusalem.</p>
<p>In a speech to a pro-Israeli American group hours before he was to confer with President Bill Clinton on the crumbling Middle East peace process, Netanyanu dismissed those who challenged &quot;our right to build apartments&quot; in East Jerusalem and added: &quot;But I want to assure you today we will never allow Jerusalem to be redivided again. Never! Never!&quot;  </p>
<p>While he broke no new policy ground in his remarks to the supportive Washington audience, Netanyahu set a tough tone for his talks with Clinton. They were hurriedly arranged in hopes of reviving Israeli-Palestinian talks brought to a halt by Arab objection to Israeli home-building in mainly Arab East Jerusalem and Arab attacks on Israelis.</p>
<p>&quot;Now there's been some talk about our giving something -- making a concession in return for a real crackdown by the Palestinian authority on the terrorist organization,&quot; Netanyahu said. &quot;And this means pure and simple surrender to terrorism. We are are being told to pay for the privilege of not being killed. We are not going to do that,&quot; he said to loud applause.</p>
<p>Palestinian officials have said their president, Yasser Arafat, will not resume peace talks unless the Israelis halt their East Jerusalem housing construction.</p>
<p>Netanyahu portrayed such construction as the normal part of city life, saying, &quot;That's what happens in cities, they grow ... And that's what we're doing. We're allowing contractors to build in Har Homa for the Jewish couple who needs it. But we're also allowing construction and contractors to build in 10 Arab neighborhoods, actually a greater number of apartments in the next three years for Palestinian couples. Why not? That is what we do as the sovereign in a united Jerusalem. We take care of all its residents.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
