<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="492173" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Food Lion results puts Delhaize under pressure.</title>
<headline>Food Lion results puts Delhaize under pressure.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Belgian retailer Delhaize came under further pressure on Monday after plunging almost six percent on Friday as leading U.S. brokerages downgraded its U.S. unit Food Lion.</p>
<p>The downgrade of Delhaize's U.S. Food Lion unit followed an announcement late on Thursday that first quarter 1997 earnings rose 11 percent, but growth had been slowed by its acquisition last year of the U.S.  Kash 'n Karry chain.</p>
<p>&quot;Food Lion's flat sales growth has worried us and means that competition is increasing in the U.S.,&quot; Generale Bank analyst Sandra Vandermissen said.  </p>
<p>&quot;(What is) more likely to trigger downward earnings revisions is the disappointing first quarter sales evolution at Food Lion's own supermarkets, which booked flat same store sales on the back of an increase in the intense competitive climate and the mild winter,&quot; Generale Bank (GB) said in a research note.</p>
<p>Vandermissens said Generale Bank had slightly lowered its results forecast for Food Lion and the predicted earnings per share of Delhaize in 1997 from 104 Belgian francs to 102 francs.</p>
<p>Belgian brokerage Vermeulen Raemdonck/BBL gave a 99 Belgian francs 1997 EPS for Delhaize.  </p>
<p>&quot;Food Lion's flat sales growth has worried us and means that competition is increasing in the U.S.,&quot; Generale Bank analyst Sandra Vandermissen said.</p>
<p>The downgrade was also sparked by news that the acquisition of Kash 'n Karry by Food Lion in December 1996 had not yet produced an immediate effect on Food Lion's 1997 earnings.</p>
<p>This was contrary to what Delhaize announced in December, analysts said.</p>
<p>The refinancing of the Kash 'n Karry's debt, synergies in technology and buying power and new marketing initiatives were expected to have helped Food Lion's results.</p>
<p>&quot;Given Food Lion's latest statement that it will take several quarters to realise the expected synergies and that the first benefits will only start to materialise during the fourth-quarter of 1997 busy holiday season, we fear the consensus estimate of an additional first year 0.03 dollar increase in EPS owing to Kash 'n Karry will prove too optimistic,&quot; GB said.</p>
<p>By 1045 GMT Delhaize was down 1.45 percent at 1,705 francs, after earlier rising 1.5 percent. Volume was high with over 370 million francs worth of the share traded.</p>
<p>&quot;We maintain our hold recommendation although we expect the shares to underperform until an announcement in the fall of this year of a partnership in Asia,&quot; GB said.</p>
<p>Vermeulen Raemdonck/BBL gave Delhaize a &quot;buy&quot; recommendation.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that there is a short term downside risk on Food Lion which will affect Delhaize. The latter remains our favourite in the Belgian retail sector on a fundamental basis,&quot; Vermeulen said.</p>
<p>-- Paul de Bendern, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6815, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
