<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="492348" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Wool blending drive produces results - IWS.</title>
<headline>Wool blending drive produces results - IWS.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The wool industry was responding to market demands by continuing to reduce fabric weight and increase blending with other fibres such as lycra, International Wool Secretariat (IWS) director of information and planning Ian Hilton told the 1997 Australian Wool Forum on Monday.</p>
<p>IWS was continuing to support production of finer wools and blends with microfibres to meet new comfort requirements, he said.  </p>
<p>IWS international product marketing manager Sarah Condie said a successful partnership of wool product innovation and marketing had delivered solid results in traditional and growing markets for wool.</p>
<p>&quot;To catch up ground lost to cotton and chemical fibres, wool had become easier to care for with the introduction of machine washable woollens and easy care wovens,&quot; Condie said.</p>
<p>Spearheading strategic or value-added blends were wool plus lycra, wool/cotton and wool/fine denier polyester, she said.  </p>
<p>&quot;While pure new wool remains the cornerstone of our activities, the newer wool blends are helping to break down the traditional barriers faced by wool and protect some of our existing markets,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>In less than two years of an IWS global marketing programme, wool plus lycra had attracted 36 retail partners worldwide, covering more than 3,600 stores, she said.</p>
<p>Consumption had grown rapidly to about 17 million metres in the first year.  </p>
<p>For every dollar IWS spent on promoting the new blend, Dupont and retailers spend five dollars, she said. In 1997/98 this meant industry would contribute about A$10 million of non-grower funds for promotion, she said.</p>
<p>Efforts by the new Lightweight Wool to penetrate the U.S. market, where consumers had believed wool was only for winter, was heavy and difficult to care for, were producing encouraging results, she said.</p>
<p>In its first year, the programme exceeded financial goals by 41 percent. Garment sales for spring/summer jumped to 158,000 units in 1996 from 93,000 units in 1995, she said.  </p>
<p>Wool's selling period was broadened to June from January and involved high-profile retailers, she said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
