<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="492439" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: CAL may adjust routes if HK fees too high.</title>
<headline>CAL may adjust routes if HK fees too high.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's China Airlines Ltd, a major carrier on the Taiwan-Hong Kong route, said on Monday it may consider alternatives for its China-bound passengers if the charges at Hong Kong's new airport were doubled.</p>
<p>Chairman Chiang Hung-i said the carrier wanted to continue its services to Hong Kong and hoped the Hong Kong Airport Authority and government would take into consideration airlines' operational costs in come up with reasonable charges.</p>
<p>&quot;But as an airline operator we pay extremely close attention to our bottom lines,&quot; he told reporters in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Direct flights between political rivals Taiwan and China are currently banned and much of the passenger and freight traffic between the two sides have to flow through Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Chiang said that if fees at Hong Kong's new airport at Chek Lap Kok was double the charges at the current Kai Tak airport, that certainly would call the airline's attention to see if there was any alternative.</p>
<p>&quot;If the alternative is available there is a possibility we'll made some necessary adjustment,&quot; he said. &quot;I hope it would not happen like that.&quot;  </p>
<p>Hong Kong's Airport Authority has proposed nearly doubling charges airlines would pay at the Chek Lap Kok, due to open in April 198, compared to those of Kai Tak.</p>
<p>Nearby Portuguese-administered Macau has laid claim to some of the Taiwan-China traffic since it opened its airport in late 1995. Air Macau and Taiwan's EVA Airways and TransAsia Airlines are authorised to operate the Taiwan-Macau route.</p>
<p>But Chiang said Taiwan-Macau flights have had only a small, less-than-expected impact on China Airlines' business.</p>
<p>He said China Airlines had more flights and good links with airlines flying into China from Hong Kong.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6369</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
