<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="492436" id="root" date="1997-04-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: OPINION - Ivan Wong comments on Malaysian palm oil.</title>
<headline>OPINION - Ivan Wong comments on Malaysian palm oil.</headline>
<text>
<p>KUALA LUMPUR, April 7 - For the second consecutive month, CPO production had turned out to be much better than previous tentative estimate. On the basis of partial data available, our preliminary estimate shows production in March rose vigorously by 160,000 tonnes or 32 percent to 663,000 tonnes. The robust month-on-month increase was evident in all producing regions in the country. Compared to a year earlier, production grew three percent. After adjusting for distortions arising from the double-festive holiday factor, production in February-March registered a strong annual growth of 8.8 percent.  </p>
<p>This is much better than the growth of 2.2 percent posted in January. The growth for the three months ended March amounted to 108,000 tonnes or 6.6 percent. In the February issue of PORLA update released last week, PORLA projected CPO production to expand 3.7 percent or around 315,000 tonnes to 8.7 million tonnes this year. This compares with the strong growth rates of 7.4 percent in 1996 and 8.2 percent in 1995. The large increase in CPO supplies couple with a moderate drop in prices to more affordable levels since February 24 had stimulated a strong recovery in demand in March.  </p>
<p>CPO offtake is estimated to have increased 185,000 tonnes to around 645,000 tonnes. This reflected a jump in palm oil export to an estimated 560,000 tonnes from a preliminary export figure of 377,000 tonnes in February reported by PORLA. The bulk of the increased exports was accounted by China which raised its offtake substantially to an estimated 115,000 tonnes from around 40,000 tonnes in February. With offtake almost matching output in March, stocks of CPO at the end of the month thus remained practically unchanged at around 725,000 tonnes.  </p>
<p>Stocks of palm oil are estimated at 415,000 tonnes as against 401,000 tonnes at end February and 406,500 tonnes a year ago. PPO stocks are estimated to have declined slightly to 310,000 tonnes. After dropping some 65 ringgit during February 24-March 7 CPO futures prices stabilised thereafter. The settlement price of the active third month contract fluctuated narrowly between 1,236 ringgit and 1,264 ringgit. Last week the price settled at 1,244 ringgit or little changed from 1,245 ringgit a week earlier.  </p>
<p>The lack of volatility in price movements had discouraged major traders from taking any big positions. Weekly turnover on the KLCE dropped to as low as 5,111 lots in the week ended March 28. It recovered slightly to 7,810 lots last week. A somewhat more volatile CBOT soy futures had little impact on the palm oil market. The inability of major competing oils such as SBO, RSO and sunoil to move decisively higher had tended to restrain the upward potential of palm oil even when the latter enjoyed a good pickup in demand.  </p>
<p>Now that Indonesian exporters have become somewhat more competitive and competing with Malaysian exporters in such major markets as China and India, palm oil prices are likely to face even greater difficulty to forge ahead in the coming weeks. Cash CPO price in January-March averaged 1,314.50 ringgit. This is 93 ringgit or 7.6 percent higher than the same period last year. We would be satisfied if prices in the second quarter could match the year ago level of 1,230 ringgit.</p>
<p>(The opinions expressed in this article represent the views of the author only. They should not be seen as necessarily reflecting the views of Reuters).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
