<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="492903" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends dull session mainly weaker.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends dull session mainly weaker.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures finished mainly weaker in thin, directionless dealings on Tuesday, pressured by light speculative selling, traders said.</p>
<p>A lack of fresh fundamental input contributed to today's sluggish tone, they said, with local activity on both sides of the market confining prices to a narrow range.</p>
<p>May closed down 0.65 cent per lb, at 178.75 cents, after trading from 180.80 to 176.00. Second-month July settled 0.55 cent weaker, at 164.50 cents, while the back months finished 1.90 lower to 3.50 higher.</p>
<p>The closely watched May/July switch, which widened to around 15.00 cents during the session, ended at 14.25 cents, down slightly from 14.35 cents at the close Monday.</p>
<p>Some traders said May's recent struggle to close over the 180.00-cent level could lead to further losses in the near-term.</p>
<p>&quot;In the short-term, I think the market will go lower simply because it's not going up,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Technically, traders pegged May support at 175.00 cents, then 172.00-171.00 cents. Resistance was seen at 183.00-183.50, followed by 185.00.</p>
<p>Volume was light, at an estimated 5,250 lots, down from Monday's official tally of 6,444 lots.</p>
<p>After Tuesday's close, CSCE reported certified coffee stocks were off 500 60-kg bags, to 81,828 bags as of April 7. There were no bags pending grading, the exchange said.</p>
<p>((--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodity Desk +1 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
