<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="492935" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Energy Dept proposes leasing oil shale reserves.</title>
<headline>US Energy Dept proposes leasing oil shale reserves.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Energy Department said Tuesday it was proposing to transfer its three Naval Oil Shale Reserves to the Interior Department to lease out and to preserve wilderness areas, instead of selling the land.</p>
<p>In a report to Congress, the department also said it was recommending transferring its Buena Vista Hills Naval Petroleum Reserve in California to the Interior Deaprtment, leaving existing leasing agreements intact.</p>
<p>The report to Congress was filed to fulfill a 1996 law requiring the Energy Department to sell its big Elk Hills oil and gas field stake in California, and decide whether to sell its reserves in Colorado, Utah and Buena Vista Hills.</p>
<p>An independent consultant told the department that selling the reserves or leasing them would yield the same value for the U.S. government, even without the 50 percent in royalties that would go to the states if the land were leased.</p>
<p>&quot;DOE concluded that transferring the properties to the Interior Department's leasing program would allow undeveloped acreage to be explored while still under Federal ownership, providing a more accurate evaluation of the properties' future mineral value,&quot; the Energy Department said.</p>
<p>The report also recommended that the government should keep its Teapot Dome reserve in Wyoming until the small field, now producing 1,800 barrels per day, is depleted around 2003.</p>
<p>The petroleum reserves were set aside early this century to build up a source of oil for the military, but have largely been used for commercial oil and gas sales. The oil shale reserves were left undeveloped because they were uneconomic.</p>
<p>However, the oil shale reserves in Colorado are in areas where natural gas is being produced commercially and the reserve in Utah is believed to have oil and gas production potential.</p>
<p>The department expects to put its Elk Hills stake up for bids later this month, so that it can meet a February 1998 deadline for a sale.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
