<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493067" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: SOCCER-JUVENTUS ON A HIGH AHEAD OF AJAX CLASH.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-JUVENTUS ON A HIGH AHEAD OF AJAX CLASH.</headline>
<byline>Philip Blenkinsop</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Cup semifinal between Ajax Amsterdam and Juventus on Wednesday pits the 1995 and 1996 champions against each other and offers a repeat of last year's final.</p>
<p>The two sides were then evenly balanced, the Italian giants claiming the title on penalties. This year, though, Juventus appear to hold the trump cards.</p>
<p>Even in the Netherlands, many doubt whether Ajax can extract revenge.</p>
<p>Last week the Dutch side's Finnish international Jari Litmanen rated Juventus the best club side in the world, saying they appeared even stronger than last year.</p>
<p>And at the weekend Juve appeared to prove him right with a 6-1 demolition of Italian champions AC Milan in the league.</p>
<p>But although Juventus start as favourites for the two-leg semifinal, Ajax's form has improved markedly since their stuttering start to the season. Since the winter break they are unbeaten in Europe and have a 100 percent record in the Dutch league.</p>
<p>Coach Louis van Gaal is upbeat about his side's prospects and believes Ajax are a much fresher and sharper outfit than the one that lost in last year's final.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is one team in the world that can beat Juventus, then it is us,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Turin team's only problem is the fitness of Croat Alen Boksic who has a muscle strain. However, the return of Frenchman Didier Deschamps should be adequate compensation.</p>
<p>Juventus coach Marcello Lippi was expected to confirm a frontline of Nicola Amoruso partnering Azzuri new boy Christian Vieri.</p>
<p>Amoruso replaced Boksic in the Milan massacre and got on the scoresheet.</p>
<p>Ajax seem set to field largely the team that came back to win a thrilling quarter-final second leg at Atletico Madrid with Patrick Kluivert, suspended for the match in Spain, now sidelined by injury.</p>
<p>The Dutch international striker would be an automatic starter. But a knee injury sustained in the 1-0 World Cup qualifier defeat in Turkey has shown no signs of improvement and he faces an operation on the day of the match.</p>
<p>Ajax expect Kluivert to be out for about a month, so he seems bound to miss the return leg in Italy. Indeed, Kluivert, who is bound for AC Milan at the end of the season, may not play for Ajax again.</p>
<p>Defender Danny Blind, midfielder Marc Overmars and strikers Nordin Wooter and Dani are all carrying slight injuries but are likely to play.</p>
<p>More doubtful is defender Mario Melchiot who saw an eye specialist on Monday.</p>
<p>Ajax's joint top scorer, Dani, who netted a sensational extra time goal in Madrid, will again be on the sidelines.</p>
<p>Probable teams:</p>
<p>Ajax - Edwin van de Saar; Mario Melchiot, Danny Blind, Frank de Boer, Winston Bogarde; Arnold Scholten, Richard Witschge, Jari Litmanen; Tijani Babangida, Ronald de Boer, Marc Overmars.</p>
<p>Juventus - Angelo Peruzzi, Sergio Porrini, Ciro Ferrara, Paolo Montero, Mark Iuliano, Angelo Di Livio, Didier Deschamps, Zinedine Zidane, Vladimir Jugovic, Christian Vieri, Nicola Amoruso.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
