<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493060" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-DODGERS LOSE BUTLER TO SALIVARY GLAND DISORDER.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-DODGERS LOSE BUTLER TO SALIVARY GLAND DISORDER.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Los Angeles Dodgers centre fielder Brett Butler, who made a remarkable recovery from throat cancer last year, is out indefinitely with a salivary gland problem, the team said Monday.</p>
<p>The injury, believed to be related to his cancer surgery, sidelined Butler for Monday night's game against the New York Mets.</p>
<p>Butler originally was to see an ear and throat specialist later this week but he had his appointment moved up to Monday. He has played in each of the Dodgers six games this season, batting .273 with a double in 22 at-bats.</p>
<p>The 39-year-old Butler learned he had cancer during a tonsillectomy in April 1996. He had surgery to remove a malignant tumour from his tonsils on May 21. He rejoined the team on August 26 and was activated from the disabled list on September 6.</p>
<p>However, Butler's season ended just five games later when a pitch broke his left hand. Overall, he batted .267 with one homer and eight RBI and eight stolen bases in 34 games.</p>
<p>Butler has a lifetime average of .290 and has 2,284 hits and 544 stolen bases. He is one of 26 players with 2,000 hits and 500 steals and was the first player in major-league history to lead the league in singles for four consecutive seasons, from 1990-93.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
