<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493028" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: HORSE RACING - LORD GYLLENE WINS DELAYED GRAND NATIONAL.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING - LORD GYLLENE WINS DELAYED GRAND NATIONAL.</headline>
<byline>Dave Thompson</byline>
<dateline>LIVERPOOL, England 1997-04-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lord Gyllene, ridden by Tony Dobbin, produced a brilliant display of front-running to win Monday's rescheduled Grand National steeplechase.</p>
<p>Lord Gyllene (14-1) made all the running and won by 25 lengths from Suny Bay (8-1), the mount of Jamie Osborne. It was the first time for more than 70 years that a horse had been in front all the way.</p>
<p>Camelot Knight, a 100-1 outsider ridden by Carl Llewellyn, ran on to be third, two lengths behind Suny Bay.</p>
<p>The race took place under the tightest security ever seen at a British racecourse after a bomb scare meant the race had to be abandoned on Saturday.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Major, breaking into his election schedule, and Princess Anne, daughter of Britain's Queen Elizabeth, attended Monday's race.</p>
<p>Along with 20,000 racing fans, they witnessed a splendid display by Lord Gyllene, an out-and-out stayer who hardly put a foot wrong.    Suny Bay kept company with the winner for much</p>
<p>of the 7.2-km trip as the 36-strong field negotiated the 30 famous obstacles.</p>
<p>But from two fences out it was clear that Lord Gyllene held all the aces and, bar a fall, it was all over.</p>
<p>Lord Gyllene scooped a record National first prize of $291,000 for owner Stan Clarke, who is chairman of Newcastle and Uttoxeter racecourses.</p>
<p>The winner is trained by Steve Brookshaw, whose late uncle Tim Brookshaw once finished second in the big race but was paralysed in a fall at Aintree in 1963.</p>
<p>Clarke said: &quot;If I sound hoarse, it's not that I'm ill. It's from all the shouting.&quot;</p>
<p>Northern-Ireland born Dobbin, steering well clear of politics (&quot;I don't get involved in any of that&quot;) was enjoying his first National success and the biggest win of his career.</p>
<p>He said: &quot;The crowd has been fantastic and he was fabulous over those fences.&quot;</p>
<p>Charlie Brooks, trainer of runner-up Suny Bay, said: &quot;We were going really well at one point but we were beaten by a better horse on the day.&quot;</p>
<p>Referring to Saturday's abandonment when the 70,000 crowd had to be evacuated, Brooks said: &quot;There is a sense of pride in racing here today and we live to fight another day.&quot;</p>
<p>Lord Gyllene had been successful in a couple of races in New Zealand, where he was bred, before being bought to race in Britain.</p>
<p>He had proved himself this season with three victories in staying races but there were fears he might be vulnerable at the end to something with more finishing pace.</p>
<p>However, as the remains of the field turned into the straight for the second and final time, it was obvious nothing had as much in the tank as Lord Gyllene.</p>
<p>The 7-1 favourite Go Ballistic, ridden by last year's winning jockey Mick Fitzgerald, never got into the argument and came home 17th of the 18th finishers.</p>
<p>Top weight Master Oats, partnered by Norman Williamson, was up with the pace for much of the trip but ran out of steam in the straight to finish fifth, just behind Buckboard Bounce (40-1), the mount of Paul Carberry.</p>
<p>Avro Anson, a well-fancied challenger from northern England, finished sixth for jockey Peter Niven.</p>
<p>Trainer Jenny Pitman, known as the Queen of Aintree, had a disappointing day with her duo.</p>
<p>Nahthen Lad finished ninth and Smith's Band, who fell at the 20th and broke his neck, was one of two fatalities in the race. The other was Straight Talk who broke a leg at the 14th obstacle.</p>
<p>Leading Irish raider Wylde Hide unseated his rider Charlie Swan at the 22nd.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIVERPOOL, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
