<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493065" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: EIB WARNS GREECE AGAINST OLYMPICS-GENERATED DEBTS.</title>
<headline>EIB WARNS GREECE AGAINST OLYMPICS-GENERATED DEBTS.</headline>
<byline>Dina Kyriakidou</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greece, among those shortlisted to host the 2004 summer Olympics, could saddle itself with huge debts by trying to stage the world's biggest sports festival, the European Investment Bank said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Warning against big infrastructure projects of only short term use, EIB Vice President Panayotis Gennimatas told an economic conference that not all grand-scale construction was necessary for economic development.</p>
<p>&quot;This goes especially for those who are seriously considering the 2004 Olympics in Athens,&quot; he said. &quot;The Olympics...could be a moment of sinful pleasure that may leave behind a lasting debt.&quot;</p>
<p>He said international exhibitions, such as one in Seville in 1992 and another planned in Lisbon for 1998, are examples of such short-lived joys.</p>
<p>&quot;A visit to the Seville fair ghost-town will be especially didactic to those who handle state money responsibly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Greece was spurned by the International Olympic Committee (IOC) in its bid to host the centennial 1996 Olympics but it has buried its anger and is trying again.</p>
<p>The IOC has described Athens' estimated revenues from the Games as optimistic but gave its bid file a good overall review, along with Rome and Stockholm. It will make its final decision in September.</p>
<p>No longer demanding the Games as its birthright as the country where the ancient Olympics were born and the modern Games revived in 1896, Greece has put on a new face of modern efficiency and state of the art facilities.</p>
<p>A new international airport and an Athens metro, mostly funded by the European Union, along with a series of ring-roads around the congested capital of four million people are scheduled to finish before the Games.</p>
<p>Greece has said it would have built the projects anyway to make the city more liveable but is speeding them up for the Olympics.</p>
<p>It already has Olympic size-stadiums but will need additional facilities such as an athletes' village and water sports venues.</p>
<p>Environmental groups have slammed the planned construction, saying it will mean disaster for an overdeveloped city that has few green spaces.</p>
<p>But the bidding committee says its plan will actually improve traffic and smog and has adjusted its designs to accommodate sensitive wildlife areas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
