<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493129" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FINNISH LEFTIST PARTY WANTS TIME-OUT ON EMU.</title>
<headline>FINNISH LEFTIST PARTY WANTS TIME-OUT ON EMU.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finland may do wisely to remain outside the founding group of Europe's single currency and not join from the start in 1999, Esko Helle, chairman of the Leftist Alliance party's parliamentary group, said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The national parliament's decision on Finnish EMU membership should not be a vote of confidence in the government, Helle said in a statement.</p>
<p>The party is one of five in the left-right-green cabinet.</p>
<p>&quot;Among ordinary people, there are doubts about economic and monetary union and the single currency so a time-out would -- for this reason -- certainly be appropriate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We can gain experience of the superiority of our own markka by initially opting out of economic and monetary union,&quot; he said. &quot;There is, of course, the risk that the government's proposal to join EMU may be rejected (by parliament).</p>
<p>&quot;If this choice leads, for example to some kind of rise in interest rates and slower economic growth, then that is the price we must pay for democracy,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Leftist Alliance deputy party chairman Martti Korhonen said in a separate statement that Finland should take a time-out to let the views of the people and political decision-makers crystallise. --Helsinki newsroom +358-9-680 50 245, e-mail news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
