<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493149" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - April 15.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - April 15.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the major events to have occurred on April 15 in history:</p>
<p>1450 - The French defeated the English at the Battle of Formigny in the last phase of the 100 Years' War.</p>
<p>1469 - Nanak, Indian spiritual teacher who founded Sikhism, born near Lahore, India.</p>
<p>1755 - Dr Samuel Johnson, English poet, journalist and lexicographer, had his famous dictionary published on this day.</p>
<p>1764 - Jeanne-Antoinette Poisson, Marquise de Pompadour, French courtier and mistress of King Louis XV, died.</p>
<p>1797 - British naval personnel mutinied at Spithead, in the English Channel.</p>
<p>1865 - Andrew Johnson became the 17th president of the United States after the assassination of Abraham Lincoln.</p>
<p>1888 - Matthew Arnold, British poet, died.</p>
<p>1891 - Katanga Company was formed in Brussels to exploit copper deposits in the Katanga area of Central Africa.</p>
<p>1912 - The White Star passenger liner Titanic sank on her maiden voyage after hitting an iceberg off Newfoundland; 1,523 of the 2,200 passengers and crew lost their lives in the supposedly unsinkable vessel.</p>
<p>1920 - Richard von Weizsaecker, German politician and statesman, born; president of West Germany 1984-94.</p>
<p>1923 - In New York, at the Rialto Theatre, Lee De Forest screened a selection of musical shorts demonstrating his sound-on-film process, the first sound films to be demonstrated before a paying audience.</p>
<p>1938 - General Francisco Franco's forces captured Vinaroz in the Spanish Civil war.</p>
<p>1942 - The George Cross, Britain's highest accolade for civilian gallantry, was conferred on Malta by King George VI for bravery in withstanding Italian and German attacks.</p>
<p>1945 - British troops liberated the Bergen-Belsen concentration camp in Germany.</p>
<p>1949 - Wallace Beery, U.S. film actor and Oscar winner for his part in the film &quot;The Champ&quot;, died.</p>
<p>1966 - Ugandan Prime Minister Milton Obote was declared president under a new constitution.</p>
<p>1971 - British and Chinese governments agreed to the reopening of a telephone link between London and Shanghai which had been closed for 22 years.</p>
<p>1974 - The 15-year rule of President Hamani Diori in Niger came to end when he was deposed in a coup.</p>
<p>1980 - French philosopher, novelist and poet Jean-Paul Sartre died. He was awarded, but declined to accept, the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1964.</p>
<p>1989 - At the Hillsborough football stadium in Sheffield, northern England, 96 people died when a gate was opened to let in supporters onto an already crowded terrace.</p>
<p>1990 - Greta Garbo, enigmatic Swedish-born film star, died.</p>
<p>1991 - European Community foreign ministers agreed to lift most remaining sanctions against South Africa.</p>
<p>1992 - Governments across the world applied U.N. sanctions against Libya because of its alleged involvement in the destruction of a Pan Am airliner over Lockerbie in 1988 and the bombing of a French plane over Niger in 1989.</p>
<p>1994 - Ministers from the world's trading nations signed the GATT pact (General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade), the biggest market-opening treaty in history.</p>
<p>1996 - South Africa's &quot;truth commission&quot;, looking into abuses during the apartheid era, began its public hearings.</p>
<p>1996 - Japan and the U.S. announced the closure of six more U.S. military facilities on the southern Japanese island of Okinawa, reducing the amount of land occupied by American forces there by a fifth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
