<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493186" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Salomon names EBRD's Freeman to key Euro job.</title>
<headline>Salomon names EBRD's Freeman to key Euro job.</headline>
<byline>Joe Ortiz</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. investment bank Salomon Brothers on Tuesday appointed the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development's (EBRD) top banker as co-head of its global investment banking operations.</p>
<p>Unlike the other two co-heads, Eduardo Mestre and Eric Fast, who are based in New York, Ron Freeman will be based in London, underlining the growing importance of Salomon's business in Europe.</p>
<p>He is currently first vice-president of the EBRD.</p>
<p>Freeman will renew old friendships at Salomon where he spent 18 years before going to the multilateral bank which took on the huge task of promoting the economic development of eastern Europe and saw its workload hugely increased by the break-up of the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>His capture in 1991 by the EBRD's controversial founding President Jacques Attali was seen at the time as a big feather in Attali's cap -- one of the few times the flamboyant Frenchman enjoyed the approval of the press.</p>
<p>Attali departed the bank in 1993, his reputation crushed by controversy over big spending on the EBRD's London headquarters, thousands of pounds was infamously spent on marble for the entrance hall, and other financial irregularities.</p>
<p>Freeman was visibly uncomfortable about the adverse publicity at the time, always wanting to focus on the positive side of what the EBRD was doing and defending Attali for having the vision to build the EBRD from a standing start.</p>
<p>But Freeman, by all accounts, also forged a strong relationship with Attali's successor Jacques de Larosiere, a former head of the International Monetary Fund, who got the EBRD back on track, cut its costs and removed it from the front-pages.</p>
<p>&quot;Ron Freeman has served the Bank in a superb way,&quot; said de Larosiere. &quot;...he has helped make the EBRD the most effective agent in financing the transition of central and eastern Europe and the CIS to a market economy.&quot;</p>
<p>Salomon, where in his previous career Freeman rose to be head of European investment banking, has been building its presence in Europe in recent times and is expected to use Freeman's east European experience to the full in promoting itself in these emerging markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Freeman fits like a glove,&quot; said one investment banker. &quot;He knows the Salomon culture and he knows everyone who matters in Europe.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
