<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493133" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Hamilton confirmed by Conservative Party.</title>
<headline>UK's Hamilton confirmed by Conservative Party.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>KNUTSFORD, England 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Neil Hamilton, a former Conservative minister accused of taking cash for asking parliamentary questions, was confirmed by local members of the party on Tuesday as their candidate for Britain's May 1 election.</p>
<p>Local Conservative Party Tresurer Tony Martin said Hamilton was adopted by a vote of 182-100 by party members in a meeting at the 500-year-old Dixon Arms pub.</p>
<p>&quot;One hundred and eighty-two people voted to select him as candidate. One hundred did not vote to select him,&quot; he told reporters waiting outside the meeting.</p>
<p>Despite pressure from senior Conservative Party officials Hamilton has refused to stand down. He has consistently denied the allegations in the influence-peddling scandal that has hurt the ruling Conservatives who are 20 points behind Labour in national opinion polls.</p>
<p>Hamilton's persistence and a decision by veteran BBC war correspondent Martin Bell to stand against him as an anti-corruption candidate have pushed the sleaze issue and the Tatton seat in northwest England to the forefront of the election campaign.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Major had refused to get involved, insisting that the decision on who should stand for the seat that Hamilton won in 1992 with a large majority of votes, should be left to the local party.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the responsibility of the people who elect their MP in the Conservative Party to select or deselect a candidate,&quot; he said in television interview earlier on Tuesday. &quot;It is the responsibility of the candidate to decide whether or not they will stand.</p>
<p>As Hamilton entered the pub for the meeting he admitted to feeling more like a pop star than a politician when he was mobbed by reporters and cameramen.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just like being Liam Gallagher (lead singer of the pop group Oasis),&quot; Hamilton told reporters.</p>
<p>Asked her feelings about the meeting, Christine Hamilton replied, &quot;Let's face the music and dance.&quot;</p>
<p>Bell, when told that Hamilton had been confirmed as the Conservative candidate, said he would fight him to the finish.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday the two men came face-to-face in a confrontation as Bell was about to address an open-air press conference explaining why he was standing in the constituency.</p>
<p>The two, standing inches apart and surrounded by a forest of cameras and microphones, traded verbal thrust and counter-thrust.</p>
<p>Hamilton asked the highly respected journalist if he was trying to destroy his political career.</p>
<p>&quot;The irresistible inference to be drawn from that is that you think I am guilty of corruption in some shape or form,&quot; said Hamilton.</p>
<p>Bell, who has dodged bullets for 30 years in wars from Vietnam to Bosnia, answered: &quot;I think the issue of trust is important.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I have not admitted any mendacity,&quot; Hamilton came back.</p>
<p>Bell, wearing his trademark white suit worn as a talisman on battlefields around the world, said he would not be drawn into the debate surrounding the cash for questions affair.</p>
<p>&quot;I refuse to be ambushed like this,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bell announced his intention to stand on Sunday. He is supported by both main opposition parties, who have withdrawn their candidates.</p>
<p>His intervention is unprecedented in post-war British politics. Bookmakers say he is 2-5 favourite to defeat Hamilton.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KNUTSFORD, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
