<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493243" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Goodale sees ideas soon on Canada grain shipments.</title>
<headline>Goodale sees ideas soon on Canada grain shipments.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Agriculture Minister Ralph Goodale said on Tuesday he expected to receive industry recommendations very soon on how to avoid the grain backlogs that have plagued Western Canada this year.</p>
<p>He said there had been consensus at a meeting that he convened in Calgary in February between representatives of the rail and grain industry that a system of rewards and penalties needed to be implemented.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a pretty common belief across Western Canada that the present system is not sufficiently accountable,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Subsequent to the Calgary meeting, industry officials met and were considering recommendations, he said.</p>
<p>One approach would be to make legally binding contractual arrangements that reward above-standard performance by the rail and grain industries and penalize below-standard jobs.</p>
<p>A second approach would be a legislative or regulatory approach, sanctioning the rewards and penalties by law.</p>
<p>A third would be a combination of the two, he added.</p>
<p>The idea would be to remove at least part of the burden, when the system broke down, from the farmer.</p>
<p>With a federal election expected in June or possibly October, it was questionable if new legislation could get through before then.</p>
<p>The looming elections were also calling into question the government's ability to pass two farm bills, although Goodale said they were not controversial and could be whisked through both houses of Parliament if there was the will.</p>
<p>One bill, C-34, would establish programs for marketing farm products and would repeal the Agricultural Products Board Act, the Agricultural Products Cooperative marketing Act and two other acts.</p>
<p>The other, C-38, would provide for mediation between insolvent farmers and their creditors.</p>
<p>((Randall Palmer, Reuters Ottawa Bureau 613-235-6745))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
