<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493275" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMEROON: Over 70 parties hope to contest Cameroon poll.</title>
<headline>Over 70 parties hope to contest Cameroon poll.</headline>
<dateline>YAOUNDE 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seventy-four political parties have applied to field candidates in Cameroon's May 17 legislative polls, electoral authorities said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;As of the deadline yesterday...we had 74 parties that indicated their intention to participate,&quot; said Eban Eton, director of political affairs at the Interior Ministry, which runs elections in the Central African nation.</p>
<p>Eton told Reuters 3.5 million voters had been registered to cast ballots at 16,000 polling stations.</p>
<p>A total of 32 parties vied for seats in the 180-seat National Assembly in the last elections in 1992, Cameroon's first multi-party poll. Only four parties were eventually represented in parliament.</p>
<p>The May poll was initially planned for March.</p>
<p>Officials said only four leading parties were likely to field candidates in all constituencies. Opposition parties last week complained bitterly about a government decision to redefine constituencies after a deadline given them to indicate where they intended to field candidates.</p>
<p>Cameroon launched its sometimes turbulent transition to democracy in 1990 along with several other African states.</p>
<p>The largest opposition party, the Social Democratic Party of crusading Anglophone politician John Fru Ndi, boycotted that poll, saying there were no guarantees for free and fair elections.</p>
<p>The Cameroon People's Democratic Movement of President Paul Biya took 88 assembly seats and allied with the National Union for Democracy and Progress, which clinched 68. Two smaller parties, the Cameroon People's Union and the Movement for the Defence of the Republic won 18 and six seats respectively.</p>
<p>The Social Democrats have promised Biya's party a tough electoral fight this time but is already crying foul over a government crackdown on unrest in its volatile Northwestern Province base.</p>
<p>Fru Ndi accused the government of dirty tricks and of seeking an excuse to postpone the poll in the province.</p>
<p>Campaigning starts on May 2 and ends at midnight on May 16.</p>
<p>Biya, who took over from independence president Ahmadou Ahidjo in 1982, faces a presidential election in October.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CAMER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="YAOUNDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMEROON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
