<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493252" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: IPL says Lakehead restart could be slow.</title>
<headline>IPL says Lakehead restart could be slow.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPL Energy Inc unit Interprovincial Pipe Line said on Tuesday that its pipelines downstream from Superior, Wisconsin could be running again today, but that it may take some time to bring them back up to capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;When we shut down Line 5 and Line 6 we had drained all of the available crude oil to pump and then we shut down, so this might take some time before we build at Superior a few batches to pump,&quot; the company said on its shipper hotline.</p>
<p>Line 5 runs north of Lake Michigan to Sarnia, Ontario from Superior. Line 6 also extends to Sarnia but via Chicago.  </p>
<p>Both are part of IPL's affiliated Lakehead Pipe Line system.</p>
<p>IPL said earlier it restarted Lines 2 and 3, which carry crude oil to Superior from Edmonton, Alberta, but only at minimum rates.</p>
<p>IPL's pipeline system was virtually shut down on the weekend after a severe storm in Minnesota knocked out three pumping stations. About one million barrels a day were cut.</p>
<p>The company said on Tuesday that some power was restored to one of the stations, allowing the trickle of oil to resume flowing from western Canada.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, companies that operate pipelines that feed into IPL in Canada said they had yet to experience any major disruptions, but were closely monitoring the situation.</p>
<p>&quot;We're just kind of constantly evaluating and talking to the field. Naturally, storage is getting filled up but we do have some restrictions in place on the pipelines as well,&quot; Koch Oil Co Ltd official Dale Archer said.</p>
<p>Koch, a major IPL-fed refiner in Minnesota, operates three feeder pipelines in western Canada. Koch pipelines include the Bow River and Koch Alberta lines in Alberta and the Mid-Saskatchewan line in Saskatchewan.</p>
<p>Archer said the restrictions were put in place as a result of the IPL outage.</p>
<p>Mobil Corp unit Mobil Oil Canada, which operates the 210,000 barrel a day Rainbow pipeline in northern Alberta and the 50,000 barrel a day South Saskatchewan line, said it had yet to restrict any deliveries to the systems.</p>
<p>&quot;There might be a few cutbacks for tomorrow, but today they're fine,&quot; Mobil spokeswoman Heather Douglas said.</p>
<p>((Reuters Calgary Bureau (403) 531-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
