<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493324" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>TANZANIA: Tanzanian arabica crop hard hit by drought.</title>
<headline>Tanzanian arabica crop hard hit by drought.</headline>
<dateline>MOSHI, Tanzania 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tanzania's northern arabica coffee production could fall to as low as 10,000 tonnes for the 1997/98 season because of a severe drought which hit much of East Africa, government and industry officials said.</p>
<p>Northern arabica production in the 1996/97 season totalled about 16,000 tonnes, according to official statistics.</p>
<p>&quot;My guess is northern production will possibly be in the 10,000 to 12,000-tonne range. The problem was the absence of short rains in October, December,&quot; said Jeremy Lefroy, the secretary of the Tanzania Coffee Association (TCA).</p>
<p>Lefroy told Reuters at the weekend in the northern coffee town of Moshi that drought &quot;was clearly going to affect northern production.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the only glimmer of hope lay in a good coffee harvest forecast for Tanzania's southern arabica region which could help offset the expected production deficit in the north. But he did not give specific figures for the southern crop.</p>
<p>Lefroy's comments were backed by Epimaki Koinange, director of the Lyamangu Agriculture Research Institute near Moshi.</p>
<p>&quot;We're expecting this year a very big reduction (in northern coffee production). The drought has caused the leaves to shed, dried the young branches. What remains is something like a stick,&quot; Koinange told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said on most trees, coffee flowers dried and fell off before the onset of the current long rains.</p>
<p>The worst effected farms were those situated on Kilimanjaro's lower and middle zones.</p>
<p>The only exception would be farms with access to drip irrigation. &quot;If there was no irrigation I think you'll have very low production.&quot;</p>
<p>Annual coffee production for 1996/97 season is expected to be about 41,000 to 43,000 tonnes, worth about $90 million. This compares to 53,000 tonnes in 1995/96.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSHI, Tanzania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TANZANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
