<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493428" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Schwabisch Hall eyes Hungary's new housing market.</title>
<headline>Schwabisch Hall eyes Hungary's new housing market.</headline>
<byline>Sandor Peto</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fundamenta Rt, a joint venture of Germany's Bausparkasse Schwabisch Hall AG and Hungary's Takarekbank, plans to become the largest player on Hungary's opening building society market, the owners said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This company must become a market leader,&quot; Takarekbank CEO Zsolt Hernadi told a news conference.</p>
<p>Takarekbank, the umbrella bank of Hungary's savings cooperatives, holds a 14 percent stake in Fundamenta Rt, while 86 percent is owned by Schwabisch Hall (BSH).</p>
<p>Fundamenta is likely to receive a licence for its operations from the country's banking watchdog within a few weeks and will be among the first building societies to appear in Hungary, Fundamenta chairman Bela Bartfai said.</p>
<p>Hungary introduced a law allowing the formation of building societies with effect from January 1 this year.</p>
<p>OTP, the largest Hungarian commercial bank, as well as Lakaskassza, jointly owned by Austria's insurance group EA Generali and Postabank, Hungary's second largest retail bank, are expected to be Fundamenta's main competitors.</p>
<p>Bartfai said that Fundamenta aims to acquire a 30- to 40-percent share of Hungary's building society market.</p>
<p>Fundamenta's products will be distributed through a network of 1,700 Takarekbank branches and savings cooperatives and some 150 outlets of Hungaria Biztosito Rt, the insurance unit of Germany's Allianz, he said.</p>
<p>Hungaria, jointly with Germany's Deutsche Genossenschaftsbank recently won a tender for the privatisation of the 60.59 percent of Takarekbank.</p>
<p>The state is granting a 40 percent subsidy to individuals who put their savings in building societies in 1997 up to an annual amount of 36,000 forints. This will be reduced to 30 percent from 1998.</p>
<p>BSH Chairman Horst Kleiner said that since 1992, BSH had acquired over 80 percent of the building society market in Slovakia, and 45 percent in the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>However, Kleiner said he did not expect BSH's Hungarian unit to show a profit as quickly as in Slovakia and the Czech Republic, where operations showed a return on investment within two years.</p>
<p>&quot;It may take four or five year for our investments to be returned,&quot; he said, adding that BSH had already had substantial costs in the past four years while it waited for Hungary to pass the necessary legislation.</p>
<p>Fundamenta's registered capital is 1.6 billion forints.</p>
<p>BSH is looking to Croatia to set up its next unit, while Schwabisch Hall hopes Poland will also approve a building society law this year, Kleiner said.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
