<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49351" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Top Philippine official condemns tax bill.</title>
<headline>Top Philippine official condemns tax bill.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior Philippine finance ministry official on Thursday condemned a House of Representatives bill on excise taxes, saying it failed to accomplish the reforms the government wanted.</p>
<p>Finance Undersecretary Milwida Guevarra told Reuters that the bill, passed earlier on Thursday after months of wrangling, retained ad valorem taxes on cigarettes.</p>
<p>The government had wanted to scrap the current ad valorem system on both beer and cigarettes, replacing it with a specific excise tax that would be simpler to enforce and allow less room for fraud.</p>
<p>&quot;With the beer, the reforms we were sponsoring were adopted. But for cigarettes, it's still going to be ad valorem,&quot; Guevarra said.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue is more of social justice and equity in our capacity to put (in place) a reform that is correct, that will be simple for us and rid itself of tax avoidance opportunities,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>Guevarra said the Lower House pricing formula imposing either a specific tax or an ad valorem tax, whichever is higher, will lead to ad valorem taxation for nearly all high and medium priced cigarettes.</p>
<p>&quot;(These) generate about 94 percent of the cigarette tax revenues,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She said the House bill set out a low specific tax on cigarettes so the ad valorem system will eventually win out.</p>
<p>On beer, the specific excise tax rates set out by the House are higher than the ad valorem rate and so they will win out.</p>
<p>House Speaker Jose de Venecia said in a statement the new tax system on cigarettes and beer would mainly be specific but an ad valorem element would be added to higher priced brands.</p>
<p>The proposed House tax scheme on cigarettes is expected to generate revenues of 3.4 billion pesos in the first year, while that on beer will be 518 million pesos, Guevarra said.</p>
<p>The government had originally estimated that reformed excise taxes would generate more than six billion pesos in the first year.</p>
<p>She expressed hope the Senate will correct the tax formula on cigarettes. The Senate is expected to take up the bill after September 23. Congress is closed on Thursday for a break.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom 63 2 841-8937, fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
