<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493607" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil power rate hike positive, but no surprise.</title>
<headline>Brazil power rate hike positive, but no surprise.</headline>
<byline>James Craig</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most Brazilian electric companies stand to gain from a recent average 9.92 percent hike in power rates, but the market was not surprised by the latest tariff restructuring, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's positive, better than we expected, but not fantastically so,&quot; Charles Barnett, director of Latin American utilities research for ING Barings, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The rate hike was better than expected, particularly on the generation side. (But) when you look at distributors, their costs are going to go up quite a lot as well,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The tariff adjustment was the result of pressure since last year from companies asking the government to eliminate cross subsidies, especially following an initial rate hike in November 1995, industry sources said.</p>
<p>The market had expected an average tariff increase of about eight percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said federal power generator Eletrobras and Sao Paulo state-owned integrated firm Cesp are likely to benefit most from the rate hike announced Monday because much of their revenue is from power generation.</p>
<p>They said Eletrobras' earnings could rise by as much as 15 percent depending on as-yet unannounced rate hikes for some of its generating units.</p>
<p>An analyst at a local brokerage, meanwhile, said she was raising her 1997 estimates for Cesp's earnings to $260 million from $170 million as a result of the rate hike. Cesp posted a loss last year.</p>
<p>State power firms Copel and Cemig, which produce some of their own power, also are likely to see earnings jump as a result of the rate restructuring, analysts added.</p>
<p>But most Brazilian power distributors will see only a moderate rise in the bottom line because the rise in revenues will be partly offset by higher costs stemming from power purchases, analysts said.</p>
<p>Roberto Dotta Filho of Indosuez said the rate hike actually represents compounded gains in earnings ranging from 7.5 percent for Cemig to 0.4 percent for Celesc. Other analysts project slightly higher figures.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see any reason for a huge impact on (stock prices of) these companies that are only going to have marginal increases or losses,&quot; Dotta Filho said.</p>
<p>Prices on the Sao Paulo Stock exchange on Tuesday appeared to corroborate that view, with most power shares dropping back on profit-taking after hefty gains Monday when the rate hike was announced.</p>
<p>The bolsa's Electrical Energy Index was off 0.53 percent at 2,703 points at 1430 local (1330 EST), with Eletrobras preferred B shares up a solid 1.41 percent at 502 reais but most others down.</p>
<p>The Mines and Energy Ministry announced hikes for Eletrobras generating units Furnas, Eletrosul and Itaipu of 14 percent, 15 percent and seven percent while rates for integrated firms Cesp and Cemig will rise 9.09 percent and 9.75 percent respectively.</p>
<p>The ministry also authorized hikes of 9.83 percent, 9.78 percent, 9.83 percent, 11.93 percent and 11.8 percent for distributors CPFL, Eletropaulo, Copel, Celesc and Cemat, respectively.</p>
<p>Analysts also said the hikes were below the 11-percent inflation registered since the last rate hike.</p>
<p>&quot;This will force the companies to cut fat,&quot; said Marco Soligo of Bear Stearns in Brazil.</p>
<p>((--Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 248 5413))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
