<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493625" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile to decide on power rationing this month.</title>
<headline>Chile to decide on power rationing this month.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chilean government will decide at the end of this month whether to start rationing electricity as the result of the severe drought which has dried dams and hurt power supplies, said a top official.</p>
<p>&quot;If the drought continues, this possibility can't be discounted,&quot; said Alejandro Jadresic, head of the National Energy Commission, Chile's equivalent of an energy ministry.</p>
<p>Measures adopted by companies and a government electricity campaign to promote power saving and find alternative energy supplies have meant rationing has been avoided so far, he said.  </p>
<p>But if the drought, the worst in Chile this century, continues in the southern hemisphere autumn, there could be the need for additional measures to control power consumption, said Jadresic.</p>
<p>Energy from dams in the central grid, which supplies most of Chile's power needs, fell to eight percent of maximum capacity on April 1, compared with 46 percent in a normal year, he said.</p>
<p>The figures &quot;confirm the seriousness of the drought,&quot; said Jadresic.  </p>
<p>If rationing is imposed, the measures will be gradual starting with a fall in voltages, a reduction in public lighting in off-peak hours, power quotas for individual consumers and, only in extreme cases, scheduled power cuts, he said.</p>
<p>A committee including government representatives and officials from power utilities is preparing a contingency plan to deal with any power shortages, he added.</p>
<p>((-- Paulina Modiano, Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595 x212))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
