<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493709" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Cohen says U.S. troops in Japan are &quot;ambassadors&quot;.</title>
<headline>Cohen says U.S. troops in Japan are &quot;ambassadors&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>YOKOSUKA, Japan 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Cohen, worried that sex crimes have hurt the image of American forces in Japan, gave the troops a pep talk on Tuesday, telling them they were their nation's ambassadors.</p>
<p>In speeches at two U.S. bases near Tokyo, Cohen paid tribute to the troops' role in maintaining stability in Asia but warned them not to let their guard down off duty.</p>
<p>&quot;So how you conduct yourselves, be it on duty or off duty, you are in fact having an impact and reflecting an image as far as who and what the United States is,&quot; Cohen told sailors at the Yokosuka headquarters of the U.S. Navy in Japan.</p>
<p>Troop behaviour in Japan has come under scrutiny since September 1995, when three servicemen raped an Okinawan schoolgirl, setting off a campaign to shut U.S. bases in Japan.</p>
<p>The issue flared again the week before Cohen arrived when a sailor at the Yokosuka base was placed in custody on suspicion of beating and sexually assaulting his Japanese girlfriend.</p>
<p>&quot;Remember, you are in effect an ambassador of the United States,&quot; Cohen said in a breakfast meeting with airmen and airwomen at Yokota Air Base on the outskirts of Tokyo.</p>
<p>&quot;Every one of you understand, and everyone understands, that you can do 100 good deeds and you will get credit for it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;On the other hand, one bad deed, and that makes the headline news and changes people's perception of what we are doing as a nation.&quot;</p>
<p>Japanese police, who have taken over the case of the sailor at Yokosuka, have since ruled out sexual assault and are treating the matter as a case of domestic violence.</p>
<p>Cohen told sailors on the U.S. missile cruiser Bunker Hill: &quot;Every time you step off this ship you are our ambassadors of goodwill.</p>
<p>&quot;Be mindful of the fact that you are not only sailors but you are also diplomats, you are emissaries...,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto has as much interest as Cohen in ensuring a better image for U.S. troops.</p>
<p>Each time there is an incident, groups opposed to the U.S. military presence seize on it as a reason to close bases.</p>
<p>On Sunday, several thousand people held a protest rally in Tokyo against the presence of the forces on Okinawa, an island that makes up less than one percent of Japan's land area but hosts the bulk of U.S. military facilities in Japan.</p>
<p>In a non-binding referendum last year, Okinawans backed a drive by the island's governor to close all bases by 2015.</p>
<p>The concentration of U.S. military facilities on Okinawa is a legacy of the U.S. military occupation of the island from 1945 until 1972, when it was returned to Japan.</p>
<p>Since arriving in Tokyo on Monday, Cohen has heard pledges from Hashimoto, as well as his Defence Agency chief Fumio Kyuma, that Japan does not seek a cutback in the present level of 100,000 U.S. military personnel in Asia, including 47,000 in Japan.</p>
<p>Cohen said he planned to assure Hashimoto in a meeting on Wednesday of U.S. determination to also keep 100,000 American military personnel in the western Pacific indefinitely.</p>
<p>&quot;At the cornerstone of our relationship as a Pacific power lies the country of Japan,&quot; Cohen told the sailors on the Bunker Hill.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="YOKOSUKA, Japan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
