<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493866" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NASA may rerun Columbia's curtailed mission.</title>
<headline>NASA may rerun Columbia's curtailed mission.</headline>
<byline>Steven Young</byline>
<dateline>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The space shuttle Columbia had barely come to a halt after its mission was cut short on Tuesday before NASA began considering sending it back to space to complete some unfinished business.</p>
<p>Space agency officials said the shuttle could be turned around in near-record time to rerun its mission, aborted because of a malfunctioning power generator. Columbia and its crew could be ready to fly again as soon as July 2.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to try to give y'all an oil change and send you back,&quot; Kennedy Space Centre director Roy Bridges joked with shuttle commander Jim Halsell after Columbia's early homecoming.</p>
<p>&quot;We are evaluating the possibility of re-flying as early as the first part of July,&quot; shuttle programme director Tommy Holloway said. &quot;I expect that evaluation will take the rest of this week.&quot;</p>
<p>Columbia soared through wispy clouds on Tuesday and touched down at the Florida spaceport at 2:33 p.m. EDT (1833 GMT), less than four days after blasting off.</p>
<p>The planned 16-day science mission was cut short because one of the shuttle's three electricity-generating fuel cells was behaving unusually and could have sparked a fire or explosion.</p>
<p>The loss of the device did not affect the landing of the $2 billion shuttle, which can fly safely powered by two working generators. Some landing systems were activated later than usual to conserve power.</p>
<p>It was only the third time in 83 missions since the shuttle programme began in 1981 that NASA called a shuttle home early because of a mechanical breakdown.</p>
<p>A faulty fuel cell was to blame for cutting short NASA's second shuttle flight in November 1981, and a failed navigation device ended a 1991 mission prematurely.</p>
<p>There were signs of trouble with the $5 million fuel cell during Columbia's countdown, but it appeared to have returned to normal before Friday's blastoff. Engineers had seen similar pre-launch readings from other generators that did not develop problems in flight.</p>
<p>One such fuel cell on shuttle Atlantis was being replaced on Tuesday as precaution, Holloway said. Atlantis was scheduled to fly to the Russian space station Mir next month.</p>
<p>Columbia's astronauts left orbit with only a fraction of their $84 million research programme accomplished.</p>
<p>&quot;We're just sorry we're having to close up shop early,&quot; mission control's Marc Garneau told the crew as they shut down Columbia's laboratory early on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Columbia's crew of seven had been living in near-darkness since the troublesome power generator was shut down on Sunday, working with flashlights. All non-essential equipment including most of the lighting was turned off to conserve power for scientific experiments.</p>
<p>The astronauts were to have performed 33 major experiments, including several to study the behaviour of fire in space.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
