<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494053" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US foreign crudes sleepy as May demand winds down.</title>
<headline>US foreign crudes sleepy as May demand winds down.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The market for foreign crudes coming into the U.S. Gulf Coast was sleepy on Tuesday as refiners began to wind down their May requirements, traders said.</p>
<p>Bellwether Brent crude remained on the sidelines, although other North See crudes such as Oseberg were still looking for homes.</p>
<p>A U.S. company that bought Oseberg from a Norwegian company at May West Texas Intermediate/Cushing minus $1.10 for April 25-30 delivery was re-offering the barrels delivered into Cushing at WTI minus 10 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>The spread between WTI and Brent was around $1.40-45 Tuesday afternoon, fueling the transatlantic trade.</p>
<p>At the same time, dated Brent strengthened somewhat on Tuesday, trading at May Brent minus 92 cents, up two cents from a deal on Monday, traders said.</p>
<p>West African barrels remained plentiful. At least two Qua Iboe cargoes for the second half of May were offered at dated Brent plus $1.75 a barrel.</p>
<p>Among other regional offerings were Rabi, Odudu, Palanca and Brass River, traders said.</p>
<p>From Latin America, an equity producer was offering Cano Limon for May 8-18 loading and Vasconia for May 15-19.</p>
<p>The prices for these Colombian cargoes were pegged around WTI minus $3.60 and $4.30, respectively.</p>
<p>A Cusiana cargo for May 17-21 was offered around $1.50-60 discount to WTI, traders said.</p>
<p>Many Gulf Coast refiners are covered for much of May, leaving a decided overhang for the month.</p>
<p>At the same time, refining margins are brightening.</p>
<p>&quot;Crude is falling faster than products, so we have healthy margins for the moment,&quot; one Gulf Coast refiner said.</p>
<p>According to the latest report from the American Petroleum Institute (API) released on Tuesday afternoon, U.S. crude runs were at 94.3 percent for the week of April 4, compared to 93.6 percent the prior week.</p>
<p>--Patricia Garip-Bertuol NY Energy Desk ((+1 212 859 1620))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
