<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494214" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: WSCC may extend 6,250 MW intertie rate to end-June.</title>
<headline>WSCC may extend 6,250 MW intertie rate to end-June.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The board of Western Systems Coordinating Council (WSCC) have until the end of the day to vote on continuing the current Pacific Intertie rating of 6,250 megawatts (MW) through the end of June, a spokesman for Bonneville Power Administration (BPA) said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Capacity on the intertie lines, which connect the Pacific Northwest to southern California, was increased from 5,200 MW to 6,250 MW late last month, after a &quot;winter&quot; operating plan was given final WSCC approval.</p>
<p>The 7,900 MW interstate transmission system had been capped at 5,200 MW since last August, after two widespread power blackouts hit the western U.S.</p>
<p>Work is still underway to develop and implement a &quot;spring&quot; operating plan to further increase capacity, but that is not expected to be finalized until at least late this month.</p>
<p>The winter plan will expire April 30 or when hydropower operations shift into springtime mode.</p>
<p>To avoid having the lines revert back to 5,200 MW, WSCC is voting on whether to approve the continuance.</p>
<p>The extension includes provisions for resassessment should &quot;summer&quot; system conditions begin or a spring plan be approved.</p>
<p>((--D Beasley, Los Angeles bureau + 1 213 955 6761))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
