<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494253" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Sobhraj free in France, probed on poisoning charge.</title>
<headline>Sobhraj free in France, probed on poisoning charge.</headline>
<byline>Christian Curtenelle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Notorious criminal Charles Sobhraj arrived in France on Tuesday, a free man after 20 years in Indian prisons but immediately faced a probe on suspicion of poisoning.</p>
<p>His lawyer Jacques Verges told reporters that Judge Franck Zientara ordered Sobhraj be investigated over an unnamed French woman's claim that she was the target of a poisoning attempt in India in 1976.</p>
<p>Sobhraj -- who claims French citizenship -- was released without bail. Being placed under investigation may, but does not automatically lead to trial.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very happy to be finally free on French soil, but I am surprised to have gone before a judge,&quot; Sobhraj told reporters as he left the lawcourts in the north Paris suburb of Bobigny.</p>
<p>Verges said his client had already been tried and sentenced in India 19 years ago on charges of attempting to poison members of a group of French engineers travelling in India.</p>
<p>He said the judge must now verify whether the charges being probed stem from the same incident, and if Sobhraj is liable for a new trial.</p>
<p>Nicknamed &quot;The Snake&quot;, Sobhraj served two decades in prison in India on a string of charges including murder and robbery committed against tourists across Asia. He was first arrested for holding up a hotel jewellery shop in India in 1971.</p>
<p>After landing at 6:40 a.m. (0440 GMT) at Charles de Gaulle airport aboard Air France flight 147 from New Delhi, Sobhraj was whisked away to criminal police headquarters in the western suburb of Nanterre for checks on his criminal record and claim for French citizenship.</p>
<p>Verges told reporters at the airport that any offence Sobhraj may have committed was covered by the statute of limitations which bans prosecution more than 10 years after the deed.</p>
<p>&quot;If the law is applied, there is no legal basis to prosecute him in France, whether some people like it or not,&quot; Verges said.</p>
<p>&quot;This melodrama...for a Frenchman who is coming home after having served his sentence and against whom no proceedings exist, shows the state's weakness, not strength,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>India ordered Sobhraj deported in February but France refused to accept him pending checks on his past record and nationality claim. Paris eventually agreed on Monday that Sobhraj, who was born to an Indian father and Vietnamese mother, had a strong claim for French citizenship.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry spokesman Yves Doutriaux said he would have to apply for a certificate of French citizenship from a judge, but indicated it would be a formality.</p>
<p>Two officials of India's Foreigners' Regional Registration Office (FRRO) accompanied Sobhraj to Paris.</p>
<p>Sobhraj, whose criminal exploits have been the subject of two books, plans to concentrate on working on a $15 million English-language film based on his life, to be produced in France with American actors. He has said he would write the script but would not play the title role.</p>
<p>&quot;In France I first want to negotiate my contracts,&quot; he told reporters in Bobigny.</p>
<p>He has said in the past he longed to roam the streets of Paris to enjoy his freedom. &quot;I want to take a walk on the bank of the River Seine in Paris,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
