<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494392" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India Congress party chief says open for dialogue.</title>
<headline>India Congress party chief says open for dialogue.</headline>
<byline>Sabyasachi Mitra</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Congress party chief, Sitaram Kesri, on Tuesday struck a conciliatory note in the nation's political crisis, saying he was open to talks with Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's ruling alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;I am ready for talks if the proposal comes from their side. There is no doubt in it,&quot; Kesri told Reuters after addressing a rally in the Indian capital.</p>
<p>Kesri triggered a political crisis on March 30 when he withdrew Congress's vital support for Deve Gowda's minority United Front coalition government. Deve Gowda now faces a vote of confidence in parliament on Friday.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday, Kesri was quoted as saying talks could begin provided Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda stepped down.</p>
<p>But the Congress leader set no such precondition at the rally.</p>
<p>&quot;We are hungry for respect, not for power,&quot; Kesri told party supporters at the rally.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't have anything personal against Deve Gowda. When I speak, I speak of Deve Gowda as the prime minister,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Many Congress members praised Kesri for his speech, which was moderate compared with an attack he launched on Deve Gowda last week.</p>
<p>&quot;The earlier speech was a natural outburst against the insults heaped on Congress by the United Front,&quot; said a senior Congress leader, who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Kesri said the 10-month old minority United Front coalition, which relied on the support of the 138 Congress deputies in parliament, never consulted the Congress party on important policy decisions.</p>
<p>Nor did the United Front support Congress in key state polls in Uttar Pradesh and Punjab, he said.</p>
<p>Kesri emphasised that Congress' fight was against communalism and poverty.</p>
<p>&quot;Today, during Deve Gowda's regime, food prices have skyrocketed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier, another Congress leader, Sharad Pawar, said the party appreciated many aspects of the pathbreaking 1997/98 (April-March) budget, hailed by industry and businessmen.</p>
<p>He assured his audience at the rally that the Congress did not want to damage the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Congress does not want to trigger a financial crisis in the country,&quot; Pawar said.</p>
<p>The United Front coalition's highest decision-making body meets on Wednesday to discuss the political situation and also seek ways for the budget to be approved in parliament.</p>
<p>The Press Trust of India said Congress had suggested the setting up of a panel for formal talks with the United Front.</p>
<p>Both Congress and United Front leaders said informal talks between the parties were going on at various levels and they hoped for a solution to the present crisis.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
