<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494382" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Egypt would mediate if Israel stalled settlement.</title>
<headline>Egypt would mediate if Israel stalled settlement.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Verma</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussa said on Tuesday his country was willing to mediate to break a deadlock in the Middle East peace process if Israel put further Jewish settlements in Palestinian territory on hold.</p>
<p>&quot;Egypt always plays a role in encouraging the peace process, brings together parties and is ready to continue this role but it will be within the framework of the Madrid principles,&quot; Moussa, visiting India for a meeting of the Non-Aligned Movement (NAM), told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Moussa was asked if Egypt was willing to mediate to rescue the peace process from an Israeli-Palestinian stand-off over the expansion of Jewish settlements in the Arab West Bank, particularly in the East Jerusalem area.</p>
<p>NAM on Tuesday urged its 113 member nations to freeze relations with Israel at existing levels to force the Jewish state to end an impasse in the Middle East peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;In view of the urgency and the seriousness of the situation, the ministers call on NAM countries, as a first step, to freeze relations with Israel at their current level,&quot; NAM said in a special declaration at the end of a two-day meeting of its foreign ministers in New Delhi.</p>
<p>The statement was issued hours after the group called for a special emergency session of the U.N. General Assembly to demand that Israel stop a Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem and all other settlement activities.</p>
<p>&quot;Any mediation should be based on the Israelis' putting a hold on their policy of settlements. There can be no compromise on this,&quot; Moussa said.</p>
<p>The NAM statement called on member states to &quot;use all available measures to ensure Israel's compliance with the terms of reference of the Madrid Conference and the land-for-peace principle and its full implementation of all agreements, undertakings and commitments reached by the concerned parties on all tracks during the peace talks&quot;.</p>
<p>Israel gave a commitment to the principle of &quot;land for peace&quot; at the Madrid peace conference in 1991.</p>
<p>The NAM declaration followed an appeal to the NAM conference by Palestinian President Yasser Arafat on Monday to freeze ties with Israel, after he said Israel's policy of building Jewish settlements in Arab areas threatened to derail peace talks.</p>
<p>&quot;The ministers also affirmed that failure by the Israeli government to respond positively would require NAM members to take further appropriate measures,&quot; the declaration said without elaborating.</p>
<p>Indian diplomats said each country's delegation to NAM would return home and examine its position on the declaration.</p>
<p>NAM also denounced two U.S. vetoes last month in the U.N. Security Council against measures criticising Israel.</p>
<p>&quot;We are talking about an Arab-Israeli peace, not an Israeli peace, not a peace according to the measurement of the Israeli current policy, and on the basis of principles that have been agreed -- land for peace, right for right and obligation for obligation,&quot; Moussa said.</p>
<p>Israeli-Palestinian peace talks have ceased and violence has erupted nearly every day since Israel broke ground for a new Jewish housing last month on Har Homa, a 6,500-home project on a hilltop in East Jerusalem that Palestinians call Jabal Abu Ghneim and on land that each side claims.</p>
<p>Moussa said he did not expect a quick resurrection of the derailed peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;Our hopes are that the United States as the sponsor of the peace talks will succeed in getting Israel to stop and roll back on its policy on settlements. But our expectations are not that high,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was due to return to Israel on Tuesday after holding talks with President Bill Clinton, who rebuffed his call for a U.S.-led Middle East summit while trying to revive stalled peace efforts.</p>
<p>Egypt became the first Arab state to sign a peace treaty with Israel in 1979 after then U.S. president Jimmy Carter hosted intensive peace talks with Egyptian and Israeli leaders.</p>
<p>Moussa said: &quot;You cannot compromise on the right of people to sovereignty and to territorial integrity, and you cannot compromise on agreements that have already been signed and principles that have already been agreed.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
