<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49439" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwaitis angry, some anxious after Iraq warning.</title>
<headline>Kuwaitis angry, some anxious after Iraq warning.</headline>
<byline>Inal Ersan</byline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kuwaitis voiced anger and annoyance on Thursday after former occupier Iraq warned Kuwait not to permit U.S. planes to attack Iraq from Kuwaiti territory.</p>
<p>But members of the country's large Asian guestworker population displayed some nervousness, saying they were receiving anxious calls from relatives back home.</p>
<p>&quot;Frightened? Never. I am one of the people who stayed in Kuwait during the (1990-91 Iraqi) occupation,&quot; said Hussein al-Kandari, an education ministry employee.</p>
<p>&quot;It is all in God's hands, but I am not frightened,&quot; said Kandari, a large, bearded figure in white Arab robes shopping for jumbo shrimps at a fish market.</p>
<p>Eight U.S. F-117A jets were to head to Kuwait on Thursday and four B-52s moved to a British base in the Indian Ocean to be in closer striking range of Iraq.</p>
<p>Many residents fled Kuwait to neighbouring Saudi Arabia when Iraq's troops stormed over the border in August 1990 to begin a seven-month occupation that was ended by the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>&quot;He does not intimidate us but we should prepare for him,&quot; said Waleed al-Damkhi who works at Kuwait's airport, referring to Iraqi President Saddam Hussein. Damkhi said there were no signs of an exodus.</p>
<p>&quot;I am 2,000 percent confident about the army's capacities with the help of brothers and friends (allies),&quot; said Damkhi.</p>
<p>Travellers said the atmosphere at Kuwait airport was calm and traffic levels were normal. People did not rush to petrol stations, banks or supermarkets -- scenes that would have been expected in the jittery period after the Gulf War.</p>
<p>The government's position on the standoff is more open than it was before invasion day in 1990, when people woke up to find Iraqi troops roaming the streets of Kuwait City.</p>
<p>The information ministry is preparing a centre at a large hotel to keep the press informed of developments.</p>
<p>Kuwait's Crown Prince Sheikh Saad al-Abdulla al-Sabah urged members of the Supreme Defence Council to stay on alert in the face of growing tension with Iraq.</p>
<p>State radio warned Iraqi President Saddam Hussein in a commentary: &quot;The lesson this time will be severe, it will be the last lesson, after which the regime will never stand.&quot;</p>
<p>Most Kuwaitis were angry that Saddam was still around to pose a threat. &quot;They (allies) should have finished him in 1991,&quot; said Saleh al-Saeed, listening to the news in his car.</p>
<p>&quot;My car is full of gasoline and I have dollars for emergencies,&quot; shrugged George, a Lebanese vendor.</p>
<p>But some expatriates were worried.</p>
<p>&quot;I would definitely leave if he (Saddam) strikes. I am not a national,&quot; said Egyptian nurse Muna Ali. &quot;Of course I am frightened. He is a reckless man. He could strike again.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Please tell us of any news as soon as you can,&quot; a worried-looking Filipina hotel employee told a journalist.  </p>
<p>The minister also stressed that Kuwait is &quot;a state with sovereignty and has the right to take all precautions that safeguard its security, safety, sovereignty and the well being of its citizens.&quot;</p>
<p>The minister said Kuwait &quot;is acting in light of its painful experiences at the hands of the Baghdad regime...&quot; Iraqi troops occupied Kuwait in August 1990, leading to the Gulf War six months later when U.S.-led coalition forces drove Iraqi troops out of Kuwait.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
