<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494440" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Non-Aligned inch forward on demand to reform U.N.</title>
<headline>Non-Aligned inch forward on demand to reform U.N.</headline>
<byline>Narayanan Madhavan</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign ministers of more than 100 nations of the Non-Aligned Movement edged towards a consensus seeking an expansion of the U.N. Security Council and a time-bound plan for nuclear disarmament, diplomats said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The ministers of some 80 countries at the two-day meeting, along with officials from others in the 113-nation movement of developing countries, were holding formal closed-door talks after an informal brainstorming session on Monday.</p>
<p>They were scheduled to present a common declaration later on Tuesday at the end of the meeting, whose inauguration was attended by U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan and Palestinian President Yasser Arafat.</p>
<p>&quot;Eventually, there will be a consensus,&quot; said an Indian Foreign Ministry official, adding that the declaration would focus on disarmament and reforms in the United Nations.</p>
<p>In his forceful address, Arafat attacked Israel for its recent attempts to build 6,500 homes in Palestinian territory captured in 1967, violating a Middle-East peace accord.</p>
<p>Peace talks were halted after Israel began work last month on the new Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem, sparking daily clashes between Palestinians and Israeli troops.</p>
<p>The speech, in which Arafat accused Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government of declaring a war on the Middle East peace process, was adopted as part of the formal records of the Non-Aligned Movement (NAM).</p>
<p>&quot;Beyond that, I don't know if anything else (on the Middle East) was discussed,&quot; the Indian official said.</p>
<p>But the meeting's chairwoman, Colombian Foreign Minister Maria Emma Mejia, said she had requested Annan to convene a special General Assembly session on the Middle East.</p>
<p>Arafat's presence at the meeting was against a backdrop of lingering questions on the relevance of NAM after the end of the Cold War and the break-up of the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>NAM officials received a boost on Monday after Annan backed efforts to expand the U.N. Security Council, whose current permanent members are the five declared nuclear powers -- Britain, China, France , Russia and the United States.</p>
<p>A critical area of NAM discussion would focus on how a proposed expansion should take place, diplomats said. A proposal was made in the U.N. General Assembly's working group earlier this year to expand the Security Council.</p>
<p>A diplomatic source said Tuesday's declaration was expected to affirm that NAM would not accept any discrimination between developed and developing countries in the candidatures for permanent seats or expansion of the council.</p>
<p>Their reference is to attempts in the U.N. to include Japan and Germany among the permanent members.</p>
<p>India, which argues against any &quot;piecemeal&quot; expansion of the Security Council, has been lobbying hard for a permanent seat.</p>
<p>A critical issue being discussed is the veto power in the council. NAM's vocal members say the veto has been abused in the past by permanent members in the U.N.</p>
<p>The foreign ministers were also expected to seek a timebound implementation of a call to eliminate nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>Last year, eight NAM members refused to endorse a global treaty to ban nuclear test blasts, seeking to link it to the timebound elimination of all nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>India conducted a nuclear test in 1974 but says it has no plans to build an atomic bomb. Western experts say it already has or can build one quickly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
