<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494475" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. offcials urge wider use of car seat belts.</title>
<headline>U.S. offcials urge wider use of car seat belts.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of senators and senior U.S. safety officials urged state governors and legislators Tuesday to strengthen seat belt laws to help reduce injuries and deaths in car accidents.</p>
<p>They said that seat belts were the main device protecting people in cars, and &quot;automatic restraints like airbags are mainly of value in supplementing seat belts.&quot;</p>
<p>In a group letter sent to state leaders across the country, the senators and safety officials noted that U.S. seat belt use is about 68 percent, and said that national seat belt use of 85 percent would prevent 4,200 traffic deaths a year and save over 27,000 people from serious injuries.</p>
<p>There were 41,500 U.S. traffic deaths in 1996.</p>
<p>Many industrialised nations have a seat belt use of more than 95 percent.</p>
<p>The letter noted that most states have secondary seat belt laws that allow a police officer to stop a car only if the driver is committing another offence.</p>
<p>It called for primary seat belt laws so a car with an occupant not buckled up can be stopped even if the driver is not committing another offence, increased penalties for not wearing a seat belt and increased visibility of enforcement.</p>
<p>The signers said higher fines and punitive &quot;points&quot; on a violators driver's license have been shown to improve seat belt usage.</p>
<p>One of the signers, Arizona Republican Sen. John McCain, said in a statement that evidence showed that the 38 child airbag fatalities -- the result of rapidly inflating airbags -- were caused because of improper child seat restraints. And he urged that the proper use of child restraints also be increased.</p>
<p>The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration has recently allowed carmakers to reduce airbag inflation speed.</p>
<p>Aside from the human misery of traffic accidents, the letter said, there is also an economic cost, with taxpayers bearing a significant portion of it.</p>
<p>The letter went to all the states except six that have seatbelt use of more than 80 percent -- California, Hawaii, New Mexico, North Carolina, Oregon and Washington.</p>
<p>Among those signing the letter, in addition to McCain, chairman of the Commerce, Science and Transportation Committee, were Transportation Secretary Rodney Slater and Jim Hall, chairman of the National Transportation Safety Board.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
