<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494479" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French hospital doctors strike enters fifth week.</title>
<headline>French hospital doctors strike enters fifth week.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A strike by French junior hospital doctors against government plans to curb health spending entered its fifth week on Tuesday with protesters calling for a 24-hour stoppage of all non-emergency care on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The strikers, dismissing reports that the protest was losing steam, called on the country's other doctors to join them in what they called a &quot;health blackout&quot;.</p>
<p>Junior doctors in Lille dumped pig manure in front of the national health insurance fund's offices and painted the building facade red.</p>
<p>The strikers said they were preparing more disruption and planned a march through Paris on Sunday supported by unions representing specialists in private practice who have opposed any reform to France's health system.</p>
<p>But there were signs that support for the strike was eroding as the doctors feel the financial pinch of their long protest.</p>
<p>Unions said the number of teaching hospitals on strike had fallen to 21 from 24 of the 26 in the country. The government put the number at 18.</p>
<p>Press reports said most chief residents, who once supported the movement, had gone back to work.</p>
<p>The government said on Tuesday about 31 percent of the junior doctors in hospitals on strike outside Paris were not working, down from a government estimate of 40 percent last week. The unions put the figure at 70 percent.</p>
<p>They said the return to work by some doctors showed devotion to their patients, not slackening support for the protest.</p>
<p>Both sides have said they want to find a way out of the conflict, but little progress has been made since the weekend when doctors and Social Affairs Minister Jacques Barrot issued calls for negotiations.</p>
<p>The strikers want the government to scrap or delay plans to fine all doctors in a region, regardless of individual practice, if the area overshoots spending limits.</p>
<p>The movement has developed into a test of the conservative government's resolve to cut deficits to allow France to qualify for the European Union's planned single currency in 1999.</p>
<p>While rejecting demands to eliminate or delay the fines and accusing the strikers of selfishly promoting their own interests, Barrot has offered to make the penalties more individualised.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
