<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494495" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Miami airport sees big jump in high tech shipments.</title>
<headline>Miami airport sees big jump in high tech shipments.</headline>
<byline>Teresa Carson</byline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Computer and telecommunications equipment shipped through Miami International Airport will nearly double over the next four years, according to airport officials.</p>
<p>&quot;About 90 percent of this equipment is bound for Latin America,&quot; Peter Reaveley, Miami International's head of route development said Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The three big economies in Latin America -- Brazil, Argentina and Chile -- are going to show strong rates of GDP (Gross Domestic Product) growth,&quot; Reaveley said.  </p>
<p>&quot;They are going to privatize large numbers of companies and as they do they will modernize office infrastructure,&quot; he said.  &quot;And they need good telecommunications to make this all work.&quot;</p>
<p>Miami International Airport should handle $5.4 billion of computers and peripheral equipment and telecommunications equipment this year, Reaveley's projections show.  About $1.8 billion of this will be telecommunications equipment and $3.6 billion will be computers and peripherals.  </p>
<p>By 2000 - 2001 that will jump to $10.1 billion.  Of the $10.1 billion, $5.2 billion is expected to be computers and $4.9 billion telecommunication equipment.</p>
<p>Computers and peripherals have for several years been MIA's biggest trade catagory by dollar value, with $2.8 billion handled in 1995, according to Dade County Aviation Department statistics.</p>
<p>Telecommunications equipment was second in 1995 with $1.2 billion.  Clothing ranked third in 1995 at $877 million.  </p>
<p>In general, MIA expects continued double-digit growth in freight.  This year MIA expects cargo to reach two million tons, and 2.3 million by 1998.  By 2000, MIA expects 2.9 million tons and it sees four million tons by 2005; by 2010 that is expected to be five million tons, more than double this year's total.</p>
<p>MIA expects freighters to continue to increase the proportion of cargo they carry to and from the airport.  This year MIA expects about 28 percent of cargo to be carried in the belly of passenger planes.</p>
<p>MIA expects that by 2010, passenger and combination aircraft will carry only 20 percent of the $5 billion in cargo.  In 1993, 32 percent of MIA's cargo was carried in the belly of passenger aircraft.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
