<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49455" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Leumi reaches accord with Africa shareholders.</title>
<headline>Leumi reaches accord with Africa shareholders.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank Leumi said on Thursday it had reached an accord with two significant shareholders in its subsidiary Africa Israel Investments on the sale of Africa Israel shares.</p>
<p>The accord will facilitate Bank Leumi's sale of part of its own shares in Africa Israel. Bank Leumi owns 65 percent of the voting rights in Africa Israel but under Israeli law it must reduce its holdings in non-banking assets to 25 percent.</p>
<p>Businessmen Eitan Wertheimer and Motti Zisser own 12.34 percent of Africa Israel shares, or 14.08 percent of the voting rights.</p>
<p>Under the agreement Wertheimer and Zisser will support the spin-off of Africa Israel's holdings in Leumi Insurance, which they had tried to stop.</p>
<p>The spin-off has been approved by Africa Israel's board of directors and will be voted on by the company's shareholders on September 19.</p>
<p>The divestment is a prerequisite for a deal enabling Italian insurer Generali Spa to take control of Leumi Insurance's subsidiary Migdal.</p>
<p>Leumi Insurance holds 68.1 percent of Migdal while Generali owns 27.1 percent and others hold 4.8 percent.</p>
<p>Under the accord, following the spin-off Wertheimer and Zisser will receive an option to sell their shares in Africa Israel together with Bank Leumi's sale of its shares.</p>
<p>If Wertheimer and Zisser decide not to sell their shares, they will have the option to bid in the tender for Bank Leumi's shares in Africa Israel.</p>
<p>Leumi believes it will get more money by spinning off the insurance holdings and selling them separately from Africa Israel.</p>
<p>Zisser and Wertheimer had accumulated Africa Israel shares in an attempt to stop the insurance spin-off.</p>
<p>Africa Israel is one of Israel's leading holdings companies with interests in insurance, tourism and construction.</p>
<p>Leumi is the country's second largest bank.</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
