<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49461" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chemical weapons pact postponed in U.S. Senate.</title>
<headline>Chemical weapons pact postponed in U.S. Senate.</headline>
<byline>William Scally</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Senate set aside ratification of a long-delayed chemical weapons treaty on Thursday amid assessments it would be saddled with unacceptable amendments or defeated.</p>
<p>Officials said they still hoped for Senate action this year, but the Senate was due to adjourn at the end of this month and there seemed virtually no chance of approval before that time.</p>
<p>The Chemical Weapons Convention, signed by the United States and other countries in 1991, has been under intense fire by conservatives, including Senate Foreign Relations Committee Chairman Jesse Helms, a Republican from North Carolina.</p>
<p>It would ban the acquisition, development, production, stockpiling, transfer and use of chemical weapons. Approval would require a two-thirds majority of the Senate.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton reacted swiftly to the postponement while on the campaign trail in Rancho Cucamonga, California.</p>
<p>&quot;I ask you to join with me in asking the Senate to resolve the remaining questions, put partisanship aside and put America on the side of a safer world, without poison gas being exposed to our citizens, or our soldiers,&quot; he told a rally.</p>
<p>Noting that the treaty was negotiated by Republican President George Bush and was submitted to the Senate three years ago, he said that &quot;bitter partisan debate&quot; that had broken out in recent days threatened to derail it.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry told reporters Clinton had put in calls to a half-dozen senators on Wednesday seeking to address the concerns of some Republicans.</p>
<p>The Senate debate that was to have started on Thursday was postponed with administration acquiescence after, according to senators on both sides of the issue, the treaty started to lose Republican support.</p>
<p>Sen. Joseph Biden, a Delaware Democrat who was to have helped steer the pact through the Senate, said in an interview supporters believed they had the votes until Republicans received a letter on the treaty from presidential candidate Bob Dole.</p>
<p>Opponents led by Helms were proposing two amendments that supporters said would have killed the treaty. One asserted that the United States could not ratify until so-called &quot;rogue&quot; states such as Iran and Libya signed on. The other would require unattainable assurances on verification.</p>
<p>Biden said it had become clear that either the amendments would be approved or the treaty would have become the first arms control pact to have been defeated.</p>
<p>Helms said the postponement was due to &quot;arithmetic -- they started counting heads and saw where they were.&quot;</p>
<p>Biden predicted that if Clinton were re-elected the treaty would pick up enough Republican support to win approval early next year, free from presidential election politics.</p>
<p>John Holum, head of the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, did not rule out action this year and said delay until next year could mean the United States would not be an &quot;original party&quot; to the treaty.</p>
<p>This status, conferring certain rights, would go to states that ratify within six months of the date that 65 states have ratified. So far 63 states have ratified the treaty.</p>
<p>Appearing before the Senate Armed Services Committee on Thursday, Bush's Secretary of State James Baker warmly endorsed the treaty. But an array of conservatives, including top aides to former President Ronald Reagan, strongly opposed it in a letter to Senate Republican Leader Trent Lott.</p>
<p>In an article in USA Today, Helms said the treaty would do nothing to protect Americans from the threat of poison gas, would improve &quot;rogue&quot; nations' access to chemical agents, impose new regulations on U.S. businesses and expose them to unprecedented inspections by international regulators.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
