<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494784" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>TUNISIA: Tunisia opens market to private Internet suppliers.</title>
<headline>Tunisia opens market to private Internet suppliers.</headline>
<dateline>TUNIS 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tunisia has issued legislation opening the local market to private Internet and other telecommunications services suppliers.</p>
<p>The legislation was in the last issue of the Official Gazetta received on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It allows private companies to set up Internet servers connected to the state's telecommunications services and to offer Internet services to local subscribers provided they vet the network's content.</p>
<p>&quot;The director (of the server's company) must keep outwatching constantly the servers' content...in order to not let in informations against the public order and moral values,&quot; the legislation says.</p>
<p>The state-controlled Tunisian Internet Agency said it has launched a tender to select two companies which will be allowed licence to manage such servers.</p>
<p>Since last year, access to Internet was allowed only through the state's agency.</p>
<p>Individual Internet subscribers currently pay 500 dinars to be connected and a 150 dinars fee per month. Telecommunciations sources said the opening up of the service to private suppliers could substantially cut the fees.</p>
<p>The new legislation also opens videotex, audiotex, databases, E-Mail, TelNet, File Transfer Protocol (FTP) and Newsgroups services to private suppliers.</p>
<p>--Tunis newsroom, 2161-787538  </p>
<p>Fernando de Sousa, Microsoft's China marketing manager for business systems, said the emphasis was on closed intranet networks rather than on expanding local access to the global Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;China is not so much interested in people surfing the Web,&quot; he said. &quot;Most of the projects in China are intranets.&quot;</p>
<p>After a high-profile confrontation with China in the early 1990s over control and development of the Chinese version of the Windows operating system, Microsoft has in the past year signed a series of agreements cementing its position here.</p>
<p>Last month, it signed an agreement with China's top personal computer maker, the Legend Group, under which it will be allowed to pre-install Chinese-language Windows 95 in its PCs.</p>
<p>Microsoft's general manager for China, Jia-Bin Duh, said revenues in China were &quot;more than doubling&quot; every year, adding that sales of server operating systems accounted for more than 50 percent of the company's China business.</p>
<p>He said that in the past year Microsoft had sold more than 10,000 copies of its Windows NT server software package, which commands a street price of around 10,000 yuan ($1,200).  </p>
<p>The company is currently investing in its future in China, particularly in terms of people and staff, Duh said, but declined to predict when Microsoft China might move into profit.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no specific target. But we're confident about this market. We'll get there, but there's no exact target,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chase said piracy of Microsoft products remained a major problem in China, but he added that significant progress was apparent in cracking down on the pirates.</p>
<p>&quot;It's hard to tell, but I understand the price of pirate CD-ROMs is getting higher,&quot; de Sousa said. &quot;I was told they have increased by 30 percent recently.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TUNIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TUNIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TUNISIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
