<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494862" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Joe Kennedy's ex-wife to appeal annulment - report.</title>
<headline>Joe Kennedy's ex-wife to appeal annulment - report.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The ex-wife of Representative Joseph Kennedy is pursuing an appeal of their marriage annulment with Catholic officials in Rome, Boston newspapers reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Sheila Rauch Kennedy, whose 12-year marriage to the Democratic congressman was annulled by church officials in Boston last year, wrote about her opposition to the marriage annulment in her book &quot;Shattered Faith,&quot; which is to be published in May, the Boston Herald reported.</p>
<p>Joseph Kennedy, 44, has said repeatedly he may run for Massachusetts governor in 1998, issued a statement about reports of his former wife's decision.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe these were personal family matters,&quot; he said. &quot;At the same time, I respect Sheila's right to express herself on this subject.&quot;</p>
<p>The couple were married in 1979 and divorced in 1991. Joseph Kennedy, the son of the slain former Attorney General Robert Kennedy, began pursuing annulment proceedings in 1993, the same year he married a member of his staff, Beth Kelly.</p>
<p>The Catholic Church considers marriage a sacramental union that cannot be ended without a grant of annulment, essentially a finding by the church that the marriage never existed.</p>
<p>In a just-released epilogueue to her book, Sheila Kennedy said the church granted the annulment on the grounds that he lacked &quot;due discretion,&quot; the Boston Globe reported.</p>
<p>&quot;In other words, at the time of our marriage, Joe had suffered from a lack of due discretion of such magnitude that he was incapable of marriage and therefore our union had never been valid,&quot; she wrote.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
