<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494917" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: East German farms must repay old debts, court rules.</title>
<headline>East German farms must repay old debts, court rules.</headline>
<byline>Ursula Knapp</byline>
<dateline>KARLSRUHE 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's supreme court, trying to untangle the legal fallout from unification in 1990, ruled on Tuesday that east German farmers must repay about 10 billion marks ($5.8 billion) of communist-era debt.</p>
<p>But the cooperative farms, which say they could face ruin if forced to foot the bill, should have easier conditions for paying off the unusual debt burden, the court said.</p>
<p>The ruling was a setback for east German farmers and politicians who argued that these were not debts in the capitalist sense.</p>
<p>They said communist planners often forced them to take unnecessary credits to finance non-agricultural work like building roads, schools or public offices in their villages.</p>
<p>Eastern leaders wanted Bonn to shoulder the farm debts in the same way in which it paid off loans taken out by east German industrial firms and local governments.</p>
<p>But the Federal Constitutional Court rejected an appeal by a collective farm in Saxony-Anhalt state which said the unusual debt burden violated its members' rights to their property.</p>
<p>&quot;The cooperative farms' duty to repay their old debts does not have any such effect,&quot; it said in its ruling.</p>
<p>The court added that the federal government should in the year 2000 review the special conditions for repaying these debts to see if they were working well or keeping the farms saddled with an unacceptable level of debt.</p>
<p>In Bonn, the opposition Social Democratic Party (SPD) criticised the ruling as &quot;not forward-looking&quot; and said it would lead to further unemployment in eastern Germany.</p>
<p>DG Bank in Frankfurt, which took over six billion of the 10 billion marks in debt in 1990, said the ruling ended a long period of uncertainty for the farming sector.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased that the issue has been cleared up,&quot; a spokesman said.</p>
<p>The German-German Unity Treaty, hammered out at high speed in 1990, classified the debts as valid credits and allowed collective farms to repay them only after they showed a profit.</p>
<p>In a special ruling meant to limit the burden, farms in the black only have to make payments up to a limit of 20 percent of their annual profits.</p>
<p>Reinhard Hoeppner, the SPD premier of Saxony-Anhalt, said forcing the farms to repay the debts would ruin many of them and allow rich westerners to buy up the land.</p>
<p>&quot;Money will then flow from east to west.  That cannot be a healthy structure,&quot; he told German Radio.</p>
<p>Bonn has already shouldered many debts left over from east German industry and local governments by diverting them into a repayment fund independent of the government budget.</p>
<p>East Germany's farm sector has shed most of its 820,000 workers and only kept 150,000, at great social cost.</p>
<p>Problems over land ownership are still unresolved and overshadow the progress made in the east.</p>
<p>Land-privatising agencies must still settle disputes over more than 1.1 million hectares (2.7 million acres), a third of total arable land and forest.</p>
<p>The Bonn government is also fending off compensation claims by former owners of estates belonging to the Prussian nobility that were seized by Soviet authorities between 1945 and 1949.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARLSRUHE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
