<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494924" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: FOCUS - Austria's OMV has record 96 earnings.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Austria's OMV has record 96 earnings.</headline>
<byline>Janet McBride</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian oil and chemicals group OMV reported a set of record earnings for 1996 on Tuesday, thanks to cost-cutting and consistently high crude oil prices, and said it expected a repeat performance this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We have achieved the best result in the history of our company. It is especially gratifying that all six business sectors ended the year in the black,&quot; chief executive Richard Schenz told a news conference.</p>
<p>Group net profit climbed 14 percent to 1.98 billion schillings ($164 million), clearing the way for the board to recommend raising the dividend payment by three schillings to 23.</p>
<p>Pre-tax earnings jumped 42 percent to 2.97 billion schillings and earnings before interest and tax (EBIT) rose 33 percent to 2.92 billion schillings.</p>
<p>The figures were in stark contrast to the early 1990s when the then state-owned and bloated firm was plagued with losses.</p>
<p>Schenz said Austria's biggest industrial group expected to achieve &quot;a similar result for 1997 as 1996&quot;, despite a recent reversal in the price of benchmark Brent crude.</p>
<p>International analysts responded positively to his comments, noting that the company had a track record of cautious earnings outlooks.</p>
<p>&quot;The prospect of good results should be taken reasonably well,&quot; said Neill Morton of HSBC James Capel in London.</p>
<p>Schenz presented Exploration and Production (E&amp;P), gas and marketing as the motors of future earnings growth. They would also take up the bulk of the firm's planned six billion schillings in annual investment over the next three years.</p>
<p>Gas continued to supply the lion's share of OMV's operating revenue in 1996, with earnings before interest and tax of 1.77 billion schillings after 1.73 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>Future spending would focus on extending OMV's gas pipeline network to secure its role as a key central European carrier of Russian supplies to the west.</p>
<p>E&amp;P, boosted by last year's high crude oil prices and a strong dollar, posted an EBIT of 0.39 billion schillings after a loss of 0.25 billion. OMV said secure oil reserves rose to 26.21 million tonnes from 25.27 million.</p>
<p>&quot;New projects in Austria, Libya and the North Sea should ensure that the positive earnings trend in exploration and production continues,&quot; Schenz said.</p>
<p>OMV had budgeted for a Brent crude oil price of $17.50 a barrel in 1997, well below the 1996 average of $20.7. On Tuesday Brent was quoted a shade above $17.5.</p>
<p>Analysts said rising output from Libya's Murzuk field, which OMV operates with Spain's Repsol and France's Total, should give a welcome boost to E&amp;P revenue this year. OMV forecast Murzuk output would double to 100,000 barrels per day by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The margin on Murzuk is pretty high even with today's low oil price,&quot; said one market watcher.</p>
<p>Marketing was &quot;on the right track for higher earnings&quot; this year in the face of cost-cutting measures in Austria and expansion in Eastern Europe, Schenz said. Last year marketing achieved an operating profit of 0.12 billion schillings after a 1995 loss of 0.06 billion.</p>
<p>Director Tassier Peyrer Heimstaett said OMV aimed to trim its domestic filling station network this year &quot;a little more than last&quot; and reduce the group workforce by five percent after four percent to 8,491 in 1996.</p>
<p>At the end of last year OMV had 726 filling stations in Austria, down from 800 the previous year, while the number of stations in southern Germany, the Czech Republic, Slovakia, Hungary, Slovenia and Croatia rose to 332 from 274.</p>
<p>&quot;By the year 2000 the network should be twice as big as it is today,&quot; Peyrer Heimstaett said.</p>
<p>OMV shares in Vienna closed 18 schillings down at 1,320. Traders traced the decline, in a generally firmer market, to profit-taking and noted OMV had already issued provisional earnings in February. ($ = 12.07 Austrian Schillings)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
