<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="495036" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Smurfit focuses on costs in regions.</title>
<headline>Smurfit focuses on costs in regions.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish paper and packaging manufacturer Jefferson Smurfit Group Plc said on Tuesday that 1996 had been characterised by earnings decline across its regions but added that focus on costs had delivered permanent savings.</p>
<p>&quot;The period was characterised by earnings decline across our regions. The extent of that decline varies by region,&quot; Smurfit said in a results statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Tough times require tough actions. We manage for the downcycle and our focus on cost take out has delivered permanent cost savings,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Smurfit said attention to working capital management had ensured low inventory and delivered a reduction in working capital during the year of 67 million Irish pounds.</p>
<p>Further improvement in its production ratios, across 400 facilities, had been realised using internal and external bench-marking processes, it said.</p>
<p>It said capital expenditure had amounted to 134 million Irish pounds but reflecting the difficult trading environment, new capital approvals for the year were restricted to 75 percent of depreciation.</p>
<p>Earlier, Smurfit announced a 52 percent drop in pre-tax profits for 1996 to 201 million punts.</p>
<p>The company said its Smurfit Worldwide R&amp;D and Innovation Centres at Talence, France and Carol Stream, Chicago, had significant success in the development of new initiatives during 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;These centres maintain a focus on innovative design and the development of new products which, coupled with continuous process improvement, will drive profitability into the next century,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Smurfit said it had concentrated on consolidating prior year investments during 1996 and said it continued to seek good corrugated conversion plants within Europe and had identified opportunities to this end.</p>
<p>Smurfit said during 1996 it had acquired Celpack, a corrugated box plant in Portugal, which would complement its existing sheet plant facilities and provide integration opportunities for its Spanish operations.</p>
<p>It said it had recently signed contracts to acquire a corrugated box plant in the Dominican Republic, adding to its Caribbean presence, and it continued to explore new opportunities in Central and Latin America.</p>
<p>&quot;The economic growth and lower inflation anticipated for Latin America together with a large forestry programme should help this region increase its contribution to the group's earnings,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;The group continues to develop from its initial modest presence in Asia and sees this as an area offering significant opportunities over the long term,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom +353 1 676 9779</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
