<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="495121" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Tesco ups profit despite margins slip.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Tesco ups profit despite margins slip.</headline>
<byline>Joe Winterbottom</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's leading supermarket group Tesco Plc on Tuesday reported a 10 percent rise in pre-tax profits and a continuing rise in sales at the start of the new trading year.</p>
<p>Tesco turned in pretax profits of 750 million pounds ($1.2 billion), up from 675 million and in line with expectations, while same store sales rose six percent in the first four weeks of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a good start in a competitive environment,&quot; the company said, reflected in a 7.5 pence rise in the company's shares to 360 by 1020 GMT.</p>
<p>Gross margins fell 0.4 percent to 5.8 percent last year, but deputy chairman David Reid said 0.3 points of the slippage was due to a petrol price war in Britain during the first half.</p>
<p>&quot;We think low inflation will probably stay on through until about the autumn,&quot; Reid said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;We are anticipating next year to be a stabilising picture on margins...petrol margins are recovering and there seems to be some reasonable stability in food prices currently.&quot;</p>
<p>Maintaining gross margins would be the key during the current year, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it will still be very competitive. I think the noise level will still be high...I think you can see that just from the various promotions that are going on.&quot;</p>
<p>Reid said Tesco aimed to launch a credit card in early July as a first step in its financial services venture with Royal Bank of Scotland with other products to follow.</p>
<p>Tesco hoped that its recent purchase of Irish supermarkets from Associated British Foods (ABF) for 630 million pounds would see a return on capital on a depreciation basis of around 15 percent compared with around nine percent on the acquisition cost.</p>
<p>He said the company's  operations in Hungary, where it has bought control of Global T.H. were showing strong sales growth.</p>
<p>&quot;Like for like sales...last year were up 37 percent...so that's why we're there.&quot;</p>
<p>He said even allowing for inflation of around 19 percent, it was a strong performance. Tesco plans to open six to eight new stores in Hungary in 1998 after one in Budapest this year.</p>
<p>Reid said the transition of management with Lord MacLaurin stepping down as chairman later this year, was proceeding very smoothly and the new team would provide &quot;more of the same.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that would include more customer initiatives based on &quot;better prices, improved service, working very hard with ClubCard...further new products and particularly also more money going into refits and extensions.&quot;</p>
<p>Tesco aims to open 26 stores in Britain this year totalling some 600,000 sq feet (55,700 sq metres) along with some 200,000 sq feet (18,500 sq metres) of extensions. ($ = 0.614 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
