<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49532" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: N.Y. Gov signs bill making healthcare competitive.</title>
<headline>N.Y. Gov signs bill making healthcare competitive.</headline>
<byline>Joan Gralla</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York Gov. George Pataki on Thursday signed a healthcare bill that will force hospitals to compete for patients, likely triggering layoffs, a blow the bill aims to cushion by helping to pay for retraining workers.</p>
<p>While the new legislation more than doubles the state's health insurance program for the children of working poor to 251,000 by December 1999, about 200,000 still will have no health coverage, an issue health associations plan to pursue.</p>
<p>&quot;That obviously has to be the next step but this is a giant step-up in program expansion,&quot; said Dr. Louis Cooper, who leads the American Academy of Pediatrics. He also heads the Pediatrics Department at St. Lukes-Roosevelt Hospital.</p>
<p>The new bill became law at a news conference held at Mount Sinai Hospital, one of the swiftest teaching and research hospitals to react to growing competition. In June, it said it planned to merge with New York University Medical Center.</p>
<p>New York legislators and health associations said that the impact of the new bill, which phases out a system under which the state set how much hospitals were paid for treating patients, will have to be monitored carefully.</p>
<p>The city has several hospitals that are renowned for their medical schools and research, which also have a tradition of caring for indigent and uninsured patients. They are vulnerable, as are smaller ones already under pressure.</p>
<p>Some modifications might be required, the officals said, as there is a risk that large companies, like insurers and big employers, with which hospitals on January 1, 1997, will start negotiating rates, might have too much clout.</p>
<p>These were not immediate issues on Pataki's horizon, as he ocused on the benefits that will result from ending the 12-year system of setting hospital rates in Albany.</p>
<p>&quot;We are just extremely confident that this new healthcare reform bill is going to increase accessibility, increase affordability and enhance the quality of care that is delivered to all New Yorkers.&quot;</p>
<p>A key part of the bill should help protect New York City's teaching hospitals, as it provides $1.385 billion to help hospitals pay for training physicians.</p>
<p>This measure should help New York state avoid a difficulty that other hospitals have experienced. &quot;We know from the experience in other states, particularly California, that teaching hospitals get clobbered there when they negotiate with health maintenance organizations,&quot; said Ken Raske. He is the president of the Greater New York Hospital Association.</p>
<p>Hospital and association officials said it was premature to estimate how deeply hospitals will have to cut costs in order to stay competitive, though they said they expected revenues will fall.</p>
<p>Dennis Rivera, president of local 1199 of the National Health and Human Services Union, said that while any estimates were preliminary, as many as 30,000 workers, including hourly and salaried employees, through-out the state might be &quot;displaced.&quot; The union represents 117,000 workers, out of about 350,000 in the state.</p>
<p>New York City likely would lose about half of these workers, he said, noting the bill provides up to $100 million to help them learn new skills, so that they can find jobs with new providers, like clinics, that are expected to open up.</p>
<p>Pataki and the legislators who attended the news conference all said that the bill was achieved in a bi-partisan fashion, though Assemblyman Dick Gottfried, D-New York City, who chairs the Health Committee, had some cautions.</p>
<p>Gottfried told reporters the new bill should strengthen the safety net and medical training. &quot;I'm very concerned though that opening up the hospital system to market forces as this legislation does is going to subject the health care system and New Yorkers who depend upon it to a lot of strain, a lot of pressures to ratchet down care and services.&quot;</p>
<p>Still, the president of Mount Sinai Hospital, expects his institution to fare well, partly due to the aid for graduate medical education, retraining and charity care.</p>
<p>&quot;We're very optimistic that we will emerge from this stronger than going in,&quot; said John Rowe.</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
