<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="495420" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Cohen gets Japan pledge on keeping U.S. troops.</title>
<headline>Cohen gets Japan pledge on keeping U.S. troops.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Cohen started the second day of a visit to Tokyo on Tuesday with public pledges already in his pocket that Japan will not seek a cutback in U.S. forces on its soil.</p>
<p>Both Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto and Cohen's Japanese counterpart, Defence Agency Director Fumio Kyuma, said on the opening day of Cohen's trip that the present level of 100,000 U.S. troops in Asia, including 47,000 in Japan, was needed for the region's security.</p>
<p>The firm pledges on Monday that Tokyo was not seeking to scale back the U.S. military presence in Japan were key to the U.S. defence secretary's trip to Japan. Hashimoto's pledge came in comments to parliament and Kyuma's was given at meeting with Cohen late on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I have repeatedly said I have no intention to call for a cut (in troop levels) at this time,&quot; Hashimoto said.</p>
<p>Cohen, making his first visit to Washington's chief ally in Asia since taking over as defence secretary, has flown into a public debate about the future of U.S. military bases in Japan.</p>
<p>Cohen praised Hashimoto's efforts to maintain Japanese support for the U.S. troops in Japan, more than half of whom are on the island of Okinawa. He said he planned to assure the prime minister in a meeting on Wednesday of Washington's determination to keep 100,000 American troops in the western Pacific indefinitely.</p>
<p>&quot;I will be conveying that we regard the Pacific region as the most dynamic in the world today and that our bilateral relationship with Japan is key to maintaining that dynamic relationship,&quot; Cohen said in remarks on Monday.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Cohen was scheduled to visit two U.S. military bases on the outskirts of Tokyo to give the forces there a pep talk, and to hold a meeting with Japanese Foreign Minister Yukihiko Ikeda.</p>
<p>He also has a meeting with top Japanese television commentators and editorial writers as part of a plan to improve the image of U.S. forces in Japan.</p>
<p>Long-standing opposition to the bases flared up in September 1995 when a young Okinawan schoolgirl was raped by three U.S. servicemen, who were later tried and jailed for the crime.</p>
<p>On Sunday, several thousand people held a protest rally in Tokyo against the presence of the forces on Okinawa, an island which makes up less than one percent of Japan's land area but hosts the bulk of U.S. military facilities in Japan. In a referendum last year, Okinawans backed a drive by the island's governor to have all the bases closed by 2015.</p>
<p>The concentration of U.S. military facilities on Okinawa is a legacy of the U.S. military occupation of the island between 1945 and 1972, when it was returned to Japan.</p>
<p>Last week, a new sex scandal threatened to upset Cohen's visit when a sailor at Yokosuka, the headquarters of the U.S. navy located on the outskirts of Tokyo, was taken into custody on suspicion of beating and sexually assaulting his girlfriend.</p>
<p>But Japanese police, who have taken over the case, have since ruled out sexual assault and are treating the matter as a case of domestic violence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
