<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="495682" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India truck strike enters second week.</title>
<headline>India truck strike enters second week.</headline>
<byline>Sabyasachi Mitra</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A nationwide strike by India's truck owners entered its second week on Tuesday without hope of an end to the crisis, authorities said.</p>
<p>&quot;There seems to be no light at the end of the tunnel,&quot; a senior government official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Industry leaders said production at factories would come to a halt if the strike dragged on for a few more days. Small producers, commodity traders and exporters had been hit hard, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is confused but we are open for negotiations. We have suggested various measures,&quot; said S.P. Singh, a spokesman for the All India Motor Transport Congress (AIMTC).</p>
<p>Singh said the government must withdraw a planned five percent service tax on road transport. &quot;Until it is dropped the strike continues,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Finance Minister P. Chidambaram proposed the tax in the federal budget for the 1997/98 (April-March) financial year.</p>
<p>The budget, now before parliament, has been held hostage by the political crisis threatening Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda, who faces a confidence vote on Friday.</p>
<p>The government has said it cannot rescind the tax as the proposal is now before parliament.</p>
<p>But Singh said: &quot;The government can write to the parliamentary panel on finance and suggest withdrawal of the service tax.&quot;</p>
<p>The transport body is also protesting a sharp rise in insurance premiums. The government has offered to refer the rise in insurance premiums to a government panel.</p>
<p>The strike has kept at least 2.2 million trucks off the roads. Small transporters who own one or two trucks constitute 93 percent of the country's fleet.</p>
<p>On Sunday, AIMTC officials consulted political parties on ways to break the deadlock. The politicians were hopeful a solution could be found soon, Singh said.</p>
<p>&quot;The biggest problem will be sending out cars,&quot; R.C. Bhargava, managing director of Maruti Udyog Ltd, the country's largest car maker, told Reuters when asked about the impact of the strike on his company.</p>
<p>&quot;We will try to keep it going but it may not be to the full extent,&quot; Bhargava said. The supply of components has begun to be hit, putting pressure on the cost of production, he said.</p>
<p>The supply of raw materials and transport of finished goods to customers were coming to a standstill, a spokesman for another company said.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless the supply of raw material is continuous, factories will soon cut down production and eventually close down,&quot; said the spokesman, who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Goods have piled up at major ports across the country, exporters said.</p>
<p>&quot;A large number of vessels have stopped calling at the ports. On March 31, the Bombay port was handling 10,500 tonnes of cargo. On April 4, the amount had dwindled to 3,600 tonnes,&quot; the Times of India newspaper quoted a Bombay Port Trust official as saying.</p>
<p>But the petroleum industry remained unaffected as state-owned oil companies relied on their own trucks to keep essential supplies going, said a spokesman for Indian Oil Corp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
