<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="495832" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US CREDIT OUTLOOK-Claims, and countdown to Friday.</title>
<headline>US CREDIT OUTLOOK-Claims, and countdown to Friday.</headline>
<byline>Scott Gerlach</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>With the first reports in a wave of key data set for release Friday, the U.S. fixed income market should tread water Thursday, analysts said.</p>
<p>Treasuries softened slightly Wednesday afternoon and sentiment appeared neutral to bearish going into Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;They'll look at the dollar tomorrow, they'll look at initial claims, they'll watch the tape,&quot; said Don Fine, chief market analyst at Chase Asset Management. &quot;But I think the market is in a holding pattern until Friday morning.&quot;  </p>
<p>Weekly jobless claims, often considered second-tier data, may get closer scrutiny as the day's only economic release.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the measures of just how strong the economy (is) has been jobless claims,&quot; said Peter Kretzmer, senior economist at NationsBanc Capital Markets Inc.</p>
<p>Claims hovered just below 315,000 for the past three weeks and economists in a Reuters survey projected they would read 313,000 for the week ended April 5.</p>
<p>Holding at low levels, the jobless figures continually remind the market of labor-sector pressures, particularly in light of tighter monetary policy, analysts said.  </p>
<p>A claims reading close to the forecast would not spook Treasuries, Kretzmer said that, while a drop to about 300,000 or below would add to fears of wage inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;It would underline the idea that the unemployment rate could fall further,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On the flip side, a modest rebound in claims would not give the market much lift, Kretzmer said.</p>
<p>Institutional factors such as changes in welfare policy partially account for the continued low claims levels, some analysts have said.  </p>
<p>The dollar's surge against the mark and yen lent minor support to the U.S. credit market Wednesday and should be at least a secondary focus Thursday, experts said.</p>
<p>The dollar posted multi-year highs versus both currencies, spurring some foreign buying of U.S. Treasuries.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been somewhat of a battle between foreign investors, who seem to want to hold U.S. securities and domestic investors, who are in a process of deciding how much to liquidate,&quot; Kretzmer said.  </p>
<p>Four senior Federal Reserve officials make speaking appearances Thursday. While most of the addresses target specific issues not directly related to monetary policy, Richmond Fed president Alfred Broaddus plans to speak on the current economy at a luncheon in Charleston, S.C. at 1230 EDT/1630 GMT.</p>
<p>Other speakers include Chicago Fed president Michael Moskow at 1300 EDT/1700 GMT, Fed Governor Susan Phillips at 1700 EDT/2100 GMT and Fed Governor Laurence Meyer at 1730 EDT/2130 GMT.  </p>
<p>Friday morning brings the week's key data: producer prices and retail sales for March.</p>
<p>The Producer Price Index was forecast to remain unchanged from February overall and up 0.1 percent in its core components.</p>
<p>Headline retail sales were expected up 0.6 percent, while sales excluding automobiles were projected up 0.4 percent.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1868 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
