<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="495992" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: CRICKET-BANGLADESH WINS BERTH IN ICC TROPHY FINAL.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-BANGLADESH WINS BERTH IN ICC TROPHY FINAL.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bangladesh earned a ticket to the 1999 World Cup on Wednesday when they beat Scotland by 72 runs in an International Cricket Council (ICC) Trophy semifinal match.</p>
<p>Bangladesh will meet Kenya, who beat Ireland by seven runs in the earlier semifinal match, in the final on Saturday.</p>
<p>But one of the losing sides can still win a place in the World Cup. They meet in the third place match on Thursday to decide the third team from the ICC Trophy to go into the next World Cup in England.</p>
<p>Bangladesh manager Gazi Ashraf said his team were never really threatened. &quot;Scotland had a good start, but they fell to the pressure, especially by our spinners and played some rash shots,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Scotland manger Bobby Hill paid tribute to the Bangldesh bowlers. &quot;We could only do as well as we could against very tight bowling. We tried but we failed. The target was too far away,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Bangladesh-Scotland match was played over two days after rains halted the match on the first day. A helicopter was used to blow-dry the field on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Mohammed Rafique led the Bangladeshi bowlers, taking four wickets and giving away just 25 runs in 5.5 overs. Enamul Hoque Moni snapped up three wickets for 31 runs in his 10 overs.</p>
<p>Greg Williamson was Scotland's top batsman with an unbeaten 39 while Iain Philip had 37 and George Salmond contributed 24.</p>
<p>For Bangladesh, who batted on Tuesday, Mohammed Khaled scored 70 runs, Amimul Islam 57 and Minhajul A. Nano 39 not out.</p>
<p>Scores: Bangladesh 243 for seven in 50 overs; Scotland 171 all out in 44.5 overs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
