<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496043" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAWI: MALAWI GOVERNMENT THREATENS TO FIRE STRIKERS.</title>
<headline>MALAWI GOVERNMENT THREATENS TO FIRE STRIKERS.</headline>
<dateline>BLANTYRE 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Malawi government on Wednesday ordered civil servants, who have been striking since Monday, to return to work or face dismissal.</p>
<p>&quot;The government wishes to commend the majority of civil servants for turning up for work today (Wednesday) despite persuasion from the union leadership to join them in the strike staged in some parts of the country,&quot; a government statement said.</p>
<p>Malawi's 100,000 civil servants, the lowest paid in Southern Africa, are pushing for a 100-percent pay rise recommended by an independent commission of inquiry. The lowest-paid employee receives $20 per month.</p>
<p>Government said it had declined to award the requested increase for fear of destablising the country's economy, which in 1996 grew by more than nine percent.</p>
<p>Official projections forecast economic growth of seven percent in 1997, with the chiefly agriculture-based economy boosted by the last two years' good rains.</p>
<p>Official figures show annual inflation for last December dropped to 6.7 percent from as high as 98 percent in December 1995. But analysts said ordinary citizens in the roughly 10 million population were still feeling the effects of previous high inflation.</p>
<p>World Bank representative Arif Zulfiqar said the government needed to halve its civil service to be able to award a 100-percent pay rise.</p>
<p>A government spokesman told radio on Monday night that the state acknowledged civil servants were ill paid and was willing to resume negotiations which had failed on Saturday.</p>
<p>Government has said it would award senior civil servants 10 percent and the lowest-paid servants 47 percent.</p>
<p>---- Johannesburg newsroom (+27-11) 482-1003 ---</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BLANTYRE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAWI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
