<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496090" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: SHIPPING SELL-OFF TALKS TO CONTINUE IN MAY.</title>
<headline>SHIPPING SELL-OFF TALKS TO CONTINUE IN MAY.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Latvian Shipping's (LS) potential strategic investors will submit their business plans to the Privatisation Agency (LPA) in May, an agency official is quoted on Wednesday by the Diena Bizness newspaper.</p>
<p>The valuation of LS by Coopers &amp; Lybrand will not be ready in spring as earlier planned, but on August 7, Raitis Kitners of LPA is quoted by the newspaper as saying.</p>
<p>Latvian Shipping is estimated to be the world's 19th largest shipping firm and has 39 tankers and 24 reefers (refrigerator vessels) and seven dry cargo vessels. LS annual turnover is close to $300 million.</p>
<p>The fact, that the valuation will be ready only in August will not hinder the sale of a 25-30 percent stake to a strategic investor, Kitners is quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Around 14 companies and institutions including Nomura and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) have said that they are interested in taking part in the sale of a 25 to 35 percent stake in LS.</p>
<p>This stake up for sale will be based on a new share emission and not come from the existing LS shares, Kitners is quoted as saying.</p>
<p>The audit company will be ready to hand in its valuation only after the groups consolidated audit is complete, which is planned to be ready on July 7, Dienas Bizness says.</p>
<p>Latvian Shipping has earlier this year decided on a strategy to improve its financial situation and reduce losses.</p>
<p>The company is estimated to have made a loss of $25 million last year and $51 million the year befor.</p>
<p>-- Martinsh Gravitis, Riga Newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
