<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496185" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: More optimism seen in London freight Panamax secto.</title>
<headline>More optimism seen in London freight Panamax secto.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Freight market conditions for capers and handies remained flat but there was more optimism in the Panamax sector, brokers reported. Rates did not show general improvement - the BFI was down 8 to 1,442 - but a better volume of fresh enquiry was said to have encouraged owners' expectations.</p>
<p>Grain - Despite denials that Chinese interests had bought 1.5 million tonnes of Canadian wheat there were some signs that grain trading was picking up. In the caper sizes, apart from potential Saudi barley business for April/May shipment from the continent, Dreyfus was interested in a possible prompt replacement of 50/100,000 tonnes capacity for Commander 123,180 dwt for Mississippi/Holland. The vessel was reported to have had difficulties presenting clean for grain.</p>
<p>Dreyfus also quoted 29/40,000 grains 55' Mississippi/Lisbon-Hamburg range for 18/25 April. Toepfer had 18,000 wheat Duluth/Limassol for 25 April/5 May and possibilities for 55,000 heavy grain Nueva Palmeira completing Brazil or Brazil only/Lisbon-Hamburg for 25 April/5 May and 1.6/1.8 million cft Mississippi/Lisbon-Hamburg including WC UK and Ireland for 15/25 April. Shipmair had an enquiry for a small Panamax delivery Recalada 20/30 April for a trip to Skaw-Passero and Molinos quoted 22/25,000 sunpellets 58' Buenos Aires/Lisbon-Hamburg range including Seaforth for 5/25 May.</p>
<p>Transfield had 50/55,000 heavy grain and/or fertilisers US Gulf/China for 18 April/5 May. Fixture reports in the Atlantic were thin - Helen B was linked with HMM for about 50,000 heavy grain US Gulf/Cigading at close to $23.75, and Continental fixed Alam Progreso for 25,000/10 heavy grain US Gulf/Philippines at about $44.00, both for prompt dates. In the Pacific new grain enquiry was quoted by Cargill for 50,000 barley Vancouver/Saudi Arabia for 20/30 April, Continental with 54,000 heavy grain NOPAC/Taiwan for 29 April/9 May and Halla 54,000 heavy grain Nopac/Japan for 15/30 April.</p>
<p>Various new orders were seen from Australia to Thailand, Red Sea and Arabian Gulf destinations. Dreyfus was rumoured to have fixed a Panamax for grain from NOPAC to Taiwan on private terms.</p>
<p>Minerals etc - Eastern caper markets were active, even if rates remained relatively weak. CRA fixed Thalassini Axia 164,796 dwt for iron ore from Dampier to Redcar and Showa booked Anangel Splendour 161,000 dwt delivery China for a Pacific round, both on private terms. Sinotrans fixed the 1976-built Kiho 169,472 dwt on subjects for 9/11 months at $12,500 daily, Showa took Good News 138,000 dwt delivery China for a Pacific round at $13,500 daily and the 1973-built Alina 129,000 dwt was understood fixed on subjects delivery China mid-May for a west Australian round at $9,750 daily.</p>
<p>Navix booked the Shinwa-relet newbuilding Tian Yang Hai 170,000 dwt delivery ex-yard S Korea for a trip via Australia to the continent on private terms. In the Atlantic Cetragpa agreed a steady $5.20 for Scf Challenger for 100,000/10 coal Hampton Roads/Sines for end April/early May. Some lower rates were seen for Panamaxes in the East, but Hanjin was said to be on subjects with the 1982-built Vitali 65,739 dwt delivery retro sailing far east end-March for a Pacific round at a firm $11,850 daily.</p>
<p>In the Atlantic the Marifran-relet Lady Moyne 65,000 dwt was rumoured fixed by Italian charterers delivery prompt Continent for short period at $9,000 daily, and Ispat Tarang 70,329 dwt open Lisbon prompt may have been fixed for 3-5 months although full details were lacking.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
