<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496161" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-UK Conservatives have increased tax - study.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-UK Conservatives have increased tax - study.</headline>
<byline>Cheryl Juckes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The tax burden on ordinary British families has increased during the last five years of Conservative government, a leading independent think-tank said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Venturing into highly controversial election territory, the Institute for Fiscal Studies said the average household now paid seven pounds a week more in tax than it did before the April 1992 election because of changes in tax and benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;We find average losses of seven pounds per week, with richer groups losing most in cash terms,&quot; the Institute said.</p>
<p>&quot;But, proportionately, people right at the bottom and in the middle of the income distribution have lost most -- over three percent of their post-tax income.&quot;</p>
<p>The Labour party, which opinion polls suggest is well ahead of Prime Minister John Major's Conservatives in the run-up to the May 1 election, hailed the report as a &quot;damning indictment of the Conservative tax record since 1992.&quot;</p>
<p>The Conservatives have claimed credit for reducing income tax rates but have offset this by reducing tax-free allowances and raising other taxes.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Major should come clean and admit that he is lying about tax,&quot; said Labour's finance spokesman Gordon Brown.</p>
<p>The Conservatives played up the report's finding that they had presided over a rise in living standards and its criticisms of Labour's plans to impose a windfall tax on the profitis of privatised utility companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's IFS report confirms the substantial rise in living standards under this government since the last election,&quot; Chancellor of the Exchequer (finance minister) Kenneth Clarke said.</p>
<p>Clarke said the IFS had concluded that Labour's tax plans would benefit households in the top half of the income scale more than those in the bottom half.</p>
<p>The IFS report said Labour's windfall tax could be unfair because some of the current shareholders who would bear the impact of the tax were not those who had benefited from low issue prices when the companies were floated.</p>
<p>It also warned the move could mean higher prices and lower investment by the firms if it provoked worries about the stability of the tax and regulatory regime.</p>
<p>But on the issue of helping the poor, neither of the main parties won a glowing report from the IFS.</p>
<p>Labour wants to introduce a 10 percent starting rate of tax, half the current level, while the Conservatives would like ultimately to make 20 percent the standard tax rate for all.</p>
<p>&quot;Neither change would help the poorest, who don't pay income tax,&quot; the Institute said. &quot;A better way of cutting income tax to help the poor, if cut income tax they must, is to raise tax free allowances.&quot;</p>
<p>The report said that public spending curbs planned by both parties were so tight that they could not be achieved without reducing the size and scope of the welfare state.</p>
<p>Labour has promised to live within spending plans laid down by the Conservatives for its first two years in office.</p>
<p>The IFS said that the plans for spending growth of just 0.4 percent over the next three years contrasted with the long term average of 1.9 percent. &quot;Spending increases this low have neve before been achieved,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>If the government did not meet these plans it would have to increase taxation as well as spending.</p>
<p>The IFS said government borrowing would continue to fall as the economy continued to grow, provided current tax and spending plans were met.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
