<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496192" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST-Australian Sports News - April 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-Australian Sports News - April 10.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Super League player Ricky Stuart's comments that the game was turning into touch football have been down-played by Super League officials and described as courageous by leading ARL spokesman Phil Gould. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Soccer Australia is in a short-term financial crisis and has asked all clubs and state federations to pay outstanding fees or face expulsion. Nearly $A1 million is owed to the leading organisation, which is confident it will receive the required funds. Pge 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Brisbane Bullets basketball team will be looking to rise to previous heights this season, after a succession of disappointing years. Since their last championship in 1987, the Bullets have only played in one grand final. Page 18.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Cathy Freeman has been rejuvenated after racing in South Africa and competing against world class athletes, after a slow domestic season. Freeman scored three wins and her best times of the year before leaving for Texas yesterday to undertake six weeks of training. Page 49.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Renee Levett has completed her first season on the International Snowboard Federation professional World Cup circuit, becoming the first Australian woman to compete full-time on the circuit. Competing in the slalom and giant slalom events she finished asthe highest ranked amateur athlete. Page 49.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian golfer Greg Norman has enlisted the services of a motivational speaker to rediscover positive thoughts before the US Masters begins this week. Norman also thanked the media for their support in difficult times. Page 49.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Australia has won the fifth one-day cricket international in South Africa, with young Tasmanian batsman Michael DiVenuto receiving man-of-the-match honours with 89 runs. DiVenuto suffered a groin strain and will not play in the next game on Friday, with Mark Waugh expected to return from injury to take his place. Page C19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Women's National Basketball League has proposed a world club championship between the world's top Australian, American, European and Brazilian leagues in 1999. Coverage of the Australian women's league may move from the ABC depending on the NBL's coverage rights, to be finalised at the end of this season. Page C19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Jockey Damien Oliver has quit racing in Hong Kong to return to Australia and his family after becoming disillusioned by the Hong Kong racing scene. Oliver will hold talks with former trainer Lee Freedman next week, although Freedman already has two leadig riders in his stable. Page C18.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE HERALD SUN</p>
<p>Carlton AFL player Greg Williams has been suspended for three matches for striking, but his club will not commence another legal challenge. At the judiciary last night, Craig O'Brien from the Swans was cleared of a striking charge, but Adelaide's Darren Jarman received a two-match suspension from a charge of striking. Page 88.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The AFL will not reschedule starting times at the Gabba for future Brisbane Lions games. The Brisbane and North Melbourne clubs both requested night games to ensure the safety of players in hot conditions. Page 86.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Melbourne will host the next men's soccer game on May 28 at the commencement of the Super Stars of Soccer series. This will involve local and foreign-based players chosen by head Australian coach Terry Venables. The second game of the series will be played in Sydney on June 4. Page 77.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>The Hahn Cup rugby union competition will be expanded next year from 14 to 24 teams from New South Wales, Queensland, NSW Country and Melbourne. The Cup starts in March and games will be played for six weeks along Australia's east coast, including Townsville and Melbourne. Page 86.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian club rugby union players will be paid on contract for the first time this season. Warringah and West Harbour clubs have signed deals to receive $A500 a win for first grade through signed agreements between the clubs and players. Page 86.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Super League Queensland skipper Allan Langer will receive an official warning to change his tackling style before Friday's opening Tri-Series game against New South Wales. Langer will receive a written complaint about the danger of tripping-style tackles which caused a serious knee injury in an opposition player last week. Page 84.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
