<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496273" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Bank SBM stocks push Mauritius Bourse index up.</title>
<headline>Bank SBM stocks push Mauritius Bourse index up.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>State Bank of Mauritius (SBM) stocks pushed up market index Semdex at the Stock Exchange of Mauritius on Wednesday, bourse officials said.</p>
<p>Semdex climbed by 6.61 points to 378.80. Traded volume was 26.92 million rupees from 1,131,191 shares compared to 20.15 million rupees on 485,820 shares on Monday.</p>
<p>SBM gained 10 cents to 13.00 rupees on 726,160 shares, Mauritius Commercial Bank (MCB) was stable at 85.50 rupees on 43,000 shares, whereas British American Insurance (BAI) lost 5 cents to 8.50 rupees on 14,340 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a big buying interest on SBM on Wednesday as it was not quoted last Monday due to a great demand for its shares and not a single offer,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>He said that the same thing happened to Shell which was not traded in five consecutive weeks prior to Wednesday, when it gained 1.20 rupees to 21.60 rupees on 26,630 shares.</p>
<p>Hotel-based Sun Resorts was 1.60 rupee higher to 46.70 rupees on 202,571 shares, New Mauritius Hotels (NMH) lost 70 cents to 35.30 rupees on 76,000 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investors have shown buying interest in Sun Resorts,&quot; another broker said.</p>
<p>Air Mauritius lost 30 cents to 39.70 on 150 shares.</p>
<p>--Clifford Vellien, Port Louis ++230 211-9555</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
