<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496376" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenia cenbank stands by foreign investor rules.</title>
<headline>Slovenia cenbank stands by foreign investor rules.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of Slovenia governor France Arhar said on Wednesday there were no plans to abolish controversial new rules that force international investors to open special accounts in order to trade in securities.</p>
<p>&quot;We are preparing no changes (to the custodian account rules),&quot; Arhar said in a speech to financiers.</p>
<p>He added that the central bank had suggested the watchdog Securities' Market Agency should extend the regulations to domestic investors.</p>
<p>Arhar argued that the new rules, which triggered an exodus of foreign investors after their introduction in February, were necessary to regulate the securities market.</p>
<p>The decree instructed international investors to open the special accounts at any one of Slovenia's 14 fully licensed banks. The banks have still to make the accounts available.</p>
<p>Arhar forecast three banks would begin offering the accounts in the near future, contradicting bank officials who have said the accounts were unlikely to start operating before the end of April.</p>
<p>Arhar did not name the three banks.</p>
<p>Since the ruling the blue-chip SBI index has dropped 18.4 percent and daily volume, at an average of 70 million tolars ($0.45 million), is one seventh of its earlier size.</p>
<p>Consequently some traders had speculated the Bank of Slovenia may decide to ease the custodian account scheme in order to facilitate international portfolio investment.</p>
<p>-- Marja Novak, Ljubljana newsroom, 386-61-125-8439</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
