<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496310" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin gets tough with Russian parliament.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin gets tough with Russian parliament.</headline>
<byline>Philippa Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian President Boris Yeltsin lashed out at his parliamentary opponents for a second day on Wednesday, anxious to show a firm hand before leaving for a spring holiday next week.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, beset by months of illness until February, has been cracking the whip over parliament and his newly-reshuffled government this week as pressure grows for a resolution of Russia's acute economic problems.</p>
<p>He accused the communist-dominated lower house of overstepping the constitution, saying in a letter to its speaker Gennady Seleznyov that it had no right to make political judgements on foreign and domestic policy.</p>
<p>He also had strong words for the upper house, the Federation Council, where the communist lobby has been reinforced by recent local elections.</p>
<p>&quot;We will work together, as long as you take into account that I am the head of state,&quot; Interfax news agency quoted Yeltsin as telling a group of senators.</p>
<p>Power in Russia has been concentrated firmly in the president's hands since a new constitution was approved in 1993, the year in which Yeltsin dissolved parliament and sent in tanks against hardline deputies.</p>
<p>But a group of current deputies stepped up pressure on the executive on Wednesday, walking out of the lower house complaining that a lack of government funding was threatening the spring sowing campaign and putting the harvest at risk.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, who has spent more than a month planning and implementing a radical cabinet reshuffle he hopes will break the economic crisis, this week spelt out its priorities.</p>
<p>At the top of the list is collecting taxes and paying overdue wages and pensions to millions of Russians, some of whom have not received money for six months.</p>
<p>New Deputy Prime Minister Oleg Sysuyev, responsible for the social sphere, said on Wednesday that wage arrears were gradually being paid off but pension payments had fallen behind target again in March.</p>
<p>He confirmed that a revenue shortfall meant the government would have to cut the social budget this year and said it was time to face the unpalatable truth that social protection did not come without a price.</p>
<p>&quot;We love our people very much and decide to protect them, and in that way we deceive them,&quot; said Sysuyev.</p>
<p>Acknowledging that he already had an unenviable task, Sysuyev said had nevertheless agreed to take on the vacant post of Minister of Labour along with his existing portfolio.</p>
<p>At 44, Sysuyev is one of a group of young reformers taken on by Yeltsin to try to tackle the growing payments crisis, restructure swathes of bankrupt industry and fight corruption, which has put many Russians off capitalist-style reforms.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, set to discuss corruption in a radio address on Thursday, told new First Deputy Prime Minister Boris Nemtsov that all officials should follow their example. &quot;You and I have the same credo -- not to take bribes,&quot; Yeltsin said.</p>
<p>&quot;He hasn't taken a kopeck and I haven't taken a kopeck,&quot; he added, referring to the now-obsolete subdivision of the rouble.</p>
<p>Yeltsin also signed a decree aimed at reducing corruption on Tuesday, which prompted Economy Minister Yakov Urinson to tell Ekho Moskvy radio on Wednesday: &quot;By this presidential decree... we are closing all the main channels for abuse in this area.&quot;</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;Total hundred percent prevention is impossible because our people are very inventive.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
