<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496354" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania leu almost flat, market unmoved by news.</title>
<headline>Romania leu almost flat, market unmoved by news.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's leu currency ended bobbing around 6,900/7,100 to the dollar on Wednesday, almost unchanged and in narrow ranges against 6,850/7,200 at the opening in a fairly liquid interbank market, dealers said.</p>
<p>Traders said the market was unmoved by the news Romania signed a letter of intent for the resumption of International Monetary Fund credits. The letter is to be discussed by the IMF Board later this month.</p>
<p>News that Romania's monthly inflation hit an all-time high of over 30 percent last month came after trading hours.</p>
<p>A few dealers said the figure looked &quot;surprisingly high&quot; but were reluctant to venture any further prediction over its impact on the market or on the currency.</p>
<p>Traders said an announcement that the central bank would withdraw banking licences from troubled banks Dacia Felix and Credit Bank would help improve the soundness of the sector. Neither bank has operated on the market for several months.</p>
<p>Money market trading stayed low with short-term prices near 100 percent, slightly up from about 90 in the morning.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected a heavy oversubscription for fixed-interest T-bills to be offered on Thursday as their yield was at about 193 percent, or the Bucharest Interbank Offered Rate (BUBOR) set five days ago.</p>
<p>They also said the BNR was likely to cut its minimum permitted rate for its auctioned refinancing credits on Thursday to about 170 percent from last week's 190 percent.</p>
<p>On the retail market, the leu hovered at around 6,500/6,900 to the dollar.</p>
<p>-- Mirela Eremia, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
