<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496425" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albanian opposition ends 1-year parliament boycott.</title>
<headline>Albanian opposition ends 1-year parliament boycott.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's main opposition Socialist Party returned to parliament on Wednesday nearly a year after it abandoned its seats charging widespread election fraud.</p>
<p>The leftist party agreed to drop its boycott of the parliament in a bid to help rebuild confidence and restore order to the violence-plagued Balkan nation.</p>
<p>The nine Socialist deputies entered the 140-seat parliament for the first time since last April. They arrived with no fanfare just moments before the session began and sat quietly at their desks, left symbolically unoccupied for the last year.</p>
<p>&quot;We are coming into parliament to show that our party is committed to resolve the crisis, even though we are not responsible for it,&quot; said Namik Dokle, the party's parliamentary leader, in a brief address.</p>
<p>&quot;With this political will we can build and we can give hope to the people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Socialists' return to parliament was another small but important step on the road to normalcy for Albania, which has been ravaged by weeks of violence that has left more than 200 people dead and about 700 injured.</p>
<p>Albania, already Europe's poorest nation, plunged into near chaos when get-rich-quick investment schemes collapsed earlier this year and armed rebels took control of southern Albania during an unchecked spasm of looting and banditry.</p>
<p>But in another hopeful sign that the violence is gradually subsiding, the Interior Ministry and local authorities said on Wednesday they knew of no major violence or killings in the last 24 hour period, making it the quietest night in weeks.</p>
<p>The state-run ATA news agency, which has also kept close tabs on shootings, did not report any killings overnight. Police have imposed a strictly enforced 8 p.m. to 7 a.m. curfew since March 2.</p>
<p>The publisher of the independent daily newspaper Dita Informacion said unknown assailants had shot at his house on Tuesday but no one was injured.</p>
<p>Shpetim Nazarko, whose paper failed to appear on Wednesday after its first issue in a month on Tuesday, told Reuters several gunmen shot wildly at his house in a Tirana suburb in the early afternoon on Tuesday.</p>
<p>He said he did not know the reasons for the attack. But the English-language Albanian Daily News said Nazarko's newspaper had published an article on Tuesday critical of President Sali Berisha.</p>
<p>The return of the Socialists to parliament was hailed by political leaders and local newspapers, who said they hoped the legislature would pave the way for early elections.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome the arrival of the Socialist deputies in the parliament,&quot; said Ali Spahia, parliamentary leader of the majority Democratic party. &quot;We are ready for agreements, compromises which aim at guaranteeing peace and democracy in the country.&quot;</p>
<p>The Socialists had refused to recognise the results of the last elections in May 1996, which showed Berisha's rightist Democratic party winning 87 percent of the vote.</p>
<p>International observers also found irregularities in the elections. Charges of election fraud were a key factor in precipitating the violent uprising.</p>
<p>Dokle, whose party joined the Democratic party and eight smaller parties in an emergency all-party government on March 11, said the Socialists would work in parliament on the legal framework for the distribution of international humanitarian aid and to set up &quot;free and fair elections&quot; due in late June.</p>
<p>&quot;Anyone who opposes this government not only will fail but will be cursed by a shocked people,&quot; said Dokle,</p>
<p>Government sources in Tirana said military experts from six countries planning to protect humanitarian aid shipments to Albania, starting next week, had arrived in Albania.</p>
<p>The sources said military experts from Italy, which plans to lead the 6,000-man force, along with France, Greece, Romania, Spain, Spain and Denmark were inspecting facilities that would house the troops.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
