<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496432" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenia GSM consortium to invest up to 120 mln DM.</title>
<headline>Slovenia GSM consortium to invest up to 120 mln DM.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenia's GSM Consortium said on Wednesday it would invest up to 120 million marks ($70 million) over five years in developing a mobile phone network if its bid for Slovenia's second licence succeeded.</p>
<p>The consortium is a joint venture between unlisted switchboard maker Iskratel, 48 percent owned by Germany's Siemens, export-import firm Intereuropa, petrol trader Istrabenz and Finland's Telecom.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to develop the network in several phases,&quot; project manager Bojan Dremelj told a news conference.</p>
<p>He said the group would invest up to 80 million marks in the first three years and 120 million over five years in the network's technical development of the network.</p>
<p>He said the group's final goal was to cover 50 percent of Slovenia, which currently has one of the poorest coverage ratios in Europe. The country's mountainous terrain made full coverage difficult, Dremelj added.</p>
<p>&quot;We are ready for the race for the licence and we think our offer will be the best of all -- we expect to get the licence in the third quarter of this year,&quot; consortium president Milan Jelenc said.</p>
<p>Jelenc said that all four partners would share investment costs equally.</p>
<p>Currently only state-owned Mobitel has a licence to operate a mobile telephone system in Slovenia.</p>
<p>The government has not yet said if and when it might grant another licence, but parliament is expected to pass a telecommunictaions law in the next few months that would lay the groundwork for a tender. -- Novica Mihajlovic, Ljubljana newsroom, 386-61-125-8439</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
