<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496513" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Bank of America eyes Brazil's retail banking.</title>
<headline>Bank of America eyes Brazil's retail banking.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of America, which for years has been active in Brazil in the corporate banking business, said it will look at opportunities in the country's retail banking sector.</p>
<p>&quot;Retail banking here is very attractive. We are interested in this market,&quot; said Bank of America Chairman and CEO David Coulter at a news conference on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Bank of America is a large retail bank in the United States. It is very natural for us to think about doing consumer business outside the U.S.,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Coulter said he doesn't have any strategy in mind but bank officials noted the institution could enter the retail business by expanding its Brazilian subsidiary Multi-Banco, which already operates as a commercial bank.</p>
<p>He also said it is unlikely that Bank of America will bid at a big bank privatization in Brazil, although he noted that the bank &quot;definitely has the financial size of looking at opportunities around the world.&quot;</p>
<p>Interest in Brazil's retail banking market has increased after the nearly three-year-old Real stabilization plan improved Brazilians' purchasing power and led to an increase in demand for credit and banking services.</p>
<p>The most recent example of foreign interest in the country's retail banking was the takeover of Banco Bamerindus, Brazil's fourth largest private bank, by HSBC Holdings Plc, one of the world's largest financial conglomerates.</p>
<p>For the time being, Bank of America said it plans to expand its corporate banking operations in Brazil, focusing on capital markets and project financing, particularly in telecommunications and power sectors.</p>
<p>Bank of America has been asked to provide financing for a group of investors comprising U.S. AirTouch Communications and local groups Odebrecht, Camargo Correa and Unibanco bank, which is bidding to operate Band B cellular services.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
