<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496722" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan telecoms giant cuts rates.</title>
<headline>Taiwan telecoms giant cuts rates.</headline>
<byline>Lawrence Chung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's telecommunications liberalisation has forced state-owned Chung Hwa Telecom to cut its mobile and overseas calling rates before the entry of foreign-backed rivals later this year.</p>
<p>Effective from April 16, mobile phone rates will be cut by 90 cents to T$5.6 per minute, while overseas calling rates will be reduced by 3-17 percent, Chung Hwa said in a statement on Wednesday. Chung Hwa is Taiwan's largest telecoms firm.</p>
<p>Monthly rental for mobile phones will also be slashed by half to T$600 and rental fees for pagers will be cut by T$200 to T$300 per month, the statement said.</p>
<p>International and domestic data communication monthly charges, including Chung Hwa's Hinet internet service, will all be cut by up to 33 percent -- the lowest charges in Asia, the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;The reductions aim to improve our competitiveness in both domestic and international markets,&quot; said Chung Hwa spokeswoman Hsu An-ning.</p>
<p>She said the cuts will make the firm's international service charges the 10th lowest in the world.</p>
<p>But the reduction of the popular cellular, data communication and other service charges has caught newcomers who plan to launch their services this year off-guard.</p>
<p>Private telecom companies, particularly eight firms which planned to start their mobile services in the second half of this year, criticised Chung Hwa's plan as being unfair.</p>
<p>&quot;Announcing the reduction ahead of our planned launch is obviously targeting us. It is unfair,&quot; said an official with Pacific Telecommunications System.</p>
<p>Pacific, which has investment from U.S.-based GTE Corp, was among local consortiums awarded the lucrative mobile phone franchises by Taiwan's transportation and communications ministry in January.</p>
<p>Mobile telephony is one of several telecom sectors liberalised by parliament in January 1996, opening it up for private and limited foreign investment.</p>
<p>Vincent Chow, area sales manager of Ericsson which on Wednesday launched its GF788 GSE mobile phone in Taiwan, said at least one million cellular telephones would be marketed on the island after the eight companies started their services.</p>
<p>Hsu Chieh-kuei, vice-transport minister, was quoted by state-run Daily News as saying that after the April 16 reduction, &quot;there should be no more rate cuts to avoid backlash from the would-be new comers&quot;.</p>
<p>Ministry officials said the planned cuts were in line with the liberalisation of the island's telecoms market.</p>
<p>Analysts, however, said there was a need for the government to further upgrade its telecommunications technology and liberalise such business if Taiwan wanted to develop itself as an Asia-Pacific telecommunications centre.</p>
<p>&quot;In the face of strong competition, Chung Hwa has to cut its charges, but this does not mean its competitiveness will increase,&quot; Ma Kai, chief researcher of the private Chung Hwa Institution for Economic Research, said by telephone.</p>
<p>He said if Chung Hwa wanted to increase competitiveness, it should further improve its services and upgrade its technology.</p>
<p>Before Chung Hwa became a company in July 1996, it was a part of Taiwan government's Directorate-General of Telecommunication which had monopolised the island's telecommunications business for 48 years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
