<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496708" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Euroyen, JGBs firm after choppy session.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Euroyen, JGBs firm after choppy session.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Euroyen and Japanese government bond (JGB) futures were off their lows in late Wednesday trade, lifted by Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka saying Japan would maintain its easy monetary policy.</p>
<p>After a choppy day which saw December Euroyen fall through support at 99.09 to a low of 99.07 in reaction to a sharp drop in JGBs, the contract stabilised and was quoted around 99.11 at 1110 GMT, down 0.01 from its IMM close.  </p>
<p>Dealers said JGB futures came off in early trade on comments by Eisuke Sakakibara, director-general of the Finance Ministry's International Finance Bureau, that the Japanese economy was now in an upward trend.</p>
<p>A report in the Yomiuri Shimbun daily quoting Sakakibara saying Japan's long-term interest rates could rise once people realised the economy was not that bad was also blamed for the sell-off in JGB and Euroyen futures.  </p>
<p>But the Bank of Japan (BOJ)'s move to leave an unexpected surplus in the money market, and the subsequent drop in the unsecured overnight call loan rate to 0.44 percent, sparked a recovery, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market should be very firm. I'd expect buying interest to emerge around 99.05 in December Euroyen,&quot; said a trader with a U.S. house, adding that the contract would be capped at 99.20.</p>
<p>Other dealers saw the contract facing resistance at 99.13 and its recent high of 99.18.</p>
<p>June JGBs settled at 127.07 against their previous 126.96 after falling to a low of 126.58.  </p>
<p>A trader with a European house said stop-loss sales were triggered after the contract fell below 126.80 but the market rebounded on good buying around the intra-day low.</p>
<p>He said reports that Kampo, Japan's Postal Life Insurance Bureau, had said it planned to buy JGBs and foreign bonds worth more than six trillion yen supported the market.</p>
<p>Eurodollar futures ended steady in thin trade with September unchanged against an IMM close at 93.720 on volume of 3,635 lots. -- Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
