<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496801" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. military unveils new &quot;Raptor&quot; stealth fighter.</title>
<headline>U.S. military unveils new &quot;Raptor&quot; stealth fighter.</headline>
<byline>Martin Langfield</byline>
<dateline>MARIETTA, Ga. 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Air Force unveiled on Wednesday its new stealth fighter plane for the next century, billing the controversial F-22 as the most sophisticated and powerful fighter in the world.</p>
<p>In a joint ceremony with aviation giants Lockheed Martin and Boeing and engine makers Pratt and Whitney, the Air Force deployed lasers, military pageantry and foot-stomping music in a spectacular introduction for the sleek, twin-tailed aircraft, nicknamed the &quot;Raptor.&quot;</p>
<p>The light gray single-seat plane costs more than $70 million per unit and is designed, its makers say, &quot;to secure air dominance over any adversary aircraft.&quot;</p>
<p>The first production F-22 glowered malevolently in the half-light of a hangar as dignitaries including U.S. House of Representatives Speaker Newt Gingrich and Secretary of the Air Force Sheila Widnall inspected its lines.</p>
<p>The F-22, the first of nine to be built under the makers' current contract, will have its first flight next month.</p>
<p>&quot;It really is a miracle machine,&quot; Lockheed Martin Aeronautics Sector President Micky Blackwell told reporters. &quot;The first thing the F-22 will kill is the enemy's appetite for war...It's almost goosebump time.&quot;</p>
<p>Stealth aircraft present a minimal profile to enemy radars, enabling them to ghost towards their targets and destroy them while remaining virtually invisible to electronic surveillance.</p>
<p>Unlike the angular, black F-117 stealth plane, however, the F-22 is smoothly designed, hiding its powerful array of weapons within its fuselage to further avoid detection.</p>
<p>It also uses advanced computer technology and ground- breaking engine technology to cruise at speeds of around Mach 2, or twice the speed of sound, while remaining as manoeuvrable as slower subsonic fighters.</p>
<p>Despite its touted merits, the F-22 has come under cost pressure as the Defence Department reviews whether U.S. defences need all the planes and other weapons now planned.</p>
<p>A Pentagon analyst group concluded early this month that plans to buy 438 F-22s could cost $16 billion more than the Air Force's $71 billion estimate.</p>
<p>Air Force Chief of Staff Gen. Ronald Fogleman said on Wednesday the analysis was based in some cases on cost assumptions higher than those used by the Air Force, and Defence Secretary William Cohen told Congress recently that if costs do rise the number of planes will be cut or costly features cut.</p>
<p>The Congressional Budget Office has questioned whether the military can afford what it estimated would be a $350 billion cost for all three new planes now planned -- the Air Force F-22, the Navy F/A-18E/F and a Joint Strike Fighter for all services.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARIETTA, Ga."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
