<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496814" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks tumble as profit-taking halts three-day rally.</title>
<headline>Stocks tumble as profit-taking halts three-day rally.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue-chip stocks ran into a wall of selling Wednesday as profit-taking halted the market's three-session comeback after last week's headlong fall.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average closed down 45.32 points at 6,563.84. Last week, the market tumbled 215 points on interest-rate worries.</p>
<p>In the broader market, declining issues led advances 1,271 to 1,209 on active volume of 451 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Technology and financial stocks, two groups that had paced the market's rally, were the hardest hit.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we saw some giveback in the techs as well as the banks,&quot; said Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;You'll see these stocks run up and then tend to give ground before the earnings,&quot; he said. Banks are among the first companies to report their results each quarter.</p>
<p>The first-quarter earnings reporting season will get underway in earnest next week, and it should last until the end of the month.</p>
<p>While many analysts generally view the stock market's recent woes as part of a correction, there is mounting evidence the pullback is taking an toll on investors.</p>
<p>According to a newly released survey by financial services company Quick &amp; Reilly, 39 percent of investors described themselves as bullish, down from 58 percent in January.</p>
<p>Those expressing a bearish market outlook rose to 31 percent, up from 20 percent three months ago. The survey showed the prevailing investor mood as &quot;conservatism rather than panic&quot;, Quick &amp; Reilly said.</p>
<p>The stock market's recent ills also were reflected in a $2.4 billion drop in assets at Fidelity Investments' flagship Magellan Fund. The firm said Magellan assets fell to $51.4 billion at the end of March from $53.8 billion in February.</p>
<p>Fidelity also said Magellan boosted the share of assets in stocks to 95.5 percent at the end of February -- the most recent month for which figures are available -- from 93.5 percent a month earlier, shrinking its cash and bond holdings.</p>
<p>There were pockets of strength in the market. Dow index component Procter &amp; Gamble Co. jumped 4 to 119-3/4 after announcing it would acquire Tambrands Inc. for $50 per share in cash, or some $1.85 billion.</p>
<p>Tambrands, which had gained in recent sessions on rumours of the deal, rose 2 to 48-1/8.</p>
<p>Transportation stocks were higher, paced by rallies in railroad companies CSX Corp. and Norfolk Southern Corp., in the wake of their agreement to split up Conrail Inc.</p>
<p>CSX climbed 1-1/2 to 45-3/4 and Norfolk Southern gained 1/4 to 87-1/8. Conrail rose 3/8 to 113-3/4.</p>
<p>HBO &amp; Co. rallied 1-3/4 to 51-3/8 after the health care information company's first quarter earnings beat Wall Street estimates.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index lost 7.94 points to 1,249.43.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks fell 5.52 to 760.60. The American Stock Exchange index was up 1.56 to 562.98.</p>
<p>The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks fell 2.02 to 400.29. The average share was down 21 cents.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 7,268.605 down 37.144 or 0.51 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
