<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496988" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT rice ends choppy session mixed, old crop up.</title>
<headline>CBOT rice ends choppy session mixed, old crop up.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT rice futures ended a choppy session mixed with new crop months up on increasing spot demand, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;At $11.00 to $11.20 (per cwt), demand is beginning to show up,&quot; a floor trader said. &quot;We're finding good buying there and selling around $11.30.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders cited reports Costa Rica was tendering on April 30 for 26,500 tonnes optional origin long grain rough rice or 18,000 tonnes long grain milled rice.</p>
<p>Floor sources also noted Argentina has sold large quantities of rice and may not be able to sell much more.</p>
<p>&quot;Argentina's been our number one competitor lately,&quot; a trader said. &quot;When Brazil comes to them looking for rice, they may not have any left to sell.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders expected Thursday's USDA export sales report to show between 18,000 and 28,000 tonnes of rice sold.</p>
<p>New crop months closed lower but floor sources noted continued concerns wet weather in the U.S. south would delay rice plantings. &quot;The window for optimal planting is coming under some pressure here,&quot; a floor source said.</p>
<p>Rice ended five cents per cwt higher to four cents lower with May up one at $11.27-1/2.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated by CBOT at 400 lots, compared with Tuesday's actual volume of 325 lots.</p>
<p>((Emily Kaiser 312-408-8749))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
