<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="496919" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. says Russia-NATO deal still in works.</title>
<headline>U.S. says Russia-NATO deal still in works.</headline>
<byline>Carol Giacomo</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States said on Wednesday a NATO-Russia security deal has not yet been concluded and a spokesman appeared unaware of plans announced by Russia's foreign minister for a May 27 signing ceremony in Paris.</p>
<p>Asked about Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov's announcement in Paris earlier that Moscow hoped to sign such an agreement with the Western alliance in Paris on May 27, State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said:</p>
<p>&quot;I saw the same press reports. We'll just have to check with the Russians to verify what exactly...the foreign minister meant by those remarks.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We obviously want to get to the point where there is an agreement between Russia and NATO on a charter. I don't believe a final agreement has been reached on those charter negotiations. They continue and will continue,&quot; Burns added.</p>
<p>Another official said France had been pressing for a May 27 meeting in Paris but &quot;I don't believe it's finalised.&quot;</p>
<p>Primakov made his announcement after talks with French President Jacques Chirac. He said President Boris Yeltsin had accepted an invitation to come to Paris next month to sign an accord establishing a new, cooperative relationship between NATO and Russia, provided it is ready in time.</p>
<p>During a summit with President Bill Clinton in Helsinki last month, Yeltsin maintained Russia's strong opposition to NATO's plans to expand its membership into the former Warsaw Pact countries of eastern Europe.</p>
<p>But he agreed to work with the United States and the rest of NATO on a document designed to ensure cooperation between the alliance and Russia as a foundation of European security into the next century.</p>
<p>The document is to be signed by Yeltsin and leaders of the existing 16 NATO member states at a meeting before a planned July summit in Madrid when NATO will formally announce what new countries will be invited to join the alliance.</p>
<p>Poland, Hungary and the Czech republic are considered certain but Romania and Slovenia are also under consideration.</p>
<p>At a news briefing, Burns said he hoped there was progress made in Paris between the Russians and the French.</p>
<p>But he stressed that NATO Secretary General Javier Solana is leading these negotiations on a NATO-Russia charter and &quot;he will conclude them.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;So, we're hopeful about a charter. We want there to be a charter but I don't believe that NATO and Russia have agreed on the outlines of a charter deal,&quot; Burns said.</p>
<p>Solana will be in Washington on Thursday for a breakfast discussion with Albright on these subjects.</p>
<p>Also, Russian Deputy Foreign Minister Georgy Mamedov is in Washington this week for talks with Deputy Secretary of State Strobe Talbott, the administration's chief Russia policymaker, and other senior officials.</p>
<p>U.S. officials said these discussions have focused on NATO expansion, the proposed charter, the June summit in Denver of the Group of Seven industrialised nations plus Russia, arms control agreements decided in Helsinki and other issues.</p>
<p>Diplomats in Europe said the choice of Paris as a venue for the Russia-NATO summit strongly suggested the prospect of a &quot;grand deal&quot; in which France and the United States would also settle their dispute over the European role in a reformed Western alliance, enabling Paris to rejoin NATO's integrated military command 30 years after it withdrew.</p>
<p>But Burns said all of the disputed issues over the southern command were not yet resolved.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
