<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="497035" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US forests need 'active management'-House leaders.</title>
<headline>US forests need 'active management'-House leaders.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican leaders of the U.S. House embraced &quot;fact-based forestry laws&quot; Wednesday and welcomed a report that said active management of U.S. forests would bring more benefits than any other approach, including untouchable reserves or intense logging.</p>
<p>&quot;I would suggest our vision ought to be fact-based, integrated scientific management,&quot; Speaker Newt Gingrich said in urging the Agriculture and Resources committees to launch a new debate on forest policy.</p>
<p>One critic, the Western Ancient Forest Campaign, said the report hailed by Republicans &quot;is strongly biased toward timber production&quot; and came from a panel of scientists picked by a pro-logging lawmaker.</p>
<p>The ten-member panel concluded that &quot;integrated management&quot; would yield the greatest overall benefits to society and wildlife.</p>
<p>&quot;Only the value (of) 'reserve areas' is not well or moderately well preserved,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>By comparison, the report said current policy resulted in an accumulation of diseased or dead trees susceptible to massive wildfires, loss of habitat for species that rely on lightly wooded areas or savannas, and increased reliance on imported lumber or alternative construction materials like steel.</p>
<p>Panel members presented the report at a joint meeting of the Agriculture and Resources committees. The session was timed to allow Gingrich, Georgia Republican, to make an unusual appearance at a hearing to discuss the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact is we're entering a new era,&quot; Gingrich said before introducing and repeating his goal of &quot;fact-based, integrated scientific management&quot; to guide government.</p>
<p>Alaska Republican Don Young, chairman of the Resources Committee, said the report was the first step toward better forest management.</p>
<p>&quot;We aim to move away from rhetoric and towards fact-based forestry laws that allow management to improve the environment and give people a chance to work in the woods,&quot; Young said.</p>
<p>Agriculture chairman Bob Smith, Oregon Republican, said &quot;creative, active management&quot; was needed.</p>
<p>&quot;Reading this report, it's hard not to conclude that the present policy of large, unmanaged forest setasides is failing,&quot; Smith said.</p>
<p>There are 156 million acres in the national forest system of the Agriculture Department. The Interior Department has vast forest holdings as well.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
