<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49704" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - Argentine Calvo on &quot;real&quot; devaluation.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Argentine Calvo on &quot;real&quot; devaluation.</headline>
<byline>George Lerner</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina could give fresh energy to its sluggish economy by employing a &quot;real&quot; devaluation, which would boost import tarriffs and export subsidies without tampering with the exchange rate, an informal economic advisor to the Argentine government said.</p>
<p>Guillermo Calvo, who stepped down as a formal advisor in Argentina's economy ministry last week, told Reuters that policymakers had been receptive to the plan, but decided that such a remedy would not be required.  </p>
<p>&quot;We discussed the issue within the team, and we decided not to move in that direction now because we got strong signals from the market that the recovery was on its way.&quot;</p>
<p>A real devaluation would &quot;mimic&quot; a currency devaluation while leaving intact the vaunted Convertibility Plan, the cornerstone of Argentina's stabilization effort that pegs the peso to the U.S. dollar, Calvo said.</p>
<p>The plan would avoid spooking foreign investors because the value of Argentine assets would remain unchanged, as would the prices of domestic services, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;If a devaluation were to be called for, you can mimic that by this combination,&quot; Calvo said. &quot;It would help support convertibility and make it stronger.&quot;</p>
<p>Calvo said that the plan had technical complications, such as how to impose tarriffs and subsidize exports given Argentina's participation in Mercosur, the South American customs union.</p>
<p>The economy ministry opted against the &quot;real&quot; devaluation because of strong signals of recovery, but would reconsider the plan should the economy not gain momentum over the next few months, Calvo said.  </p>
<p>&quot;If they reach December and unemployment is still there and activity has not picked up, then we will start looking for options and this is a very sound one,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He described the plan as a temporary policy to be phased out after a year or so, adding that it should be replaced by more fundamental measures such as lowering labor costs.</p>
<p>He said that Economy Minister Roque Fernandez had listened to the plan and had not been &quot;negative&quot; about it, although other members of the economic team had expressed reservations.  </p>
<p>Calvo, who stepped down from his post as an advisor to the economy ministry last week, said he had needed to return to the United States and had no major disagreement with the team.</p>
<p>&quot;The position I took required me to be there all the time, which was something I could not commit myself to do,&quot; Calvo said. &quot;We continue a very close relationship.&quot;</p>
<p>Regarding the austerity measures before Congress, Calvo expressed concern that 14 Peronist deputies were among those who did not attend the lower house vote Wednesday night, thus denying the session quorum.  </p>
<p>&quot;That's a little worrisome, because it's more than just the opposition now,&quot; Calvo said. &quot;It's problems inside the Peronist party, which is what we fear the most. A collapse of the unity there is very hard to put together.&quot;</p>
<p>Calvo said the tax program was most significant as a symbol to foreign investors who the country would need to refinance large amounts of debt over the next year.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not so concerned for the deficit itself, but it may not be a good signal because it may be taken by foreign investors that Congress is not determined to help,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Argentina faces serious needs to finance its debt, with $4.4 billion of paper set to mature from now until year-end, and another $15 billion in 1997.</p>
<p>Calvo said he was worried that if Argentina did not show determination in moving toward fiscal balance, foreign investors might balk at refinancing, meaning that interest rates could skyrocket or that the country could land in a position comparable to Mexico's 1995 financial crisis.  </p>
<p>A good portion of the refinancing seemed likely to come though syndicated loans, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;I am pretty confident we should be able to refinance $7-$8 billion easily within the bank community,&quot; he said. &quot;That would be a shot in the arm.&quot;</p>
<p>The financial markets had seemed receptive to Argentine fiscal discipline, as evidenced by the Eurobonds placed last week, Calvo said.</p>
<p>-- 212 859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
