<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="497256" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France praises accord in Central Africa.</title>
<headline>France praises accord in Central Africa.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>France on Wednesday praised the appointment of two nominees of former army mutineers to government posts in the Central African Republic as part of reconciliation measures after a series of bloody army revolts.</p>
<p>&quot;France expresses its satisfaction at the conclusion between the Central African parties of an accord...that opens prospects for a peaceful solution to the crisis...&quot; the Foreign Ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>It urged the two sides to scupulously abide by the accord in order to take the country to reconciliation and recovery.</p>
<p>President Ange-Felix Patasse on Monday put former interior minister Lieutenant-Colonel Evariste Martial Konzale in charge of security and disarming civilians, and gave Brigadier-General Didas Ndayen, a former secretary of state for defence, the job of reorganising the army.</p>
<p>They will have the rank of minister-delegate.</p>
<p>The appointments followed talks between Patasse and leaders of troops who mutinied three times in less than a year.</p>
<p>French troops, in the country under a defence pact, restored order as the latest mutiny, which began in November, degenerated into ethnic bloodshed. They later handed over to African peacekeepers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
