<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49720" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYSE said to set Sept 17 cutoff for options bids.</title>
<headline>NYSE said to set Sept 17 cutoff for options bids.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) has set September 17 as the deadline for bids for its equity options business, industry sources said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The New York Stock Exchange wants final proposals on their desk by (next) Tuesday,&quot; a source at the American Stock Exchange (AMEX) said.</p>
<p>But a New York Stock Exchange spokesman was unable to confirm whether that date was the deadline.  </p>
<p>The four other U.S. options exchanges -- the Chicago Board Options Exchange, the Philadelphia Stock Exchange, the Pacific Stock Exchange and the AMEX -- have all expressed interest in the business, as has the New York Cotton Exchange.</p>
<p>As the deadline for final proposals draws near, speculation about which exchange would get the business increased a notch on Thursday, with the AMEX cited most commonly as the winner.</p>
<p>&quot;I hear the NYSE has all but done a deal with the AMEX,&quot; one industry source said.  </p>
<p>Another source said the AMEX had held or had scheduled a special meeting on the deal this week.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks to me like a done deal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The NYSE spokesman said he could not comment, but an AMEX spokesman denied the speculation.</p>
<p>&quot;We're submitting a proposal, we're very interested,&quot; an AMEX spokesman said. &quot;But I couldn't say we're close to a deal.&quot;  </p>
<p>On Wednesday, AMEX vice president of derivatives Joseph Stefanelli said in an interview with Reuters that the exchange would &quot;very shortly&quot; submit its proposal to the NYSE.</p>
<p>Stefanelli declined to say exactly when the proposal would be made or to disclose its financial terms.</p>
<p>He called the AMEX's bid &quot;very realistic and very competitive.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said speculation or not, the AMEX appeared to have the upper hand, especially because it is located just blocks from the NYSE in lower Manhattan.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the deal will be done with us,&quot; the AMEX source said. &quot;We're making a very competitive bid and people don't want to go from New York to, say, Chicago.&quot;</p>
<p>In the interview on Wednesday, Stefanelli said: &quot;The most important factor is to disrupt the lives of the current membership as little as possible. We're looking at bringing their membership to trade on our floor.&quot;</p>
<p>--Gregory Crawford, derivatives desk, (312) 408-8750</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
