<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="497332" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India rulers, Congress in talks to resolve crisis. [CORRECTED 13:15 GMT]</title>
<headline>India rulers, Congress in talks to resolve crisis. [CORRECTED 13:15 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Sabyasachi Mitra</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's ruling United Front coalition began talks with the rebellious Congress party on Wednesday to resolve an 11-day-old political crisis threatening the government's survival.</p>
<p>Witnesses said negotiations had begun at the New Delhi home of Farooq Abdullah, the chief minister of Jammu and Kashmir state. They said the coalition's negotiators had spoken to Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda ahead of the meeting.</p>
<p>News that the two sides were preparing for talks raised hopes they could resolve their differences before a vote of confidence in parliament set for Friday. The Bombay Stock Exchange's benchmark 30-share index surged 131.80 points, or 3.74 percent, to end at a provisional close of 3,652.29.</p>
<p>Congress party president Sitaram Kesri sparked the crisis on March 30 when he announced the withdrawal of his party's support, vital for Deve Gowda's minority centre-left coalition.</p>
<p>Kesri has demanded that the prime minister step down but the alliance has rejected the demand.</p>
<p>The coalition named a three-member panel for the talks, comprising Abdullah, Harkishan Singh Surjeet, general secretary of the Communist Party of India-Marxist and Andhra Pradesh state Chief Minister Chandrababu Naidu, United Front officials said.</p>
<p>Witnesses said Congress was represented by former ministers Sharad Pawar (corrects from Sharad Yadav) and Madhavrao Scindia, and leaders Jitendra Prasad and J.B. Patnaik.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not want to predict what will be the outcome. But I hope there will be some positive solution to some of the issues,&quot; the Press Trust of India (PTI) news agency quoted Deve Gowda as saying ahead of the talks.</p>
<p>Congress officials earlier said it would be at least a day before the situation cleared.</p>
<p>Deve Gowda, whose ten-month-old minority government faces its crucial test on Friday, said he hoped parliament would pass the 1997/98 (April-March) budget that day.</p>
<p>&quot;I even now expect and I hope that all political parties will cooperate to pass the finance bill and the budget pending before parliament on April 11,&quot; Deve Gowda said.</p>
<p>The budget, which would slash corporate and personal income tax rates, has been held hostage by the political uncertainty.</p>
<p>Kesri on Tuesday said he was willing to hold talks with the United Front, and wanted &quot;respect, not power&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;For stability, it is desirable that Congress has a say in governance,&quot; said a senior Congress leader, who asked not to be identified. &quot;The leader can be selected by consensus.&quot;</p>
<p>PTI quoted Deve Gowda as saying: &quot;The United Front has already decided that there will be no change in leadership. This issue is not negotiable.&quot;</p>
<p>But United Front spokesman Jaipal Reddy earlier on Wednesday declined to comment on the leadership question when asked if the coalition would agree to drop Deve Gowda.</p>
<p>The United Front lacks an outright majority in the lower house of parliament and depends on Congress to face down a challenge by the right-wing Hindu Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP).</p>
<p>The 15-member United Front has 180 deputies in the 545-seat lower house of parliament, the Lok Sabha, while the BJP and its allies have 193 and Congress 140.</p>
<p>Speculation has centred on a possible reconciliation between the United Front and Congress, neither of which wants snap elections that could strengthen the BJP.</p>
<p>But a United Front official said the alliance did not want Congress to enter the ruling coalition. Congress has supported the government without holding any cabinet portfolios.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
