<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="497306" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch shares end low-volume session higher.</title>
<headline>Dutch shares end low-volume session higher.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares ended a low-volume session more than one percent up on Wednesday, coasting higher on the back of a strong dollar and firm guilder bonds in the absence of any major corporate news or indicators.</p>
<p>The AEX blue chip index finished the day up 11.08 points or 1.52 percent higher at 738.69, helped mainly by gains in index heavyweights Royal Dutch, Philips and Unilever, dealers said.</p>
<p>Other component stocks were slightly higher across the board, except KLM, off O.90 guilders at 55.40.</p>
<p>KNP BT ended down 0.80 guilders at 39.10.</p>
<p>However, the paper and office equipment maker was trading ex a dividend of 0.85 guilders.</p>
<p>Dealers said KLM, which on Tuesday reported an improved load factor for the 1996/97 book year ended March 31, was being undermined by a single large seller.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a single big party operating on the sell side (in KLM) but there are very few buyers,&quot; one dealer said. &quot;When there's so little volume the share price can fall quite fast.&quot;</p>
<p>Philips' 1.10 guilder gain to 89.90 was underpinned by reasonable volumes, dealers said. The stock built on yesterday's gains following a broker upgrade from Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>The stock opened up 0.90 at 89.70 and traded around these levels all day, with a brief high of 90.70. Sentiment was also aided by the recent gains in high-tech stocks on Wall Street.</p>
<p>Royal Dutch added 4.70 guilders to 330.70, continuing its recent comeback on signals the oil price has bottomed out.</p>
<p>Among the smaller caps, electronics firm Getronics gained 1.20 guilders to 60.90 on rumours of a possible takeover by Philips or Cap Gemini, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I haven't heard anything to back up these rumours, though,&quot; one dealer added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
