<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="497354" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: U.N. agencies press on with Afghan polio campaign.</title>
<headline>U.N. agencies press on with Afghan polio campaign.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two U.N. agencies vowed to press ahead with a mass polio immunisation campaign in northwest Afghanistan, even though warring factions had broken a truce agreement there.</p>
<p>The immunisation would continue until April 10 despite renewed fighting in the area, said a joint statement by the United Nations children's fund UNICEF and the World Health Organisation (WHO).</p>
<p>The two agencies had secured the agreement of the Taleban Islamic movement and northern Uzbek chief General Abdul Rashid Dostum to a cessation of hostilities during the vaccination campaign from April 6 to 10.</p>
<p>But fighting broke out between their forces in Badghis province on April 6. &quot;This is a clear violation of the agreement reached with the major factions,&quot; the statement quoted UNICEF representative for Afghanistan Jim Mohan as saying.</p>
<p>He said the break in the ceasefire was most regrettable but &quot;in no way should this discourage us from continuing to support the enormous effort being made by thousands of Afghans working deligently to make sure that this campaign is a success.&quot;</p>
<p>More than 13,000 health workers and volunteers are working throughout Afghanistan to administer the polio vaccine after the United Nations raise some $1.8 million to implement the campaign, the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the right of all children to be immunised. The perpetrators of the current conflict should not be allowed to prevent innocent children from travelling to health centres to be vaccinated against polio,&quot; Mohan said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to work towards the goal of eradicating polio by the end of the decade, and I sincerely hope that we can persuade all sectors of Afghan society to support this aim, to lay down their arms and join the battle against this dreaded disease.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
