<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="497691" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Sluggish UK manufacturing shows skewed economy.</title>
<headline>Sluggish UK manufacturing shows skewed economy.</headline>
<byline>Rosemary Bennett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>UK manufacturing output edged up another notch in February, but it badly lags service sector output and the imbalance in the economy could worsen if monetary rather than fiscal policy is tightened after the election, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;What we have is a strong consumer sector and strong services with manufacturing barely crawling upwards,&quot; said Adam Cole, UK economist at James Capel.</p>
<p>&quot;What we need to see is tighter fiscal policy with interest rates held down, but it looks like we'll get the opposite. Policy is going badly astray.&quot;  </p>
<p>Manufacturing output grew 0.2 percent in February for year-on-year growth of 1.8 percent. This was unchanged from January's rate which was revised up to 1.8 percent from an initial estimate of 1.6 percent.</p>
<p>Manufacturers say that after being hit by slow economic growth overseas, exports are now suffering as a result of the pound's seven-month rally which has dampened demand for British goods abroad.</p>
<p>The pound has been driven up on expectations of higher UK interest rates and some economists say a rate rise, widely expected after the May 1 election, could drive it even higher.  </p>
<p>Even if the pound has peaked for now, most economists agree the worst of the impact has yet to be felt.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a little bit soon for the effect of the pound to be fully felt. We're looking at the end of the year for that,&quot; said Cole.</p>
<p>But in the meantime, very robust consumer spending will help counteract softer demand overseas.</p>
<p>&quot;The monthly and three month rises in manufacturing output suggest the strength of domestic demand is so far offsetting the impact of sterling,&quot; said Jonathan Loynes, UK economist at HSBC Markets.  </p>
<p>&quot;Note in particular the strength of durable goods in the breakdown which clearly reflects the strength of consumer spending.&quot;</p>
<p>Output of durable goods rose 2.7 percent in the three months to February, up from 1.9 percent in the three months to January.</p>
<p>Andrew Milligan, economist at General Accident, is more optimistic about the state of manufacturing, saying the soft export-related sectors are masking the real, and more promising, picture.</p>
<p>&quot;Textiles is the only area showing a decline. Sterling's strength and overseas competition are key factors there.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said the other key weak area -- chemicals and plastics -- has been hit by the slowdown in Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;Those aside most sectors are showing pretty strong growth, which ties in much better with the upturn in domestic demand we all know about.&quot;</p>
<p>But Loynes said output growth could slow again as the impact of sterling really hits home later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be no surprise to see output grow more slowly in the summer as the pound's rise starts to bite.&quot;</p>
<p>And while the main dampening effect on output will be from sterling, an interest rate rise will not help manufacturers.</p>
<p>&quot;That's why we'd recommend a fiscal rather than monetary tightening,&quot; said Loynes.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7715</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
