<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49765" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: &quot;Soccer moms&quot; new focus in U.S. presidential race.</title>
<headline>&quot;Soccer moms&quot; new focus in U.S. presidential race.</headline>
<byline>Randall Mikkelsen</byline>
<dateline>MARLTON, N.J. 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>In the 1996 U.S. presidential election, a fierce struggle is underway for the votes of &quot;soccer moms&quot; -- suburban women who are financially stressed and fighting to balance the demands of work and kids.</p>
<p>It's not clear who first coined the term &quot;soccer moms,&quot; but it has become the hot political catchphrase of the year.</p>
<p>Most seem to be leaning towards President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>They can be found in suburban parks and sports fields many evenings at this time of year, watching their sons and daughters play a game America is rapidly claiming as its own.</p>
<p>On a warm late-summer evening in this Philadelphia suburb, a half-dozen youth soccer games are underway in a field whose parking lot is jammed with minivans and four-wheel-drives -- the workhorse family vehicles of choice throughout America.</p>
<p>&quot;You've got me at a good time,&quot; said Debbie DiFilipo, a 38-year old nurse, sitting on a blanket and watching her daughters scamper after the ball. &quot;I'm stressed to the max. I'm overloaded today.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I got home 15 minutes ago. I threw dinner down the kids' throats. Got their homework out of the way. Fed the dog, fed the cat. I've got a son at another field and two daughters here,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Her politics?</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not going to vote for (Republican Bob) Dole,&quot; she said. &quot;I think he's old ... in a lot of ways.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Not that I think Clinton's a piece of cake,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Although the number of &quot;soccer moms&quot; is hard to pinpoint, said pollster John Zogby, &quot;we are focusing on that group because that's a group that under normal circumstances could go either Republican or Democrat.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Whoever wins that, kind of wins a medal for the year, if not the election,&quot; Zogby said.</p>
<p>In a Reuters survey conducted by Zogby in early August, Clinton held a 48 to 29 percent lead over Dole among women, and 51 to 22 points among working women. In the suburbs, Clinton led 42 points to 31 overall.</p>
<p>Compared to other voting blocs, suburban middle-class women tend to be more socially liberal and concerned with issues such as child care or parental leave. But their view of government activism often stops short of support for welfare programmes, Zogby said.</p>
<p>Marlton, in the southern end of the presidential battleground state of New Jersey, is a town of about 34,000 people, with a 1994 median household income of $57,000.</p>
<p>In 1992 election, it chose Republican incumbent George Bush over Clinton by 6,524 votes to 6,165, with independent Ross Perot drawing 3,264.</p>
<p>This year, DiFilipo's sentiments were echoed by several other Marlton mothers interviewed at the soccer matches.</p>
<p>Many were highly sceptical of Dole, citing his age of 73 and his emphasis on cutting taxes that many said was unrealistic or unrepresentative of their needs.</p>
<p>Some said Clinton seemed more in touch with their concerns, but they had their doubts about him too.</p>
<p>&quot;I voted for Clinton (in 1992), but I'm not that big a supporter of him either,&quot; said Lois McFadden, a 39-year-old court reporter and mother of three. &quot;I guess the economy hasn't come around well enough. The taxes haven't come down.&quot;</p>
<p>Neverthless, she said, she had ruled out voting for Dole, whom she described as &quot;too old and too right-wing.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole did have the support of Nina Gilbert, 45, a mother of two who said abortion is a key factor in her political decisions and who criticised Clinton's character.</p>
<p>&quot;I'll vote for anybody but Clinton, but probably Dole,&quot; Gilbert said, watching her daughter try out for a Catholic school team at a field down the street.</p>
<p>She also said she thought the Republicans should get credit for trying to wrestle with long-term economic problems such as old-age programmes.</p>
<p>Laura Olt, a 37-year-old secretary, said she had been impressed by enthusiasm shown at the Republican convention.</p>
<p>But she said she decided after viewing post-convention commercials that she would vote for Clinton, because Dole was too narrowly focused on cutting taxes.</p>
<p>&quot;We need somebody who's going to be helping take care of the kids -- child care, health care. And they (the Dole campaign) are pushing a tax cut,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Most of the soccer moms interviewed said they were unaware that they had become the political flavor of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;It's interesting to know they think we might matter,&quot; McFadden said &quot;God knows there are enough of us out here.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARLTON, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
