<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49775" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Yankee issuers stir calm US corporate primary mart.</title>
<headline>Yankee issuers stir calm US corporate primary mart.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A number of yankee debt offerings have stirred up activity in a relatively quiet corporate bond primary market as most domestic players remain on the sidelines, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's still no official calendar but some issuers are stepping in on any dips in Treasury yields to price debt,&quot; one syndicate source said.</p>
<p>Wednesday's yankee debt offerings were well received, dealers said. European Investment Bank's 10-year global bonds were seen trading firmly, where initially priced, at a spread of 17 basis points over Treasuries.  </p>
<p>&quot;EAB's issue came at a spread of 17 basis points and has held firm at that level,&quot; said one syndicate source.</p>
<p>So far on Thursday, Anixter International Inc priced $100 million seven-year notes to yield 135 basis points over Treasuries via Merrill Lynch &amp; Co, dealers said.</p>
<p>Comerica Inc is expected to price $150 million in A2/A rated 30-year subordinated debt via CS First Boston. Price talk on the issue is seen in the 85-87 basis points area, dealers said.</p>
<p>Among other names rumored to come to market are Wells Fargo and Co and NationsBank, sources added.  </p>
<p>In the private placement sector, United USN Inc is expected to set $155 million in eight-year 144A senior notes.</p>
<p>Also, First Nationwide Holdings is expected to price $525 million in seven-year senior subordinated 144A notes via Smith Barney.</p>
<p>In other yankee offerings, Australia &amp; New Zealand Banking Group Ltd priced $500 million in 10-year yankee subordinated notes to yield a spread of 64 basis points via Merrill Lynch &amp; Co.  </p>
<p>&quot;ANZ's 10-year deal was very successful,&quot; said one syndicate source. &quot;It was upped in size to $500 million from an initial size of $400 million to meet investor demand.&quot;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Tennessee Valley Authority priced DM 1.5 billion 10-year global bonds to yield a spread of 17 basis points.</p>
<p>TVA and EIB saved millions of dollars by avoiding the currency swap market on their huge global bond issues by enacting a direct, back-to-back swap agreement, dealers said.</p>
<p>TVA gave the mark proceeds of its deal to EIB in return for the bank's dollar proceeds. The two will also exchange interest payments on the bonds, dealers added.</p>
<p>--Nancy Leinfuss, 212-859-1675</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I84000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
