<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="497759" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Arafat's spokesman slams Congressman Gingrich.</title>
<headline>Arafat's spokesman slams Congressman Gingrich.</headline>
<dateline>GAZA 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat's spokesman on Wednesday slammed U.S. Congressman Newt Gingrich for saying Washington should pressure Palestinians and not Israel over a crisis in peace moves.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Gingrich will not be able to improve his bad image with the American people by attacking the Palestinian people and President Arafat in order to satisfy the Jewish lobby in the United States,&quot; spokesman Marwan Kanafani said in a statement about the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p>
<p>&quot;Gingrich did not show only a shameful ignorance of international politics but he also contributed to supporting the Israeli extremists to continue challenging the international community and to commit more violations against the political and human rights of the Palestinian people.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton said on Tuesday he believed there was a &quot;fairly decent chance&quot; of reviving peace talks between Israel and the Palestinians halted when Israel broke ground for a Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>There have been daily clashes between Israeli troops and Palestinians in the West Bank since the March 18 ground breaking for the 6,500-home development.</p>
<p>Clinton spoke a day after holding talks with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and ahead of talks expected later in the week with Palestinian representatives.</p>
<p>Gingrich on Tuesday accused Arafat of backing a &quot;terrorist&quot; campaign against Israel and urged Clinton to demand the Palestinian leader end the violence immediately.</p>
<p>&quot;How can the American government claim any possible sense of moral equality between a genuine democracy seeking peace at the risk of lives of its citizens and a force which after three years has refused to renounce its destruction of Israel?&quot; Gingrich said in a speech to an American Jewish lobby group, the American Israel Public Affairs Committee.</p>
<p>&quot;There should be no question of any pressure on the Israeli government to make any concessions until Arafat has met those demands ... and the burden should be placed by the American government on Arafat and the Palestinian Authority before a word is said to Israel,&quot; Gingrich said.</p>
<p>Palestinians say the East Jerusalem construction is designed to pre-empt negotiations on future control of that part of the city. Israel says the interim peace deal does not bar it from building and that it will continue to do so.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GAZA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
