<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="497856" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Factory trawler group drops Alaska tax challenge.</title>
<headline>Factory trawler group drops Alaska tax challenge.</headline>
<byline>Yereth Rosen</byline>
<dateline>ANCHORAGE, Alaska 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Operators of factory trawlers that operate off Alaska's coast have dropped their challenge to a state tax levied on fish harvested in federal waters, industry officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The American Factory Trawler Association, a Seattle-based organisation representing most U.S.-flagged vessels that catch North Pacific groundfish and process it at sea, said its members have abandoned their claim that the tax is unconstitutional.</p>
<p>Recent changes to the tax made it more palatable to factory trawler operators, Paul MacGregor, AFTA executive director said.</p>
<p>&quot;We never opposed paying a tax,&quot; he said. &quot;We thought that if the legislature came up with a fair tax that put us on a level playing field with the shoreside processors that are our competition, that was okay.&quot;</p>
<p>The association -- which has clashed with Alaska officials in the past -- was seeking smooth relations with the state, and dropping the tax challenge was part of that strategy, MacGregor said.</p>
<p>Factory trawler owners were also making efforts to hire more Alaska residents, increase partnerships with Alaska Native villages and reduce fishery waste, he said.</p>
<p>The tax was enacted by the state legislature in 1994 and imposes a 3.3 percent levy on processed seafood products shipped through state ports or transferred within state waters.</p>
<p>The trawler association sued in Alaska Superior Court in 1994 to block the tax. It argued that the state lacked constitutional authority to impose it because most of the taxed activities take place outside of Alaskan waters.</p>
<p>Fishing companies began paying the tax in 1995. Over $13 million in receipts have accrued and have been placed in escrow, awaiting resolution of the legal dispute.</p>
<p>Cities and the state have long taxed harvests of vessels operating in state waters, within three miles of shore, and the output of seafood plants located on shore.</p>
<p>The factory trawler fleet nets and processes Alaskan pollock, the nation's biggest commercial fish harvest, and other bottom-dwelling fish species, such as cod, rockfish and flatfish.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I03000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANCHORAGE, Alaska"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
