<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49795" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ex-Chemical Bank trader pleads guilty.</title>
<headline>Ex-Chemical Bank trader pleads guilty.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Victor Gomez, formerly Chemical Bank's principal trader in Mexican pesos, pleaded guilty on Thursday to making unauthorised trades that resulted in a $70 million loss to the bank in 1994.</p>
<p>Gomez, 35, pleaded guilty in federal court to a 13-count indictment charging him with bank fraud and making false entries in bank records.</p>
<p>He faces a possible maximum sentence of 30 years on each count and fines of $1 million on each count. U.S. District Judge Michael Mukasey set a sentencing date of Dec. 13.</p>
<p>Gomez had been arrested on March 20 by Scotland Yard at his home is Chesham, outside of London.</p>
<p>The indictment against him charged that in November and December 1994 Gomez took unauthorised positions in Mexican pesos exceeding $200 million. He admitting hiding the positions by entering fictitious offsetting trades into Chemical's computer systems.</p>
<p>The secret positions caused the bank to lose about $70 million when the peso was suddenly devalued on Dec. 20, 1994, and subsequently fell further.</p>
<p>In pleading guilty, Gomez said that he had intended for the trades to be profitable. &quot;At no time did I intend to victimise Chemical Bank,&quot; he told the judge.</p>
<p>Gomez's trading was discovered by the bank at the end of 1994 and it publicly announced the losses on Jan. 3, 1995.</p>
<p>Chemical Bank has since merged with Chase Manhattan Corp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
