<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="498086" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania signs letter of intent for IMF credits.</title>
<headline>Romania signs letter of intent for IMF credits.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Dascalu</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's new centrist government signed a letter of intent on Wednesday for the resumption of International Monetary Fund credits, a key element in underpinning its drive for market reforms.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Mircea Ciumara and Central Bank chief Mugur Isarescu signed the letter and turned it over to the IMF's chief negotiator for Romania.</p>
<p>The Fund's Board is to discuss restoration of credits to Romania, which were suspended last year while ex-communists were still in power, at a meeting later this month in Washington.</p>
<p>Neither side disclosed the contents of the letter. Government sources say Romania is seeking about $400 million in credits from the IMF and up to $600 million from the World Bank.</p>
<p>IMF negotiator Poul Thomsen said the government's reform programme, drawn up in February, was proceeding well. &quot;I'm encouraged in many respects by the main stabilisation achieved by the government,&quot; he told reporters after the signing ceremony.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased that the programme is on track and in some areas is doing better than (planned). Previous programmes have collapsed in months because of the lack of structural reforms.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said the Fund still wanted assurances that measures on restructuring or closing down inefficient industries and farms &quot;will be put in place within weeks&quot;.</p>
<p>He also said approval of an austerity budget, to be presented to parliament on Thursday, was vital to the programme's success.</p>
<p>The government introduced steep price increases on staple goods and utilities in February and earlier this week rushed to approve a law on proceeding with delayed bank privatisation.</p>
<p>The central bank has tightened monetary policy to restore confidence in the leu currency after removing restrictions on foreign exchange markets.</p>
<p>The 1997 budget calls for monthly inflation, which hit a 45-month peak of 18.8 percent in February, to be reduced to 2.2 percent by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The budget deficit, three times over target last year at 5.8 percent of gross domestic product, is to be pared to 4.5 percent this year.</p>
<p>On the eve of Wednesday's ceremony, centrist President Emil Constantinescu warned ministers against complacency.</p>
<p>State television showed him telling cabinet ministers and members of parliament that &quot;we are far from the point where we can relax in thinking that we have done our duty to the people who elected us&quot;.</p>
<p>Among the government's shortcomings so far, he said, were a delay in introducing a revenue-generated tax on oil products, slow approval on certain aspects of privatisation and a lack of action on reducing the overmanned civil service.</p>
<p>The IMF halted credits to Romania last year after the leftist government, thrown out of office by centrists last November, overshot spending targets and slapped curbs on foreign exchange markets.</p>
<p>Many Romanian and Western economists have said slow reforms and overspending by the ex-communists destabilised the economy and sent Romanian living standards plunging below those of other east European countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
