<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="498061" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania says plans to shut refineries due IMF.</title>
<headline>Romania says plans to shut refineries due IMF.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's government said on Wednesday it planned to close two oil refineries as part of moves to restructure loss-making industries, in line with suggestions made by the IMF for vital loans.</p>
<p>Romania is seeking about $400 million in credits from the IMF and up to $600 million from the World Bank.</p>
<p>A government statement said the big state  Petromidia SA refinery on the Black Sea coast and the smaller  Darmanesti SA refinery in eastern Romania had been included on the list of 10 loss-making companies which it planned to close.</p>
<p>The move is part of ambitious plans by the new centrist government headed by Prime Minister Victor Ciorbea to restructure various industries and make them profitable.</p>
<p>The statement gave no deadlines for their closure but sources in the sector said May 4 was a possible date.</p>
<p>Romania's 11 refineries inherited from the former communist regime have a processing capacity of 34 million tonnes a year, exceeding by far the country's needs. A closure of the two refineries would not affect the Balkan country, analysts say.</p>
<p>However, it appeared on Wednesday that the government project clashed with the interests of Petromidia's management.</p>
<p>Petromidia was built in the 1980s and is Romania's most modern refinery, with good access to export markets via the Black Sea. It is capable of running a variety of relatively heavy and sour crudes.</p>
<p>The news agency Mediafax quoted a Petromedia executive as saying the State Ownership Fund (FPS) had decided to privatise the refinery &quot;after it received letters from big strategic investors saying they are interested in Petromidia.&quot;</p>
<p>The FPS owns 70 percent stake in Petromidia.</p>
<p>&quot;The difficult financial situation of Petromedia is due to the system of pricing used in the past which prevented us from recouping losses,&quot; refinery director Gelu Patrahau said.</p>
<p>Disruptions in crude supplies also had been behind the refinery's failure to process profitably, he said.</p>
<p>Government officials were unavailable for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
