<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="498045" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: U.N. CALLS ON NIGERIAN GOVERNMENT TO HALT EXECUTIONS.</title>
<headline>U.N. CALLS ON NIGERIAN GOVERNMENT TO HALT EXECUTIONS.</headline>
<byline>Stephanie Nebehay</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two U.N. rights investigators, warning that the rule of law in Nigeria was on the verge of collapse, called on the military government on Wednesday to halt extra-judicial executions and arbitrary arrests by security forces.</p>
<p>In a scathing report to the U.N. Human Rights Commission, they called on Lagos to release and pardon political prisoners including those convicted in the 1995 trial of alleged &quot;coup plotters&quot;, including former head of state Olusegun Obasanjo.</p>
<p>Nigeria must allow the Supreme Court to hear an appeal by Chief Moshood Abiola, the presidential claimant jailed on treason charges since June 1994, according to Malaysian lawyer Param Cumaraswamy, U.N. rapporteur on the independence of judges and lawyers, and Senegal's Bacre Waly Ndiaye, U.N. rapporteur on extrajudicial or arbitrary executions.</p>
<p>The murder of Abiola's wife, Kudirat, in June 1996 should also be fully investigated, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears that under the military government of Nigeria today the rule of law is on the verge of collapse, if it has not already collapsed,&quot; their joint report said. &quot;Whether there is a Constitution left is debatable.</p>
<p>&quot;The Government of Nigeria must take effective measures to prevent extrajudicial, summary or arbitrary executions, as well as torture, ill-treatment and arbitrary arrest and detention, by members of the security forces,&quot; they added.</p>
<p>&quot;This situation is exacerbated by governmental lawlessness in the form of refusal by the military government and its agencies to obey court orders.&quot;</p>
<p>Some 70,000 people remain detained either upon conviction, remand or without trial, according to the U.N. investigators. Some 60 per cent await trial, and Abiola &quot;continues to languish&quot; in jail awaiting his appeal to be heard by the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>The U.N. investigators repeated that they had called off their mission to Nigeria in February after authorities denied them full access to detainees -- including those already tried.</p>
<p>They urged the 53-member forum to appoint a separate country rapporteur to closely scrutinise Nigeria -- Africa's most populous country. Their report was based on allegations from non-governmental organisations and a recent trip by an aide.</p>
<p>But Auwalu Yadudu, top legal adviser to Nigeria's military ruler, General Sani Abacha, took the floor at the U.N. Commission on Tuesday evening to defend his country's record.</p>
<p>Yadudu -- said by diplomats to &quot;call the shots&quot; on legal matters in Nigeria -- rejected allegations of summary executions, torture and arbitrary detentions as &quot;unfounded&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a matter of serious concern that events in Nigeria have been deliberately misrepresented and exaggerated,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Yadudu pledged that &quot;all suspects&quot; charged last month for alleged involvement with a spate of recent bombings in Nigeria -- who face the death penalty for treason -- would receive a public trial &quot;in full observance of due process of the law&quot;.</p>
<p>Rights groups fear that the 12 to 15 dissidents accused of treason -- who include exiled Nobel literature laureate Wole Soyinka -- will be tried by a special tribunal without a right to appeal in conditions like those of author Ken Sara Wiwa and eight Ogoni activists hanged amid an outcry in November 1995.</p>
<p>Along with Soyinka, others charged in absentia at a Lagos magistrate court were several exiled leaders of the opposition group the National Democratic Coalition (NADECO). The remaining 10 or so suspects are in detention.</p>
<p>Soyinka and other pro-democracy activists are fighting for Abacha's annulment of 1993 elections to be reversed and for Abiola, who took a commanding lead in that vote, to be freed and installed as president.</p>
<p>Abacha, who seized power in 1993 after previous army rulers aborted a plan to return Nigeria to civil rule, has promised that constitutional rule will start by October 1, 1998.</p>
<p>Yadudu also refuted the U.N. investigators' claim that authorities had not been ready to grant them full access to detainees in line with normal procedures for such missions. &quot;We are unable to accept any such account,&quot; he told the Commisssion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
