<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="498108" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - British business press - April 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - British business press - April 9.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>-- HALIFAX REVEALS PLANS TO KEEP SHAREHOLDERS</p>
<p>The Halifax has unveiled plans to try and keep its eight million shareholders after its conversion to a bank in June. The group expects about a fifth to sell their shares as soon as the largest building society comes to the market. Shareholders will be sent details of their choices and will be asked what they want to do with bonuses. However, the information does not tell them that the shares are counted as free by the Inland Revenue and do not count towards the annual Pep allowance.</p>
<p>-- CLOTHES DESIGNER TO FLOAT</p>
<p>American fashion house, Polo Ralph Lauren, is to become the latest designer company to file for a listing on the New York Stock Exchange. According to a filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission, Ralph Lauren plans a 600 million dollar floatation as the company and its existing shareholders sell off stock. The company will remain under control of the Lauren family, which holds all the B shares.</p>
<p>-- DIXONS LINKS UP WITH CELLNET</p>
<p>Electrical retailer Dixons has linked up with Cellnet, the mobile phone operator, as a partner for its communications offshoot by selling a 40 per cent stake in the business for 57 million stg. Cellnet is paying 25 million stg for its stake in The Link with further payments of 32 million stg tied to performance and expansion over the next five years. Market leader Vodafone will have difficulty finding space in the network of Link shops being developed by the partners.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>-- TESCO PULLS CLEAR OF J SAINSBURY</p>
<p>Tesco has overtaken J Sainsbury in group profits for the first time. In the 12 months to February 22 pre-tax profits rose to 750 million stg from 685 million stg a year ago. Shares in rival superstore groups Asda and Safeway were dragged higher in the wake of Tesco's shares rising 11 and a half pence. City worries about the fall in inflation were offset by reassurances about stable profit margins and Tesco continues to attack costs in the supply chain.</p>
<p>-- FREEMAN TO REJOIN SALOMON FROM EBRD</p>
<p>Vice-president of the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development, Ron Freeman, has resigned. He will take up a high- profile position at Salomon Brothers in London as the most senior executive in charge of European investment operations. The search for a successor to Freeman has been overshadowed by an internal dispute over the candidate's nationality. According to a verbal agreement between the bank's member countries, the first vice-president should be American.</p>
<p>-- BARINGS OFFER TO BE MADE SOON</p>
<p>Negotiations, brokered by the City Disputes Panel, about a compensation offer for thousands of Barings bondholders, who lost 275 million stg in the 1995 crash, are nearly complete. Any deal will need court approval. Those who will receive a payout include many elderly investors who bought into one or more of the three bond and loan note issues and the large life and pension funds, such as Legal and General and Scottish Amicable.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>-- BIG TIPPLE TAKES A TOPPLE</p>
<p>It has been revealed in a study by drinks industry research group Stats MR that sales of Allied Domecq produced Teacher's Scotch Whisky, the U.K.'s third-biggest U.K. Scotch brand, have collapsed by more than a quarter in the second half of last year. Allied Domecq said the fall was the result of a decision to hold the price of Teacher's and not get involved in the pre-Christmas discounting war.</p>
<p>-- PROFITS CLIMB AT UPBEAT TARMAC</p>
<p>Tarmac, the building materials group, have unveiled a higher than expected rise in profits. The group said it expected the U.K. construction industry to improve steadily during the year and 1998. Chief executive Neville Simms said that the commercial market was progressing well and that the strong economy meant that industrial spending was increasing and demand for new housing was picking up.</p>
<p>-- COMMERCIAL UNION THROWS IN LOT WITH OLD RIVAL AS IT BUYS INTO LLOYD'S MARKET</p>
<p>The U.K.'s biggest composite insurer, Commercial Union, has begun to do business in the Lloyd's of London insurance market. CU is paying 5.8 million stg for a 51 per cent stake in the Marlborough Underwriting Agency, which is owned by investment company Blenheim Partnership. CU's U.K. divisional director, Peter Rice, said that the long-term aim was to make Marlborough a major agency at Lloyd's.</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>-- WHEN THE BOSS'S DAUGHTER IS NOT ASSURED A JOB</p>
<p>Anthea Cudworth, the daughter of John Cudworth, the chairman of merged life assurance group United Assurance, has become one of the first victims of cutbacks which include 2,200 job losses. According to analysts, the departure of the chairman's daughter has caused some friction between the chairman and chief executive George Mack, whose decision it was to close her department. However, this is denied by the company.</p>
<p>-- HISTORY AS EDDIE HOMES IN FOR SHOW WITH KEN</p>
<p>U.K. monetary policy will be set outside central London for the first time. Eddie George and Treasury officials will travel to Rushcliffe, in the Midlands, to fit in with Chancellor Clarke's busy schedule. The meeting could be the last between Clarke and George if the Conservatives lose the next election. According to the City, Clarke will talk about the damage the strong pound is doing to exports and he will turn down George's advice to raise interest rates.</p>
<p>-- SCOTRAIL DEAL COULD BE FIRST TEST FOR LABOUR</p>
<p>If the Labour Party wins the forthcoming election its first test of competition policy will come from the proposed acquisition by National Express, the coach and rail group, of ScotRail, the train operator. No announcement was made by the DTI before Parliament was dissolved, leaving the next government to make a decision. The Labour administration may refer the deal to the MMC and Margaret Beckett, shadow President of the Board of Trade, will rule on the acquisition.</p>
<p>BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
