<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="498207" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Opposition sees Australian bank foreign ownership.</title>
<headline>Opposition sees Australian bank foreign ownership.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian opposition on Wednesday predicted significant foreign ownership of the banking system and also mergers between the big-four banks after the release of the Wallis report into Australia's financial system.</p>
<p>The Labor opposition was concerned about the Liberal-National government letting the two largest life insurance offices merge with the big banks, treasury spokesman Gareth Evans told reporters.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's clear that significant foreign ownership of banks is on the way,&quot; Evans said, shortly after Treasurer Peter Costello released the Wallis report on the financial system and announced some new policies.</p>
<p>&quot;Mergers between the big-four major banks are clearly only a matter of time,&quot; Evans said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a legitimate concern about the removal of restrictions on any of the big four merging with the two major life offices,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Earlier, Costello responded to the Financial System Inquiry, headed by businessman Stan Wallis, by abolishing the so-called six-pillars policy, which forbids mergers between the big-four banks and the two biggest life offices.</p>
<p>But Costello said he planned to retain his general discretion to veto bank mergers and acquisitions and said he would use it to ban combinations between the big four.</p>
<p>He would end the blanket ban on foreign takeovers of banks but would stand against large-scale foreign ownership of the system.  </p>
<p>The big-four are National Australian Bank Ltd, Commonwealth Bank of Australia Ltd, Westpac Banking Corp and Australia and New Zealand Banking Group. The two biggest life offices are the Australian Mutual Provident Society (AMP) and National Mutual Holdings Ltd.</p>
<p>Evans said the opposition would need to examine the report in greater detail before giving a more thorough response.</p>
<p>But he called for the government to immediately clarify its position on bank fees and charges, which are highly unpopular among consumers.  </p>
<p>Among the report's many recommendations was a suggestion that the government take responsibility for protection of banking consumers away from the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission, which was only recently formed by merging Australia's anti-monopolies and consumer watchdogs.</p>
<p>Evans said: &quot;There's real grounds for concern about the ACCC ... losing its consumer watchdog powers, which is particularly ominous in the light of the recommendation of the Wallis committee that banks and other financial institutions should be free to set fees and charges, quote, 'without government intervention or suasion'.&quot;  </p>
<p>Any legislation needed to back new government financial policies would have to survive the upper house of parliament, the Senate, where the government does not command a majority.</p>
<p>Labor policy could therefore help determine whether changes take place.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
