<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="498213" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Warehouse sees lower H2 operating profit.</title>
<headline>Warehouse sees lower H2 operating profit.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand discount retailer The Warehouse Ltd said on Wednesday it expected its operating profit in the second half year to be &quot;considerably less&quot; than that of the first six months to January 31.</p>
<p>The company announced a net profit of NZ$25.3 million for the period, and declared a dividend of 6.0 cents per share.</p>
<p>In a statement it said that, based on its trading performance and market conditions, the directors were confident of achieving a sound financial result for the full year.  </p>
<p>Warehouse said it generated about 60 percent of its total expected annual sales and a significant proportion of operating earnings in the first half due to seasonal factors -- with the second half profit seen lower as a result.</p>
<p>Its first half profit was up NZ$9 million, or 55.7 percent, on the $16.2 million achieved in the same year-ago period and even tops the $23.2 million reported for the year to March 31, 1996.</p>
<p>The Warehouse said group sales for the half year were up $45.3 million, or 14.9 percent, on the $304.6 million total for the same 1995/6 period and same-store sales rose 3.8 percent.  </p>
<p>Operating profit was 11.2 percent of sales, compared to 8.6 percent a year ago.</p>
<p>The company said its TUI information system operated accurately over the period, and the distribution centre computer system got up and running. Some observers had predicted teething difficulties with TUI would hit the result.</p>
<p>&quot;These systems provide the directors with comfort as to the competence and accuracy of information systems,&quot; the directors said, adding they envisaged further cost savings and efficiency improvements.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
