<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="498535" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy PM Prodi seen leaving President's palace.</title>
<headline>Italy PM Prodi seen leaving President's palace.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi went to see President Oscar Luigi Scalfaro on Wednesday as newspapers reported he was preparing to offer his resignation over a vote on an Italian-led security mission for Albania.</p>
<p>Witnesses said they saw Prodi leave the presidential palace. A security guard outside said he had seen the Prodi go in at 10 a.m. (0800 GMT). No further details were immediately available.  </p>
<p>Prodi's 11-month old administration has been thrown into chaos after a hard-left ally, which holds the balance of power in the Chamber of Deputies (lower house), refused to back the Albania operation.</p>
<p>The lower house was due to vote on the mission to Albania later on Wednesday, with Prodi now needing the support of the centre-right Freedom Alliance opposition bloc to get approval for the involvement of Italian troops.</p>
<p>The Freedom Alliance supports the operation, but has refused to vote for the government motion and instead called on Prodi's coalition to accept its own, similar resolution. It said it might support a joint motion if Prodi promised to tender his resignation.</p>
<p>Scalfaro, who is the supreme arbiter in Italian politics, would almost certainly ask Prodi to seek a vote of confidence in parliament if he offers to resign. The hard-left Communist Refoundation has indicated it would back the government in such a vote provided it was not tied to the Albania mission.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
