<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49873" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Ireland denies rumours EU summit will be scrapped.</title>
<headline>Ireland denies rumours EU summit will be scrapped.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Gaunt</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rumours circulated in European Union capitals on Thursday that a summit in Dublin next month to discuss the bloc's future would be cancelled because too few EU leaders want it.</p>
<p>Ireland, due to host the special summit as EU president, shot down talk of a cancellation, but diplomats in Brussels said the rumours reflected divisions within the bloc over the meeting's timing and usefulness.</p>
<p>&quot;The summit is going ahead, period,&quot; a spokesman of the Irish EU presidency said. Other Irish officials were at Dublin Castle, sizing up the venue for telephones.</p>
<p>Leaders are supposed to meet in Dublin on October 5 for informal talks on the progress of the EU's inter-governmental conference (IGC) -- negotiations on a new treaty to pave the way for new members from eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Formal talks have been under way since March, but critics charge that they have become bogged down, with countries reading out a series of wish lists.</p>
<p>Any notion that the IGC, due to run until mid-1997, will mark a significant step in Europe's political intergration has long gone. Officials say, however, the new treaty can still help prepare the bloc for a future with a dozen or more new members.</p>
<p>Such issues as the size of the European Commission, voting weights in decision-making and how to take effective foreign policy decisions are all on the table.</p>
<p>The special meeting was called for by EU leaders at their Florence summit at the suggestion of French President Jacques Chirac. It is to jump-start the talks and spur negotiators on to agree a draft treaty to be handed to EU leaders at another summit in Dublin, in December.</p>
<p>But diplomats said very few countries were keen on having a special summit without any real feel for what it would do. Ireland spent most of August trying to get its partners to accept a date -- settling on October 5 only last weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;The question of usefulness has been posed all along,&quot; one EU diplomat said. &quot;In Florence it was Chirac who was the only one pushing for it. Then (German Chancellor Helmut) Kohl added his voice.&quot;</p>
<p>The French and German foreign ministers are to meet in Paris on October 2 to discuss a joint approach to the summit.</p>
<p>Another diplomat said Britain, the Netherlands, Italy, and some of the bloc's Nordic countries were the most lukewarm to the summit. Ireland itself was less than enthusiastic.</p>
<p>&quot;Those dissatisfied with the way the treaty is being negotiated at the moment don't see the need for the summit,&quot; the diplomat said. &quot;Those who have publicly expressed the need for a quicker pace of negotation are more enthusiastic.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain, the country least keen on further EU political integration, has a special reason for disliking the October 5 summit. It comes just three days before the ruling Conservative Party, torn over Europe, holds its annual conference.</p>
<p>British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind has publicly questioned the usefulness of the summit, but a British spokeswoman in London said she knew of no plans for the Dublin meeting to be shelved.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
