<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="498735" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US corporate bonds firm, find solace in JC Penney.</title>
<headline>US corporate bonds firm, find solace in JC Penney.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. corporate bonds took solace in the successful placement of Wednesday's $2.5 billion J.C. Penney Co deal and spreads remained firm, dealers said.</p>
<p>All tranches of the J.C. Penney deal held firm or tightened marginally throughout the session with the exception of the $350 million 30-year debt, traders said. The 30-year bonds, priced to yield 120 basis points over the Treasury curve, widened to a 123 basis point spread.</p>
<p>But one trader suggested the 30-years were too tightly priced to begin with, and that the deal undeniably bolstered tone in a corporate market thirsting for direction.  </p>
<p>Reflecting a the strong bid for shorter paper, J.C. Penney's $700 million five-year notes were bid at 46 near the close, four basis points tighter than its original level.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is firm,&quot; one trader said. &quot;A lot of accounts were waiting to see how the deal would come and they were relieved. There is some depth to the market.&quot;</p>
<p>But even with the one-month backup in yield, the heady demand for corporates seen earlier this year has yet to be matched. Sentiments remain somewhat cautious ahead of U.S. inflation data on Friday and still-strong prospects for another short-term interest rate hike by summer, they said.  </p>
<p>In other high-grade action, Hilton Hotels Corp upsized and then priced $375 million 10-year 7.95 percent notes to yield 110 basis points over Treasuries.</p>
<p>The deal came on the wider side of price talk and included a coupon reset feature that would be triggered by a downgrade to speculative ratings. The notes are rated Baa1 by Moody's and BBB-plus by Standard &amp; Poor's, both ratings three notches above junk bond status.</p>
<p>The feature was used in response to uncertainty surrounding Hilton's outstanding hostile bid for ITT Corp.  </p>
<p>Also on Thursday, The Money Store Inc priced $300 million of debt in two-parts. A total of $175 million 8.05 percent five year notes were priced to yield 128 basis points over Treasuries and another $125 million 8.375 percent seven-year notes were priced at 150 basis points over.</p>
<p>CIT Group Holdings Inc issued $100 million investment grade three-year debt to yield 23 basis points over.</p>
<p>In the high-yield arena, several new issues priced, including the first German mark-denominated junk bond.  </p>
<p>Geberit International SA, a manufacturer of sanitary plumbing products, issued 157.5 million marks in 10-year global senior subordinated notes via lead manager Merrill Lynch at par to yield 10.125 percent.</p>
<p>Domestic junk deals featured $165 million 10-year senior notes from Syratech Corp priced at par to yield 11 percent via NationsBanc Capital Markets Inc and $75 million in 10-year senior notes from Tultex Corp priced at par to yield 9.625 percent via J.P. Morgan Securities.</p>
<p>Secondary talk was punctuated by three to four point losses for Stratosphere Corp's first mortgage notes following Grand Casinos announcement that it may abandon support of the troubled Las Vegas casino.</p>
<p>The debt was seen as low as 75 bid before closing off three points to 76 bid, 77 offer, one trader said.</p>
<p>((--Al Yoon, 212-859-1672))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
