<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="498931" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-NOVOTNA ADVANCES IN FLORIDA, CAPRIATI IS INJURED.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-NOVOTNA ADVANCES IN FLORIDA, CAPRIATI IS INJURED.</headline>
<dateline>AMELIA ISLAND, Florida 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top seed Jana</p>
<p>Novotna of Czech Republic won a 4-6 6-4 6-0 second-round match</p>
<p>at the Bausch &amp;Lomb Championships, and two prominent players</p>
<p>withdrew because of injuries on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Defending champion Irina Spirlea of Romania and Jennifer</p>
<p>Capriati of the U.S. were the latest players to be forced out</p>
<p>of the $450,000 tournament for health reasons.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Monica Seles withdrew with bronchitis and a</p>
<p>fever.</p>
<p>On the court, 16-year-old Venus Williams lost to Chanda</p>
<p>Rubin 6-4 6-0 in a 62-minute, second-round match.</p>
<p>Also winning second-round matches Wednesay were eighth</p>
<p>seed Iva Majoli of Croatia, ninth seed Mary Joe Fernandez of</p>
<p>the U.S., 11th seed Mary Pierce of France, 12th seed Amanda</p>
<p>Coetzer of South Africa and 13th seed Brenda Schultz-McCarthy</p>
<p>of the Netherlands.</p>
<p>A sprained right wrist forced the seventh seeded Spirlea</p>
<p>to withdraw. As a result wild-card entrant Marlene Weingartner</p>
<p>of Germany advanced to the third round.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year, it was my best tournament and this is my best</p>
<p>memory, being here,&quot; Spirlea said. &quot;I was saying to my coach</p>
<p>before coming here, how much I was really looking forward to</p>
<p>playing Amelia because after a few wins, being there feels</p>
<p>like it's home.&quot;</p>
<p>The 27th-ranked Capriati, who is not scheduled to play</p>
<p>again until Rome the first week in May, suffered a groin</p>
<p>injury and could not play in her scheduled match against lucky</p>
<p>loser Mariana Diaz Oliva.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very disappointing, it's a bummer,&quot; Capriati said.</p>
<p>&quot;I have to rest it at least for a few more days for it to</p>
<p>fully recover. I've been playing really well, so I felt I had</p>
<p>chances here.&quot;</p>
<p>At 4-4 in the first set, the fourth-ranked Novotna played</p>
<p>two tentative games to lose the set.</p>
<p>In the second set, Novotna went ahead 5-2 and was serving</p>
<p>for the set in the eighth game. She failed to take advantage</p>
<p>of five set points in the eighth game and had to wait until</p>
<p>serving in the 10th game to even the score at one set apiece.</p>
<p>Novotna played spectacular tennis in the third set, never</p>
<p>losing a game and winning 25 of the 36 points in the set.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt I was playing pretty good tennis even though I</p>
<p>lost the first set,&quot; Novotna said. &quot;I was serving big today.&quot;</p>
<p>The 30th-ranked Rubin and 102nd-ranked Williams played</p>
<p>each other close for the first eight games of the match.</p>
<p>That's when Rubin took over, winning the final eight games.</p>
<p>Rubin lost only six points in her final four service games.</p>
<p>At first, Rubin had difficulty dealing with Williams'</p>
<p>serve, but then she started to control the match by dictating</p>
<p>the points.</p>
<p>&quot;She has the power and she has the shots, but moving her</p>
<p>around the court definitely was to my advantage,&quot; Rubin said.</p>
<p>&quot;By the end of the first set, I was playing well and took her</p>
<p>out of her game.&quot;</p>
<p>Willams said of the loss, &quot;I don't thnk I did too much</p>
<p>wrong, it's just Chanda did everything right. She didn't give</p>
<p>me any opportunities back, she capitalised on everything.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMELIA ISLAND, Florida"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
