<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="498950" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: MOTOR RACING-VILLENEUVE OUT TO EXTEND WILLIAMS DOMINANCE.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-VILLENEUVE OUT TO EXTEND WILLIAMS DOMINANCE.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jacques Villeneuve has fond memories of last year's second place finish in the Argentine Grand Prix as he tries to strengthen Williams' grip on motor racing at this week's race.</p>
<p>The 25-year-old Canadian heads his team's assault at the Oscar Galvez circuit in Buenos Aires, sharing the lead of the world drivers' title race with Briton David Coulthard of McLaren.</p>
<p>Villeneuve finished second in Argentina last year behind then team-mate Damon Hill, who also won in 1995 and who went on last year to lift the world crown.</p>
<p>Villeneuve, the red-hot pre-season favourite, will draw on last year's experience at this week's event.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year, it was only my third Grand Prix race. But this year I'm looking forward to returning to Argentina with prior knowledge and experience of the circuit.</p>
<p>&quot;It was not a bad weekend there last year and the car was pretty good. So, I've got good memories.</p>
<p>&quot;The circuit is very modern. It is full of hairpins and chicanes so I think it is a great challenge. But this year's car is strong, very strong and the team are working very hard and well and I feel pretty confident. I must say a victory would be great&quot;</p>
<p>Villeneuve's confidence is not entirely shared by  team-mate Heinz-Harald Frentzen of Germany, yet to score a point this season. Last Friday he flew to England to attend critical talks at team headquarters aimed at resolving his early-season problems with the set up of his car.</p>
<p>&quot;Without doubt, I am hoping to be in a better position in Argentina than I was in Brazil,&quot; he said after long talks with his engineers. &quot;It just didn't seem to come together for me there.</p>
<p>&quot;But I am confident about finding a good set-up in Argentina. I like the circuit at Buenos Aires, it reminds me of a go-kart track.&quot;</p>
<p>The tight, twisty and relatively small circuit was criticised last year for being too bumpy for Grand Prix cars but is believed to have been resurfaced since.</p>
<p>However, it is rarely used for racing and is expected to be a low-grip track which could require the cars to run with high downforce levels.</p>
<p>This may upset the established order and offer the Bridgestone tyre company, newly-arrived rivals to Goodyear, a chance to steal a march with the Arrows and Prost teams. In Sao Paulo, the Bridgestone-shod Prost of Oliver Panis finished third and a repeat performance could be delivered.</p>
<p>Villeneuve's chief challenge, however, is likely to come from the rapidly-improving Benetton team and in particular Frenchman Jean Alesi.</p>
<p>Alesi tested at Silverstone last week and the team will have a new front suspension system in Argentina.</p>
<p>Team-mate Gerhard Berger of Austria, second behind Villeneuve in Brazil, will also be strong despite the distractions of his father being imprisoned for fraud - unrelated to motor racing - and the birth in Lisbon last week of his third daughter.</p>
<p>The Ferrari and McLaren teams should also be reliable and quick with Michael Schumacher in particular likely to shine.</p>
<p>But it will be a difficult weekend for the new Stewart team, making their first visit to the track, and for Jordan with their two inexperienced drivers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
