<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="498960" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-GREENS, PIN PLACEMENTS MAKE FOR MASTERS MISERY FOR MANY.</title>
<headline>GOLF-GREENS, PIN PLACEMENTS MAKE FOR MASTERS MISERY FOR MANY.</headline>
<byline>Larry Fine</byline>
<dateline>AUGUSTA, Georgia 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Furiously fast greens, fiendish pin placements and brutal breezes combined to make Masters misery for many in Thursday's opening round at Augusta National Golf Club.</p>
<p>Birdies were scarce but double and triple bogeys were plentiful as the 86-man field for the season's first major championship struggled to survive.</p>
<p>&quot;Every shot was a potential disaster. Every putt was a potential disaster,&quot; said Briton Colin Montgomerie, who managed to shoot even-par 72 to stay within range of the lead.</p>
<p>&quot;It was probably the hardest front nine holes I'll ever play because of the greens and the pin placements,&quot; said Montgomerie, the European tour's leading money winner the last four years. The Briton shot 34 on the back nine to overcome his two-over 38 on the first nine.</p>
<p>Loren Roberts, one of the U.S. tour's best putters, shot 85. U.S. Open champion Steve Jones posted an 82. Ken Green recorded an 87.</p>
<p>&quot;I was kind of shell shocked. I've never seen pins like this,&quot; said Roberts, who lost the 1994 U.S. Open crown in a playoff. &quot;On a couples of holes, you had no chance.&quot;</p>
<p>Roberts, who had three sevens on his card, said: &quot;It was the worst round in competition I ever had.&quot;</p>
<p>Things worked out better for Fred Couples, the 1992 Masters champion. But he was still spooked by conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;The greens are like concrete. The pins were borderline suspect. If the weather stays like this, over par could win,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>U.S. tour veteran John Cook was one of the unfortunate early starters who played in bone-chilling temperatures.</p>
<p>&quot;The greens are rock hard and the pins are on a slant. this morning it was 45 degrees (7 C.) and the wind was blowing 20 miles an hour (32 kph),&quot; Cook said.</p>
<p>&quot;Go out and look at the first hole, the green's blue,&quot; he said, kidding about the cold start to the day.</p>
<p>Temperatures warmed and the wind calmed down somewhat as the day wore on, but the greens got bumpier and later starters found little comfort on the testing layout.</p>
<p>&quot;That's by far the toughest I've ever seen the course play without some strong wind or unusual conditions,&quot; said 1993 U.S. Open champion Lee Janzen.</p>
<p>Wind and dry weather ensured that the speed of Augusta's notoriously sloped greens would remain fast, leaving the players to call on divine intervention to soften them up.</p>
<p>&quot;If the weather stays the same it's only going to get worse,&quot; said Montgomerie. &quot;If Mother Nature doesn't help us out over par might well win. We need some help from above.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUGUSTA, Georgia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
