<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499025" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLAND HEADING FOR A $12 BLN TRADE GAP IN 1997.</title>
<headline>POLAND HEADING FOR A $12 BLN TRADE GAP IN 1997.</headline>
<byline>Jan Strupczewski</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish exports growth remained well behind imports growth in February with no signs of a trend change, putting the economy on a fast track to a more than $12 billion trade deficit in 1997, analysts said.</p>
<p>The current account gap widened by $233 million in February to $1.13 billion while the trade deficit increased by $706 million to $2.18 billion. Poland's trade deficit in 1996 was $8.15 billion and currenct account gap was $1.35 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The exports growth in February is still four times smaller than imports and this is worrying, especially with the steep fall of inflows from cross-border trade,&quot; said Tadeusz Chroscicki, chief analyst at the Centre for Strategic Studies.</p>
<p>Exports in January-February were 8.6 percent higher than in the same period of 1996 while imports were 31.0 percent higher.</p>
<p>The unclassified flows, comprising mostly cross-border trade, fell to $793 million in the January-February period from $1.21 billion in the same period of last year.</p>
<p>Analysts were concerned the current account gap for the first two months of the year has already reached levels for the whole of 1996 but some said this could be partly caused by importers postponing many 1996 deals until January, to pay lower border tax introduced this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The current account gap now is as big as for the whole of 1996, so a $12 billion trade gap this year is likely,&quot; said Krzysztof Rybinski, chief economist at ING Bank in Warsaw.</p>
<p>The 1997 budget assumes a $9.5 billion trade deficit.</p>
<p>Analysts said the uninspiring trade data was likely to further delay a potential cut in the monthly crawling peg devaluation rate of the zloty against a basket of five currencies, now at one percent.</p>
<p>&quot;One should not expect a cut in the crawling peg in the next months for sure,&quot; Rybinski said.</p>
<p>But analysts were unanimous that although Poland should do everything to stimulate its exports, a one-off devaluation of the zloty was out of question as an export-boosting measure.</p>
<p>&quot;God forbid a zloty devluation, it is a measure which does not solve anything in the long run,&quot; said CSS's Chroscicki.</p>
<p>Analysts said that high real interest rates kept by the central bank to cool domestic demand and therefore imports, were not enough to improve the trade balance.</p>
<p>&quot;We can cool domestic demand for imports but in the longer term the stimulation of exports is the key,&quot; said Krzysztof Bledowski, chief economist at WoodCommerz in Warsaw.</p>
<p>Analysts also said Poland's current account gap, seen at 3.5 percent of the gross domestic product or $4-5 billion this year against one percent of GDP last year, was still very small for a developing economy.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not worry about the deficit too much because the imports structure is good -- mostly investment -- which will bring higher productivity and competitiveness of exports later,&quot; said Andrzej Burliga, analyst at Bank Zachodni SA.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
