<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499111" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: DHL sees growth in UK import market share.</title>
<headline>DHL sees growth in UK import market share.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>DHL Worldwide Express forecast it will raise its share of an estimated annual 100 million stg UK import express market to seven percent by end-1997 and 40 percent within a decade, from four percent now.</p>
<p>The express parcels giant formed an 'Import Express' unit in Britain a year ago and UK managing director Nick Butcher said it had so far won 700 regular clients, including Umbro, SmithKline Beecham Plc and Kellogs.</p>
<p>He told a news briefing here that by the end of this year, DHL expected to have 48 originating countries involved in UK express imports, compared to 38 at present, to be covered by DHL services.</p>
<p>Added UK 'Import Express' product manager Chris Wright: &quot;We have taken a relatively low-key approach because we wanted to grow at a rate we were comfortable with.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we are going to step up the pace of expansion quite considerably and are working towards adding the Middle East, India, Pakistan and China to the service by the end of this year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>DHL said it bases its 100 million stg per year valuation on what it described as the &quot;accessible market&quot;, covering all shipment inbound to the UK, by road or air, up to 50 kg per piece and 250 kg per total shipment. --Reuters Air Cargo Newsroom Tel +44 171 542 7706; Fax +5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
