<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499363" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech cenbank lowers minimum reserve requirement.</title>
<headline>Czech cenbank lowers minimum reserve requirement.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech National Bank's (CNB) governing board on Thursday agreed to lower commercial banks' minimum reserve requirement to 9.5 percent from 11.5 percent, the central bank's press office said.  </p>
<p>&quot;On the basis of the favourable development of the monetary indicators, above all money supply and the rate of inflation, the banking board decided to lower the basic rate of compulsory minimum reserves of banks from the current 11.5 percent to 9.5 percent, effective May 8, 1997,&quot; it said it a statement.</p>
<p>It added that the central bank &quot;expected&quot; the move to lead to higher deposit rates for clients.</p>
<p>&quot;The (CNB) board stated that it confirmed the urgency of the basic problems of the economy which the CNB has been pointing out in recent months,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The statement added that there was a &quot;continuing imbalance in external relations caused by excessive wage growth, the trend of the state budget toward a deficit and shortcomings in the micro (economic) sphere.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;These facts can undermine sustaining the desirable pace of economic growth and require a relevant reaction in economic policy which the government is preparing,&quot; it added.  </p>
<p>The crown fluctuated on Thursday ahead of the central bank statement as nervous dealers questioned whether the central bank would lower interest rates and reduce the spread against other major currencies which has made crown investments attractive and forced the currency to strengthen.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus and other government ministers have been critical of the central bank's moves last June to tighten monetary policy, when it raised its key discount rate one full percentage point to 10.5 percent while raising the minimum reserve requirement to 11.5 percent from 8.5.</p>
<p>Klaus has said the resulting slowdown in inflation has not been worth the price of a weakening in economic growth.</p>
<p>Earlier the Czech news agency quoted CTK quoted Finance Minister Ivan Kocarnik as saying that government ministers had agreed in a late night meeting on Wednesday to coordinate key monetary policy decisions.</p>
<p>The comment sparked speculation that a rate cut might be coming, but the central bank left its interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 420-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
