<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="49934" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Who will design for Dior?.</title>
<headline>Who will design for Dior?.</headline>
<byline>Lee Yanowitch</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Christian Dior, one of France's most legendary fashion houses, kept the industry guessing on Thursday over its choice of a new designer, but it looked like it would be Britain's John Galliano.</p>
<p>&quot;John has a strong chance of being offered the job,&quot; a Galliano spokeswoman told Reuters. &quot;Nothing is official.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked whether Galliano would accept the job if it were offered to him, she told Reuters: &quot;Yes, I think so. It would be an incredible opportunity.&quot;</p>
<p>Rumours have swept the Paris fashion crowd since the house announced in July that Italian designer Gianfranco Ferre was leaving after nine years.</p>
<p>Galliano was appointed barely a year ago at Givenchy, which is owned by the same firm as Dior, luxury giant LVMH Moet Hennessy Louis Vuitton.</p>
<p>The hip and romantic son of a plumber has successfully turned Givenchy's prim, ladylike fashions into wild, intricate and sexy clothing sought by supermodels and screen stars alike.</p>
<p>If Galliano left Givenchy, where he now produces four collections a year as well as his own ready-to-wear line, that firm would have to begin its own search for a new designer.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to me it would be impossible to design for three houses, it's too many collections a year,&quot; the Galliano spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>The ultimate decision is up to LVMH chairman Bernard Arnault who chose Galliano for the position at Givenchy.</p>
<p>The name of a replacement will be made public between now and October's ready-to-wear shows, when Ferre presents his final collection for Dior. But in the frenetic run-up to an announcement, every trendy, inventive designer has been mentioned as a possibility.</p>
<p>Media reports that Arnault met U.S. designer Marc Jacobs twice in Paris in June sent tongues wagging that he would be the lucky man.</p>
<p>A Dior spokeswoman on Thursday confirmed the meetings but would only say: &quot;When you're looking for someone, you meet people.&quot;</p>
<p>The only person who has categorically denied being interested in the job is Vivienne Westwood, who figured in rumours throughout August. A former school teacher credited with inventing punk, Westwood said she was flattered by the hearsay but dismissed it out of hand.</p>
<p>The choice of either Galliano or Westwood, both madly inventive, would be consistent with Arnault's desire to have the most talented of the fashion pack in his empire.</p>
<p>It was he who recognised the talent of Christian Lacroix -- the current star of haute couture along with Galliano -- and put up the money to open his fashion house.</p>
<p>The Dior job is not a small one. Whoever gets it will design the four yearly fashion collections which, while only a small part of the firm's sales, give all its other products -- watches, perfumes, pocket books, eyeliner and panty hose -- the brand image that makes them sell.</p>
<p>The French may grudgingly admit that Britain, Italy and New York are gaining on Paris fashion, but the idea of a foreigner leading one of the most &quot;French&quot; of the French fashion houses has stirred up anti-British sentiment among some chauvinists.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFAS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
