<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499415" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Speculation raises Croatian stocks before polls.</title>
<headline>Speculation raises Croatian stocks before polls.</headline>
<byline>Davor Huic</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatia's dormant stock market has awoken just before regional elections set for Sunday, buoyed by one bank's results and speculation by local brokers that the ruling party will retain power.</p>
<p>After a short but powerful bull run in January, the market stabilised and saw lazy trading on stagnant prices in the past few weeks.</p>
<p>Dealers and analysts blamed the lull on pending elections for county and municipal governments and parliament's upper House of Counties.</p>
<p>It will be the first time since 1990 that minority Serbs from Eastern Slavonia, who rebelled against Croatia's independence in 1991, will take part in a Croatian election.</p>
<p>The area, now patrolled by 5,000 U.N. soldiers, is to be reintegrated with the rest of the country in mid-July. But many Serbs do not like the plan and it remains unclear how many will take part in the election and how many will leave afterwards.</p>
<p>Foreign investors have avoided buying in Croatia of late, swayed by reports that the ruling Croatian Democratic Union (HDZ) will fare badly in the polls while fearing possible transitional problems in Eastern Slavonia, dealers said.</p>
<p>Independent opinion polls have shown the popularity of the conservative nationalist HDZ, led by charismatic 74-year-old President Franjo Tudjman, slipping to between 25 and 35 percent in most districts over the past three years.</p>
<p>&quot;What foreign investors prefer is stability, a status quo, and any hint of a possible change in government can scare them away,&quot; one Croatian dealer said.</p>
<p>But contrary to expectations, the first two trading days of the week saw some brisk activity and on Wednesday the gainers outnumbered the losers 15 to one.</p>
<p>This was partly due to a sharp rise, both in London and Zagreb, of the leading commercial bank, Zagrebacka, which on Tuesday received its first ever credit rating and released better-than-expected 1996 business results.</p>
<p>Another factor is that most market participants believe the opposition -- three large and a dozen smaller parties -- will not be able to influence the main outlines of Croatian economic policy even if it does well in the elections.</p>
<p>Zagrebacka traded well above its all-time high on Wednesday, reaching 2,080 kuna per share in Zagreb and $35 per one Global Depository Receipts, issued 10 for each share, at Seaq International in London.</p>
<p>Other issues followed, including blue-chip drug firm Pliva, food concern Podravka, chocolate maker Kras, some tourist firms and the small but respected private bank Varazdinska.</p>
<p>&quot;Many good stocks have reached their lows and some investors obviously thought this was a good time to buy despite the risks implicit in the elections,&quot; said Zoran Ilic of Consult Invest brokerage.</p>
<p>One trader who spoke on condition of anonymity said the most active players on the market were the brokerage houses themselves, who are buying now, speculating that prices would go up after the elections.</p>
<p>&quot;The general feeling among traders is that nothing much will change after the elections, and that the stock market will recover pretty soon,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever happens, it will not have an immediate effect on the stock market -- these elections will be an indicator as to what will happen in one or two years,&quot; the trader said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
