<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499537" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: World must not pressure Israel - Peres.</title>
<headline>World must not pressure Israel - Peres.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO, Chile 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli former Prime Minister Shimon Peres on Thursday rejected international pressure on countries involved in the Middle East peace process, saying it was an internal issue for those nations.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically I believe that peace cannot be imposed from outside. It must be decided within countries themselves,&quot; Peres told reporters after meeting Chilean Vice President Carlos Figueroa at the Moneda presidential palace.</p>
<p>&quot;The world must not pressure Israel. But at the same time I believe that within my country we have to try all possibilities for returning to the path of peace.&quot;</p>
<p>Peres, a Nobel Peace Prize winner and an author of the peace accord with the PLO, was speaking on the first day of a two-day visit to Chile. Arriving in Santiago late on Wednesday, he lashed out at his successor Benjamin Netanyahu, accusing him of breaking his promises to end terrorism and bring peace to the region.</p>
<p>&quot;The promises and announcements which Netanyahu made before being elected have not stood the test of time,&quot; he said. &quot;He promised there would be peace at a low price, that terrorism would be eliminated ... and that he would maintain the union of Jerusalem. None of these promises have been fulfilled.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked about Netanyahu's decision to build Jewish housing in Jerusalem's east sector, Peres said: &quot;We have the right to build in Jerusalem but we do not have the obligation to stop being wise.The problem is not so much the construction as much as the need to sit down with the Palestinians to reach an agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>The Labour Party leader, who was invited to Chile by local socialist parties, was due to travel on Thursday to Valparaiso to unveil a mural in homage of assassinated Israeli Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin. He was to fly to Brazil later.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO, Chile"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
