<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499518" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine stocks close lower, await U.S. data.</title>
<headline>Argentine stocks close lower, await U.S. data.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine stocks continued their downward drift Thursday in slow trading and braced for Friday's U.S. inflation data, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we followed through on the week's negative tone, with a lot of apathy because the outlook isn't clear in the United States or in Brazil,&quot; said Dario Lizzano, head of research at Santander Investments, referring to U.S. interest rate concerns and Brazil's fiscal woes.</p>
<p>The blue-chip MerVal index  .MERV, however, pulled off a session floor of 700.49 in late trading and closed at 705.91, with a 1.0 percent loss.  </p>
<p>Floor volume remained extremely weak at 16.9 million pesos against 14.7 million Wednesday, while over-the-counter turnover shrank to 90.4 million pesos from 130.3 million Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Institutional investors are stuck on the sidelines and therefore the market is moving in tight bands set by speculators,&quot; Lizzano saud.</p>
<p>Traders said the U.S. producer price index could help establish a clearer trend on the markets.</p>
<p>&quot;We may go up or down depending on the outcome, but we're likely to see stronger volume,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>The broad market index closed off 0.5 percent, with losers pounding winners 42 to five and 12 issues closing flat.</p>
<p>Heaviest main-tier decliners were holding company Comercial del Plata, Banco Frances and construction stock Polledo, down 3.4 percent, 2.9 percent and 2.8 percent, respectively. Banco Frances was initiated as a &quot;buy&quot; near the close by UBS Securities.</p>
<p>The only MerVal risers were foods giant Molinos, Telefonica and power utility Central Costanera, which firmed 0.8 percent, 0.7 percent and 0.3 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>((-- Carmen Pignotti, Buenos Aires Newsroom 541 318-0657))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
