<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499710" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Patten valedictory lauds UK tycoons for HK success.</title>
<headline>Patten valedictory lauds UK tycoons for HK success.</headline>
<byline>Kenneth Barry</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong Governor Chris Patten on Thursday made the first of many farewell speeches in the run-up to the colony's handover, telling Britain's business elite they shared the credit for Hong Kong's economic miracle.</p>
<p>Patten was honoured at a farewell luncheon by the British Chamber of Commerce in Hong Kong whose companies' stock market capitalisation is worth a combined HK$70 billion ($9 billion).</p>
<p>Britain's 28th and last colonial governor, who hands the reins in Hong Kong back to China at midnight on June 30, said a big reason for the territory's five percent annual growth rate was the &quot;entrepreneurial spirit and hard work of the Chinese people&quot;.</p>
<p>But he also told the executives, whose trader-forebears had urged Britain to seize the colony from China more than 150 years ago, that they had brought the rule of law, and civil and social infrastructure to Hong Kong.</p>
<p>&quot;You are part of the reason for Hong Kong's success story story and I am absolutely confident in future you will continue to be a crucial part of that success,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Patten, who has kept Hong Kong's income tax rate among the world's lowest at a flat 15 percent and whose vigorous free-market philosophy appeals to the business community, received warm applause from the 250 executives at the lunch.</p>
<p>Patten, chosen as governor by fellow Conservative and Prime Minister John Major five years ago, has crossed swords with Chinese leaders recently over their plans to undo democratic political reforms introduced during his term, after the handover.</p>
<p>But in his speech Patten avoided direct mention of differences over issues such as Beijing's plan to curb civil liberties in Hong Kong. He praised Chinese leaders' skills at guiding economic policies that have helped Hong Kong thrive.</p>
<p>&quot;Much of what happens to Hong Kong depends on whether China sustains the enormously important success of opening its economy. The skill with which this process has been handled so far holds out some hope,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>China resolved in February to repeal several existing Hong Kong laws protecting civil liberties and political rights, a move that was attacked by Britain, some of its allies and the territory's democracy groups.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's future leader, Tung Chee-hwa this week launched plans to curb public demonstrations and foreign funding for political groups after the handover.</p>
<p>However, Patten said even when sovereignty over Hong Kong rested in Britain, the territory was actually run by those in Hong Kong, and he said his biggest hope was that &quot;that degree of autonomy continue in the future&quot;.</p>
<p>Under Sino-British agreements, the territory of 6.4 million people has been guaranteed a high degree of autonomy for 50 years after the handover.</p>
<p>Patten said the greatest lesson that Hong Kong could offer the economies of the West, hampered by slow growth and political cynicism was its enthusiasm.</p>
<p>In Hong Kong, he added, it was exciting that &quot;people in every walk of life think they can make things better for themselves through their own efforts&quot;.</p>
<p>($1 = HK$7.74)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
