<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499746" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: BOJ poised to seize chance to sell dollar - traders.</title>
<headline>BOJ poised to seize chance to sell dollar - traders.</headline>
<byline>Yoshiko Mori</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Japan (BOJ) is poised to seize a good opportunity for dollar-selling intervention if the dollar jumps again to above 127 yen, senior traders in Tokyo said.</p>
<p>At the same time, policy-makers are warning market participants that if they continue to push up the U.S. currency they may get their fingers burnt, they said.</p>
<p>The dollar hit a fresh high of 127.16 yen in early Tokyo trading on Thursday, its highest level since August 1992.</p>
<p>&quot;We're sitting on a time bomb,&quot; said a city bank trader.</p>
<p>He said Japan has the world's largest &quot;war chest&quot;, referring to its external reserves of $219.357 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The possibility of intervention is very strong when the dollar next recovers to over 127 yen, given escalating irritation of monetary authorities perceived by the market,&quot; said Shinichiro Maruyama, head of spot trading in the Industrial Bank of Japan's international treasury department.</p>
<p>Traders said both the BOJ and the Ministry of Finance (MOF) have stepped up the frequency of inquiries at commercial banks in the past few weeks to check the forces in the market and also to see who are the dollar buyers behind the rally.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka, in a speech to bank executives on Thursday, said the yen's recent fall against the dollar had been excessive and that Japan would deal &quot;decisively&quot; with any such excessive moves.</p>
<p>Senior MOF official Eisuke Sakakibara also said on Thursday that intervention in foreign exchange markets by Japanese authorities is possible if exchange rates deviate greatly from economic fundamentals.</p>
<p>Akira Kurihara, chief spot dealer at Norinchukin Bank, said: &quot;The fact that they (officials) are all saying things this strongly seems to suggest that something must be going on... It definitely feels somewhat unpleasant.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that the exchange value of the greenback against the yen has been hitting the level at which dollar-selling interventions were last carried out in August 1992.</p>
<p>The last dollar-selling intervention against the yen in Tokyo was conducted in August 1992 by the BOJ.</p>
<p>The official discount rate was at 3.25 percent at that time, compared with 0.5 percent now.</p>
<p>IBJ's Maruyama said the impact of such dollar sales may be partly muted by potential dollar demand by Japanese institutional investors who are keen to invest in higher yielding foreign assets.</p>
<p>The main cause behind the current dollar rally is wide rate differentials with such countries as the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;A chance of single-handed intervention by the BOJ may be in the cards, considering the risk that the dollar would settle in a 125-130 yen range from the previous 120-125 yen,&quot; said Ryohei Muramatsu, manager of treasury and foreign exchange at Commerzbank's Tokyo branch.</p>
<p>--Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-8676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
