<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499783" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>QATAR: Qatar seeks to raise stake in satphone venture.</title>
<headline>Qatar seeks to raise stake in satphone venture.</headline>
<byline>Kedar Sharma</byline>
<dateline>DOHA 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qatar's telecommunications company said on Thursday it planned to raise its stake in an international consortium aiming to offer a global mobile satellite communications service by next century.</p>
<p>Qatar's state-owned telecommunications agency Q-Tel holds 0.69 percent of the equity -- or 100,000 shares worth $10 million -- in the London-based ICO Global Communications, which was founded in 1995.</p>
<p>ICO was set up by 47 investors worldwide to develop the International Mobile Satellite Organisation's (Inmarsat) satellite-based mobile telephone system. Inmarsat is a multinational cooperative based in London.</p>
<p>ICO has raised $1.5 billion from its investors.</p>
<p>Q-Tel general manager Izzat al-Rashid said: &quot;ICO is best placed to dominate the satellite communications market and we are planning to invest heavily into it.&quot; He did not say how large a share Q-Tel wished to hold.</p>
<p>Other Middle East investors include Bahrain Telecommunications Company (Batelco), Etisalat of the United Arab Emirates, Saudi Arabia's Ministry of Posts, Telegraphs and Telephones, the Saudi Public Investment Fund, Mobile Telecommunications Co  MOTE.KW of Kuwait, Kuwait Investment Authority, Telecommunications Company of Iran, National Telecommunications Organisation of Egypt (Arento) and the Lebanese Telecommunications Company.</p>
<p>The consortium plans to send 10 satellites into space by early next century to cover the entire globe with its communications network.</p>
<p>&quot;By the end of 1999, six satellites will be up and operational, and when the full 10 are up every square inch of the world will be covered,&quot; said Mike Whiddett, senior vice -president and chief financial officer of ICO.</p>
<p>Addressing a regional investors' forum of ICO Global Communications in the Qatari capital, he said satellite communication would have to fill in the gap uncovered by cellular phones.</p>
<p>He said studies had shown that 80 percent of the world and 40 percent of its population would be left outside the reach of cellular phones by 2000 because of geographical factors like difficult terrain.</p>
<p>Whiddett said satellite phones were more expensive than cellular ones but said the ICO was trying to cut consumer costs.</p>
<p>&quot;We are aiming at providing a round-the-world service for around $1.25 per minute,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DOHA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="QATAR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
