<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499749" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Mazda president says worst over for troubled firm.</title>
<headline>Mazda president says worst over for troubled firm.</headline>
<byline>Miki Shimogori</byline>
<dateline>HIROSHIMA, Japan 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mazda Motor Corp president Henry Wallace, the first outsider to run a major Japanese company, said on Thursday the worst is over for the troubled carmaker.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the worst is over, although I think we still have a long way to go as a company before I would be comfortable that we are in good shape,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview at the company's headquarters in Hiroshima in western Japan.</p>
<p>Mazda, now effectively controlled by Ford Motor Co, will enjoy the full benefits of platform sharing and other synergies with the American car giant in the years to come, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Real benefit from synergies with Ford will come beyond 2000,&quot; said Wallace, 51, a Briton.</p>
<p>In April last year, Ford raised its equity stake in the fifth-ranked Japanese carmaker to one-third. A few month later, Wallace came from Ford to take the wheel, setting himself the task of steering the troubled firm back to prosperity.</p>
<p>Wallace, a native of Edinburgh, has been with Ford since joining its British unit in 1971.</p>
<p>He said Mazda will unveil a general outline for sharing a car platform with Ford in the coming few weeks, although he gave no details about which models may use the common platform, which includes the engine and transmission, or when the plan would be implemented.</p>
<p>Japanese media reports say the two firms will share a common platform for their mainstay cars --  Mazda's Familia and Ford's Escort -- from the year 2002.</p>
<p>Mazda is known for its high engineering capability, but has been hurt by shrinking market share as its strategy of becoming a niche maker of luxury sports cars failed.</p>
<p>Wallace said the company's parent net income was likely to be in the black for the year that ended in March, and he expects the business to get stronger in the current year.</p>
<p>He was pleased with the recent rise of the dollar, which had helped boost exports and profits at Japan's carmakers.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not disappointed to see where it (the dollar) is in the marketplace,&quot; Wallace said. He believes the dollar may reach as high as 130 yen in the short term, but that it could slip back to below 120 yen by the end of this year.</p>
<p>The dollar has risen steadily in recent months and hit 127.16 yen on Thursday, its highest level since August 1992.</p>
<p>In November, Mazda predicted its parent current profit would rise to 11 billion yen in 1996/97, up from 1.23 billion yen the year before, when it posted its first profit in three years thanks to sales of shareholdings and painful cost-cutting.</p>
<p>But at the operating level, Mazda has been in the red since 1993/94 due largely to poor sales at home and abroad, and it predicted that it would do no more than break even for the year to March 1997.</p>
<p>Operating profit reflects the company's business performance. Current profit includes operating profit and non-operating income or losses from sources such as interest payments and dividends.</p>
<p>Wallace said Mazda was aiming at a global market share of 3.5 percent to 4.0 percent in the long term from the current two percent. It also seeks seven percent of Japan's vehicle market by the turn of the century, up from the current five percent.</p>
<p>But private analysts are sceptical about Mazda's future business, saying the road ahead is still bumpy.</p>
<p>Nobuaki Yanachi, a senior analyst at Kankaku Research Institute, said: &quot;I cannot say for sure that the worst is over for Mazda. At the moment, it is being aided by the weak yen and healthy sales of its new models, but we're not sure how long these factors will last. The focus is on whether Ford will provide added financial support to Mazda.&quot;</p>
<p>Wallace flatly denied any need for Mazda to receive additional support in the form of further equity investment. &quot;We probably need to do some refinancing in the future but I don't see why we need an increase in capital.&quot; ($1=127 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HIROSHIMA, Japan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
