<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499722" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China Vanke sees slow 1997 on restructure.</title>
<headline>China Vanke sees slow 1997 on restructure.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Conglomerate China Vanke Co Ltd expects 1997 earnings to be similar to 1996 due to an ongoing restructuring, a company spokeswoman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Vanke has been reconfiguring its businesses, selling stakes in some non-property subsidiaries to focus its efforts more fully on real estate, the spokeswoman told the Hong Kong-based newsletter China Securities Bulletin.</p>
<p>Vanke, based in Shenzhen, is involved in real estate, retail, foreign trade and industrial production.</p>
<p>&quot;Vanke will complete its business adjustment by the end of 1997 before entering a fast-growth period starting next year,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>The company, with property projects scattered throughout China's main cities, plans to increase its land reserve in Shenzhen in 1997 as it believes Hong Kong's return to China will boost Shenzhen's real estate market, the official said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong, bordering Shenzhen, reverts to Chinese rule on July 1, 1997.</p>
<p>Vanke on Thursday posted net profits of 151.76 million yuan for 1996 under international accounting standards.</p>
<p>Vanke booked after-tax profits of 154.53 million yuan for 1995 under international standards, the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Real estate accounted for about 52 percent of Vanke's profits in 1996, Vanke said in its 1996 annual report published in the Shenzhen-based Securities Times.</p>
<p>Vanke plans to make a 2.727-for-10 rights offer, tentatively priced at between 4.5 and 5.0 yuan per share, in the first half of 1997 to raise 389 - 432 million yuan, the annual report said but gave no more details on the issue.</p>
<p>Vanke plans to use the rights proceeds to increase land holdings in Shenzhen and finance property projects, the official said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
