<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499824" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bennett executive charged in Ponzi scheme.</title>
<headline>Bennett executive charged in Ponzi scheme.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former executive of the scandal-ridden Bennett Funding Group was charged in civil and criminal suits Thursday growing out of the government's probe of one of the largest Ponzi schemes in history.</p>
<p>Kenneth Kasarjian, 52, who was a senior vice president of Bennett from 1990 through May 1995, was charged with securities fraud in a criminal complaint filed by the Manhattan U.S. Attorney's office. He also was named in a related civil suit filed by the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
<p>Kasarjian pleaded guilty later Thursday afternoon to the criminal counts of securities fraud, obstruction of justice and conspiracy to commit bankruptcy fraud. He faces a possible maximum prison term of 30 years and fines of $2.5 million.</p>
<p>The SEC had sued Bennett Funding in March 1996 accusing the Syracuse, N.Y.-based office leasing and financing company and its Chief Executive Patrick Bennett with fraudulently selling $570 million worth of securities. The SEC alleged that the company was being run as a &quot;massive, ongoing Ponzi scheme&quot; and one of the largest such schemes in history.</p>
<p>In a Ponzi scheme, payments are made to original investors with funds from new investors instead of from profits.</p>
<p>Bennett Funding filed for bankruptcy one day after the SEC sued the firm. Court papers said that more than 12,000 investors had lost some $674 million in the scheme.</p>
<p>Former SEC Chairman Richard Breeden was appointed by the court as bankruptcy trustee and he sued the Bennett family members on behalf of investors who alleged the Bennetts used their money to buy a racetrack, a hotel, gambling casinos and a yacht.</p>
<p>The SEC alleged that between 1991 and 1996 Bennett Funding and certain individuals sold several hundred millions dollars of securities including purported assignments of equipment leases and promissory notes. The SEC alleged the company did not have sufficient receivables to support the assignments.</p>
<p>In some instances, such as the sale of purported New York City Transit Authority Lease Assignments, the underlying leases did not exist. In other instances the leases purportedly sold were already pledged to other investors or to banks.</p>
<p>The SEC alleged that Kasarjian and The Kenton Group Inc., a company he controlled, broke federal securities laws when they sold Bennett Funding lease assignments and notes.</p>
<p>Kasarjian and Kenton also allegedly participated in sham transactions that were used to overstate income on Bennett Funding's audited financial statements, the SEC charged.</p>
<p>The SEC also alleged that in 1995 and 1996 the defendants fraudulently sold about $27 million in membership interests in certain funds that were designed to invest in municipal leases and other debt instruments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
