<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499808" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Banker sentenced in New York for Venezuelan fraud.</title>
<headline>Banker sentenced in New York for Venezuelan fraud.</headline>
<byline>Jeanne King</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Cuban-born businessman was on Thursday sentenced to at least one year in jail, but no more than three, for defrauding Venezuelan depositors of millions of dollars.</p>
<p>Orlando Castro Llanes, 71, who built a business empire in Venezuela, had faced up to four years in prison when he was found guilty of fraud on Feb. 19 after a four-month trial in Manhattan Supreme Court.</p>
<p>Justice Edward McLaughlin stayed the sentence until a May 6 hearing to determine restitution that Castro Lllanes will have to pay.</p>
<p>The banker, who will be sent to a New York state prison, is eligible for parole almost immediately because he has been in jail since his arrest in April last year.</p>
<p>His attorneys said they were appealing his conviction.</p>
<p>The complicated financial case that also involved his son and grandson was tried in New York because prosecutors said money was fraudulently transferred through New York banks. The transactions included two multi-million dollar transfers.</p>
<p>Jurors decided that New York had jurisdiction of the case.</p>
<p>His son, Orlando Castro Castro, 47, and his grandson, Jorge Castro Barredo, 29, were found guilty in February of fraud and grand larceny. Castro Castro was scheduled to be sentenced on April 21 and Castro Barredo on May 5.</p>
<p>Castro Llanes, known as &quot;Don Orlando&quot; left Venezuela in 1994 after prosecutors issued arrest warrants against him and several associates on charges of financial fraud and other crimes.</p>
<p>The defense contended he was set up by the Venezuelan government, which was seeking political revenge.</p>
<p>Before sentencing, Castro Llanes spoke of his businesses in Venezuela and of the thousands of people he employed.</p>
<p>&quot;I can only say that I feel proud of my life and being proud of my life is not a crime,&quot; he said. &quot;I can say that I have done my duty.&quot;</p>
<p>Prosecutors said the three defendants illegally used deposits in a family controlled bank, Banco Progreso International de Puerto Rico (BPIPR) to prop up financial institutions they controlled in Central and South America.</p>
<p>The prosecution said the three men misled Venezuelan depsoiters to believe BPIPR was a safe offshore bank subject to tight regulatory control, attracting deposits of more than $55 million.</p>
<p>Prosecutors also claimed the defendants lied to regulators in Puerto Rico by falsely claiming BPIPR funds were held in Panama and thus not subject to Puerto Rican oversight.</p>
<p>BPIPR closed in January 1995, with uninsured loses to depositors of more than $15 million.</p>
<p>The judge said most of the testimony during the trial seemed like &quot;conventional business practices&quot; but told Castro Llanes he had &quot;crossed the line when you misrepresented the company (BPIPR) to the banking commissioner in Puerto Rico.&quot;</p>
<p>Castro Llanes built a business empire in Venezuela that included banks, four insurance firms, 40 radio stations, car rental companies and coffee manufacturing plants.</p>
<p>He was also accused of illegally transferring more than $10 million out of BPIPR into Banco Progreso S.A.C.A. in Caracas in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PURI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
