<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499920" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot resid prices mixed, HSFO gains.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot resid prices mixed, HSFO gains.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot residual fuel prices were mixed Thursday in sluggish activity, with relatively firm bunkers boosting high sulphur grades, while low sulphur held steady or lost ground, industry sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;There could be some room to move up, particularly high sulphur, but no one's loading up. They're only buying as they need it,&quot; said one cash trader, noting some record cold in the Midwest and East should stir some demand.</p>
<p>In New York Harbor, firm bunkers drove three percent up slightly to near the $14 a barrel level, with 2.2 percent moving up to $14.25 in sympathy, traders said.  </p>
<p>NYH 0.3 percent high pour slipped about a quarter to $16.25 on weak utility demand. Despite gains in New York city gate gas prices this week from the cold, traders said HP still remained the more expensive alternative.</p>
<p>NYH physical one percent again was unchanged at $15.25-50, steadied by further gains in crude.</p>
<p>At the U.S. Gulf, three percent notionally was up slightly to $13.25-50, while one percent was still quoted at $15.00-25.</p>
<p>No NYH or USG deals were reported.</p>
<p>On Thursday, New York city gate swing gas prices were unchanged in the low-to-mid $2.40s/mmBtu, or $15.44 a barrel equivalent, bolstered by well-below normal temperatures in the area. Gas at Henry Hub, the NYMEX delivery point, also held steady in the mid-$1.90s/mmBtu, or $12.29 a barrel.</p>
<p>((J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
