<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="500106" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Court martial trial to begin in Army rape case.</title>
<headline>Court martial trial to begin in Army rape case.</headline>
<byline>Randall Mikkelsen</byline>
<dateline>ABERDEEN, Md 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The court-martial of Staff Sgt. Delmar Simpson, accused of raping six women as part of the military's biggest sexual misconduct scandal since the 1991 Tailhook affair, was set to begin Friday.</p>
<p>Simpson, 32, faced 19 counts of rape and 55 other charges of sexual misconduct and other crimes involving 22 women. The alleged acts occurred between November 1994 and August 1996, while Simpson served as a drill instructor at the Army's Ordnance Centre and School at the Aberdeen Proving Ground.</p>
<p>His was the highest-profile case and the first to go to trial in an investigation that led to charges of sexual misconduct against 10 trainers at the proving ground. Four of the 10 cases have been resolved through plea agreements or administrative proceedings.</p>
<p>The investigation prompted a nationwide military probe into sexual harassment after it was disclosed in November. It has led to criticism that the military failed to prevent the sexual harassment as well as to charges that investigators unfairly targeted black soldiers and tried to coerce rape accusations from witnesses.</p>
<p>Simpson pleaded guilty to 16 of the counts against him -- 11 counts of improper sexual intercourse with trainees and five counts of propositioning. But he pleaded innocent to the rapes and other misconduct charges.</p>
<p>The case, beginning with opening arguments Friday, was likely to pit Simpson's version of frequent casual sex with eager participants against what the prosecution has described as acts of force and intimidation by a higher-ranking soldier who had immense control and authority over his trainees.</p>
<p>&quot;It's that whole relationship that has to be seen as the context of these charges,&quot; an army legal expert said. &quot;They (the drill instructors) are your mom and your dad, your principal ... That's what's drilled into them (soldiers) in basic (training).&quot;</p>
<p>Simpson's lawyers said violations he has already admitted pertain to the relationship between drill instructor and trainee. But they said the sex was consensual and reflected a military base where discipline had broken down.</p>
<p>&quot;When you get into rape and indecent assault, that's a whole different category than fraternisation and socializing type regulation,&quot; Simpson's civilian attorney Frank Spinner said this week. &quot;Some of the women were mutually involved, were consensually involved in some of these activities.&quot;</p>
<p>Deciding the case, in a trial expected to last two to three weeks, will be a six-member military jury composed of one white woman, two black men and three white men. Four of the jurors are officers.</p>
<p>Simpson faces a maximum penalty of life in prison if convicted of rape. On the guilty pleas, he faces a total maximum penalty of 32 years in jail, a dishonourable discharge and forfeiture of pay and allowances.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABERDEEN, Md"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
