<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="500360" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian parties say mid-term polls inevitable.</title>
<headline>Indian parties say mid-term polls inevitable.</headline>
<byline>Jawed Naqvi</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Early elections in India looked inevitable on Thursday after the ruling alliance blocked the Congress party's quest to head a new coalition, preferring to face a test vote in parliament, politicians said.</p>
<p>A 12-day-old crisis, triggered by a Congress decision to withdraw support for Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's United Front alliance, deepened when his former ally ordered its deputies to topple the centre-left government.</p>
<p>The right-wing Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), sensing electoral gains from likely snap polls, ordered its own deputies to attend the lower house on Friday but delayed a final decision on how they should vote.</p>
<p>&quot;We will do everything to precipitate elections,&quot; BJP general secretary Venkaiah Naidu told Reuters. &quot;The party will take a final decision tomorrow morning, but we are not interested in the government's survival.&quot;</p>
<p>Congress issued a notice to deputies to vote against the confidence motion which Deve Gowda was set to put before the house at 11 a.m (0530 GMT) on Friday.</p>
<p>The order raised pressure on Deve Gowda's coalition to bow to its rival's demand for the prime minister to relinquish power before the vote.</p>
<p>But the United Front alliance stood firm. &quot;Our stand is final. There is no question of a change of leadership,&quot; United Front leader Harkishen Singh Surjeet told a news conference.</p>
<p>While both sides held open the possibility of last-minute talks before the confidence vote, the United Front said it was prepared to face the electorate for the second time in a year if Deve Gowda was defeated in parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;It is reasonable to expect elections in May or June,&quot; a senior United Front official, who asked not to be identified, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not only confident, but it is eminently reasonable that the caretaker government will be headed by Deve Gowda.&quot;</p>
<p>Talks between the two groups earlier ended in deadlock, with the United Front refusing to abandon its support for Deve Gowda, who took power at the head of the minority government last June after inconclusive elections.</p>
<p>Congress stood firm by its demand that Deve Gowda must step down. Congress party chief Sitaram Kesri accuses him of trying to sideline India's oldest party.</p>
<p>Congress held out the possibility of further negotiations after the parliaemntary vote, but United Front spokesman Jaipal Reddy told reporters: &quot;You may believe in miracles, I don't. Both sides have hard positions that do not allow for a meeting ground.&quot;</p>
<p>Some politicians said Congress appeared to want Deve Gowda to quit before the vote while the two sides sought to find a new leader from either of the camps, averting snap polls that analysts said would strengthen the BJP.</p>
<p>The Hindu nationalist party held power for 12 days last May but stepped down when it failed to muster a majority and it believes fresh polls could strengthen its hand.</p>
<p>If the BJP, the largest party in parliament, were to abstain from the confidence vote, the coalition could still survive.</p>
<p>A United Front official said that in such an event Deve Gowda would still call early elections. &quot;The BJP will do it only to kill us later. Why should we wait for that moment?&quot; he asked.</p>
<p>The BJP controls 193 votes in the 545-seat lower house of parliament, the Lok Sabha, while Congress has 140 and the United Front coalition 180.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
