<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="500366" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian truck owners back at work after strike.</title>
<headline>Indian truck owners back at work after strike.</headline>
<byline>Sambit Mohanty</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian truck owners returned to work on Thursday after a 10-day strike that crippled industry and pushed up prices, but they said freight rates would rise before a backlog in goods was cleared in two weeks' time.</p>
<p>&quot;It will take 15 days for goods piled up to be cleared,&quot; S.P. Singh, spokesman of the All-India Motor Transport Congress (AIMTC), told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The freight rate will go up by 15 to 20 percent during this period... The rates will normalise after that,&quot; another AIMTC official added.</p>
<p>Truck owners on Wednesday ended the strike after the government agreed to their demand that they not be held responsible for collecting a five percent service tax and to hold a proposed rise in insurance premiums in abeyance.</p>
<p>The AIMTC, which represents nearly 2.2 million truck owners, said the strike had been called off in all states including western Maharashtra where it had continued well into Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The strike has ended in Maharashtra also,&quot; Chittaranjan Dass, AIMTC president, told Reuters.</p>
<p>News agencies quoted Maharashtra Chief Minister Manohar Joshi as saying that members of the state truckers' union went back to work after a meeting with the government at which both sides reached agreement on most of the truckers' demands.</p>
<p>Singh said truck owners had lost about 36 billion rupees ($1 billion) due to the strike. Analysts said the economy faced an estimated loss of about 70 to 80 billion rupees a day.</p>
<p>&quot;By today evening about 450,000 trucks will be on the roads,&quot; Singh said. It would be two to three days before all trucks took to the roads as most drivers had gone on leave.</p>
<p>&quot;Fruit and vegetable prices have gone up by at least 25 percent in different states,&quot; said an official of the Punjab, Haryana and Delhi Chambers of Commerce and Industry. &quot;But it will normalise soon.&quot;</p>
<p>He said industrial production in the northern states had come to a &quot;grinding halt&quot; and estimated it would take two days to restart.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still working out the loss (to industry),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the arrivals at market of summer crops of rice, wheat and oilseed had come to a standstill.</p>
<p>Shipping had also been hit. &quot;I expect a lot of export commitments to be cancelled,&quot; said one Bombay-based commodity analyst. ($1 = 35.8 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
