<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="500498" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chilean brewery to start Guinness production.</title>
<headline>Chilean brewery to start Guinness production.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO, Chile 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile's largest brewery Compania Cervecerias Unidas (CCU) will start producing a Latin American version of the famous Guinness stout later this month, officials said Thursday.</p>
<p>The new beer, which will be brewed in CCU's plant under supervision by Arthur Guinness Son &amp; Co. (Dublin) Ltd., will give the traditional Irish drink a South American flavor.</p>
<p>&quot;Latin America's consumption has been centred on soft lagers. That's why we think that consumers are prepared to develop a beer culture in the strong, dark segment of the beer market,&quot; said Don Blaustein, Guinness' president for Latin America and the Caribbean.</p>
<p>Guinness is the world's largest producer of dark beer.</p>
<p>&quot;Guinness is well represented in Europe, North America and the Caribbean. Now, Latin America is our great objective,&quot; said Blaustein.</p>
<p>Guinness will be produced in Chile by mixing a concentrate sent from the firm's headquarters with a national beer, said Victor Nazal, deputy brands manager at CCU.</p>
<p>The deal with Guinness forms part of the Chilean brewery's strategy to diversify its brands in the local market where it controls 80 percent of sales.</p>
<p>Last year CCU signed a pact with U.S. beer-maker Anheuser Busch to brew and distribute Budweiser beer in Argentina.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO, Chile"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
