<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="500406" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian metals may ease as truckers call off strike.</title>
<headline>Indian metals may ease as truckers call off strike.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aluminium prices slipped but other metals were largely steady in limited trading on Thursday, traders said.</p>
<p>Aluminium fell 25 rupees to 7,450 rupees per quintal on demand resistance, they said.</p>
<p>Aluminium was up by 25 rupees per quintal on Wednesday following a report that Indian aluminium producers have hiked selling prices by 4,000/5,000 rupees per tonne. Sluggish physical buying capped the rally, they said.</p>
<p>Copper was steady at 13,500 rupees. So were zinc at 7,850 and lead at 4,550 rupees per quintal amid limited activity.</p>
<p>Tin was steady at the previous level of 31,600 rupees and so was nickel at 36,800 rupees per quintal, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Inflow of imported metals from port to the market was slow because of the truckers strike but now truckers have called off their agitation and supplies will improve in the coming days,&quot; said Sharad Parikh, president of Bombay Metal Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;Improved supplies in the coming days may put some pressure on the prices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-Bombay Commodities +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
