<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="500575" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Freddie Mac investing practises probe sought.</title>
<headline>Freddie Mac investing practises probe sought.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rep. James Leach, chairman of the House Banking and Financial Services Committee Thursday called for a probe into the investment practices of Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corp.</p>
<p>The Iowa Republican called for a General Accounting Office investigation after he learned that Freddie Mac has reportedly bought $340 million in Philip Morris bonds, including a $125 million lot issued this week.  </p>
<p>&quot;This is easy money,&quot; the congresman said in a statement. &quot;Freddie Mac was established by an act of Congress for a specific purpose - to advance home ownership, not to facilitate tobacco sale.&quot;</p>
<p>On Monday, Freddie Mac used its Government-Sponsored Enterprise to borrow $125 million at 6.99 percent and then turned around and bought $125 million in identical Phillip Morris bonds at 7.68 percent, the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;What Freddie Mac's action amounts to is taxpayer subsidization of corporate arbitrage and, implicitly, the tobacco industry,&quot; Leach said.  </p>
<p>Under its federal charter, Freddie Mac has a line of credit with Treasury, special exemptions from certain Securities and Exchange Commission filing requirements, and is exempt from payment of state taxes, the statement said.</p>
<p>Leach said these attributes give the appearance to the markets that Freddie Mac has government agency status.</p>
<p>In a report to House committee last year, the Congressional Budget Office found that in the latest year reviewed (1995) Freddie Mac had an effective $2.6 billion government subsidy based on its status.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if Freddie Mac's market actions are legal, they are not appropriate,&quot; Leach said, adding &quot;It is free lunch for Freddie Mac's shareholders.&quot;  </p>
<p>In an April 10 letter to James Hinchman, GAO acting director, Leach asked congress' investigative arm to look into the profile of Freddie Mac's investment portfolio and what are its holdings of private company securities.</p>
<p>Leach also asked for information regarding Freddie Mac's investment policy and what is the justification for buying private company securities.</p>
<p>He also wanted to know if Freddie Mac has issued bonds mainly for arbitrage purposes and how extensive are Freddie Mac's trading activities, among others.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
