<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50067" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia seeks bank growth through mergers.</title>
<headline>Malaysia seeks bank growth through mergers.</headline>
<byline>Madhav Reddy</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's central bank ends its annual conference with chief executives of the country's banking institutions on Thursday, urging them to grow through mergers as the country opens its markets.</p>
<p>Bank Negara Malaysia Governor Ahmad Mohd Don stressed the need for local banks to gain the size needed to compete effectively in international markets.</p>
<p>&quot;For those who do not have the size but aspire to play a bigger role, the Governor urged these financial institutions to seriously consider the option of merger,&quot; a statement from the central bank said at the opening of the four-day conference.</p>
<p>The Governor told bankers in the statement that size was becoming increasingly important to compete in the financial markets and even large banks in more developed economies were recognising the need to merge.</p>
<p>Mergers would allow companies to retain their market dominance and enjoy the benefits of synergy and economies of scale, the statement said.</p>
<p>Bank Negara has been trying to get smaller banks to merge or strike strategic alliances and prepare to meet foreign competition as Malaysia is forced to remove all barriers under the World Trade Organisation's rules.</p>
<p>It also wants to reduce the number of commercial banks from 37, saying this number was too high for the country's market.</p>
<p>The central bank created a two-tier system a year ago which allowed the larger, better managed banks to operate in a more liberal environment and gave them operational privileges such as the ability to take foreign currency deposits.</p>
<p>A Tier-I bank needs at least 500 million ringgit ($200 million) in shareholders' funds, which should be expanded to one billion ($400 million) in three years. Only seven local banks and four foreign banks have been designated Tier I.</p>
<p>According to industry sources the central bank was now considering a ban on branch expansion by the Tier-II or smaller banks. No comment could be obtained from the central bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The two-tier concept has not produced the results that Bank Negara was looking for, that is induce more mergers and capital expansion among banks. This is why new measures are required,&quot; said a senior executive with a large Malaysian bank.</p>
<p>Only one merger has been announced so far. Singapore-based Oversea Chinese Banking Corporation Ltd announced a few months ago that its Malaysian operations will merge with Malaysia's Pacific Bank Bhd.</p>
<p>&quot;Some banks are reluctant to explore the merger option because they are happy as they are, though odds are getting stacked against them,&quot; the chief executive of a local bank said recently.</p>
<p>He said each of these banks had created a niche market for themselves, which was expanding with the growing business among existing clientele.</p>
<p>&quot;There is also a great fear that cultural conflicts which go with mergers may pull down both the merging banks. Mergers are not always desirable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In a market flooded with ready-made clothes from big brands, there will always be some who like tailormade garments,&quot; he added, referring to the need for banks in a niche market.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230 8911)</p>
<p>($1= 2.5 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
