<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="500776" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: BELGIAN RENAULT STAFF TO RESUME WORK ON MONDAY.</title>
<headline>BELGIAN RENAULT STAFF TO RESUME WORK ON MONDAY.</headline>
<byline>Nieck Ammerlaan</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A majority of workers at the doomed Belgian plant of French car maker Renault SA on Thursday voted to halt their five-week strike against the plant's impending closure.</p>
<p>Of the 3,100 employees of the Renault Industrie Belgique assembly plant in Vilvoorde near Brussels, 2,721 took part in the referendum with 68.7 percent backing a union recommendation to resume work, Belgian radio BRTN said.</p>
<p>The radio said production would now resume on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not that (this strike) has been too long, but it is in everybody's interest to return to work,&quot; a worker who was in favour of the resumption later told RTBF radio.</p>
<p>The vote had been expected to be close with workers facing a tough choice between approving a strike to the bitter end, or go back to work, continue to occupy part of the plant and stage occasional protests.</p>
<p>After the ballot Renault workers planned to go to the Belgian plants of Ford, Volkswagen, Volvo and Opel to call for support and hand out pamphlets.</p>
<p>Since group headquarters announced the decision in late February to close the plant by July, workers have held billions of francs worth of finished cars hostage, hoping to use them as bargaining chips in any negotiations with management.</p>
<p>Loss-making Renault is closing the plant to tackle overcapacity and rising costs. Production will be moved to France and Spain.</p>
<p>Vilvoorde unions recommended a resumption of work at the profitable and efficient plant -- a move analysts see as part of a strategy to begin lengthy negotiations with management on the terms and conditions of the mass dismissal of the workers.</p>
<p>Unions have slammed Renault's decision, which they say broke Belgian, French and European Union labour laws since the company failed to inform and consult workers adequately.</p>
<p>Belgian and French courts have ruled the closure procedure followed by Renault was illegal and ordered the company to play it by the book, handing the unions a moral victory.</p>
<p>In answer to the rulings the unions called the referendum, working on the assumption that since the courts have re-set the clocks to February 26 -- the day before the Renault decision -- workers should do the same and return to work.</p>
<p>Analysts say that Renault chief executive officer Louis Schweitzer would use a continued strike to his advantage, claiming that the workers did not want to play by the rules or even that their unwillingness to work only underlined the need for the plant to be shut down.</p>
<p>After the court rulings, which Renault has said it is appealing, unions decided to take legal action to force the company to pay out wages to the workers for the duration of the strike since formally they had remained on the Renault payroll.</p>
<p>Workers would repay the unions any strike money received.</p>
<p>A conservative estimate put the sum involved for Renault at some 65 million Belgian francs ($1.8 million).</p>
<p>It is unclear how long any talks on the terms and conditions of the closure could take. The court appeals could take until the end of April, and only then would the procedure start. The actual closure of Vilvoorde would likely be later than July.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710 ($ = 35.54 Belgian Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
