<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="500790" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - RMC profit down after accounting change.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - RMC profit down after accounting change.</headline>
<byline>Edna Fernandes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>British building materials group RMC Group Plc reported lower pre-tax profits of 295.3 million pounds ($478.8 million) on Thursday and announced a surprise change in its accounting policy.</p>
<p>Had the old accounting system been used, the pre-tax profit would have been lower in what the company described as a difficult year.</p>
<p>For 1996 the company used average exchange rates instead of end-of-year rates in a policy switch designed to strip out foreign exchange volatility which RMC said was distorting its results.</p>
<p>The pre-tax profit fell from 324.9 million pounds in 1995. Based on the previous accounting system, RMC's profit was at the top end of market forecasts at 275.8 million pounds compared with 329.3 million in 1995.</p>
<p>Analysts has expected profits of between 248 million and 275 million under the old system.</p>
<p>Chief Executive Peter Young said 1996 was a difficult year characterised by &quot;a severe and prolonged winter across Europe which had an adverse effect on profits&quot;.</p>
<p>Market conditions in Germany posed a particular problem while the British construction market was lacklustre in 1996. Both are seen improving in 1997, analysts said.</p>
<p>Simon Brown, analyst at UBS, told Reuters the results were sound and that the outlook was reasonably positive. &quot;They seem to be getting things in Germany right and the U.S. is doing well,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In mid-morning trade in London, RMC shares were down two and a half pence at 998 1/2 pence, after a strong run in recent sessions.</p>
<p>On the accounting changeover, RMC said: &quot;The volatility in 1996 of the currency markets caused the group to change its policy.&quot;</p>
<p>Finance Chief David Jenkins told Reuters that RMC was &quot;the second to last in the sector to do this&quot;, following the pound's surge against the mark and dollar in recent months.</p>
<p>&quot;The policy of cautious international growth, supported by financial strength and stability, should enable the group to progress in 1997,&quot; said RMC.</p>
<p>Young said he saw the key German market showing some profit recovery this year and Britain should also benefit from a stronger housing and commercial market.</p>
<p>Jenkins said reports of German woes were exaggerated, adding that RMC's recent restructuring with the loss of 1,100 jobs was biting but should deliver benefits from now on. The United States was seen continuing to make excellent progress.</p>
<p>&quot;Conditions are very buoyant in Florida and South Carolina and the recovery in northern California continues,&quot; the finance director said.</p>
<p>But the fourth biggest profit generator, Israel, is seen as exposed to political uncertainty as the Middle East peace process runs into trouble.</p>
<p>Jenkins said RMC had no involvement in building any of the Jewish settlements in territory under dispute.</p>
<p>Looking at a divisional breakdown of the 1996 results, total sales were 4.55 billion pounds versus 4.54 billion, with the year dividend 26.5 pence versus 25.05 pence per share.</p>
<p>Ready mixed concrete and aggregates showed sales of 2.85 billion pounds versus 2.84 billion, with profits down to 171.5 million from 199.3 million.</p>
<p>Cement, lime and concrete products' sales were 1.14 billion versus 1.16 billion, with profits down to 127.6 million from 138.8 million.</p>
<p>Merchandising, home improvement products, waste control and leisure saw sales of 565.5 million versus 535.6 million, with profits of 26 million versus 22.6 million.</p>
<p>($ = 0.616 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
