<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501064" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Juppe raps defendant in France's bugging scandal.</title>
<headline>Juppe raps defendant in France's bugging scandal.</headline>
<dateline>AUCH, France 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Prime Minister Alain Juppe reacted angrily on Thursday when a senior aide to the late president Francois Mitterrand said he would breach state secrecy to defend himself in a telephone bugging scandal.</p>
<p>&quot;The only person who can decide on official secrecy is the prime minister, not just any individual,&quot; Juppe told reporters in response to the statement by Gilles Menage, the former head of the Socialist head of state's private office.</p>
<p>Menage is under investigation for allegedly authorising an anti-terrorism unit in Mitterrand's office to carry out widespread illegal wiretapping of journalists, lawyers and politicians from 1982 to 1986.</p>
<p>Juppe said he had set very clear guidelines on the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything that followed normal, legal procedures comes under official secrecy. Everything which was done outside the law is of course not covered by official secrecy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Menage told a radio interviewer on Thursday that Juppe's decision to maintain partial state secrecy in the affair prevented him from defending himself properly.</p>
<p>&quot;After four years of investigation, I have concluded that official secrecy is pernicious for everyone -- for the justice authorities, for the public, for the memory of those who were involved and the honour of those who are accused, and for my own legal defence,&quot; Menage told Europe 1.</p>
<p>He said the wiretapping had not been the work of a rogue unit of &quot;cowboys&quot; working at the Elysee presidential palace but of &quot;a whole decision-making chain...the prime minister, the head of his office and the government communications centre&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It is unrealistic that after the wiretapping went up this whole chain, only those who worked at the Elysee are accused,&quot; Menage said. &quot;The Elysee wiretaps were carried out by the government which took political responsibility for them.&quot;</p>
<p>The former Mitterrand aide said reports of the number of people whose telephones were tapped had been wildly exaggerated.</p>
<p>&quot;We must tell the truth to the justice authorities. We must tell the truth to the French people. Above all, we must stop this exaggerated, emotional atmosphere,&quot; he added. Mitterrand, who ruled from 1981-95, died last year of prostate cancer.</p>
<p>Separately, Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre said he was suing the spokesman of the Socialist Party, Jean Glavany, for defamation over allegations of &quot;manipulation&quot; of the bugging scandal by counter-espionage services.</p>
<p>A ministry statement said Glavany had accused counter-espionage agents of sifting through bugging archives found in a garage in February and taking away documents before the arrival of magistrates.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCH, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
