<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501089" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Waigel -- ready for tax compromise with German SPD.</title>
<headline>Waigel -- ready for tax compromise with German SPD.</headline>
<dateline>LUDWIGSBURG, Germany 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Finance Minister Theo Waigel said on Thursday he was ready to reach a compromise with the opposition Social Democrats (SPD) at talks on key tax reforms which will resume next week.</p>
<p>But Waigel told reporters he was not prepared to abandon the overall strategy of the coalition government to cut taxes in a bid to attract job-creating investment to Germany.</p>
<p>He also said it was vital in the interests of German workers that a deal is struck before the summer holidays.</p>
<p>Talks on Waigel's package of 30 billion marks in income and corporate tax cuts are due, after a hiatus, to resume next Tuesday after Chancellor Helmut Kohl agreed to an SPD demand that he take part in person.</p>
<p>SPD leader Oskar Lafontaine has also called for a cut in social insurance charges for workers from this summer in addition to big tax cuts for average earners at the start of next year.</p>
<p>But Waigel said social security reforms should be mapped out first before bringing cuts in contributions into the tax debate. &quot;The SPD must be ready to cooperate on the reforms of social security and pensions as well as in cutting labour costs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Waigel was speaking to reporters after telling a savings bank conference here that recent economic setbacks would not stop Germany qualifying for European monetary union.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUDWIGSBURG, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
