<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501114" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: FOCUS-Telefonica to name U.S. partner soon.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Telefonica to name U.S. partner soon.</headline>
<byline>Sharman Esarey</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's Telefonica de Espana, working feverishly to pick a U.S. partner, said on Thursday it still had to reach a decision on an alliance that could reshape the global telecommunications sector and vault Telefonica into the top league.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the recently privatised telecommunications company said the board had still not fixed what it wanted to do with its international alliances.</p>
<p>&quot;It's true that the board met yesterday to study the issue of an international partner, but it wasn't the only subject and we haven't made any decision yet.&quot;</p>
<p>Telefonica is half-way through a self-imposed deadline of six weeks to make a decision. Analysts said the group was likely to press ahead swiftly, given the industry uproar prompted by news it was talking to firms outside its current alliance.</p>
<p>Telefonica said talks with various operators had intensifed and that it would probably make a decision in coming days, according to a statement from stock market commission CNMV.</p>
<p>Three weeks ago, Telefonica chairman Juan Villalonga said the group was in talks with the chairmen of MCI, British Telecom and Southwestern Bell Corp as well as with AT&amp;T, with whom it has an alliance already.</p>
<p>Telefonica is attractive because it has extensive Latin American holdings through its international subsidiary TISA, which had sales last year of around 350 billion pesetas ($2.4 billion).</p>
<p>Villalonga intends to exploit this advantage to snatch a U.S. partner that will convert Telefonica -- once a state-run behemoth that took six months to install a phone -- into one of the top six leading international telecommunications groups.</p>
<p>Telefonica currently forms part of Unisource, a primarily European consortium directed by AT&amp;T which groups Sweden's Telia, Swiss Telecom and Koninklijke PTT Nederland of the Netherlands.</p>
<p>But analysts believe Telefonica is now favouring MCI over AT&amp;T, which would mean a break with Unisource and would probably force other operators to rejuggle partnerships.</p>
<p>Both MCI and AT&amp;T would provide Telefonica with an inroad into the enormous U.S. market, but MCI's powerful European partner BT may persuade Telefonica in its favour.</p>
<p>&quot;MCI would give Telefonica access to the U.S. where it is a key operator. But AT&amp;T could also provide that access,&quot; a Madrid-based analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;But this is not just about U.S. access, Telefonica's talks imply it is reviewing its entire system of alliances...to allow them to expand in the future,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>MCI is hooked up with AT&amp;T's key rival, BT. Concert, their planned merger, could offer Telefonica better European growth than Unisource, which analysts say has not provided Telefonica with huge benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;Doing an alliance with MCI would also mean one with BT, which is the most competitive group at the moment. It would also remove one of Telefonica's key European rivals,&quot; another Madrid-based analyst said. ($ = 145.4 Spanish Pesetas)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
