<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501285" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: BT confident EU will approve MCI merger.</title>
<headline>BT confident EU will approve MCI merger.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Telecommunications Plc said on Thursday it remained confident that the European Commission would clear its merger with MCI Communications of the United States.</p>
<p>The European Union executive has until June 11 to take a final decision, but a Commission source said it would probably be able to rule on the case earlier.</p>
<p>He declined to give details but EU Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert said last month the Commission would clear the merger if the firms confirmed proposed &quot;remedies to competition problems&quot;.</p>
<p>Mike Corkerry at British Telecommunication's EU affairs office in Brussels said he was confident that the merger would be approved but refused to go into details about possible conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;We've always felt that this is going on okay,&quot; he said, adding that the companies were still talking with the Commission on the issue.</p>
<p>The Commission started a full probe into the $20 billion merger at the end of January saying it was concerned that it might harm fair competition on the route between the U.S and Britain as well as the U.S.-Europe route.</p>
<p>The Commission said in the January statement that it would investigate further whether the new entity, called Concert Plc, could divert U.S.-European traffic through the UK or whether it would have any impact on the availability of transatlantic cable capacity to new market entrants.</p>
<p>The impact of the merger on the teleconferencing market would also have to be carefully assessed.</p>
<p>The deal, which involves BT taking over MCI, was not expected to pose major competition problems in Europe because the British telecoms sector is more liberalised than any other market in continental Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
