<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501286" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: First private tv station to hit Vienna airwaves.</title>
<headline>First private tv station to hit Vienna airwaves.</headline>
<byline>Elizabeth Fullerton</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Just two months after Austria unveiled a draft law to liberalise its television and radio markets, Vienna's first private cable television station is about to go on air.</p>
<p>The new station, Wien 1, is being marketed as hip, slick and on the ball, using glossy graphics and fast-paced shots to dance music in the style of MTV.</p>
<p>It will be available to some 800,000 of the roughly one million Viennese from April 15, via the domestic cable network Telekabel.</p>
<p>&quot;Take a look -- a look at Vienna&quot; is the Wien 1 philosophy.</p>
<p>&quot;With Wien 1 we are beginning a new era in media in Vienna,&quot; Friedrich Loew, General Director of broadcasting company Elbemuehl which part owns the station, told a news conference on Thursday.</p>
<p>Until February Austria was considered to be pitifully backward in its media, offering just two state-owned terrestrial television channels ORF 1 and ORF 2, which often broadcast the same programme simultaneously.</p>
<p>The new station is owned by RTV Regional-TV Services AG, a holding in which Elbemuehl, Austrian bank BAWAG and First Austrian savings bank each have 20 percent.</p>
<p>Negotiations about the remaining 40 percent were continuing, but no decision had been made as to the eventual ownership structure, Loew said.</p>
<p>The station's total budget for 1997 is 100 million schillings ($8.3 million) with 50 million schillings set aside for advertising spending.</p>
<p>RTV Regional-TV Services AG has basic capital of 40 million schillings and also owns local broadcaster RTV in Lower Austria. Loew said the holding was seeking more investors.</p>
<p>Wien 1 will broadcast around the clock, producing three hours of new material daily, which will be repeated in stages.</p>
<p>The programme will feature news, entertainment, chat shows, travel and weather updates, vignettes from Vienna life, and local gossip.</p>
<p>&quot;Wien 1 is a Viennese programme, exclusively oriented to Vienna, which also aims to involve Viennese citizens actively,&quot; Loew said.</p>
<p>The station envisages it will reach between 50,000 to 60,000 viewers daily in the first few months.</p>
<p>&quot;We are targetting mainly young, educated earners and families with a good income,&quot; said Alfreda Bergmann-Fiaka, director at Telekabel. &quot;We can only cross our fingers and hope we have not got it wrong,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>In 1993 the European Court of Human Rights ruled that Austria's stringent media laws violated the right to free speech.</p>
<p>Under the new law cable stations will not need a licence to broadcast. Media stakes will be limited to 26 percent and foreign stakes, excluding the Europe Economic Area -- comprising European Union members and some non-EU western European countries to 49 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
