<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50129" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch shares close up boosted by benign core PPI.</title>
<headline>Dutch shares close up boosted by benign core PPI.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares regained ground in afternoon trade on Thursday, boosted by a firmer Wall Street after benign core U.S. producer price data.</p>
<p>The AEX index closed up 2.83 points at 564.90, off an earlier high of 565.54.</p>
<p>The U.S. producer price index rose 0.3 percent in August, with the core index -- excluding food and energy -- falling 0.1 percent, data interpreted by the markets as neutral.</p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters had forecast a modest 0.1 percent month-on-month gain in both overall and core rates.</p>
<p>Some dealers tipped the market to show a steady rise in the near term, with the AEX index heading towards it's all time high around 572 points.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of the stocks that are heavily weighted in the AEX -- such as ABN AMRO, ING and Philips -- could go higher without any problems, so it would be easy for the index to move up 10 to 15 points,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>But he added niggling interest rate concerns and the end of the company results season meant downside risks remained.</p>
<p>One of the day's star performers was Anglo-Dutch group Unilever, whose shares rose 10.40 guilders to 264.60.</p>
<p>Analysts said a number of upbeat presentations on the company's outlook in the U.S. suggested solid growth in the firm would come in faster than expected.</p>
<p>Royal Dutch also showed solid gains as ongoing concerns about rising oil prices in the wake of unrest in Iraq spurred investors to snap up the stock. It closed up 1.80 guilders at 262.50, off an earlier high of 264.90.</p>
<p>DSM stock closed up 2.00 guilders at 162.50 after the Dutch chemical industry association VNCI predicted a plastics recovery in the second half year on rising sales prices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
