<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501283" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARY PRIVATE TV BIDS IN, SEPTEMBER START LIKELY.</title>
<headline>HUNGARY PRIVATE TV BIDS IN, SEPTEMBER START LIKELY.</headline>
<byline>Denes Albert</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's radio and television body ORTT said on Thursday it had received three bids for the two national commercial TV channels offered for 10-year concessions.</p>
<p>The bidders for Hungary's television market, which attracted $200 million in advertising fees last year, will only be announced once the validity of the bids has been established, an ORTT official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the checks to be done by the second half of next week,&quot; ORTT spokesman Gyorgy Lovas told Reuters.</p>
<p>He added that one bidder had bid for the first channel, one for the second, and a third for both channels.</p>
<p>Foreign companies said to be lining up to bid for the TV channels include U.S.- based Central European Media Enterprises , CLT-Bertelsmann , which owns RTL satellite television, a Hungarian-Swedish consortium MTM-SBS and a consortium of French channel TF1 and the German Westdeutsche Allgemeine Zeitung.</p>
<p>The ORTT did not release the names of the bidders.</p>
<p>The minimum concession fee is eight billion forints per channel per year, plus VAT at 25 percent, three years payable in advance.</p>
<p>Only consortia were allowed to bid, no single company is allowed to have more than a 49 percent stake, while Hungarians have to hold a minimum of 26 percent.</p>
<p>Under Hungary's media law, bids have to be evaluated within 60 days and the winners have to go on air three months after the concession contracts have been signed.</p>
<p>Lovas said a September starting time is realistic.</p>
<p>He dismissed press reports that said the tender procedure was unfair and biased.</p>
<p>&quot;The ORTT, despite imaginary or real political and other pressures, will only base its decision on the content of the bids, expert opinions and consultations with the European Media Institute,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that the tender process for two national radio channels is also underway, and the ORTT would like to see the radio channels go live by October.</p>
<p>&quot;The deadline seems tight, especially as the two radio cahnnels are not of equal value and at least six or seven groups have expressed interest so far,&quot; Lovas said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
