<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50122" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FTC approval for Time, Turner deal expected.</title>
<headline>FTC approval for Time, Turner deal expected.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Trade Commission is expected to announce Thursday that it has officially approved the $7.5 billion Time Warner-Turner merger, a decision that has been anticipated for several weeks.</p>
<p>It was not clear late Wednesday whether there were any substantive changes to a settlement worked out earlier this summer between the FTC and the two companies.</p>
<p>The final decision had been delayed because at least two of the five FTC commissioners objected to the way the deal was handled by the agency's chairman and one of his top aides, sources said.</p>
<p>The final vote is expected to be 5-2 in favour of the deal. The dissenting commissioners objected that senior FTC officials overrode a decision by agency staffers to fight the merger in court.</p>
<p>After several months of discussions between the companies and the agency, competition bureau chief William Baer and FTC chairman Robert Pitofsky began negotiating directly with Time Warner, Turner and Tele-Communications Inc.</p>
<p>Staffers at the agency were demoralised by the decision by Pitofsky and Baer to bypass agency careerists, sources said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
