<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501277" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan's Nippon Credit Bank in deal with Bankers Trust.</title>
<headline>Japan's Nippon Credit Bank in deal with Bankers Trust.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nippon Credit Bank Ltd, a heavily indebted Japanese bank in the midst of a restructuring, said Thursday it will tie up with New York blue chip Bankers Trust New York Corp.</p>
<p>NCB has been considered the most endangered large bank in Japan's faltering banking sector.</p>
<p>On April 1 it announced that it was retreating from the international arena. It also said it was selling prime real estate and floating new shares to try to rebuild its capital, depleted by problem loans left over from Japan's 1980s &quot;bubble&quot; economy.</p>
<p>Under the alliance, Bankers Trust will help NCB &quot;securitize&quot; some of its loans, turning them into equity and boosting liquidity.</p>
<p>The tie-up with Bankers Trust will also enable NCB to maintain services to its customers after its planned withdrawal from overseas business, the two banks said.</p>
<p>NCB said it would also consider a capital tie-up with Bankers Trust, which is on a global expansion drive. Earlier this week it agreed to buy retail brokerage Alex. Brown Inc. for $1.7 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;We will consider limited capital participation in each other after the ongoing restructuring of NCB's capital is completed,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said such an equity deal would be the first time a foreign bank has taken a stake in a Japanese bank. But they said that it was very unlikely that Bankers Trust would take over NCB, since its return on equity is too low by international standards.</p>
<p>As one of Japan's three long-term credit banks, NCB raises the bulk of its cash through issuing debentures rather than taking deposits from customers. But in a blow to NCB's image, the debentures were recently downgraded to junk-bond status by Moody's Investors Service.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
