<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501451" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: OPINION - Bottom-fishing likely in Jakarta shares.</title>
<headline>OPINION - Bottom-fishing likely in Jakarta shares.</headline>
<byline>Jos Parengkuan</byline>
<text>
<p>Research Director, PT Lippo Securities</p>
<p>JAKARTA, April 10 - The correction in the Jakarta stock market at the beginning of March came about a month sooner than we expected.</p>
<p>Until the end of February, the market was still sailing smoothly. A benign macroeconomic outlook, liquidity inflows and expectations of solid FY96 results all contributed to the bull run, pushing the Jakarta Composite Index (JCI) to an all-time high in late February and making it the best-performing market in the region since November last year. But just when everyone was wondering when the party would end, a spate of negative news came to the surface.</p>
<p>Initially, the correction was triggered by fears of an interest rate hike in the United States and disappointing FY96 results from HM Sampoerna, Semen Gresik and Bank Negara Indonesia. This was soon followed by news that the central bank would impose stricter credit growth limits for commercial banks, and a penalty on banks that fail to meet the small business loan requirement. Finally, the market was rattled by news that the government may end Telkom's monopoly on fixed wire basic services sooner than the original schedule and grant a licence to another joint venture company.</p>
<p>OUTLOOK REMAINS CLOUDY FOR NEXT TWO MONTHS</p>
<p>Going forward, the market looks set to go through a rough time on a two months' view.</p>
<p>Expectations of further increases in U.S. interest rates will put a cap on any market rally in the short-term. Outbreaks of riots could pick up in the lead-up to the May general election, and although so far this has done little to rock the market, investors are likely to react differently if any riots take place in the capital city. The market also seems vulnerable to rumours about President Suharto's health, especially after his recent comments that those wishing to re-elect him should take his age into consideration. The comments also had the effect of reviving speculation the he may not run in the upcoming (presidential) election.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, local investors are hurting. With the JCI having quickly retreated to its beginning-of-the-year levels, many of the local punters have seen their profits wiped out or even turned into losses. The sharp market decline in the last six weeks has triggered margin calls, and we have seen a lot of what appears to be forced selling by a number of local brokers of late.</p>
<p>BUT THERE ARE REASONS TO REMAIN POSITIVE..</p>
<p>The macroeconomic picture nonetheless remains favourable.</p>
<p>Inflation continues to look tame, the current account seems to be under control, and barring any dramatic increase in U.S. interest rates, domestic rates could soften further considering the excess liquidity in the banking system.</p>
<p>The central bank clearly wishes to see lower interest rates in order to discourage short-term capital inflows. In the meantime, it is hoping to keep monetary expansion in check through sterilised intervention and moral suasion on commercial banks to restrain their credit growth. Although the moral suasion tactic has not proved effective in the last two years, we are convinced the degree of violation will abate, especially with the implementation of the new rulings on small business loans and foreign-currency borrowings as well as the administrative sanctions on banks that violate the credit growth targets set by the central bank.</p>
<p>..WITH VALUATIONS NOW BACK IN BUY TERRITORY</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the market's valuation has retreated to levels which we believe to be reasonably attractive, with the prices of major stocks having dropped by some 10-20 percent in the last six weeks. The market is currently trading at 13.5x FY97 earnings versus a projected compound growth rate of 21 percent for this year and the next.</p>
<p>If the last two years are any indication of the future, we may be close to the bottom of the cycle in terms of valuation given that the market's propsective PE multiple has been oscillating within a relatively narrow band of 13x-16x since the beginning of 1995. If the market finishes the year with a prospective PE multiple of 13x, then we are looking at a year-end JCI of roughly 740 points, up 16 percent from the current level.</p>
<p>It is also worth bearing in mind that stock valuations will become even more compelling when investors start to look at 1998 earnings in three months time. On an FY98 basis, the market is currently trading at 11.1x earnings.</p>
<p>AND OPPORTUNITIES ABOUND</p>
<p>In conclusion, we fell that the ability to ride out the bumpy road ahead and look beyond short-term share price performances is key.</p>
<p>Investors are likly to adopt a wait-and-see approach in the lead-up to the election and announcement of Q1 results, which could lead to prolonged market weakness. However, this should be seen as an opportunity to re-position investment portfolios and switch into counters that have been beaten up.</p>
<p>From the earnings perspective, banking remains our favoured sector as the listed banks look set to report strong Q1 earnings figures on the back of a margin expansion and strong pick-up in loan growth in the Q4 last year.</p>
<p>(NOTE - The views expressed in this article represent the views of the author only. They should not be seen as reflecting the views of Reuters).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
