<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50144" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Vienna stocks battered by Flughafen sell-off.</title>
<headline>Vienna stocks battered by Flughafen sell-off.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian shares suffered bruising losses on Thursday as investors scurried to sell airport operator Flughafen Wien after it reported disappointing half-year earnings.</p>
<p>The ATX index of 21 blue chips shed 19.83 points, or 1.9 percent, to close at the day's low of 1,013.84. Of its constituents, 15 fell, four gained and two were unchanged.</p>
<p>Traders said the ATX is likely to fester around 1,020 points unless steelmaker VA Stahl's half-year figures due Friday present another surprise.</p>
<p>&quot;If VA Stahl comes out in-line with expectations, then that could bolster the market. At present we've got to digest the shock from Flughafen,&quot; said one trader. Traders said the ATX should first see support at 1,010 but that there was room down to 980 points.</p>
<p>Flughafen lost 15 percent and was by far the most actively traded stock on turnover of 231,001 lots. By contrast, the next most active stock, Creditanstalt's preferred shares, traded just under 44,000 lots.</p>
<p>The company said first-half pre-tax profit fell to 389 million schillings from 407 million in the year-ago period. The market had been looking for pre-tax profit to come in at around 450 to 470 million schillings.</p>
<p>The day's worst performer was Flughafen, shedding a hefty 107.4 schillings to 608.6, while Wolford was the leading gainer, adding on 1.53 percent to 2,584.</p>
<p>Also strong were VA Tech and insurer Wiener Staedtische. VA Tech added on nine schillings after surprising the market on Wednesday with better-than-expected first half earnings, and Wiener Staedtische gained 11 schillings after it announced today first-half premium income surged 34 percent.</p>
<p>Fibre-maker Lenzing tumbled 3.25 percent to 625 schillings on a report by London brokers James Capel predicting second-half losses will exceed the 84.5 million schillings pre-tax loss posted in the first six months.</p>
<p>The all-share Vienna Bourse index lost 5.21 points or 1.3 percent to close at 398.47.</p>
<p>The September ATX future fell 13.1 points to 1,016 on turnover of 409 contracts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
