<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501421" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Result restores faith in The Warehouse.</title>
<headline>Result restores faith in The Warehouse.</headline>
<byline>James Gray</byline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A big earnings turnaround in The Warehouse Group Ltd has restored the market's faith in the retailer, and analysts said on Thursday they were now looking at a full year result above NZ$30 million.</p>
<p>The discount chain on Wednesday reported earnings of NZ$25.3 million for the six months to January. Most analysts had expected a result under $20 million.</p>
<p>The company, which has changed to a January 31 balance date from a March 31 date, reported a NZ$5.26 million profit in the four months to July 31.  </p>
<p>&quot;There is probably some conjecture on what it means for the full year result still, but it definitely restores the company's credibility,&quot; said one analyst, who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>The Warehouse was caned by the market when it last year reported an annual result of NZ$23.11 million, down sharply from $35.23 million a year earlier and radically lower than market expectations. The stock at one point was driven down to NZ$2.00 -- its lowest point since listing in November, 1994.</p>
<p>Overstocking and systems problems were blamed for the poor outcome.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's a continuation of the rebuilding of its credibility after the hiccup of 1996 and the market loves them again,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;There had been a lot of doubters in the market. I guess they've got their act together a little quicker than people thought in terms of manning costs and other such things.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said there was some suggestion the period may have been more buoyant seasonally than originally thought.</p>
<p>Most now expected an annual result over NZ$30 million. The range of forecasts was wide, though an outcome in the high $30 millions was seen as unlikely.  </p>
<p>A clearer picture for the full year is expected to emerge when the company holds briefings on Friday.</p>
<p>The positive earnings surprise boosted the stock to a high for the year of NZ$3.75, later easing to NZ$3.67, which was 47 cents up on Wednesday's close.</p>
<p>The Warehouse is 53 percent owned by its principal, Stephen Tindall, and the Tindall foundation.</p>
<p>The AMP Society revealed on Monday that it held 8.09 percent, but brokers said the sharp gain in price was purely result-related and nothing to do with illiquidity.  </p>
<p>Warren Couillault, retail analyst at SBC Warburg, said The Warehouse had gone through a restoration process over the last six months.</p>
<p>&quot;I suppose the surprise is that margins have rebounded quite strongly. Most people were forecasting pretty strong gains but it was a bit of a surprise across the board,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;None of that result is assistance from the economy. It's 100 percent them getting their act together and taking out costs they incurred last year.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64-4-4734746)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
