<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501432" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Birch says has no agreement on NZ rating upgrade.</title>
<headline>Birch says has no agreement on NZ rating upgrade.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister Bill Birch said on Thursday that New Zealand had no agreement with credit rating agency Standard and Poor's on a sovereign upgrade.</p>
<p>Returning from a trip to New York where he met the rating agencies, he said that S&amp;P had not told him that the state of the New Zealand economy invited a rating upgrade, although this had been the gist of his presentations to them on the nation's economic outlook.  </p>
<p>Birch was unable to confirm wire agency reports that Standard &amp; Poor's had said it could see New Zealand's ratings improving if the currency economic trajectory continues.</p>
<p>&quot;They (ratings agencies) didn't go that far,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The minister said he had spent quite a lot of time with S&amp;P's New York-based head of sovereign ratings, David Beers.</p>
<p>&quot;What we said to him was that .. given our very positive fiscal forecasts and the performance of our economy, that must be an invitation to them to look at an upgrade.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Beers) nodded very sagely and wisely, and took the point on board,&quot; Birch added.  </p>
<p>Birch's comments echoed those he made to Reuters Financial Television in an interview from Hong Kong on Wednesday.</p>
<p>After those remarks the NZ dollar was squeezed higher and short term interest rates fell by up to 10 basis points.</p>
<p>Birch said he had also spoken to Moody's Investors Service, adding, &quot;we went pretty much through the same issue and we got pretty much the same respose from them.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Moody's made no indication of when it might change its rating stance on the country. &quot;They really would make their own judgement about it, and if they were considering an upgrade they would put us on what they call a positive watch&quot;.  </p>
<p>In S&amp;P's case, Birch said it was also &quot;a matter for them to decide&quot; when and how it expressed any change in rating view.</p>
<p>He said S&amp;P shared his opinion that forecasts of steady increases in the current account -- which some economists and analysts see as an area of concern in New Zealand's medium-term outlook -- could be regarded without too much worry.</p>
<p>&quot;Current account deficits can be an issue, particularly if a government is borrowing offshore to sustain high levels of consumption, but we are not doing that.</p>
<p>&quot;We are net savers, we have paid off our...foreign exchange public debt, and so the government itself is not contributing to the current account deficit.&quot;</p>
<p>Last year New Zealand paid off a tranche of foreign currency loans and has no net offshore debt outstanding.</p>
<p>--Catherine McCaw, Wellington newsroom +64 4 471 4273</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
