<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501530" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul says troops exchange warning shots on border.</title>
<headline>Seoul says troops exchange warning shots on border.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean soldiers fired 10 warning shots after spotting a group of North Korean soldiers at the border line within the Demilitarized Zone (DMZ) on Thursday, a Seoul military statement said.</p>
<p>The North Koreans returned the warning shots, the statement said. The shooting took place at 9.30 a.m. (0030 GMT), hours before U.S. Defence Secretary William Cohen visited the heavily-fortified DMZ, it added.  </p>
<p>The incident took place on the eastern sector of the DMZ, about 60 miles (100 km) east of the border crossing village of Panmunjom, which Cohen visited, South Korean military officials said.</p>
<p>South Korean troops patrolling the border broadcast warnings through loudspeakers at five or six North Koreans near the Military Demarcation Line before firing shots into the air, the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;The North Korean soldiers fired warning shots and withdrew,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The demarcation line runs through the middle of the four-km (2.5 mile)-wide DMZ, which has split the Korean peninsula since the 1950-53 Korean War.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
