<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501621" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Bankard says 1997 income target achievable.</title>
<headline>Bankard says 1997 income target achievable.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Credit card company Bankard Inc said on Thursday its 200 million peso net income target for this year was on track and dismissed fears its credit receivables and defaults have been on the rise.</p>
<p>&quot;It's on track for our target this year ... We are shooting for 200 million pesos this year in terms of bottom line,&quot; said Timothy Yang, vice president and financial controller, when asked about the company's first quarter performance.</p>
<p>The company registered a net income of 161.460 million pesos in 1996, against 125.930 million pesos in the previous year.</p>
<p>Yang also said the company did not experience any deterioration in the quality of its receivables.</p>
<p>&quot;That has not been our experience. In fact, our asset quality in 1996 is much better than that in 1995, less write offs as a percentage of receivables,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said first quarter write offs was about the same as in fourth quarter last year.</p>
<p>Bankard chairman Rafael Buenaventura said the company was able to keep its default rate down despite the substantial increase in volume.</p>
<p>&quot;If you are selective, you can still do business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bankard has been targeting the upper and upper-middle class markets.</p>
<p>The company is set to launch four new products this year to expand its cardholders' base which stood at 250,824 by the end of last year. Another 60,000 new cardholders were registered in the first two months of this year.</p>
<p>--Manila newsroom 63 2 8418938 Fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150108">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
