<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501759" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Main points of Reuter quarterly survey on Italy.</title>
<headline>Main points of Reuter quarterly survey on Italy.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main points of a Reuter quarterly poll of 17 analysts on the outlook for the Italian economy. The survey was conducted April 1 to 3.</p>
<p>* Italy's languishing economy is unlikely to emerge from the doldrums until the fourth quarter of 1997 when gross domestic product (GDP) growth will inch up from one percent and continue rising in 1998. The poll showed a mean forecast for 1997 growth of 1.1 percent against a previous estimate of 1.2 percent.</p>
<p>* The lira will weaken past 1,000 per mark in coming months but will stay within 2.25 percent of its 990 per mark central parity in Europe's exchange rate mechanism and is expected to gravitate back towards the 990 rate by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>* Economists see the Bank of Italy reducing key rates as early as the end of April when consumer price inflation could fall below 2.0 percent. Its discount rate stands at 6.75 percent.</p>
<p>* Consumer price growth is likely to dip below 2.0 percent in the second quarter of this year but that threshold will signify the trough in the trend of falling inflation and Italy is likely to end the year with 1997 average of 2.2 percent.</p>
<p>* Producer prices are forecast on average to grow 1.6 percent in the current 1997 quarter, rising to 2.3 by the final three months of the year and creeping up to average 2.6 in 1998.</p>
<p>* The mean forecast for 1997 industrial production saw limited growth of 0.8 percent, rising progressively from a fall of 1.7 percent in the first three months of the year to a 2.6 percent increase in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>* Unemployment is seen little changed with a mean forecast of 12.3 percent which could decline to 12.0 percent in 1998 if planned government policy measures to create jobs bore fruit. In the quarter to January, the jobless rate stood at 12.4 percent.</p>
<p>* Bond yields are expected to creep up over the coming quarter even if the Bank of Italy can see its way to lowering official interest rates, although current political uncertainty and concern that European economic and monetary union (EMU) may not start on time are making yields hard to predict.</p>
<p>* Expectations for the benchmark 10-year BTP yield at the end of June vary by two points, with the average 7.85 percent -- a little up on the current yield of 7.63 percent.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +392 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
