<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501753" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: UPM plans to cut Rauma stake more.</title>
<headline>UPM plans to cut Rauma stake more.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish forest industry group UPM-Kymmene Oy said in a statement on Thursday it was studying the possibilities to further reduce its stake in engineering group Rauma Oy and bring it to a significant minority holding.</p>
<p>&quot;UPM-Kymmene and Rauma now agree that the shareholders of both companies will be best served by reducing the UPM-Kymmene holding in Rauma as soon as possible, subject to market conditions,&quot; it said, adding SBC Warburg would act as adviser.  </p>
<p>UPM has proposed to its annual general meeting on Thursday to pay 3.00 markka per share of its 4.50 markka 1996 dividend in Rauma shares, reducing its 73.3 percent stake to 59.9 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;For the longer term, UPM-Kymmene's objective is to retain only a significant but minority shareholding in Rauma,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>UPM has earlier announced that it intended to bring its Rauma holding below 50 percent through other means. In its 1996 annual report, it said the dividend was a one-time arrangement.</p>
<p>&quot;The reduction of the holding and subsequently increased liquidity is expected to enhance the attraction of Rauma shares to investors,&quot; UPM said.</p>
<p>UPM said it would use funds derived from any potential sale of Rauma shares to focus on its core pulp and paper business.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +358-9-680 50 245, news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
