<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501723" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwait Oil Co union says considering strike in May.</title>
<headline>Kuwait Oil Co union says considering strike in May.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kuwait Oil Co (KOC) workers union said on Thursday it was considering a possible strike in May over a dispute with the state-owned firm about promotions.</p>
<p>&quot;If there was no solution next month...there could be a strike,&quot; union chairman Mohammad al-Sarahan told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we are in talks with the (KOC) officials.&quot;  </p>
<p>Sarhan said: &quot;If the circumstances required and we found a firm stance from the management of the company (KOC)...there would be a strike.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Things here are going towards aggravation because the issue of (workers') grades, over which the 1995 strike took place, is not over yet despite promises by officials.&quot;</p>
<p>In March 1995 the union launched a strike aimed at halting Kuwait's three percent share of world production to demand a reshuffle of employment grades.</p>
<p>There are some 750 KOC export, maintenance, and gas operations workers whose working conditions needed to be fixed, he said.</p>
<p>KOC is the production arm of the state-owned conglomerate Kuwait Petroleum Corp (KPC) which oversees the oil industry.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in talks with the Ministry of Social Affairs and Labour,&quot; he said. The Ministry mediates between workers and employers in labour disputes.</p>
<p>OPEC member Kuwait produces about 2.0 million barrels of crude per day.  </p>
<p>A senior KOC official said he would not comment on the matter &quot;until the company recieves details from the union about the subject.&quot;</p>
<p>Kuwait newsroom, Inal Ersan +965-243-1920</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
