<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501750" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: World trade growth slowed in 1996, WTO reports.</title>
<headline>World trade growth slowed in 1996, WTO reports.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Growth in the world goods trade, hit by sluggish demand in Western Europe and slowdown in major Asian economies, dropped to four per cent last year from eight per cent in 1995, an authoritative report said on Thursday.</p>
<p>But, in its annual review of global figures, the World Trade Organisation (WTO) predicted a modest increase in trade volume in 1997 if an expected overall recovery in the two key regions during the year is confirmed.</p>
<p>And the report found Latin America, with a growth in export volume of 11 per cent led by a strong 20 per cent surge from Mexico, and North America -- the United States and Canada -- with 5.5 per cent, running well ahead of the global average.</p>
<p>The global figure was three per cent lower than that predicted by the WTO early last year and one per cent down on a forecast it issued last December at its first-ever ministerial meeting in Singapore.</p>
<p>Also down was the growth rate of the value of trade in commercial services, from banking to tourism, which dropped to about five per cent from 14 per cent in 1995.</p>
<p>Compiled by WTO economic analysts, the report noted that last year's growth in goods trade volume was in line with the average for the first four years of the decade, and followed two strong years with a peak at 10 per cent in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;A modest increase in trade growth is expected this year, based largely on the projected recovery of economic growth and trade in Western Europe and Asia, and continued high growth in Latin America,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The report recorded that trade growth was still running well ahead of world goods output or GDP -- 2.5 per cent last year -- as it has consistently since the mid-1980s, underpinning WTO arguments that trade is a motor of the global economy.</p>
<p>With Western Europe performing poorly for the fifth year, it was Asia's surprise export growth decline from over 9.5 per cent in 1995 to 2.5 per cent, that had played a major part in the downswing, the study indicated.</p>
<p>&quot;Although output growth was still well above that of the six other regions, Asia's export growth in 1996 was not only below output growth, but also the smallest export growth among the regions,&quot; the WTO said.</p>
<p>The extent of the slowdown was unexpected, considering that the drop in the region's GDP growth rate was modest, it added.</p>
<p>The report said there was still no full explanation of the causes of the Asian decline, but suggested one reason was a sharp drop in world demand for office and telecommunications equipment which play a major role in Asian exports.</p>
<p>In value terms, according to the report, global exports had gone over the $5,000 billion mark ($2.9 trillion) for the first time, touching $5,100 billion by the end of December, a figure which also marked a four per cent increase on 1995.</p>
<p>This compared with 20 per cent value growth in 1995 over 1994, but much of the relative decline was accounted for by the effect of the appreciation of the U.S. dollar in 1996 against other major currencies, according to the report.</p>
<p>In terms of value, the United States remained the world's number one individual exporter, with a nearly 12 per cent share of the global total of $5,100 billion, and the top importer, with just over 15 per cent, according to the report.</p>
<p>But with figures for all its 15 members counted together, the European Union was the top exporting power, while, excluding trade among its members, it remained the second importer after the United States.  $= 1.722 German Marks)  REUTERS</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
