<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501815" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - April 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - April 10.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in the Swedish papers this morning. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAGENS NYHETER</p>
<p>- Swedish financers the Wallenbergs have strengthened their power by getting influence in companies previously outside the family's sphere, according to former AB Volvo head, Per Gyllenhammar. He said in a TV interview that Sweden needed alternatives to Wallenbergs' empire.</p>
<p>- The Swedish government will, in its April 15 spring budget proposal, allocate 1.1 billion crowns annually to Stockholm's traffic system, a source told the newspaper.</p>
<p>- Sweden's main opposition party, the conservative Moderate Party, approves of the way the minority Social Democratic government has handled negotiations about the European Union's future by giving it four points out of a possible five.</p>
<p>SVENSKA DAGBLADET</p>
<p>- There are large price differences on electricity in the Stockholm region. Heating a house with electricity is 4,293 crowns cheaper annually in Taby than on the islands in Malaren.</p>
<p>- The Swedish government says it could see Estonia joining the European Union (EU) before the other two Baltic countries, Latvia and Lithuania.</p>
<p>- Marcus Storch will step down as chairman of investment company Custos after losing a power struggle in construction company Skanska, in which Custos holds 6.1 percent of capital and 23.6 percent of votes.</p>
<p>DAGENS INDUSTRI</p>
<p>- The dominoes continue to fall in unexpected ways following the announcement on April 3 that Percy Barnevik would take over as chairman of Investor, the financial vehicle of the Wallenberg family. Only three weeks prior to the annual board meeting of holding company Custos, chairman of the board Marcus Storch has resigned, following a corporate struggle regarding the appointmentof a new chairman of construction company Skanska.</p>
<p>- Minister of Culture Marita Ulvskog plans to force the Bonnier group, Sweden's largest publishing conglomerate, to relinquish part of its media holdings. Ulvskog objects to Bonnier-owned Marieberg's purchase of a large stake in commercial television station TV4.</p>
<p>- A majority of Swedish legislators are expected to support a proposal to sell 49 percent of public telephone company Telia. The only party still opposed to privatisation is the Left Party, according to an analysis of the Swedish telephone market by the Procivitas consulting group.</p>
<p>-- Birgitta Forsberg, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
