<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501899" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU:  EP BUDGETS COMMITTEE AGENDA - APRIL 14-15.</title>
<headline>EP BUDGETS COMMITTEE AGENDA - APRIL 14-15.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Budgets [[ Monday 14 April 1997 ]] 1. Adoption of draft agenda (222.015 ) 2. Chairman's announcements 3. Approval of minutes of meetings of: - 10 March 1997 (PE221.999 ) - 19-20 March 1997 (PE222.001) 4. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure 5. Financial implications of enlargement of the Union (PE222.012 ) - Rapporteur: Efthymios CHRISTODOULOU (PE222.003 ) - Exchange of views in preparation for the Round Table on 22 May (PE221.996/ANN) ===] 1998 budget 6.1 Budget 1998 - Section III (T05367) BUD0083 + BUDG Fond R TILLICH Stanislaw. (PPE) - Working Document 2: Preparation for enlargement (PE222.000 ) - Exchange of views 6.2 Financial perspective: adaptation and technical adjustment - T05398 - ( BUD0088 - SEC(97)0364 - C4-0111/97 (PE222.008 ) - SEC(97)0362 - Rapporteur: Stanislaw TILLICH - Consideration and adoption of a draft report 6.3 EP estimates for 1998 (T05370) BUD0086 + BUDG Fond R TOMLINSON John E. (PSE) (PE222.014) - Consideration of draft report - Deadline for tabling amendments 6.4 Information policy: EURONEWS - Rapporteurs: Stanislaw TILLICH and Laurens Jan BRINKHORST - - Joint Working Document 3 (PE222.005 ) - Exchange of views ===] 1997 budget 7.1 Implementation of the 1997 budget - other institutions - Rapporteur: Juan-Manuel FABRA-VALLES - - Notice to members 8/97 (PE222.009 ) - - Notice to members 9/97 (PE222.010 ) 7.2 Possible transfers 8. Arable crops and agricultural structures: amendment of Regulations (EEC) 1765/92 and 2328/91 (T04950) CNS96213 COM(96)0422 C4-0449/96 CNS96212 COM(97)0022 C4-0448/96 + BUDG Avis A KATIFORIS Georgios. (PSE) (PE219.055/DEF) F AGRI Fond R FUNK Honor. (PPE) (PE219.617 ) - Adoption of draft opinion 9. Agricultural prices for 1997/98 and related measures (T05050) CNS97087 COM(97)0089 C4-0114/97 CNS97088 COM(97)0089 C4-0115/97 CNS97089 COM(97)0089 C4-0116/97 CNS97905 COM(97)0089 C4-0117/97 CNS97091 COM(97)0089 C4-0118/97 CNS97092 COM(97)0089 C4-0119/97 CNS97093 COM(97)0089 C4-0120/97 CNS97094 COM(97)0089 C4-0121/97 CNS97906 COM(97)0089 C4-0122/97 CNS97096 COM(97)0089 C4-0123/97 CNS97097 COM(97)0089 C4-0124/97 CNS97098 COM(97)0089 C4-0125/97 CNS97099 COM(97)0089 C4-0126/97 CNS97100 COM(97)0089 C4-0127/97 CNS97101 COM(97)0089 C4-0128/97 CNS97102 COM(97)0089 C4-0129/97 + BUDG Avis A KATIFORIS Georgios. (PSE) (PE222.004 ) + BUDG Avis KATIFORIS Georgios. (PSE) (PE222.004 ) F AGRI Fond R STURDY Robert W. (PPE) (PE221.786 ) - Adoption of draft opinion 10. Amendment of the Financial Regulation applicable to the general budget of the European Communities (SEM 2000) (T04961) CNS96189 COM(96)0351 C4-0497/96 + BUDG Avis A DELL'ALBA Gianfranco (ARE) (PE221.614 ) F CONT Fond R SARLIS Pavlos. (PPE) - Adoption of draft opinion 11. Annual report of the Cohesion Fund, 1995 (T04994) COS0461 COM(96)0388 C4-0509/96 + BUDG Avis A KAKLAMANIS Nikitas. (UPE) F REGI Fond R NOVO Honorio. (GUE) (PE219.991 ) - Adoption of draft opinion 12. Sport in the European Union (T04688) B4-0467/96 B4-0467/96 + BUDG Avis A TOMLINSON John E. (PSE) (PE219.095) F JEUN Fond R PACK Doris G. (PPE) (PE221.803/A) 13. Council Regulation on general rules for the application of measures to improve the production and marketing of honey (T05312) CNS96282 COM(96)0596 C4-0031/97 + BUDG Avis A TRAUTMANN Catherine. (PSE) F AGRI Fond R LULLING Astrid. (PPE) (PE220.712 ) - Adoption of draft opinion 14. Openness in information society services; amendment of Directive 83/189/EEC - technical standards and regulations (T04382) PE222.007 CNS96283 COM(96)0592 C4-0030/97 + BUDG Avis L F ECON Fond R HENDRICK Mark P. (PSE) (PE221.828 ) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 15. VAT on telecommunications (amendment of Directive 77/388/EEC) (T05400) CNS97030 COM(97)0004 C4-0100/97 + BUDG Avis L (PE222.002 ) F ECON Fond R (ELD) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 16. Date of next meeting (PE/III/OJ/97-08 ) - FIN - END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
