<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501913" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-HUSTON EAGLES LAST HOLE TO LEAD MASTERS.</title>
<headline>GOLF-HUSTON EAGLES LAST HOLE TO LEAD MASTERS.</headline>
<byline>Walter Bagley</byline>
<dateline>AUGUSTA, Georgia 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>John Huston eagled the 18th hole -- from the 10th fairway -- on Thursday to lead the first round of the Masters on a day when putting Augusta National's greens was a nightmare for many golfers.</p>
<p>Huston, whose best Masters was his first in 1990, holed out with a five-iron from 190 yards away on Augusta's 405-yard final hole to post a five-under-par 67 -- his first sub-par score in seven rounds in the Masters.</p>
<p>Woods, seeking to become the youngest Masters champion, easily outplayed defending champion Nick Faldo in the most closely followed pairing of the day.</p>
<p>Faldo, hoping to add a fourth Masters green jacket to his already crowded closet, shot 75 after going out in five-over 41 as both he and Woods struggled before enormous galleries.</p>
<p>Woods, a three-time U.S. Amateur champion, finished alone in fourth place, just ahead of 1994 champion Jose Maria Olazabal of Spain, who is recovering from a career-threatening injury, former British Open champion and two-time PGA Championship winner Nick Price and Costantino Rocca of Italy.</p>
<p>Ten players were at level par 72, including former winner Fred Couples and two-time champion Bernhard Langer of Germany.</p>
<p>Only seven players broke par -- the third fewest in one round of the Masters -- thanks to the early swirling winds and some very challenging pin placements on Augusta's always superfast greens.</p>
<p>&quot;After the fourth hole, I would have bet no one was going to finish in the 60s,&quot; said Huston, who played in the second-to-last pairing of the day, when the wind had dissipated.</p>
<p>Stankowski also took advantage of steadily improving weather conditions -- as did Woods, who bogeyed the first, fourth, eighth and ninth holes before righting himself.</p>
<p>&quot;I was pretty hot over the way I was playing,&quot; Woods said of his front nine, before showing why so many people expect him to become one of the game's finest players.</p>
<p>&quot;We got the better draw with the weather,&quot; Stankowski admitted. &quot;When the wind is blowing you have to play differently.&quot;</p>
<p>Forty of the 86 players shot 77 or worse as some unusual pin placements had many golfers putting defensively -- even on their third or fourth putts.</p>
<p>&quot;I had a lot of six to 10 footers that I was just trying to two-putt,&quot; said Azinger, who is fully recovered from cancer that sidelined him for most of 1994.</p>
<p>A club official, in a highly uncharacteristic revelation for Augusta National, said the committee that decided where to cut the holes on the putting surfaces had been taken surprise by the wind and the firmness of the greens.</p>
<p>&quot;The conditions were more difficult than they thought they would be,&quot; the official said. It was a statement that provoked no argument.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the time I was just trying not to three-putt,&quot; Stankowski said, summing up the kind of day it was for almost everyone.</p>
<p>That was one very good reason why Huston was overjoyed with his eagle at the last.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a relief that you don't have to putt,&quot; he said of holing out from the fairway.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUGUSTA, Georgia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
