<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501943" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: TENNIS-JOHANSSON CONTINUES HOT STREAK IN HONG KONG OPEN.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-JOHANSSON CONTINUES HOT STREAK IN HONG KONG OPEN.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's Thomas Johansson, the hottest player on the circuit with 14 straight victories, reached the semifinals of the Hong Kong Open on Friday with two wins in five hours.</p>
<p>Johannson, whose ranking has jumped from 60 to 39 thanks to back-to-back successes in Copenhagen and St Petersburg, sailed past American Jim Grabb 6-1 6-2 in his second round match and then defeated another American, 20-year-old Justin Gimelstob, 6-4 6-4 in the quarter-finals.</p>
<p>&quot;I played really well today and kept the run going,&quot; said 22-year-old Johansson, the fourth seed. &quot;It was a tough match against Gimelstob and I was lucky to win the break points.&quot;</p>
<p>Johansson will play top seed and two-time Hong Kong Open winner Michael Chang in the semifinals. The Chinese-American, who enjoys great support in Hong Kong, finished off his rain-delayed second round match against compatriot Jeff Tarango 6-4 4-6 6-1 and then beat seventh-seed David Prinosil of Germany 6-1 7-6 (7-5) in the quarter-finals.</p>
<p>&quot;Thomas (Johannson) is definitely on a high,&quot; said Chang, winner here in 1994 and 1995. &quot;I have never played him but when you are up against a Swede it is always going to be tough.&quot;</p>
<p>The other semifinal will be between fifth seeded Australian Patrick Rafter, who booked his place with a near faultless 6-3 6-1 win over Davis Cup teammate Todd Woodbridge, and qualifier Brian MacPhie of the United States.</p>
<p>MacPhie, ranked a lowly 308th in the world, defeated the unseeded Sebastien Lareau of Canada 6-3 6-3 in the last eight after causing an upset in the second round earlier in the day when he beat the number two seed, Marc Rosset of Switzerland, 7-6 (7-2) 6-2.</p>
<p>&quot;If I serve well I can frustrate players,&quot; said MacPhie after reaching his first ATP Tour semi-final. &quot;This could be a real jump start for my singles career. If I keep playing the way I have been, I can do alright against Pat (Rafter).&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
