<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="502025" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: BUCHAREST BOURSE TO IMPROVE SETTLEMENT SYSTEM.</title>
<headline>BUCHAREST BOURSE TO IMPROVE SETTLEMENT SYSTEM.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bucharest stock exchange said on Friday it aimed to present within a month an improved version of a system allowing custodians to take part in clearing and settlement of trades.</p>
<p>&quot;New rules are being elaborated and they will be finalised and endorsed in up to four weeks,&quot; a bourse statement said.</p>
<p>Under the present system, custodians have control over shares but make settlements through private Bankcoop SA, the exchange's settlement bank, bourse official Adriana Tanasoiu told Reuters.</p>
<p>The improved system will allow them to become members of the custody system and make their own settlements for their clients, she added.</p>
<p>Equity market regulator CNVM said it had so far licensed four banks and a securities company to operate as custodians in Romania.</p>
<p>Tanasoiu said the Romanian subsidiary of Dutch ABN-AMRO was the first to act as custodian on the stock exchange, using the present system.</p>
<p>On Friday, ABN-AMRO said it had started operating as a custodian also on the over-the-counter market.</p>
<p>The Bucharest branch of Dutch ING Bank also announced it had won a CNVM licence to act as a custodian bank offering services for both equities and treasury bills.</p>
<p>The other two banks are Societe Generale and Romanian commercial bank Banca Transilvania.</p>
<p>Creditanstalt Securities SA, which operates as broker on Romania's stock exchange and OTC market, has also launched licensed custody services.</p>
<p>Custody services, a new product in Romania, were welcomed by bourse officials, brokers and analysts.</p>
<p>They say the new facilities minimising risks to investors' holdings would boost foreign investment and encourage big players to step into the market.</p>
<p>-- Luli Popescu, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
