<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="502108" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Capacity war hits UK-Jo'burg, Lagos aircargo rates.</title>
<headline>Capacity war hits UK-Jo'burg, Lagos aircargo rates.</headline>
<byline>Bob Murphy</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>While the ex-UK to South Africa and Nigeria air cargo markets continue to attract large volumes of freight, fierce capacity competition is placing downward pressure on rates, a Reuters survey shows.</p>
<p>To other African countries, rate levels differ considerably, depending on the state of local economies, marketplace demand and the number of flights available on particular routes.</p>
<p>But a general consensus of opinion amongst airlines and forwarders questioned was that the most encouraging UK-Africa routes in terms of present cargo yields and potential included Zimbabwe, Ghana, Ethiopia, Botswana and, to a slightly lesser extent, Kenya.</p>
<p>On the other hand, they noted that Zambia and Malawi are markets struggling due to a combination of economic and political difficulties.</p>
<p>&quot;South Africa has always been a good airfreight destination for Britain, attracting a consistently high level of traffic,&quot; said Alex Hedges, director of BDA International, UK cargo general sales agent for Air Seychelles which serves Johannesburg via Mahe.</p>
<p>He added that the decline of the rand against the pound over recent times initially affected demand. But South African companies began running out of supplies and turned back to UK and other European manufacturers to replenish their supplies.</p>
<p>&quot;But although we have seen more cargo coming onto the route, this has been offset by a lot more capacity being introduced over the last six months, including freighters,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ethiopian Airlines' UK passenger and cargo sales manager Peter Talkington noted that fierce competition had seen ex-London cargo rates steadily fall to South Africa over the past year.</p>
<p>&quot;And we are well aware of British Airways' aggressive pricing policies on the route,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Philip Thompsett, UK/Ireland manager of all-cargo Affretair, sister company of Air Zimbabwe, said he believed there were now up to 50 carriers offering UK-South Africa services via numerous routeings.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a big market and we send 50-60 tonnes a week to Johannesburg from the UK. But naturally, all of this competition has driven rates down -- by 40 percent in the last two years I would estimate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The regular Reuters UK-Africa air cargo market report is substantially expanded from this edition, with Lagos, Harare, Accra and Entebbe added to Johannesburg, Nairobi and Libreville in the rates table.</p>
<p>Nigeria was described as &quot;a dirt cheap market...it is now and always has been&quot; by Mark Bright, director of Cameroon Airlines' UK cargo gsa Air Cargo Partners.</p>
<p>He forecast that the situation would not improve in the foreseeable future due to strong competition, much of it offered by low-cost charter operators flying freighter aircraft.</p>
<p>Colin Carr, director of Nigeria Airways'  NIA.CN UK cargo gsa Air Sea Broker, agreed that London-Lagos was &quot;highly competitive and very much a low rate market&quot;, adding that it was also &quot;volatile&quot;.</p>
<p>He said that Nigeria was traditionally used as a &quot;staging post&quot; stopover by many airlines flying to and from southern Africa because of its usually low fuel charges.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of weight and volume, large volumes of cargo are moved from the UK to Nigeria and as far as demand is concerned, the market is quite buoyant at present,&quot; he stated.</p>
<p>&quot;But all the capacity made available by both charter and scheduled carriers keeps rates down,&quot; said Carr.</p>
<p>Another route that attracted plenty of airfreight but also suffered from too much capacity was London-Nairobi, said Kenya Airways' UK cargo manager Jeffrey Fish.</p>
<p>But without elaborating, he hinted that current healthy market conditions could soon see rate increases introduced by more than one carrier.</p>
<p>Air Seychelles' Hedges described Kenya as &quot;a very competitive, up-and-down, fairly low rate market&quot;, adding that it was presently &quot;fairly consistent...quite buoyant&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
