<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="502258" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania awaits exiled king as Italian troops land.</title>
<headline>Albania awaits exiled king as Italian troops land.</headline>
<byline>David Brough</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-04-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanians awaited on Saturday the arrival of their exiled king, who was expected to appeal for an end to violence in the lawless Balkan state after the first contingent of a multinational security force arrived.</p>
<p>Guri Durollari of the Legality Movement Party said King Leka I had received the approval of the government to return home and would arrive at Tirana airport at 1 p.m. (1100 GMT) on a private plane from exile in South Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;He will call on Albanians to put an end to violence and to put their guns away,&quot; Durollari told Reuters.</p>
<p>King Leka, 58, who was only a few days old when his father, King Zog, fled the country with his family in 1939, would call for a referendum to let Albanians decide whether or not to restore the monarchy, Durollari said.</p>
<p>&quot;He is here to settle. He is here to stay,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Leka, tall and bespectacled, only once tried to visit Albania, in 1993. He was unceremoniously bundled back onto a plane within 24 hours on the grounds that his passport marked &quot;Kingdom of Albania&quot; was invalid.</p>
<p>Durollari said President Sali Berisha had reiterated his approval of Leka's visit during a meeting in Tirana on Friday.</p>
<p>About 70 Italian soldiers arrived in Albania on Friday to prepare for the landing from Monday of a 6,000-strong multinational force that aims to protect the distribution of food and medicines to Albanians after weeks of near-anarchy.</p>
<p>Albanians greeted their arrival with indifference.</p>
<p>Twenty beaming Italian soldiers marched onto a pier in the western port of Durres beginning a mission marking the first time Italy had led a multinational force in post-war history.</p>
<p>&quot;Our mission does not rule out risks, but we hope the Albanian people will understand that we are here to help them,&quot; said Colonel Enrico Nardi, commander of the Italian unit in Durres, 40 km (25 miles) west of Tirana.</p>
<p>Four Lockheed C130 Hercules aircraft carrying more than 50 paratroopers arrived at Tirana's airport in the morning.</p>
<p>As well as the Italians, soldiers from France, Spain, Romania, Turkey and Greece are coming to Albania to help safeguard deliveries of emergency food and medical supplies.</p>
<p>The armed lawlessness in which more than 200 people were killed and 700 wounded since several fraudulent get-rich-quick investment schemes collapsed claimed more casualties on Friday.</p>
<p>A 16-year-old boy was killed in a village near the southern town of Vlore when a grenade he was playing with exploded, police said. A 15-year-old boy was seriously injured.</p>
<p>Several people were hurt in a gun battle between police and a gang in Fier, 110 km (70 miles) south of Tirana, police said.</p>
<p>Two armed men stormed a town meeting and tried to take control, they said. The two were backed by about 15 others firing rifles into the sky.</p>
<p>After a skirmish with police, the gang commandeered a police armoured personnel carrier (APC) and escaped.</p>
<p>In the northern town of Shkoder, hospital workers demonstrated on Friday against the violence after two doctors were shot and wounded in a daylight attack on the hospital. The reasons for the attack were unclear.</p>
<p>Albanian state television showed graphic images of doctors operating on a colleague.</p>
<p>On Friday night, a regular crackle of automatic rifle fire rang out in Tirana.</p>
<p>In Durres, dozens of journalists greeted the Italian soldiers, but only a handful of Albanians were on hand.</p>
<p>&quot;All this for only 20 soldiers?&quot; asked 50-year-old port worker Besim, watching three dozen newsmen scramble to interview them. &quot;There are more journalists than soldiers.&quot;</p>
<p>The advance unit landing at Tirana airport included special forces to secure the perimeter and specialists to ensure the airport could operate round the clock.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
