<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="502357" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Italian troops arrive on historic Albanian mission.</title>
<headline>Italian troops arrive on historic Albanian mission.</headline>
<byline>Marko Bello</byline>
<dateline>DURRES, Albania 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The first 20 Italian troops on an historic mission to Albania arrived in this port city west of Tirana on Friday and were immediately ambushed by a small army of journalists.</p>
<p>Outnumbering the soldiers by nearly two to one, reporters and cameramen quickly descended on the advance party for interviews as soon as they stepped onto the dock.</p>
<p>The soliders, clad in combat fatigues, chatted warmly for about an hour with the pack of nearly 40 journalists and camera crews, most of them from Italy. Standing on the sun-drenched pier in front of the brilliant turquoise Adriatic, they also handed pieces of candy to local children.</p>
<p>The arrival of the first soldiers in the first Italian-led multinational security force was big news in Italy and many countries sending 6,000 troops to help secure the supply of medical and food supplies.</p>
<p>But only a handful of Albanians, who have been waiting for more than a month for international assistance to arrive, were on hand to witness the Italians in Durres.</p>
<p>&quot;All this for only 20 soldiers?&quot; asked a 50-year-old port worker named Besim as he watched the commotion on the dock. &quot;There are more journalists here than soldiers.&quot;</p>
<p>Many of the television camera crews spent the night scanning the sea for the first signs of the Italian transport ship Pantelleria, which left the southeastern Italian port of Brindisi on Thursday after darkness fell.</p>
<p>The ship, escorted by the minesweeper Rimini, arrived shortly after 8 a.m. (0600 GMT) and spent about 30 minutes trying to get its gangplank lined up on the shore. Five military vehicles armed with roof-mounted machine guns drove off first, followed by the rest of the 20 soldiers.</p>
<p>Although Albania has been racked by weeks of near anarchy and armed banditry, Durres' port has been quiet for several weeks and regular passenger ferry traffic to Italy was resumed two weeks ago.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't thing they are going to attack us, because they need us,&quot; said an Italian lieutenant named Sandro, who politely declined to provide his surname. &quot;We want to help our Albanian friends.&quot;</p>
<p>Noting that he had already served in Bosnia, Sandro said he would not hesitate to help supply aid in Albania's south, where armed rebels have been in control since early March.</p>
<p>&quot;I am ready to go to Vlore too,&quot; he said, referring to the southern Albanian city.</p>
<p>A captain named Giorgio, like the others carrying a pistol and rifle, said many of the troops had been on other U.N.-backed peacekeeping missions and said he hoped the Albanians understood they were here to help.</p>
<p>&quot;I have been in Somalia, Addis Ababa and I think it is going to be okay even here,&quot; Giorgio said.</p>
<p>Asked by one Italian reporter if he knew that Italy's fascist leader Benito Mussolini sent troops to occupy Albania through the Durres port 58 years ago this month, Sandro shrugged his shoulders.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know what happened then, but I am sure we are here to help people in need,&quot; Giorgio said.</p>
<p>Although the Albanian media has so far devoted surprisingly little attention to the arrival of the multinational forces, several local residents said they were glad the troops had finally arrived.</p>
<p>&quot;They are welcome and we need them,&quot; said a 28-year-old port worker named Asim. &quot;We don't think they will be attacked. We love Italy and Italian people because we watch Italian TV all the time.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DURRES, Albania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
