<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="502370" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>MACEDONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Macedonia - April 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Macedonia - April 11.</headline>
<dateline>SKOPJE 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Skopje press on Friday, Reuters has not verified them nor does it vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>NOVA MAKEDONIJA</p>
<p>- According to the Macedonian public prosecutor, no government officials were clients of the bankrupt TAT financial society from Bitola. According to the statement only daughter of education minister Sofija Todorova and the wife of Construction minister Jorgo Sundovski, who has resigned, had deposits in TAT.</p>
<p>- Macedonian Prime Minister Branko Crvenkovski said following talks with German chancellor Helmut Kohl that Germany would continue its support to Macedonia which has proved that economic and political reforms can be achieved in a peaceful way.</p>
<p>- Despite Macedonian officials' protests U.N. special human rights envoy for the former Yugoslavia Elisabeth Rehn asks for extension of her mandate in Macedonia.</p>
<p>- Greek composer Mikis Theodorakis said in Skopje that politicians should resolve political problems while peoples should cooperate at all levels. Theodorakis is in Macedonia for a performance of Zorba the Greek in the Macedonian National Theatre on Saturday. -- Mircela Casule, Skopje newsroom 389 91 201 196</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MCDNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SKOPJE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MACEDONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
