<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="502437" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>HAITI: Grammy-award winning Haitian group returns home. [CORRECTED 08:45 GMT 12/4]</title>
<headline>Grammy-award winning Haitian group returns home. [CORRECTED 08:45 GMT 12/4]</headline>
<byline>Anna Wardenburg</byline>
<dateline>PORT-AU-PRINCE 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Members of the million-selling Haitian-American rap group the Fugees waved from the balcony of the national palace in Port-au-Prince on Friday to fans crowding up to the fence to glimpse their new idols.</p>
<p>&quot;I am one of those kids that was never allowed in the palace. That means any one of those children could be standing in this spot too,&quot; singer Wyclef Jean said.</p>
<p>The Fugees are a rare success story for this poor and politically troubled country and Fugee mania has gripped Haiti on their homecoming from the United States for a benefit concert.</p>
<p>Their album &quot;The Score&quot; has sold 14 million copies worldwide, and the group won a Grammy award for Best Rap Album in February. It also won for Best R&amp;B Duo or Group Performance for the song &quot;Killing Me Softly With His Song.&quot;</p>
<p>(Corrects to make clear &quot;The Score&quot; is not their first album.)</p>
<p>Since the group arrived on Wednesday, their music has taken over Haiti's airwaves and their latest song, &quot;One Chance&quot;, sung in Creole, is on the lips of many Haitians.</p>
<p>Jean and another member, Praz, were born in Haiti and moved to the United States as children. The third member, Lauryn Hill, was born in the United States to Haitian parents.</p>
<p>The homecoming concert on Saturday will raise money for refugees repatriated from the Dominican Republic.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of these people were taken from their families and their jobs and sent back to Haiti with nothing,&quot; Hill said.</p>
<p>A stage has been erected on the downtown waterfront. MTV is filming the concert, and streets have been cleaned and potholes filled so the world will see a positive image of Haiti.</p>
<p>&quot;I am glad that MTV and all the international media have come so the world can see that Haiti is a country in peace,&quot; Haitian President Rene Preval said at Friday's ceremony in their honour at the palace.</p>
<p>On Thursday the Fugees were given the key to the city by folk singer and mayor Manno Charlemagne after visiting refugees and children at a school in La Saline slum.</p>
<p>&quot;I want the world to know I am a child of Haitian culture,&quot; Wyclef said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT-AU-PRINCE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HAITI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
