<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="502450" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks dragged sharply down by Wall Street.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks dragged sharply down by Wall Street.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks closed sharply down on Friday after succumbing to a domino effect that spread from Wall Street throughout Latin American markets in the wake of strong U.S. sales and producer prices data, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The bourse definitely slid due to developments on the Dow Jones. They propped it up at support but pressure from the U.S. long bond still weighed it down,&quot; said Roberto Galvan,</p>
<p>The leading IPC share index ended down 57.29 points, or 1.50 percent, at 3,764.46. Trading volume was moderate at 62.6 million shares.  </p>
<p>&quot;U.S. producer price data released early today, and hourly wages last week have fueled exoectations of a rates hike at the U.S. Federal Open Market Committee meeting on May 20,&quot; Galvan said.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones plunged 148.36 points to 6,391.69, while the U.S. 30-year Treasury bond was off 21/32 to yield 7.17 percent.</p>
<p>In Brazil, the Bovespa index fell 2.21 percent to 9,518 points, while the Argentine Merval index plummeted 2.79 percent.</p>
<p>Dealers noted a lack of foreign investors in the market.  </p>
<p>&quot;Locals are still making the market. Share prices fell on thin volume because most dealers are just switching paper without greatly modifying positions,&quot; a floor trader said.</p>
<p>Traders said Telmex L shares weighed down the bourse most and accounted for 21 percent of all shares traded. The telecomms firm's L class ended down 36 centavos at 15.84 pesos, while its ADRs ended off 7/8 at 40.</p>
<p>Financial Group GFB B class was another heavily traded decliner, off six centavos at 2.58 pesos on fears of interest rate hikes that would increase the group's past-due loans burden, traders said.  </p>
<p>On the broad market, 102 stocks changed hands, of which decliners outnumbered gainers by 54 to 18.</p>
<p>Cement maker Grupo Cementos de Chihuahua was a prominent gainer list, up 32 centavos to 7.82 pesos on expectations the U.S. Department of Commerce would lower anti-dumping tariffs levied on imports of Mexican cement. Situr, tourist arm of the debt-burdened Sidek group, headed the sliders' list, off three centavos to 20 centavos. Sidek also fell sharply, by three centavos to 31 centavos.  </p>
<p>Dealers also drew attention to retail stock Salinas y Rocha which reversed an early gain to close unchanged at 80 centavos, following a denial from the company that it was negotiating an assets sale.</p>
<p>(( --Karina Balderas, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9562))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
