<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="502528" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Cuba sends mission to Mexico's top election body.</title>
<headline>Cuba sends mission to Mexico's top election body.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cuban officials on Thursday paid a visit to Mexico's Federal Electoral Institute (IFE) and showed &quot;special interest&quot; in the way it was set up and run, the institute said in a statement.</p>
<p>Institute officials did not ask why the Cubans were interested in the autonomous institute that is charged with conducting mid-term elections here in July.</p>
<p>They declined to speculate whether Cuba may be interested in replicating such a body on the Communist-ruled island.</p>
<p>The statement said the Cuban mission included Rebeca Mujica Ramirez, from the international relations department of the Cuban Communist Party's Central Committee.</p>
<p>&quot;They showed special interest in the setting up and operating of the Federal Electoral Institute, in the programmes of permanent updating and purging of the electoral register, as well as the processes for setting up voting booths and the diffusion of election results,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Cuba's communists, headed by Fidel Castro, have governed Cuba since the 1959 revolution. Mexico's Institutional Revolutionary Party has won power at the ballot box since 1929, though it has often been accused of resorting to fraud.</p>
<p>Many foreign missions have visited the election institute this year to see how it plans to conduct the July 6 elections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
