<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="502561" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: INTERVIEW - Thais see foreign investment slowing.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Thais see foreign investment slowing.</headline>
<byline>Anchalee Koetsawang</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's Board of Investment forecast on Friday that foreign investment in the country, one of the major engines of growth, would be steady to lower this year over 1996 as the national economy cooled.</p>
<p>The government-run board granted tax and other investment incentives to 942 projects worth 427 billion baht (US$16.4 billion) in 1996, most of which were foreign investment, its secretary general Staporn Kavitanon told Reuters.</p>
<p>Despite the anticipated economic slowdown, Thailand would still be able to attract foreign investments especially in manufacturing of vehicle parts and components, chemicals, electronics and electrical parts and commponents, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The foreign investment in the past two years were mostly in major projects, making the amount high. This year the investments will gear toward supporting industries,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Major investment projects approved last year included U.S. auto giant General Motor Corp's car assembly plant, the Texas Instrument's semiconductor plant and International Business Machines's hard disk drives plant.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not expect the amount of investments to exceed that of last year due to the economic slowdown. But at least it should not drop much either,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thailand's free market, diversified economy and large domestic market and relatively high growth would continue to attract overseas investors, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We might be overwhelmed by the financial trouble and oversupplies problems in the property sector for now. But I believe the fundamental remain strong,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thai authorities last month ordered a revamp of the sick financial sector which has lent billions of dollars to the liquidity-hit and depressed property sector.</p>
<p>The Bank of Thailand has projected that the gross domestic product will grow around 6.8 percent versus 6.7 percent in 1996. Some private analysts expect a lower growth figure.</p>
<p>Investment from Japan is expected to slow down due to the weaker yen and lingering effects of its financial troubles while the investment from the United States was likely to pick up in line with an improving economy, he said.</p>
<p>The board would also aim to promote investment in the medical and service industries, although the focus would remain on efforts to make Thailand a regional hub for the automobile industry.</p>
<p>Staporn estimated Thailand would be able to export between 50,000-100,000 units of vehicles this year and projections were for an increase to 200,000-300,000 units in the next three years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
