<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="502516" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Jilted Colombian lover torches house, killing six.</title>
<headline>Jilted Colombian lover torches house, killing six.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A young man on Colombia's Caribbean coast doused a fisherman's home with gasoline and set it ablaze early on Friday, killing all but one of the seven people trapped inside, authorities said.</p>
<p>Police in the port city of Barranquilla said the attacker, who remained at large, was apparently enraged because a young woman who lived inside the house had spurned his advances.</p>
<p>&quot;He had been rejected on repeated occasions by a young woman who lived there,&quot; a senior police official told local radio.</p>
<p>He identified victims of the blaze, which was particularly intense because fuel tanks for a fishing boat had been stored inside the house, as three adults and three children, the youngest of whom was just 4 years old.</p>
<p>Franciso Cano, the only survivor of the blaze, said everyone was fast asleep when it engulfed the house in the pre-dawn darkness.</p>
<p>&quot;It didn't give us time to do anything,&quot; he told the Radionet news station from his hospital bed in Barranquilla. &quot;It's a miracle that I managed to get out alive.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
