<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="502911" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Third ex-Soviet diplomat accused of drunk driving.</title>
<headline>Third ex-Soviet diplomat accused of drunk driving.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The State Department said on Friday it expected to ask Kyrgyzstan to waive the immunity of an official in the third alleged drunk driving case this year involving diplomats from the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Spokesman Nicholas Burns said Erkinbek Atabekov, a second secretary at the Kyrgyz embassy, failed a Breathalyzer test after his van was involved in a collision with two parked vehicles in a Washington street late on Thursday evening.</p>
<p>No one was injured in the accident. Washington police cited Atabekov with driving while intoxicated.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect once formal charges are filed, we will send a formal notice to the embassy of Kyrgyzstan requesting a lifting of his diplomatic immunity so he can face prosecution here in Washington,&quot; Burns told a news briefing.</p>
<p>If the waiver is not granted, the State Department has the power to ban the diplomat from driving for a year, Burns said. Kyrgyzstan is a mountainous republic in Central Asia.</p>
<p>Burns also corrected a statement he made a week ago that the State Department had asked Russia to waive the immunity of a junior diplomat who was stopped by police near Annapolis, Maryland, and given three citations including one for drunk driving.</p>
<p>He said the State Department was discussing the case of second secretary Vadim Savelyev with the Russian embassy, but had not requested a waiver so far.</p>
<p>The most serious case was that of Georgian diplomat Gueorgui Makharadze, whose immunity was waived by his government after he was involved in a car crash that killed a teenage girl in Washington in January.</p>
<p>Makharadze pleaded innocent to charges of involuntary manslaughter and aggravated assault and was scheduled to be tried starting July 21.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KIRGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
