<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503108" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bonn's Waigel says three percent means 3.0 for EMU.</title>
<headline>Bonn's Waigel says three percent means 3.0 for EMU.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>FUERTH, Germany 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Finance Minister Theo Waigel on Friday dismissed speculation that he had softened his stance on the budget deficit limit for countries wishing to take part in European Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>Since February, Waigel has backed off calling for a precise ceiling of 3.0 percent of gross domestic product (GDP), prefering only to speak of three percent. In the last two days he has not mentioned any figure at all.</p>
<p>But at a meeting of his Christian Social Union (CSU) party in Fuerth, Waigel said the text of a motion on EMU spelling out a ceiling of 3.0 percent had been agreed with him.</p>
<p>&quot;Three percent is 3.0,&quot; Waigel told reporters. The motion was approved by the meeting in the southern town of Fuerth.</p>
<p>The European Union's Maastricht Treaty calls for nations to show a budget deficit no higher than a reference value of three percent of GDP if they want to join economic and monetary union (EMU), scheduled to start in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;We stand behind strict fulfilment of the entry criteria laid down in the Maastricht Treaty,&quot; Waigel told delegates of at the meeting.</p>
<p>The party's newly-appointed deputy secretary-general Joachim Herrmann explained the party had agreed on &quot;3&quot; percent, adding &quot;that means 3.0 percent and nothing else.&quot;</p>
<p>Bavaria's premier Edmund Stoiber, one of Germany's most strident defenders of a strict interpretation of Maastricht , who is also seen as a rival to Waigel for the party's leadership, agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;The deficit criterion reads 3.0 percent and not 3.2 or 3.15 percent and that is exactly what we want to decide today.&quot;</p>
<p>The quibbling over exactly what &quot;three&quot; means has become a central point of political debate about EMU in Germany as high unemployment and fragile growth place a question mark over Bonn's ability to meet a 2.9 percent deficit target this year.</p>
<p>Waigel insisted in his speech: &quot;Germany will fulfil the criteria, contrary to any doubt by some.&quot;</p>
<p>Independent economists have said Germany could still hit the three percent budget deficit target on the nose, as long as growth picks up during the rest of the year.</p>
<p>To accelerate growth, and tackle Germany's most pressing problem, an 11.7 percent jobless rate, Waigel said Bonn's ambitious tax reform package must be pressed through soon.</p>
<p>&quot;Anyone who blocks the tax reform is partly to blame that no new jobs are created,&quot; Waigel said, adding: &quot;We need the tax reform now as a positive signal for investments.&quot;</p>
<p>After Waigel on Thursday signalled his party's willingness to compromise on some points, he accused Oskar Lafontaine, the leader of the opposition Social Democrats (SPD), of souring the public mood with obstructionist policies and suggestions.</p>
<p>&quot;I have the impression that Lafontaine is only interested in creating a mood and not really interested in Germany's welfare.&quot;</p>
<p>Eager to play down criticism that new austerity measures were directly linked to his hardline stance on EMU entry criteria, Waigel said savings now would benefit a future generation.</p>
<p>Waigel also warned against complacency because Germany would risk being left behind if did not push on with reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no alternative to the goals and the speed with which we seek to achieve these.&quot;</p>
<p>Some members of the SPD, notably Lower Saxony premier Gerhard Schroeder, have said it would be sensible to delay the currency union's planned 1999 launch date, in order to give nations more time to meet qualify.</p>
<p>Both Waigel and Stoiber again criticised Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel, a member of the Kohl governments junior coalition partner, the Free Democrats, for saying EMU's &quot;point of no return&quot; had been passed and that meeting the Maastricht criteria was a process rather than a target to be met on a certain day.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FUERTH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
