<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503209" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian government defeated in vote of confidence.</title>
<headline>Indian government defeated in vote of confidence.</headline>
<byline>Hari Ramachandran</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda lost a vote of confidence in parliament on Friday, ending his minority government's 10-month grip on power in the world's second most populous country.</p>
<p>The speaker of the lower house, P.A. Sangma, said 292 deputies in the 542-member lower house, the Lok Sabha, voted against Deve Gowda and 158 voted in favour. &quot;The motion is negative,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked to react, Deve Gowda told Reuters: &quot;It was expected.&quot;</p>
<p>Aides said the prime minister would give his resignation to President Shankar Dayal Sharma, who under the constitution could ask him to remain as caretaker, choose a new leader or call general elections.</p>
<p>&quot;He will resign today. He is meeting the president tonight,&quot; Deve Gowda's spokesman H.K. Dua told reporters.</p>
<p>Deve Gowda's fate was sealed on Thursday when his ally-turned-foe, the Congress party, ordered its 140 deputies to vote against him.</p>
<p>Congress, India's oldest party, suffered its worst defeat in general elections last year and had reluctantly supported Deve Gowda's centre-left United Front coalition to prevent the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) from taking power.</p>
<p>But Congress president Sitaram Kesri unexpectedly withdrew his party's make-or-break support on March 30, accusing Deve Gowda of trying to sideline Congress and failing to join forces against the BJP in populous Uttar Pradesh state.</p>
<p>In his speech concluding 12-1/2 hours of debate on the confidence motion, Deve Gowda defiantly defended his coalition's record and said he would have no regrets leaving office.</p>
<p>He also said he was prepared to face mid-term polls, a prospect that many of his coalition partners do not relish.</p>
<p>Deve Gowda referred frequently to Kesri, saying: &quot;I have been branded as inefficient by the Congress president. The final judgement...is before the nation of 950 million people. The inefficient prime minister will go before the nation.&quot;</p>
<p>He said it was no use trying to &quot;patch up&quot; relations with Congress as this would serve no purpose. &quot;We don't want elections but we see no alternative road,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The prime minister's 75-minute speech appeared to dampen prospects that his 15-party United Front and Congress would be able to choose a new Indian leader and avert mid-term elections.</p>
<p>Bitter foes during the general election campaign last year, the United Front and Congress joined hands only to put an abrupt end to the BJP's 12-day stint in power.</p>
<p>They both accuse the BJP of favouring India's Hindu majority at the expense of the Moslem minority.</p>
<p>Congress deputies said earlier a deal was being hammered out to replace Deve Gowda in an attempt to avoid elections, which politicians said could be held by June if the impasse continued and would almost certainly strengthen the BJP.</p>
<p>But the United Front appeared to toughen its rhetoric as the day wore on. &quot;We are going to the people,&quot; Jammu and Kashmir state chief minister and United Front member Farooq Abdullah said. &quot;I don't see any other alternative but elections.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
