<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503339" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: FEATURE - Afghan conflict clouds future for Central Asia.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Afghan conflict clouds future for Central Asia.</headline>
<byline>Tim Johnston</byline>
<dateline>KABUL 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>With the advent of spring and the failure of U.N.-sponsored peace talks, the purist Islamic Taleban seems increasingly likely to launch a new offensive to capture the 25 percent of Afghanistan they do not control.</p>
<p>As warmer weather thaws the snow that froze the front lines between the Taleban and the opposition in the mountain passes of the Hindu Kush, many observers are looking beyond the possible resumption of fighting and asking what will happen if the Taleban take the opposition-held northern provinces.</p>
<p>The United Nations special representative to Afghanistan, Norbert Holl, recently warned that a military solution runs the risk of widening the conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;A military solution...may just change the dimension of the political problem from a domestic issue to an international issue,&quot; said Holl.</p>
<p>One analyst in Kabul sees two major problems if the Taleban to manage to take the northern provinces.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Taleban defeat the opposition, it is going to push large numbers of disgruntled and heavily-armed opposition fighters over the border into the Central Asian republics. They are unlikely to go into a quiet retirement,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Central Asian republics north of here are still fragile, and the last thing they need is another destabilising factor,&quot; said the analyst, who asked to remain anonymous.</p>
<p>CENTRAL ASIAN NEIGHBORS FEAR RADICAL MOVEMENT</p>
<p>He said the Central Asian states are also nervous about having a radical Islamic movement on their southern border.</p>
<p>&quot;Islam has been blamed for much of the instability that has plagued the region since the break-up of the former soviet union, including the civil war in Tajikistan and riots in Uzbekistan.</p>
<p>&quot;The Central Asians are frightened that the Taleban will further encourage Islamic radicals inside their borders, and may even try to continue their crusade northwards -- Bukhara (in Uzbekistan) used to be major site of Islamic pilgrimage,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Taleban have denied they have any ambitions outside of Afghanistan's borders.</p>
<p>Last Saturday, foreign ministers of four Central Asian republics -- Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan -- and the Russian first deputy foreign minister met in the Tajik captial Dushanbe to discuss the issue of Afghanistan.</p>
<p>In a joint communique released after the meeting, the foreign ministers expressed their anxiety at the continuation of armed hostilities in Afghanistan and stated their readiness for &quot;close joint action&quot; in protecting their common borders. The communique did not define what form this action would take.</p>
<p>The analyst believes a Taleban victory in Afghanistan at the cost of possibly expanding the conflict and destabilising Central Asia could defeat the objective of improving trade and regional prosperity.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a question of trade. The Afghan conflict has held up economic development in the whole region by blocking natural trade routes from Central Asia to the sub-continent and the Indian Ocean. But if you get a unified government in Afghanistan at the cost of a broader conflict involving Central Asia itself, economically very little is gained,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Differences over Afghanistan have already led to an estrangement between Pakistan and Iran.</p>
<p>The prospects of the United Nations being able to persuade the warring factions to come to a peaceful settlement, always dim, are receding.</p>
<p>PEACEFUL RESOLUTION TO CONFLICT UNLIKELY</p>
<p>In a recent interview, Taleban leader Mullah Mohammed Omar told a Pakistan-based newspaper that he believed a military solution was more likely.</p>
<p>&quot;The time for a negotiated solution is fast running out as the Taleban are marching victoriously into northern Afghanistan. We feel a military solution has better prospects right now after numerous failed attempts to reach a peaceful negotiated settlement,&quot; Omar was reported as telling the News on Sunday.</p>
<p>Maintaining the status quo, with the Taleban in most of the country and the opposition holding most of the provinces that border Central Asia, is unlikely to provide a stable solution in the long term.</p>
<p>Both sides in the Afghan conflict have said they are committed to a unified Afghanistan.</p>
<p>CONFLICT HOLDS UP PIPELINE</p>
<p>As long as the conflict continues, plans to build a pipeline between Central Asia's gas fields and the sub-continent through Afghanistan will remain on hold, notwithstanding the desire of the Central Asian states to break the stranglehold of Russia on their economies.</p>
<p>Iran, which has already developed strong trade ties with the republics, has suggested an alternative route for the pipeline through its territory.</p>
<p>Although the possibility of a unified Afghanistan appears closer, it will not necessarily lead to development of a regional economy. The splits that have torn Afghanistan for the past five years could be exported to the region as a whole.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
