<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50348" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FINNISH CORPORATE MARKKA CREDIT STOCK FELL IN JULY.</title>
<headline>FINNISH CORPORATE MARKKA CREDIT STOCK FELL IN JULY.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The stock of banks' markka credits to the corporate sector turned into a decline in July after rising steadily for six months in a row, according to central bank statistics received on Thursday.</p>
<p>Average interest charged on new markka credits to the corporate sector rose by more than half a percentage point in July to 5.72 percent -- the highest in any month since February -- from 5.20 percent in June, the Bank of Finland said.</p>
<p>The corporate sector's stock of markka credits fell to 83.1 billion markka in July from 83.5 billion in June. The stock had been rising every month from a low of 78.6 billion in December.  </p>
<p>In July, banks extended 2.06 billion markka in new markka credits to the corporate sector, the lowest in any month since September last year. July is usually among the most quiet months of the year due to summer holidays.</p>
<p>The average rate of interest on the stock of banks' credits to the corporate sector was 5.61 percent in July, down from 5.70 percent in June.</p>
<p>The stock of banks' total markka credits to the public contracted to 268.4 billion markka in July from 269.1 billion in June. New markka credits granted in July amounted to 8.3 billion markka in July, the smallest amount since November last year.  </p>
<p>Interest charged on new markka credits to the public averaged 5.62 percent, up from 5.46 percent in June, but the average rate of interest on the entire stock of banks' markka lending to the public fell further, to 6.47 percent in July from 6.54 percent in June, the central bank said.</p>
<p>The volume of new markka housing loans granted by banks in July was 2.14 billion markka, almost as much as in the two previous months and higherthan in March and April when demand for housing loans started to show signs of recovery.</p>
<p>Banks granted new housing loans at an average interest rate of 6.53 percent in July, down from 6.58 percent in June.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
