<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503535" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Softs Outlook -Sugar to expire, cocoa seen nervous.</title>
<headline>Softs Outlook -Sugar to expire, cocoa seen nervous.</headline>
<byline>Medora Lee</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>LIFFE white sugar futures' May expiration on Tuesday will take the spotlight while cocoa futures try to overcome nervousness from last week's rollercoaster activity.</p>
<p>Coffee futures were seen easing amid roasters' absence as they inventory stocks before the March-end financial period.</p>
<p>Slack EU sugar demand was seen limiting the physical delivery and chances of a short squeeze in London, traders said.</p>
<p>White sugar's expiration is expected to result in a physical delivery of about two cargoes of European Union (EU) origin.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the whites are going through a bit of (a) slump...at the moment, as you're not really shifting sugar, I think people are only taking off the bits and pieces of business that goes on every day,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody is willing to take a big gamble. Everyone is a bit lethargic. I don't think the whites are going to have any real surprises,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, traders will stay watchful of New York because trade houses there are said to be very short nearby months, and uncertainty lingers over availability of origins for May expiry.</p>
<p>After expiration, traders expected usual cross and against actuals activity as May positions are rolled into August, although one major trade house has been buying May outright.</p>
<p>In cocoa, traders said last week's volatile activity had clouded the near-term outlook and widened July's trading band to between 980 and 1,065.</p>
<p>Though cocoa recovered well from last Monday's tumble to about one-month lows made on agressive fund sales, technicians were not yet ruling out another setback.</p>
<p>Lawrence Eagles, commodity analyst with GNI Ltd, said cocoa's upside path would not be cleared until July hurdled its April 2 peak of 1,065 stg. Before that, July would have to break resistance at 1,034 and minor resistances at 1,049 and 1,062.</p>
<p>But he said sustainable gains could be difficult because of signs this year's cocoa deficit would be smaller than forecasts six months ago due to a larger-than-expected Ivorian crop.</p>
<p>And although fund selling dried up late last week, which allowed cocoa to rise to a weekly high on Friday, Eagles speculated that funds remained net long the market and could reemerge to threaten cocoa gains if trade demand did not surface to soak up sales.</p>
<p>Initial July support rests at 985, with critical support at 980. A close below 987 could mean a drop to 940.</p>
<p>Coffee futures were expected to drift lower without any roaster buying activity as roasters returning from Easter continued to inventory for the financial period ending March 31.</p>
<p>Origins are also expected to step up selling into any May advance up to $1,700, making further gains to last month's peak of just above $1,800 seem unlikely in the near-term.</p>
<p>In robusta, producer sales from Vietnam have eased due to the end of the main crop, and the market is now bracing for sales of the main Indonesian harvest.</p>
<p>&quot;Origins have been quiet. However, a scale-up selling is hovering over the market up to $1,700,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Indonesia, which is harvesting and shipping its main crop, has been surprisingly quiet, possibly awaiting higher prices.</p>
<p>Immediately, traders said May could drift down to $1,560-$1,540 a tonne this week.</p>
<p>Robusta's fortunes also hinge on New York arabica futures' sharp swings. Traders said a July break below 170 cents a lb could accelerate a fall to the 160- to 165-area.</p>
<p>The possible Colombia truck drivers' strike on April 20 may provide some support, but traders doubt if it would materialise as the government may try to intervene.</p>
<p>--London newsroom +44 171 542 8072</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
