<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503565" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK government keeps rates on hold before election.</title>
<headline>UK government keeps rates on hold before election.</headline>
<byline>Rosemary Bennett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Conservative finance minister Kenneth Clarke left interest rates unchanged at 6.0 percent on Friday after his last pre-election monetary meeting with Bank of England Governor Eddie George.</p>
<p>Following Thursday's meeting between Clarke and George in Nottingham, the central bank engaged in routine money market operations at unchanged rates on Friday, indicating official rates had been left on hold.</p>
<p>Economists believe George is likely to have renewed his request for a quarter-point rate rise to cool demand in the economy and choke off future inflationary pressure.</p>
<p>But as expected, Clarke, thought to be reluctant to upset millions of home-owners before the May 1 election by increasing the cost of their mortgages, left rates unchanged.</p>
<p>His decision means opposition Labour party finance spokesman Gordon Brown, who opinion polls suggest is likely to head the Treasury next month, will have to seriously consider a rate rise when he meets George for the first time on May 7.</p>
<p>Tim Melville-Ross, director-general of the Institute of Directors, said he would welcome an early rate rise.</p>
<p>&quot;The economic imperatives right now are for a certain amount of activity to be taken out of the economy, either through an increase in interest rates or through a fiscal package of some kind -- probably both,&quot; he told Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>He expects interest rates to rise within a month of the election.</p>
<p>&quot;That may sound like bad news but it's better news than the alternative, which is for inflationary pressures which are beginning to emerge in the economy -- notwithstanding the strength of sterling -- to get out of control,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kevin Gardiner, an economist at Morgan Stanley, said that while Labour had not explicitly suggested it would institute a tougher monetary policy than the Conservatives, it had insisted it would be tough on inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;It's quite likely Brown would raise rates at that first meeting,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Brown will be trying to establish credibility on inflation as soon as possible and might welcome the opportunity do that early on to assure people he wasn't bluffing.&quot;</p>
<p>If Labour does win, Brown will inherit a buoyant economy combining steady growth, robust consumer demand and, so far, low and falling inflation.</p>
<p>But many independent economists are worried about building inflationary pressures and the imbalance between a strong services industry, reaping the benefits from domestic demand, and the sluggish manufacturing sector, under siege from a strong pound.</p>
<p>&quot;We have passed the point in the business cycle where we can enjoy both strong growth and stable inflation,&quot; said David Mackie, UK economist at JP Morgan.</p>
<p>Underlying inflation edged down to 2.9 percent from 3.1 percent in February, but is still above the government's 2.5 percent target, which Labour has also adopted.</p>
<p>Although many economists expect inflation to fall a little further in the summer, they say the strength of domestic demand and already present wage pressures mean it risks picking up again strongly later in the year.</p>
<p>A rate rise, rather than tax rises, early in the next administration, may exacerbate this imbalance, hitting manufacturing hardest and possibly sending the pound even higher.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
