<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50357" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dlr unable to tread into higher terrain in Europe.</title>
<headline>Dlr unable to tread into higher terrain in Europe.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar managed to claw its way back above 1.51 marks in afternoon Europe but lacked the incentive to bring it above the key 1.5160 marks area.</p>
<p>U.S. producer price data were unconvincing, leaving players to wait until more inflation data and retail sales figures are published tomorrow to cement their views on what the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) will decide when it meets on September 24, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The headline rate was disappointing but the core rate fell. There are few inflation pressures in the pipeline but it won't change the view of the Fed hawks,&quot; said DKB's Nick Stamenkovic.  </p>
<p>The August producer price index rose 0.3 percent, higher than a 0.1-percent rise forecast, while the core rate fell 0.1 percent comapred with expectations of a 0.1-percent gain.</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers won't prompt a consensus within the Fed,&quot; DKB economist Stamekovic said.</p>
<p>At 1450 GMT, the dollar stood at 1.5116/22 marks compared with 1.5080/85 late on Wednesday. It quickly retreated after nudging the 1.5155 marks high hit on Wednesday, which is also a technically crucial barrier because it was the high set on July 16 when the dollar posted its fourth biggest one-day loss on record.  </p>
<p>Around midday, the dollar got a boost when a Bundesbank spokesman said council member Klaus-Dieter Kuehbacher said key German rates could fall more if economic conditions permitted.</p>
<p>The German central bank's September monthly report reaffirmed market perception that the Bundesbank favours a weaker mark because it said current exchange rates matched economic fundamentals far better than in 1995. The mark is about two percent lower in value against the 18 most important currencies than it was earlier this year, the bank said.</p>
<p>Although dollar/yen has benefitted from dollar/mark's rally this week, convincing gains beyond 110 have yet to materialize.  </p>
<p>Joe Prendergast, foreign exchange strategist at Merrill Lynch, noted that speculation of Japanese capital repatriation ahead of half-year book closings this month may give some seasonal support for the yen. He added, however, that he expected dollar/yen to test the 113.50 high from January 1994 once the end-September fiscal book squaring is over.</p>
<p>The dollar stood at 109.88/98 yen at 1500 GMT, slightly below 110.18/23 in late European dealings on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now, Japanese investors are still risk adverse,&quot; said Stamenkovic. &quot;Once the half-year is over though, they could seek higher returns overseas, which could allow the dollar to rally.&quot;  </p>
<p>Familiar ranges are seen prevailing until U.S. consumer price data tomorrow at 1230 GMT. Although the market has factored in a quarter point rise in the federal funds target rate, an unexpected increase in the CPI would likely frighten stocks, bonds and then the dollar, analysts said.</p>
<p>The demand side of the U.S. economy will come into focus from retail sales, which are expected to have picked up 0.7 percent in August from a 0.1 percent increase in July.</p>
<p>The Italian lira rebounded when Treasury undersecretary Laura Pennacchi denied saying a 1020 lira/mark ERM entry level would be appropriate. --Kaori Enjoji, London +44 171 542 6721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
