<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503501" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: VW wows German stock market with 97 outlook.</title>
<headline>VW wows German stock market with 97 outlook.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT, Germany</dateline>
<text>
<p>The stock of Europe's largest carmaker Volkswagen soared to record highs Friday on an extremely upbeat outlook for 1997 and a series of analysts' upgrades.</p>
<p>VW shares hit an all-time high of 1,117.50 German marks ($649), a rise of over 12 percent, in bourse trade in Frankfurt and analysts said they could head as high as 1,500 marks ($872), this year.</p>
<p>The stock lipped from the highs later in the day as profit-taking kicked in, but still ended with marked gains. VW closed the bourse session at 1,072.50 marks ($624), up 76.50 marks ($44.5), or 7.68 percent, before easing to 1,049 marks ($610) in post-bourse dealings.</p>
<p>The stock's dramatic rise began Thursday, when Volkswagen kicked off 1997 by forecasting better first quarter earnings due to a 9.5 percent rise in sales and said it expected higher profits and turnover for the year.</p>
<p>Shares penetrated the 1,000 mark level for the first time shortly after the results were announced. They continued to strengthen after analysts met Volkswagen and emerged bullish.</p>
<p>A rash of earnings upgrades followed, as well as hikes in share price targets for the year, and Volkswagen advanced strongly early on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
