<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503578" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Merrill offers all-night dealing for UK election.</title>
<headline>Merrill offers all-night dealing for UK election.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. investment bank Merrill Lynch on Friday said it will be offering all-night share dealing services in UK stocks on the night of the general election.</p>
<p>Voting at 47,000 polling stations will end at 2100 GMT on Thursday May 1, well after normal business hours and the result is not likely to be known until about 0300-0600 GMT on Friday. A spokesman for Merrill said the situation was unique. The U.S. brokerage has never offered an all-night service before. But Smith New Court, bought out by Merrill in 1995, traded through the night in the 1992 election. &quot;This is an opportunity for Merrill Lynch to demonstrably show our clients that we are there for them when they need us,&quot; said Richard Silverman, a company spokesman. &quot;It is important that we are there for clients on this special night, and we will be happy to serve as many or as few clients that decide to make use of the service,&quot; he said. Normal dealing costs will apply, the company said. The service could appeal to anyone who has used the election as a component in their investment strategy and Merrill's decision is likely to force others to follow suit, traders said. The Conservative</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
