<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503667" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: Cyprus shares end week down 0.89 pct on correction.</title>
<headline>Cyprus shares end week down 0.89 pct on correction.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cyprus equities ended the week with a 0.89 percent drop which analysts described as a price correction from a 6.67 percent buying spree jump in March.</p>
<p>The 42-share Cyprus stock exchange general index ended 0.89 percent, or 0.72 points lower on Friday, closing at 79.52 from 80.24 last week.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a correction and some profit taking but it is not a long term thing,&quot; said Christodoulos Ellinas of Share Link Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a short-term bear market and I believe it will go up in the next few days,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Turnover during Friday's trading session rose to 1.2 million pounds ($2.3 million) from the average of 760,000 pounds during the previous days of the week. The average turnover of the bourse between March 31 and April 4 was 1.5 million pounds.</p>
<p>&quot;Technical analysis this week indicates a bearish short-term market as the nine day moving average is down, but on the other hand it points to a bullish long term market as the 45-day moving average is up,&quot; said the Cyprus Investment and Securities Corporation in its weekly report.</p>
<p>Banking shares, the strongest of the seven sub indices, closed at 89.43, down 1.23 percent from last Friday's close.</p>
<p>Trading on Bank of Cyprus fully paid shares closed at 336.5, down one cent from 337.5 on April 4. The Cyprus Popular Bank closed 10 cents lower, at 311.5.</p>
<p>Hellenic Bank  fully paid shares were trading at 284.5, two cents lower from last week. Stocks of the Universal Savings Bank were trading at 185.5, jumping nine cents from last week's close.</p>
<p>Insurance companies closed at 61.27 from 61.76 last week. Industrial stocks declined 0.22 percent, closing at 83.62.</p>
<p>--Nicosia newsroom 357 2 365089</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
