<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503673" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Iran protestors pelt German embassy with tomatoes.</title>
<headline>Iran protestors pelt German embassy with tomatoes.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of Iranians marched on the German embassy in central Tehran on Friday, and many pelted the building with tomatoes in protest at a German court verdict accusing Iran of ordering political murders, witnesses said.</p>
<p>The demonstrators, who had marched four km (2.5 miles) to the mission from Friday's mass prayers at Tehran University, rushed a line of riot police behind barricades at the embassy, but were pushed back, the witnesses said.  </p>
<p>Witnesses said the protestors, many of them members of a hardline Islamist group, chanted &quot;Death to Germany&quot; and &quot;Fascist Germany, servant of Zionism&quot;, in addition to the familiar slogans &quot;Death to America&quot; and &quot;Death to Israel&quot;.</p>
<p>Six busloads of riot police were guarding the embassy where barriers had been erected in the morning. Police had stopped traffic from entering streets near the compound.</p>
<p>In a resolution, protesters demanded that Germany apologise for what they described as an affront to Iran and urged the Iranian government to break off ties if Bonn refused to apologise. The resolution gave Germany until Tuesday to issue an apology.</p>
<p>Germany on Thursday withdrew its ambassador from Tehran and expelled four Iranian embassy staff from Bonn. Tehran then recalled its chief envoy and asked four German diplomats to leave.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
