<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503796" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. judge censured for calling British law primitive.</title>
<headline>U.S. judge censured for calling British law primitive.</headline>
<byline>Jeanne King</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A judicial watchdog commission on Thursday censured a New York judge who criticised the British legal system in open court during the sentencing last year of a British woman who admitted killing her newborn baby.</p>
<p>The New York State Commission on Judicial Conduct in a determination made on April 2 and released on Thursday said New York State Supreme Court Justice Robert Hanophy made &quot;undignified, discourteous and disparaging remarks&quot; at the sentencing of Caroline Beale, who had pleaded guilty to manslaughter in a plea bargain agreement in connection with the death of her baby daughter.</p>
<p>During the sentencing, Hanophy blasted the woman's parents, and her father, Peter Beale of Chingford, Essex, in particular for calling the U.S. justice system &quot;barbaric and uncivilized.&quot;</p>
<p>Beale's parents told reporters at an earlier hearing that their daughter's experience showed the United States was an uncivilized country with a &quot;medieval&quot; legal system.</p>
<p>Beale was charged with murder after her arrest at Kennedy International Airport in September 1994 when she was caught trying to smuggle her baby girl's corpse, hidden in plastic under her coat, onto a flight to London. She told police the child had been stillborn in a hotel room.</p>
<p>Hanophy at the sentencing referred to Beale's father as &quot;Ralph Kramden - the guy with the big mouth.&quot; Kramden was a loud-mouth bus driver character played on television by the late actor Jackie Gleason.</p>
<p>The judge also said that remarks made by Beale's mother to reporters &quot;got under my skin.&quot;</p>
<p>The Commission, which has censured 174 judges in the last 20 years, said Hanophy reacted &quot;out of pique.&quot;</p>
<p>During the sentencing of Beale, Hanophy had also referred to the so-called &quot;Guildford Four,&quot; alleged Irish Republican Army bombers jailed for a London bombing and then released many years later for wrongful conviction. The British &quot;did everything to see that they remained in prison even though they knew or should have known that they didn't belong in there,&quot; Hanophy said.</p>
<p>The Commission said that Hanophy's remarks had no relevance to the crime for which Beale had been convicted. &quot;His gratuitous and irrelevant reference to defendants from Northern Ireland who had been sentenced in British courts was mean-spirited and political in nature,&quot; the Commission report said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
