<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503770" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Daily Variety - April 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Daily Variety - April 11.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following stories appeared in Friday's Daily Variety:</p>
<p>* Boston investment firm Bain Capital Partners is backing a three-way independent merger of Live Entertainment, Trimark Holdings and October Pictures, sources said, which could create a $200 million company.</p>
<p>* Sony Pictures Entertainment will shut its low-budget independent unit Triumph Pictures following the completion of its current slate of pictures, the studio said.</p>
<p>* Although films by several of the biggest international directors -- Oliver Stone, Ang Lee, Abbas Kiarostami, Zhang Yimou -- have yet to be screened, the line-up for the 50th Cannes Film Festival is taking shape.</p>
<p>* News Corp Chief Executive Rupert Murdoch used a Senate hearing to pitch his soon-to-be-launched American Sky Broadcasting DBS service as a powerful new competitor which would limit the cable industry's ability to raise subscriber fees.</p>
<p>* With record attendance, extra space, new exhibitors, and bigger stands, international TV trade shows Mip opens Friday with a clutch of initiatives aimed at boosting European TV production.</p>
<p>* Shirley MacLaine will make her feature film directorial debut with the romantic comedy-drama &quot;Kingdom Come&quot; for producers David Kirkpatrick and Bernie Williams, from a script by Christopher Lofton and MacLaine.</p>
<p>((New York newsdesk 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
