<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503927" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek shares end up 0.14pct, seen directionless.</title>
<headline>Greek shares end up 0.14pct, seen directionless.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek equities ended 0.14 percent higher on Friday and analysts say the bourse's direction in the short-run was not clear. But, in the medium-term they expected another rise which will be led by banks and telecom shares.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market is directionless on a day-to-day basis. But it will definitely moving upwards in the medium-term as all fundamentals remain strong,&quot; said analyst George Dimitriou, at Ergo Securities.</p>
<p>The market's correction in the past few sessions have been small, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;The downside potential of the market is limited. I believe that 1,350 points is a solid support level,&quot; said Dimitriou.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Jersey Ltd issued two million American-style, drachma-denominated call warrants on a basket of eight Greek shares involved in infrastructure works.</p>
<p>The underlying stock basket includes the stocks of OTE, Intracom, Titan Cement, Heracles, Aktor, Aegek, Hellenic Technodomiki and Michaniki.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a positive development for Greek equitites which now become more internationalised. It also clearly depicts the investment interest on the external front,&quot; said Dimitriou.</p>
<p>The Athens general share index ended 0.14 percent or 2.01 points higher at 1,421.03 from Thursday's 1,419.02 close, after opening at 1,416.52. The session's high was at 1,426.43 and its low at 1,414.24 points.</p>
<p>Turnover rose slightly to 14.9 billion drachmas on volume of 4.0 million shares. Decliners led advancers 106 to 105, with 34 issues unchanged on 245 traded.</p>
<p>Sectoral indices were mixed. Banks rose 0.14 percent and construction gained 0.27 percent. Industrials closed up 0.61 percent and insurance stocks settled 0.50 percent higher.</p>
<p>Small caps ended down 0.27 percent.</p>
<p>The Merrill Lynch call spread warrant on OTE with a strike price of 3,800 drachmas was quoted higher at 1,090.0-1,120.0. Shares of OTE telecom, the underlying, ended up 25 drachmas, to close at 6,200.</p>
<p>The ING Baring Financial Products American style call warrant based on a basket of six bank stocks was quoted higher at $59.09-$60.78. The strike price is set at $99.60 and the warrants expire October 8, 1997.</p>
<p>The recently issued ING Baring Financial Products American- style call warrant on a basket of six blue-chips denominated in drachmas was quoted lower at 2,059-2,252 drachmas.</p>
<p>The strike price is set at 10,000 drachmas and the warrants expire on February 2, 1998.</p>
<p>--Margarita Sotiropoulou, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4 (c) Reuters Limited 1997</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
