<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503969" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss investors plan new Geneva-based airline.</title>
<headline>Swiss investors plan new Geneva-based airline.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH, Switzerland</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of investors, including the Canton of Geneva, are considering founding a new airline -- Swiss World Airways -- to fly between Geneva and the United States.</p>
<p>Jean-Charles Simon, member of the Swiss parliament and Swiss World Airways chairman, said the airline plans to start operating in the second half of 1997 with two leased Boeing 767 aircraft.</p>
<p>The move is in response to a decision by Swissair last year to scrap most of its loss-making long-haul flights from Geneva in favour of the Zurich hub.</p>
<p>&quot;As an international city we cannot be satisfied by just having a regional airport. It must be part of a long-distance network and without going through Kloten (Zurich Airport),&quot; Simon told daily newspaper Tages-Anzeiger.</p>
<p>Simon said Swiss World Airways could be profitable if it was able to capture just half of the at least 320 passengers daily that he said Swissair had lost by cancelling almost all its long-distance flights from Geneva.</p>
<p>The Boeing 767 aircraft would have 208 seats each.</p>
<p>Swissair's decision to focus its operations in Zurich were strongly criticised by both national and local politicians from the French-speaking part of Switzerland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
