<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504031" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Major challenges Blair over Europe.</title>
<headline>UK's Major challenges Blair over Europe.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister John Major on Friday kept up his criticism of the main opposition Labour Party's policies on Europe, accusing it of being prepared to damage Britain's interests by transferring powers to Brussels.</p>
<p>Speaking at his daily election news conference, Major said Labour leader Tony Blair's plan to sign up to the European Union's Social Chapter covering common workplace standards would do untold damage to British business and jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;Just today, Labour declared themselves new friends of business. Yet he (Blair) plans to sign up to the social chapter, accept the Working Time Directive, hand over more trade union powers and open the gate to an unlimited stream of new regulations that the British parliament would be unable to prevent.</p>
<p>&quot;Changing from the red flag to the white flag is no bargain for Britain in Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>He was flanked at the news conference by Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind and Trade Secretary Ian Lang.</p>
<p>Rifkind said Labour's pledge to retain Britain's veto over social matters was worthless. Working conditions, consultation with workers, equal opportunities and health and safety were all subject to qualified majority voting.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a fraud on the British people for Labour to suggest which proposals they would accept and those they would not,&quot; Rikind said.</p>
<p>&quot;Signing up to the social chapter will open the door wide for European labour law and over-regulation,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Lang attacked Labour over the Working Time Directive.</p>
<p>He said the European Commission wanted to extend the directive, which states that no worker should have to work more than 48 hours each week, to all areas of employment.</p>
<p>&quot;Labour claim to be listening to business, yet they are staunch supporters of the Working Time Directive,&quot; Lang said.</p>
<p>&quot;A measure, which in its original form would cost busineses in the UK up to two billion stg a year, under these proposals would cost still more,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Lang pledged that a Conservative government would go to the mid-year Inter-Governmental Conference (IGC) and insist the effects of the directive be removed from Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;Labour would roll over and accept the Working Time Directive even in its new extended form. Only the Conservatives will get rid of this damaging directive once and for all,&quot; Lang said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
