<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504327" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Nippon Oil, Cosmo Oil to step up supply links.</title>
<headline>Nippon Oil, Cosmo Oil to step up supply links.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nippon Oil Co Ltd and Cosmo Oil Co Ltd said on Friday they had reached an agreement to step up cooperation in domestic oil product distribution to try to cut costs.</p>
<p>&quot;We have reached a preliminary agreement on tie-ups in domestic distribution, though details have yet to be ironed out,&quot; a Cosmo Oil spokesman said.</p>
<p>The cooperation would enable Nippon Oil trucks to collect oil products, such as gasoline and gas oil, at Cosmo's refineries, and vice versa as early as October, he said.</p>
<p>Both firms already routinely supply oil products to each other's coastal tankers.</p>
<p>The cooperation is expected to be carried out in the Tokyo-Yokohama area, where Nippon Oil operates the 385,000 barrel-per-day (bpd) Negishi refinery, and in the Chukyo area of central Japan, where Cosmo runs the 155,000 bpd Yokkaichi plant, he said.</p>
<p>The volume of oil products supplied to each other is expected to reach about 800,000 kilolitres a year, which would save Cosmo about &quot;several hundred million yen&quot; a year, the Cosmo spokesman said.</p>
<p>Oil refiners in Japan, whose financial situations have worsened since oil product imports were deregulated a year ago, have been seeking distribution tie-ups in an effort to cut costs.</p>
<p>Nippon Oil is already cooperating with Idemitsu Kosan Co Ltd in the distribution of asphalt, heavy fuel oil, kerosene and gas oil, and plans to extend that cooperation to gasoline next year.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Cosmo and Japan Energy Corp have been supplying each other's oil trucks with gasoline on an experimental basis since January.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Energy Desk +81-3-3432-8837</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
