<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504416" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: South Lebanon is calmer a year after Israeli blitz.</title>
<headline>South Lebanon is calmer a year after Israeli blitz.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Tarnowski</byline>
<dateline>TYRE, Lebanon 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A year after Israel's 17-day blitz on Lebanon, fighting sputters on along the last Arab-Israeli frontline but military observers say the conflict level is lower and civilians are less at risk.</p>
<p>Hizbollah (Party of God) guerrillas still attack Israeli troops in south Lebanon with mortars, anti-tank rockets and roadside bombs as they did before the blitz in April 1996, and the Israelis still respond with shelling and air raids.</p>
<p>But the number of attacks is down and the Israelis are taking more care in their responses to avoid hitting civilians, says Timur Goksel, spokesman for UNIFIL, the 4,500-member U.N. peacekeeping force in south Lebanon.</p>
<p>Most important of all, Hizbollah has not fired Katyusha rockets into Israel since the blitz ended on April 27, 1996.</p>
<p>Both sides are trying to respect a U.S.-brokered ceasefire understanding that banned shooting from or at civilian areas and set up a five-nation monitoring group to take up complaints in an effort to avert future escalations, Goksel told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The targeting of civilians on either side of the border has ended, though I cannot say it has completely stopped on this side because Lebanese civilians are still being hit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Israel launched the blitz on April 11, 1996, saying it was to destroy Hizbollah and stop the Katyushas. Hizbollah, which said it only bombarded Israel in reply to shelling of Lebanese villages, emerged almost intact from the confrontation.</p>
<p>But up to 200 people, mainly civilians, died, 100 in Israeli shelling of a U.N. base packed with refugees. Their cemetery in the southern town of Qana has become a shrine for the Lebanese.</p>
<p>The damage caused by the blitz set back Lebanon's efforts to rebuild after the 1975-90 civil war. Officials say it cost $500 million and the loss of one or two percentage points of economic growth, accentuating a serious slowdown in 1996.</p>
<p>Goksel says the five-nation monitoring group has helped to prevent the fighting from escalating during the past year.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the monitoring committee was a very bright idea as a limited conflict control mechanism,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The group includes the United States, France, Israel, Syria and Lebanon. It issues low-key decisions on complaints by Israel of guerrilla attacks launched on its troops from villages and Lebanese government complaints of Israeli shelling of villages.</p>
<p>Goksel cites at least one case when a likely Katyusha attack on Israel was pre-empted by the expectation that the committee would handle the issue that had angered Hizbollah.</p>
<p>&quot;The monitoring group is at least slowing things down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It has become a sort of wailing wall, but that's part of being a conflict control mechanism, a place where you let off your anger, where you can make complaints and get some approval and public exposure for your position,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;The Israelis seem happy about it because in a few cases they have credited the presence of the monitoring committee with actually preventing possible attacks into Israel.&quot;</p>
<p>Lebanon also appears satisfied as at least one statement by the group has deplored Israeli shelling of civilians.</p>
<p>But the drop in guerrilla attacks does not signal a weakening of Hizbollah's resolve to drive the Israelis from Lebanon and it has not reduced Israeli casualties.</p>
<p>Israel has lost six dead and had 26 soldiers wounded this year compared with 27 dead in the whole of 1996.</p>
<p>Goksel says guerrilla attacks have fallen due to Israeli measures to make its men harder to hit, but Israeli casualties continue because Israeli troops have taken over more frontline posts and patrols from their local militia allies.</p>
<p>Israel has reduced troop and logistics movements, made them irregular, strengthened fortifications and increased troop numbers in Lebanon to 2,000 from 1,200. And the troops no longer go home for weekends along dangerous Lebanese roads.</p>
<p>As a result, hard-core Hizbollah fighters now launch only three or four operations a month compared with double or triple that number last year.</p>
<p>Despite all this, Lebanon is unpredictable and Goksel is not certain the monitoring group could control a major flareup.</p>
<p>&quot;How far its role will last is beyond me,&quot; he said. &quot;It all depends on the situation on the ground.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TYRE, Lebanon"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
