<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504477" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Friday April 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Friday April 11.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the top headlines in leading Italian newspapers.</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP POLITICAL STORIES</p>
<p>* Prime minister Romano Prodi comfortably survived a vote of confidence called in the Senate after his hard left Communist Refoundation allies broke ranks and defied the government on a security force for Albania. The centre-left government won the vote by 162 votes to 81 with one abstention, Prodi said he was confident his government would also win the Chamber of Deputies' approval (all).</p>
<p>* Democratic Party of the Left (PDS) leader Massimo D'Alema harshly criticised Prodi's address to the Senate, calling it a shame the way the prime minister tried not to oppose Communist Refoundation's claims. Foreign minister Lamberto Dini was also not satisfied with Prodi's weak attitude towards his hard-left ally (all).</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>* A report by national statistics institute ISTAT showed Italy had a 3.089 trillion lire trade surplus with non-European countries in February. ISTAT also said that Italy had a global trade surplus in January of 1.655 trillion lire against a surplus of 135 billion lire in January 1996 (all).</p>
<p>* The Ministry of Transport said new car registrations rose 25.04 percent to 220,500 units in March compared with 176,348 in March 1996 (all).</p>
<p>* Carmaker Fiat saw a rise of 22.7 percent in its group March new car registration to 96,020 vehicles from 78,278 in March 1996 (all).</p>
<p>* The board of Monte Paschi di Siena said it had approved the purchase of a three percent stake in Istituto Bancario San Paolo, thus becoming part of a hard-core of shareholders in the Turin-based bank due to be privatised later this year (all).</p>
<p>* Rainer Masera, director general of investment bank IMI, said the group, which currently holds a two percent stake in San Paolo, is very likely to exercise the option to raise its stake to five percent and thereby become of a hard core of allies in San Paolo (Il Sole 24 Ore).</p>
<p>* Information technology group Olivetti fell 6 percent on the Milan bourse on press reports of losses of over 50 billion lire at its Telemedia company (all).</p>
<p>* Net yields of three, six and twelve-month short-term Treasury bills (BOTs) fell below 6 percent, the lowest level in the last twenty years (all).</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129450</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
