<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504540" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ascend net up 139 pct, Cascade sales growth slows.</title>
<headline>Ascend net up 139 pct, Cascade sales growth slows.</headline>
<text>
<p>ALAMEDA, Calif., April 10 (Reuter) Ascend Communications Corp. on Thursday said first quarter net income before charges rose 139 percent from a year earlier, whiles its merger partner Cascade Communications Corp. reported a big loss after a charge for an acquisition.</p>
<p>Alameda, Calif.-based Ascend said net income for the three months to March 31 rose to $46.3 million, or 36 cents a share, from $19.4 million or 15 cents a share in the year-earlier first quarter.</p>
<p>This was slightly above Wall Street's consensus estimate of 33 cents a share, according to First Call.</p>
<p>First quarter net sales for the fast-growing maker of remote networking products was $202.4 million, up 120 percent from $92 million in the first quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>Westford, Mass.-based Cascade Communications Corp., reported a loss of $198.3 million, or $2.13 per share, for its first fiscal quarter ended March 29, after a one-time charge of $213.1 million related to its acquisition of Sahara Networks.</p>
<p>Excluding the charge, Cascade reported earnings of $14.8 million, or 15 cents a share, compared with net income of $10.4 million, or 11 cents a share a year ago.</p>
<p>Revenues for the first quarter rose 61 percent to $90.3 million from $56.0 million for the same period in 1996, but this was down 18 percent from $110.3 million sequentially from the previous, fourth quarter in an industry where large double-digit sequential quarterly gains are the norm.</p>
<p>Ascend's acquisition in a stock exchange was initially valued at $3.7 billion, but the value has since slipped --- falling below $3 billion at one point -- along with declines in the company's stock price.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
