<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504539" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE - U.S. entertainment finds growing audience overseas.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - U.S. entertainment finds growing audience overseas.</headline>
<byline>Lisa Marie Pane</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Americans often grumble that there is little of value on television or in the movie theatres these days. But the companies that produce those shows are finding a receptive audience abroad.</p>
<p>With the opening of borders in Eastern Europe and a growing interest in television elsewhere on the continent, American companies are finding they can use programmes created for the United States to generate additional revenue by selling them overseas.</p>
<p>Although American television and movies have long been a popular export, industry executives and analysts say the European market in particular has been expanding and offering more opportunities lately.</p>
<p>&quot;The possibilities of that are endless, and we're all beginning to see that,&quot; Paramount Pictures Chairman Sherry Lansing said recently at the Variety-Schroder Wertheim Big Picture conference.</p>
<p>Schroder Wertheim analyst David Londoner said during the past nine years the compound revenue growth rate for media companies in foreign markets was 18 percent versus 14 percent in the United States.</p>
<p>Londoner said he had estimated that film studios in 1996 would see a 33 percent drop in operating profits. However, the decline was just 5 percent -- largely because deals in Germany and elsewhere in Europe &quot;really supported the industry,&quot; he said at the conference.</p>
<p>Overseas markets are viewed as fertile ground for American media and entertainment companies now that the frenzy of mergers and acquisitions has tapered off.</p>
<p>At the same time, the deregulation of television and creation of free markets in eastern Europe has spawned an audience, once accustomed to a steady diet of government-fed programming, hungry for sitcoms, movies and other shows.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the melding of these two things at the same time,&quot; Prudential Securities analyst Melissa Cook said. &quot;It's been explosive.&quot;</p>
<p>Eastern Europe's population is about 344 million, far more than the 263 million in the United States. Yet the number of TV households is just 88.5 million compared with 94 million in the United States.</p>
<p>Among Western Europe's 383.5 million people, there are about 137.5 million TV households.</p>
<p>&quot;I think more and more you're going to see producers look at the full range of markets,&quot; Cook said.</p>
<p>One reason is because of television shows such as &quot;X-Files&quot; and movies such as &quot;Fatal Attraction.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;X-Files,&quot; which airs on News Corp's Fox network, got its start in Australia and Canada. Its popularity there propelled it into the U.S. market. It's now highly popular in Europe, as well, with its theme song even hitting the charts in Britain.</p>
<p>Paramount's &quot;Fatal Attraction,&quot; which was released in September 1987, posted $156.6 million at box offices in the United States and Canada -- but brought in close to $340 million worldwide.</p>
<p>Movie industry experts estimate box office growth in North America at between 2 percent and 3 percent annually in the next five years, reaching about $6.85 billion by 2002.</p>
<p>In contrast, box office growth in Europe is expected to be in the range of 4 percent and 5 percent in the next five years, reaching about $5.77 billion by 2002.</p>
<p>Still, there are some obstacles and quirks in the European market.</p>
<p>There are a mix of languages and cultures, leading to different tastes in entertainment. There also are varying degrees of technological advances.</p>
<p>Companies cannot rely solely on American shows, media executives said. It's also necessary to produce local language programming. Media executives said that's especially true with game shows; while the format might be copied, those shows must be produced in the native language to attract an audience.</p>
<p>&quot;Europe is not Kansas,&quot; Central European Media Enterprises Ltd President and Chief Executive Len Fertig said at the Variety-Schroder Wertheim conference. &quot;This is not one big country that speaks the same language.&quot;</p>
<p>Central European Media owns, operates and develops national and regional television stations in emerging markets of central Europe, as well as regional commercial TV stations in Germany.</p>
<p>The issue was part of a panel discussion at the Variety-Schroder Wertheim conference, prompting some American media executives quip that the infiltration of American programmes could end up having the same destructive cultural effect on the rest of the world that has been experienced in the United States -- the so-called &quot;dumbing-down&quot; of society.</p>
<p>But some Europeans aren't sure that's such a bad thing.</p>
<p>&quot;The Germans are starting to laugh. It's an amazing event,&quot; joked Klaus Hallig, the U.S. representative for Germany's Kirch Group. &quot;And the one who really did it is Bill Cosby.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
