<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504689" id="root" date="1997-04-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: N.Irish raids yield rifles and arrests.</title>
<headline>N.Irish raids yield rifles and arrests.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-04-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>British forces seized two rifles and arrested seven men in a major security operation close to the Northern Ireland border with the Irish republic, security sources said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The operation was aimed at finding arms used by IRA guerrilla snipers who have killed eleven British soldiers and police officers along the disputed frontier during the conflict over Britain's rule over Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>Police confirmed that one of the seized rifles was a U.S.-manufactured Barrett &quot;Light Fifty&quot; with telescopic sight, among the most lethal weapons used by Irish Republican Army snipers. The other gun was a Kalashnikov assault rifle.</p>
<p>In February a British soldier Stephen Restorick, 23, was killed by a single shot at a security checkpoint in Bessbrook, Country Armagh.</p>
<p>Security sources said a car, specially fitted with armour plating, and of a type known to have been used in IRA gun attacks, had also been found.</p>
<p>The discovery and the arrests were made near Crossmaglen, County Armagh, in the heart of what has been dubbed &quot;bandit country&quot; because of the high level of guerrilla activity in a 28 year IRA war.</p>
<p>Police confirmed that a number of men had been arrested late on Thursday. Since then soldiers and police have been carrying out a major search. &quot;It's fairly big stuff,&quot; said a security source.</p>
<p>The IRA resumed hostilities a year ago after abandoning a 17 month ceasefire.</p>
<p>On Thursday a policewoman was seriously wounded in a gun attack in Londonderry city, in the north-west of the province. IRA guerrillas have killed two soldiers, including Restorick, in gun and bomb attacks in the province since last October.</p>
<p>It has also set off a series of bombs on mainland Britain, killing two civilians.</p>
<p>British and Irish politicians blame the IRA for making Northern Ireland even more unstable. Protestant guerrillas loyal to Britain say their truce of October 1994 is still in force but &quot;Loyalist&quot; hardliners have been blamed for series of attacks on Catholic nationalists, including two murders in the past year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
