<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504643" id="root" date="1997-04-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: TENNIS-CLAVET SETS UP FINAL WITH CORRETJA.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-CLAVET SETS UP FINAL WITH CORRETJA.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-04-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's Francisco Clavet clawed his way back from a set down to beat compatriot Felix Mantilla 3-6 7-5 6-0 on Saturday and reach the final of the Estoril Open.</p>
<p>In Sunday's final he faces fellow Spaniard Alex Corretja, who had little trouble in dismissing an out-of-sorts Javier Sanchez 6-3 6-1 in the other all-Spanish semifinal.</p>
<p>Mantilla had served for the match at 5-3 in the second set after having won the first 6-3 but Clavet managed to break him.</p>
<p>Playing some of the best tennis seen in the tournament so far, Clavet then saved five break points on his own serve before finally levelling for 5-5.</p>
<p>He immediately broke again before wrapping up the set on his own serve with an ace.</p>
<p>Mantilla, the highest-ranked player still in the tournament at number 14 in the world, began to tire.</p>
<p>After injuring his left leg, which required several minutes of massage before he could continue, Mantilla offered little further resistance and Clavet, who defeated world number eight Carlos Moya in the quarter-finals, ran away with the third set.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt that Mantilla was very tired and I took advantage of the chance to attack more. This victory is very special because Mantilla is very difficult to beat,&quot; said Clavet.</p>
<p>Earlier, Corretja had been in devastating form against Sanchez, brushing him aside in little over an hour.</p>
<p>After taking the first set, he broke Sanchez at the start of the second and then allowed him just one more game, with a Sanchez double fault finally ending the match.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
