<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504682" id="root" date="1997-04-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Moldova vows to press ahead with economic reform.</title>
<headline>Moldova vows to press ahead with economic reform.</headline>
<byline>Brian Killen</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moldovan Prime Minister Ion Ciubuc said on Saturday that the government would press ahead with economic reforms and concentrate on boosting the role of the private sector.</p>
<p>&quot;We are convinced that it is only through social and economic reforms that we can improve the situation in Moldova,&quot; he told the annual meeting of the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD).</p>
<p>Ciubuc called for support from international institutions but made no reference to a threat this week by the International Monetary Fund to suspend a $195-million three-year loan programme because of what it called an unsatisfactory economic performance.</p>
<p>&quot;Without foreign investment and support from international institutions it will be difficult for Moldova to solve the problems it faces in the transition to a market economy,&quot; Ciubuc said.</p>
<p>&quot;Increasing participation of the private sector in the economy is going to make the republic more attractive to foreign investors,&quot; he added. Over 40 percent of Moldova's gross domestic product comes from the private sector.</p>
<p>The energy and agro-business sectors have been targetted as priority areas for restructuring and privatisation.</p>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Ion Gutu, responsible for the economy and reforms, said Moldova had lagged behind in restructuring at the micro-economic level.</p>
<p>World Bank representatives in Moldova have voiced concern at the slow pace of structural reforms in the former Soviet republic of 4.4 million people, located between Ukraine and Romania.</p>
<p>Moldova, which had built up a reputation as one of the fastest reforming members of the Commonwealth of Independent States, saw output continue to fall last year.</p>
<p>&quot;We are really gearing our efforts to restructuring our domestic industrial enterprises,&quot; Gutu said.  &quot;We must single out those sectors of the economy that are viable from those doomed to fail.&quot;</p>
<p>Gutu said the emphasis would be on creating and strengthening small- and medium-sized companies and many of these would be sold off at auctions in the coming days.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOLDV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
