<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504717" id="root" date="1997-04-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia may receive last IMF loan in 1997 - Chubais.</title>
<headline>Russia may receive last IMF loan in 1997 - Chubais.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-04-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's First Deputy Prime Minister Anatoly Chubais said Moscow could receive its final loan from the International Monetary Fund this year, Itar-Tass news agency reported.</p>
<p>The report also quoted Chubais as saying Russia's economic situation was good enough that loans from the World Bank that now go straight into the federal budget could be put into concrete investment projects.</p>
<p>First Deputy Prime Minister Boris Nemtsov said on Saturday a housing reform project could be among the first to be implemented under a $3 billion World Bank loan this year.</p>
<p>Nemtsov, who met World Bank President James Wolfensohn on Saturday, said the housing reform project, originally scheduled to start in 2000, could break ground as early as this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot wait until the year 2000 to reform our housing system and the modernisation of the water and sewage system, and so we discussed the desirability of changing the start of the project from 2000 to 1997 or 1998,&quot; Nemtsov told reporters.</p>
<p>He said the World Bank loan would also be used to support the pension system and child support payments as well as to finance housing, energy conservation and other investment projects.</p>
<p>Chubais also said the World Bank would act as guarantor for a loan from a Western consortium of banks to implement a sea-based launch pad for commercial satellites, Tass said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
