<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504738" id="root" date="1997-04-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Vukovar teenagers graduate to uncertain future.</title>
<headline>Vukovar teenagers graduate to uncertain future.</headline>
<byline>Jovan Kovacic</byline>
<dateline>VUKOVAR, Croatia 1997-04-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's a high school graduation night and teenagers are celebrating their first taste of adulthood, singing and dancing to blaring music and toasting their future with champagne in a restaurant on the Danube.</p>
<p>The boys are uncomfortable in their formal suits and ties have been loosened under flushed faces as the party swings into high gear. Their girlfriends are immaculately dressed and made up, enjoying the rivalry with each other and the attention of the boys.</p>
<p>But it's all a little unreal. These are young Serbs with nowhere to go.</p>
<p>The Friday night party is being held in the devastated town of Vukovar in Eastern Slavonia, a former rebel Serb enclave due to revert soon to Croatian control.</p>
<p>On Sunday, local elections will be held in Eastern Slavonia as one of the final steps towards the end of local Serbs' hopes of remaining independent.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel like Cinderella,&quot; says Sandra, a graduate of the Vukovar economic high school. &quot;I fear the stroke of midnight when all this will vanish.&quot;</p>
<p>Vukovar was practically obliterated by the local Serbs and the Yugoslav army during a bitter six-month war in 1991 when the Serbs rebelled against Croatia's secession from former Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>The Croats were driven out and a few thousand Serbs remained, patching up homes but unable to rebuild the vast destruction without assistance from neighbouring Serbia which was loth to invest in the area.</p>
<p>Embittered local Serbs see that as a sure sign that Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic, whom the West holds responsible for starting the war to create greater Serbia, was prepared a long time ago to sell out his ethnic kin.</p>
<p>Vukovar is now packed with Serb refugees from Bosnia and other parts of Croatia, and the Greater Serbia dream is in tatters.</p>
<p>In a few months, former Croat neighbours will return and many Serbs fear their revenge for the destruction and atrocities committed during the war.</p>
<p>Their dilemma is that they have have nowhere to flee, since Serbia will not have them.</p>
<p>&quot;My cousin was killed, my father lost an arm, and I still consider myself lucky compared to some of my friends. But now my family is asking the awful question -- why was all this suffering necessary?&quot; Sandra says.</p>
<p>&quot;Now our leaders are urging us to become Croatian citizens, trying to convince us it is such a wonderful thing. Why didn't they say the same thing six years ago and spare us the suffering?&quot;</p>
<p>Just hours ahead of elections, Serb leaders were making a strong pitch for their people to obtain Croat documents, effectively becoming Croatian citizens, and vote on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is not a solitary reason why you should move now. Stay here until the very end,&quot; Vojislav Stanimirovic, the local Serb party leader, told a poorly attended rally on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Bloody hell, they gave us plenty of reason to fight six years ago,&quot; Nikola, another graduate, says.</p>
<p>&quot;These kids have really had a bum deal. They have lost the best part of their youth to war, devastation and deprivation,&quot; a teacher says, speaking on condition of anonymity.</p>
<p>&quot;For who knows what the next day may bring? Everything is uncertain here, but nothing more so than the future of these child-adults.&quot;</p>
<p>Like most children in war-torn Croatia and Bosnia, these children had no psychiatric counselling and no guidance for the future.</p>
<p>&quot;What can I do with my diploma, but tear it up? Is there any work for me here, will the Croats give me any work, will Serbia give me any work? The answer is no.&quot; Nikola says.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel like a rat in a trap. I can now run only in circles, but there is no way out.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VUKOVAR, Croatia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
