<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504709" id="root" date="1997-04-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Tudjman party faces opposition challenge in vote.</title>
<headline>Tudjman party faces opposition challenge in vote.</headline>
<byline>Mark Heinrich</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-04-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Franjo Tudjman's nationalist party faces a centre-left opposition challenge in major cities in regional elections on Sunday which will include former rebel Serbs for the first time.</p>
<p>His Croatian Democratic Union (HDZ) drew a smaller crowd at its final election rally in Zagreb's baroque main square on Friday evening than the rival Social Democrats (former communists) did there two nights before.</p>
<p>Saturday was a day of electoral silence after a two-month campaign for municipal and county councils and parliament's upper House of Counties. Presidential elections follow this summer and Tudjman, 74, will run despite being ill with cancer.</p>
<p>The regional elections will be independent Croatia's first peacetime vote and a revealing test of Tudjman's personal popularity as well as his willingness to heed the popular will, since his party could be defeated in some major cities.</p>
<p>Tudjman, an authoritarian ex-general, led Croatia in a successful 1991 war for independence from Yugoslavia but fighting with Belgrade-backed local Serbs ended only in 1995.</p>
<p>The Croatian army reconquered two of three rebel minority enclaves that year. Serbs in the third, Eastern Slavonia, agreed to &quot;peaceful reintegration&quot; under U.N. supervision after Belgrade withdrew its support for their revolt.</p>
<p>Serb leaders formed a single party bloc (SDSS) to enter the elections only at the last minute after moderates shunted aside diehard nationalists opposed to a Croatian restoration.</p>
<p>The SDSS said it was time for Serbs to battle with votes rather than guns and its priority would be to hold Zagreb to promises of significant minority rights made under Western pressure to foster Serb-Croat reconciliation.</p>
<p>&quot;These are the first truly fair, open, democratic elections in a region that is very cynical about elections,&quot; said Jacques Klein, transitional U.N. administrator of Eastern Slavonia.</p>
<p>U.N. monitors said the SDSS could win up to a dozen of 30 districts on the fertile plain abutting the Danube river border with the Yugoslav republic of Serbia.</p>
<p>The HDZ was tipped to capture overwhelming majorities in other Slavonian districts, backed by Croat refugees from the 1991 war who will be voting absentee but want to reclaim their homes once Zagreb's authority is reinstated this summer.</p>
<p>U.N. peace forces will be on alert for possible attempts to disrupt voting. The enclave will be sealed off against intruders and a special U.N. &quot;intervention group&quot; equipped with helicopters will be ready to go anywhere at short notice in case of trouble, a Belgian U.N. general told reporters.</p>
<p>Hundreds of international monitors will scrutinise the elections for possible irregularities in Eastern Slavonia and across the rest of the republic of 4.7 million.</p>
<p>Away from the enclave, polls suggested the HDZ, relying heavily on Tudjman's &quot;Father of the Nation&quot; charisma, would retain majorities in smaller municipalities but the biggest cities including Zagreb, Split and Osijek were up for grabs.</p>
<p>The HDZ's popularity has slumped to between 20 and 35 percent in urban Croatia in a post-war backlash over corruption-tinged privatisation that enriched a politically connected elite while most Croats found it increasingly hard to make ends meet.</p>
<p>Bread-and-butter grievances have revived the appeal of the Social Democrats (SDP). The HDZ countered with a barrage of anti-SDP advertising claiming Croatia's independence and stability would collapse if &quot;Yugo-nostalgic&quot; parties took over.</p>
<p>It tried to sow suspicion of the SDP's communist past in Yugoslavia. SDP leaders described HDZ tactics as desperate.</p>
<p>Analysts said the HDZ's new fixation on former communists suggested it feared being outpolled by the SDP alone in Zagreb. The SDP was running in coalition with the Social Liberals.</p>
<p>The Croatian capital will be the biggest prize by far in the elections. Its metropolitan area boasts a third of Croatia's population, half of its productive economy and a powerful political patronage machine.</p>
<p>In 1995, Tudjman exercised his &quot;national security&quot; veto to quash an opposition coalition victory in elections for Zagreb's city and county councils and impose his own provisional mayor.</p>
<p>Critics said the HDZ could try to rig vote totals on Sunday or resort to legalistic obstruction in the aftermath to stave off defeat in the largest cities.</p>
<p>But diplomats believe the HDZ has less room to ignore a popular verdict now than in 1995 because Croatia has joined the Council of Europe and must behave more democratically to qualify for integration with the West.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
