<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504702" id="root" date="1997-04-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALI: Mali kicks off second multiparty elections Sunday.</title>
<headline>Mali kicks off second multiparty elections Sunday.</headline>
<byline>Mamadou Kaba</byline>
<dateline>BAMAKO 1997-04-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mali, widely praised for its smooth democratic transition in 1992, kicks off its second multiparty national elections on Sunday with a parliamentary poll the opposition says cannot be free and fair.</p>
<p>The election, for the 147 seats in a new national assembly, pits supporters of President Alpha Oumar Konare, a historian elected in 1992, against two main opposition alliances.</p>
<p>The landlocked West African nation's two main opposition groups, in a joint communique published on Thursday, denounced delays in issuing voter cards and displaying electoral lists, saying such problems could threaten stability.</p>
<p>But the independent national electoral commission (CENI), set up by Konare at the opposition's demand, said apart from isolated problems in the south and north the country of 11 million people was ready for the poll.</p>
<p>&quot;Conditions do not exist for the Malian people to express themselves freely,&quot; the opposition Front for Change and Democracy (FCD) and the Rally of Patriotic Forces (RFP) said in their statement. Such conditions threatened the democratic process and social peace, they added.</p>
<p>The RFP, led by its charismatic secretary general Choguel Maiga, is largely composed of supporters of the former single party and jailed former dictator Moussa Traore, whose 1991 overthrow cleared the way for democratic reform.</p>
<p>The FCD portrays itself as heir to the tradition of independence leader Modibo Keita, a fiercely nationalist and hardline socialist leader who declared a one-party state after independence from France in 1960.</p>
<p>Konare, who will face nine challengers in May 4 presidential elections, has steered Mali on a path of economic liberalisation which has won praise from the United States and the World Bank.</p>
<p>James Wolfensohn began his first foreign trip as World Bank president in Mali in 1995 and a year later the then U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher singled out Mali as the first stop of his own first major African tour.</p>
<p>Mali, on the fringe of the Sahara desert, has few natural advantages apart from gold -- a sector it is expanding.</p>
<p>Konare sealed a peace deal last year in a revolt by light-skinned Tuaregs in the north, who took up arms in 1990 denouncing domination by majority blacks from the south.</p>
<p>Five million Malians are eligible to vote on Sunday in the 9,500 polling stations. Electoral commission officials say those without voting cards will be able to use their identity cards if they are on the voter lists.</p>
<p>A dozen observers from Germany, Canada, Britain and the Netherlands will monitor polling.</p>
<p>The government says the low turnout of observers reflects foreign confidence in Mali's democracy. The opposition says foreign nations do not want to be linked with electoral chaos.</p>
<p>Polls open at 8 a.m. (0800 GMT) and close at 6 p.m. (1800 GMT). First results are likely after a couple of days. The constitutional court will ratify and announce final results.</p>
<p>Second round runoffs will take place on April 27.</p>
<p>The elections were put back from March at the request of the election commission, which cited organisational delays.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAMAKO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
