<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504834" id="root" date="1997-04-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: 400 march on South Carolina capitol.</title>
<headline>400 march on South Carolina capitol.</headline>
<dateline>COLUMBIA, S.C. 1997-04-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of people marched to a gathering at the South Carolina State House Saturday to pressure lawmakers into taking a tougher stance on church burnings and other hate crimes.</p>
<p>The march, which organisers dubbed The National March of Solidarity to Challenge Hate in America, began in downtown Columbia and ended at the state's capitol building, where speakers called on citizens to join the fight against racial hatred.</p>
<p>The crowd of blacks and whites, which officials estimated to number about 400, came from as far away as Detroit and New England.</p>
<p>Some 200 black churches have been destroyed by fire since 1991, including 31 in South Carolina.</p>
<p>Two Ku Klux Klan members were sentenced to prison after pleading guilty to setting two of the church fires in South Carolina. Two other Klan leaders pleaded guilty to encouraging them to burn the churches.</p>
<p>The Rev. Terrance Mackey, pastor of one of the churches burned by Klan members, helped organise Saturday's march. Mackey said he had received threats since the march was announced, including a man who told him if the march were held, &quot;This is war.&quot;</p>
<p>He also pointed to what he said was a small bullet hole in a window of the building where the march was planned as a sign of intimidation, and said that law enforcement officials did not take it seriously.</p>
<p>Columbia Police Chief Charles Austin said Mackey reported the hole to the State Law Enforcement Division, not the police, but that both agencies had thoroughly investigated the incident. He said it was uncertain whether the hole even came from a bullet or when it was made.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLUMBIA, S.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
