<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50484" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Beirut takes attack warning seriously - official.</title>
<headline>Beirut takes attack warning seriously - official.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Beirut is taking seriously a warning by Israel's proxy militia in south Lebanon of a big Israeli military operation if there is an upsurge of violence in the south, a senior foreign ministry official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Lebanon is taking these grave threats seriously,&quot; the official told Reuters. &quot;We are surprised that they come when security conditions in south Lebanon are relatively stable.&quot;</p>
<p>General Antoine Lahd, commander of the South Lebanon Army (SLA), issued the warning on Wednesday while urging Lebanon to reconsider Israel's &quot;Lebanon first&quot; proposal for a conditional withdrawal of its troops from south Lebanon.</p>
<p>Israel said in July it was ready to pull out under a deal to be negotiated with Syria, if Syrian troops also left Lebanon and if the Lebanese army could guarantee Israel's security against cross-border guerrilla attacks.</p>
<p>Both Syria and Lebanon rejected the offer.</p>
<p>Lahd said Lebanon faced the possibility of widescale Israeli retaliation if pro-Iranian Hizbollah (Party of God) guerrillas stepped up their attacks on Israeli troops occupying a 15-km (nine-mile) south Lebanon border strip.</p>
<p>Israel launched a bloody 17-day blitz against Lebanon in April after tit-for-tat bombardments of civilian areas by the two sides.</p>
<p>Beirut newspapers on Thursday quoted parliament Speaker Nabih Berri, Lebanon's top Shi'ite Moslem official, as warning of possible Israeli attacks before the U.S. presidential election in November.</p>
<p>&quot;Israel might benefit from the no-decision situation in the United States before the election to get the green light for launching an offensive against Lebanon,&quot; Berri said.</p>
<p>The foreign ministry official, who asked not to be identified, said Lebanon insisted on implementation of U.N. Security Council resolution 425 from 1978 calling for immediate and unconditional Israeli withdrawal.</p>
<p>He said Foreign Minister Faris Bouez would raise the issue with his Syrian counterpart Farouq al-Shara during a visit to Syria on Thursday ahead of a meeting of Arab foreign ministers in Cairo.</p>
<p>Damascus is the main power broker in Lebanon with 35,000 troops stationed throughout most of the country.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
