<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504856" id="root" date="1997-04-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Fire damages Turin Cathedral, famous shroud saved.</title>
<headline>Fire damages Turin Cathedral, famous shroud saved.</headline>
<dateline>TURIN, Italy 1997-04-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A huge blaze destroyed part of this northern Italian city's cathedral early on Saturday, but firefighters smashed through bulletproof glass to save the historic Turin shroud which was housed in the 15th century building, police said.</p>
<p>The fire, its cause unknown, gutted a side chapel and spread to an adjoining royal palace as emergency crews from around the region rushed to the scene to try to halt the flames.</p>
<p>Nobody was believed to have been injured in the blaze, which threatened to destroy one of the Roman Catholic church's most famous relics.</p>
<p>Cathedral guards said they thought the fire started shortly before midnight (2200 GMT) in the Guarini chapel, home of the Turin shroud -- a piece of cloth imprinted with the image of a man's body that many Roman Catholic believers take to be the figure of Christ after his crucifixion.</p>
<p>The shroud, which was displayed behind bullet proof glass, was plucked to safety by fireman Mario Trematore, who, with the help of colleagues, managed to smash the protective covering as flames engulfed the chapel.</p>
<p>A huge crowd which had gathered in a central square in front of the cathedral to watch the blaze burst into applause as the firemen carried the famous white cloth to safety.</p>
<p>&quot;God gave me the strength to break that glass,&quot; Trematore was quoted as saying by Italian newsagency Ansa.</p>
<p>Cardinal Giovanni Saldarini, based in Turin, rushed to the scene as soon as he was told of the fire and inspected the shroud after it was brought out of the cathedral.</p>
<p>&quot;It's intact, it's a miracle,&quot; he said. The cloth was then taken to his house for safe keeping.</p>
<p>Witnesses said huge orange flames leapt from part of the roof of the cathedral, lighting up the night sky, as the fire started to attack the adjacent royal palace, which also dates back to the 15th century.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an overwhelming tragedy,&quot; the mayor of this wealthy city, Valentino Castellani, told reporters. &quot;It is too early to say what damage has been caused to the precious Guarini chapel or to the palace,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Onlookers said the blaze had defaced part of the palace's facade and had taken hold in the building's west tower. Locals said the tower had only recently been restored and contained some of the building's most ornate and precious furnishings.</p>
<p>Fireman tried to douse the wing from three sides and powerful fire engines based in the city airport were called in to help the rescue teams.</p>
<p>Saturday was the second time the Turin shroud has come close to being destroyed by fire in its long history.</p>
<p>Brought to light in France in 1353, the shroud was taken to Turin in 1694 after a blaze wrecked the place it was being stored in. The cloth still bears the marks of that fire.</p>
<p>The shroud became famous worldwide at the end of last century when a photographic negative revealed the image of a man who had appeared to have been crucified. Many people believe Christ was wrapped in the cloth after his death, though scientists say its origins are in the Middle Ages.</p>
<p>The fire in the cathedral was the second time in just over a year that an historic Italian building had been hit by a blaze.</p>
<p>Venice's famous Fenice opera house was gutted in 1996 in a fire which magistrates are still investigating. Some newspapers have suggested the Mafia might have started the inferno.</p>
<p>Officials in Turin said it was too early to say what had caused the cathedral fire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TURIN, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
