<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504894" id="root" date="1997-04-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian air operations resume after strike ends. [CORRECTED 14:15 GMT]</title>
<headline>Indian air operations resume after strike ends. [CORRECTED 14:15 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Sambit Mohanty</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian air traffic controllers on Saturday ended a strike over the suspension of a colleague which had disrupted domestic and international flights and stranded thousands of passengers, aviation officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;The strike has been called off and normal services are expected to be restored by around 5 p.m. hours (1130 GMT),&quot; a spokesman for state-run Indian Airlines, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Thousands of people were stranded across India, as well as at airports in Singapore, Hong Kong and Bangkok, when the controllers launched their strike without warning shortly before noon on Friday, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;The operations have resumed,&quot; said another spokesman of IA.</p>
<p>The first Indian Airlines international flight (corrects to insert name of airline) to Sharjah from Bombay was scheduled to leave at 4 p.m.(1030 GMT) but it was delayed as some clearances were awaited, he said.</p>
<p>Its first domestic flight (corrects to make clear it is an Indian Airlines flight) was scheduled to leave Delhi for Bombay at 6.30 p.m. (1300 GMT), he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Two of our flights one to Bombay and the other to Bangalore had already left after 5 p.m.,&quot; said a spokesman of private domestic carrier Jet Airways.</p>
<p>IA officials estimated that total industry losses amounted to at least 300 million rupees ($8.4 million).</p>
<p>&quot;The strike disrupted about 200 flights yesterday,&quot; Vikram Badshah, director (corporate affairs) of IA told Reuters.</p>
<p>Twenty eight Indian Airlines flights had been cancelled by 10.30 a.m. on Saturday, he added.</p>
<p>In Hong Kong, airport officials said 800 passengers were stranded as 14 flights to or from India and the Middle East were cancelled since Friday afternoon due to the strike.</p>
<p>Officials said 2,000 people were marooned for the night at a Singapore airport because there were no hotel rooms available for them after Singapore Airlines suspended 13 flights to 12 destinations in India.</p>
<p>British Airways put more than 700 people in hotels in Bangkok when three of its flights were delayed, a spokeswoman said. Australian airline Qantas made similar arrangements.</p>
<p>The Indian controllers went on strike to protest the suspension of a colleague, who, airport authorities say, was punished for a lapse that could have resulted in a mid-air collision.</p>
<p>But talks between the Air Traffic Controllers' Guild and the Airports Authority of India (AAI) proved successful after AAI withdrew the suspension order, officials said.</p>
<p>But they vowed to continue investigations into the matter.</p>
<p>&quot;...That (the agreement) does not dilute the management's prerogative to carry our further inquiries and take appropriate steps,&quot; an AAI official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Officials of the Air Traffic Controllers' Guild were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>The world's worst mid-air collision occurred in New Delhi's skies last November between a Saudi Arabian Airlines Boeing 747 and a Kazakh Ilyushin Il-76 freighter, killing all 349 people on the two planes. ($1 = 35.8 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
