<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="504938" id="root" date="1997-04-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India Essar to raise refinery capacity.</title>
<headline>India Essar to raise refinery capacity.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-04-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Essar Oil Ltd said on Saturday it planned to raise the capacity of its proposed refinery to 10.5 million tonnes of crude a year from 9.0 million tonnes.  </p>
<p>The cost of the refinery would go up to 58.15 billion rupees from the earlier estimate of 53.50 billion rupees, a company official told Reuters on Saturday.</p>
<p>She gave the following reasons for the increased cost:</p>
<p>* The rupee had depreciated to 35.90 against the dollar from 31.50 when the cost was earlier calculated</p>
<p>* Essar Oil is adding a hydro desulphurisation unit as per new government guidelines on sulphur content in diesel</p>
<p>* &quot;A delayed coker is included in the configuration to improve the gross refining margin by $0.30 per barrel,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>She said the currrent gross refining margin was $5.8 per barrel.</p>
<p>Essar Oil plans to create a separate joint venture firm to build infrastructure facilities such as single buoy mooring for the receipt of crude oil, jetty and rail/road despatch stations for product shipments, storage tanks and pipelines, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;Discussions with potential joint venture partners are in an advanced stage,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The refinery is expected to be commissioned by April 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;About half of the civil works for crude and vacuum distillation units has been completed,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Over 4,000 workers are working on the site on the western Gujarat coast, supervised by 30 expatriates from ABB Lummus besides 300 engineers from the state-run Engineers India Ltd, Tata Consultancy Engineers and Essar Group engineers, she said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
