<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505137" id="root" date="1997-04-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Russian officials optimistic on tax as crunch looms.</title>
<headline>Russian officials optimistic on tax as crunch looms.</headline>
<byline>Brian Killen</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian officials beamed optimism on Sunday over prospects for tax collection under a new government team despite failing to reach targets so far this year and doubts among senior members of parliament. &quot;I think that this problem should be settled once and for all in 1997,&quot; Central Bank Chairman Sergei Dubinin told the annual meeting of the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD).</p>
<p>&quot;This is really a key problem for financial stabilisation,&quot; he said. &quot;At the start of 1997 we saw a gradual increase in budget revenues from month to month, but it is still lower than planned for in the 1997 budget.&quot;</p>
<p>Failure to meet targets for tax collection has prompted the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to suspend payments to Russia under a $10 billion lending programme. But the IMF now looks set to restart disbursals after recent government assurances.</p>
<p>Dubinin told Reuters that budget income was the only figure not yet agreed with the IMF. &quot;This figure will be agreed after April 20, so we have about a week for this,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>First Deputy Finance Minister Alexei Kudrin, an influential member of the new government, told Reuters Financial Television that tax was a top priority, along with improving state controls over monopolies in gas, electricity and the railways.</p>
<p>&quot;A new tax code will be introduced to the State Duma (lower chamber of parliament) in April,&quot; he said. &quot;We are taking every possible step linked to reform of the tax system.&quot;</p>
<p>Kudrin believed that tax collection, which was about 55 percent of the amount called for in the budget in the first quarter, could be increased by about two percentage points of gross domestic product by the end of this year.</p>
<p>Alexander Shokhin, first deputy speaker of the Duma, was less sanguine, saying it would be tough to raise tax collection without fundamental reforms and these had to be submitted urgently to the opposition-dominated legislature. &quot;Some tax changes should not wait for adoption of the new tax code so that they can take effect in the second half of this year,&quot; he said, adding that there ought to be an overall reduction in taxation with more focus on indirect levies. &quot;This could have a positive impact even this year, but it will still be difficult to implement the budget,&quot; he said during a break at the EBRD meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has to submit a new version of the budget in April. Many expenses have to be sharply cut.&quot;</p>
<p>Sergei Vasilyev, first deputy head of government administration, said the new tax code would significantly simplify the system, widening the base and eliminating some exemptions. He gave no details.</p>
<p>Vasilyev said other planned reforms included measures by the middle of this year to introduce international accounting standards, target welfare benefits to help the most needy and moves to promote private pension plans.</p>
<p>Kudrin, a close confidant of First Deputy Prime Minister Anatoly Chubais, said the new government team was the most competent since market reforms started in 1992.</p>
<p>&quot;Only now do we have a government that shares common principles and has a common goal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Central bank governor Dubinin was sure this year's performance would be better. &quot;There will be a great administrative effort to collect taxes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Revenues from alcohol sales would also be strictly controlled, he added.</p>
<p>--EBRD newsroom, +44 171 796 5146</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
