<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505175" id="root" date="1997-04-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire rebels to relaunch offensive, capital jittery.</title>
<headline>Zaire rebels to relaunch offensive, capital jittery.</headline>
<byline>John Chiahemen</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-04-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's rebels said on Sunday they were relaunching their whirlwind offensive after expiry of a three-day deadline for President Mobutu Sese Seko to quit.</p>
<p>The new military governor of Zaire's teeming capital, a declared rebel target, appealed for calm, saying that developments on the war front had sown panic in the city.</p>
<p>On the humanitarian front, relief officials announced a cholera epidemic among Rwandan Hutu refugees in the rebel-held east, saying it would delay a planned repatriation airlift.</p>
<p>&quot;An atmosphere of panic, due essentially to the situation in the east of our country, reigns among Kinshasa's men and women,&quot; General Amela Lokima told state television.</p>
<p>&quot;The most fantastic rumours according to which the city of Kinshasa would soon fall to the armed rebellion are gaining ground,&quot; he said in an address during the lunchtime news.</p>
<p>The television announcer said panic had gripped districts of Kinshasa near the airport after anti-Mobutu militants urged residents to evacuate.</p>
<p>Opposition militants who have declared support for rebel leader Laurent Kabila have called for a total shutdown of the capital on Monday as part of a planned campaign to force an end to Mobutu's 32-year rule.</p>
<p>Amela called on Zaireans and foreigners living in the city of five million people to remain calm, adding: &quot;The security of our capital is our fundamental duty.&quot;</p>
<p>The rebels, who control half the vast Central African nation, including its mineral-rich economic heartland, said on Sunday they were resuming their offensive.</p>
<p>Bizima Karaha, foreign affairs commissioner in the rebel alliance, told a news conference at their headquarters in the eastern city of Goma that Mobutu had had his last chance.</p>
<p>&quot;We have decided that we will not give Mobutu any more chance... We want them (the government) to go -- and after they have left we will consider a ceasefire because if Mobutu leaves it will be the end of the war,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The rebels have been pushing for a summit between Mobutu and Kabila. Karaha said Kabila would probably go to South Africa soon to spur negotiations on Mobutu's departure.</p>
<p>On Saturday, Mobutu dismissed Kabila's deadline for him to show willingness to quit but left the door ajar for face-to-face talks with Kabila, whose rebels took up arms in October in a dispute over Zairean nationality for ethnic Tutsis.</p>
<p>&quot;If he asks me politely I cannot refuse to talk to a compatriot but (for him) to be in Goma and say I give him three days, it's not my style or nature. I cannot reply,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mobutu, 66, had prostate cancer surgery in Europe in August. He has accused rivals of taking advantage of his illness.</p>
<p>He declared a nationwide state of emergency on Tuesday, naming Amela among five military governors in areas not under rebel control.</p>
<p>He named General Likulia Bolongo as his emergency rule prime minister on Wednesday, shunting aside his veteran opposition foe Etienne Tshisekedi, who had held the job for less than a week.</p>
<p>With Tshisekedi supporters accusing Mobutu of treason and openly calling for his removal, Likulia said on Saturday that all street protests in Kinshasa were banned.</p>
<p>&quot;The people cannot take to the streets. We are under a state of emergency. Police measures have been taken to curb activities of the political parties,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Thousands of opposition militants trying to move Tshisekedi into the premier's offices clashed with troops on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
