<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505134" id="root" date="1997-04-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Blair pledges to give up negative poll campaigning.</title>
<headline>Blair pledges to give up negative poll campaigning.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>MILTON KEYNES, England 1997-04-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tony Blair on Sunday vowed to give up negative campaigning in the run-up to the May 1 election, when he hopes to become Britain's first Labour prime minister since 1979.</p>
<p>&quot;People deserve a better election campaign than the tit-for-tat election campaign they are getting,&quot; Blair said in a speech at Milton Keynes, central England.</p>
<p>Aides denied Blair's new emphasis signalled that attacks by the ruling Conservatives on him last week had hit home, denting Labour's huge opinion poll lead.</p>
<p>One poll in the Sunday Times showed Labour had fallen four points in a week to 48 percent support. Two others gave Labour a 16 point lead over the Conservatives compared with figures above 20 percent when the campaign began three weeks ago.</p>
<p>The Conservatives last week attacked Blair for what they claimed were u-turns on key policies, such as Labour's new-found willingness to consider privatisation of some industries such as Britain's air traffic control system.</p>
<p>A senior Blair aide, Alistair Campbell, said Labour had never believed it was 20 points ahead.</p>
<p>He said voters were becoming bored with a campaign in which they constantly saw politicians slinging abuse at each other, blaming the Conservatives for never talking about their own policy plans.</p>
<p>&quot;The more relentlessly negative they become, the more positive we will get,&quot; Campbell, Blair's chief press officer and &quot;spin doctor&quot; said.</p>
<p>Blair unveiled new campaign advertising slogans which made no mention of his political opponents.</p>
<p>They emphasise Labour's key commitments -- &quot;Income tax rates will not rise,&quot; &quot;Class sizes will be smaller,&quot; &quot;NHS (health) waiting lists will be shorter,&quot;, &quot;More jobs for young people&quot; and &quot;Young offenders will be punished&quot;.</p>
<p>Blair hopes to keep up the momentum this week with keynote speeches on education, health and the party's claim to be aiming for a &quot;one nation Britain&quot;.</p>
<p>Aides say the speeches will aim to emphasise that although Blair has moved his party to the centre, jettisoning many traditional socialist beliefs, a Labour government would mean a more caring administration.</p>
<p>&quot;When people say to me You have betrayed the Labour Party through change', I say not to change is a betrayal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said traditional Labour policies were no longer appropriate given the nature of the global market and called for &quot;an enlightened view of society which recognises that we do best as individuals in a decent society&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILTON KEYNES, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
