<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505128" id="root" date="1997-04-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Anti-EU crusaders rally in London.</title>
<headline>Anti-EU crusaders rally in London.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Marshall</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of anti-Brussels crusaders rallied under the banner of billionaire Sir James Goldsmith's Referendum Party on Sunday to demand Britain's withdrawal from the European Union.</p>
<p>To a standing ovation from the self-styled &quot;rabble army&quot; of Referendum Party supporters, Goldsmith fired up his troops ahead of the May 1 general election with a speech in London's Alexandra Palace denouncing European integration.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue is whether Britain remains an independent and free nation or whether it becomes a province of a bureaucratic, federal superstate,&quot; he declared, to cries of &quot;Never&quot; from the crowd.</p>
<p>&quot;The politicians have no right to give away without our consent the freedoms that have been fought for for generations.&quot;</p>
<p>The party said 10,000 people attended the rally. As speaker after speaker denounced the bureacrats in Brussels, thousands of mainly elderly supporters waved red, white and blue British flags and white Referendum Party banners.</p>
<p>They sprang to their feet to sing the chorus of the party's specially-composed anthem, &quot;Let the people decide.&quot;</p>
<p>Goldsmith, whose pet political projects have ranged from trade to the environment, said he had no ambitions of high office for himself but simply wanted the people to have their say.</p>
<p>The party, formed last year and largely funded by Goldsmith, says its sole purpose is to secure a referendum on whether Britain stays in the EU.</p>
<p>Both the ruling Conservative and opposition Labour parties say they will hold a referendum on joining a single currency, but Goldsmith wants a poll on EU membership itself.</p>
<p>&quot;The Referendum Party seeks no power for itself. The only power it seeks is for you to be able to decide. Once a referendum has been held, our party will dissolve,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But there was no doubting how his supporters would vote in such a plebiscite.</p>
<p>&quot;In this century a million Britons have given their lives so that our islands should remain free from German domination. Did they die for nothing, I ask?&quot; said Sir George Gardiner, the party's first and only member of parliament after defecting from the Conservatives last month.</p>
<p>&quot;They fought and died to preserve the birthright of every Briton and you will never find me selling that birthright,&quot; he told the crowd.</p>
<p>Opinion polls suggest the Referendum Party will get around two percent of the vote in the election, but it could affect the result by taking votes from the Conservatives in marginal seats.</p>
<p>&quot;This government has betrayed the nation and it has betrayed the democratic process. It will be therefore be punished on May 1,&quot; Goldsmith said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
