<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505126" id="root" date="1997-04-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EBRD says maintains ties with struggling Belarus.</title>
<headline>EBRD says maintains ties with struggling Belarus.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) has confidence in the government of the former Soviet republic of Belarus despite its economic and political problems, EBRD first vice-president Ron Freeman said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Belarus, Russia's economically backward western neighbour, has undertaken reform at a much slower pace than in most former Soviet republics, prompting the World Bank and International Monetary Fund to break off relations.</p>
<p>&quot;Belarus has really been struggling,&quot; Freeman told reporters at the EBRD annual meeting in London.</p>
<p>&quot;But they haven't been doing it in bad faith, that's not our impression. We just think they're in a very difficult position. We are proceeding more slowly than we anticipated but we're definitely still working with them.</p>
<p>&quot;We have good people, good counterparties in the government, in whom we have confidence and with whom we are working closely and we continue to have an active Belarus programme. We'll be OK.&quot;</p>
<p>Freeman said Belarus had an &quot;impeccable&quot; record in servicing debt on some projects such as telecommunications, which was a basically sound business. But it had difficulties in other areas where there were problems with, for example, engineering, tendering or environmental compliance.</p>
<p>Asked whether political conditions in the country, where President Alexander Lukashenko has been accused of wielding near-dictatorial powers, could be a factor in EBRD relations with Belarus, Freeman said they could be.</p>
<p>&quot;It's within the responsibility and the authority of our board of directors to say that a given country -- and I'm not pointing to Belarus in particular -- is not complying with Article 1 of the EBRD's charter, which requires that they be moving towards a multi-party democracy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>This would mean instructing EBRD staff in the country to cease operations. &quot;The Board has not done that,&quot; Freeman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
