<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505258" id="root" date="1997-04-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil stevedores say talks with Cosipa stalled.</title>
<headline>Brazil stevedores say talks with Cosipa stalled.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-04-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian stevedores said initial talks to solve a labor dispute with steel firm Companhia Siderurgica Paulista (Cosipa) had stalled, but they hoped to resume negotiations at any time.</p>
<p>&quot;We did not reach an agreement,&quot; said Abelardo Fernandes, president of the National Stevedores' Union, adding that he was waiting for Cosipa to schedule new talks with unions.  </p>
<p>Twenty-six stevedores have been occupying two vessels at Cosipa's private terminal at Santos port for more than 10 days. They are protesting the firm's decision to use its own workers to load and unload at the terminal.</p>
<p>Military police officers are stationed on the pier, but have yet to carry out a judge's order to evacuate the workers.</p>
<p>The stevedores have warned they will immediately call a strike if the police tries to evict them, or if Cosipa allows new vessels to dock at the terminal and uses its own workers to load and unload cargo.  </p>
<p>The stevedores' action at the port has effectively paralyzed Cosipa's operations at the terminal, where four vessels were lined up Friday to unload iron ore, coal and metal products.</p>
<p>Union representatives met with Cosipa officials on Friday for talks attended by a labor mediator which lasted seven hours.</p>
<p>The stevedores say they are ready to offer a number of concessions in exchange for keeping their jobs, including a reduction in work teams.</p>
<p>&quot;They are even ready to unload vessels for free if the company has a shortage of any raw materials needed to continue operating,&quot; said Fernandes. &quot;But they are not going to give up the right to work.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- Joelle Diderich, Sao Paulo +55 11 248 5414))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
