<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505319" id="root" date="1997-04-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan to sell state telecom shares in '98 - papers.</title>
<headline>Taiwan to sell state telecom shares in '98 - papers.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-04-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan would sell between 10 and 30 percent of shares in state-owned Chunghwa Telecom Co at the end of 1998 as part of its privatisation plan, several Taiwan newspapers reported on Sunday.</p>
<p>Under a proposed plan, Chunghwa would also consider selling 20 percent of stakes to overseas investors.</p>
<p>Chunghwa, capitalised at T$96 billion, was in the process of revaluating its assets, the Commercial Times newspaper said.  </p>
<p>Before Chunghwa became a company in July 1996, it was a part of Taiwan government's Directorate General of Telecommunications which had monopolised the island's telecommunications business for 48 years.</p>
<p>Under reform laws enacted in January 1996, Taiwan liberalised its telecommunication market.</p>
<p>Foreign interests may own up to 20 percent of Taiwan firms offering common-carrier services, a ratio designed by parliament to ensure local control of what is considered a strategic resource.</p>
<p>Common-carrier services are the main telephone and data lines in Taiwan's telecom network, including mobile telephony and retail telephone services.</p>
<p>Since January 1996, foreigners have been free to own to operate Internet services, airline reservation systems and other value-added services that piggy-back common carrier networks.</p>
<p>((-- Taipei Newsroom 2-5080815))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
