<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505434" id="root" date="1997-04-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Wheat arrives in Iraq under U.N. deal - paper.</title>
<headline>Wheat arrives in Iraq under U.N. deal - paper.</headline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1997-04-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nearly 300,000 tonnes of wheat have arrived in Iraq under its oil-for-food deal with the United Nations, the government newspaper al-Jumhouriya said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;The amount of wheat arrived in Iraq under the memorandum with the United Nations has reached until April 11 281,793 tonnes,&quot; said the paper, quoting Iraqi Communications and Transport Minister Ahmed Murtada Ahmed Khalil.</p>
<p>The deal, which went into effect in December, allows Iraq, which is under U.N.-imposed sanctions for its 1990 invasion of Kuwait, to sell oil worth $2 billion to buy food and medicine.</p>
<p>Foodstuffs bought under the pact have been piling up but no medicine has arrived yet.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, the government began distributing an increased food ration of nine kilos (20 lb) of flour a month, up from seven kilos (15.4 lb). The government has been handing out flour, along with other foodstuffs, to Iraqis at giveaway prices since the sanctions were imposed.</p>
<p>Rations of other commodities such as sugar, rice, pulses, cooking oil, soap and tea would be raised from May.</p>
<p>Khalil said work was underway at Umm Qasr port in southern Iraq to unload three more vessels carrying French and Australian wheat.</p>
<p>The first consignments of food imported under the deal reached Iraq last month.</p>
<p>The minister said a shipload of vegetable oil was expected to dock at Umm Qasr in few days.</p>
<p>The United Nations has deployed more than 120 international observers to supervise the arrival, storage and distribution of food. Twenty U.N. observers have been sent to the three Kurdish provinces in northern Iraq, which are out of the control of the government, to monitor food and medicine distribution there.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
