<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505485" id="root" date="1997-04-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Nestle CFO sees forex gains tapering off.</title>
<headline>Nestle CFO sees forex gains tapering off.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-04-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mario Corti, chief financial officer of Nestle SA, said the company may realise more currency gains in 1997, but that the positive impact from currencies may lessen in the second half of this year.</p>
<p>In an interview published in the weekend edition of the Basler Zeitung, he also said financial markets generally overestimated the impact of currencies on the company's results, saying the franc's declines added &quot;only 1.4 percentage points to revenue growth of 7.1 percent&quot; in 1996.  </p>
<p>&quot;The currency influence is clearly overestimated. Of course, it helped us in the second half (of 1996). It has also helped us so far in the current year, but the current growth rates -- I am speaking only in terms of currencies -- will probably not be maintained,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Swiss franc weakened during the second half of last year as the dollar rose to over 1.30 francs by the end of December from around 1.20 to the Swiss franc in late July.</p>
<p>The franc has continued to depreciate against the dollar in 1997, closing on Friday at 1.4678 francs.  </p>
<p>Corti also said low coffee prices last year added to Nestle's positive results, but said that coffee, too, was just one factor among many.</p>
<p>&quot;I understand analysts who would like to attribute our success to just two or three factors. With us, it is not that simple,&quot; Corti said.</p>
<p>Corti said with respect to financial management that some changes were being considered, including cash management.  </p>
<p>&quot;There is the question regarding how high our liquidity reserves should be, in which currencies they should be held, and in which form,&quot; he said. Currently he said Nestle keeps much of such liquidity in Swiss francs.</p>
<p>&quot;Low Swiss franc money rates have been a liability for us,&quot; he said. Swiss franc short-term rates have held at or below two percent for much of the past year.</p>
<p>&quot;A second area which we want to address is risk management for the group, with respect not only to interest rates and currencies, but also to commodity risks,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>He said any talk on share markets about a possible repayment to shareholders was not a topic currently at Nestle.</p>
<p>&quot;For us at the moment, it is not a topic, because Swiss tax regulations with respect to capital buy-backs still have some sticking points. The simplest way to reduce capital would be a nominal share redemption, but this way is also closed to us because our shares already are at the legal (nominal) minium nominal value of 10 francs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Corti also reiterated in the interview, following comments made at the end March, when the company presented 1996 results, that it planned no major divestitures.</p>
<p>((-- Zurich Editorial, +41 1 631 7340))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
