<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505551" id="root" date="1997-04-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Anti-EU crusaders rally in London.</title>
<headline>Anti-EU crusaders rally in London.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Marshall</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of anti-Brussels crusaders backing billionaire Sir James Goldsmith's Referendum Party rallied on Sunday to demand Britain withdraw from the European Union.</p>
<p>The party said 7,000 to 10,000 supporters had gathered at Alexandra Palace in north London to hear a succession of speakers denounce the EU ahead of Britain's May 1 election.</p>
<p>Goldsmith, a brilliant businessman whose pet political projects have ranged from trade to the environment, said he had no ambitions of high office for himself but simply wanted the people to have their say.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue is whether Britain remains an independent and free nation or whether it becomes a province of a bureaucratic, federal superstate,&quot; he said in prepared remarks.</p>
<p>&quot;The politicians have no right to give away without our consent the freedoms that have been fought for for generations.&quot;</p>
<p>As speaker after speaker denounced the bureaucrats in Brussels, crowds of mainly elderly supporters waved red, white and blue British flags and white Referendum Party banners.</p>
<p>The party says its sole purpose is to secure a referendum on whether Britain will stay in the EU, not to campaign for its exit. But there was no doubting how its supporters would vote in such a plebiscite.</p>
<p>&quot;The European commissioners want you to expunge from your mind any thoughts of nationhood, of independence, of sovereignty of the will of the people,&quot; party candidate Brian Slater said to cries of &quot;Never&quot; and &quot;Shame&quot; from the crowd.</p>
<p>Both the ruling Conservatives and opposition Labour Party say they will hold a referendum on joining a single currency, but Goldsmith wants a poll on membership of the EU itself.</p>
<p>&quot;The Referendum Party seeks no power for itself. The only power it seeks is for you to be able to decide. Once a referendum has been held, our party will dissolve,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Goldsmith poured scorn on Conservative Prime Minister John Major, saying he had handed over Britain's powers to Brussels.</p>
<p>&quot;This government has betrayed the nation and it has betrayed the democratic process. It will be severely punished on May 1.&quot;</p>
<p>Major is widely expected to be defeated by Labour. Goldsmith's party is just one of a cluster of new one-issue groupings to emerge at this election.</p>
<p>Analysts say the party has little chance of winning even a single seat, but may still affect the election by pinching votes from the Conservatives in marginal seats and helping send them into opposition for the first time in 18 years.</p>
<p>The Conservatives have been dogged by divisions over Europe, with many of the party's supporters sharing much of Goldsmith's hostility towards the EU. One disaffected Conservative politician, Sir George Gardiner, defected to the Referendum Party last month, giving it its first seat in parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;In this century a million Britons have given their lives so that our islands should remain free from German domination. Did they die for nothing, I ask?&quot; Gardiner told the crowd. &quot;They fought and died to preserve the birthright of every Briton, and you will never find me selling that birthright...&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
