<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505572" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: ATHLETICS-COE READY FOR HIS 800 METRES RECORD TO FALL.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-COE READY FOR HIS 800 METRES RECORD TO FALL.</headline>
<byline>Alan Wheatley</byline>
<dateline>CAMBORNE, England 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The longest-surviving world record in athletics, Sebastian Coe's mark for the 800 metres set in 1981, will probably fall soon. Who says so? Coe himself.</p>
<p>Coe, who is seeking re-election as a Conservative member of parliament for the Cornwall constituency of Falmouth and Camborne, said on Monday he expected the record to go to Wilson Kipketer, the Kenya-born Dane.</p>
<p>&quot;He's very talented. He's been running some very, very big times indoors and he'll be able to do that outdoors soon,&quot; said Coe during a campaign stop by Prime Minister John Major.</p>
<p>Kipketer claimed the indoor world record last month in a time of one minute 42.67 seconds, more than two seconds quicker than Coe ever managed indoors. His target now is Coe's 800 metres outdoor record of one minute 41.73 seconds set in Florence.</p>
<p>Asked whether Kipketer could take his crown this summer, Coe said: &quot;He stands a good chance. He's the first one that's looked like an 800-metre runner for a number of years.&quot;</p>
<p>Coe, who won gold over 1,500 metres at the Moscow and Los Angeles Olympics, used to hold the world record over 1,500 metres and one mile and his indoor time over 1,000 metres has still not been bettered.</p>
<p>Coe said he thought the main reason why his records had stood so long was, paradoxically, the increasing professionalism of athletics which was putting too many demands on top runners.</p>
<p>&quot;They're spending a bit too much time with their agents and not enough time on the track, if you want the honest answer,&quot; said Coe, who still likes to train hard for an hour each day.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't believe you can chase the dollar and focus on championships.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a balance and if you're good enough to get paid for racing that's great. You should use it as a stepping stone. But some of these guys are running 40, 50, 60 races a year and by the time they get to the championships, they're absolutely knackered,&quot; Coe said.</p>
<p>He said that, in contrast, when he was at his peak in the early 1980s he would spend three-quarters of the year training and then run at most eight races over the two months prior to a championship.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they're asking too much of themselves. You're not going to run great times unless you put the training in,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Coe said he was not despondent about the state of British athletics, despite a meagre medal haul at last year's Atlanta Olympics. &quot;I don't suddenly think the talent has dried up. I'm convinced the talent's out there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he said more money and effort had to be put into helping athletics clubs to spot and nurture young talent.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got to make some adjustments because great athletes don't just fall off trees. They're not the result of a happy accident, they're a result of perhaps 20 years' coaching,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAMBORNE, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
