<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505526" id="root" date="1997-04-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Afghan Taleban seeks world help to revive sports.</title>
<headline>Afghan Taleban seeks world help to revive sports.</headline>
<byline>Sayed Salahuddin</byline>
<dateline>KABUL 1997-04-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sports officials of Afghanistan's Taleban Islamic movement appealed for international help on Sunday to revive sporting events in the war-shattered country.</p>
<p>&quot;We call on the...international community to help us financially in the sports field for the promotion of sports and its revival,&quot; the man in charge of the Afghan Olympic Committee's foreign relations, Mohammad Ashraf Sadiq, said.</p>
<p>He made the appeal in a speech to a sports parade, the second since the Taleban captured Kabul last September, in an apparent move to show to the outside world that the purist Islamic movement is not against sports.</p>
<p>Around 1,500 athletes had gathered in Kabul's only stadium, which was once a front line between rival factions which fought for the control of the capital.</p>
<p>With broken windows and scars of shell scars and bullet holes, the stadium is in a desperate state.</p>
<p>&quot;Sports is the only recreation for Afghans and if we get support and financial help, we can build sports centres and buy facilities,&quot; Sadiq said.</p>
<p>He said Kabul had received invitations from several countries for participation in various sports contests, but could not send athletes abroad because of financial constraints.</p>
<p>&quot;We have received invitations from Japan, Russia and Poland for world wrestling and marathon races, but...for lack of finance we cannot take part in these contests,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Spectators and participants at Sunday's parade were all men representing the fields of wrestling, boxing, martial arts, hockey and basketball.</p>
<p>&quot;Those youths who do physical excercise on the basis of heavenly law and Sharia (Islamic law) for their health and soundness are the pride of our country,&quot; a banner held by a team of Taleban members wearing black turbans proclaimed.</p>
<p>The prolonged civil war has destroyed most sports facilities and hundreds of athletes have fled abroad.</p>
<p>In 20 years, Afghanistan sent its first competitor, a boxer, to last year's Olympics in Atlanta. He enventually sought asylum in the United States.</p>
<p>The head of the Afghan national sports Olympic committee, Abdul Shakoor Motmain, called on all Afghan athletes abroad to return home.</p>
<p>&quot;I invite all of our sportsmen who live overseas to come back for establishing national teams and that we will provide all necessary facilities for them with security and assurances of freedom and security,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Motmain also said Taleban had received offers from a couple of countries to train a football side.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
