<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505741" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Virgin to fly private aircraft services - paper.</title>
<headline>Virgin to fly private aircraft services - paper.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>British entrepreneur Richard Branson is expected to enter the private jet business with the launch on Tuesday of Virgin Executive Aviation, the Independent reported.</p>
<p>The newspaper said the new firm was taking over two executive jets based at London Heathrow and a fleet of eight helicopters based at Wycombe Air Park, west of London, to offer onward flights to business class traffic on Branson's Virgin Atlantic long-haul airline.</p>
<p>&quot;The intention is to offer an executive jet service to Virgin Atlantic customers flying Upper Class into Heathrow and Gatwick and then needing to get elsewhere fast,&quot; the Independent said.</p>
<p>The two jets could fly eight to 10 passengers as far as Moscow or Marrakesh, while the helicopters will ferry passengers between London's airports and the Battersea heliport in central London, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>The new firm was a joint venture with the McCarthy Corporation, an investment company run by Rory McCarthy, a pilot and business partner of Branson's who was also a co-adventurer in his abortive attempt earlier this year to fly round the world in a balloon.</p>
<p>The Independent said the initial investment in Virgin Executive Aviation would be only 10 million stg ($16.3 million) since the aircraft were being provided by McCarthy.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717 ($ = 0.614 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
