<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505751" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: North Sea crudes quiet, levels steady to firmer.</title>
<headline>North Sea crudes quiet, levels steady to firmer.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea crude oil markets saw a quiet start to the week as traders awaited the remaining May loading programmes. Some saw continuing downward pressure on prompt cargoes but others felt current prices represented a good buying opportunity.</p>
<p>'It's time to stock up all the tanks if you haven't done it already,' one refiner said.</p>
<p>Differentials did seem to be improving even on grades such as Statfjord which, at the start of the day, had four unsold cargoes in the April 20-25 period.</p>
<p>An April 23-25 Statfjord was bought by a refiner on Monday at Dated Brent -3 cents, while over two million barrels of end month Forties changed hands at dated Brent +6 cents.</p>
<p>Sellers pointed out that 600Kb cargoes carried a premium as they gave buyers a freight advantage.</p>
<p>An April 23-25 minimum sized cargo of Brent crude oil was bought by a refiner at May Brent -55 cents.</p>
<p>An end month Troll was heard to have been sold but price details were not immediately available.</p>
<p>Intermonth Brent paper spreads held steady despite gains on outright levels following the NYMEX gasoline lead.</p>
<p>Brent May/June talked around -23/-21 cents after an early trade at -20 cents. June/July traded twice at -11 cents and July/Aug moved twice at -9 cents and once at -10 cents.</p>
<p>After loosing ground early on, CFD's held at lower levels in thin trade. This week (April 14-18) moved at June Brent -67 cents, while April 21-25 moved at June -58 cents.</p>
<p>The week 28-02 week sold at June -53 cents.</p>
<p>The May Brent programme was expected to be released early on Tuesday and volume was expected to be up on the month.</p>
<p>--Siobhan Hayden London Newsroom +44 171 542 8978</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
