<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505819" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks close softer despite Wall St rebound.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks close softer despite Wall St rebound.</headline>
<byline>Lydia Zajc</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toronto's key stock index ended softer in light trading on Monday, depressed by weak gold shares and fears of a Canadian interest rate hike.</p>
<p>The Toronto Stock Exchange's 300 Composite Index eased 4.31 points to close at 5679.33, down more than 10 percent since its life-time high of 6348.02 on March 11.</p>
<p>Turnover was thin with 63.6 million shares changing hands worth C$965.6 million ($689.7 million).</p>
<p>The TSE was restrained on Monday by a weak Canadian dollar which prompted concerns that the Bank of Canada may have to raise Canadian rates to prop up the currency, said Dunnery Best, Midland Walwyn's director of private client investing.</p>
<p>Canada's dollar closed at C$1.3994 (US$0.7145) on Monday after the central bank intervened to support the sagging unit.</p>
<p>In New York, the Dow Jones Industrial Average recouped some of Friday's 148-point loss, rising 60.21 points to close at 6451.90 on Monday.</p>
<p>Fears of rising U.S. interest rates, which dragged North American markets lower last week, appear to have subsided, Best said.</p>
<p>&quot;Has it run its course? I would say largely,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Other stock analysts suggested the threat of higher U.S. rates is not over and they predicted the correction would resume.</p>
<p>Of Toronto's 14 sub-indices, nine weak groups were led by gold, consumer products and real estate. Gainers included media, oils and base metals.</p>
<p>Declining stocks outnumbered advances 581 to 351 with 290 unchanged.</p>
<p>Hot stocks included Ballard Power Systems Inc. which jumped 3.25 to 39.50 after German industrial group Daimler-Benz AG said it bought a 25 percent stake in Ballard.</p>
<p>The two companies plan to jointly develop fuel cells for electric vehicles.</p>
<p>Among gold stocks, Bre-X Minerals Ltd. slipped 0.05 to 2.45 on 5.6 million shares, the heaviest trader on the TSE.</p>
<p>Golden Rule Resources Ltd. fell 0.65 to 5.15 in heavy dealings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
