<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50589" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Sept 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Sept 12.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gillette Co is near an agreement to acquire Duracell International Inc in a stock deal worth over $7 billion, the Wall Street Journal reported Thursday.</p>
<p>Other top stories included:</p>
<p>* The Federal Trade Commission plans to announce Thursday it approved a settlement allowing Time Warner Inc and Turner Broadcasting System Inc to complete their merger.</p>
<p>* Rockwell International Corp and U.S. Robotics Corp are each developing equipment that speeds computer communication over telephone lines.</p>
<p>* The U.S. Food and Drug Administration said some men using a prostate drug made by Merck &amp; Co developed a condition associated with breast cancer.</p>
<p>*  Prudential Insurance Co of America plans to sell nearly all of its remaining real-estate holdings, valued at $5.6 billion, over three years.</p>
<p>* Xerox Corp and Kohlberg Kravis Roberts &amp; Co called off the planned $2.3 billion sale of Xerox's Talegen insurance unit to KKR.</p>
<p>* Motorola said weak chip sales and competition in cellular phone sales will hurt third-quarter earnings.</p>
<p>* The Federal Reserve said labor markets tightened and wages rose modestly, but inflation was still in check.</p>
<p>* Federal regulators said bad credit-card debt reached its highest level since 1992, causing banks to write off 36-percent more loans in the latest quarter.</p>
<p>* General Motors Corp offered to guarantee lifetime employment to current United Auto Workers union members in exchange for permission to cut workforces after those members retire.</p>
<p>* Crude oil prices hit five-year highs amid escalating tensions between the United States and Iraq.</p>
<p>* Mutual funds received about $19 billion in stock mutual funds in August, a sharp rebound from July's $5.8 billion.</p>
<p>* MCI Communications Corp projected good growth in its data and network-consulting business.</p>
<p>* Crop prices fell after the government raised it monthly wheat and corn harvest estimates.</p>
<p>* H.J. Heinz Co got a saucy bounce in its stock this week when an announcement that it planned to shed some non-core assets produced headlines heralding a major restructuring. - Heard on the Street</p>
<p>* Bond prices ended little changed after initially dropping on concerns about impending economic data and a jump in oil prices. - Credit Markets</p>
<p>--New York Newsdesk  (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
