<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50594" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. prepares to retaliate against Iraq.</title>
<headline>U.S. prepares to retaliate against Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kearns</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. warplanes moved into position on Thursday for almost certain retaliatory bombing raids against Iraq as Pentagon planners picked targets to hurt Iraqi President Saddam Hussein.</p>
<p>U.S. Air Force and Navy forces prepared to strike back at the Iraqi military for firing a missile early Wednesday at two U.S. fighters on patrol over Iraq.</p>
<p>After a day of bellicose warnings from Washington, President Clinton told reporters travelling with him on a campaign stop in Arizona late Wednesday that the time for talking had ended.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want to get into a word war here,&quot; Clinton replied when asked about his plans for Iraq. &quot;We want to manage the situation in an appropriate and disciplined way.&quot;</p>
<p>He spoke as Pentagon officals sent radar-eluding F-117A &quot;stealth&quot; fighters and massive B-52 bombers into position to pummel Iraqi targets with missiles and bombs.</p>
<p>In the bowels of the sprawling Pentagon, planners pored over possible targets, ranging from mobile truck-carried radar and missile batteries to command centres in and around Baghdad.</p>
<p>&quot;The determination of the United States in dealing with the problem of Iraq should not be underestimated,&quot; Clinton said at a campaign stop in Sun City, Arizona.</p>
<p>He said U.S. pilots policing &quot;no fly&quot; zones over northern and southern Iraq would be protected.</p>
<p>But senior officials said consultations with U.S. allies were in high-gear even as the military was ready to pounce.</p>
<p>They said there was great fear that an unstable Iraq would create a power vaccum in the region that Iran would rush to fill. Washington also does not want to risk inflaming public opinion in the Arab world at a time when the Middle East peace negotiations are in a delicate stage.</p>
<p>A White House official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said: &quot;It's critical that we communicate with the leaders of those countries as we did last time to best ensure that we get their input before we take whatever action we take.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Because of our strategic interests in the region, we want to ensure that the leaders in those countries that we have close relationships with are aware of our intentions and given the courtesy of a full read on what we will do,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>This does not mean, however, that any opposition to the plans will mean they would be changed. &quot;These considerations will not ultimately dictate completely whatever action we take. They will not shape exclusively what decision we make,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>Eight F-117A's flew to Kuwait and four B-52s moved from from Guam in the Pacific Ocean to a British airbase on the Indian Ocean island of Diego Garcia to be in closer striking range to Iraq, U.S. officials said. The United States sought and received permission from Kuwait, which was liberated from occupying Iraqi troops by a U.S.-led coalition in 1991.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, an Iraqi MiG-25 and a military helicopter defied U.S. warnings and briefly flew into a no-fly zone in southern Iraq but no shots were fired.</p>
<p>An Iraqi SAM-6 surface-to-air missile missed U.S. F-16 fighters over northern Iraq.</p>
<p>Other officials said U.S. B-52 bombers like those used in the cruise missile raids on southern Iraq last week had been moved from Guam to the Diego Garcia base after Britain granted permission for their basing there for a month.</p>
<p>Defence officials said the stealth fighters could be used at night to drop laser-guided bombs on Iraqi command and control centres if Clinton ordered new strikes.</p>
<p>U.S. warships and B-52s launched 44 Tomahawk and airborne cruise missiles in two salvoes against air defence targets in southern Iraq fighter last week to punish Saddam for using his forces to attack Kurds in northern Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
