<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505998" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Central Europe stocks fall on Wall Street losses.</title>
<headline>Central Europe stocks fall on Wall Street losses.</headline>
<byline>Sandor Peto</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Central and east European stock markets dropped on Monday following the Dow's sharp fall on Friday and larger downward corrections may come later this week if the Dow continues to go down, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;If Wall Street continues as it began on Friday, (price falls) are inevitable later this week,&quot; said London-based ICE securities analyst Rudi Voros.</p>
<p>&quot;There are interest rate hike expectations in the U.S. and the effect of them will be felt in central and eastern European markets sooner or later,&quot; he said. &quot;The extent of a rate hike will be also decisive, but (stock) markets are in a (downward) correction phase anyway.&quot;</p>
<p>European markets traded lower on Monday, hit by the 2.27 percent fall in the Dow industrial index on Friday.</p>
<p>Poland's WIG index fell 417.2 points, or 2.6 percent to 15,846.6 points on Monday, a drop which analysts attributed to Friday's Wall Street plunge.</p>
<p>&quot;The market looks bad, we had falls in higher turnover despite strong Friday buying...and investors increasingly watch foreign bourses before making any decisions,&quot; said Tomasz Berent, an analyst at IB Austria brokerage.</p>
<p>Hungary's BUX index fell 56.67 points or 1.06 percent,  to close at 5,442.59 points.</p>
<p>Dealers said the fall was mainly due to the Dow's weakness.</p>
<p>&quot;We felt the impact of the U.S. market,&quot; said Balazs Bathory of Creditanstalt Securities.</p>
<p>The Czech bourse's RPIX index dropped 11.8 points or 1.02 percent, to 1,141.1 points.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Dow's falls had a relatively light effect on central and Eastern European share price on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;They are going down but they are not going down extraordinarily,&quot; said Frances Cloud, Nomura Equity Research analyst in London. &quot;The market won't go down seriously until investors actually sell stocks and at the moment investors are not selling.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said the Hungarian and the Polish stock markets were the most exposed to developments in the U.S. economy in the region.</p>
<p>Voros said foreigners are the main investors on the Hungarian market, and there were also substantial foreign investments in Poland.</p>
<p>If the Dow continues to fall, Hungary's BUX index is likely to follow it in the next few weeks, but expected good corporate results, to be released in the first half of May, are likely to reverse a potential falling trend, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if there is a fall, I expect it to be followed by stabilisation and the market can move upward again following first quarter results,&quot; he said. &quot;If the results prove to be positive, the Hungarian market can become independent on international trends.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that the outlook of the Polish and the Hungarian bourses was more positive for the long term than that of the Czech market, as corporate restructuring was more advanced in Poland and in Hungary.</p>
<p>&quot;We see many structural problems on the Czech market,&quot; he said. &quot;Czech 1996 results were negative... the Czech crown is very strong and the situation of exporter companies is difficult,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>However, price movements on the Czech bourse were less dependent on Wall Street than in the other two countries, he said as &quot;it looks like (foreign investors) are not committing significant funds to the Czech market.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
