<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="505985" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hectic Budapest sees limit rises in most grains.</title>
<headline>Hectic Budapest sees limit rises in most grains.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Price rises in Chicago triggered limit rises in all grains except maize on the Budapest Commodity Exchange (BCE) on Monday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Milling wheat prices rose 20 cents per bushel overnight, a limit-up rise was imminent, it was just a question of who would start it in the local market,&quot; said Istvan Markus of Swap.</p>
<p>Milling wheat prices rose the daily 400 forint-limit, with old crop ending at 25,730 forints per tonne for May while new (1997) crop prices ended between 22,200 forints for July and 25,400 for March.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who could not buy milling wheat went for feed wheat,&quot; Markus added.</p>
<p>New crop feed wheat prices also rose by the limit to between 21,200 forints for July and 22,600 for December. Untraded May feed wheat remained flat at 22,950 forints.</p>
<p>&quot;The milling wheat price surge was mirrored by feed barley prices as well, a traditional phenomenon of the Budapest market,&quot; Markus said.</p>
<p>New crop feed barley prices went limit-up at between 19,000 forints for July and 20,800 forints for December.</p>
<p>Tradeless sunflowerseed futures also rose the limit in all maturities, closing at 34,600 forints for May, 43,550 forints for September and 44,100 for April 1998.</p>
<p>Markus said that whatever the international trends, milling wheat prices would shortly hit a psychological ceiling and a strong downward correction would follow, probably this week.</p>
<p>&quot;One or two further limit-up rises are possible,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Only maize bucked the trend on Monday with the most active May maturity easing 50 forints to 18,450 on position-closing. Other months were mostly flat and untraded except for July with 70 contracts.</p>
<p>Total grains turnover surged to 478.2 million forints or 1,095 contracts from Friday's 234.6 million forints.</p>
<p>Milling wheat accounted for the bulk of the turnover with 770 contracts.</p>
<p>Lot size= 20,000 kgs</p>
<p>($1=180.51 Hungarian forints)</p>
<p>-- Denes Albert, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
