<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="506090" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Sandinista strike sputters at start in Nicaragua.</title>
<headline>Sandinista strike sputters at start in Nicaragua.</headline>
<byline>David Koop</byline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of pro-Sandinista protesters blocked major roads across Nicaragua on Monday in a national strike against the right-wing government, but the country appeared to be largely unscathed by the protest.</p>
<p>While traffic was slowed across Nicaragua, and strikes by some transport unions made finding a bus difficult, police reported no serious violent incidents, and stores and offices opened for business as usual.</p>
<p>&quot;At this moment the situation is totally under control,&quot; Nicaragua's Police Chief Franco Montealegre said.</p>
<p>Strike leaders said the protest would continue until the government of President Arnoldo Aleman agreed to a 15-point list of demands, including actions to curb unemployment and resolve Nicaragua's property dispute. But government officials said turnout for the strike was low.</p>
<p>&quot;I left my house this morning peacefully and heard nothing alarming. I've heard of no violence and I feel little tension in the air,&quot; National Assembly President Ivan Escobar Fornos, a member of Aleman's Liberal Alliance coalition, said.</p>
<p>In the past some major Sandinista-led street protests have led to bloody shootouts between protesters and police. The Sandinista Front, which came to power in the 1979 revolution, is now the country's main opposition party.</p>
<p>Fears of a violent protest were raised on Monday when local newspaper La Tribuna published an interview with former President Daniel Ortega in which he warned the Sandinistas would be obliged to &quot;take up arms&quot; if the government did not cede to the strikers' demands of easing an austerity plan.</p>
<p>&quot;If we let the government continue applying its dictatorial project there will be no alternative but to take up arms once again to end the dictatorship,&quot; Ortega, a former guerrilla commander who was president from 1984 to 1990, said.</p>
<p>Local radio reports said protesters had formed &quot;human barricades&quot; on some roads outside Managua, and one police official suffered a cut lip when he was struck by a rock.</p>
<p>Vice Minister of Transportation Pablo Hurtado Vijil said the majority of bus routes were functioning across Nicaragua and police were clearing the roadblocks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
