<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50600" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Orange County jurors may be deadlocked.</title>
<headline>U.S. Orange County jurors may be deadlocked.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA ANA, California 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jurors in the trial of former Orange County, California, Budget Director Ronald Rubino told the judge on Wednesday that they believed they were deadlocked.</p>
<p>Rubino, 44, was indicated by a county grand jury in December 1995 for allegedly aiding former county Treasurer Robert Citron in diverting funds from other government agencies for the county's benefit.</p>
<p>Rubino, who has denied any wrongdoing, faces up to nine years in prison if convicted on the felony counts. Rubino's criminal trial is the first arising from the Orange County bankruptcy, the largest municipal failure in U.S. history.</p>
<p>The jury has been deliberating since September 4.</p>
<p>After a flurry of notes on Wednesday afternoon, the panelists wrote: &quot;We are hung.&quot;</p>
<p>Judge J. Stephen Czuleger told the jurors to return on Thursday morning to try to continue deliberations.</p>
<p>Orange County filed for protection under Chapter 9 of the federal Bankruptcy Code on December 6, 1994, after sustaining investment losses of more than $1.6 billion.</p>
<p>The county emerged from bankruptcy in June of this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA ANA, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
