<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="506081" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania - April 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania - April 14.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Romania signed the accord to join the Central European Free Trade Association. The accord will become effective on July 1.</p>
<p>- The government plans to put the State Ownership Fund under its control.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- The local leu currency will apreciate against the dollar soon, Finance Minister Mircea Ciumara said.</p>
<p>- The government will start talks on amendments to the law on foreign investment.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Trade union leaders from the Petromidia SA refinery, which the government plans to close down as part of a restructuring project, will start talks with the government in a bid to prevent Petromidia's closure.  </p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- Unindentified persons destroyed some 80 tombs in an Orthodox cemetery in the Transylvanian city of Cluj.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- President Emil Constantinescu will meet leaders of the leftist opposition to discuss ways to secure their support in parliament for the approval of vital laws for the reforms.</p>
<p>- Prosecutors started investigations in the case of a group of magistrates in the Vilcea county allegedly involved in illegal adoptions.</p>
<p>-- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
