<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="506083" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - April 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - April 14.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on Monday. Prepared for Reuters by the Co-operation Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- The leader of the Fatherland &amp; Freedom party, Maris Griblats, announced that a compromise on choosing two of the privatisation agency's directors through an open competition is nothing but avoiding transparency in the privatisation process and making it only partly democratic.</p>
<p>- There was a military review in Liepaja on April 12, devoted to the fifth anniversary of Latvian navy forces. The navy has 17 warships, of which two are mine sweepers.</p>
<p>- President Guntis Ulmanis arrived in France on a two-day official visit, whose goal is to draw attention to security issues in the Baltic region.</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Valdis Birkavs anounced on his return from a central Asian tour that his visit was a success. He said that Latvia, Russia and Uzbekistan may create a joint work group to expanding the transit corridor and make it safer. Around 1/3 of Uzbekistan's cotton exports goes through Latvian harbours.</p>
<p>BIZNES &amp; BALTIJA</p>
<p>- Beginning today, shares of Latvia's Savings Bank will be available in public auction.</p>
<p>SM</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Valdis Birkavs announced at a press-conference that Latvia is ready to sign a border treaty with Russia at any time.</p>
<p>DIENAS BIZNESS</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Roberts Zile said in an interview that he believes tax rates in Latvia are at a normal level except for social tax. The minister regards free economic zones as one of instruments to increase the country's GDP.</p>
<p>- The state revenue service plans to invest 22.7 million lats over the five coming years to increase the state income.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7215240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
