<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50601" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rubin says IMF close to gold sales pact.</title>
<headline>Rubin says IMF close to gold sales pact.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Rich Miller, Economics Correspondent</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund is very close to an agreement to sell off some of its gold to help finance aid to the world's poorest nations, Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We've made a lot of progress,&quot; Rubin told reporters following a speech to government workers here. &quot;I think we're getting very close. (But) it's not quite done yet.&quot;</p>
<p>The IMF board is slated to meet on Friday to discuss ways to beef up its Enhanced Structural Adjustment (loan) Facility for poor nations and back a multilateral initiative to provide debt relief for some of the worst off countries as well.</p>
<p>IMF management, backed by the United States, Britain and most other member nations, has proposed selling around five million of the Fund's 104 million ounces of gold to help finance the stepped-up assistance to poor countries.</p>
<p>But a few nations -- Germany, Italy and Switzerland -- have opposed the proposal, arguing in part that the IMF should not sell gold except in cases of extreme financial emergency.</p>
<p>International monetary sources, who declined to be identified, said they did not expect a formal vote on the proposal. IMF Managing Director Michel Camdessus wants to avoid a bitter fight at the board meeting and instead may seek a general consensus for the sale of gold if needed.</p>
<p>But it is not clear how specific a commitment he will be able to secure on that issue, and when. Supporters of the plan seem increasingly confident of an agreement, but acknowledge that the final deal has not yet been sealed.</p>
<p>Monetary sources did not rule out the possibility that the board may not be able to hammer out an agreement on Friday, and may have to meet again next week.</p>
<p>There is even a chance that the issue may not be definitively settled until the IMF's policy-making Interim Committee of finance ministers meets on Sept. 29.</p>
<p>&quot;The board meeting may not be conclusive,&quot; one source said. &quot;You may get an infuriatingly vague agreement, but I'm not even sure of that.&quot;</p>
<p>The IMF board is expected to reiterate its support for the multilateral debt initiative and for beefing up the Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility (ESAF).</p>
<p>But the question is where the money for that will come from. Bilateral contributions are one possibility and Germany has already said it is willing to put up some of its money.</p>
<p>The IMF could also tap some of the reserves it has set aside to back up existing ESAF loans, because not all of that money may be needed for that purpose.</p>
<p>But Camdessus would like a commitment from member nations that the IMF could also sell some of its gold if necessary to fill any remaining financing gap.</p>
<p>&quot;It may well just be a matter of wording, with certain understandings just to save everyone's face,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>That may mean a clear commitment by IMF member nations to find the necessary funding for strengthening ESAF, with an understanding that gold sales would be used if other financing alternatives did not prove adequate.</p>
<p>International monetary sources said IMF managment has assured member nations that any gold sales would be carried out in such a way as to minimise their impact on the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The technique of sale has not been considered at all,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>In the past, the IMF has sold gold through public auction.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
