<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="506156" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile economy grows 4.5 percent in Q1 - Aninat.</title>
<headline>Chile economy grows 4.5 percent in Q1 - Aninat.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile's economic growth slowed sharply to around 4.5 percent in the first quarter from 7.7 percent in the previous three months, said Finance Minister Eduardo Aninat on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate gross domestic product growth to be around 4.5 percent in real terms in the first quarter with spending growth at practically zero percent,&quot; Aninat told reporters.</p>
<p>Chile's economy expanded a strong nine percent in the first quarter of 1996.  </p>
<p>Aninat made his estimate when commenting on the Central Bank's decision to cut interbank interest rates by 0.25 percentage point Friday.</p>
<p>The cut, the second in two months, followed a welter of figures showing the bank's tight policy had brought Chile's robust economic growth under control.</p>
<p>The bank took the decision after being assured that the economy will meet the 5.5 percent government inflation target this year, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We do not see any type of special pressure of cost or demand which will alter the goal to 5.5 percent inflation with growth close to a target we are calculating today of 5.8 percent,&quot; said Aninat. ((-- Rodrigo Martinez, Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595 x212))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
