<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="506140" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Hungary offers Mexico trade 'bridge' to Europe.</title>
<headline>Hungary offers Mexico trade 'bridge' to Europe.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian President Arpad Goncz, starting a two-day state visit on Monday, suggested that Mexico use his country as a bridge for trade with Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;We are offering Mexico the possibility of using us as a base and bridge for trade between Western and Eastern Europe,&quot; Goncz told his Mexican counterpart Ernesto Zedillo at a reception in a flag-festooned National Palace.</p>
<p>Speaking through an interpreter, Goncz said Hungary's strategic location made it an ideal trade stepping stone to all of Europe for countries such as Mexico looking to fortify links with the continent. The European Union and Mexico have started talks aimed at strengthening political ties and setting up a free trade agreement, but progress has been slow because of opposition from some EU members.</p>
<p>Goncz, making the first state visit by a Hungarian president since diplomatic ties were restored between the two nations 20 years ago, said Hungary had recognised the need to join the global economy.</p>
<p>&quot;We see it as a paramount need that we take part in this world formation...&quot; Goncz said. &quot;This is what has brought us here,&quot; he added. He is accompanied by 30 prominent Hungarian businessmen.</p>
<p>Goncz was scheduled to speak to the Mexican Senate and to inaugurate, along with Zedillo, the Mexico City International Festival on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
