<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="506442" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends up sharply on nearby supply woes.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends up sharply on nearby supply woes.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee prices ended sharply higher Monday, led by steep gains in the spot May contract, as near-term supply concerns were reignited by news Colombia had closed coffee registrations for May and June shipments, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very positive,&quot; said Stephen Smith, president of South Futures in Miami. &quot;They closed registrations all the way through June. No more coffee is going to be sold.&quot;</p>
<p>Spot May delivery ended up 6.90 cents at 196.00 cents a lb after trading from 197.00 to 186.20. Second-month July settled 4.80 cents higher at 177.00 cents, while the back months closed up 0.95 to 4.00.</p>
<p>Private exporters from Colombia, the world's second largest producer, said Monday the country's National Coffee Growers' Federation notified them in a statement it was closing registration for May/June coffee shipments, effective immediately.</p>
<p>Federation officials could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>&quot;It turns off the faucet, but not permanently,&quot; said Refco analyst Ann Prendergast. &quot;It's percieved as bullish because the market's already worried about short supplies.&quot;</p>
<p>The May/July switch, a barometer of nearby availability, ballooned to a hefty 19.00 cents, up from 16.90 cents at the close on Friday.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, traders await the Green Coffee Association of New York's monthly stock data due after the close of business on April 15 to better gauge the U.S. supply situation.</p>
<p>Coffee fell sharply last week on talk of a 500,000 to 1.0-million bag rise in the March inventory, but traders now expect an increase of 250,000 to 350,000 bags from February's 1.54 million bags.</p>
<p>Refco's Prendergast noted that recent forecasts of a stock build below 500,000 bags may have also contributed to today's upswing.</p>
<p>&quot;The GCA is now expected to be well below 500,000 bags,&quot; she said. &quot;Just two weeks ago people were talking about a 500,000 to one-million bag increase.&quot;</p>
<p>Some analysts also worried that many Latin American countries, who have shipped heavily in the last two months to take advantage of the higher futures prices, may have little coffee left to sell.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch said in its bi-weekly report that any build in March GCA stockpiles would only temporarily relieve supply tightness as &quot;heavy shipments being made in the last quarter are likely to abate in the next month and beyond as origins deplete reserves of fresh coffee and stocks.&quot;</p>
<p>After Monday's close, CSCE reported certified coffee stocks were off 250 60-kg bags, to 80,828 bags as of April 11. There were no bags pending grading, the exchange said.</p>
<p>Volume reached an estimated 8,328 lots.</p>
<p>((--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodity Desk +1 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
