<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="506454" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE world sugar ends down, May-July active.</title>
<headline>CSCE world sugar ends down, May-July active.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE world sugar ended lower on Monday in a session dominated by heavy selling of the May-July switch, dealers said.</p>
<p>The spot May contract bore the brunt of the day's losses, as speculators, eager to unwind positions ahead of the contract's expiry in two weeks, rolled longs into the back months.</p>
<p>Traders said views the market was substantially overbought after rallying recently to seven-month highs contributed to today's weakness.</p>
<p>Both speculators and the commercial sector sold the market on the opening, but short-covering by the trade helped recoup some of the early losses. From then on, traders focused on the switch, shaving six points off the spot premium by the close.</p>
<p>&quot;May-July selling put pressure on the market all day,&quot; one broker said. &quot;There just wasn't much buying around...and speculators have an enormous long position.&quot;</p>
<p>Spot May fell 0.09 cent a lb on the day, to 11.24, having traded from 11.12 to 11.27. July fell 0.03 cent, to 11.13, while the remaining months eased between 0.01 and 0.06 cent.</p>
<p>Without an injection of positive fundamentals, traders said the pressure on May could continue for the next several sessions.</p>
<p>&quot;I still see the funds and the commission houses have some rolling out to do, so it's not finished yet,&quot; said another trader. May's open interest remained fairly heavy, reaching 62,083 lots as of last Friday's close.</p>
<p>Technically, light support for the May contract was seen at 11.08-11.10, a notch under today's session floor. A breach of that level could provoke a test of the 10.80-10.90 range, traders said. To the upside, a significant hurdle awaited the market at last week's high of 11.38.</p>
<p>The day's volume was estimated at 28,701 lots, compared with 29,221 lots on Friday.</p>
<p>((-- W Pollack, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
