<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="506429" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Novellus sees Q2 revs up over Q1 - analysts.</title>
<headline>Novellus sees Q2 revs up over Q1 - analysts.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Novellus Systems Inc told analysts in a conference call Monday that it expects second quarter revenues to increase about 10 percent over the first quarter, analysts said.</p>
<p>The chip equipment maker posted first quarter earnings of $0.91 a share on net sales of $101.7 million, down from earnings of $1.55 a share and net sales of $115.3 million last year.</p>
<p>Novellus, which had been hard hit by a string of bad news Monday, fell 22 to 53-1/4.  </p>
<p>Novellus also reiterated to analysts that it will fight an unfavorable jury verdict on a patent infringement lawsuit filed by rival Applied Materials Inc, while also continuing to develop distinct, new products that do not infringe on Applied Material's patent. The jury found that Applied Material's fundamental process patent for despositing dielectric layers between metal layers of semiconductor chips was infringed by systems sold by Novellus.</p>
<p>The decision was the first of many that are expected in the next year involving a series of competing claims of patent infringement between the company and Applied Materials.  </p>
<p>Novellus warned that potential damages from the case could have a material adverse impact on the company.  The company declined to elaborate on the potential impact, analysts said.</p>
<p>Due to the jury verdict, Novellus said it not accepting new orders for domestic delivery of systems that use the TEOS patent process.  The company also said it will reconfigure future product shipments to comply with the verdict.</p>
<p>The jury verdict concerns only Novellus' domestic sales. No decision has been made regarding the foreign sales.</p>
<p>Analysts said the TEOS process affects only 10 percent of Novellus' business in the U.S. and about 20 percent worldwide.  </p>
<p>Although it is a declining portion of Novellus' business, some investors were concerned that the company may not be able to make up for the shortfall, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be difficult to replace this product. Customers are very risk-averse,&quot; said Milind Bedekar, an analyst with Prudential Securities.</p>
<p>While Novellus said it will soon offer alternative process chemistries that do not use TEOS process, analysts cautioned that customers would be experiment with new products.  </p>
<p>PaineWebber analyst Gunnar Miller said the jury verdict was a &quot;psychological blow&quot; to Novellus. Although the financial impact will likely be limited, the &quot;negative psychological impact could be more pronounced,&quot; Miller said.</p>
<p>Elliott Rogers, an analyst with Deutshe Morgan Grenfell, called the jury verdict a &quot;travesty,&quot; saying Novellus could have probably settled the case for less than the potential damages award.</p>
<p>&quot;If one believes the case was open and shut, they probably should have settled. But once you go into court, the die is cast,&quot; Rogers said.</p>
<p>The news of the jury verdict was compounded by the company's announcement that its first quarter book-to-bill ratio fell short of one-to-one.</p>
<p>The book-to-bill ratio is a key indicator of sales trends. A ratio of one-to-one means that for every $100 of equipment shipped, $100 of new orders were booked.</p>
<p>Rogers said he expects Novellus' second quarter bookings to be stronger.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect their operating fortunes will likely improve in the second half,&quot; Rogers said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
