<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="506772" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cardiac defibrillators reduce deaths - U.S. study.</title>
<headline>Cardiac defibrillators reduce deaths - U.S. study.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. researchers on Monday said they had halted a study comparing two treatment options for a heart disorder because one of the treatments, a cardiac defibrillator, showed such clear life-saving benefits.</p>
<p>The National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute (NHLBI) found the cardiac defibrillator, which is implanted, reduced deaths among patients with an abnormal heart rhythm or arrhythmia. The study had been designed to compare the defibrillator to an anti-arrhythmic drug.</p>
<p>The device does not prevent irregular heartbeats but it responds to them and helps the heart return to its normal pace.</p>
<p>&quot;(It) is like having an emergency room implanted in your chest,&quot; said Dr. Douglas Zipes, head of the study's steering committee and a cardiologist at the Indiana University School of Medicine.</p>
<p>&quot;We've known for some time that these devices stop arrhythmias and restore normal heart rhythm. But it has not been known until now whether they improve overall survival,&quot; said Institute director Dr. Claude Lenfant.</p>
<p>The study involved patients with a history of ventricular fibrillation or serious ventricular tachycardia, both of which are life-threatening. Some patients were treated with the implanted devices, and some with one of two drugs.</p>
<p>More than 1,000 patients were enrolled and followed at 50 U.S. and Canadian clinical sites.</p>
<p>After a year, the patients in the defibrillator group had a 38 percent reduction in deaths, compared to the group getting drugs. In years two and three, the reduction was 25 percent. With such clear benefits, the team halted the study.</p>
<p>In the overall population, this would translate into saving 1,000 lives a year, Lenfant said. He urged patients now on drugs for these heartbeat problems to talk to their doctors about switching to the implant.</p>
<p>The defibrillator costs about twice as much as the drugs -- $66,600 for implanting the device versus $34,000 for monitoring a hospitalized patient on the drugs. But the costs may drop over time as the devices become more common and hospital stays decrease.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
