<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="506715" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Patriot to buy Wyndham, 11 hotels for $1.1 billion.</title>
<headline>Patriot to buy Wyndham, 11 hotels for $1.1 billion.</headline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Patriot American Hospitality Inc. , the nation's second-largest hotel real estate investment trust, said Monday it agreed to acquire Wyndham Hotel Corp. and 11 hotels for about $1.1 billion.</p>
<p>Under terms of the agreement, Patriot will acquire Wyndham for $611 million in stock and $152 million in the assumption or retirement of debt, and pay another $330 million in cash for 11 Wyndham-branded hotels.</p>
<p>Patriot, with 54 hotels, said it also will pay $14 million to partnerships affiliated with members of the Trammell Crow family if two of the hotels meet certain operational targets.</p>
<p>Patriot said it expects to complete the acquisition in the fourth quarter, and that it will add to its earnings upon completion and &quot;contribute significantly to per-share growth in 1998 and future years.&quot;</p>
<p>As a result of its previously announced merger with California Jockey Club and Bay Meadows Operating Co., Patriot will become one of only four companies to enjoy the benefits of a &quot;paired share&quot; ownership.</p>
<p>Under this structure, Patriot said, it will be able to own hotels and lease them to the paired operating company while retaining the benefits of Real Estate Investment Trust tax status.</p>
<p>&quot;The acquisition of Wyndham culminates Patriot's evolution from a hotel REIT into a nationally branded, fully integrated hotel company,&quot; said Paul Nussbaum, Patriot chairman and chief executive. &quot;In acquiring Wyndham, we also maximize the benefits arising from our acquisition of the paired share ownership structure and take another significant step toward becoming a world-class hotel company.&quot;</p>
<p>Patriot said it is committed to completing the Cal Jockey/Bay Meadows merger, and upon completion of that deal and the Wyndham transaction, it intends to rename its paired operating company &quot;Wyndham International.&quot;</p>
<p>The paired shares of Patriot American Hospitality and Wyndham International will trade on the New York Stock Exchange under the symbol PAH, it said.</p>
<p>Wyndham's stock fell $1.75 to $27.875 on the New York Stock Exchange, while Patriot lost 87.5 cents to $21.375, also on the NYSE.</p>
<p>Following completion of the deal, Nussbaum will continue to serve as chairman and CEO of Patriot, and Wyndham Chairman and CEO James Carreker will hold the same positions at Wyndham International.</p>
<p>In a teleconference with Wall Street analysts and reporters, Carreker said Wyndham's initial international expansion will be north and south, into Canada and Mexico. He called Mexico &quot;a natural expansion of our Caribbean presence,&quot; adding, &quot;Mexico's the next destination stop for us.&quot;</p>
<p>Nussbaum said Crowe family interests and Wyndham management holding a total of 59 percent of the company's stock have agreed to vote in favour of the merger.</p>
<p>Noting that the Crowe family now holds about 47 percent of Wyndham's stock, Carreker said this will be diluted to &quot;roughly 14 percent&quot; of the merged company.</p>
<p>Nussbaum added that some of the Crowe family holding will be in a special class of stock to comply with tax regulations relating to its status as an REIT.</p>
<p>Upon completion of the Wyndham deal, Patriot's hotel portfolio will include 88 owned or leased hotels in the United States, Canada and the Caribbean. In addition, it has signed contracts or letters of intent to acquire 19 hotels, with more than 4,600 rooms, for approximately $441 million. In addition, it will manage or franchise 81 hotels.</p>
<p>The company's hotels operate under numerous national and international hotel brands. They include Wyndham, Grand Heritage and Carefree Resort properties, and Marriott, Doubletree, Hilton, Hyatt, Holiday Inn, Sheraton, Radisson and otohers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
