<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="506867" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OPTIONS - Calm dollar keeps lid on volatilities.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - Calm dollar keeps lid on volatilities.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatilities for dollar-pair options were little changed from Friday as spot dollar hovered around 1.73 marks, options traders said.</p>
<p>Market participants on Monday morning continued to adopt strategies anticipating further gains in the dollar because of interest rate differentials, they said.</p>
<p>Several sources said one such transaction was executed this morning in dollar/mark. The buyer was said to have purchased $500 million in one-year 1.73 dollar calls before the spot dollar brushed against the level to post a new 37-month high at midday.  </p>
<p>The presence of willing sellers blunted the impact of the large trade on volatility, said a trader for a European bank.</p>
<p>Implied volatility for one-year dollar/mark was 9.4/9.6 percent, about 0.1 point lower than on Friday.</p>
<p>One-month volatility was unchanged at 9.1/9.3 percent. Earlier in the day, one-month was slightly lower before the dollar pushed above 1.73 marks.</p>
<p>The next important level for dollar/mark will be 1.75, options traders said.  </p>
<p>Support for the dollar should continue to stem from expectations for further short-term interest rate hikes in the U.S., making low-delta dollar calls attractive, said Soma Rao, first vice president and options sales manager for Smith Barney Inc.</p>
<p>Risk reversals, the put-call pricing differential, stayed skewed slightly in favor of mark puts. One-month 25-delta risk reversals stood at 0.1/0.4.</p>
<p>Near term, however, worries about the stability of the U.S. stock market after last week's steep fall may continue to drag on the dollar, Rao said.  </p>
<p>After soaring to a 56-month high against the yen last week, dollar/yen was lagging dollar/mark because of sales of mark/yen, said a second European bank trader.</p>
<p>The dollar this morning was maintaining a bid above 126.00 yen but was unable to muster momentum to retest last week's high above 127.00.</p>
<p>One-year dollar/yen volatility was virtually unchanged at 10.5/10.6 percent late morning. One-month dollar/yen was 9.4/9.6 percent, down 0.1 point.</p>
<p>Chicago Derivatives Desk ((312-408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
