<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50686" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: EU wheat subsidy hopes fade with tax bids - trade.</title>
<headline>EU wheat subsidy hopes fade with tax bids - trade.</headline>
<byline>Dominique Vidalon</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trade reports that some exporters are still willing to pay taxes to export European Union soft wheat are dashing hopes the European Commission may quickly restore export subsidies for its wheat, grain traders said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Tax bids are clearly offsetting demand for subsidies,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Officials close to the EU executive said last week the EU was unlikely to restore wheat subsidies as long as exporters are ready to pay an export tax.</p>
<p>The EU has been under trade pressure to restore subsidies as world prices fell in recent weeks on prospects of promising crops.</p>
<p>France on Wednesday raised the prospect that subsidised EU wheat sales may soon resume after suspension because of record world prices.</p>
<p>Alain Moulinier, director general of French grain office ONIC office said at a Wednesday news conference &quot;currently we have taxes but we will return to subsidies&quot;.</p>
<p>In response, U.S. Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman seemed to threaten a trade war if EU subsidies distorted the market.</p>
<p>&quot;If they use export subsidies, we will aggressively use the tools at our disposal to fight fire with fire...We're going to have more competitive wheat markets next year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In France traders bid to export a massive 407,600 tonnes of wheat at refunds ranging from 0.47 to 10 Ecus while in Germany they bid to export 13,500 tonnes of wheat at rebates ranging from 0.99 to 6.0 Ecus per tonne.</p>
<p>But exporters bid for the export of 3,000 tonnes of wheat in Greece and 1,500 tonnes in Denmark at unspecified taxes.</p>
<p>Traders said bids placed in Denmark may be destined to cover wheat sales to Norway and Poland, two destinations for which traders are willing to pay an export tax.</p>
<p>Traders said last week operators may bid for taxes throughout September mainly to cover a few deals with eastern Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole problem is that taxes still work on some destinations while refunds are needed to cover deals to other areas,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The Commission has also been reluctant to yield to trade pressure for subsidies as it is waiting to get a clearer harvest picture.</p>
<p>ONIC expects the EU 1996 grain harvest to exceed the 1991 record level of 194.8 milllion tonnes seen before the reform of the Common Agricultural Policy.</p>
<p>Estimates for the EU soft wheat harvest were between 88 and 89 million tonnes, Alain Moulinier said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>French wheat failed to react to reports of massive wheat bids in France, with Rouen delivered wheat for September quoted at 875 francs per tonne, unchanged from Wednesday. --Paris newsroom +331 4221 5432</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
