<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50694" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Highlights of Thursday's Commission briefing. [CORRECTED 12:28 GMT]</title>
<headline>Highlights of Thursday's Commission briefing. [CORRECTED 12:28 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the midday briefing by the European Commission on Thursday:</p>
<p>Spokesman Willy Helin dismissed French news reports implying that French Finance Minister Jean Arthuis had written to Commissioner Karel Van Miert in order to modify the rescue plan for Credit Lyonnais approved by the Commission on July 26, 1995 (corrects by inserting dropped reference to Credit Lyonnais).</p>
<p>Helin confirmed Arthuis's letter to Van Miert but said it had never been question of a new rescue plan. The letter was in reply to one sent by Van Miert, in which the Commission was asking for technical details on the rescue plan adopted the year before.</p>
<p>Asked about the financial future of the European Coal and Steel Community (ECSC), spokesman Nikolaus van der Pas said the Commission had discussed the statute of the ECSC loans on Wednesday. The outcome of the discussions was that the loans should continue to benefit from the Triplar statute. He also said that the Union should foresee a guarantee line to ensure this statute. Those questions would be further discussed between member states, he added.</p>
<p>Van der Pas reminded reporters that a news conference on the conservation of Brazilian tropical forests pilot programme would be held at 1600/1400 GMT in the press room.</p>
<p>- - - - The Commission released the following documents:</p>
<p>- IP/96/824: The Commission wants to incorporate a reference to services of general interest in the treaty.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/207: Speech of Commissioner Martin Bangemann at the second forum of the European Union and the Central and Eastern European countries on &quot;The Central and Eastern European countries and the Information Society&quot;.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/209: EU-Ukraine relations, address at the International conference on small and medium-sized enterprises and agriculture, by Commissioner Hans van der Broek.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/210: &quot;Don't shoot the referee&quot;, speech by Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan to the European Union of Women.</p>
<p>- COM(96) 443: Communication of the Commission: Services of general interest in Europe.</p>
<p>- Eurostat: Statistics in focus, External trade, 1996 No 8, European Union trade with the Commomweath of Independent States, results of 1995.</p>
<p>- Europinion No 9, results of &quot;Continuous tracking&quot; surveys of European Union (April, May, June and July 1996).</p>
<p>- ME96/12.9: Midday express</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
