<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="507069" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SGS-Thomson first quarter result falls.</title>
<headline>SGS-Thomson first quarter result falls.</headline>
<byline>Marcel Michelson</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>SGS-Thomson Microelectronics NV, the Franco-Italian semiconductor producer, on Monday reported a decline in first quarter earnings due to price erosion but predicted improvement for the remainder of the year.</p>
<p>The company's share fell by some five percent to a low of 368.10 francs before recovering some ground to 382 francs at 1055 GMT, a fall of 2.75 percent while the blue-chip index was down 0.99 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The results were pretty terrible,&quot; said one share trader.</p>
<p>SGS-Thomson, listed in Paris and New York, reported a drop in net income to $90.50 million from $175 million on lower sales of $944.90 million against $1,027.70 million in the first quarter of 1996. The company pays no dividend.</p>
<p>&quot;As expected, first quarter revenues were negatively impacted by market pricing conditions,&quot; president and chief executive officer Pasquale Pistorio said in a statement.</p>
<p>SGS-Thomson has so far been shielded from strong price erosion in chips because it does not produce DRAM (dynamic random access memory) chips whose prices have plunged.</p>
<p>&quot;Also, the combination of a stronger dollar and lower demand for products destined for digital consumer applications reduced first quarter demand,&quot; Pistorio said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are certainly encouraged by our ability to maintain gross margin levels, which were bolstered by better operating conditions in the last months of the quarter,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Pistorio was in Catania, Sicily, on Monday for the official opening of an eight-inch wafer plant (fab) by Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi who said he wanted to favour high-technology investments in the region.</p>
<p>Pistorio said the Catania plant had weighed on results.</p>
<p>&quot;The decline in other income reflected our decision to move ahead with the qualification of our eight inch fab in Catania. As a result, start-up expenses reached their highest level in a period when other income is historically low,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Market conditions remained as we had anticipated at the time of our year-end 1996 earnings release,&quot; Pistorio said.</p>
<p>&quot;As the quarter came to a close, we saw signs that prices of several standard products were stabilizing and in some cases increasing from recent low levels. Additionally, order rates accelerated last month, although overall visibility, while better than in the fourth quarter of 1996, remains modest.&quot;</p>
<p>Pistorio said that sales in the second quarter were expected to be around one billion dollars.</p>
<p>&quot;Somewhat firmer pricing and continued manufacturing efficiencies should result in a gross margin for the second quarter above that of the first quarter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Being a year of progressive recovery, the traditional seasonal effect should be offset by strengthening market conditions and we expect sequential growth both in sales and gross margin in the third and fourth quarters of 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
