<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="507061" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALTA: Middle East crisis clouds Euro-Med talks.</title>
<headline>Middle East crisis clouds Euro-Med talks.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Wright</byline>
<dateline>VALLETTA 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ministers from European and Mediterranean countries began arriving in Malta on Monday for a conference meant to build a peace partnership but clouded by conflict in the Middle East.</p>
<p>For the first time since clashes erupted after Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu gave the green light for building a Jewish settlement in East Jerusalem, Palestinian and Israeli leaders will be in the same room.</p>
<p>European Union Commission vice-president Manuel Marin, arriving in Malta, said the fact that Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy and Palestinian President Yasser Arafat would both attend the meeting was &quot;good news&quot;.</p>
<p>Levy, the likely focus of Arab criticism, only decided on Monday to attend, his ministry said. He had apparently hesitated to appear at a forum where the Arab delegations outnumber his team eight to one.</p>
<p>Diplomats say the Europeans would like to keep the crisis in Middle East talks in the background and concentrate on the long- term economic and security relationship between the northern and southern shores of the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussa said before leaving for Malta on Monday: &quot;The Middle East is not on the agenda but it is there, looming in the air...and we, the Mediterraneans, cannot not be affected.&quot;</p>
<p>Arafat, due on Tuesday, will relish the opportunity to tell a largely sympathetic audience that Israel's settlement policy in East Jerusalem is the main reason why peace talks have collapsed.</p>
<p>The Arabs say Netanyahu must go back on his decision.</p>
<p>The Europeans appear to have accepted that the Middle East will loom large but are seeking damage-limitation.</p>
<p>EU council chairman Hans van Mierlo, Dutch foreign minister, told reporters at Malta's Luqa airport: &quot;Of course the Middle East will be discussed but very moderately because it is something separate.&quot;</p>
<p>But disagreement dominated the runup to the conference opening on Tuesday. Malta's coordinator Paul Mifsud told a news briefing that general statements by ministers, originally planned to be broadcast live, might now not be. He would not give a reason.</p>
<p>Palestinian efforts to bring Europe more into the Middle East process, resisted by Israel, appeared to be gaining ground. EU special envoy Miguel Angel Moratinos was at the centre of efforts to arrange a PLO-Israeli meeting in Malta.</p>
<p>Palestinian spokesman Nabil Abu Rdainah said Levy and Arafat would not meet there but that Palestinian Planning and International Cooperation Minister Nabil Shaath might meet the Israeli minister.</p>
<p>The Arabs, especially those in the eastern Mediterranean, argue that any debate on security cannot ignore Israel's attitude in the Middle East peace talks.</p>
<p>&quot;The Arab concept is linked to developments in the Middle East peace process, because a bigger threat to security and stability comes from what is happening there,&quot; said Algerian Foreign Minister Ahmed Attaf, coordinator of the Arab group.</p>
<p>Lebanese Foreign Minister Faris Bouez said on departure from Beirut that his country wanted the 27 ministers to call for resumed Middle East peace talks along the guidelines set at the Madrid conference in 1991.</p>
<p>The key concepts in Madrid were &quot;land for peace&quot; and a ban on unilateral steps which prejudice the outcome of talks on the final status of Jerusalem and the occupied territories.</p>
<p>&quot;Our position in this regard is...that we are not to return to negotiations on any new basis,&quot; Bouez added.</p>
<p>The Europeans do not disagree but, like the United States, they are seeking a practical way out of the present impasse.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Moratinos said last week that the Europeans had prepared an initiative with this aim.</p>
<p>The initiative calls on both parties to abstain from unilateral actions, for Israel to agree to a freeze on Jewish settlement on occupied land and for a stronger Palestinian commitment to prevent political violence, he said.</p>
<p>But the initiative appears to please neither side and the Europeans have not been saying much more about it in public.</p>
<p>Netanyahu says he will never renounce an Israeli right to settle Jews in East Jerusalem and the West Bank.</p>
<p>Egypt's Moussa said on Saturday the European initiative was better than what the United States had to offer but still was not up to Arab expectations.</p>
<p>He was non-committal on arrival in Malta, merely saying &quot;We will talk about it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARABST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALTA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALLETTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALTA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
