<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="507156" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish shares seen continuing down in quiet trade.</title>
<headline>Danish shares seen continuing down in quiet trade.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish share prices closed lower on Monday hit by declines on Wall Street last Friday, with dealers seeing further falls ahead in an undramatic, thin market.</p>
<p>&quot;Provided the Dow does not fall as much today as it did on Friday, we should only see a steadily yet moderately downward trend here on Tuesday in a quiet, low turnover market,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The KFX top-20 index closed 1.55 point or 1.01 percent down at 152.53, while the KFX June future finished untraded at 153.00 point.  </p>
<p>Overall bourse turnover was 752 million crowns.</p>
<p>Losses were spread fairly evenly over the KFX shares, only Chr.Hansen -- unchanged -- and Coloplast -- up five crowns to 444.00 -- escaped unscathed.</p>
<p>Former KFX company East Asiatic shed three crowns to 162.00 on fears that China's threat to boycott Danish industry for Denmark's tabling of a U.N. human rights resolution against Beijing might hit the company hard.</p>
<p>Novo Nordisk, with major in-country investments in China, closed four crowns down at 664.00 --Chris Follett, Copenhagen newsroom +45-33-969652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
