<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="507198" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan invites tenders for 50,000 tonnes sugar.</title>
<headline>Pakistan invites tenders for 50,000 tonnes sugar.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The state-run Trading Corporation of Pakistan (TCP) said on Monday it had invited tenders for the import of 50,000 tonnes of crystal white refined sugar to reach Karachi by June and July.  </p>
<p>A TCP official, who asked not to be named, said the TCP had asked suppliers for shipment of 25,000 tonnes of sugar to reach Karachi not later than June 20, 1997 and the remaining 25,000 tonnes by July 10, 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Tenders would be opened on May 3, 1997 in the presence of the bidders or their representatives,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>He said the TCP had set a late shipment date to allow more suppliers to participate in the tender.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment I am not sure what prices would be quoted but we are loooking at a discount of $10 to $15 a tonne for June-July shipments,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>TCP in its last tender in January had imported 25,000 tonnes of sugar from the Indian Sugar General Imports &amp; Export Corporation while another 35,000 tonnes from the State Trading Corporation of India.</p>
<p>Private traders have also booked orders for imports of 150,000 tonnes this year.</p>
<p>Pakistan has already imported a total of 484,835 tonnes of sugar worth $185 million during the July-March 1996/97 period, the Federal Bureau of Statistics said.  </p>
<p>The Pakistan Sugar Mills Association said sugar production had reached 2.213 million tonnes by March 31 compared to 2.365 million tonnes in the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>It said mills aimed to produce 2.4 million tonnes in 1996/97, compared to 2.47 million in 1995/96 and 3.0 million in 1994/95. ($1 = 40.22 rupees)</p>
<p>-- Ovais Subhani 9221-5685192</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
