<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="507109" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Analysts applaud P.Telecom Concert choice.</title>
<headline>Analysts applaud P.Telecom Concert choice.</headline>
<byline>Paula Cordeiro</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Portugal Telecom's choice of the Anglo-American venture Concert as its strategic ally was widely applauded by analysts who saw it as the best option in commercial and marketing terms.</p>
<p>They said that the experience of the British Telecommunications Plc and MCI Communications Corp alliance could also prove useful in helping the Portuguese concern to complete its adaption to a fully liberalised telecommunications market in Europe. Portugal must remove all remaining barriers by 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;Both BT and MCI can make a contribution to Portugal Telecom's adaption (to the open market) and in terms of marketing and commercial strategies,&quot; said analyst Jose Antonio Goncalves of Lisbon's Tottadealer.</p>
<p>&quot;This alliance is a good choice (because) perhaps it is the strongest in commercial and marketing terms,&quot; said Daniel Bennett of brokers M.Valores.</p>
<p>PT announced on Monday that it had opted for Concert as its strategic ally, with its two partners sealing the deal by agreeing to take symbolic stakes in the Portuguese concern.</p>
<p>Spain's Telefonica de Espana SA could eventually also ally itself with Concert, by way of MCI, widening further the alliance's scope, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Portuguese concern chose Concert in preference to the AT &amp; T Corp -led Unisource and the Franco-German grouping Global One which were also seeking to draw Telecom into their orbits.</p>
<p>Analysts said that Telecom's shares could recover the highs of 6,650 escudos set in mid-March over the medium term. The stock was up 30 at 6,130 escudos on Monday in heavy trade, moving against the overall weaker trend on the Lisbon bourse.</p>
<p>&quot;In the medium term, the price of PT has room to return to its highs of the year. It continues to be one of the most attractive shares on the Portuguese market,&quot; said Mari Vargas of Santander Investment in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Even at current levels, we are reaffirming our buy recommendation,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Jose Freire of Espirito Santo Research said that PT had opted for the most aggressive alliance in the world, which should bring benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;This alliance is going to defend our traffic in Portugal. PT will now have the dimension to compete for other companies, particularly in markets where it has more influence such as the Portuguese-speaking countries,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said that the alliance should help strengthen Portugal Telecom's hand in Latin America where it already has an alliance with Brazil's Telebras.</p>
<p>&quot;Inside Concert, PT has an even better chance because it will have even greater weight,&quot; said Vargas.</p>
<p>But analysts were divided over the implications for Portugal Telecom of an eventual alliance between Telefonica and MCI, as has been widely forecast.</p>
<p>Telefonica is looking for an American partner for its international arm, Telefonica Internacional, and analysts have predicted the choice will fall on MCI. The Portugal Telecom statement announcing the Concert deal even said as much in the English version before it was withdrawn as &quot;an error&quot;.</p>
<p>Some analysts said that the arrival of Telefonica might not be positive for Telecom because it could limit its potential for expansion into other Latin American countries where the Portuguese lacked a presence.</p>
<p>But other analysts saw this greater geographical spread of Telefonica, which already has accords in a number of countries, as offering opportunities for cooperation.</p>
<p>&quot;Telefonica would reinforce this decision (choice of Concert) which is spot on,&quot; said Vargas.</p>
<p>-- Lisbon bureau 3511-3150035</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
