<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="507383" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: RAUTARUUKKI RAAHE MODERNISATION ON TRACK.</title>
<headline>RAUTARUUKKI RAAHE MODERNISATION ON TRACK.</headline>
<byline>John Acher</byline>
<dateline>RAAHE, Finland 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The modernisation of Finnish steel maker Rautaruukki's Raahe works is on track and aims to keep the mill competitive even if steel prices fall, the mill's management said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The aim is to be so competitive that we can make a profit even if steel prices turn weak,&quot; Kari Norberg, vice president for production, told Reuters in an interview at the steel works in north-western Finland.</p>
<p>At a news conference in Helsinki, Rautaruukki CEO Mikko Kivimaki said steel prices were likely to rise later in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;All the work is on schedule and all is within budget. We are within one percent of our cost estimate,&quot; said project manager Yrjo Suvanto, referring to the six-year investment programme with a total budget of 2.2 billion markka.</p>
<p>That sum comprises the 1.7 billion markka that the company includes in its Raahe Steel 2000 programme, and 500 million to replace two blast furnaces.</p>
<p>Rautaruukki on Monday announced it would issue new shares and that the state would reduce its stake in the company to well below 50 percent from the current 68.7 percent through a share offering to foreign and domestic investors.</p>
<p>The proceeds of the offering would be used largely to finance the Rautaruukki 2000 investment programme, the company said.</p>
<p>The Raahe investment programme, begun in 1995 and due for completion in 2000, involves a range of plant improvements and is expected to raise Raahe's steel and rolling mill output to 2.8 million tonnes per year, from 2.3 million tonnes in 1994 before the modernisation programme started.</p>
<p>&quot;We have about 40 different projects under way, and the value of the individual investments ranges from five to 370 million markka,&quot; Suvanto said.</p>
<p>The programme began with the 500 million markka investment to replace two blast furnaces in 1995 and 1996, raising capacity to 2.5 million tonnes of iron per year.</p>
<p>That part of the programme has been completed and the new furnaces are expected to serve for 15 years.</p>
<p>This year, about 700 million markka would be invested, mainly at the steel shop, where the converters -- the equipment that converts iron into steel -- are being upgraded to handle a larger input and a new continuous casting machine is being installed, Suvanto said.</p>
<p>At the strip mill, a new slab reheating furnace is being built at a cost of about 370 million markka, he said.</p>
<p>The second phase of the investment programme will involve replacing two other continuous casting machines to raise the coil size from 20 to 30 tonnes, Suvanto said.</p>
<p>The modernisation programme calls for about 200 million markka to be spent in 1998 and more than 400 million in 1999, Norberg said.</p>
<p>In the year 2000, annual investment at the Raahe works is expected to fall back to 200-300 million markka, which is about the normal level needed for regular upkeep and development of the plant, Norberg said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are striving for better product quality and higher efficiency,&quot; Norberg said. &quot;Efficiency will come from the increase in capacity and the smaller workforce needed to run it.&quot;</p>
<p>At the turn of the century the Raahe steel works would employ about 3,350 workers, down from about 3,650 in 1994 before the modernisation took off, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've calculated that the programme as a whole will reduce costs by an average of 10 percent per product,&quot; Norberg said.</p>
<p>&quot;In four or five years, the programme will have paid for itself,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Assuming stable steel prices, the investment programme would increase Raahe Steel's net sales by over 20 percent, he said, but added that this was a difficult figure to estimate because about half of net sales came from internal invoicing of other Rautaruukki units.</p>
<p>In 1996, the Raahe Steel unit had net sales of 4.51 billion markka, down from 5.03 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>The profit margin on the increased net sales would be higher because costs would fall and new higher value-added grades would be introduced, Norberg said.</p>
<p>Raahe steel already produces over a thousand customised grades of steel, and the investment programme would add dozens of new grades to the range, Norberg said.</p>
<p>Energy consumption, accounting for about 15 percent of total production costs, would become more efficient: &quot;The goal ... is for energy costs to fall three to four percent,&quot; Norberg said.</p>
<p>Production would also be faster: &quot;We now use about two and a half hours to produce a tonne of steel. When the programme is over, it will take two hours,&quot; Norberg said.</p>
<p>Raahe Steel's operations were moving towards shorter throughput times, fast delivery times and small, customized batches, Norberg said.</p>
<p>&quot;This modernisation programme is being conducted in a running plant,&quot; Suvanto said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will hardly need any extra stoppage days this year due to the programme,&quot; Norberg said.</p>
<p>--Helsinki Newsroom +358-9-680 50 235</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RAAHE, Finland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
