<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50744" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy Fin Min studies personal, region tax changes.</title>
<headline>Italy Fin Min studies personal, region tax changes.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Italian finance ministry plans to introduce a new regional tax (Irep) aimed at corporates and self-employed workers as well as an increase in personal tax (Irpef), with money from this going back to the regions.</p>
<p>A source at the ministry said the changes would not alter overall fiscal burden in Italy and would be introduced as part of the 1997 budget package.</p>
<p>&quot;The increase being considered for Irpef is between 0.5 to 1.0 percent,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>&quot;The increase will cover the abolition of health taxation... and will not make any difference to tax revenues,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said bands for the Irep tax, which will be replacing various taxes due to be scrapped, would be set at between three and five percent of taxable income. &quot;There will be a margin autonomy for the regions to set their own thresholds,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The government has pledged to increase the fiscal power of the regions in a bid to cut the influence of central administration. -- Rome newsroom +396 6782501</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
