<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50740" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Czechs welcome Kohl's reconciliation gesture.</title>
<headline>Czechs welcome Kohl's reconciliation gesture.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech embassador in Bonn welcomed on Thursday remarks by Chancellor Helmut Kohl that he hoped a post-war reconciliation accord would be concluded by the end of the year.</p>
<p>In an interview with German Radio Ambassador Jiri Grusa welcomed Kohl's remarks made on Wednesday in a keynote address to parliament as &quot;new and positive&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Kohl spoke in clear language which is receiving much attention from the Czech public,&quot; Grusa said.</p>
<p>This came as a &quot;wonderful addition&quot; to recent remarks by German president Roman Herzog, who stressed the inviolability of today's border with Poland at a meeting of people expelled from areas now part of Poland and Russia.</p>
<p>The German-Czech talks, now running for over a year, are intended to close the book on both the Nazi occupation of Czechoslovakia and the subsequent expulsion of millions of ethnic Germans from the country.</p>
<p>Kohl pleaded for patience in his parliamentary address. &quot;We want to conclude this agreement this year,&quot; he said, adding that he wanted it to be symbolically crowned by a speech in Bonn by a representative of the Czech government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
