<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="507447" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: New Croesus-UFG Russia Fund launched.</title>
<headline>New Croesus-UFG Russia Fund launched.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Optima Fund Management on Monday announced the launch of the Croesus-UFG Russia Fund investing in Russian &quot;liquid market&quot; equities.</p>
<p>The fund, a joint venture with US-based Croesus Capital Management and Russia-based United Financial Group, absorbed the assets of Optima's original Russian investment vehicle -- The Optima Opportunity Fund.</p>
<p>The open-ended fund with assets of around $80 million currently, plans to offer early stage investment in a low P/E market.</p>
<p>UFG executive director Charles Ryan says the fund will target a wider range of stocks than the top-tier blue chips.</p>
<p>&quot;There are probably 100 to 150 stocks we would take a hard look at, but we wouldn't necessarily invest in all of them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ryan said diminished Russian political risk, and improving market infrastructure were encouraging interest, and the fund would seek to invest in blue chips of the future.</p>
<p>He said there were many stocks looking to raise their international exposure, and as a result transparency would improve. Also, the expected inclusion of Russia in the IFC Emerging Markets index by mid-1997 was likely to support the market.</p>
<p>Ryan said there were &quot;investable&quot; stocks in the market with P/E valuations of one to two, against blue chip levels of above 14, with good opportunities seen in banking, engineering and food processing.</p>
<p>The majority of the fund remains heavily invested in the top-tier Russian stocks.</p>
<p>Boris Federov, UFG chairman and former Russian finance and deputy prime minister, said the Russian government's commitment to implementing policy reforms following recent appointments, including Anatoly Chubais and Boris Nemtsov as deputy prime ministers, was positive.</p>
<p>Also, the government has stated that federal and regional tax policy, the most important barrier still remaining in Russia's recovery, will be its highest reform priority.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear political risk is minimal, although the risk that they will move too slowly exists,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Andrew Gill, London newsroom +171 542 5887</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
