<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="507585" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Arafat in Cairo for talks with Mubarak.</title>
<headline>Arafat in Cairo for talks with Mubarak.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat arrived in Cairo on Monday and went immediately into talks with Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak, presidential sources said.</p>
<p>Arafat told reporters at Cairo airport he would discuss with Mubarak how to protect peace &quot;particularly in light of continued Israeli efforts to break the agreements signed in Washington and Cairo.&quot;</p>
<p>Arafat's adviser Nabil Abu Rdainah said Arafat's talks in Cairo came after American and European efforts to overcome a crisis with Israel over its building of a new settlement in Arab East Jerusalem achieved no results yet.</p>
<p>Arafat was due to continue to Malta on Monday to take part in a meeting of European and Mediterranean foreign ministers. Arafat will relish the opportunity to tell the ministers that Israel's settlement policy in East Jerusalem is the main reason peace talks have collapsed.</p>
<p>The PLO has said resumption of peace talks with Israel were conditioned on freezing work that began on March 18 at Jabal Abu Ghneim, the Jerusalem hilltop where 6,500 homes for Jews are planned.</p>
<p>Palestinians have clashed with Israeli troops in the West Bank almost every day since work started there.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
