<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50751" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German net trade income falls in June - Buba.</title>
<headline>German net trade income falls in June - Buba.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A fall in invisible transactions helped trim Germany's current account deficit in June although net income from foreign trade fell to a real six billion marks from 8.4 billion marks in May, the Bundesbank said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Federal Statistical Office reported on September 10 that the deficit in June fell to 2.1 billion marks from 2.5 million in May.</p>
<p>&quot;Exports have increased slightly, but the simultaneous rise in imports made a stronger impact,&quot; the Bundesbank said.</p>
<p>The central bank also said that in July, net inflows to German securities fell to 5.4 billion marks from a net 16 billion in June.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank said foreign interest in German securities, especially fixed income, remained high in July with inflows at 15 billion marks, up from 14.8 billion in the previous month.</p>
<p>However domestic investors also increased their investments in foreign securities to a net 9.6 billion marks after seliing 1.2 billion marks in June.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank's net external assets rose by 600 million marks in June and fell by 2.7 billion marks in July.</p>
<p>The statement said the drop was caused by foreign central banks buying back ECUs which the Bundesbank had acquired as part of its intervention activities in the European Monetary System.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
