<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="507804" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Bosnian Serb in first Swiss war crimes trial.</title>
<headline>Bosnian Serb in first Swiss war crimes trial.</headline>
<byline>Elif Kaban</byline>
<dateline>LAUSANNE, Switzerland 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Switzerland's first ever war crimes trial began on Monday amid confusion over the identity of a Bosnian Serb accused of torture and murder.</p>
<p>A lieutenant-colonel presided over the trial of Goran Grabez, who appeared nervous on the first day of the proceedings which are expected to end on Friday.</p>
<p>The 32-year-old former driver from the Bosnian town of Prijedor faces a maximum 20 years jail if found guilty on four counts of war crimes committed at the Serb-run Omarska detention camp in northwestern Bosnia in July, 1992.</p>
<p>Under Swiss procedure, he was not immediately asked whether he pleaded guilty or not.</p>
<p>Grabez was arrested two years ago in Geneva after Moslem refugees alleged he was a guard at Omarska and had tortured inmates. He denies the allegations, saying he was in Austria and Germany at the time.</p>
<p>The defence has called Austrian witnesses to try to prove Grabez was there when the alleged offences took place. But a police official told the court Grabez appeared to have changed the date of an Austrian stamp on his passport.</p>
<p>Monday's proceedings focused on the question of the defendant's identity.</p>
<p>In written testimony, a Moslem survivor from the Omarska camp, and a former friend of Grabez, claimed to have seen the Bosnian Serb at the detention camp, armed and in uniform.</p>
<p>But the witness failed to identify Grabez when shown a photograph of Bosnian Serb guards at Omarska, the court heard.</p>
<p>There was also confusion over a Bosnian government letter asking Switzerland to arrest a man it named as Goran Karlica, not Grabez.</p>
<p>The prosecutor, Major Claude Nicati, said although the prosecution had yet to ask for a sentence, Grabez faced up to 20 years in jail under the Swiss military penal code if found guilty.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first war crimes trial in our history. We have to judge this man,&quot; Nicati told Reuters.</p>
<p>At times, the trial appeared to lack the gravity that might have been expected.</p>
<p>The presiding judge, Lieutenant-Colonel Luc Hafner, interrupted the trial to joke when cannons were fired outside the building to celebrate a local holiday here.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't worry, the cannons have nothing to do with us,&quot; he said, as other judges laughed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAUSANNE, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
