<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="508391" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - April 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - April 14.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Jordanian press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-RAI</p>
<p>- A Palestinian girl shoots Israelis after crossing into the Israeli occupied West Bank from Jordan; sources say she acted in revenge for the killing of her brother in an Israeli prison in 1988.</p>
<p>- Crown Prince Hassan inspects the new Justice Palace complex; stresses the importance of the independance of the judiciary.</p>
<p>AD-DUSTOUR</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Abdul Salam al-Majali says will set up a new ministerial committee to study unifying benefits of public sector employees; the issue has been a bone of contention between unionists and the government.</p>
<p>- An official source says the interrogation still underway by the military prosecutor handling the case of the imprisoned Jordanian soldier who shot the Israeli schoolgirl last March.</p>
<p>- Why hasn't the U.N. compensation money for Jordanian victims of the Iraqi invasion of Kuwait arrive yet?</p>
<p>AL-ASWAQ</p>
<p>- Majali expected to meet parliamentary deputies on Monday to continue consultations on domestic issues in run up to national elections next Novemeber.</p>
<p>- Arrest of illegal arms smugglers by the border police.</p>
<p>JORDAN TIMES</p>
<p>- Saudi King Fahd congratulates King Hussein on his successful prostate surgery.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
