<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="508341" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: FORECAST - Japan March money supply to grow 2.8-3.1%.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Japan March money supply to grow 2.8-3.1%.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's money supply growth for March is expected to have remained slow at 2.8 to 3.1 percent due to sluggish fund demand by the large exporting firms that are spearheading the economic recovery, economists polled by Reuters said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Exporters are already awash with cash and have no need to borrow funds from banks,&quot; said a senior economist at Daiwa Research Institute.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, banks, which are still in the process of bad-loan write-offs, are wary of making loans to such risk-inherent entities as small venture capital firms, he said.</p>
<p>Economists' forecasts for year-on-year growth in Japan's broadly defined money supply average of M2 plus certificates of deposit (M2+CDs) in March ranged from 2.8 percent to 3.1 percent.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the broader measure of liquidity including the total amount of M2, CDs, postal savings, deposits at agricultural financial institutions and trust banks, bank debentures, Japanese government bonds, investment trusts and foreign bonds, is expected to show about 3.8 percent growth year-on-year, they said.</p>
<p>The larger growth seen for broader liquidity is mainly in response to rises in purchases of foreign bonds by individual and institutional investors, they said.</p>
<p>The March money supply figures will be released by the Bank of Japan at 8.50 a.m. on Thursday (2350 GMT Wednesday).</p>
<p>The economists' forecasts are as follows:</p>
<p>    Nomura Research		   +2.9 pct</p>
<p>    Daiwa Research		    +3.0 pct</p>
<p>    Yamaichi Research		 +3.1 pct</p>
<p>    Fuji Securities		   +3.0 pct</p>
<p>    DKB Research			+2.8 pct</p>
<p>---Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-8676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
