<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="508358" id="root" date="1997-04-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan metal refiners run at full speed as yen sags.</title>
<headline>Japan metal refiners run at full speed as yen sags.</headline>
<byline>Nao Nakanishi</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Many of Japan's copper and zinc refineries are running at full capacity as the strong dollar and firm metal prices bring them windfall profits, traders and analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;Our smelters are running at close to 100 percent of their capacity,&quot; said a spokesman at Nippon Mining and Metals Corp, the country's biggest copper producer.</p>
<p>Output schedules by Japan's refining companies showed that refined copper output would rise 0.7 percent to 642,006 tonnes in the 1997/98 first half, despite an expected 6.3 percent output drop by the second-largest producer, Mitsubishi Materials Corp due to scheduled maintainance at its Naoshima smelter in western Japan.</p>
<p>Japan's third-biggest copper smelter, Sumitomo Metal Mining Co, the most aggressive of Japan's non-ferrous metals companies in its involvement in mining projects overseas, plans the largest production increase of 5.4 percent.</p>
<p>A Sumitomo spokesman said the company would announce a production capacity increase at its Besshi smelter on Tuesday.</p>
<p>This follows a similar move by Nippon Mining, which is to boost output at Saganoseki by 1999. Its Iijima zinc smelter and Kosaka copper smelter also plan small output increases.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not surprising that they're running their plants at full capacity. Under current conditions, the more they produce, the more they earn,&quot; said one copper trader.</p>
<p>Minoru Hasegawa, analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, agreed, saying:  &quot;They (copper refineries) are benefitting from the triple merits: the cheap yen (against the dollar), good metal prices and larger output. They will see a profit jump.&quot;</p>
<p>Japan's smelters are expected to announce their results for 1996/97 in late May.</p>
<p>The dollar now stands at around 126 yen, compared with about 108 yen during the 1996/97 first half and a post-World War Two record low of 79.75 in April 1995.</p>
<p>Japan's smelters benefit from the dollar's strength against the yen as their treatment and refining charges from mining companies are denominated in dollars.</p>
<p>In 1994/95, when the yen was flying high against the dollar, Japan's copper refineries were only running at 88 percent of capacity, while its zinc refineries were at less than 75 percent of capacity, according to Ministry of International Trade and Industry.</p>
<p>The dollar's advance came on top of a recovery in metal prices from a slump in the second half of 1996, triggered by a scandal at Sumitomo Corp which suffered a loss of $2.6 billion as a result of a decade of unauthorised trading by its former chief copper trader.</p>
<p>This, combined with the strong yen against the dollar, has led to closure of zinc smelters by Mitsubishi Materials and Nippon Mining over the last few years.</p>
<p>Copper is trading on the London Metal Exchange around $2,300 a tonne, off its recent peak of $2,440 in March, but well above last June's 2-1/2 year low of $1,745. Zinc is quoted around $1,240 a tonne, compared with a recent peak of $1,266 and last year's low of $997.</p>
<p>Deutsche Morgan's Hasegawa said zinc refineries now enjoyed similar advantages to copper refining companies. But it was difficult to increase their output because there was not much ore available, he said.</p>
<p>The company schedules showed though Sumitomo is boosting zinc output by 4.8 percent in the 1997/98 first half, Japan's total production will stay little changed at 294,168 tonnes.</p>
<p>While high global copper prices in recent years encouraged miners to expand output or develop new mines, zinc prices lagged, leading to a decline in mine supply.</p>
<p>Analysts also noted refining zinc needs a good deal of electricity, which is expensive in Japan, so that zinc refining is not as profitable as copper refining.</p>
<p>--Tokyo Commodities Desk +81-3-3432-6179</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
