<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="508567" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-MONACO, BORDEAUX SEEK CONFIDENCE BOOSTER.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MONACO, BORDEAUX SEEK CONFIDENCE BOOSTER.</headline>
<byline>Rex Gowar</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bordeaux and Monaco, their confidence badly dented by recent setbacks, are both desperate for victory when they clash in the French first division on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Monaco may have virtually sewn up the league championship and so secured a berth in the European Cup but their confidence was badly affected by their 3-1 away loss to Internazionale in the UEFA Cup last week.</p>
<p>And their apparently rock solid team spirit was blown apart with a scathing attack on team mates and coach Jean Tigana by Victor Ikpeba over his role as eternal substitute.</p>
<p>The Nigerian Olympic gold medallist, whose goal in Milan has kept Monaco's hopes of reaching the UEFA final alive, said in last Friday's France Football: &quot;I've had enough of being taken for an animal. I want to know if they're no longer counting on me.&quot;</p>
<p>Ikpeba, who only weeks before the outburst extended his contract with Monaco until 2001, has since cleared the air with Tigana and the club authorities.</p>
<p>He could even start the match at Bordeaux. Brazilian Sonny Anderson is out with a pulled muscle and wants to ensure he is fit for the home leg against Inter next Tuesday.</p>
<p>Monaco have struggled to overcome the disappointment of their Milan performance.</p>
<p>&quot;We've found it hard to regain our spirits... We so wanted to do well there (in Milan) that we were in a bad way for the next two days,&quot; midfielder Sylvain Legwinski said. &quot;We must recover our solidarity.&quot;</p>
<p>Anderson said: &quot;We must play this match thinking of preparing for the (UEFA Cup) semifinal (second leg)... If we win we'll be almost (league) champions and it could give us great confidence.</p>
<p>&quot;If we lose to Bordeaux we will continue to question ourselves and that wouldn't be good... But it will be very hard because Bordeaux will want to make their fans forget the League Cup final defeat.&quot;</p>
<p>Sixth-placed Bordeaux were fighting on three fronts for a place in Europe until 10 days ago.</p>
<p>In that time they have lost a French Cup quarter-final and Saturday's League Cup final against Strasbourg and are now under pressure in the last UEFA Cup slot in the championship.</p>
<p>&quot;In our six remaining matches we must take 11 points out of 18 to qualify for Europe,&quot; said Bordeaux's Belgian goalkeeper Gilbert Bodart, who saved three penalties in Saturday's shoot-out and still ended up a loser.</p>
<p>Coach Rolland Courbis said the match against Monaco was perfect for forgetting the disappointments.</p>
<p>&quot;It's important to dive back into an important match and not dwell upon (the defeats),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Courbis' squad is at full strength and he should name almost the same team as for the League Cup final, although he is expected to put teenage forward Peter Luccin on from the start.</p>
<p>Strasbourg, who are fifth, could end Nantes' long unbeaten run -- 25 matches -- for the second time in three seasons.</p>
<p>Fourth-placed Strasbourg, who are at home to Nantes on Wednesday, ended their run at a league record 32 matches during Nantes' 1994-95 championship-winning season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MONAC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
