<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="508589" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: RADIO ROMANIA AFTERNOON HEADLINES AT 1 PM.</title>
<headline>RADIO ROMANIA AFTERNOON HEADLINES AT 1 PM.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Radio Romania news:</p>
<p>* Parliament's upper and lower chambers continue debates on the 1997 budget law and voted chapters on social protection, industry, trade and agriculture expenditures.</p>
<p>Some 5.5 trillion lei were allocated for social security.</p>
<p>* The budget chapters for farming and mining stirred heated debates, with MPs of the Party of Social Democracy (PDSR) criticising the budget draft for cutting subsidies to the mining sector.</p>
<p>Parliament adopted the article providing 1,071 billion lei in mining subsidies in its original version.</p>
<p>* Opposition proposals for amendments to increase subsidies to various sectors were rejected because they did not mention means to fund bigger budget expenditures.</p>
<p>* Romanian Foreign Minister Adrian Severin will start tour of Italy and the U.S. to plead for the country's early NATO admission, foreign ministry spokeswoman Gilda Lazar said.</p>
<p>She said Severin would start an official visit to Italy on Wednesday to meet Italian President Oscar Luigi Scalfaro, Prime Minister Romano Prodi and his counterpart Lamberto Dini.</p>
<p>Severin will also pay an official visit to Washington starting April 20 with a similar mission, Lazar said. He is expected to meet U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright.</p>
<p>* Romania's former King Michael will make a two-week visit to Romania to celebrate Orthodox Easter. He will visit Timisoara, Brasov and Iasi and will only spend one day in Bucharest.</p>
<p>-- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
