<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50866" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Aussie dlr idles as market mulls rate riddle.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Aussie dlr idles as market mulls rate riddle.</headline>
<byline>Wayne Cole</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar churned in a tight range Thursday as sentiment on interest rates see-sawed.</p>
<p>An unexpected jump in Australia's unemployment rate to 8.8 percent in August from 8.5 percent set some tongues wagging, but dollar bulls took reassurance in a healthy 37,900 rise in employment, which was well above the 12,000 forecasted.</p>
<p>Top officials at the Reserve Bank also aired their thoughts on the economy, but again analysts considered the comments so evenly balanced that it should not alter forex market assumptions a rate cut was unlikely until November, if at all.  </p>
<p>By 4.40 pm (0640 GMT) the local dollar stuck at US$0.7988/93 after an early US$0.7986/91 and US$0.7989/94 late Wednesday. That was its third successive session in a US$0.7980/8020 range.</p>
<p>It fared better on the crosses thanks to a U.S. dollar rally through 110.00 yen, and climbed to 88.00/10 yen from 87.75/85, not far short of July's four-year high of 88.50.</p>
<p>There was the usual talk of dual currency samurai demand, but no actual bond issues to prove it, and a jump in oil prices also aided the dollar -- Australia is a net exporter of oil while Japan imports all its needs.</p>
<p>In trade weighted terms it was steady at 58.8.  </p>
<p>The bond and money market chose to see the jump in the unemployment rate as increasing the chance of another monetary policy easing before year-end.</p>
<p>The 90-day bank bill future for December edged up eight basis points to 93.22, implying a rate of 6.78 percent compared to the current official rate of 7.0 percent.</p>
<p>But dollar bulls chose to focus on the rise in employment for the month which was at the top end of forecasts even when the addition of 10,000 temporary jobs for the national census was taken into account. Full-time employment rose 11,200 while 26,700 part-time places were created.  </p>
<p>If that sort of growth were maintained, they said, it might just keep the Reserve Bank's finger off the rate trigger.</p>
<p>The RBA's thinking got a timely airing when outgoing governor Bernie Fraser and incoming governor Ian Macfarlane testified to a parliamentary committee.</p>
<p>Fraser said the economy continued to grow relatively robustly with low inflation, but unemployment was too high and the RBA stood ready to ease again if the economy needed support.</p>
<p>He saw scope for the economy to grow faster without threatening inflation which, analysts said, probably meant he also saw scope for lower interest rates down the track.  </p>
<p>However, Fraser added that the effects of the last rate cut, on July 31, would only become apparent in the months ahead, suggesting the bank was not considering an early policy easing.</p>
<p>&quot;On balance it looks like the RBA still has a bias to ease,&quot; said Anthony Thompson, an economist at Hongkong Bank Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;But I don't think the rise in unemployment has increased the chance of a cut,&quot; he said. &quot;It's employment growth that's important -- that's what feeds though into household income and point to where business confidence is heading.&quot;</p>
<p>Other domestic data out today were also seen arguing against an early cut in rates.  </p>
<p>Private sector credit leapt 1.6 percent in July boosting annual growth to 13.2 percent. Credit for personal use surged 2.8 percent, the largest monthly gain since the consumer boom of 1990, on top of a hefty 1.6 percent gain in June.</p>
<p>That gelled with the surprisingly strong 2.4 percent rise in retail sales seen in July, both of which came before the RBA's cut in official interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;Growth accelerated across all financial aggregates and annual growth rates remain consistent with a somewhat faster pace of economic growth than the consensus view would suggest,&quot; said Tony Meer, an economist at Bain.  </p>
<p>All-in-all, most analysts saw no reason after today's developments to revise their opinion that another easing was possible, but probably not until November at the earliest.</p>
<p>By then the key consumer price and wages data for the third quarter would have been released -- in late October -- and the impact, if any, of the last rate cut would be more apparent.</p>
<p>The next domestic figure of note is merchandise imports for August which are not due until next Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
