<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="508881" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia, NATO leaders meet for tough talks.</title>
<headline>Russia, NATO leaders meet for tough talks.</headline>
<byline>Philippa Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov meets NATO Secretary General Javier Solana on Tuesday for another round of bargaining about future relations between Moscow and the Western alliance after it expands eastwards.</p>
<p>Primakov and Solana meet behind closed doors as both sides step up rhetoric to win more concessions in talks on a deal aimed at saving Moscow's face and ruling out new conflict in Europe.</p>
<p>Interfax news agency said the talks, due to start at noon, (0800 GMT) would last three hours. Both sides had agreed not to release any information about the talks.</p>
<p>Both sides hope for a breakthrough which will enable them to sign an accord laying out the terms for peaceful coexistence into the next century. But both look unhappy about the current state of negotiations.</p>
<p>&quot;The main problem of minimising harm for Russia from NATO's enlagement has not been solved yet,&quot; Itar-Tass news agency quoted Russian Deputy Foreign Minister Georgy Mamedov as saying. Mamedov recently held talks in Washington.</p>
<p>The main sticking point is Russia's fear that the alliance's plans to invite in former Soviet bloc countries in July will lead to a military build-up near its borders.</p>
<p>&quot;So far NATO has not changed enough so that we would not feel a threat if the alliance's military structures near our borders,&quot; Mamedov said.</p>
<p>Russia is also demanding a say in some NATO decision-making under the accord, which it hopes to sign in six weeks.</p>
<p>But Russian officials say the two sides, anxious to avoid potentially damaging point-scoring, have agreed to keep the details of the talks under wraps.</p>
<p>&quot;The main thing is to reach a result, not to tell the world who did what to bring about the success,&quot; Interfax quoted a Russian foreign ministry source as saying.</p>
<p>On the eve of the talks, both NATO and the Kremlin appeared prepared to dig in their heels rather than give any more ground.</p>
<p>Some NATO members &quot;are not showing enough desire to seek a compromise,&quot; said Yeltsin's spokesman Sergei Yastrzhembsky, who this month took on extra responsibilities for coordinating foreign policy in the Kremlin.</p>
<p>&quot;Such an agreement must be reached on an equal basis, but not at all costs,&quot; Yastrzhembsky told Interfax news agency.</p>
<p>In Brussels, diplomats said they were disappointed with the tough conditions laid down by Primakov in Paris, where they said he had effectively asked NATO to rule out any future military reinforcement of new alliance members.</p>
<p>NATO, which has sparked Russian charges it is creating new divisions in Europe with its enlargement plan, says it does not want the new members -- expected to be Poland, Hungary and the Czech republic -- to feel like a second class group.</p>
<p>Primakov also said in Paris that Russia hoped to sign a partnership document with NATO on May 27.</p>
<p>But the NATO diplomats said his negotiating stance looked like a step back from last month's Russian-U.S. summit in Helsinki, at which President Bill Clinton appeared to have more or less successfully defended the document on offer.</p>
<p>&quot;Solana is going to have to be very tough, we have made a generous offer which meets many Russian concerns. Whether Moscow takes it or not, enlargement is going ahead anyway,&quot; said a senior Western diplomat. 150802 GMT apr 97</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
