<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="508927" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania Democrats say no polls until south disarms.</title>
<headline>Albania Democrats say no polls until south disarms.</headline>
<byline>Llazar Semini</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's right-wing Democratic Party on Tuesday ruled out holding general elections in Albania until rebels controlling the south had been disarmed.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless the (rebel) committees are disarmed, we can hardly consider holding free elections. The disarming of the rebels is a pre-condition for the elections,&quot; Genc Pollo, the party's newly-elected secretary-general, told a news conference.</p>
<p>The Democratic Party of President Sali Berisha is a leading party in the &quot;government of national reconciliation&quot; set up last month after the small Balkan state slid into near-anarchy following the failure of fraudulent investment plans.</p>
<p>Rebel committees, which blamed Berisha for the collapse of the schemes, took control of much of the south of Albania, which is awash with arms following the looting of armouries deserted by soldiers and police at the height of the violence.</p>
<p>Tritan Shehu, leader of the party, said the deployment of a multinational force in Albania would make it easier to restore law and order before the general elections due in June.</p>
<p>Nearly 300 people have been killed and about 700 injured since the armed insurrection began in late February.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope the coming of the multinational force will be a positive factor to help fulfil the conditions for the general elections,&quot; Shehu said.</p>
<p>More than 1,000 Italian, French and Spanish troops began arriving by air and sea on Tuesday to spearhead an eight-nation protection force for humanitarian aid supplies to Albania. Their mandate does not include disarming Albanians.</p>
<p>Shehu, whose party won a landslide victory in 1996 polls boycotted by the opposition, which claimed electoral fraud, and criticised by international organisations, accused former communists of staging the uprising in order to destroy his party.</p>
<p>He also said the party had failed to warn people about the dangers of the investment schemes, in which many Albanians had ploughed their life savings.</p>
<p>&quot;The party...did not give the alarm in time about the failed pyramid schemes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Pollo rejected requests by rival political parties to reform the electoral law.</p>
<p>&quot;Local elections last year showed that the prevailing electoral law is totally acceptable and represents no obstacle to the forthcoming general elections,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
