<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="509114" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico 1997 public finances to be strong -Werner.</title>
<headline>Mexico 1997 public finances to be strong -Werner.</headline>
<dateline>CANCUN, Mexico 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's public finances will remain in a strong shape in 1997, deputy finance minister Martin Werner said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1995 when the economy shrank by about six percent, the government budget was in balance and it was in balance again in 1996, and we will see very strong public finances in 1997,&quot; Werner told a conference here on emerging markets.</p>
<p>Werner noted that Mexico has radically changed its debt profile since the 1994 peso crash.  </p>
<p>In 1995, Mexico had more than $40 billion of foreign denominated debt, while in the last two years the federal government has managed to raise $20 billion in world capital markets, Werner said.</p>
<p>&quot;This has helped us to radically change our amortization schedule,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>For 1997 and 1998 Mexico has $9.0 billion in debt to roll- over, but of that, only $4.0 billion has to be raised on credit markets. The other $5.0 billion will be renegotiated with international organizations such as the World Bank, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The profile of our debt is no longer an issue for the future,&quot; he said. &quot;Mexico today is much less vulnerable than we were in 1994.&quot;</p>
<p>Werner noted that Mexico's debt to export ratio was one of the lowest in Latin America, with only Colombia and Chile having lower ratios.</p>
<p>He also noted that the nation's stock exchange was adapting to provide new projects.</p>
<p>The first step in making the Mexican market more international will be to introduce trading of dollar-denominated bonds and notes on the Mexican bolsa, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;With the introduction of the Afores (private pension funds), there will be demand for longer-term instruments,&quot; he noted. The private pension system will begin operating in the second half of the year.</p>
<p>He said that by the end of the year Mexico hopes to open a futures market on the peso exchange rate and on interest rates, and then later develop options for these products.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to bring some of this trading back to Mexico,&quot; he said, noting that trade of these products is now in Chicago.</p>
<p>Mexico also aims to have debt and equities from other countries, particularly in Latin America, listed on the Mexican bolsa, thus making it a center for trading, he added.</p>
<p>He noted that Mexico needed to develop new mechanisms to help consolidate access for medium-sized firms to securities markets and develop a derivatives markets, he noted.</p>
<p>((--Robert Kozak, Mexico City newsroom, 525 728-7902))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANCUN, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
