<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="509155" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUATEMALA: Victims blast reopening of Guatemala stadium.</title>
<headline>Victims blast reopening of Guatemala stadium.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Ortiz</byline>
<dateline>GUATEMALA CITY 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The families of 78 fans killed in an overcrowded soccer stadium last year blasted sports promoters on Wednesday for planning to reopen the stadium without compensating the victims.</p>
<p>The tragedy occurred before the kickoff at a World Cup classifying match between Costa Rica and Guatemala on Oct. 16. Overcrowding triggered a human avalanche in the stadium's cement bleachers when holders of cheap tickets crammed in.</p>
<p>&quot;It is like a sick joke to us that they are opening the stadium on (another) Wednesday the 16th. We are upset and sad because in reopening it they are only thinking of making money,&quot; Elida Trejo, who lost her husband, Carlos Caracun, a bus driver, and her son, William, told Reuters.</p>
<p>FIFA, the World Cup soccer authority, on Monday granted permission to use Guatemala's Mateo Flores stadium for a Central American soccer tournament on April 16-27. The stadium had been closed while the Guatemalan Soccer Federation made changes to improve security for fans.</p>
<p>Trejo said it was unfair that promoters would make money while families have yet to receive any of the economic aid the government promised. President Alvaro Arzu, who was at the stadium the night of the tragedy and cancelled the game in a teary-eyed address from midfield, promised the families would get the ticket income from the game, but the money, about $270,000, has been frozen until court cases are resolved.</p>
<p>A presidential commission investigated the tragedy and found extreme overcrowding plus a lack of an emergency plan and crowd-control measures led to the worst tragedy in World Cup history. Investigations by the public prosecutor's office showed 60,000 people including 45,000 ticket-holders, unticketed children and gate-crashers were packed into the stadium, which engineers have said should hold only 32,676.</p>
<p>A government report said 55,000 people were in the stadium, and FIFA said the stadium was built to hold 29,700.</p>
<p>A lawyer representing Trejo and other relatives of victims tried last week to block the reopening until families received damages and compensation, but a judge denied their motion.</p>
<p>Rene Cordoba, attorney for the families, told Reuters the victims had been forgotten while sports authorities plan the Central American tournament. &quot;They have been very interested in investing money into rehabilitating the stadium but they scorn the matter of the victims. The sports authorities have minimised the deaths of these people,&quot; Cordoba said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the prosecution of 18 men charged in the incident has been stalled in the courts. Judge Salvador Velasco told Reuters preliminary appeals could drag on for months before he would decide whether to take them to trial.</p>
<p>The accused were indicted for criminal negligence for allowing overcrowding on the night of Oct. 16. While out on bail they are allowed to continue managing soccer events.</p>
<p>State prosecutor Selvin Galindo said the 18 people charged were ticket-takers, stadium employees and heads of the sports federations that manage big sporting events at Mateo Flores. &quot;There was negligence and imprudence on the part of the sports directors,&quot; Galindo told Reuters. He said they were out on bail of up to $50,000 each.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUATEMALA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUATEMALA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
