<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="509206" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian Broadcasting Corp Midday Update.</title>
<headline>Australian Broadcasting Corp Midday Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>AUSTRALIA WANTS COORDINATED INTERNATIONAL APPROACH TO IRAN</p>
<p>Australia says there should be a coordinated international approach to dealing with Iran's use of state-sponsored terrorism.</p>
<p>The Foreign Ministers, Alexander Downer, said Australia would make a careful assessment of the German court finding that Iran had ordered the murder of four dissidents.</p>
<p>Mr Downer said he would speak today to Australia's Ambassador to Iran, Stuart Hume, who has been recalled from Tehran.</p>
<p>The Foreign Minister said Australia would consult partners such as the European Union and North America.</p>
<p>Mr Downer said Australia had been discussing with Tehran the unused line of credit granted Iran in 1991 -- worth 750-million US dollars.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>EXTINGUISHING NATIVE TITLE REJECTS RULE OF LAW: PEARSON</p>
<p>Adviser to the National Indigenous Working Group, Noel Pearson, says the idea of extinguishing native title rejects democracy and the rule of law.</p>
<p>Mr Pearson says the supporters of extinguishment are prepared to show unfaithfulness to the rule of law because they won't accept the law benefiting a different race.</p>
<p>Mr Pearson says the Wik and Mabo decisions are expressions of Australia's democracy and civilisation.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ATTACKS BY QLD NATIONALS PAR FOR THE COURSE, SAYS SHARP</p>
<p>Federal Transport Minister and National Party Member, John Sharp, says the Queensland National's attacks on the deputy Prime Minister over Native Title are just their way of getting a message across.</p>
<p>Mr Sharp says attacks by the Queensland National's have been par for the course for Federal National Party leaders for a very long time.</p>
<p>He says Mr Fischer is doing a very good job and has the support of the Federal team.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>AUSTRALIA POST'S MONOPOLY TO BE REVIEWED</p>
<p>The National Competition Council promises to consult widely when it examines whether Australia Post should keep its monopoly on postal services.</p>
<p>The Federal government is yet to set a timetable and terms of reference, but the Council says it expects to conduct the inquiry under national competition laws.</p>
<p>The Competition Council's Executive Director, Ed Willett, says the review will consider whether restrictions on competition in postal services are in the public interest.</p>
<p>He says the likely contenders in any open market, will be consulted, as will customers who have particular interests in</p>
<p>Australia Post services.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SHIPPING FEDERATION SAYS MARITIME UNION CAN'T BE BYPASSED</p>
<p>The international organisation representing merchant seamen has come out in support of the Australian Maritime Union, saying Australian ship owners can't avoid dealing with the union.</p>
<p>The International Transport Workers' Federation says it will have no part of a proposal to help the government deal with the Maritime Union.</p>
<p>The still-to-be released Manser Report into reform of the shipping industry says foreign workers on foreign ships on domestic routes could be represented by the federation.</p>
<p>But, the federation says it will do nothing to help foreign ships sail between Australian ports.</p>
<p>The Maritime Union has long said it will fight to prevent foreign ships sailing domestic routes.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MOLLER'S MOTHER SAYS HE WAS MURDERED</p>
<p>The mother of former police officer Clinton Moller, found hanged in his cell in Sydney's Parklea prison on the weekend says she believes he was murdered.</p>
<p>The former policeman was found dead less than 24-hours after being moved from Long Bay Jail, midway through an eight-month sentence for contempt of the Wood Police Royal Commission.</p>
<p>Shirley Moller says she believes her son was moved so he could be killed, because somebody in a high place felt he knew something they didn't want revealed.</p>
<p>Mrs Moller says authorities had five-and-a-half hours alone with her son to cover what they wanted covered.</p>
<p>She also says his wife-to-be was not allowed inside the prison gate, but was told over the phone he was dead.</p>
<p>Mrs Moller says she wants an independent inquiry into her son's death because he did not commit suicide.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>COLONIAL STATE BANK INCREASES FEES</p>
<p>The Australian Consumers Association says bank fee increases won't end with the Colonial State Bank which has become the first bank to increase charges following the Wallis Report into the finance industry.</p>
<p>Colonial has doubled fees on its everyday deposit and savings accounts to 40 cents.</p>
<p>Mara Bunn of the Consumers Association says banks will increase fees and charges, whenever possible, to generate additional profits.</p>
<p>Last week's Wallis Report recommended banks should be free to set fees and charges, based on costs.</p>
<p>But Colonial's Marketing Manager Paul Tissot has defended the new fees, saying that while the bank charges for all transactions, it also pays the highest interest rates.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
