<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="509202" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexican crude ports remain shut with ships waiting.</title>
<headline>Mexican crude ports remain shut with ships waiting.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two of Mexico's main crude ports remained closed for a third day with tankers waiting to load and set sail, port officials said on Monday.</p>
<p>Dos Bocas and Pajaritos closed late Saturday because of storms in the Gulf of Mexico  and were still shut as of 7 p.m. on Monday (0000 GMT on Tuesday). Officials told Reuters the ports would be unlikely to open before late Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very ugly here. I think we will stay closed through Wednesday,&quot; a Pajaritos official told Reuters. Winds at the terminals were between 40 and 50 kmh at the ports, with waves up to 12 feet high.  </p>
<p>At Dos Bocas, a port captain said two crude tankers were waiting for weather conditions to improve before setting sail. Weather at the ports will be reviewed at 7 a.m., and a decision will be made on whether to open the terminals.    U.S.-bound</p>
<p>John Young has been held up during the three-day closure, unable to load a contracted 1.45 million barrels of Maya heavy crude, and U.S. Bona Spring was waiting to load 525,000 barrels of Maya, he said.</p>
<p>Eight tankers were stuck waiting to enter Pajaritos and eight were waiting to leave, according to a port official. Of the arriving ships, he said five were from state oil monopoly Petroleos Mexicanos (Pemex), while four of the ships waiting to sail were Pemex's.</p>
<p>Pemex's largest crude port, Cayo Arcas, was reported open at 7:20 a.m. on Monday after shutting at 7:20 p.m. on Saturday.</p>
<p>Cayo Arcas shipped an average 576,300 barrels per day (bpd) of crude in 1996, while Dos Bocas shipped 505,900 bpd and Pajaritos shipped about 416,200 bpd, according to Pemex.</p>
<p>((--Timna Tanners, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-7903))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
