<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="509453" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Washington Mutual confident on merger.</title>
<headline>Washington Mutual confident on merger.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Washington Mutual Inc Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Kerry Killinger said Tuesday he was confident the company's offer to acquire Great Western Financial Corp would be approved by shareholders and close in the third quarter.</p>
<p>At the savings bank company's annual shareholder meeting, Killinger did not even mention the competing offer from H.F. Ahmanson and Co until he was asked during a question and answer period.</p>
<p>&quot;We view our offer as superior and we have a definitive agreement,&quot; he told reporters after the meeting.  </p>
<p>Killinger said he expected shareholders of both Washington Mutual and Great Western to approve the deal at special meetings tentatively planned for sometime in June.</p>
<p>Executives from the two companies already have been working together to plan the integration of data processing and systems, Killinger told reporters</p>
<p>&quot;We expect this transaction to be approved by the shareholders and be closed by the third quarter, so it's appropriate to get planning on it right now,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The exact date for special shareholder meetings will be set in documents to be filed soon with the Securities and Exchange Commission, Killinger said.</p>
<p>The meetings probably would be held around the same time as Great Western's annual shareholders meeting, currently scheduled for June 13.</p>
<p>Ahmanson is in the process of soliciting shareholder consents to consider several proposals at Great Western's annual meeting, where it also is expected to nominate for election three directors sympathetic to its offer, Killinger told shareholders.  </p>
<p>But he said such &quot;maneuvering&quot; was not a major issue for Great Western.</p>
<p>&quot;From our perspective we think that the primary focus is on our deal, and we want to get our deal in front of shareholders,&quot; Killinger said.</p>
<p>A lawyer representing Washington Mutual said it could take another week for Great Western's independent auditors to inspect and certify Ahmanson's consent solicitation.</p>
<p>In response to a reporter's question, Killinger said Washington Mutual would continue its expansion strategy even if it were foiled in its bid for Great Western.</p>
<p>&quot;We would anticipate a number of opportunities for acquisitions that we would pursue, especially in California where the market is consolidating,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he noted that Great Western would have to pay Washington Mutual a breakup fee of up to $175 million plus expenses if it were to agree to be acquired by another suitor instead.</p>
<p>((-- Martin Wolk, Reuters Seattle bureau, 206-386-484))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
