<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="509439" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. debt futures end higher, extend post-CPI gains.</title>
<headline>U.S. debt futures end higher, extend post-CPI gains.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. debt futures closed higher as both June T-bonds and September Eurodollars extended post-CPI gains on short-covering, traders said.</p>
<p>Aside from continued short-covering, bond futures traders said hedge funds were light buyers and noted cash note buying from a West Coast-based fund.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, one major U.S. dealer stepped up in the Eurodollar pit and aggressively bought September Eurodollars, pushing the contract to 93.72.</p>
<p>&quot;There are just a lot of shorts in here,&quot; one floor source said.  </p>
<p>Dealers and traders with short positions, which many floor sources believe were accumulated during Friday's sell-off, were forced to cover immediately after the U.S. Consumer Price Index (CPI) was released on Tuesday morning.</p>
<p>The CPI rose 0.1 percent overall and was up 0.2 percent in the core rate, slightly lower than average trade estimates for gains of 0.2 percent and 0.3 percent, respectively. However, the bond futures pit had been pricing in a core CPI gain of about 0.4 percent.</p>
<p>Most traders were expecting short-covering to continue on Wednesday if June T-bonds closed at or above the 108-00 area.  </p>
<p>One analyst said the fact that June bonds settled above a channel trendline level from early February at 107-17/32 was a positive near-term development.</p>
<p>September Eurodollars steadily inched up near resistance at 93.75 after initially stalling around the 93.70 level.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not wildly bullish here, but people think we will go higher,&quot; one Eurodollar futures said.</p>
<p>Tim O'Neill, chief economist at Chicago's Harris Bank and its parent company Bank of Montreal, was slightly cautious, noting that the market still faces a week full of U.S. economic indicators.  </p>
<p>&quot;Despite the good news on the inflation front, this week still has the potential to be nerve-racking for the markets,&quot; O'Neill said in a news release.</p>
<p>One Wednesday at 0830 EDT/1230 GMT, U.S. March housing starts will be released. Starts are expected on average to fall to a seasonally-adjusted rate of 1.46 million units from 1.528 million in February.</p>
<p>U.S. March industrial production and capacity utilization data will be released on Thursday. Production is seen rising 0.6 percent from up 0.5 percent in February, while utilization is estimated to rise to 83.6 from 83.3.  </p>
<p>&quot;Unexpectedly strong numbers would further confirm an economy that has a lot of momentum and is not about to be slowed down,&quot; O'Neill said.</p>
<p>The market had little reaction to U.S. weekly Redbook retail sales which were up 0.6 percent.</p>
<p>At the end of pit trade, June T-bonds were 30/32 higher at 107-20/32, notes were up 17/32 at 105-25/32, September T-bills were up 0.06 to 94.295, and September Eurodollars were up 0.65 to 93.71. ((DerivativesDesk(312)408-8750)) E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
