<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="50943" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-RBA's Fraser sees scope for narrower bond gap.</title>
<headline>RTRS-RBA's Fraser sees scope for narrower bond gap.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reserve Bank of Australia Governor Bernie Fraser said on Thursday there was scope for the differential between Australian and U.S. bond yields to narrow further as inflation was expected to keep falling for another year at least.</p>
<p>&quot;There's scope for the differential on bond yields to narrow further,&quot; Fraser told a parliamentary committee.  </p>
<p>&quot;The narrowing of this long term bond differential that we're talking about has occurred because we're getting some runs on the board on low inflation and because investors believe that the Reserve Bank is serious when it says that inflation will be held within the two to three percent (band),&quot; Fraser said.</p>
<p>&quot;As I've already said, at least for the next year or so, we expect inflation to be coming down from where it is, so in that sense there's room for those differentials on bond yields to perhaps narrow even further,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's inflation and all the factors that go into that that are the critical things.&quot;  </p>
<p>The differential between U.S. and Australian ten year bond yields has dropped from aroun 250 basis points in April to around 120 points currently.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
