<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="509417" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BHA Group March 31 backlog up vs year-ago.</title>
<headline>BHA Group March 31 backlog up vs year-ago.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>BHA Group Holdings Inc said Tuesday its backlog stood of $45.7 million as of March 31, up from $43.8 million on December 31 and $35.7 million on March 31, 1996.</p>
<p>Earlier, BHA reported record second quarter earnings of $0.32 a share, up from $0.28 a year ago.  Sales were $33.6 million, up from $31.2 million.</p>
<p>Domestic businesses performed well during the period, the company said, with its fabric filter operation increasing sales across traditional and targeted industrial markets.  </p>
<p>&quot;The domestic electrostatic precipitator business also posted a strong quarter as several large replacement parts orders were shipped during the period,&quot; James Lund, president, said in a statement.</p>
<p>While year-to-date sales for this segment are in line with internal projections, Lund said the company continues to be cautious about the domestic market for electrostatic precipitator replacement parts and services as it remains competitive.</p>
<p>&quot;International sales for the quarter decreased as compared to the first quarter of this fiscal year and the same period in the prior year, due in part to the timing of execution of project work,&quot; Lund aid. &quot;We are optimistic about the long-term prospects of our international replacement parts and service business and are committed to expanding our presence.&quot;</p>
<p>He added BHA has decided to establish a presence in China, which is expected to be operational by the summer of 1997.</p>
<p>BHA Group makes and markets industrial air pollution control parts and services worldwide.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
