<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="509696" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Over 30 die in haj fire, stampede in Saudi Arabia.</title>
<headline>Over 30 die in haj fire, stampede in Saudi Arabia.</headline>
<byline>Hilary Gush</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than 30 Moslem pilgrims, most of them Pakistanis, died in a blaze and consequent stampede on Tuesday at a tent compound near the Islamic holy city of Mecca, diplomats in Saudi Arabia said.</p>
<p>A fire raged through some 50,000 tents at the plain of Mena where about two million Moslems were gathering at the start of the centuries-old haj rite, Pakistan's Ambassador Shahed Amin said. Witnesses in Mecca, 11 km (seven miles) away, said they could see black smoke covering the sky over Mena.</p>
<p>&quot;Thirty are believed to be dead. We fear they may all be Pakistanis,&quot; Amin, who toured the site of the fire in Mena, told Reuters by telephone from Mecca.</p>
<p>&quot;There are probably more (dead) but I cannot speak for other nationalities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Witnesses told Reuters they heard the wailing sound of ambulance sirens and fire engines rushing to the scene. Helicopters from the fire department flew overhead, they added.</p>
<p>Saudi television said the blaze, which began at 11.45 a.m. (0845 GMT) and spread quickly in high winds, had been extinguished by 3.05 p.m. (1205 GMT).</p>
<p>There has been no official Saudi comment on any casualties.</p>
<p>Indian deputy chief of mission in Riyadh, George Joseph, said many families were separated while making their way to Mena, making it difficult to determine an exact number of casualties.</p>
<p>Bangladesh's consul general said at least one person had died in a stampede as crowds rushed to escape the flames.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as we know all Bangladeshis are safe except for one person who died in a stampede,&quot; Mohsen Ali Khan said, adding there were some 35,000 Bangladeshi haj pilgrims.</p>
<p>The cause of the fire was not immediately known, but residents said civil defence officials blamed the blaze on a gas explosion, probably caused by pilgrims cooking on gas stoves.</p>
<p>The fatal blaze is the latest tragedy to strike Moslems on pilgrimage to Mecca, their holiest shrine. Able-bodied Moslems are obliged to make the haj at least once if they can afford it.</p>
<p>The worst of recent Mecca tragedies was a stampede in 1990 in which 1,426 pilgrims were crushed to death in a tunnel. In 1994, 270 pilgrims were killed during a stampede.</p>
<p>Last year Saudi Arabia said three people were killed when a fire swept through the tent camps in Mena. The fire had started when Saudis lit a stove in their tent and spread because of strong wind.</p>
<p>India's Joseph, speaking by telephone from Riyadh, said pilgrims affected by Tuesday's fire were being evacuated from the plain at Mena and moving back towards Mecca.</p>
<p>&quot;People are being evacuated from Mena back to Mecca, which is the only safe place,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some Indian tent camps were burnt. We have no idea if any of our people were hurt,&quot; Joseph said, adding the embassy had been flooded with calls from concerned relatives of pilgrims. Some 80,000 Indians are performing haj this year.</p>
<p>Amin, the Pakistani ambassador, said about 30,000 people were in the Pakistani camp. &quot;There has been extensive damage to about 50,000 tents&quot; across the tent city, he said.</p>
<p>One witness told CNN the smoke turned day into night and there was &quot;mass hysteria&quot; among the pilgrims.</p>
<p>State-run Tehran radio said the fire destroyed a number of Iranian pilgrims' tents, but said there were no casualties among its nationals. Iran has in recent years sent around 60,000 pilgrims to haj.</p>
<p>Witnesses said the fire had slowed down the movement of pilgrims from about 100 countries who began leaving Mecca on Tuesday after dawn prayers at the Grand Mosque where they circled Kaaba seven times, the first haj ritual.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia, custodian of Islam's two holiest shrines, has spent $18.6 billion in the last decade on expanding sites in Mecca and surrounding areas.</p>
<p>Saudi officials had said they were doing their best to ensure a safe haj. They have urged the pilgrims to abide by security instructions, especially in usually congested areas.</p>
<p>Cameras installed on main roads, bridges and tunnels monitor pilgrims' movements to ensure that haj proceeds peacefully.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
