<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="509701" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Iran to stage wargame surprise attacks on &quot;enemies&quot;.</title>
<headline>Iran to stage wargame surprise attacks on &quot;enemies&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iranian forces will stage amphibious wargames in the Gulf next week to train for surprise attacks against &quot;enemies&quot; posing threats to the Islamic republic, Iran's official news agency IRNA said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It quoted Revolutionary Guards Commander General Mohsen Rezaei as saying 200,000 troops and volunteer Bassij forces would take part in the manoeuvres code-named &quot;Tariq-ol Qods&quot; (Road to Jerusalem). He did not say when exactly the wargames would start.</p>
<p>Stretching from the northern Gulf to the Gulf of Oman, the wargames will test the defensive tactics and the ability of the forces to &quot;catch enemies by surprise in the event of potential threats to Iran&quot;, Rezaei said.</p>
<p>Iran regularly holds wargames in the Gulf. Tehran has rejected Western media reports that it was linked to a bombing in Saudi Arabia in June which killed 19 U.S. airmen and some Iranian officials have said the reports indicated that Washington was preparing to attack Iran.</p>
<p>Rezaei last year warned Israel and the United States against aggressive moves, saying Iran would retaliate strongly throughout the Gulf.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
