<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="509764" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Buoyant call market helps Sprint, GTE and Ameritech.</title>
<headline>Buoyant call market helps Sprint, GTE and Ameritech.</headline>
<byline>Nick Louth</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Major telecommunications companies Sprint Corp., GTE Corp. and Ameritech Corp. reported strong first quarter earnings Tuesday, citing gains in revenues from local, long distance and wireless services.</p>
<p>Kansas City, Mo.-based Sprint Corp., the nation's No.3 long distance carrier, said higher-than-expected first-quarter earnings were aided by an 8.5 percent rise in long distance revenues and a 6 percent rise in local phone revenues.</p>
<p>It also cited a 14.5 percent increase in use of its long distance network, and lower-than-expected costs so far for setting up its new wireless network.</p>
<p>The company reported first quarter net earnings of $290 million, or 67 cents per share, on revenues of $3.62 billion. A year earlier Sprint earned $309.3 million, or 77 cents a share, on revenues of $3.37 billion.</p>
<p>While lower than last year's first quarter, the earnings beat Wall Street expectations of 63 cents a share, according to First Call, which tracks such estimates.</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to believe double-digit volume, revenue and operating income growth for the full year are achievable (in the long distance market),&quot; Art Krause, Sprint's chief financial officer, told a conference call.</p>
<p>Analysts say the company has done well to weather the ferocious competition raging through the long distance market, in which GTE is already competing and the so-called Baby Bell regional telephone companies are soon expected to enter.</p>
<p>Krause said this year Sprint would package together wireless and local calling with its long distance services to make the services more attractive to both new and old customers.</p>
<p>Sprint reported a 35 percent surge in revenue from wholesale traffic -- carrying traffic for other carriers.</p>
<p>&quot;Sprint's long distance business is growing the fastest of the big three,&quot; said industry analyst Bette Massick of brokers Bear Stearns. AT&amp;T Corp. and MCI Communications Corp. are respectively the largest and second largest in the industry.</p>
<p>Sprint stock rose 62.5 cents to $44.375 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Stamford, Conn.-based GTE Corp. reported a 9 percent rise in first quarter profits, thanks to stronger sales of both wireline and wireless services.</p>
<p>The company, the only large phone company so far able to offer both local and long distance calling, earned $665 million, or 69 cents a share, on revenues of $5.28 billion.</p>
<p>A year ago it earned $608 million, or 62 cents a share, on revenues of $4.95 billion.</p>
<p>GTE's income slightly exceeded Wall Street expectations.</p>
<p>Domestic cellular-service revenues rose 11 percent from a year ago. At the end of March 1997, GTE had 4 million domestic cellular customers, an increase of 30 percent from a year ago, and 1 million long distance customers from nil a year ago.</p>
<p>International network revenue climbed 10 percent, including more than 40 percent growth in cellular customers in Canada and the Dominican Republic, GTE said.</p>
<p>It said first quarter sales of new and expanded services, such as voice messaging, data services, long distance, Caller ID and Internet access, grew 58 percent.</p>
<p>GTE stock rose 50 cents to $43.25 on the NYSE.</p>
<p>Chicago-based Ameritech Corp., a Midwest regional Bell, reported higher first quarter earnings helped by a 50 percent increase in paging customers to 1.2 million and a 26 percent rise in sales of call management services such as Caller ID, call waiting and voice messaging.</p>
<p>Ameritech's international businesses contributed more than one-fourth of the company's earnings growth, the company said, with international investments including Belgacom SA of Belgium, MATAV of Hungary, Telecom Corp of New Zealand, NetCom of Norway and an alliance in China.</p>
<p>Ameritech earnings rose to $536 million, or 97 cents a share, from $478 million, or 86 cents a share, a year ago. Revenues rose to $3.86 billion from $3.57 billion a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Driven by strong customer demand, new services and entry into new markets,  Ameritech is entering an era of greatly expanded opportunity,&quot; Chairman Richard Notebaert said in a statement. Ameritech stock gained $1.375 to $58.125 on the New York Stock Exchange in mid afternoon trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
