<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="510089" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Consumer prices edge up modestly in March.</title>
<headline>Consumer prices edge up modestly in March.</headline>
<byline>Alver Carlson</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The economy continued to move steadily ahead without inflationary pressures, according to government data released Tuesday, easing fears of a big Federal Reserve interest rate hike and sending stock and bond markets sharply higher.</p>
<p>Analysts said an unexpectedly modest increase in the Consumer Price Index, coupled with a small increase in inventories held by business, should take the pressure off the Fed, although a slight increase in interest rates still seems to be in the cards.</p>
<p>There had been concerns that price pressures from wage gains in a strong economy with low unemployment were on the verge of breaking out and that the Fed, which inched rates up last month, would clamp down hard to stem the pressure.</p>
<p>&quot;The CPI report indicates that inflation continues to be very well contained despite continued pressure in the labour market and stronger-than-expected first-quarter growth,&quot; said Donaldson, Lufkin and Jenrette brokerage economist Elliott Platt.</p>
<p>He said, however, that despite the favourable performance of consumer prices so far this year, a raise in interest rates by the Fed when its policy-makers next meet on May 20 should still be anticipated.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, Wall Street seemed delighted, and stock and bond markets rallied.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average was up 99.14 points, or 1.54 percent, at 6,551.04 in early afternoon trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The bellwether 30-year Treasury bond was up more than a full point, sending its yield down to 7.08 percent from Monday's close of 7.17 percent. Bonds' prices and yields move in opposite directions.</p>
<p>The Labour Department reported the CPI rose 0.1 percent in March after being up 0.3 percent in February.</p>
<p>Excluding the often-volatile food and energy sector, the so-called core rate that economists believe more closely follows underlying inflation trends rose 0.2 percent after being up the same amount in February.</p>
<p>The March data was better than Wall Street estimates that the overall index would rise 0.2 percent and the underlying or core rate would increase 0.3 percent.</p>
<p>At the same time, the Commerce Department said inventories held by businesses grew slightly in February, although sales were the strongest in nearly a year.</p>
<p>Total business inventories rose 0.3 percent to a seasonally adjusted $1.02 trillion after a revised 0.4 percent rise in January, the department said. Sales increased strongly by 1.4 percent to $746.27 billion after a 1.2 percent January rise.</p>
<p>Department officials said February sales were the strongest for any month since April 1996 when they also increased 1.4 percent.</p>
<p>The inventory-to-sales ratio, which measures how long it would take to deplete stocks at the current sales pace, dropped to a record low of 1.36 months' worth in February from 1.38 months' in January.</p>
<p>&quot;The inventory and business sales data reinforce the view that inventories are lean and that company behaviour related to inventories will contribute to economic growth in 1997,&quot; said KeyCorp bank economist Ken Mayland.</p>
<p>But to many, the main question down the line is whether companies, which appear to be burdened by increasing wage pressure at a time of very tight labour markets, will begin to pass these costs along to their customers.</p>
<p>Even in this area, the news for March seemed to be good. The Labour Department reported average weekly earnings of U.S. workers, after adjusting for inflation and seasonal factors, rose only 0.1 percent in March.</p>
<p>The increase followed a 2.3 percent jump in February average weekly earnings and stemmed from a 0.4 percent increase in average hourly earnings, which was offset by a 0.3 percent decrease in average weekly hours.</p>
<p>The 0.1 percent increase in the CPI also contributed to the slight increase.</p>
<p>In its inflation report, the department said energy prices fell 1.7 percent after rising 0.3 percent in February, while food prices were unchanged after being up 0.3 percent in February. Gasoline was off 2.1 percent.</p>
<p>The new data on inflation comes after last week's report showing that while wholesale prices fell in March, they moved disturbingly higher at the underlying level.</p>
<p>One big culprit in the rise in underlying consumer prices was airline fares, which rose 4.5 percent, in part because of the reimposition of the 10 percent airline fare tax.</p>
<p>Apparel costs, which rose 0.2 percent in February, fell 0.3 percent, while transportation costs edged up 0.1 percent after falling 0.1 percent in February.</p>
<p>Entertainment costs matched a 0.2 percent rise in February, while housing prices were unchanged after rising 0.3 percent in February.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
