<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="510215" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALTA: EU tries to stage Arafat-Levy meeting in Malta.</title>
<headline>EU tries to stage Arafat-Levy meeting in Malta.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>VALLETTA 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union on Tuesday tried to persuade Palestinian President Yasser Arafat and Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy to meet after both sides blamed the other for the breakdown in the Middle East peace process.</p>
<p>The EU's 15 foreign ministers -- gathered for a European-Mediterranean conference here -- held separate meetings with Arafat and Levy in an attempt to  bring them together.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea is to try to arrange that a bilateral meeting will take place,&quot; said Josep Coll i Carbo, spokesman for European Commission vice-president Manuel Marin.</p>
<p>Arafat and Levy briefly shook hands during a reception hosted by Maltese Prime Minister Alfred Sant. It was the highest level contact since the Israeli government decided to press ahead with a Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem last month, sparking Palestinian protests and the latest crisis.</p>
<p>Palestinian Planning Minister Nabil Shaath earlier said he would meet Levy but no time had been fixed.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a meeting but not with (Palestinian President Yasser) Arafat,&quot; Shaath told Reuters. Asked if he himself would be meeting Levy, he said: &quot;Yes.&quot;</p>
<p>The gap between the two sides was apparent as Arafat and Levy adressed the conference.</p>
<p>&quot;With the current Israeli government we have faced many obstacles and impediments,&quot; Arafat said. &quot;Instead of continuing to build and reinforce fruitful cooperation and mutual respect ... the Israeli government continues its settlement policy.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been running around in closed circles without reaching any kind of positive agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>In response, Levy appealed for ... &quot;the Palestinian Authority to broadcast, to publicise an unequivocably clear message against terrorism, refuting terrorism, returning to the dialogue, making the peace objective a common goal&quot;</p>
<p>Despite the efforts of the European Commission to promote the Malta conference as a showcase for EU-Mediterranean cooperation, the Middle East crisis dominated the opening session.</p>
<p>In recognition of the gravity of the crisis, Dutch Foreign Minister Hans van Mierlo -- the conference chairman -- agreed to give double speaking time to Levy, Arafat and Algeria, coordinator of the Arab group.</p>
<p>With other ministers overstepping their alloted time, the meeting adjourned at 1615 GMT with nine delegations still to be heard. It will resume on Wednesday morning.</p>
<p>EU efforts to bring about a breakthrough in the Middle East are being matched by the U.S..</p>
<p>On Monday, U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright despatched envoy Dennis Ross back to the region for talks with Arafat and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>
<p>Senior Arab officials met earlier on Tuesday and Algerian Foreign Minister Ahmed Attaf said they wanted a reference to the Middle East stalemate in the final statement, but EU officials said they would try avoid this.</p>
<p>&quot;I think when you try to assess the situation in the Mediterranean region and talk about political dialogue and security in this region you cannot avoid talking about the peace process in the Middle East because it is a major threat to the security and stability of the region,&quot; Attaf told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We want the final declaration to make a reference to this situation and express a position regarding the stalemate the peace process is facing.&quot;</p>
<p>Other controversies, bracketed in a recent draft of the final statement, are over human rights, recognition of NGOs (non-governmental organisations) and the rights of emigrants -- mainly a reference to foreigners working in Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALTA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALLETTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALTA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
