<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="510319" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Peseta debt/interbank market closing report.</title>
<headline>Peseta debt/interbank market closing report.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>After a very cool reaction to the new 25 basis points fresh rate cut, Spanish government bonds climbed on Tuesday afternoon pulled higher by foreign markets.</p>
<p>But at the end of the day bonos underperformed Bunds, with the 10-year spread widening a bit, toward 100 basis points.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is still very strong. I'm thinking it's only a bit more cautious than others. Tomorrow I'm expecting it to at least maintain today's gains,&quot; a dealer in Madrid said.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday. the Bank of Spain sanctioned its third rate cut of the year. &quot;That's discounted. Maybe some people were disappointed because it could have done more,&quot; a dealer added.  </p>
<p>&quot;Fundamentals are doing fine. The risk here is to suffer by other markets' movements,&quot; a dealer in Madrid said.</p>
<p>After the rate cut, Spain's yield curve flattened, with the two- to ten-year spread tightening to around 129 basis points from 136 bps before the rate decision.</p>
<p>But dealers expect that the market could soon resume a rising trend on expectations of other official rate cuts.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the one-year bill yields are expected to fall sharply at an auction to around 5.30 percent from 5.59 percent at the previous sale on April 2, dealers added.</p>
<p>-- Madrid Newsroom, + 341 585 8340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
