<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="510340" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Fincantieri assembles first ship for Disney.</title>
<headline>Fincantieri assembles first ship for Disney.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian state-controlled shipbuilder Fincantieri said it has completed the assembly of the two fore and aft sections of the cruise ship &quot;Disney Magic&quot;, for Walt Disney Co's Disney Cruise Line.</p>
<p>The ship is the first of two 85,000 gross tonnes, 2,400 passenger capacity sister ships Fincantieri is building for Disney which is entering the cruise industry for the first time.</p>
<p>The &quot;Disney Magic&quot; and the &quot;Disney Wonder&quot; are due to be handed over at the start and at the end of 1998 respectively.</p>
<p>Cruise industry experts estimate that Disney spent more than $300 million to build each ship.</p>
<p>Fincantieri said in a statement that the two sections of the &quot;Disney Magic&quot; were built separately at its Venice Marghera and Ancona shipyards and then welded together at Marghera where fitting-out will be completed.</p>
<p>&quot;This was an exceptional ship's surgical operation that has never been accomplished with another cruise vessel,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The &quot;Disney Magic&quot; construction confirms Fincantieri's leading role among the few world shipyards capable of building large cruise ships, with a market share of over 40 percent in terms of gross tonnage.</p>
<p>Fincantieri said that since the mid-1980s it has won contracts on the world market for 21 cruise vessels -- 10 of which have already been handed over - for an aggregate value of over 11 trillion lire ($6.5 billion).</p>
<p>Its orderbook for the remaining 11 vessels to be built currently totals over 6.5 trillion lire.</p>
<p>Fincantieri made a 1996 group net profit of 50.3 billion lire against 25.2 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>On Saturday April 19, it is due to officially hand over the &quot;Dawn Princess&quot; to Peninsular and Oriental's Princess Cruises at its Monfalcone shipyard near Trieste. The &quot;Dawn Princess&quot; is a sister of the 77,000 tonne &quot;Sun Princess&quot; which was delivered in November 1995.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129589</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
