<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="510411" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian stocks ignore bank policy, up on budget hopes.</title>
<headline>Indian stocks ignore bank policy, up on budget hopes.</headline>
<byline>Priya Ramani</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian stock markets on Tuesday shrugged off a central bank credit policy designed to lower interest rates as investors focused on efforts to form a new government and pass a pro-growth budget, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;We consider it mildly favourable for the stock market,&quot; Paribas Capital Markets' strategist Rupa Bose said of the policy for the first half of 1997/98 (April-March).</p>
<p>Bose said the slack season credit policy was unlikely to have an immediate effect on equities.</p>
<p>Reserve Bank of India (RBI) governor Chakravarty Rangarajan told Reuters Television that capital markets would be boosted by the policy announcements that allowed banks to buy more company shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Certain stipulations on bank lending against shares and investments in shares have been modified. All this will mean a boost to the capital market,&quot; Rangarajan said in an interview.</p>
<p>Bombay's benchmark index was steady after the announcements and closed 57.72 points, or 1.61 percent, higher at 3647.44.</p>
<p>Traders said news of a likely resolution to the ongoing political crisis remained uppermost in investors' minds, and that the RBI measures were largely anticipated.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is up on hopes of an early end to political instability,&quot; said Sanat Dalal, a member broker at the Bombay Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>India's United Front coalition, backed by the Congress party's promise of renewed support, was trying to form a new government under a different leader to replace the defeated Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda.</p>
<p>The centre-left government lost a confidence vote last Friday after Congress withdrew its backing and demanded the alliance change its leader as a condition for resuming support.</p>
<p>Traders said the market's key concern was the passage of the pro-business 1997/98 federal budget that has been held hostage by the political turmoil.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a good credit policy but there are no surprises -- positive or negative,&quot; said Sandeep Dixit, banking analyst at Lehman Brothers in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of increasing credit demand from corporates, the policy has built up on what the budget did,&quot; Dixit said.</p>
<p>The federal budget announced on February 28 boosted business confidence by slashing corporate and personal taxes across the board.</p>
<p>&quot;If the budget does not get passed, will we still see a pick-up in demand for credit?&quot; Dixit asked.</p>
<p>Parliament has agreed to take up the budget in a special session next week.</p>
<p>The RBI said in its policy for the first six months of 1997/98 (April-March) that banks -- which previously invested in bonds, shares, debentures and preference shares -- must now invest this money entirely in ordinary shares.</p>
<p>Banks could lend this money to companies against shares as the firms waited for capital to be raised through a public issue, RBI said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;I think interest rates will come down, because the steps taken in this policy will lead to an increase in the lendable resources of banks,&quot; Rangarajan told Reuters Television.</p>
<p>Soon after he spoke state-run Corporation Bank said it planned to cut is prime lending rate to 14.0 percent from 14.5 percent.</p>
<p>--Bombay Newsroom, 265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
