<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="510402" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Moslem rebels appeal for Kashmir hostages' release.</title>
<headline>Moslem rebels appeal for Kashmir hostages' release.</headline>
<byline>Sheikh Mushtaq</byline>
<dateline>SRINAGAR, India 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moslem militants linked by India to the kidnapping of four Western tourists in Kashmir appealed on Tuesday for the hostages' safe return.</p>
<p>&quot;We appeal to the hostage-takers to release the innocent foreign tourists on humanitarian grounds,&quot; the Harkat-ul-Ansar group said in a statement, triggering fresh speculation about the abductions, which occurred nearly two years ago.</p>
<p>Indian officials say the Harkat is close to the shadowy Al-Faran guerrilla group that has claimed responsibility for the abductions. Both have denied any links with each other.</p>
<p>&quot;Indian intelligence agencies are trying to malign Harkat-ul-Ansar and are implicating us in kidnapping cases,&quot; the group's statement in Urdu said.</p>
<p>&quot;We sympathise with the families of the hostages who continue to be in mental trauma for the last two years. They have been coming from far off places repeatedly to Kashmir, appealing to the kidnappers to release their dear ones,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Britons Keith Mangan and Paul Wells, and four other Western tourists were abducted in July 1995. An American escaped and a Norwegian, Hans Christian Ostroe, was found beheaded in August 1995.</p>
<p>Authorities have detected no trace of Mangan, Wells, American Donald Hutchings or German Dirk Hasert for months.</p>
<p>On Monday, the families of the two Britons appealed for news, good or bad, of their whereabouts.</p>
<p>&quot;For over 21 months, we have been kept in an agonising situation, not knowing the truth. We want the truth, be it good or bad,&quot; said Bob Wells, father of hostage Paul Wells.</p>
<p>&quot;Any information, old or new, will help ease our pain,&quot; he said. &quot;We hope they are alive, but nobody has any certain information. We only wish for our loved ones to be returned to us.&quot;</p>
<p>Bob Wells was accompanied by Paul's girlfriend Catherine Moseley, Mangan's wife Julie and a cousin of hers who is heading a campaign in Britain to free the hostages.</p>
<p>The four Britons plan to spend the next three weeks meeting officials in India, travelling through Kashmir and on to Pakistan to appeal to the people for news about their loved ones, Mangan said.</p>
<p>India controls two-thirds of Kashmir and Pakistan the rest.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SRINAGAR, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
