<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="510661" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GTE Q1 shows solid growth across businesses. [CORRECTED 14:35 GMT]</title>
<headline>GTE Q1 shows solid growth across businesses. [CORRECTED 14:35 GMT]</headline>
<text>
<p>STAMFORD, Conn. - GTE Corp's first quarter net earnings of $0.69 per share beat the Wall Street consensus expectation by $0.01 a share, as the company demonstrated its continued capacity to charge ahead on all cylinders.</p>
<p>GTE said the number of domestic access lines grew 1.5 milion, or 8 percent, to 20.3 million in the first quarter versus a year ago. Total minutes of use in its domestic network rose about 14 percent to 19.8 billion (Corrects from million).</p>
<p>It reported earnings of $0.62 in the first quarter a year ago. The latest quarter's consolidated revenues and sales rose 7 percent to $5.28 billion versus $4.95 billion a year ago.  </p>
<p>GTE Chairman and Chief Executive Charles R. Lee (Corrects to add middle initial and surname) said the results reflected strong volume increases and underscored the strength of core operations, both domestic and international.</p>
<p>&quot;GTE just continues to execute beautifully,&quot; agreed Montgomery Securities analyst Bill Vogel, who reiterated his buy rating on the stock Tuesday.</p>
<p>Domestic cellular-service revenues rose to $617 million in the first quarter, up 11 percent from a year ago. At the end of March 1997, GTE had 4 million domestic cellular customers, an increase of 900,000 or 30 percent, from the prior year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
