<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="510649" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - TI CFO sees margins rising.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - TI CFO sees margins rising.</headline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Texas Instruments Inc has run up gains in operating profit margins in recent months and expects to improve further as it focuses on its young differentiated semiconductor businesses, Chief Financial Officer Bill Aylesworth said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our objective is to continue to improve our operating profit margin and we think that is possible, certainly when it led by the good performance that we are getting from our digital signal processing area,&quot; Aylesworth told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Aylesworth said TI's overall operating profit margin improved in the first quarter to 10.0 percent, up from 5.5 percent in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>&quot;When our operating profit margin was only 5.5 percent, we certainly didn't think that was satisfactory. At 10 percent that's better, but we want to continue to improve that from there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Aylesworth said the improvement to date was largely due to strong margins from digital signal processors (DSPs), which translate sounds and sights into digital computer language and are the focus of TI's growth plans.  </p>
<p>Aylesworth said the DSP business would grow at around 35 percent this year and has already seen its margins rise from the low-teens into the mid-teens.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to drive margins there into the high-teens and towards the 20 percent area,&quot; he said. &quot;As that happens, then our overall margin certainly has the potential over a period of time to increase several percentage points more.&quot;</p>
<p>TI earlier reported first quarter net earnings of $129 million, or $0.66 per share, down from $163 million, or $0.84 per share, in the same period last year. But earnings per share from continuing operations rose to to $0.70 from $0.68.  </p>
<p>The company said rapid growth in its DSP and mixed-signal/analog products had compensated for the sharp drop in common memory chip prices throughout 1996.</p>
<p>Aylesworth said prices for dynamic random access memory (DRAM) chips had improved in recent weeks. As an example, he said spot prices for 16-megabyte DRAMS were below $6 in January but have since risen to between $9 and $10.</p>
<p>He said demand for DRAMs continued to grow at around 75 percent per year but that prices would depend on whether a global excess of supply could be corrected.</p>
<p>Aylesworth said the uptick in pricing suggested a recent improvement in supply conditions but that it was still premature to call it a lasting trend.</p>
<p>Even with the recent improvement, DRAM prices are still sharply lower than this time last year. Prices for 16-megabyte DRAMS ended 1995 at around $40 and stood at around $20 at the end of the first quarter last year.</p>
<p>Aylesworth said TI's DRAM division was till losing money but its performance in the first quarter was better than in the fourth quarter of last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
