<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="510779" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: FOCUS - Bank of Spain cuts rate, has room to cut more.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Bank of Spain cuts rate, has room to cut more.</headline>
<byline>Sharman Esarey</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Spain sanctioned an expected reduction in its key money market rate on Tuesday, and further rate cuts could be prompted by the nation's progress on economic requirements to join the European single currency.</p>
<p>The central bank lowered the rate to 5.50 percent from 5.75 percent at its regular repurchase auction, just one month after its last cut. Already this year the Bank of Spain has reduced the rate three times, paring it by 75 basis points.</p>
<p>Economy Minister Rodrigo Rato said the Bank of Spain would have more scope for rate cuts if the conservative Popular Party government continued to pursue its economic policies.</p>
<p>&quot;If the government reduces pressure on the public deficit, as it is doing, liberalises markets and instill confidence in consumers as well as in investors, then there is scope for rate cuts...as we had this morning,&quot; Rato told journalists.</p>
<p>The conservatives, which took over the goverment last spring after 13 years of Socialist rule, have made participation in the single currency launch the cornerstone of their economic policy and now meet three of the five requirments.</p>
<p>In a Reuter poll of 11 economists conducted on Monday, 10 of those surveyed predicted the interest rate reduction. Nine opted for a decline of 25 basis points, and one for a larger cut of 50 basis points, based largely on sharp improvement in inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;This rate cut was necessary, expected and coherent with the recent behaviour of markets,&quot; said Antonio Garcia Rebollar, a director of Renta 4 brokerage.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect new and substantial rate cuts with a view to the development of (inflation), although they will be linked to market stability, fundamentally with the exchange rate of the peseta and with long-term 10-year interest rates,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>This year's marked moderation in inflation, once a major economic handicap that was seen keeping Spain from its aspirations to join the euro launch in 1999, was seen as the main factor behind the Bank of Spain's decision.</p>
<p>In March data released last week inflation fell to its lowest level in 29 years at 2.2 percent on the year, after 2.5 percent in February and 2.9 percent in January.</p>
<p>Spain had met the single currency criteria for inflation with the February fall. Under the terms of the Maastricht Treaty, inflation must not exceed the average inflation rate of the three best performers by more than 1.5 percentage points.</p>
<p>Spain also meets criteria on long-term interest rates and on the peseta, which weathered the rate cut stoically and should continue steadily between 84.00 and 84.55, analysts say.</p>
<p>Last month the peseta got through the two-year anniversary of its last devaluation, on March 8, 1995, thereby meeting another Maastricht criterion.</p>
<p>Spain must still meet two of the five criteria. It has pledged to reduce its deficit to three percent of gross domestic product as required. Its debt levels are set to fall although they will not meet the 60 percent reference value.</p>
<p>&quot;Further (interest rate) moves will depend on the domestic inflation trend and the euro mood. If these two things go in the right direction we'll have more cuts, small ones, during the year,&quot; said Valentin Fernandez, economist at Credit Lyonnais in Madrid.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
