<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="510765" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel March CPI higher-than-expected 1.0 percent.</title>
<headline>Israel March CPI higher-than-expected 1.0 percent.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV, Israel 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's consumer price index rose by a higher than expected 1.0 percent in March, the government said Tuesday, and analysts said the report reduced chances of an interest rate cut by the central bank.</p>
<p>Private sector economists had forecast a rise of about 0.7 percent.</p>
<p>The March increase, following a 1.2 percent rise in February, equalled the March 1996 figure and brought inflation in the past 12 months to 10.4 percent.</p>
<p>The government has set a 1997 inflation target of 7 to 10 percent, against inflation of 10.6 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Israel's financial markets had hoped a low CPI in March would prompt the Bank of Israel to reduce interest rates at the end of the month. The Treasury and the business sector have called on the bank to lower rates to boost the ailing economy.</p>
<p>But Bank of Israel Governor Jacob Frenkel is unlikely to ease monetary policy as long as inflation levels remain high.</p>
<p>&quot;The figure is very disappointing and it is clear that the Bank of Israel will not lower its key lending rate in the near future. It might even decide to raise rates,&quot; said Doron Tsur, head of research at Sahar Securities.</p>
<p>The base rate currently stands at an annualized 13.9 percent.</p>
<p>The Central Statistics Bureau, which announced the March figure, attributed the rise to higher prices for fruit and vegetables, education and housing. The latter, influenced by a higher dollar, rose by a steep 1.3 percent in March.</p>
<p>The CPI data was announced after the close of trading on the Tel Aviv stock market. Traders said they expected share prices to decline on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The April CPI is also expected to be relatively high because of seasonal changes and the decline of the shekel against the dollar,&quot; Tsur said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E71">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV, Israel"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
