<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51097" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan gas oil desulphurisers on line.</title>
<headline>Japan gas oil desulphurisers on line.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two Japanese oil firms brought advanced gas oil desulphurisation units on line on Wednesday to meet a stringent standard on sulphur content in gas oil to be introduced next year, company spokesmen said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Japan Energy Corp started commercial operation of a 27,000 barrel-per-day (bpd) gas oil desulphuriser at its 95,000 bpd Chita plant in Central Japan</p>
<p>Construction of the facility cost 5.5 billion yen.</p>
<p>The other refiner, Kashima Oil Co Ltd, brought its 35,000 bpd gas oil desulphurisation facility, which cost 6.6 billion yen, on stream at its 180,000 bpd Kashima plant in eastern Japan.</p>
<p>The new units are capable of cutting sulphur content in gas oil to below 0.05 percent, they said.</p>
<p>A similar desulphurisation unit with a capacity of 40,000 bpd is scheduled to start commercial operations at Japan Energy's 200,200 bpd Mizushima plant in western Japan as early as late November.</p>
<p>The government plans to lower the maximum allowable sulphur content in gas oil to 0.05 percent in October 1997 from the current 0.2 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
