<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="511030" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Alleged victims testify at Army scandal rape trial.</title>
<headline>Alleged victims testify at Army scandal rape trial.</headline>
<byline>Charles Cohen</byline>
<dateline>ABERDEEN, Md. 1997-04-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The first two alleged victims to testify at the court-martial of Staff Sgt. Delmar Simpson said Monday he used rank, shock and his imposing six-foot build to overpower and rape female trainees.</p>
<p>The prosecution witnesses, who have not been publicly named, said they were intimidated and isolated by Simpson, the subject of the highest-profile case in a growing Army sex scandal in which 11 other drill sergeants have also been charged.</p>
<p>The first woman testified that after the alleged rape, Simpson said he would see her later in the week. The other, who was on military sick leave in her quarters, said that Simpson suddenly opened the door, looked in, and then left.</p>
<p>&quot;It scared me. I didn't know what he was going to do,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The first trainee also said she had consensual sex with two other drill sergeants. It is against Army regulations for a drill sergeant to have sex with a trainee.</p>
<p>The second woman described a rumour that Simpson and another sergeant were running a tally on how many women they could have sex with.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't want to be on his list either,&quot; she said, claiming Simpson called her to his office for being out of bed after hours. She said she heard Simpson and another drill sergeant &quot;had a thing going to see who could get more women.&quot;</p>
<p>The Washington Post reported in Tuesday editions that some drill sergeants at Aberdeen kept lists of female trainees they had sex with, passed the names among themselves and, in one case, allegedly used the information to blackmail a woman.</p>
<p>Drill sergeants and trainees referred to the practice as &quot;the game&quot;, according to a sworn statement of a witness and to an Army official, the newspaper reported.</p>
<p>In the harshest testimony so far, the second woman said Simpson forced her onto a sofa and raped her when she tried to complain about how he was picking on her.</p>
<p>&quot;When he laid me down, I asked him to stop. I begged him to stop and that's when he put his hand over my mouth,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>A third woman trainee testified she was a victim of an unsolicited kiss by Simpson and described a climate of sexual promiscuity among Army drill sergeants.</p>
<p>&quot;After the first two weeks there were rumours going around about people having sex with drill sergeants, about persons sneaking around with this person and this person is fine,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>During the cross examination of the first alleged rape victim, defence attorney Frank Spinner asked if she was certain of her story, warning the woman she could face charges if her story was different than her sworn statement.</p>
<p>The NAACP and the Congressional Black Caucus have criticised that investigators used coersion in taking statements from the alleged rape victims.</p>
<p>Simpson, 32, faces 19 counts of rape and 39 other charges including indecent exposure, battery and maltreatment involving 13 women. He has pleaded innocent to the charges but earlier pleaded guilty to 11 counts of improper sexual intercourse with trainees and five counts of propositioning.</p>
<p>The alleged acts occurred in 1995 and 1996, while Simpson was a drill instructor at the Ordnance Centre and School at the Aberdeen Proving Ground, overseeing classes of five to 45 soldiers receiving advanced instruction after basic training.</p>
<p>Simpson's attorneys have said their client engaged only in consensual sex. &quot;A number of female soldiers in training were attracted to and willingly engaged in sexual intercourse with Staff Sgt. Delmar Simpson,&quot; defence attorney Capt. Edward Brady said in his opening statement last week.</p>
<p>Brady said Army investigators used excessive zeal in interviewing witnesses. &quot;Their own witnesses will tell you that (investigators) actively encouraged them to embellish their statements ... to 'make it jucier,'&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABERDEEN, Md."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
