<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="511029" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Intel stock could fall, despite doubled earnings.</title>
<headline>Intel stock could fall, despite doubled earnings.</headline>
<byline>Kourosh Karimhany</byline>
<dateline>SANTA CLARA, Calif. 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Intel Corp.'s stock may face new selling pressure on Tuesday after the company warned revenues for the second quarter may be flat to only slightly higher than the first quarter.</p>
<p>Intel, the world's biggest computer chipmaker, reported on Monday that its first-quarter net income more than doubled, handily beating most Wall Street earnings forecasts.</p>
<p>However, industry analysts said the better-than-expected performance was quickly overshadowed by the company's projection that revenues for the three months ending in June may be flat to only slightly higher than the $6.45 billion in revenues reported in the first quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a solid quarter, showing Intel's dominance,&quot; said Peter Andrew, analyst at investment bank AG Edwards &amp; Sons Inc. in St. Louis. &quot;But the flat revenue projection could upset some people.&quot;</p>
<p>Indeed, late Monday, after the earnings announcement, shares of Intel traded as low as $129.25 in after-hour trading, down sharply from the Nasdaq close of $133.75.</p>
<p>Intel's first-quarter net income jumped to $1.98 billion, or $2.20 a share, from $849 million, or $1.02 a share, in the same quarter a year ago. Revenue jumped 39 percent to $6.45 billion.</p>
<p>The first quarter profit easily topped Wall Street's consensus estimate of $2.07 a share. But, some analysts said Intel's earnings were not as strong as they looked, noting about 5 cents of the quarterly profit came from non-recurring revenue and another 5 cents came from lower-than-usual expenses.</p>
<p>Subtracting the 10 cents from the reported per share figure, Intel's profit would have been only $2.10 -- not much better than analysts' &quot;whisper&quot; or unpublished estimates.</p>
<p>For Intel, which has consistently exceeded Wall Street expectations by a wide margin, a quarter in which it only narrowly beats the so-called whisper number could give investors the jitters.</p>
<p>&quot;In previous quarters, they blew away the estimates,&quot; said Drew Peck, analyst at Cowen &amp; Co. in Boston.</p>
<p>Analysts said such a move could also weigh on other tech stocks because Intel is widely regarded as a bellwether for the personal computer industry.</p>
<p>In its statement, Intel also warned that gross margins -- the difference between revenues and costs of goods sold -- would likely shrink in coming quarters from the lofty level of 64 percent reported in the first quarter.</p>
<p>Intel said second quarter gross margins are likely to be flat or slightly below 64 percent and for the full year margins are likely to slip to 60 percent &quot;plus or minus a few points&quot;.</p>
<p>Analysts said some of the margin pressure may come from price cuts Intel is planning to announce later this month on its Pentium chips. Last week, some observers speculated Intel may cut chips prices more than expected to fend off competition from rival chipmakers such as Advanced Micro Devices  AMD.  Concerns over the level of price cuts sent shares of Intel down sharply last week.</p>
<p>During a conference call with reporters and analysts Intel executives said the April price cuts would be roughly the same as the previous reductions announced last February. Those reductions ranged from zero up to 34 percent.</p>
<p>Intel said the number of chips it shipped in the first quarter was flat compared with the fourth. That suggested its new line of Pentium microprocessors with souped-up multimedia capabilities did not help to boost personal computer sales, analysts said.</p>
<p>Because Intel supplies the chips for 80 percent of the world's personal computers, Intel's flat sales could mean growth has &quot;plateaued&quot; for the entire industry, Peck said.</p>
<p>Still, Intel is notorious for giving conservative outlooks to Wall Street to keep expectations in line, other analysts said.</p>
<p>International PC sales is booming, which could offset slowing sales in the U.S., said Martin Pyykkonen, analyst at investment bank Furman Selz.</p>
<p>And strong sales of software based on Microsoft Corp.'s Windows NT software standard is boosting demand for Intel's speedy chips, Pyykkonen said.</p>
<p>Analysts also noted Intel is one of the most profitable companies, inside and outside the computer business. The company's net profit of nearly $2 billion came on only $6.45 billion in sales. To put that in perspective, General Motors Corp. -- the biggest U.S. company in terms of revenue -- earned $1.8 billion in the first quarter on revenue of $42.3 billion, meaning that GM earned slightly less than Intel even though the auto giant had nearly seven times more revenue in the quarter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA CLARA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
