<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="511152" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS - German coalition, SPD in last-ditch tax talks.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - German coalition, SPD in last-ditch tax talks.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Busvine</byline>
<text>
<p>BONN, April 15 (Rueter) - German Chancellor Helmut Kohl on Tuesday met leaders of the opposition Social Democrats (SPD) for talks on tax reforms seen by both sides as a last chance to achieve an early deal to boost jobs and investment.</p>
<p>Arriving for the negotiations, SPD leader Oskar Lafontaine said: &quot;We are going into these talks with a will to agree. We want results...Any decision which serves the battle against unemployment will win our support.&quot;</p>
<p>Peter Hintze, general secretary of Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU), said if the talks failed the coalition would seek to push its own tax legislation through the Bundestag lower house of parliament before the summer break.</p>
<p>&quot;The SPD must come clean today, and show whether it will hold to its blockade or participate in this great tax-cutting project to create more jobs in Germany,&quot; Hintze said.</p>
<p>The two sides have very different recipes for reviving weak investment and getting Germany's 4.5 million jobless back to work. Economic revival is seen as vital for lasting compliance to the fiscal rigours of Europe's planned single currency.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel has proposed supply side-style tax cuts which would go hand-in-hand with scrapping over 70 tax breaks seen as distorting the economy and crippling investment. The plan would cut a net 30 billion marks ($17 billion) in tax.</p>
<p>The SPD favours a Keynesian approach, setting a series of conditions -- cutting labour insurance charges, raising child benefits, and boosting tax allowances -- in order to give a boost to domestic demand through a revenue-neutral package.</p>
<p>The SPD has demanded a cut of two percentage points in the labour overheads, while the coalition parties are prepared to offer a one-point cut -- as long as a compromise is struck on the overall tax reform.</p>
<p>A breakthrough on this point would raise hopes for a broader deal, whereas failure could consign the tax reform to parliament's tortuous mediation process. The SPD can block tax measures through its majority in the upper house of parliament.</p>
<p>Guido Westerwelle, general secretary of junior coalition partners the Free Democrats (FDP), said it was vital that real tax cuts come out of the reform to boost investment.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't just want a tax reform, we want a tax-cutting reform,&quot; he said. &quot;Everything else is a placebo.&quot;</p>
<p>The SPD would pay the price for any obstruction tactics at future regional elections to be held in the runup to a general election in autumn 1998, the coalition leaders added.</p>
<p>Although both sides agree broadly on the need to cut the bottom rate of income tax to below 20 percent from 26 now, and to slash the main corporate tax rate to 35 percent from 47, they are far apart on top-rate income tax.</p>
<p>&quot;We are at odds on the question of the top income tax rate,&quot; SPD finance spokeswoman Ingrid Matthaeus-Maier, a member of the six-strong SPD negotiating team, told DeutschlandRadio Berlin earlier.</p>
<p>Bonn has proposed cutting the top income tax rate to 39 percent from 53 percent, and the entry rate to 15 percent from 26 percent. It wants to tax income above 13,000 marks for single wage-earners.</p>
<p>The SPD wants a smaller drop in the top tax rate and the tax-free threshold set at 14,000 marks.</p>
<p>($ = 1.730 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
