<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51121" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: ASEAN says U.S sanctions violate international law.</title>
<headline>ASEAN says U.S sanctions violate international law.</headline>
<dateline>BATAM, Indonesia 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Members of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) told the United States on Wednesday that its campaign to economically isolate Iran and Libya violated international law.</p>
<p>Izhar Ibrahim, the Indonesian Foreign Ministry's political affairs head, said the seven-member grouping had expressed concern over Washington's sanctions law on the first day of the 13th ASEAN-U.S. Dialogue.</p>
<p>&quot;ASEAN, in general, expressed its concern about the U.S. law,&quot; Ibrahim told reporters. &quot;We believe it does not conform with the principles of international law because it is actually a law of the United States which may have a negative impact on relations between other countries.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. sanctions law, which seeks to punish foreign firms that invest $40 million or more per year in energy projects in Iran or Libya, violated national sovereignty, he added.</p>
<p>Ibrahim said Indonesia, the world's largest Moslem nation and a major oil and gas exporters, was also affected by the law.</p>
<p>&quot;We are a member of OPEC (the Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries) and Iran and Libya are also members of OPEC and we have economic cooperation with these countries,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ibrahim said the U.S. delegation, led by Winston Lord, the assistant secretary of state for east asian and pacific affairs, told senior ASEAN officials at the two-day dialogue that it was not Washington's intention to violate international law.</p>
<p>&quot;(They said) it is their own law intended for their own citizens,&quot; he said, adding the U.S. side had admitted the law did have an impact on the private sectors of other countries.</p>
<p>ASEAN comprises Brunei, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BATAM, Indonesia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
