<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="511466" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT -Gilts range-bound, capped by 109-08.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT -Gilts range-bound, capped by 109-08.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>British gilts will remain trapped in a narrow range on Tuesday, confined by strong resistance at 109-08 on the upside, and support at 108-15, technical analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Gilts will be stuck in a range with possibly a very marginal upside bias,&quot; said Marc Ostwald, technical strategist at London Bond Broking here.</p>
<p>He said the June contract would run into an initial band of resistance at 108-27 to 108-31, an area of old lows.</p>
<p>Charts show the contract hit a daily low of 108-31 on April 9, and one of 108-28 on April 10.  </p>
<p>&quot;That band constitutes an area of severe congestion which the market needs to get through to see any further gains,&quot; said Ostwald.</p>
<p>He said is the contract pushes up through 108-31 it would soon stall at further resistance at 109-08.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd be more surprised to see that level go -- but if it does, it could go to 109-18, the top of the current range.</p>
<p>The June contract hit a daily high of 109-18 on April 9.</p>
<p>Traders on LIFFE were fairly bullish on the June gilt, citing an initial target of 109-08, followed by 109-23.</p>
<p>By 0705 GMT, the June gilt was up 8/32 at 109-03.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market's looking extremely perky -- it met all its targets yesterday, I'm quite bullish,&quot; said one LIFFE trader at a British bank.</p>
<p>Charts show 109-23 is a 38 percent retracement of the move from the March 11 high of 112-09 down to the April 1 low of 108-05.</p>
<p>On the downside, Ostwald said congestion at 108-12 to 108-15 was the first support. The contract hit a daily low of 108-12 on April 4, 108-14 on April 14 and 108-15 on April 7.</p>
<p>If that gives way, the next support comes in at 108-05, the cyclical low on April 1, Ostwald said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Medium term I'm pretty negative on gilts,&quot; said Ostwald. &quot;There's the chance of quite a severe down dip coming up to the election -- after that it could rally.&quot;</p>
<p>By 0717 GMT June short sterling was up two basis points at 93.42.</p>
<p>The LIFFE trader said investors were generally short June short sterling, adding the market would aim for 93.48, 93.50.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been a bit of a change in feeling, people are only going for a quarter point rather than a half point rise in UK rates and the producer price index (on Monday) was a lot better than expected,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
