<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="511476" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - UK Conservatives face struggle in Cornwall.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - UK Conservatives face struggle in Cornwall.</headline>
<byline>David Ljunggren</byline>
<dateline>PENZANCE, England 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The spring sun is shining brightly on Britain's picturesque Cornish Riviera but the political outlook for the ruling Conservatives is gloomy.</p>
<p>It is probable their uninterrupted 46 years hold on the St Ives constituency, on the distant south-western tip of England, will be broken at the general election on May 1.</p>
<p>In many ways, St Ives is a microcosm of the country. People in the constituency's sleepy port of Penzance, 320 miles (500 km) from London, are deeply disillusioned by politicians whom locals say have consistently ignored Cornwall's serious problems.</p>
<p>Voters have turned away from the Conservatives because of their perceived incompetence. They are lukewarm about the Labour Party and look upon May 1 as an opportunity to lodge a protest against the London-centric political establishment.</p>
<p>&quot;We're fed up with politics. No one has the edge. I don't believe the public care at all. They've bored us all to tears,&quot; said local baker Ian Trelawney.</p>
<p>Tourism apart, western Cornwall relies heavily on the fishing and farming industries, two powerful lobbies which the Conservatives and the European Union have managed to alienate in recent years.</p>
<p>LIBERAL DEMOCRATS CONFIDENT IN THE SOUTH-WEST</p>
<p>What promises to be a bitter pre-election battle is made more intriguing by the intervention of anti-European entrepreneur Sir James Goldsmith, whose Referendum Party is threatening to siphon away votes from the Conservatives.</p>
<p>The minority Liberal Democrats are confident they can take the seat as part of a clean sweep of south-western England, where their influence has traditionally been strong.</p>
<p>Local candidate Adrian George, who lost the 1992 election to the Conservatives by just 1,645 votes, is proposing a &quot;Contract with Cornwall&quot; to address the crisis in the region.</p>
<p>Although Cornwall is famed for its unspoiled beaches, cosy summer cottages and spectacular scenery, the postcard images conceal one of the poorest areas in the country.</p>
<p>Local unemployment is as high as 22 percent, almost four times the national average, and many of the jobs which do exist are low-paid and seasonal. Young people in search of decent work tend to move away and often fail to return.</p>
<p>Poor infrastructure means prices are high while what little industry there was in the region has moved away.</p>
<p>&quot;The Conservatives are facing major trouble here. They've forced the issue of Europe onto the agenda but the real issues are health, education and the economy of Cornwall,&quot; said George.</p>
<p>He wants a local university to stem the exodus of young people and is pressing for a Cornish Development Agency to funnel funds into the impoverished region and attract more grants from the European Union.</p>
<p>CONSERVATIVES FIELD UNTRIED CANDIDATE</p>
<p>To make matters worse for the Conservatives, their popular legislator David Harris is stepping down after 14 years to make way for untried insurance broker William Rogers.</p>
<p>&quot;No one's perfect, we all make mistakes, and the government is no different,&quot; Rogers told a meeting of local activists.</p>
<p>&quot;The Conservative party is no different. But on all the crucial decisions the Conservative party has been right.&quot;</p>
<p>But an unofficial Reuter poll failed to find a single local person apart from those at the meeting who vowed to vote Conservative. Many said they had yet to make up their minds.</p>
<p>At the cattle market in nearby Helston, farmers discussed grimly what should be done with hapless Agriculture Minister Douglas Hogg, widely blamed for mishandling a crisis over mad cow disease which helped force down meat prices.</p>
<p>&quot;That bloody Hogg -- you want to put him in his bloody hat and float him down the Thames. He's cost us thousand of pounds,&quot; shouted one cattle man. &quot;I've never seen such a balls-up by the politicians. It makes me sick.&quot;</p>
<p>Fellow farmer Doug Palser was in more relaxed mood but said the Conservatives had no chance in St Ives. &quot;Over the last 18 years they've done well but they've gone to sleep. It's time for a change,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>EU POLICY HAS HIT FISHING INDUSTRY HARD</p>
<p>Another traditional Conservative bulwark is Newlyn, one of England's busiest fishing ports.</p>
<p>But trawlermen complain the government has failed to push through changes to the EU's Common Fisheries Policy, which they say encourages other nations to take British fish stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;At the end, despite all the fine words, nothing is ever done which makes any difference,&quot; said Mike Townsend, head of the Cornish Fish Producers' Association.</p>
<p>It is no coincidence that the local Referendum Party candidate is Mick Faulkner, who has trawled these waters for 17 years and says Newlyn's 3,000 fishermen will vote for him.</p>
<p>All good news for George as he starts canvassing for votes, but his smiles turn to scowls when a minibus equipped with loudspeakers suddenly appears on the same street to campaign noisily for the main opposition Labour party.</p>
<p>&quot;We have Labour campaigning very hard to elect a Conservative. No sane person can figure out why they're doing this,&quot; George said testily, reflecting fears that Labour could split the opposition vote and let the Conservatives back in.</p>
<p>The man inside the bus, Labour candidate Chris Fegan, is surprisingly confident given that he has to gain 15,000 extra votes to stand any charge of winning the seat. But he says Labour, tipped to win the national election, is unstoppable.</p>
<p>&quot;We see Labour's policy of introducing a minimum wage as the answer to Cornwall's problems. There are people working on piece rates on farms and coming away with 10 pounds ($16) at the end of the day,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But the promises of politicians are of little consolation to those who worry that the very future of western Cornwall is at risk unless the government starts taking an interest.</p>
<p>Faulkner walked along the Newlyn quayside, pointing out rusting English trawlers which he said would not be replaced because no one had any faith in the industry.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe this is the last generation of boats which will be fishing here. So what will my 15-year-old son do when he finishes school? He will have to move away like all the rest.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PENZANCE, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
