<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="511546" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ plans market-driven compulsory pension scheme.</title>
<headline>NZ plans market-driven compulsory pension scheme.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand's Treasurer Winston Peters on Tuesday outlined the coalition government's controversial plans for a compulsory national pensions savings scheme and said it would be based on existing market strengths.</p>
<p>In a speech to Wellington's financial community he said, &quot;Savings invested in the scheme should be invested as well as possible,so the aim is to set up a regulatory regime that preserves the competitiveness of a the market-based financial system.&quot;  </p>
<p>Compulsory superannuation, known to most New Zealanders as 'compulsory super', was championed by Peters' nationalist New Zealand First party in last year's election campaign but opposed by National -- now its partner in government.</p>
<p>As part of their coalition agreement NZ First and National decided to put the concept to a postal referendum spread over three weeks this September. The proposals for the design of the preferred scheme should be published in early June.</p>
<p>Peters told his audience of investment management professionals that there ought not to be any need for the government to provide any guarantee for a scheme, saying &quot;the market needs to stand on its own performance&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Investments should provide the best possible financial returns while diversifying against risks. This suggests the best policy for scheme funds would be to allow full freedom to invest in New Zealand or abroad,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>One possible route would be to structure the basic compulsory scheme around a set minimum annuity fund to which the saver would not have access before retirement, Peters added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150214">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
