<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="511506" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian bank mergers possible later - Beerworth.</title>
<headline>Australian bank mergers possible later - Beerworth.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government could lift its restriction on mergers between Australia's four largest banks if it gets a second term, Bill Beerworth, a member of the Wallis Inquiry into Australia's financial system, said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Asked at a seminar when he thought mergers between the big four banks would become possible, Beerworth said, &quot;I think that the government may take another tack over time, perhaps in its second term if it gets a second term.&quot;</p>
<p>The next Federal election is due by early 1999.  </p>
<p>The Wallis report, which was released last Wednesday, recommended the end of the &quot;six pillars&quot; policy which prevented mergers between the big four banks and the nation's two largest insurance firms.</p>
<p>The big four are the National Australia Bank Ltd, Commonwealth Bank of Australia, Westpac Banking Corp and the Australia and New Zealand Banking Group Ltd .</p>
<p>The two large insurance firms are the AMP Society and National Mutual Holdings Ltd.  </p>
<p>In its response to the report the government approved the end of the &quot;six pillars&quot; policy but continued a ban on mergers between the big four banks.</p>
<p>Beerworth said the government's stance that a change in this merger policy was linked to funds becoming available cheaply to small business groups, was a political statement.</p>
<p>&quot;That I think will occur well beyond the beginning of the next century,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Beerworth said he thought the banks needed to become more subtle in their arguments for mergers.  </p>
<p>The &quot;national champion&quot; scenario used by some banks was a hollow argument, Beerworth said.</p>
<p>&quot;That pre-disposes that citizens and clients of banks in this country will cross-subsidise to create world-wide empires for banks. I don't think that is a very useful argument,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Beerworth said the major banks also focused too much on what he called the &quot;headline&quot; savings from closing branches.</p>
<p>&quot;Headline savings aren't very impressive to the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission (ACCC).&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the banks are going to need to be a lot more subtle. They are going to need to do what they are doing in the United States and talk about the efficiency ratio and what would be the changes if an acquisition actually occurred,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Beerworth said that when the banks could persuade the ACCC and the government that efficiency ratios would be lifted then they would have a much better chance of getting approval to merge.</p>
<p>On Sunday, Australian Treasurer Peter Costello said it would be at least a year before the government would permit the big four banks to consider merging with one another.  </p>
<p>Costello said the banking sector would have to become more competitive before such mergers would be approved.</p>
<p>-- Michael Stapleton, Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1811</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
