<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="511867" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey's Ciller backs anti-Islamist crackdown.</title>
<headline>Turkey's Ciller backs anti-Islamist crackdown.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's deputy prime minister, Tansu Ciller, told governors to enforce secularist laws as part of curbs on Islamist activism demanded by the military, Anatolian news agency said.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to personally give you an order to end certain abuses in our country and carefully carry out the laws as dealt with by the National Security Council,&quot; the agency quoted her late on Monday as telling a meeting of dozens of provincial governors.</p>
<p>The military-dominated council in Febuary called on Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan's coalition government to stamp out the growing influence of Islam in public life.</p>
<p>The army's demands have upset the coalition's balance between Islamist Erbakan's wing and secularists of Ciller's True Path Party. Several True Path ministers have publicly criticised the Islamists' reluctance to toe the generals' line.</p>
<p>Ciller told the governors, who have wide security powers, to uphold laws. &quot;I want you...not to forget that fundamentalism is an important problem,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Her warning follows a directive to governors from the interior minister, also from Ciller's party, to enforce anti-Islamist measures.</p>
<p>The army has called for strict adherence to decades-old bans on Islamic sects and the prohibition of government workers wearing Islamic dress.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
