<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="511886" id="root" date="1997-04-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALTA: Israelis, Palestinians to hold talks in Malta.</title>
<headline>Israelis, Palestinians to hold talks in Malta.</headline>
<byline>John Baggaley</byline>
<dateline>VALLETTA 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli and Palestinian ministers will meet in Malta on the sidelines of a European-Mediterranean conference opening on Tuesday to try to end weeks of deadlock in the Middle East peace process.</p>
<p>Palestinian Planning Minister Nabil Shaath said he would meet Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy. No time has been fixed. Levy is arriving on Tuesday for the two-day conference on the Mediterranean island.</p>
<p>It will be the first time Israelis and Palestinians have met at this level since Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu ordered work to start on a Jewish settlement in disputed Arab East Jerusalem a month ago.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a meeting but not with (Palestinian President Yasser) Arafat,&quot; Shaath told Reuters. Asked if he himself would be meeting Levy, he said: &quot;Yes.&quot;</p>
<p>The Europeans at the Malta conference have been pressing for an Israeli-Palestinian meeting in the hope of breaking the deadlock in Middle East peace talks.</p>
<p>Arafat left Cairo early on Tuesday for Malta.</p>
<p>Parallel U.S. efforts to get the peace process back on track after almost daily violence between Palestinians and Israelis were mirrored in an announcement in Washington that special envoy Dennis Ross would return to the Middle East this week.</p>
<p>U.S. officials said Ross would leave Tuesday evening and return by the weekend after talks with Netanyahu and Arafat. Ross is expected to fly to Tel Aviv.</p>
<p>Secretary of State Madeleine Albright, announcing the trip, said the talks would focus &quot;on how to stem violence and what steps they are prepared to take to stop the deterioration and lay the basis for making the peace process work again.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton would then decide &quot;what the United States can and will do to re-establish the credibility of the process&quot;, Albright told reporters.</p>
<p>In the Maltese capital Valletta, senior Arab officials were to meet on Tuesday to plan a joint strategy for the EU-Med conference of 27 ministers opening later in the day.</p>
<p>Planned as a follow-up to the Barcelona 1995 conference, which forged a partnership between 15 EU countries and 12 Mediterranean partners, the Malta meeting has been overshadowed by the Middle East.</p>
<p>Egyptian Foreign Minister Amra Moussa said the Arab group would meet &quot;to discuss and coordinate our policies vis a vis the agenda of the meeting -- relations within the Barcelona process, the economic, political and agriculture sides.&quot;</p>
<p>Diplomats say the Europeans had wanted to keep the crisis in Middle East talks in the background and concentrate on the long- term economic and security relationship between the northern and southern shores of the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>Earlier, a European source told Reuters that work on the draft declaration to be submitted to the ministers had been delayed by concerns on the Middle East.</p>
<p>&quot;The main dispute is over the peace process. The text repeated the Barcelona declaration. The Arabs want to take it further with a reference to Israeli settlements,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked whether the group wanted settlements included in the final communique, Moussa said: &quot;No, not exactly, no. The issue is very important for us but we also want the process to go smoothly but we are going to raise the question definitely. But it's not on the agenda.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the Middle East issue would &quot;end up by a paragraph&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALTA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALLETTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALTA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
