<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="512273" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYCE cotton settles down, new contract lows hit.</title>
<headline>NYCE cotton settles down, new contract lows hit.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYCE cotton futures closed down but above contract lows amid steady shortcovering by the trade, floor sources said.</p>
<p>Spot May finished down 0.88 cent at 70.88 cents a lb after trading from 71.76 to 75.50 cents, a fresh contract low. July went out 0.86 lower at 72.54 cents after hitting a contract low of 72.20.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at 27,500 lots compared with Tuesday's official 14,140 lots.</p>
<p>Aggressive fund and commission house selling pushed the spot month under its previous contract low of 70.90, to a new low of 70.50 cents.</p>
<p>The trade, which was a seller earlier in the week, covered short positions and carried prices off the lows by the close, trading sources said. But additional losses are anticipated, with nearby support seen at 70.00 cents.</p>
<p>Market analysts said burgeoning supplies will continue to weigh on the market in the longer term.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not seeing a lot overnight with export business,&quot; Carl Anderson, a cotton marketing specialist with Texas A &amp; M University, said.</p>
<p>Certificated stocks remained unchanged from the previous session but still high at 221,862 bales, as of Tuesday.</p>
<p>Open interest in May fell 2,542 lots to 25,695 lots as of Monday's close. Open interest in July climbed 1,084 lots to 24,277 lots.</p>
<p>((S Rostler, New York Commodity Desk, 212-859-1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
