<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51238" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: FOCUS - Warsaw outperforms flat Central Euro bourses.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Warsaw outperforms flat Central Euro bourses.</headline>
<byline>Emese Bartha</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Warsaw outperformed other east European bourses this week as prices were slack or weaker on other markets of the region.</p>
<p>The Central European Share Index (CESI), which reflects price movement of 50 selective Hungarian, Czech and Polish stocks, remained practically unchanged.</p>
<p>WARSAW</p>
<p>Polish shares set a 30-month high on Friday and analysts said gains would continue, with players buying before mid-September, when some technical analysts see a rise, and before the release of firms' August earnings next week, expected to be good.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems there's now a preponderance of investors who don't fear a fall,&quot; said Krzysztof Rogalski, an analyst at Bank Staropolski brokerage. On Friday the WIG index closed at 14,296.3 points, up 782.2 points from last Friday's close.</p>
<p>Analysts said a good sign for stocks was that mass privatisation NFI units fell eight percent in lower turnover on Friday, suggesting that the units may be hitting a correction after their surge by 44 percent since late August, with some capital flowing to stocks.</p>
<p>BUDAPEST</p>
<p>Friday's losses chopped off modest gains that Hungarian shares accumulated this week. On Friday the BUX index ended at 3,533.09 points, down 11.06 points from last Friday.</p>
<p>The week brought amendments in trading rules which traders said they still had to adapt to, but in the second half of the week once again the fundamentals took charge.</p>
<p>PRAGUE</p>
<p>An absence of fresh factors and speculative selling in the biggest Czech banking issue Komercni Banka pushed the Prague Stock Exchange's PX50 index slightly lower during the week and dealers saw little chance of a speedy rebound.</p>
<p>The PX50 lost 5.1 points, or 0.88 percent, in the week to Friday while the high cap dominated RPIX index fell five points to 1,159.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the other main markets in the region they are not so active in general and so I expect the Czech market to follow that trend,&quot; said Karel Ruzicka of ING Barings.</p>
<p>Dealers said Komercni's downtrend was unlikely to have been caused by fundamental reasons and said technical factors were probably responsible.</p>
<p>BRATISLAVA</p>
<p>The insignificant trading with most of the Slovak blue chips, losses to shares of financial institutions and lack of fresh factors were behind the Bratislava Stock Exchange's several subsequent drops over this week.</p>
<p>The 12-share SAX index fell during the week to Friday's close at 208.65 points, from Monday's open at 212.56 points.</p>
<p>SOFIA</p>
<p>Three corporate issues traded on the Bulgarian stock market from Monday to Friday with two of them falling due to low investor interest, brokers said.</p>
<p>Only Varna Grand Hotel bucked the trend as it advanced two levs to 85 levs, remaining still below the 100 lev face value.</p>
<p>The 13-share Reuter All Bulgaria Stock Index (RABSI) closed at 41.14 points, up 0.53 from last Friday, propelled by Varna Grand Hotel.</p>
<p>ZAGREB</p>
<p>Croatian stocks traded mixed throughout the week with new upward movements in leading stocks and traders predicted that the market would remain stable for at least another week.</p>
<p>Fully-listed drugs firm Pliva rose 200 kuna to close at 12,200 and Zagrebacka Banka ended the week up at 750 from last Friday's 730 kuna. Confectioner Kras was the week's strongest gainer, adding 40 kuna to a fresh 350-kuna high.</p>
<p>LJUBLJANA</p>
<p>Share prices fell 2.6 percent in Ljubljana this week, which was highlighted by a &quot;black Monday&quot; due to the sharp plunge of financial consultancy Dadas shares.</p>
<p>Dadas plummeted 53.05 percent on Monday on rumours that its brokerage may be banned from trading. That pulled the SBI index down by 5.01 percent to the new all-time low at 893.88 points.</p>
<p>Through the week the SBI index fell 15.32 points to 925.72.</p>
<p>BUCHAREST</p>
<p>Bucharest bourse shares traded in modest volumes this week, as thin investor interest pushed most prices down.</p>
<p>Two independent value-weighted indices on Thursday showed drops from the previous session. The VAB, computed by Vanguard SA securities company, and the BIG, compiled by Bucharest Investment Group SA brokerage house were 5.2 percent down. Their base was 1,000 points last November.</p>
<p>TIRANA</p>
<p>Neither treasury bills nor state bonds changed hands in the four-month-old Tirana Stock Exchange during its weekly sessions on Monday and Thursday.</p>
<p>		CLOSE   WEEK'S CHANGE    1996/HIGH    1996/LOW</p>
<p>		SEPT 12  NET     PCT</p>
<p> CESI     1,516.48    +7.71    +0.51    1,544.70     959.24</p>
<p> WARSAW  14,296.3   +728.2     +5.4    14,296.3    7,725.2</p>
<p> BUDAPEST 3,533.09  - 11.06    -0.31    3,574.65   1,557.91</p>
<p> RABSI	 41.14  +  0.53    +1.31	 55.48	40.61</p>
<p> PRAGUE     573.8   -  5.1     -0.88	582.0	425.9</p>
<p> BRATISLAVA 208.65  -  3.91    -1.87	226.34     150.4</p>
<p> LJUBLJANA  925.72  - 15.32    -2.6     1,589.18     891.93</p>
<p>BUCHAREST</p>
<p> VAB-Index  316.5   -334.0    -10.5	 879.3	297.8</p>
<p> BIG-Index  315.0   -332.6    -10.4	 820.9	294.9</p>
<p>All-time high: WIG 20,760.3 (March 8/1994); BUX 3,574.65 (Sept 2/1996); RABSI 112.2 (April 27/1994); PX50 1,002.4 (April 7/1994); SAX 402.3 (Feb/1994); SBI 1,598.02 (June 28/1994).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
