<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="512442" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: RALLYING-MAKINEN EXTENDS CHAMPIONSHIP LEAD WITH CATALUNYA WIN.</title>
<headline>RALLYING-MAKINEN EXTENDS CHAMPIONSHIP LEAD WITH CATALUNYA WIN.</headline>
<dateline>LLORET DE MAR, Spain 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Defending world champion Tommi Makinen stretched his lead in this year's title race with victory in the Catalunya Rally on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Finland's Makinen, driving a Mitsubishi, finished  seven seconds ahead of Italian Piero Liatti in his Subaru for his second consecutive win, following his success in the Rally of Portugal three weeks ago.</p>
<p>Makinen had started the final leg of the rally sharing the lead with Liatti. Over the first three stages of the day he built up a 10-second advantage over his rival.</p>
<p>But on the penultimate stage, the 17th, Liatti set the fastest time to bring the gap down to four seconds and set up a thrilling final stage, which Makinen completed three seconds faster.</p>
<p>Such a close finish is rare in world rallying, though last year's Catalunya Rally saw winner Briton Colin McRae finish just seven seconds ahead of Subaru team mate Liatti.</p>
<p>Frenchman Gilles Panizzi brought the Peugeot team some consolation with a fine third-place finish. He had led for much of the opening day in his two-wheel drive car and lost the lead only when he suffered a puncture on the sixth stage.</p>
<p>Panizzi's team mate, Frenchman Francois Delecour, was disqualified on Wednesday when he was bump-started by one of his team's support vehicles after mechanical problems had prevented him reaching the start line.</p>
<p>McRae finished in fourth place after matching the leaders for pace on the final day. His hopes for victory were ruined by a puncture on the 11th stage after he had led the rally for the start of the second leg.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LLORET DE MAR, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
