<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51252" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: German Bunds set to outshine U.S. and Japanese bonds.</title>
<headline>German Bunds set to outshine U.S. and Japanese bonds.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Nisbet</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bunds will stay top of the class in the months ahead for investors comparing the relative merits of the world's big three bond markets, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;European outperformance is nowhere more evident than in the 10-year German-U.S. spread which we see widening to right through 100 basis points in the next two to three months,&quot; said David Brown at Bear Stearns International in London.</p>
<p>Brown, chief European economist, recommended investors prefer Bunds to U.S. or Japanese government bonds because of the rosy outlook for German fundamentals.</p>
<p>He said they should be neutral to slightly underweight in Treasuries, because of the &quot;strong possibility&quot; of a quarter point rise in interest rates by the U.S. Federal Reserve on September 24, and very underweight JGBs.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a very good chance we will see six percent taken out on the 10-year Bund yields over the next couple of months and a 50-50 chance of them trading down to 5.75 percent before the year-end,&quot; Brown said.</p>
<p>Steve Barrow, international economist at Chase in London, said he preferred markets outside the big three, but forced to choose would favour Germany, Japan and the United States in that order.</p>
<p>He expected a 25 basis point U.S. rate rise on September 24, and advised avoiding the short end for that reason.</p>
<p>He foresaw further outperformance by Bunds against Treasuries in spread terms and no real risk, probably even in the longer term, that the Bundesbank would need to follow the Fed in tightening monetary policy.</p>
<p>Brown said the current gross yields of 6.25 percent on 10-year Bunds and 6.87 percent on Treasuries left a big gulf with the comparable Japanese yield of only 2.91 percent.</p>
<p>Positive factors for Bunds listed by Brown were stagnant German economic growth compared with the United States, lower inflation, and interest rates heading down instead of up.</p>
<p>He said that as the Japanese economy picked up and the threat of a big budget deficit loomed, the only real attraction of investing in JGBs would be a rising yen.</p>
<p>But he saw a risk the dollar/yen exchange rate would move to 115 from 110 in the next three to six months.</p>
<p>Barrow said that the least unfavourable places to invest among the big three were 10 to 30 years for the U.S., the four to five year area for Japan, and one-year for Germany.</p>
<p>Kim Thomsen, head of fixed income at Danske Invest in Copenhagen, Denmark's largest investment fund, said he found the U.S. market more enticing than Japan or Germany over the next one to two months.</p>
<p>He said he would not go recommend buying U.S. Treasuries but was on the lookout for good buying opportunities once there were expected signs of a second half slowdown.</p>
<p>He said that unless there were strong figures from economic indicators in the meantime, he did not think the Fed would raise interest rates on September 24 but would prefer to stay on the sidelines till November.</p>
<p>Thomsen said there was growing evidence that the Atlanta Olympics had a greater impact on the economy than previously thought, opening the way to a big contraction when that temporary stimulus ended.</p>
<p>He said he believed the October U.S. non-farm payrolls data would provide the first clear evidence of this.</p>
<p>Thomsen said the T-note/Bund spread could widen a little short-term, but narrow after the U.S. turnaround to between 35 to 50 basis points in October/November.</p>
<p>He saw a big risks in JGBs, with a possibility that big institutions would stop investing in the market again in view of the threat of tightened monetary policy to curb growth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
