<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="512545" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: ERA PANK SATISFIED WITH MARKET POSITION.</title>
<headline>ERA PANK SATISFIED WITH MARKET POSITION.</headline>
<byline>David Mardiste</byline>
<dateline>TARTU, Estonia 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Era Pank, the Tartu-based bank which is Estonia's seventh largest in terms of balance sheet volume, is satisfied with its position on the market and hopes to increase customer service.</p>
<p>Era Pank chairman Andres Bergmann also said that the bank was active in Ukrainian markets.</p>
<p>&quot;We aim to provide a very good client service and to provide a service to those clients with good links between East and West,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>The bank currently has just three branches, one in Tartu, one in Tallinn and in Parnu but Bergmann said he did not consider the bank as a niche operation.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not see the bank having lots of branches but within our branch building we try to provide complete banking and financial services,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;At present we are the seventh largest bank by balance sheet volume and we are active in foreign exchange trading,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our foreign exchange dealing in Ukraine is one of the highest of the Estonian banks,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Bergmann's is one of the few banks which does not have a stock market listing and he said he was happy with the way things were.</p>
<p>&quot;If you go to the share market then it is a question of what you are in it for. We are now equipped with enough own capital to support our balance volume, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;If more is needed then we will consider going to the market,&quot; Bergmann said.</p>
<p>Treasury department head Vivika Tael said the bank's aim was to boost its service levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The key for development in the next year is providing medium-sized clients with a client-oriented service,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>-- Tallinn newsroom +372 630 6400</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TARTU, Estonia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
