<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="512686" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Italian,Spanish bonds lose out in Q1-investor poll.</title>
<headline>Italian,Spanish bonds lose out in Q1-investor poll.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investors moved out of Italian and Spanish bonds dramatically in the first quarter and shifted their allocations in German and U.S. bonds to shorten duration, according to a survey by Paribas Capital Markets on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Bond buyers remain overweight in German bonds and have risen to overweight in U.S. bonds.</p>
<p>The survey was undertaken between April 1 and 10 to reflect the changes made to investor portfolios during the first quarter. In all 102 multi-currency investors were canvassed.</p>
<p>The allocations were measured in an index from zero to 100, 100 being the maximum overweight.</p>
<p>&quot;The most significant change during Q1 1997 was the reduction in exposure to the lira and peseta bond markets,&quot; said Graham McDevitt, head of global bond strategy at Paribas in London.</p>
<p>The allocation of Italian bonds has dropped 13 points to a level of 40 and Spanish bonds have fallen 16 points to 42, since the last survey was conducted in January.</p>
<p>By contrast U.S. Treasuries have risen four points to 56, the same level as Danish bonds. The allocation of Danish bonds fell slightly from 58 previously.</p>
<p>&quot;Interestingly, the duration of dollar holdings were shortened significantly during the past three months. However, in terms of currency overlay, investors remain very overweight dollars, increasing long positions by four on the index, to 70,&quot; said McDevitt.</p>
<p>Investors remain overweight in German and British bonds, both of which have risen a modest two points to 60 and 65 respectively.</p>
<p>McDevitt said in terms of European currencies, the survey showed a clear preference for sterling, which had an overweight position of 62 on the currency overlay index.</p>
<p>At the other end of the scale, investors remain underweight in Japanese, Belgian and French bonds.</p>
<p>The allocation of yen bonds has slipped a further two points on the index to a very underweight position of 18.</p>
<p>&quot;The weak profile of the Japanese currency was reflected in a further shortening of investor positions,&quot; McDevitt said.</p>
<p>French franc bonds had dropped six points from January to an allocation level of 22, while Belgian bonds had fallen eight points to 20.</p>
<p>--International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 4041</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
