<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51300" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Volcker starts hunt for Swiss Holocaust accounts.</title>
<headline>Volcker starts hunt for Swiss Holocaust accounts.</headline>
<byline>Michael Shields</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH, Switzerland</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Federal Reserve Chairman Paul Volcker pledged Friday that a commission he heads would do its best to search for dormant accounts in Swiss banks left by Holocaust victims, but said the huge task would take time.</p>
<p>Volcker, now a high-powered New York banker, said he was convinced Jewish groups, Swiss bankers and the Swiss government were dedicated to work together to find the truth.</p>
<p>But he told reporters after two days of talks in Switzerland that the painstaking search through banking records up to six decades old would take at least a year to finish and would probably not satisy everyone in the end.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a common desire to investigate and review this matter in a systematic and thorough way so that ... the issue can be put to rest once and for all 50 years after the war,&quot; he said after meeting Jewish groups, bankers and government officials.</p>
<p>&quot;With the best will in the world ... it is something that is going to take time. It is a very detailed process ... to provide the kind of assurance people want.&quot;</p>
<p>The panel, which includes representatives of Jewish groups and the Swiss Bankers Association, will go through bank records to check banks' own survey that found 39 million Swiss francs ($31.4 million) in accounts that might stem from the Holocaust.</p>
<p>The World Jewish Congress has called that figure too low and said billions of dollars in assets might have been stashed away from the Nazi regime by Jews afraid of losing their lives and property. It says the wealth might still be in Swiss banks.</p>
<p>Volcker took pains to point out his panel would check only dormant accounts in Swiss banks, and not try to track down another hot topic -- gold stocks the Nazis looted from vanquished nations and peoples and then moved to Switzerland.</p>
<p>&quot;What happened to Belgian gold or foreign central banks' gold is not our business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A separate investigative commission being set up by the government will examine this in the broader context of to what extent neutral Switzerland helped support Hitler's Germany.</p>
<p>Volcker, who said he was picked to head the panel because he was neither Swiss nor Jewish, stressed how difficult the task that lay ahead would be.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it will be easy and I don't think anyone should be under the illusion that this will be a simple job,&quot; he said, noting previous efforts to clear up the matter had left unanswered questions.</p>
<p>&quot;Fifty years afterward, different perceptions remain. It is kind of a running sore. The scab had been picked out a little bit here,&quot; he said. &quot;It ought to be settled as well as we can and that's what we mean to do.&quot;</p>
<p>He was starting the job by interviewing accounting companies that will be given the task of poring over old records on bank accounts, safety deposit boxes or other assets.</p>
<p>Volcker laughed when asked if he was afraid he was lending his name to a task that had limited chances of success.</p>
<p>&quot;Am I worried that we will get an answer that is convincing? That is why we want to do as good a job as we can,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We do have a committee that represents both the bankers and the Jewish community. The ideal result will be that they come to some kind of consensus and I can willingly be the spokesman for their consensus.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
