<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51304" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Heineken stock mauled as Europe beer sales go flat.</title>
<headline>Heineken stock mauled as Europe beer sales go flat.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Scott</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM, Netherlands</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investors savaged Heineken stock Friday after disappointing first-half results and a surprise profit warning from the Dutch brewing giant prompted analysts to downgrade their estimates.</p>
<p>The company posted a 6 percent rise in first-half 1996 net profit to 297 million guilders ($175.2 million), and warned that full-year net would be &quot;somewhat&quot; lower than 1995's 664 million guilders ($392 million), blaming stagnant European beer markets.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected first-half net profit of between 308 million and 322 million guilders ($182 million and $190 million).</p>
<p>Heineken stock plunged over 50 guilders ($29), or almost 14 percent, to a low of 312.00 guilders ($184.07), before bouncing back to close down 40.20 guilders ($23.72) at 322.50 ($190.27).    Speaking at a news conference to present the results,</p>
<p>Chairman Karel Vuursteen added to investors' woes by warning that double-digit net profit growth for the company over the next three years could not be guaranteed.</p>
<p>&quot;Within this integration phase it's very difficult to give a prediction, but over the next three years I don't think you can count on double-digit net profit growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the main problem dogging the group was that there would be no more growth in European beer markets, which would lead to increasing pressure on margins.</p>
<p>In 1995, Heineken beer sales in Europe accounted for almost half of total worldwide sales.</p>
<p>A number of analysts cut their own profit estimates following the group's pessimistic expectations.</p>
<p>Dealers expected the stock to drop up to 20 guilders ($12) further Monday as analysts digested comments from the company's presentation and investors watched weekend press comment.</p>
<p>The results prompted frenzied dealing in Heineken stock with over 3.7 million shares changing hands Friday against the usual 200,000 to 400,000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM, Netherlands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
