<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513002" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - April 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - April 16.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Wednesday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- The counting of ballot papers starts in Eastern Slavonia. First unofficial results expected on Thursday.</p>
<p>- Council of Europe monitors describe Sunday's elections as regular and fair.</p>
<p>- EBRD announced in London that it will concentrate on directly giving loans to private firms in Croatia and also fully support privatisation. It has described the Croatian economy as &quot;reaching a high level of transition&quot;.</p>
<p>- Croatian UN ambassador, Ivan Simonovic is to take part in the subpoena discussion in the Hague. The discussion will revolve around the issue of whether the Hague war crimes tribunal can order senior officials of a country to hand over documents that the tribunal finds important for the case, regardless of whether this is regarded as being a top secret document.</p>
<p>- The situation in Zagreb after the elections: Is a new crisis on the horizon or will a coalition be formed between the Croatian Democratic Union (HDZ) and the Croatian Peasant's Party (HSS) or will some other agreement be reached eventually?</p>
<p>- Croatia and Slovenia to hold talks for the second time on the esatblishment of a free trade zone on April 17.</p>
<p>- Some 85,000 mobile phones registered in Croatia and the trend is expected to grow.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- The cost of covering the basic monthly needs of a family of four in April has gone down by 6.4 percent or by 282 kuna.</p>
<p>- The private carrier North Adria Aviation to open a regular line on the route Rijeka-Split-Dubrovnik.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Some 70,000 local Serbs voted in Eastern Slavonia, says UNTAES spokesman Philip Arnold.</p>
<p>- HDZ party favourites including ministers Davor Stern and Miroslav Separovic lost to much less well known opposition candidates in Zagreb.</p>
<p>- Croatia to review categorisation of private tourist accommodation, offering some 300,000 beds.</p>
<p>- Croatian Privatisation Fund president Tomislav Druzak advises beneficiaries of the mass privatisation scheme not to sell immediately shares they get in exchange for vouchers.</p>
<p>- State electricity board was owed 363.8 million German marks for unpaid bills in January, 79 million more than a year ago. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
