<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513257" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Metrobank to expand consumer loans business.</title>
<headline>Metrobank to expand consumer loans business.</headline>
<byline>Ramoncito dela Cruz</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Metropolitan Bank and Trust Co Inc (Metrobank) is venturing into the more lucrative but riskier consumer loans segment, bank officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Metrobank has built its position as the country's biggest bank on the basis of its strong manufacturing and trade loans portfolio.</p>
<p>&quot;We will go into consumer lending in the countryside considering that Metrobank has the most number of branches in countryside,&quot; president Antonio Abacan told analysts after the bank's annual stockholders meeting.</p>
<p>Concerns over rising defaults, especially in consumer-related loans for homes and cars should not deter the bank's move into the profitable segment, as Metrobank has been prudent in giving out loans, he said.</p>
<p>Metrobank's past due loans declined to 1.7 percent of its outstanding loan portfolio last year from 1.9 percent in 1995, senior vice president Alfredo Javellana said.</p>
<p>&quot;Past due ratio has been kept stable (and it's) on the downtrend,&quot; Javellana said.</p>
<p>Abacan also said the bank had fully provisioned for its non-performing loans to avoid a sudden effect on its bottomline when they fall due.</p>
<p>Banking stocks have been battered in the past weeks after a preliminary report from the Central Bank said the industry's past due loans have been on the rise.</p>
<p>Consumer banking is fast becoming a very profitable segment in the banking industry due to the growing affluence in the middle-income market.</p>
<p>Metrobank launched two banking products in the middle of last year to cater to new car and home owners.</p>
<p>The bank will put up consumer lending centres in the countryside to push for the two loan products, Abacan added.</p>
<p>The bank planned to put up an additional 35 branches this year, in addition to the existing 335 branches nationwide.</p>
<p>The bank has also earmarked one billion pesos as capital expenditure for this year to be sourced from internally generated fund.</p>
<p>Most of this will go to branch expansion and renovation and upgrading of its equipment, Javellana said.</p>
<p>The bank reiterated its earlier predictions that net income for 1997 would be much higher than the 5.002 billion peso net income reached last year.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a range of a low of 6.5 billion to 7.0 billion pesos,&quot; Javellana said.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8938</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
