<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51321" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek shares break resistance, extend climb.</title>
<headline>Greek shares break resistance, extend climb.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek equities continued their advance for the fourth consecutive day in heavy trading volume breaking resistance at 950 points as the bulls felt frisky on Friday.</p>
<p>Market watchers sensed the beginning of a bull trend saying further gains could unfold with the market discounting a strong government after the elections.</p>
<p>&quot;There was buying in quality stocks, blue chips and the market definitely broke resistance at 950. I see a long term bullish trend in the make even if we witness an interim correction next week,&quot; said analyst Emmanuel Varsos at Investment Analysis.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be viewed as a buying opportunity. This stands whatever the election outcome on September 22,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The two lead candidates for prime minister, socialist Costas Simitis and conservative Miltiadis Evert, will face off in a TV debate Friday evening hoping to lure the undecided voters in what the press has dubbed the &quot;couch elections&quot;.</p>
<p>Greece will hold early elections September 22.</p>
<p>The Athens general share index closed 1.44 percent, or 13.58 points higher at 958.19 from Thursday's 958.19 close after opening at 944.55 points. Turnover eased to 9.5 billion drachmas from 11 billion on Thursday on volume of 4.45 million shares.</p>
<p>Advancers led decliners 121 to 95 with 23 issues unchanged on 239 traded. Banks climbed 1.50 percent, industrials jumped 2.50 percent and construction eased 0.46 percent. Small-caps firmed 0.86 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
