<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513306" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: A Soriano officers deny rift in board.</title>
<headline>A Soriano officers deny rift in board.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Officials of holding firm A. Soriano Corp (Anscor) on Wednesday denied there was a rift in the board of directors and attributed newspaper reports on trouble within the company to disagreements &quot;between brothers&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It's (disagreements) were between brothers,&quot; A Soriano vice chairman Carlos Soriano told reporters when asked to comment on the reports of a rift with his elder brother Andres Soriano III.</p>
<p>Newspaper reports of disagreements between the Soriano brothers on the management of the company their grandfather founded in 1930 had sparked speculation there would be a battle for control of the board at the firm's stockholders meeting on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The 11-member board of Anscor met before the stockholders meeting to thresh out the problems,&quot; an official of the company who did not want to be named told Reuters.</p>
<p>The elder brother Andres Soriano, who is chairman of Anscor, said: &quot;There are problems but we figured out things which we don't need to publicise.&quot;</p>
<p>Andres Soriano is also chairman of San Miguel Corp, one of the largest companies in the Philippines.</p>
<p>Company officials declined to say what stake the Sorianos held in Anscor.</p>
<p>Anscor has interests in banking, transportation, real estate, mining, power generation, resort, cargo handling, manufacturing and agribusiness.</p>
<p>--Manila newsroom (632) 841-89-36, fax 817-62-67</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
