<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513599" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS -- regroup, but end down 1/8.</title>
<headline>U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS -- regroup, but end down 1/8.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. municipal bonds regained some lost ground late in the day, but ended the day in the loss column.</p>
<p>After fading as much as 3/8 by midday on economic data and a softer tone, muni prices crawled back to off about 1/8 on pure sentiment - &quot;a better feel&quot; - said one trader.</p>
<p>Revenue bonds were off about 1/8 to 1/4, while high grade bonds were off about 1/8.</p>
<p>There was not much action in the secondary, the trader said.</p>
<p>For Thursday, &quot;we will watch Treasuries, follow their lead,&quot; the trader said. On Wednesday, the 30-year bond closed off 2/32 to yield 7.10 percent.</p>
<p>As for Wednesday's primary market, some deals were repriced, raising yields slightly.</p>
<p>&quot;The weakest part of the market was in the longer intermediate range, reflected in the pricing,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>Municipal bond sales on Wednesday totaled about $850 million in 27 sales.</p>
<p>The New York Metropolitan Transportation Authority led the pack with the largest negotiated offering, a $383 million issue repriced to raise yields, through a syndicate headed by Bear Stearns &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Oregon's sale of $155 million of certificate of participations were restructured, according to Bear Stearns.</p>
<p>Municipal bond sales for Thursday, April 17 are expected to total $169 million in 17 sales, according to Reuters Municipal Bond Information Group.</p>
<p>Negotiated offerings total $143 million in five sales, with a $97 million Missouri Housing Development Corporation through A.G. Edwards &amp; Sons, Inc. topping the list.</p>
<p>On the competitive side, 12 sales totaling $26 million are on the schedule. A $23 million Sarrah Scott Middle School District, Ind., deal at 1400 EDT is the largest.</p>
<p>An additional nine sales totaling $256 million are on the possible calender, meaning underwriters have said they may price the bonds Thursday, depending on market conditions.</p>
<p>In debt futures at the close, June Treasury bonds fell five ticks to 107-15/32, while June municipal bonds lost 10 ticks to 112-9/32. The MOB spread closed at 154 ticks, down from 159 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
