<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51353" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ford-UAW talks continue as deadline nears.</title>
<headline>Ford-UAW talks continue as deadline nears.</headline>
<byline>David Lawder</byline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bargainers for Ford Motor Co and the United Auto Workers continued to hammer away at crucial outsourcing and supplier issues Friday as the midnight Saturday strike deadline loomed for a new labour contract.</p>
<p>As talks continued into the evening, people familiar with the discussions said negotiators were leaning toward a three-year contract that offers base wage increases of at least two percent a year.</p>
<p>There had been some talk earlier the two sides may craft a contract longer than the traditional three years.</p>
<p>But J.P. Morgan analyst David Bradley said the length of the contract is minor compared to Ford's need to secure more long-term flexibility to purchase parts in a cost-efficient manner.</p>
<p>&quot;What Wall Street worries about is Ford's ability to control their cost structure over time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the current contract, covering nearly 400,000 workers at Detroit's Big Three automakers, workers earned a three percent base-wage increase in the first year, and lump-sum bonuses of three percent in the second and third years.</p>
<p>Meanwhile UAW members Friday went through the motions of preparing for a possible strike at Ford when the current pact expires at midnight Saturday, but the union pledged not to strike General Motors Corp. and Chrysler Corp.</p>
<p>GM and Chrysler spokespersons said the union extended their contracts with the companies because it is concentrating its bargaining for a new national contract at Ford.</p>
<p>&quot;It means we're safe from a strike until they come to our company to negotiate,&quot; said Chrysler spokeswoman Nicole Solomon.</p>
<p>The &quot;extension agreement letter&quot; is typically sent by the UAW to the automakers that are not selected as the lead company in the talks.</p>
<p>But the letter came later than usual this year because the UAW delayed its choice of a bargaining target and then decided to continue talks at Chrysler and GM last week after selecting Ford. The extension calls for the UAW to give three days notice to give a new strike deadline.</p>
<p>As the deadline drew closer, UAW members at Ford plants around the country began making strike preparations as union and company negotiators continued to press for a tentative agreements covering Ford's 104,000 UAW hourly workers.</p>
<p>&quot;We're ready to roll,&quot; said Jerry Klein, president of Local 249 at Ford's Kansas City, Mo. assembly plant. &quot;All we need is the call.&quot;</p>
<p>At Local 862 in Louisville, Ky., the nearly 8,000 union members there have assembled signs and received assignments for picketing plants 24 hours a day, seven days a week, said Jerry Young, vice president of the local, one of Ford's biggest.</p>
<p>Although workers at Ford voted overwhelmingly to go on strike if they UAW President Stephen Yokich has gone out of his way this year to say that he does not want a strike. A long and costly walkout would slash large profit-sharing payouts expected by Ford workers this year.</p>
<p>Chrysler, however, faces the growing possibility of a strike in Canada by the Canadian Auto Workers. Company and union officials said Thursday that they were far apart over outsourcing issues. CAW president Buzz Hargrove said the union will strike unless Chrysler gives into CAW demands on the issue.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
