<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513587" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SEC calls press report of Levitt fundraising silly.</title>
<headline>SEC calls press report of Levitt fundraising silly.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Securities and Exchange Commission spokesman on Wednesday tossed off as &quot;nonsense&quot; a press report about political fundraising activities by Chairman Arthur Levitt before he was appointed to head the agency.</p>
<p>&quot;The bottom line is that this is nonsense, and we are not even going to dignify it with a response,&quot; Chris Ullman, SEC director of public affairs, said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>He was responding to a report in The Bond Buyer Wednesday that Levitt was one of several &quot;leading national fundraisers&quot; for the Democratic party during the 1992 election who was &quot;interested in serving&quot; in the Clinton administration, according to documents released this week by the Democratic National Committee (DNC).</p>
<p>The paper said that the documents include a Dec. 21, 1992 memo from two DNC employees to the former deputy director of then President-elect Bill Clinton's transition team, listing Levitt as a &quot;must consider&quot; for five administration posts, including ambassadorships to Germany or Mexico.</p>
<p>The paper said it is not clear whether Levitt actively sought the administration posts.</p>
<p>The story raised eyebrows on Wall Street on Wednesday because Levitt has launched an aggressive campaign to eliminate &quot;pay-to-play&quot; - or the giving of political contibutions in return for bond business - in the muni arena.</p>
<p>Wall Street bond firms signed a voluntary ban on pay-to-play in their sector several years ago and the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board issued a rule restricting the practice by dealers soon after.</p>
<p>Levitt has criticized bond lawyers for not developing a voluntary ban on the practice.</p>
<p>Paul Maco, head of SEC's Office of Municipal Securities, said &quot;there's no comparison&quot; between Levitt's fundraising activities and pay-to-play.</p>
<p>&quot;Any inference to the contrary is simply another effort to cloud the issues surrounding pay-to-play. One is open and disclosed political support for a candidate for public office followed by public service in public office after the merits of the appointment have been reviewed and confirmed by the U.S. Senate,&quot; Maco said.</p>
<p>&quot;The other is the often hidden making of political contributions to override considerations of merit - quality, experience and competence - to get local government securities business and calling into question the integrity of the municipal securities market,&quot; Maco added.</p>
<p>Howard Zucker, who chairs the public finance committee of the American Bar Association's state and local governments section, said he had no comment.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
