<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513626" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr/yen ends flat in US amid intervention fears.</title>
<headline>Dlr/yen ends flat in US amid intervention fears.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar ended little changed against the yen, trimming losses on fears of central bank intervention fueled by remarks from a senior Japanese financial official and the U.S. trade representative, experts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is quite clear that both the U.S. and Japanese goverments want the dollar not to go up further,&quot; said Takanobu Igarashi, senior economist at Sanwa Bank Ltd in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't expect intervention is coming at around this level,&quot; he said when the dollar was trading near 125.60 yen.  </p>
<p>&quot;But if it (the dollar) goes up further to 127 or 128, then the possibility grows much larger,&quot; Igarashi said.</p>
<p>The dollar closed at 125.78/88 yen, barely changed from 125.77/87 yen at the open.</p>
<p>Senior Japanese Finance Ministry official Eisuke Sakakibara warned again overnight that recent movements in the yen-dollar exchange rate were clearly excessive.</p>
<p>He also said Japanese authorities will take decisive action at an appropriate time and when they see that intervention can be effective.  </p>
<p>&quot;So people are trying to protect themselves against that event,&quot; he said referring to intervention to boost the yen.</p>
<p>Much of the trading activity involving the yen against marks and Swiss francs is funneled through dollars. Traders noted that this helped boost the dollar against the German and Swiss currencies on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The dollar closed at 1.7290/95 marks, 1.4715/25 Swiss francs and Canadian $1.3974/79, up from 1.7245/50 marks, 1.4655/65 Swiss and C$1.3963/68 at the open. Sterling rose to $1.6242/52 from $1.6210/15. The Australian dollar rose to $0.7725/30 from $0.7719/29. ((-- Donna Sells 212-859-1668))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
