<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513646" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE cocoa ends broadly lower, focus on May-July.</title>
<headline>CSCE cocoa ends broadly lower, focus on May-July.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE cocoa futures ended broadly lower in sluggish trading Wednesday, dragged down by speculative selling of the nearby May/July switch ahead of the spot month's delivery period, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was weakness on rollover ahead of (May) first notice day,&quot; one trader said. &quot;People were cleaning up thier May positions.&quot;</p>
<p>Spot May cocoa settled down $14 at $1,400 a tonne, toward the bottom of its $1,417 to $1,397 range. Most-active July slid $16 to $1,439 after posting trades from $1,457 to $1,435. The outer months lost $14 to $16.</p>
<p>The market headed lower at the outset on the heels of losses in the London cocoa market overnight, traders said. Downward momentum accelerated after July slipped chart support at $1,444, they said.</p>
<p>Dealings centered on the nearby switch, as speculators adjusted positions before May goes into notice period on April 17. May's discount to second-month July pulled back to $39 at the close, down from $41 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>May open interest fell 2,458 lots Tuesday, to 4,854 lots, while July's open interest rose by 1,483 lots to 32,548 lots.</p>
<p>Technically, near-term support was seen at last Friday's low of $1,433, with resistance pegged at $1,457 to $1,459, with a large chart gap looming at $1,480 to $1,504.</p>
<p>On the fundamental side, news Bahia 1996/97 cocoa arrivals totalled 2,834,701 million 60-kg bags by the week ending April 6 compared with 2,626,668 bags by April 7 of last year had little impact on the market, traders said.</p>
<p>The U.S. first-quarter grind data is due Friday at 0845 EDT, but traders expect the data to have little effect on prices. Analysts' grind forecasts ranged from flat to up five percent.</p>
<p>Volume reached an estimated 12,028 lots, with switches accounting for much of the day's turnover, traders said.</p>
<p>((--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
