<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513739" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. equities exchanges wary of CFTC reforms.</title>
<headline>U.S. equities exchanges wary of CFTC reforms.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nine U.S. stock and options exchanges said Wednesday that the proposed reform of the Commodity and Futures Trading Commission would allow futures exchanges to &quot;unilaterally opt out&quot; of any government regulations.</p>
<p>William Brodsky, head of Chicago Board of Options Exchange, told a U.S. House Agriculture subcommittee that proposed legislation to deregulate the futures market could have unintended consequences for the U.S. securities markets.</p>
<p>&quot;The professional markets exemption would permit the futures exchanges to unilaterally opt out of whatever aspects of the Commodity Exchange Act they felt were burdensome or inconvenient,&quot; Brodsky said.</p>
<p>&quot;These could include intermarket circuit breakers, margin requirements, frontrunning rules, recordkeeping requirements and audit trail requirements,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Brodsky, who spoke on behalf of eight other exchanges including New York Stock Exchange and American Stock Exchange, urged the subcommittee to exclude equity swaps and equity hybrids from any reforms to the CFTC's oversight of futures and options.</p>
<p>The group of exchanges said the language of the proposed legislation introduced by Rep. Thomas Ewing, R-Ill, could allow traders to create unregulated options on a single stock or trade stock indices without regulation by Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
<p>&quot;They could be trading in a black hole of no regulation at all in products that relate to the equity market,&quot; Brodsky said.</p>
<p>Under questioning by the subcommittee, Brodsky said he did not believe U.S. equity exchanges were suffering from competition by exchanges in London and Singapore, which have less government regulation.</p>
<p>&quot;When it comes to the equity products, I don't believe they markets overseas have a competitive advantage,&quot; Brodsky said. &quot;I don't believe we are suffering right now from a competitive assault.&quot;</p>
<p>((-Washington commodities desk, 202-898-8467))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
