<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513758" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: House tax panel left out of budget talks, Rangel says.</title>
<headline>House tax panel left out of budget talks, Rangel says.</headline>
<byline>Tabassum Zakaria</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The ranking Democrat on the House tax-writing committee Wednesday said the panel and its Republican chairman had been left outside budget-making talks, which led to returned accusations of partisanship.</p>
<p>Representative Charles Rangel, a New York Democrat, told reporters that the House Ways and Means Committee, where all tax legislation must originate, and its chairman, Bill Archer, were non-players, leaving tax policy to be dictated by Senate Republicans.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want to be pessimistic about this procedure we're going through with the budget, but it doesn't help me at all to see that the Ways and Means Committee ... are not involved in this at all, we're non-players except my chairman speaking from time to time about substantial (tax) cuts,&quot; Rangel said.</p>
<p>Ari Fleischer, spokesman for Archer, of Texas, responded: &quot;It's unfortunate that Mr. Rangel continues to play the role of extreme partisan and opponent to everything this new Congress and Chairman Archer are doing.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked about what process tax talks were likely to take, Rangel replied: &quot;This procedure is so unusual that I cannot answer that because Archer is a non-player. So we have to depend on Roth and Lott and they're not that close together.&quot;</p>
<p>He was referring to Senate Finance Committee Chairman William Roth of Delaware, who has proposed a $140 billion tax cut over five years, and Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott of Mississippi, who started the year with legislation for about $200 billion in tax cuts.</p>
<p>President Clinton's budget calls for $98 billion in tax cuts over five years. Republicans want a capital gains tax cut, estate tax cut and tax credits for families.</p>
<p>House Republicans have not publicly said what size tax cut they would like to see.</p>
<p>&quot;It's by design that Chairman Archer is not announcing his tax preferences at this time, unlike the Senate which has put a bill on the table,&quot; Fleischer said. &quot;The chairman's a good negotiator and will keep his cards close to the vest.&quot;</p>
<p>Each side said the other was disconnected from leaders of their own party.</p>
<p>Archer's position of wanting to scrap the national income tax and replace it with a sales tax is outside the mainstream among Republicans. House Majority Leader Dick Armey, a Texas Republican, meanwhile, has been advocating a flat tax.</p>
<p>Fleischer said Rangel was a leader of the &quot;left wing&quot; of the Democratic party and was cut off from President Clinton,  &quot;so we understand that they lash out, but it's unfortunate none-the-less.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked where the tax issue currently stood in negotiations, Fleischer said: &quot;We're waiting for the administration to make a further offer. We would like to have a higher net tax cut.&quot;</p>
<p>Talks on taxes were expected to occur mainly by telephone for now, he added. Both Archer and Roth Tuesday had said they did not know when the face-to-face budget negotiations between congressional leaders and White House officials taking place in the Capitol would return to taxes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
