<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51373" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Iraq suspends threats, U.S. Stealth planes land.</title>
<headline>Iraq suspends threats, U.S. Stealth planes land.</headline>
<byline>Ashraf Fouad</byline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq abruptly dropped its threat to shoot at western planes patrolling its airspace on Friday, hours after U.S. Stealth bombers arrived in Kuwait as part of a major U.S. military buildup in the Gulf.</p>
<p>President Saddam Hussein's ruling Revolutionary Command Council &quot;has decided today to suspend our military reaction (until further notice)...as of 2400 local time (2000 GMT),&quot; the Iraqi News Agency reported.</p>
<p>The United States, which had dispatched a second aircraft carrier as well as Stealth aircraft and B-52 long-range bombers to confront Iraq, said immediately it would be &quot;looking at actions not statements.&quot;</p>
<p>But the Iraqi agency, quoting an official spokesman for the ruling Revolutionary Command Council, said Baghdad still considered the no-fly zones over northern and southern Iraq -- patrolled by western aircraft but closed to Iraqi planes -- to be illegitimate.</p>
<p>The withdrawal of its vow to shoot at planes flying over its territory followed a vow of no &quot;surrender&quot;. Iraq, which a week ago said it no longer recognized the five-year-old no-fly zones, had accused U.S. President Bill Clinton of arrogance.</p>
<p>&quot;We are much smaller than America, which has a great power,&quot; Iraq's Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz said in an interview with Russian television. &quot;But what shall we do? &quot;Shall we surrender? Definitely not, because American greed knows no limit.&quot;</p>
<p>The preparations for an attack on Iraq produced criticism of Clinton from both directions -- with critics at home saying he has shown weakness and those abroad urging restraint.</p>
<p>Top U.S. security officials met at the White House on Friday to plan the next move in their response to Iraq firing missiles at U.S. air patrols over Iraq.</p>
<p>Eight F-117A Stealth fighters landed in Kuwait about dusk on Friday but the aircraft carrier Enterprise, carrying another 75 warplanes, was unlikely to be in the Gulf until Sunday.</p>
<p>The Stealth planes, which can evade radar, used laser-guided 2,000 pound bombs to hit key targets in Baghdad during the 1991 Gulf War when a U.S.-led coalition drove Saddam's occupation forces from Kuwait.</p>
<p>The aircraft carrier Enterprise, with 75 warplanes, was steaming from the Adriatic Sea to the Gulf via the Suez Canal to join the carrier Carl Vinson. The two ships have F-14 fighters adapted to carry accurate laser-guided bombs.</p>
<p>The United States had already moved long-range B-52 bombers to a British base on the Indian Ocean island of Diego Garcia, within striking distance of Iraq.</p>
<p>The bombers were used to launch cruise missile strikes against Iraq last week in reprisal for moving troops into the Kurdish north of Iraq, a region closed to Iraqi forces and under Western protection for the past five years.</p>
<p>In another echo of the Gulf War, the U.S. Army said it was activating two Patriot anti-missile batteries, used to defend Saudi Arabia and Israel against Iraqi Scud missiles in 1991.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they (Saddam's government) really only understand disproportionate force,&quot; said former U.S. Secretary of State James Baker, who helped build the coalition for the Gulf War.</p>
<p>But divisions in the coalition that fought Iraq five years ago, already apparent after the U.S. missile strikes last week, continued to grow.</p>
<p>Turkey, which provides a base for western aircraft to protect Kurds in northern Iraq against Saddam, warned against further U.S. strikes and called for a diplomatic strategy.</p>
<p>China said on Friday it strongly opposed a U.S. attack on Iraq, saying such problems should be resolved under United Nations resolutions.</p>
<p>Russia, another of the five permanent members of the Security Council that had approved the Gulf War, sounded a similar warning on Thursday. France also expressed concern.</p>
<p>Although Washington made clear its priority was in southern Iraq, near the oil-rich Gulf states, the crisis began with Saddam's military backing for a Kurdish faction that secured control of northern Iraq this week.</p>
<p>Iraq underlined its renewed influence in the north after five years, saying on Friday it had resume sending fuel supplies to the Kurdish region.</p>
<p>But fear of Saddam's return to the north prompted Kurds opposed to the Baghdad government or with links to the West -- military and aid organisations -- to flee.</p>
<p>Turkey's ambassador to Washington, Nuzhet Kandemir, said Ankara was providing aircraft to help the United States fly 2,500 Americans, Kurds and Iraqi dissidents from northern Iraq.</p>
<p>The United Nations refugee agency UNHCR said in Geneva it had confirmed that 30,000 other Iraqi Kurds were now in Iran.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
