<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513833" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian government faces Thursday confidence vote.</title>
<headline>Italian government faces Thursday confidence vote.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's centre-left coalition government on Wednesday called a confidence vote in the lower house of parliament to try to ram through a long-stalled draft law covering civil service reforms.</p>
<p>The vote, to be held at 7 p.m. (1700 GMT) on Thursday, will be the second in as many weeks. The episode last week pushed the year-old administration led by Prime Minister Romano Prodi to the brink of collapse.</p>
<p>Regional Affairs Minister Franco Bassanini told parliament the measure had been taken to ensure passage of a bill already approved in the upper house, where the government has a majority, but hit by delays in the lower assembly.</p>
<p>&quot;This draft law contains very urgent measures which very many bodies have called for and are waiting for,&quot; Bassanini said in a speech to parliament before calling the vote.</p>
<p>The draft law, passed by the Senate last July, contains measures to simplify bureaucracy and procedures in public adminstration.</p>
<p>&quot;I recognise that there has been important work carried out on the text in parliament and at the commission level with the contribution of all political parties. But faced with behaviour that, unfortunately, I must call delaying, I must announce the confidence vote,&quot; Bassanini said.</p>
<p>The speaker of the lower house Luciano Violante suspended the session immediately afterwards.</p>
<p>Before the vote was called, opposition deputy Elio Vito had called for consideration of the draft law to be suspended until after local elections on April 27, pointing out that Bassanini was standing in Milan city elections.</p>
<p>Afterwards about 30 far-right deputies protested outside parliament calling for Prodi to resign.</p>
<p>The opposition deputies were particularly angered that Bassanini had called the vote after being given cabinet authorisation on March 27.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not possible that the government...could have given Bassanini a &quot;blank cheque&quot; to eventually call a confidence vote on something, the text of which was unknown,&quot; said far-right deputy Teodoro Buontempo.</p>
<p>The confidence test is designed to approve with a simple yes or no vote those articles of the draft legislation that have yet to be passed. If the government loses, it falls.</p>
<p>Prodi does not have a majority in the Chamber of Deputies (lower house), where he relies on the support of hard-left Communist Refoundation allies who have proved difficult partners since the government took office a year ago.</p>
<p>Refoundation caused waves last week when they voted against the deployment of a security force for Albania. The force was approved with votes from the centre-right opposition.</p>
<p>The hard-left party later fell back into line by backing the government in two confidence votes in parliament, necessary to reconfirm the majority behind Prodi.</p>
<p>Bassanini's law has been stalled by opposition politicians absenting themselves repeatedly, ensuring a quorum was not achieved.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks to me like Bassanini has lost his nerve,&quot; commented Giuseppe Pisanu, leader of the parliamentary group of opposition Forza Italia deputies, after the session.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
