<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513860" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: China envoy hits &quot;hostile&quot; West over rights row.</title>
<headline>China envoy hits &quot;hostile&quot; West over rights row.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A top Chinese diplomat on Wednesday accused the United States and other Western countries of displaying &quot;hostility&quot; to Beijing by seeking to have a United Nations body censure its human rights record.</p>
<p>The envoy, Geneva ambassador Wu Jianmen, also suggested the violent suppression of China's pro-democracy movement in 1989 would eventually be seen as having saved the country from collapsing into anarchy.</p>
<p>&quot;Relations between countries are like relations between people. If you are hostile to me, then I feel hostile to you,&quot; he told journalists only hours after the U.N. Human Rights Commission effectively rejected the Western censure bid.</p>
<p>He said China felt &quot;resentful&quot; towards countries like Denmark that tabled and backed a resolution criticising it on human rights which failed to get to a vote in the Commission.</p>
<p>The normally suave Wu, who also accused the West of trying to force alien cultural concepts on China, did not specify whether Beijing would retaliate against the range of countries that supported the resolution.</p>
<p>But he told a a press breakfast that if it came to a choice on a commercial deal and there were equal offers from Denmark and France -- which did not back the censure bid -- then the French would get preference.</p>
<p>Beijing has already postponed official visits to the country by delegations from Denmark, as well as the Netherlands which also sponsored the resolution.</p>
<p>Tabled by Denmark after a split in the European Union, it was blocked when a majority of 27 mainly developing countries in the 53-member Commission backed a Chinese &quot;no action&quot; motion.</p>
<p>It was the seventh year in a row that the West had failed to get a vote, and the defection of major powers like France, Germany, Italy, Spain, Canada and Australia from a group that had sponsored a resolution in the past was seen as a triumph for Beijing, and for Wu personally.</p>
<p>In Beijing, his successor as government spokesman Shen Guofang voiced &quot;admiration and gratitude&quot; to all the countries &quot;that have upheld justice and rendered support to China&quot; in the six-week diplomatic tussle in Geneva.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope the United States, Denmark and a few other countries that have clung to a confrontational approach will.... draw a lesson from their failure and make a clear break from their erroneous practice of tabling an anti-China draft resolution,&quot; Shen declared.</p>
<p>Asked at the Geneva breakfast for his view on the June 1989 military action against students and workers camped in and around Beijing's Tienanmen Square, Wu said &quot;history&quot; should be allowed to judge.</p>
<p>&quot;In the history of any nation there are moments of crisis. When that happens, you have to deal with it with the means available,&quot; he declared. &quot;The judgement should be left to history.&quot;</p>
<p>Wu, who accused Western media of suppressing positive news about his country, said that if China was allowed to collapse into chaos a flood of people out of the country would have a disastrous effect on its neighbours.</p>
<p>&quot;It would mean the end of the East Asia boom. China is too large,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
