<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513840" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Velayati slams Berlin verdict in letter to Kinkel.</title>
<headline>Velayati slams Berlin verdict in letter to Kinkel.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Fleck</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iranian Foreign Minister Ali Akbar Velayati on Wednesday attacked a German court verdict that concluded that Iran had ordered the killings of Kurdish dissidents in Berlin in 1992.</p>
<p>Velayati said last Thursday's verdict was in violation of international legal norms in a letter addressed to German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel made available to the media by the Iranian embassy in Bonn.</p>
<p>&quot;The presiding judge...made unfounded and politically motivated allegations against the Islamic Republic of Iran, flouting...the principle of 'State Immunity'...without a shred of evidence,&quot; the four-page letter said.</p>
<p>&quot;The witnesses were exclusively assembled from a group of sworn enemies of the Iranian Government and members and supporters of terrorist and armed separatist groups,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The Berlin court sentenced to jail three Lebanese and an Iranian for the murder of the four men in a restaurant in the city in the case that lasted three and a half years.</p>
<p>The court said Iranian leaders including the state president and the religious leader had ordered the killings. But it only mentioned Intelligence Minister Ali Fallahiyan by name. Iran has repeatedly denied all involvement.</p>
<p>It was the first time a European court had clearly attributed political responsibility for any of the dozens of assassinations of Iranian opposition figures abroad since the Islamic revolution in 1979.</p>
<p>The German Foreign Ministry declined comment on the letter which coincided with a German newspaper report that the Federal Prosecutor's Office had decided formally to launch investigations into Velayati.</p>
<p>German prosecutors denied the Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung newspaper report they had decided to launch any such probe, but said the office was still considering whether there were grounds to investigate Iranian officials &quot;at all levels&quot;.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the Federal Prosecutor's Office said it was studying last week's court verdict that top Iranian leaders ordered four killings in Berlin.</p>
<p>She said the checks would include deciding whether some suspects were immune on political or diplomatic grounds.</p>
<p>The newspaper said prosecutors had ruled out proceedings against Iranian President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani and religious leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei because of &quot;immunity problems&quot;.</p>
<p>The Frankfurter Allgemeine also reported investigators had searched the offices of a company in the Frankfurt area earlier this month as part of a probe into allegations of illegal arms procurement by Iran.</p>
<p>Prosecutors confirmed an investigation was under way but declined to comment on any details. Opposition politicians, however, were quick to condemn Iran.</p>
<p>&quot;The court in Berlin has scarcely announced its verdict and already further criminal activities are appearing,&quot; the opposition Social Democrats said.</p>
<p>The issue looked set to remain controversial as parliament announced it would hold a debate on relations with Iran on Thursday. The opposition Greens party submitted a motion calling for diplomatic ties to be &quot;frozen at a minimum&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
