<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513944" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss stocks end lower.</title>
<headline>Swiss stocks end lower.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss shares ended weaker on Wednesday after a session which saw prices fluctuate within narrow trading ranges.</p>
<p>The market ran out of steam after a firm opening and turned lower when U.S. data signaled strong economic growth, share dealers said.</p>
<p>The blue-chip SMI closed 17.8 points lower at 4,625.6 and the broad SPI was down 8.40 to 2,927.32. SMI futures fell 28 to 4,626.</p>
<p>Roche, down 25 to 11,825, led the actives list. Novartis was down five to 1,780. The company is due to announce first quarter sales data on Thursday.</p>
<p>Overall trading volume was 1.88 billion Swiss francs.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market would remain volatile with U.S. markets determining future direction for the Swiss bourse.</p>
<p>Holderbank fell 21 francs to 1,116 reflecting market disappointment over last night's news that the cement producer planned to take provisions totalling 450 million Swiss francs.</p>
<p>Selected cyclical stocks like Fischer, Rieter, Saurer and Sulzer were firm for most of the session but also came under pressure when the broad market turned lower.</p>
<p>Banks and insurers suffered from an uncertain interest rate outlook.</p>
<p>UBS, down two francs to 1,322, holds its annual shareholders meeting on Thursday afternoon. Traders expected no surprises from the meeting.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
