<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513956" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Investment risk linked with vision - mines financier.</title>
<headline>Investment risk linked with vision - mines financier.</headline>
<byline>Brian Spoors</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The extent of investment risk in emerging markets depends on the &quot;vision of the management of the country,&quot; leading mining financier Robert Friedland told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;To be involved in an emerging market you have to be three years early not one day late,&quot; Friedland said referring to the rising entry cost as an emerging market became more fashionable.</p>
<p>&quot;Peru five years ago was regarded as a pariah but now it is enormously chic. It depends on the vision of the management of the country and how they see things can change,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Friedland is chairman of Ivanhoe Capital Corporation which is involved in minerals, energy, telecommunications and real estate in 46 emerging markets and is headquartered in Singapore.</p>
<p>He said all emerging countries needed to raise capital and natural resources was an obvious start for them in gaining an export to raise foreign exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;Poland and Hungary bit the bullet five years ago and are reaping enormous benefits today. That transition (period) is when they need foreign investment,&quot; he said. In 1996 Friedland was voted Canada's mining financier of the year. His former company Diamond Fields Resources discovered the huge Voisey bay nickel deposit in Labrador which was the sold to the giant mining company Inco for development for over C$4 billion.</p>
<p>Now interests are broadening. &quot;Energy is very significant and now accounts for about half our portfolio,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Interests are in Russia, Malaysia, China, Indonesia and Peru. The Russian interest, through his group company Black Sea Energy is a potentially major oilfield in Siberia.</p>
<p>Already $50 million has been raised for the project and a further $100 million will be sought by year end.</p>
<p>Ivanhoe Capital also has interests in China developing low cost housing and talc, the industrial mineral used in printing and paper making.</p>
<p>Major developments are scheduled for Kazakstan through the Toronto-listed Indochina Goldfields.</p>
<p>&quot;Kazakstan is making enormous strides. It has a very dramatic programme with its state assets and has the potential to be a Saudi Arabia,&quot; said Friedland. &quot;Its president is a man of enormous vision which will eventually bring enormous benefit,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Kazakstan was the &quot;model for the region&quot; among the central Asia republics and was aiming to be an Asian tiger rather than &quot;another sick ex-Soviet economy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Indochina Goldfields last December bought for U.S. $60 million the Kazakstan government's holding in the Bakyrchik gold mine giving it a 37-percent interest in the 10.5 million ounces of gold contained in the deposit.</p>
<p>The comany also has a 50 percent interest in the Monywa Copper mining compex in Burma which with potential ore reserves of two billion tonnes, should be producing 25,000 tonnes of high grade copper cathode next year on its way to planned refined production of 128,000 tonnes per year.</p>
<p>&quot;Indochina also has a very large series of (gold) opportunities in Indonesia,&quot; Friedland said.</p>
<p>A spin off from his original company Diamond Fields Resources -- Diamond Fields International -- has located diamond deposits on the seabed off Namibia.</p>
<p>&quot;I like diamonds. There are no central banks to make the price drop like in gold...they have managed to retain real value better than gold over the past ten year. They are very healthy looking indeed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He thought it was possible to unearth another find -- &quot;a millenium find&quot; -- on the scale of Voisey Bay.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be another millenium deposit, in fact given technology there could be one every five years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>However he added, &quot;It would be very difficult to find such a large nickel deposit but never underestimate the tools available to industry today like computers, remote sensing from satellites and side scan radar.&quot;</p>
<p>	 --Zurich Newswroom +411 631 7454</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150203">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
