<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513928" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU labour, employers split over plant closures.</title>
<headline>EU labour, employers split over plant closures.</headline>
<byline>Gillian Handyside</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>European employer and trade union groups are divided over whether to strengthen European Union legislation on worker consultation in the wake of the controversial decision by Renault to close a plant in Belgium.</p>
<p>The European Trade Union Confederation (ETUC) and the European employers' lobby UNICE agreed at a meeting called by the EU Dutch presidency on Tuesday to continue talking about how to interpret existing EU rules.</p>
<p>But they differed over whether to go further.</p>
<p>&quot;We are against changing the legislation,&quot; UNICE official Olivier Richard told Reuters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But ETUC spokesman Wim Bergans said existing EU laws were ambiguous and national sanctions too weak to prevent firms laying off workers without consulting them.</p>
<p>The two sides hope to present a compromise to a meeting of EU social affairs ministers in June. The ministers will hear an initial report at a meeting in Luxembourg on Thursday.</p>
<p>Belgian and French courts have both ruled that Renault violated EU rules on worker consultation in closing a plant in Vilvoorde with a loss of 3,100 jobs.</p>
<p>During Tuesday's meeting with Dutch Employment Minister Ad Melkert and EU Social Affairs Commissioner Padraig Flynn, ETUC and UNICE agreed to work to clarify how much notice companies should give workers about restructuring plans.</p>
<p>&quot;The heart of the debate with the ETUC will be when consultation takes place,&quot; UNICE's Richard said.</p>
<p>An EU law on collective redundancies requires companies to tell workers of any closure decisions &quot;in good time&quot;. Trade unions interpret that to mean workers should be informed before any decision is taken and involved in drawing up any plan of action, Bergans said.</p>
<p>But UNICE's Richard insisted it was up to management to make redundancy decisions and the EU rules only obliged firms to inform their workers once that decision had been taken.</p>
<p>Melkert and Flynn said on Tuesday consultation was effective only if it was &quot;carried out well in advance.&quot;</p>
<p>Richard said the Renault decision was a one-off &quot;accident&quot; and should not spark off a hot-headed revision of EU rules.</p>
<p>Richard, a French lawyer, said UNICE was confident that if Renault's appeal against the court decisions failed, France and Belgium would impose swingeing national sanctions on the firm.</p>
<p>But Bergans said national sanctions were &quot;peanuts&quot; and the trade unions would support the Commission if it proposed European measures to back them up.</p>
<p>The public-sector employees group CEEP will take part in future talks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
