<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513929" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain to boost growth with liberalisation measures.</title>
<headline>Spain to boost growth with liberalisation measures.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain reaffirmed on Wednesday its plans to boost economic growth through liberalisation measures and the reduction of the public deficit.</p>
<p>Economy Minister Rodrigo Rato told parliament that the main target of a recently-approved three-year stability plan was to see economic growth at a higher rate than inflation, as has been the case in recent months.</p>
<p>&quot;To have the economy growing above prices we will continue to follow the same economic policy which made that possible... reducing the public deficit through a new model of expenditures and (economic) reforms,&quot; Rato said.</p>
<p>The 1997-2000 plan forecasts average growth at 3.2 percent, while the private consumption deflator is expected to stand at around 2.3 percent.</p>
<p>Although the reduction of public spending should not affect private citizens, Rato reiterated that the country needs to keep health expenditure under control.</p>
<p>But he also explained lower expenditures are expected to stem from a reduction in public consumption and from lower financial expenditures.</p>
<p>Interest payments are expected to fall to around 1.1 percent of gross domestic product in 2000, with a reduction of an average 0.5 percent each year.</p>
<p>-- Madrid Newsroom, + 341 585 8340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
