<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51411" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Wembley shoots for national stadium goal.</title>
<headline>Wembley shoots for national stadium goal.</headline>
<byline>Keith Weir</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wembley Plc, which owns and operates the home of English soccer, stepped up its campaign on Friday for the north London site to be chosen as the new national stadium.</p>
<p>Wembley stadium and the northern city of Manchester are rival bidders as the site for a state-of-the-art venue which could host future Olympic Games and World Cup finals.</p>
<p>Wembley said it had been told by Britain's Sports Council that a decision on the site would be made by the end of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Our capital city location is very important. If we are going for the World Cup then playing in the capital is a major advantage,&quot; said Wembley chief executive Alan Coppin in an interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We are already the de facto national stadium,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Coppin was speaking after Wembley Plc, which also operates greyhound tracks in Britain and the U.S., announced pre-tax profit of 7.7 million pounds ($12.0 million) in the first six months of 1996, after a 5.5 million pound loss in the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>Wembley stadium, built in the 1920s, is in line for a 150 million pound ($233 million) redevelopment if it wins the contest with Manchester.</p>
<p>Around 65 percent of the funding will come from the National Lottery with initiatives such as the sale of debenture seats providing the rest.</p>
<p>Award-winning architect Sir Norman Foster has unveiled radical plans for the stadium including the repositioning of its famous twin towers.</p>
<p>Coppin said that this summer's European soccer championship when Wembley played host to six matches including the final had proved the stadium's unique atmosphere.</p>
<p>&quot;The atmosphere at Wembley is second to none in the world,&quot; said Coppin, adding that he had found the new Amsterdam Arena stadium, home to former European champions Ajax, sterile by comparison on a recent visit.</p>
<p>The spirit of England's 1966 World Cup triumph was revived during Euro '96 as the home nation reached the semifinals, playing its games before partisan but sporting Wembley crowds.</p>
<p>The success of the tournament has prompted talk of an English bid to host the 2006 World Cup.</p>
<p>Coppin refuted suggestions that Wembley's facilities were outdated, saying they compared favourably with the best in other European nations such as Italy.</p>
<p>He noted that the impact of Euro '96 on profits had not been great as the stadium staged only one more major event in the first part of this year than 12 months earlier. He added this prompted confidence that the improvement could be maintained. ($1=.6430 Pound) ($1=.6430 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
