<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="514347" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Trustbuster - no anticompetitive aerospace mergers.</title>
<headline>Trustbuster - no anticompetitive aerospace mergers.</headline>
<byline>David Lawsky</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trustbuster Robert Pitofsky said Tuesday that despite reductions in military spending, the government should not permit aerospace mergers that are anticompetitive.</p>
<p>&quot;The defense industry is undergoing a period of significant consolidation,&quot; the Federal Trade Commission chairman told a Senate Armed Services subcommittee. &quot;This does not mean that policy makers should acquiesce in anticompetitive mergers.&quot;</p>
<p>Pitofsky said consolidation can occur in ways that protect the Department of Defense from becoming beholden to a single supplier, who would be free to control prices.</p>
<p>Pitofsky's testimony came as the Federal Trade Commission is considering the proposed merger of Boeing with McDonnell-Douglas.</p>
<p>Forty percent of Boeing's business and 75 percent of McDonnell-Douglas's business is with the military.</p>
<p>The merger also has implications for the commercial airline manufacturing industry. The only two American manufacturers of large commercial airliners are Boeing and Douglas.</p>
<p>Beyond focusing on whether mergers should occur, the Senate subcommittee looked into the practice of permitting companies to charge the Pengaton for a share of the costs of restructuring after they merge.</p>
<p>With the shrinking military budget, the Department of Defense has encouraged some mergers.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe it makes good business sense to permit defense contractors to include in the price of defense goods those resaonable costs they incur to become more efficient producers,&quot; testified Eleanor Spector, Pentagon director of defense procurement.</p>
<p>But David Cooper, associate director of defense acquisition issues for the General Accounting Office, testified such efficiencies -- in other words, savings to taxpayers and the government -- have proved elusive.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not seen the evidence of reduced prices,&quot; he said. Rep. Christopher Smith agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;The so-called savings to the taxpayer are not verifiable,&quot; said Smith, a New Jersey Republican. In fact, he said, there would be greater net savings for taxpayers if the costs were not reimbursed.</p>
<p>&quot;Why do these companies need taxpayer encouragement?&quot; he asked. &quot;If the underlying (merger) is prudent and profitable it will occur anyway.&quot; He called the payments an example of President Clinton's &quot;corporate welfare.&quot;</p>
<p>Smith has introduced a measure to abolish such payments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
