<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="514429" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Weaker Wall Street undermines European stocks.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Weaker Wall Street undermines European stocks.</headline>
<byline>Peter Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street opened softer on Wednesday after Tuesday's big rally and leading European shares, which had opened higher boosted by the Dow's second biggest one-day gain ever, followed suit.</p>
<p>On the currency front the dollar was mixed, holding steady against the mark -- although well down from Tuesday's 37-month high of 1.7375 marks -- but edging lower against the yen.</p>
<p>British, German and French blue chips all took early comfort from the dramatic overnight rise in U.S. stocks but fell back from their highs later in the morning. They slid into negative territory after Wall Street opened lower, partly due to stronger than expected U.S. industrial production data which revived rate hike fears.</p>
<p>By mid-afternoon London shares were down a few points after having been half a percent ahead in early morning. Dealers said sentiment was underpinned to a degree by British unemployment figures which, as expected, showed a 41,000 drop in the jobless total in March.</p>
<p>&quot;We've had a bit of a mark-up but the fund managers still don't want to do too much,&quot; the head of trading at a major investment house said. &quot;There is still too much uncertainty about for the market to go charging forward.&quot;</p>
<p>Fears that the opposition Labour Party, the clear favourite to win Britain's May 1 election, would need to raise corporate taxes to shore up fragile government finances were cited as a contributing factor to the FTSE index's recent thin trading volumes.</p>
<p>Analysts also cited worries that a Labour finance minister might agree to a 50 basis point interest rate rise shortly after the ballot in order to establish credibility with the financial markets.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt the DAX index of floor trading closed up about three quarters of a percent before Wall Street opened, but the IBIS DAX index of electronic trading was down by about the same amount shortly after New York trading began.</p>
<p>During the day new result details from Daimler-Benz were viewed positively but not with the same enthusiasm that greeted recent figures from BMW.</p>
<p>Nevertheless Daimler shares were among the heaviest-traded, rising in IBIS electronic business to an all-time high of 142.15 marks before falling 1.30 marks to 138 marks after Daimler announced plans for a 1.1 billion mark offering.</p>
<p>In Paris French shares also fell back from their peak of over half a percent up and were trading a third of a percent down, under the influence of Wall Street, shortly after New York opened for business.</p>
<p>In currencies the yen perked up slightly after comments from senior Japanese Finance Ministry official Eisuke Sakakibara. In a speech to currency dealers in Tokyo he said Japanese authorities would intervene in forex markets when appropriate and when it would be effective.</p>
<p>He repeated comments he made overnight that recent yen moves were excessive and the market had taken a too pessimistic a view of the Japanese economy, which he said was very healthy.</p>
<p>&quot;Sakakibara keeps making these comments but he's using the intervention word more which is having some impact,&quot; said Teis Knuthsen, economist at First Chicago in London. &quot;But there is still a deep-rooted skepticsm whether Japan will actually start intervening.&quot;</p>
<p>Dollar/yen, which held a tight range around 126 yen for much of the European morning session, had eased to around 125.55 by mid afternoon -- down from late Tuesday's 126.28.</p>
<p>&quot;The yen is overweak at the moment which, to an extent, is the Japanese authorities' fault,&quot; said Roger Francis, senior analyst at IBJ International.</p>
<p>&quot;Sakakibara can't say rates will go up without upsetting the markets, but he is saying the market should think about the future course of the economy.&quot;</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1430 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was quoted at 1.7275 marks and 125.55 yen after ending at 1.7333 and 126.28 in late trading in Europe on Tuesday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1430 GMT</p>
<p>LONDON - The FTSE-100 index was down 2.9 points at 4,283.9.</p>
<p>PARIS - The CAC-40 was down 8.05 points at 2,612.58.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - The 30-share DAX index closed up 25.77 points at 3,353.45.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold was fixed lower at $339.90 versus $341.75 at the close in London on Tuesday. Silver was firmer at $4.79. ($ = 1.726 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
