<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="514476" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: OPTIONS - Eurolira vols slip on rate cut talk.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - Eurolira vols slip on rate cut talk.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatility of Eurolira options on LIFFE slipped lower on Wednesday amid speculation about the timing of a possible cut in Italian interest rates, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Bank of Italy is widely expected to cut interest rates before the end of the month in response to falling Italian inflation. The disount rate is currently at 6.75 percent and the Lombard rate at 8.25 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Volatility is off, especially in June,&quot; said an Italian bank trader in London. &quot;It was very high before and people are selling calls they bought earlier and taking profits.&quot;</p>
<p>Brokers quoted implied volatility on Eurolira options at around 16.5 percent in June and around 18.5 percent in September.</p>
<p>At Tuesday's close implied volatility levels were at 17.40 percent in June and 19.03 in September. June vol has come off from 22.0 percent in mid-March.</p>
<p>At 1246 GMT, the underlying June Eurolira future was at 93.22, down 0.06 on the day, while September futures were at 93.54, also down six basis points from Tuesday's close.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is waiting for the Bank of Italy to cut rates,&quot; said a broker on the LIFFE floor. &quot;Before it happens the market is volatile as people speculate as to the timing of such a cut.&quot;</p>
<p>Around 1,000 lots of both the 93.75 calls and the 94.00 calls and over 800 lots of the 93.50 calls had been traded in the session so far according to LIFFE data.</p>
<p>Volatility levels on other interest rate options had also eased slightly and were expected to remain at lower levels for now, traders said.</p>
<p>Brokers said volatility on Euromarks was still levels low enough to attract buying interest, while short sterling implied volatilty levels were not expected to move much until after the British election on May 1.</p>
<p>--Deepthi Wickremasinghe, Bonds Unit +44 171 542 4041</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
