<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="514500" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: N Sea May crudes stumped by lack of buying interes.</title>
<headline>N Sea May crudes stumped by lack of buying interes.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brent crude slipped on the paper market on Wednesday while physical crude premiums held steady.</p>
<p>But traders said wet North Sea crude trade remained inert.</p>
<p>The usual flurry of activity on the release of monthly loading programmes failed to happen, they said. Only a handful of May cargoes have traded so far leaving equity holders somewhat bewildered at the absence of buying interest.</p>
<p>&quot;The buying pattern has definitely changed to a much closer time frame. More refiners are now happy to wait until the last minute and others have full tanks already. It is unbelievably quiet,&quot; one equity holder said.</p>
<p>June Brent on the IPE lost some 21 cents to trade at $17.93 a barrel by 1120 GMT. Prices were pressured by Tuesday's API report on U.S. stock figures which showed sizable builds on crude, gasoline and distillates.</p>
<p>The Brent CFD market saw active selling interest with the remainder of this week offered at June -70 cents while next weeks April 21-25 dates talked June -63/-61 cents.</p>
<p>April 28-02 traded at June -52 cents while a calander May sold at June -54 cents.</p>
<p>Intermonth spreads softened with May/June at -30/-27 and June/July -15/-14 cents.</p>
<p>The first three May Brent cargoes were passing through the chains and some traders expected to see at least one five o' clocked.</p>
<p>North Sea grades held steady with Ekofisk talked Dated evens/+5 cents. A May 6-8 cargo was heard to have traded on Tuesday around Dated Brent +2/3 cents. This left five unsold cargoes in the first decade of May.</p>
<p>Oseberg was assessed at Dated evens/+5 cents. Some of the pressure was off first decade loadings with a VLCC of Oseberg moving to the Far East but second and third decade liftings saw little interest, traders said.  </p>
<p>In the Mediterranean, Russian Urals was expected to ease from its last traded level of Dated Brent -$1.15, with stiff competition from alternative grades in May.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see people running to buy with the cheaper May Kirkuk barrels and there's a lot of competition from Iranian Heavy as well,&quot; said one local refiner.</p>
<p>Only two or three Urals cargoes were still on offer for April, but buyers were keen to hold out for May Iraqi Kirkuk prices which are set to be cut by 30 cents from April to Dated Brent less $2.20.</p>
<p>Negotiations for Syrian term prices for May continued, with state oil company Sytrol looking for Dated Brent -82 cents for Light and buyers at Dated Brent -90 cents, a contract lifter said.</p>
<p>The West African crude market was murky ahead of the release of Nigerian May term prices, expected later this week.</p>
<p>&quot;People want to keep things under wraps, and they certainly don't want any bullish news to come out,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Traders said that April-loading Qua Iboe barrels were still plentiful, with at least two third decade VLCCs on offer.</p>
<p>Forcados was still assessed at around Dated Brent -25 cents, with upside limited.</p>
<p>A trading house was seen with a VLCC of three quarters Bonny Light and one quarter Bonny Medium, and a European major was also seen offering Bonny Light.</p>
<p>Differentials for Bonny Light were pegged at around Dated Brent +15 to +20 cents. --S Hayden/R Russell +44 171 542 8978</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
