<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="514505" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - UK unemployment dives to six-year low.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - UK unemployment dives to six-year low.</headline>
<byline>John Speck</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The number of unemployed Britons tumbled by 41,100 in March to a six-year low of 1.71 million, boosting the ruling Conservatives as they try to claw back lost support ahead of the May 1 election.</p>
<p>Official figures showed unemployment fell for the 13th month in a row to 6.1 percent of the workforce, from 6.2 percent in February. More than one million jobs have now been created since since 1992 when almost three million people were out of work.</p>
<p>&quot;Unemployment is falling in this country, falling rapidly, falling in a way it isn't anywhere in the European Union,&quot; Prime Minister John Major told a news conference in London.</p>
<p>But the Conservatives' efforts to ride a brisk tide of good economic news before polling day were again frustrated by fresh infighting over Europe, with some of its candidates declaring their outright opposition to a single European currency.</p>
<p>The quality of the unemployment figures also came under fire, with critics claiming 32 changes to the way the jobless total is assessed over the past 18 years made them suspect.</p>
<p>Britain's opposition Labour party said on Wednesday it will launch a review into the way the figures are compiled, to ensure the real level of joblessness is not disguised.</p>
<p>But Major, expecting further good news on the economy with inflation figures due on Thursday, said claims that unemployment was 1.7 million higher than official figures were rubbish.</p>
<p>&quot;Total and utter rubbish. British unemployment is falling whatever measure you care to use,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Conservatives are fighting the election on the back of the strong economy, claiming &quot;Britain is booming, don't let Labour blow it.&quot; But they trail Labour by around 18 points in most opinion polls and are struggling to achieve the momentum that gave them a surprise victory in the April 1992 election.</p>
<p>Since the 1990-2 recession, the economy has recovered strongly, unemployment has dived, inflation has hit 30-year lows, and real disposable incomes have jumped.</p>
<p>But the government has failed to reap any real benefit from the economic upturn, with voters mindful of past policy failures -- particularly the pound's ignominious exit from Europe's exchange rate mechanism in 1992.</p>
<p>A growing sense of insecurity about work and the welfare state, which many feel have become much less reliable, has also damaged the Conservatives' reputation as the party of sound economic management.</p>
<p>Insecurity has been driven by concern over the rise in part-time working and low pay as Britain's labour market has become similar to that in the United States than Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of the new jobs appear to be lowly paid and part-time work has seen a huge increase,&quot; said Jeremy Hawkins, economist at Bank America in London.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears job creation has been stronger on the service side of the economy rather than manufacturing, but the quality of some of those service-sector jobs is open to doubt.&quot;</p>
<p>Other figures published on Wednesday showed average earnings growth at 5.0 percent in February from January's 4.75 percent.</p>
<p>While that is almost double Britain's main inflation rate of 2.9 percent, economists said earnings have been inflated by chunky bonus figures paid to workers in London's booming financial district.</p>
<p>Government debt is also falling after a decade of big bills. The British government had to borrow 22.8 billion pounds ($37.1 billion) in the 1996-7 fiscal year to balance its books, less than the 31.7 billion it borrowed in 1995-6.</p>
<p>&quot;On current trends, we will certainly balance the budget by the year 2000, if not before,&quot; British finance minister Kenneth Clarke said in a statement.</p>
<p>Ironically, the latest borrowing figures suggest Britain would qualify for a single currency under the Maastricht treaty rules on debt levels. But both Labour and Conservative politicians say it is highly unlikely Britain would want to join the first wave of countries forming a single currency pact. ($ = 0.614 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
