<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51454" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish trade gap takes wind from zloty's sails.</title>
<headline>Polish trade gap takes wind from zloty's sails.</headline>
<byline>Wojciech Moskwa</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish zloty, long under appreciation pressure as a result of the country's huge current account surplus, is losing its upward thrust as the surplus fades with little hope of returning in full force.</p>
<p>Economists said cross-border trade inflows, which financed the trade gap and kept the zloty up in the past, were too small to offset the ever-larger merchandise trade deficit.</p>
<p>In the first seven months of this year imports soared by more than 30 percent against the same period of 1995, while exports have grown by only 10 percent and cross-border trade inflows remained virutally unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;Cross-border trade is still there, but currency inflows generated by it are not as noticable on the forex market as before,&quot; said Andrzej Kopec, chief dealer at Bank Slaski SA.</p>
<p>Poland had a minute $10 million current account deficit in the January-July period, compared to a $3.2 billion surplus in the corresponding period of 1995.</p>
<p>Economists said the current account balance deteriorated because of the more than 10 percent real-term appreciation of the zloty over the last year, as well as the need for imports, especially investment imports by the emerging economy.</p>
<p>&quot;The drastic appreciation pressure on the zloty will not return,&quot; said Adam Czyzewski of the independent NOBE institute.</p>
<p>&quot;Current account flows have balanced and large-scale speculative foreign investment inflows in treasuries have ended,&quot; Czyzewski added.</p>
<p>Throughout 1995 and early this year the National Bank of Poland was forced to intervene on the forex makret to keep the zloty from strengthening, but fading appreciation pressure has kept the central bank silent since May.</p>
<p>During the last three months the zloty has weakened more than one percent against its basket of five western currencies within its 14-percent daily trading band.</p>
<p>The band's mid-point -- the parity rate -- is set daily by the central bank according to the value of the basket, comprised mainly of the dollar and the mark and a crawling peg devaluation factor, currently at one percent per month.</p>
<p>&quot;It's basically an importers market now and strong zloty aprreciation pressure is gone,&quot; said Malgorzata Sawicka, senior dealer at Bank Handlowy SA.</p>
<p>Some analysts said the zloty may continue to depreciate in the coming months as Belarus and Russia begin to implement controls on cross-border traders, curbing hard currency flows.</p>
<p>The government, however, seems intent on keeping the zloty edging up in real terms in the next several years, which would likely require cutting the devaluation factor in line with falling inflation.</p>
<p>The finance ministry and the International Monterary Fund (IMF) have signalled this week that Poland should consider more flexibility in its exchange rate policy.</p>
<p>&quot;While the crawling peg regime had served Poland well in the past, (the IMF) generally considered that a more flexible exchange rate policy could increase the effectiveness of monetary policy and bring about lower inflation,&quot; the IMF said in a report released on Friday.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Grzegosz Kolodko said he envisiged a 4.3 percent real-term appreciation of the zloty next year but did not specify how this would be achieved.</p>
<p>&quot;Poland needs to find a balanced course for zloty appreciation, so exports are not badly damaged but inflation remains headed downward,&quot; said Aleksander Welfe, head of the independent LIFEA economic think-tank.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
