<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="514846" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALTA: Palestinians want quicker final status talks -Israel.</title>
<headline>Palestinians want quicker final status talks -Israel.</headline>
<dateline>VALLETTA 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel said on Wednesday the Palestinian Authority wanted to speed up talks on the final status of the Palestinian territories.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister David Levy told reporters after meetings with Palestinian President Yasser Arafat and Planning Minister Nabil Shaath: &quot;We are glad to see that they have expressed their will to accelerate the work on the final status.</p>
<p>&quot;They have a tendency to accept this and I am certain that this is a constructive proposal on our part,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Israel proposed last month that Israeli and Palestinian negotiators aim to complete within six months the talks on &quot;final status&quot; issues -- mainly Jerusalem, Israel's borders, refugees and the status of the Palestinian territories.</p>
<p>The Palestinians reacted with suspicion because Israel coupled this with a proposal to skip the next three stages of Israeli redeployment from parts of the occupied territories.</p>
<p>Levy did not say he was reviving the same proposal in its entirety and Palestinians were not available to comment.</p>
<p>The Israeli minister described the atmosphere at his meetings with the Palestinians as good and said they showed both sides wanted to put peace talks back on track.</p>
<p>&quot;The wish to return to the right path exists. The negotiating table is the place where the two sides will be able to discuss their problems,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>For the second time in two days he proposed Israel and the Palestinians draft a code of conduct but he gave few details of what Israel envisaged.</p>
<p>&quot;(We should) create a sort of code of conduct so that both sides will abide by their obligations and there is a will to continue and work towards this goal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The European Union has also proposed a code of conduct but theirs would bind Israel to stop building settlements or changing the demographic status in disputed areas.</p>
<p>Levy defended Israel's decision to start work on a settlement on a hillside in disputed East Jerusalem -- the immediate cause of the lastest crisis in peace talks.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying as far as possible to explain that work on (the settlement on) Jabal Abu Ghneim does not violate the agreement signed,&quot; he said. He was speaking in Hebrew, with translation into either English or Arabic.</p>
<p>French Foreign Ministry spokesman Yves Doutriaux told reporters that in talks with Arafat Levy said Israel was ready to build thousands of homes for non-Jews.</p>
<p>French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette, Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussa and European special envoy Miguel Angel Moratinos were present at the meeting.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALTA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALLETTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALTA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
