<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="514849" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: BBV Q1 earnings seen jumping 24.2 pct.</title>
<headline>BBV Q1 earnings seen jumping 24.2 pct.</headline>
<byline>Sharman Esarey</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's Banco Bilbao Vizcaya is expected to report a 24.2 pct profit jump in the first quarter, but the full strength of the rise will be hidden by conservative provisioning, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Attributable profit at Spain's second-largest bank is seen at 24.61 billion pesetas, up from 19.81 billion in the same period one year ago, according to a Reuter survey of analysts conducted on Wednesday. Results are due on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically the rise is due to new units in South America and improvement in its domestic business,&quot; said Jose Sevilla, analyst at Merrill Lynch in Spain.</p>
<p>Growth in traditional loan business is outpacing competitors, as BBV has managed to protect its domestic margins despite sharp competition, analysts said. The group is also keeping a tight rein on costs.</p>
<p>Net interest income, which reflects traditional loan business, is set to rise some 22 percent amid volume growth and astute margin management, the survey showed.</p>
<p>BBV's business volume is probably growing at around 10 percent compared with eight to nine percent on average in the sector, said Juan Berberana, analyst at AB Asesores in Madrid.</p>
<p>Overall costs are expected to have risen 16 percent, given Latin American purchases, but domestic cost growth is likely not to exceed two percent, Berberana said.</p>
<p>A Latin American shopping spree -- including buying the branch networks of Banca Cremi and Banco de Oriente in Mexico, the takeover of Colombia's leading Banco Ganadero, and the acquisition of Banco Frances del Rio de la Plata -- will also add substantially to results, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Improvement in the profit and loss account will rest equally on domestic business and last year's Latin American acquisitions,&quot; Inverban said in a note.</p>
<p>But the bank's conservative bad debt policy will veil the extent of its basic strength.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very conservative bank,&quot; said AB's Juan Berberana. &quot;They are looking for extensive solidity in the balance sheet.&quot;</p>
<p>Its provisions for bad debts are already above the industry average and could grow further this quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;We calculate earnings figures released will not fully reflect the growth story at BBV given the bank's continuing conservative strategy of overprovisioning,&quot; Inverban said.</p>
<p>--Madrid Newsroom +34 1 585 2167</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
