<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="514926" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Buba - mark's value not dampened by pre-EMU shifts.</title>
<headline>Buba - mark's value not dampened by pre-EMU shifts.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German mark remains an attractive reserve currency in the run-up to Europe's currency union, the Bundesbank said on Wednesday, noting technical factors, not investment shifts had bolstered other currencies.</p>
<p>In its April report the Bundesbank shot down suggestions that the mark's recent depreciation against several key currencies, including the dollar and sterling, was triggered by a flight to quality as Germany prepares to give up the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;Apart from the fact that the data about the currency structure of international investments argues against a flight out the mark, the recent currency market developments also do not offer up a fundamentally different opinion,&quot; the Bundesbank wrote.</p>
<p>Germany and a number of other European nations plan to give up their national currencies to adopt a common European currency, the euro, in 1999. Britain at this time has no plans to adopt that new currency.</p>
<p>&quot;While the dollar and sterling have clearly appreciated in value in the last months, the appreciation is related to these currencies' earlier weakness in 1995 and also to the favourable economic fundamentals in these nations, which are also visible in the favourable interest differentials with Germany,&quot; the Bundesbank said.</p>
<p>Even as the dollar and sterling have appreciated, the Bundesbank noted that the Swiss franc, long considered a safe haven during times of crisis, had given up some of its gains recently.</p>
<p>Consequently the Bundesbank concluded, &quot;In the end, even the current interest rate and exchange rate constellations do not detract from the ongoing attractiveness the mark has as an international investment currency.&quot;</p>
<p>In order to ensure a smooth transition between the mark and the euro, allowing the euro to assume the mark's role as a reserve currency, the Bundesbank said it was paramount there be no doubts about policymakers' will to stick by budget austerity.</p>
<p>&quot;This includes an interpretation of the Maastricht Treaty convergence criteria that is strict and makes no compromises in terms of stability policy,&quot; the Bundesbank said.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
