<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51509" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan GDP slips in April-June quarter.</title>
<headline>Japan GDP slips in April-June quarter.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's economy shrank in the three months to June after strong growth in the previous quarter, the government announced on Friday.</p>
<p>The Economic Planning Agency (EPA) said gross domestic product (GDP) -- a key gauge of the economy's health -- fell a real 0.7 percent in the April-June period from the previous quarter. This would translate into a drop of 2.9 percent on an annualised basis.  </p>
<p>In the January to March period, the real GDP grew a revised 2.9 percent quarter on quarter or an annualised 12.2 percent. The GDP measures the country's output of goods and services minus net income from overseas production.</p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters estimated an average fall of quarterly 1.1 percent in the April-June period, with the forecasts ranging between a drop of 0.3 and 1.8 percent.</p>
<p>The government declared in February that the economy was gradually recovering after four years of negligible growth. But recent economic data have shown that the recovery was not gaining momentum.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto has said he would like to look at the GDP data before deciding the date of the general elections and whether to draw up an extra budget with economic stimulus steps.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
