<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="515133" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian dlr steadies, but fundamentals shaky.</title>
<headline>Australian dlr steadies, but fundamentals shaky.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar had a steadier session Wednesday recouping much of its offshore losses to end relatively flat on the day overall.</p>
<p>It touched a two-month low around US$0.7823 overnight as U.S. investment banks bailed out, but dealers said that seemed to complete the most urgent selling and good bids were evident at the lows. Exporter demand and talk of Asian buying of local bonds forced short covering which saw it regain 1/4 cent.</p>
<p>But they cautioned the bounce was more a technical reaction to an oversold position than an improvement in sentiment which remained hostage to narrowing yield differentials.  </p>
<p>By 5.00 pm (0700 GMT) the dollar had dug in at US$0.7745/50 having crept up from a US$0.7723 low, but was still short of Tuesday's US$0.7760/65 and far from Friday's US$0.7895 peak.</p>
<p>Traders said immediate support was put at US$0.7720 and US$0.7705 while resistance had already been met around US$0.7745 this morning and the currency needed to recover US$0.7785 at a minimum to counter the bearish trend.</p>
<p>Traders continued to report rumours of buying interest related to the sale of a Victorian power station and three Federal airports to largely offshore-led groups which could amount to more than A$6.0 billion of inflow.  </p>
<p>The currency had a quiet day on the crosses after slipping again overnight to end at 97.55/65 yen from a Tuesday finish 97.91/01 and at 60.2 in trade weighted terms from 60.3.</p>
<p>Today's only economic release was the Westpac consumer sentiment index and this proved slightly positive for the currency as it suggested confidence was holding up despite poor unemployment data released last week.</p>
<p>The index eased just 0.7 percent in April after rising 4.9 percent in March and a majority of consumers felt it a good time to buy a major household item. The next major release is not until next Wednesday when Q1 consumer price data are out.  </p>
<p>The U.S. equivalent was out Tuesday and showed a modest 0.2 percent rise in core CPI sparking a huge rally in equities and smaller gains in Treasury prices.</p>
<p>Unfortunately for the local dollar Australian bonds enjoyed even bigger gains which further narrowed the A$'s yield premium.</p>
<p>In any case, analysts still felt the Federal Reserve would tighten at its May meeting as growth was running well above trend and inflationary pressures had to be headed off.</p>
<p>That contrasted with Australia where the Reserve Bank confidently expected underlying inflation to remain around the floor of its 2-3 percent range for this year and into 1998.  </p>
<p>The differing outlooks had resulted in U.S. market interest rates for periods from nine months to one year rising above those in Australia, while yields on Australian one and two-year bonds had dipped below those offered by Treasuries.</p>
<p>This was a seminal event for Australian debt since the market had long demanded a premium for holding it due, amongst other things, to a poor record of inflation control in the 1970s and 80s and a deteriorating fiscal position.</p>
<p>Longer-dated domestic bonds did still pay more than their U.S. counterparts but the spread had shrunk dramatically in the last year as the RBA impressed with its anti-inflation stance.  </p>
<p>The government had also undertaken to correct the budget deficit, helping the 10-year spread contract to just 96 basis points today from more than 300 a year ago.</p>
<p>This in turn had mixed implications for the Australian dollar, which had often relied on its status as a high yielding currency to attract foreign funds.</p>
<p>On the one hand the reduction, and in some cases disappearance, of its short term interest premium was likely to see hot money head for the U.S. dollar and other better paying alternatives like sterling.  </p>
<p>However, the relatively subdued outlook for inflation here when compared to the U.S., and the U.K. for that matter, meant offshore investors should become more confident about holding Australian debt and other assets.</p>
<p>This trend should prove supportive of the local dollar in the long run, although for now the course of short term differentials was likely to mesmerise the market.</p>
<p>-- Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
