<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="515152" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: S&amp;P affirms Australian Capital Territory ratings.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P affirms Australian Capital Territory ratings.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's said it has affirmed the Australian Capital Territory's (ACT) AAA for long term and A1-plus short-term local currency ratings.  </p>
<p>It also affirmed the AA long-term and A1-plus short term foreign currency ratings on the ACT government. The foreign currency ratings reflected the sovereign credit risks associated with the rating on the Commonwealth Government of Australia.</p>
<p>The local currency outlook is stable, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>The local currency ratings of the ACT government reflected its extremely low debt levels, solid economic base and sound budgetary performance, the rating agency said.</p>
<p>The supporting relationship between the Federal and State/Territorial Governments in Australia also underpinned the rating, as did Canberra's place as the national capital.  </p>
<p>The ACT has the lowest debt burden of all Australian States and Territories as a result of the Commonwealth Government not transferring any state-type general government debt to the ACT on self-government, and successive ACT governments taking a low-debt approach to financing activities, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the ACT economy has been severely affected by the cuts to Commonwealth outlays since the election of the Federal Liberal-National Party Government in March 1996, the ACT continues to have a solid fundametal economic base,&quot; S&amp;P added,  </p>
<p>On the stable outlook, S&amp;P said that while borrowing requirements would add to debt over the next year, the ACT had significant flexibility to deal with any future revenue or expenditure shocks.</p>
<p>The foreign currency outlook was positive, reflecting the outlook on the Commonwealth Government of Australia.</p>
<p>--Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
