<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="515174" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia sells LNG to U.S. as Japan demand falls.</title>
<headline>Australia sells LNG to U.S. as Japan demand falls.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Faced with a drop in demand from its traditional Japanese market, Australia's North West shelf partnership has agreed to sell three cargoes of liquified natural gas (LNG) to a U.S. company on a spot sales basis, operator Woodside Petroleum Ltd told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We can confirm three cargoes are going to the U.S.,&quot; a Woodside official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>It is the first time sales have been made to the U.S., the official said. The first cargo of around 125,000 cubic metres of LNG is scheduled for April 24, the official said.  </p>
<p>Subsequent shipments were scheduled for later this year, he said.</p>
<p>The buyer of the LNG is Boston-based Distrigas, a 100 percent subsidiary of Cabot Corp, the official said.</p>
<p>The first shipment is to be loaded onto the Khannur, a vessel owned by Cabot, the official said.</p>
<p>Japanese utility and industrial users typically buy most of the seven million tonnes of LNG produced annually from the North West Shelf under long-term contracts.</p>
<p>However, a downturn in demand has left the partnership with excess LNG to sell, the official said.  </p>
<p>Woodside declined to say at what price the negotiated sales were made, although they are usually sold at a discount to long-term contracts.</p>
<p>The equal stakeholders in the North West Shelf gas project are Woodside, The Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd, The British Petroleum Co Plc, Chevron Corp Royal Dutch/Shell Group and Japan Australia LNG (MIMI) Pty Ltd.</p>
<p>The partnership is in negotiations with Japanese customers to double output of the North West Shelf, located offshore the state of Western Australia.  </p>
<p>The expansion is unlikely before around 2001 and hinges on the partners and the Japanese customers signing long-term contracts extending out as far as 20 years</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
