<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="515499" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek stocks firm as bank shares strengthen.</title>
<headline>Greek stocks firm as bank shares strengthen.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Athens general share index was trading 1.10 percent higher in early trade after scenarios on the low profitability of certain banks were ruled out, market watchers said.</p>
<p>&quot;On Wednesday, the session will end firmer. There is no more concern about the low profitability of the banking sector, so the index will go up,&quot; said John Vezanis, the chairman at Midland Hellenobretanniki Mutual Funds.</p>
<p>Special concern with regard to the share of the National Mortgage Bank  NMGr.AT due to its low profits has also subsided, he added.</p>
<p>Vezanis said the 1997 outlook for the Greek bourse was very positive.</p>
<p>Another assistant portfolio manager said the benchmark index would fluctuate plus or minus 0.5 percent on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market is directionless and I can only predict a 0.5 percent fluctuation for the benchmark index, on a daily basis,&quot; said assistant portfolio manager at Allianz Mutual Funds, Yianna Tziovara.</p>
<p>Greece's current account deficit rose 59 percent year-on-year to $4.5 billion in 1996, the widening reflecting a 7.1 percent higher trade deficit of $18.3 billion.</p>
<p>The Athens general share index was trading 1.10 percent or 15.39 points higher at 1,410.28 from Tuesday's 1,394.89 close, after opening at 1,400.87.</p>
<p>The ING Baring Financial Products American style call warrant based on a basket of six bank stocks was quoted higher at $55.90-$57.60. The strike price is set at $99.60 and the warrants expire October 8, 1997.</p>
<p>The ING Baring Financial Products American- style call warrant on a basket of six blue-chips denominated in drachmas was quoted at 1,879-2,069 drachmas.</p>
<p>The strike price is set at 10,000 drachmas and the warrants expire on February 2, 1998.</p>
<p>The recently launched ING Baring American-style second call warrant on a basket of six bank stocks was quoted higher at $11.43-$13.13. The strike price is set at $110.0 and the warrants expire April 9 1998. --Margarita Sotiropoulou, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
