<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51558" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UAL, GE, McDonnell to pay $15 mln in crash suit.</title>
<headline>UAL, GE, McDonnell to pay $15 mln in crash suit.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>UAL Corp, General Electric Co and McDonnell Douglas Corp agreed to pay $15 million to an Illinois man whose wife and child were killed in a 1989 United Airlines crash, the plaintiff's attorney said on Friday.</p>
<p>Robert Clifford, an attorney for Terry Brown, said the settlement was among the last from the crash in Sioux City, Iowa, that killed 112 of the 296 people on board and injured the other 184. More than 285 cases from the crash have now been settled.</p>
<p>Brown, a resident of Barrington, Illinois, lost his 38-year-old wife, Janice, and 11-year-old daughter, Kimberly, in the crash. The settlement of the Brown case was approved about two weeks ago by Judge Donald O'Connell of the Circuit Court of Cook County, Brown's attorney said.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for UAL, parent of United Airlines, said the case was settled &quot;to the satisifaction of both parties,&quot; referring to the airline and the plaintiff.</p>
<p>The amount of the settlement to be paid by each of the three defendants has not been determined yet, Rick Kennedy, a spokesman for GE Aircraft Engines, said. A McDonnell Douglas spokesman said the three defendants were parties in a separate suit to determine the percentage of the settlements each company will pay.</p>
<p>As part of the Brown suit, Kennedy said, GE was prepared to acknowledge the defendants' corporate responsibility for the circumstances that led to the accident. He stressed GE did not admit to sole responsibility for the crash, which was caused by a crack in an aircraft engine fan disk that had not been detected in maintenance inspections.</p>
<p>United Airlines Flight 232 crashed on July 19, 1989, after the rear engine suddenly lost power. The plane flipped over and broke into pieces just short of the Sioux City airport runway while making an emergency landing after its hydraulic systems failed in mid-air.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
