<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="515500" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spanish Endesa share offer seen absorbed.</title>
<headline>Spanish Endesa share offer seen absorbed.</headline>
<byline>Elisabeth O'Leary</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>An autumn sale of shares in electricity group Endesa is likely to go well, even if Spain sells more than originally planned, as it will primarily be aimed at small shareholders, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if the government increases the offering to a 33 percent stake, I wouldn't have thought there would be a great problem placing it,&quot; said an analyst at a foreign brokerage in Madrid.</p>
<p>The government still owns 67 percent of Empresa Nacional de Electricidad (Endesa), via state holding company SEPI, with a market value of more than 1.5 trillion pesetas ($10.3 billion).</p>
<p>Spain had initially planned to sell its remaining Endesa shares in three lots, starting this year.</p>
<p>But the unparalleled success of public share offerings in other blue chips such as Telefonica in February and energy group Repsol this month have prompted the state to consider selling a bigger chunk of Endesa this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Originally the government had set a limit of 25 percent for this year's placement but, seeing how well the Telefonica and Repsol offers were received, it became clear that there is tremendous demand out there and there's room for a bigger stake,&quot; an official source told Reuters.</p>
<p>The design of the sale should offer at least 60 percent of the shares to retail investors. If Telefonica and Repsol are anything to go by, there is more than enough interest from the Spanish public to absorb such a big offering.</p>
<p>&quot;This more or less guarantees the success of the venture,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>SEPI chairman Pedro Ferreras said last week that the government might sell 40 percent of the electric utility this year.</p>
<p>Analysts think the state may opt for slightly less, privatising the firm in two portions of roughly 33 percent this year and next.</p>
<p>A bigger sale than originally expected should not have any lasting negative effect on Endesa's listed share price, currently at around 9,400 pesetas, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;(A bigger offering) doesn't necessarily have to be worse. I think the (current) shares will be supported, although the initial effect might be to bring them lower,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>Traders may initially sell the current shares ahead of the new offer but this should not affect the success of the operation, according to a Credit Lyonnais Securities analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;Short term the fact that traders are thinking of the increased supply might give the stock a negative tone but I don't think a bigger placement will be a bad thing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;(A negative market reaction now) might also be to do with the fact that people thought the government could be nervous that next year's placement might not go so well. But I don't think that will be the case,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He expected Endesa shares to trade around 10,500 pesetas in the medium term.</p>
<p>The prospects for a successful share offering are coupled with good forecasts for the company's performance.</p>
<p>Endesa is expected to earn profits of around 184 billion pesetas in 1997, up from 165.09 billion in 1996, according to a Reuters poll of analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;Given how well Telefonica and Repsol went, coupled with positive surprises from the company itself in terms of performance over the year, the privatisation shouldn't upset the market,&quot; a Spanish analyst said. ($ = 145.5 Spanish Pesetas)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
