<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="515631" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: PanCanadian unveils major growth plan.</title>
<headline>PanCanadian unveils major growth plan.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>PanCanadian Petroleum Ltd, targeting major growth over the next five years, expects big financial and operating gains in 1997, its chief executive said on Thursday.</p>
<p>PanCanadian's David Tuer said the company was projecting earnings this year of C$400 million or C$3.20 a share and cash flow of C$1.03 billion or C$8.20 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;This will result in a return on equity in excess of 15.5 percent,&quot; Tuer told the company's annual meeting.  </p>
<p>In 1996, PanCanadian, 87 percent owned by Canadian Pacific Ltd, posted earnings of C$346 million or C$2.75 a share and cash flow of C$1 billion or C$7.97 a share.</p>
<p>Tuer said a C$1 billion 1997 capital spending budget was expected to help PanCanadian reach average production of 150,000 barrels per day of crude oil and natural gas liquids and 780 million cubic feet per day of natural gas.</p>
<p>That would be an increase from 1996 averages of 146,331 barrels per day of oil and liquids and 717 million cubic feet per day of gas.  </p>
<p>He said about C$320 million of the company's 1997 budget would be directed to exploration and C$650 million to development drilling. Most of the money would be spent in western Canada.</p>
<p>However, about C$95 million would flow to PanCanadian's international operations, which Tuer said were poised for major growth. Current international projects include exploration and development in the North Sea, Australia, Libya, the U.S. Gulf of Mexico and South Africa.</p>
<p>Through domestic and international operations, the company has targeted a doubling of production by 2002, Tuer said.  </p>
<p>Not included in the 1997 budget are plans to make an acquisition of international assets that could be valued at between C$1.0 billion and C$1.5 billion, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We need 40 percent of that growth to come from the international side and we don't think we can get our international production up to 80,000 or 90,000 barrels a day without kickstarting it with some form of acquisition,&quot; he told reporters after the meeting.</p>
<p>He said PanCanadian was looking in various parts of the globe and was looking favorably at potential assets in the North Sea, where the company has recently bolstered activity.  </p>
<p>&quot;We've certainly been at the table to negotiate acquisitions at some of the auctions that we've seen...in different parts of the world over the past year. We just haven't been successful so far,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The company was recently successful in acquiring three new exploration licences comprising 600,000 acres in the United Kingdom's 17th licencing round and three others in the Gulf of Mexico deep water region.</p>
<p>In western Newfoundland, where PanCanadian and Dallas-based Hunt Oil Co raised speculation over the possibility of a major oil find last in 1995, the company still believes in the region's potential, he said.</p>
<p>The firms last summer put their drilling program on hold after they drilled a dry hole at a much-watched well after a successful first location, Port au Port No. 1.</p>
<p>&quot;(The No. 1 location) encountered crude oil and I think all the residents of the island were very candid about that. That well flowed significant volumes of high-quality crude oil,&quot; Tuer said.</p>
<p>&quot;That basin has all of the ingredients that you would expect to find in a world-class hydrocarbon basin.&quot;</p>
<p>He said, however, that the partners had no plans to resume drilling there this year, partially because of the increased cost of securing a drilling rig.</p>
<p>((Reuters Calgary Bureau (403) 531-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
