<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="515602" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: San Miguel earnings growth seen sluggish.</title>
<headline>San Miguel earnings growth seen sluggish.</headline>
<byline>Ramoncito dela Cruz</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Earnings growth at San Miguel Corp is likely to remain sluggish in the near term because the spin-off of its Coca-Cola bottling unit may not yield quick gains and its product lines are under pressure, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There should be some short-term weakness in its earnings,&quot; Mayenne Katimbang, vice president for research of Magnum International Securities, said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>She said food and beverage giant San Miguel's bottom line could be hurt by the merger of one of its most lucrative units, Coca-Cola Bottlers Philippines Inc (CCBPI), with Australia's Coca-Cola Amatil.</p>
<p>CCBPI has 75 percent of the domestic beverage market and contributed 39 percent to San Miguel's net income last year.</p>
<p>The Coca-Cola deal, approved by San Miguel shareholders on Tuesday, involves a share swap through which CCBPI will become a wholly-owned subsidiary of Coca-Cola Amatil, and San Miguel will in return get 25 percent of Amatil's stock.</p>
<p>The deal will mean San Miguel will become Amatil's second-largest shareholder after Coca-Cola Co.</p>
<p>San Miguel officials defended the Amatil deal at the firm's annual stockholders' meeting on Tuesday, saying it would benefit the company, but analysts remained sceptical.</p>
<p>&quot;We agree that there will be long-term benefits from the deal, but this will come in a very, very long while. Its contribution will not be significant in the next three years,&quot; a senior analyst at a foreign securities firm said.</p>
<p>He said sales in Coca-Cola Amatil's overseas markets, such as eastern European countries, were not expected to grow significantly in the coming years.</p>
<p>The market's wariness pummelled San Miguel's widely held B shares to a low of 75.50 pesos earlier this month. The company's strong defence of the deal helped it recover and on Wednesday it rose 3.50 pesos to 85.50.</p>
<p>In 1996, San Miguel posted a two percent decline in net income excluding non-recurring items to 5.26 billion pesos ($200 million) due to a slowdown in sales growth and a squeeze on margins.</p>
<p>Ben Hermoso, an analyst at Dharmala Securities, said San Miguel's food businesses, which include poultry, hogs and feeds, were not expected to recover soon because of high raw material costs and a glut in supplies since last year.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't expect much from the food business...The industry hasn't shown any improvement,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Joy Quintos, research head at Capitol Securities One, said beer sales were not expected to perform well because of keener competition, especially from foreign brands, as well as a shift in consumer taste to non-alcoholic beverages.</p>
<p>An analyst from a local brokerage house also blamed San Miguel's aggressive beer pricing strategy for the expected lower volume turnover this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The company is getting a little bit reckless about its pricing,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The wholesale price of San Miguel Beer is currently 210 pesos per case as against rival Asia Brewery's &quot;Beer na Beer&quot; brand which is sold at only 130 pesos per case.</p>
<p>The San Miguel management, however, is confident its moves augur well for the company in the long run.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident that, as the economy continues to prosper and we derive more benefits from our investments and various programmes here and abroad, your company is moving into a new era of growth and prosperity,&quot; chief finance officer Delfin Gonzalez told stockholders on Tuesday. ($1 = 26.30 pesos)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
