<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="515785" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed's Rivlin sees indicators of consumer demand.</title>
<headline>Fed's Rivlin sees indicators of consumer demand.</headline>
<dateline>PHILADELPHIA, Pa. 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Federal Reserve Vice Chair Alice Rivlin said on Thursday the U.S. economy was showing &quot;very strong&quot; indications of consumer demand, and that rapid growth in demand was very likely to cause future inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy at the moment is showing very strong indicators of consumer demand. As one looks ahead, this rapid growth in demand is very likely, judging by past experience, to give us some inflation down the line,&quot; Rivlin told a seminar at the University of Pennsylvania's Wharton School.  </p>
<p>Rivlin also told the seminar that productivity appears to be increasing faster than economists had thought, enabling companies to maintain profits at a time of rising wage pressures and an inability to pass along costs.</p>
<p>&quot;Productivity must be increasing faster than we thought it was or we couldn't have strong growth in both wages and costs, and profits holding up ... unless productivity were going up faster than we've been measuring,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She said, however, that productivity gains may partly reflect mismeasurement of the service sector, which she noted was very difficult to measure.</p>
<p>Rivlin also said the Fed's latest interest rate hike reflected a perception within the Fed that there was a risk of accelerated inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be sensible to take out a small insurance policy against that risk,&quot; she said of the recent rate hike.</p>
<p>She said it was uncertain how long the economy would remain at current strengths.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHILADELPHIA, Pa."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
