<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51577" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish bourse at record high after strong day.</title>
<headline>Swedish bourse at record high after strong day.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Swedish stockmarket closed on Friday at a record high with help from the investment sector and gaining steam after U.S. CPI data.</p>
<p>Both the bourse's general index and the OMX index closed at highs. The general index rose 1.25 percent to 2,057.65 and the OMX ended above 1,600 for the first time at 1,613.23, up 1.48 percent. Turnover was a healthy 4.9 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Investment stocks saw strong gains on a report the government planned to make tax changes which would reduce the tax investment companies had to pay if they split up.</p>
<p>Investor jumped eight crowns to 254 crowns.</p>
<p>Development company Sintercast was the star performer, soaring 56 crowns to 311 crowns after announcing its first agreement to install its technology for casting car engine blocks in a plant in Mexico.</p>
<p>Sintercast has plummeted in recent weeks after revelations that up to 57 percent of its stock was held by one of the Morgan Grenfell funds under investigation.</p>
<p>Incentive soared 21 crowns to a record 390, which brokers said was due in part to its roadshow in London this week.</p>
<p>Forestry shares fared worse than the broad market, the sector index rising only 0.50 percent.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley said it was cutting its recommendations on on MoDo to an underperform from a strong buy and on Stora to neutral from a strong buy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
