<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="516067" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: McDonald's sees record-breaking year.</title>
<headline>McDonald's sees record-breaking year.</headline>
<dateline>OAK BROOK, Ill. 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>McDonald's Corp said Thursday it generated record 1997 first quarter results despite intense competition and expects record year results.</p>
<p>&quot;McDonald's global foodservice business delivered strong results in the first quarter,&quot; Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Michael R. Quinlan said. &quot;Despite the extremely competitive U.S. operating environment, we delivered impressive growth in U.S. sales and operating income, exceeding our own expectations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident in our growth strategies and expect 1997 to be another record-breaking year,&quot; he said in a statement.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are poised to have a strong year outside the U.S., despite a slow start attributable to weak economies in several major international markets, severe weather in Europe, weaker foreign currencies and difficult comparisons due to the strong performance of many markets in first quarter 1996,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>McDonald's 1997 first quarter earnings rose to $344.5 million or $0.49 a share from $301.6 million or $0.42 in the same period a year ago. Revenues from company owned restaurants increased eight percent from a year ago to $2.62 billion. Systemwide sales from all restaurants advanced seven percent from last year to $7.83 billion.  </p>
<p>McDonald's said it plans to add between 2,400 and 2,800 restaurants globally in 1997 with a greater emphasis on full-size traditional restaurants and international locations compared with 1996. More than 70 percent of 1997 openings will be outside the U.S.</p>
<p>The company said it was able to maintain profit margins at levels similar to first quarter 1996 despite difficult sales comparisons and weak economies.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, James Cantalupo, president of McDonald's international operations, said, &quot;I expect our international results to improve for the balance of the year.&quot;  </p>
<p>At the end of the first quarter, McDonald's had 21,276 restaurants, of which 12,104 were located in the U.S..  During the quarter, 254 restaurants were added, 10 in the U.S.</p>
<p>McDonald's said a seven percent increase in U.S. sales  was significant given an extremely competitive U.S. operating environment, and one less trading day in the quarter because 1996 was a leap year. Sales benefited from marketing and promotions including Monopoly and Chicken McNuggets. Weather patterns year over year had a negligible effect on results.</p>
<p>McDonald's sales rose seven percent outside the U.S. Weaker foreign currencies and negative comparable sales on a constant currency basis tempered the results, it said. If exchange rates had remained at 1996 levels, sales outside the U.S. would have increased 14 percent.</p>
<p>Strong comparable sales last year, weak economies, as well as one less trading day and severe weather in Europe in 1997, contributed to the weakness in comparable sales in first quarter 1997, it said.</p>
<p>McDonald's said it expects results to improve for the balance of the year.</p>
<p>Shares of McDonald's were trading up 1/4 to 50-5/8.</p>
<p>		  ((Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OAK BROOK, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
