<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51606" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: MGAM woes a setback, but no disaster-senior source.</title>
<headline>MGAM woes a setback, but no disaster-senior source.</headline>
<byline>David Crossland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Recent problems at funds run by London-based Deutsche Morgan Grenfell stemmed from human frailty and a breakdown in controls but could have happened to any bank and will not do the company long term harm, a senior source said on Friday.</p>
<p>The source, who is close to Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, the investment banking unit of Germany's Deutsche Bank AG, said he doubted if a rerouting of reporting lines for MG's unit trust business to Frankfurt would be efficient.</p>
<p>The affair was a &quot;setback rather than a disaster&quot; which was confined to a small part of Morgan Grenfell's business, the source, who declined to be named, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not think it represents a serious, long-term dramatic danger to the future of Morgan Grenfell Asset Management,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>The funds, which were temporarily suspended last week, accounted for just two percent of MGAM's 70.0 billion pounds ($109 billion) under management.</p>
<p>MGAM halted trading in the three European funds due to suspected irregularities over investments in unlisted stocks. The affair embarrassed Deutsche, sparked fears it may lose its triple-A credit rating, and rattled confidence in unit trusts.</p>
<p>The problems highlighted the fact that performance was generally the main criterion for choosing investment managers and showed how important it was for funds to have adequate capital backing, which Deutsche had been able to provide, the source said.</p>
<p>The manager of two of the troubled MGAM funds, Peter Young, has been suspended and his assets frozen pending a probe into the management of the trusts, which held a high proportion of speculative, unlisted, high-technology stocks.</p>
<p>Deutsche last week took those stocks onto its books in return for a 180 million pound cash injection into MGAM and has pledged it will provide further backing if necessary.</p>
<p>The source said additional sums may have to be injected if the current probe by MG and the British fund management watchdog, IMRO, found that investors had to be compensated for a fall in the funds' value, and if penalties had to be paid.</p>
<p>Deutsche has pledged to put MGAM under tighter control from Frankfurt and has said the problems have given new impetus to a long-standing idea to shift reporting lines for MGAM's unit trust business -- its non-institutional funds -- to Frankfurt.</p>
<p>But the source said this may be an inefficient move.</p>
<p>Putting the retail fund side of MGAM under a new reporting regime could lead to a duplication of costs since MGAM fund managers at present ran institutional funds as well as unit trusts at the same time, he said. It may necessitate running yet another investment management group.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;Deutsche also has a very large retail investment business in Germany so in the overall scheme of things that may be the right thing to do.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked whether German control systems were more effective than those in Britain, the source said: &quot;I think we all know what the control environment should be.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm afraid to say that for every major multi-service financial institution there have to be risks in the kind of business we conduct.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt there was a breakdown in effective control and supervision which permitted some unsound investments to be made contrary to guidelines under which investment managers were operating. That can happen elsewhere as well.&quot;</p>
<p>The affair would affect Deutsche's 1996 results to the extent that there was a need to write off the value of the assets Deutsche had taken onto its books, the source said.</p>
<p>But the value of those holdings had yet to be determined. Several of the holdings faced initial price offerings in the coming months and could, therefore, increase in value. ($1=.6430 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
