<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="516302" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. stocks seen mixed at start.</title>
<headline>U.S. stocks seen mixed at start.</headline>
<byline>Andrej Gustincic</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street stocks are expected to open mixed on Thursday after a rally yesterday which was concentrated in blue chips while the broader market remained mixed.</p>
<p>Analysts said that most of the action will likely once again come during the last hour of trading, when programs are expected to kick in.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the same kind of Dow rally we keep seeing again and again,&quot; said Larry Wachtel, analyst at Prudential Securities. &quot;Volatility is a way of life.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said that with the addition of new components to the Dow Industrial Average, people have grown attuned daily swings of one hundred points or so.</p>
<p>&quot;A handful of blue chips did the work,&quot; he said.  &quot;Foreign markets don't show an explosive followthrough.  The Dow fell 10 percent in less than a month.</p>
<p>&quot;We are seeing a move into cyclicals like steel, chemicals and autos.  We are moving away, at least for the time being, from techs.  It's a rotational story.&quot;</p>
<p>The opening will also be influenced by February international trade data and weekly jobless claims.  </p>
<p>In Tokyo, the Nikkei Average rose 62.21 points, or 0.35 percent, to 18,093.41.</p>
<p>In London, the FTSE 100 Index was up 6.5 at 4301.1</p>
<p>U.S. shares were steady to firmer on Thursday following Wall Street's third straight winning session on Wednesday but trading activity, with the exception of red-hot tobaccos, was light, as investors remained wary about the Dow's rally.</p>
<p>Philip Morris Cos Inc which jumped $4-3/8 on Wednesday, accounting for 15 percent or 14 points of the Dow's gains, was up $1/4 to $43-1/2, while RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp added $1/8 to $33-5/8 after a $3-1/4 spurt in New York.  </p>
<p>Cyrix Corp was up $2-1/2 to $20-1/4 in Europe after hitting a high of $21 in U.S. after-hours in reaction to the company's strong first-quarter earnings report.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Microsoft Corp was up $1/2 to $97-3/4 ahead of its third-quarter figures due later on Thursday.</p>
<p>Shares in Gillette Co were shaved $3/8 lower to $81-1/2 after soaring over five percent in New York on Wednesday in anticipation of strong first-quarter figures later today.</p>
<p>The dollar slid against the mark and yen in Tokyo and was in a tight range in Europe.  </p>
<p>U.S. treasuries were mostly higher, with the long bond up 4/32 to yield 7.09 percent.</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal's Heard on the Street writes that a $300 billion pricetag for the tobacco industry to settle its liability for smoking-related damages might seem impossibly expensive, even if stretched out over 25 years. Yet tobacco stocks shot up yesterday.</p>
<p>The New York Times Market Place writes that investors have become a little hesitant about committing more cash to Boston Chicken Inc.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
