<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51636" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: FOCUS- Dutch Aug inflation falls to 1.9 pct yr/yr.</title>
<headline>FOCUS- Dutch Aug inflation falls to 1.9 pct yr/yr.</headline>
<dateline>VOORBURG, Netherlands 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dutch consumer price index (CPI) fell a provisional 0.1 percent in August from July, giving a 1.9 percent year-on-year rise, the Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS) said on Friday.</p>
<p>Economists at major Dutch banks had forecast consumer inflation to be between 2.0 and 2.3 percent, versus a revised July figure of 2.2 percent.</p>
<p>But the CBS said that the surprise fall could be a one-off.</p>
<p>&quot;For the moment, the fall in consumer prices seems to be an incidental development,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Prices for vegetables, fruit and potatoes fell because of favourable weather, while clothes were more expensive due to the introduction of the new winter collection, it said.</p>
<p>However, while clothes prices were not rising as fast as last year, some of the price hikes could trickle through into September, the CBS said.</p>
<p>Consumer prices in other categories remained mostly stable.</p>
<p>The gap between Dutch and German inflation remained at a steady 0.5 percentage points. German August inflation was pegged at 1.4 percent yr/yr from 1.6 percent in July.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E71">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VOORBURG, Netherlands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
