<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="516403" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Japan faces serious financial strains - Summers.</title>
<headline>Japan faces serious financial strains - Summers.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan faces profound economic challenges and needs to pursue a policy of domestic demand-led growth, U.S. Deputy Treasury Secretary Lawrence Summers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Among those challenges, he told the Economic Strategy Institute, were &quot;very, very serious financial strains,&quot; an aging population, and an economy overburdened by regulation.</p>
<p>&quot;The Japanese economy faces profound challenges,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Summers argued that the best way for Japan to overcome these problems was through an economic &quot;expansion led from within.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;That is crucial in order to avoid a recurrence of the kind of strains that existed at some points in the past,&quot; he said, in apparent reference to Tokyo's past friction with its trading partners, including the United States.</p>
<p>Summers spent much of his speech at the dinner meeting arguing that the United States had much to gain and little to fear from economic globalization.</p>
<p>With U.S. trade barriers already very low, the United States stands to benefit from entry into barrier-reducing trade pacts with foreign countries, he said.</p>
<p>Where trade pacts are violated, the United States will react strongly, he said.</p>
<p>He said that what he called the &quot;continued seriousness&quot; of the U.S. trade deficit showed the critical importance of bringing down trade barriers overseas.</p>
<p>He also noted that increased U.S. savings would help reduce the trade deficit.</p>
<p>&quot;We've made some progress (in increasing savings) but we need to do a lot more,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
