<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="516571" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: SLOVAK GOVT PREPARING MEASURES TO HELP TRADE GAP.</title>
<headline>SLOVAK GOVT PREPARING MEASURES TO HELP TRADE GAP.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Slovak government is preparing a series of measures to reverse the trend of the country's widening trade deficit, a senior Economics Ministry official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Deputy Economics Minister Jan Foltin told a meeting of leading local businessmen the government did not expect the 1997 trade shortfall to significantly exceed 1996's gap of 64.54 billion crowns.</p>
<p>But, he added that short-, mid-, and long-term measures to help improve the trade situation will be taken.</p>
<p>&quot;The adminitrative measures to curb import growth are not against the WTO principles...we think we have the right to protect our economy with instruments that are common even in developed economies,&quot; Foltin said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will rely mainly on pro-export measures, such as the already approved EXIM bank or the state pro-export loan guarantees, to help improve the trade balance,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He added that short-term moves will include changes in the government policy for extending state gurantees for loans.</p>
<p>&quot;At present, almost every government loan guarantee goes to cover imports, but this will change and the guarantees will from now also go to export loans,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Foltin said the government plans to extend such loan guarantees mainly for countries which it considers the most promising trade targets -- the Russia and Ukraine.</p>
<p>Mid-term measures, he said, will include a package of laws aimed at curbing consumption-oriented imports that he hopes parliament will approve in the first half of the year.</p>
<p>The laws will include protection against excessive imports -- limiting imports of some goods that are also produced in Slovakia -- and protection against subsidised imports, Foltin said. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Earlier this year parliament approved a law banning imports at dumping prices.</p>
<p>Foltin said he expected last year's major imports -- autos, repayment of Russian debt with delivery of goods and oil and gas -- to slow their growth dynamic this year.</p>
<p>These items together accounted for just over one half of last year's deficit.</p>
<p>Auto imports fell 12.1 percent, year-on-year, for the January-February period of 1997, after the government re-imposed a 17.5 percent duty on imports of new cars with engines of 1,500cc from the beginning of this year.</p>
<p>The trade deficit totalled 10.821 billion crowns for the January-February period, down from 13.193 billion for the same period last year.</p>
<p>-- Peter Laca, Bratislava Newsroom, 421-7-521-8402</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
