<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="516518" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: TENNIS-ANGRY MUSTER CRASHES OUT TO PIOLINE.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-ANGRY MUSTER CRASHES OUT TO PIOLINE.</headline>
<byline>Richard Bastin</byline>
<dateline>BARCELONA 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reigning champion Thomas Muster crashed out of the Barcelona Open on Thursday after failing to cope with either the windy conditions or his temper in a straight-sets defeat by Cedric Pioline.</p>
<p>Muster broke his racquet on the ground after losing a first set tie-break and then responded to jeers by gesturing back to the crowd before finally losing the tie 7-6 6-4.</p>
<p>The Austrian had struggled in his first clay court game of the season on Tuesday, and against Pioline he once again looked short of practice on a surface which he has made his own.</p>
<p>&quot;My game has changed a bit, I'm now better on hard courts, but I've got six weeks till Paris and the French Open,&quot; Muster said.</p>
<p>&quot;I maybe played 20 percent under my level and sometimes that isn't enough. You can't play 48 weeks, all the tournaments well, and this time it happened in Barcelona.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It was cold and it was windy, which I don't like,&quot; added Muster, whose problems were exacerbated by Pioline's probing baseline game.</p>
<p>The world number two and number one seed made a series of uncharacteristic unforced errors, and failed to put away some loose balls on crucial points.</p>
<p>Muster broke back from 3-1 down in the first set and looked to have clawed his way back into the match after forcing the tie-break.</p>
<p>But he lost his way after lobbing out after a thrilling 30-stroke rally that gave the Frenchman set point.</p>
<p>&quot;I saw that Muster was nervous because I was playing well and when I won that point he saw that I could fight,&quot; said Pioline, who had never beaten Muster before.</p>
<p>The Austrian lost his way at that stage and broke his racquet in disgust after losing the tie-break 7-4.</p>
<p>Muster responded to jeers in characteristically belligerant fashion by gesturing like a conductor asking for more volume from an orchestra.</p>
<p>&quot;(I broke it) because I was so happy at that moment,&quot; Muster said ironically. &quot;The crowd pay money and they can do whatever they want.&quot;</p>
<p>The second set went with serve until 5-4 when Pioline clinched victory on the second of two match points.</p>
<p>Pioline, seeded 16, faces a quarter-final match against Albert Costa, who was given a walkover after Germany's Marc Goellner withdrew with a fever.</p>
<p>If he beats Pioline, Costa will join fellow Spaniard Carlos Moya in the world's top ten.</p>
<p>Earlier Moya had been made to fight by unknown Moroccan Hicham Arazi.</p>
<p>&quot;The game was not easy. He's got a difficult game with strange spins and the wind was difficult for both of us,&quot; the Australian Open finalist said.</p>
<p>Moya faces a quarter-final clash against Andrei Medvedev, who needed three sets to end the run of qualifier Alberto Martin.</p>
<p>Another qualifier, Albert Portas, continued to upset the odds with a 7-5 3-6 6-1 win over compatriot Fernando Vicente.</p>
<p>Portas is set to face Morocco's Karim Alami on Friday. The winner will fill a semifinal berth against either Brazilian Fernando Meligeni or former French Open finalist Alberto Berasategui.</p>
<p>Ninth-seeded Berasategui came back from 4-1 down in the first set to dispatch fellow Spaniard Felix Mantilla 7-6 6-1.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BARCELONA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
