<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="516649" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: RTF SAYS SEES CLOSE TO PLAN ON Q1 RESULTS.</title>
<headline>RTF SAYS SEES CLOSE TO PLAN ON Q1 RESULTS.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Riga Transport Fleet (RTF) said on Wednesday that its first quarter results were close to target although it would not reveal any figures.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not have the results yet but I believe that there will be no large deviations from plan,&quot; Oleg Kolosov, RTF's general manager, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The company said that the first quarter results will be made available on April 24.</p>
<p>RTF refused to name the target figures for 1997 as they were currently undergoing a review.</p>
<p>Its profit for distribution was 1.23 million lats in the first quarter of 1996 on turnover of 3.88 million lats and expenses of 2.64 million lats.  </p>
<p>The company has already said it plans to pay one dividend per share out of its 1996 profits, which will be voted on at the shareholder meeting.</p>
<p>It said it has 17 refrigerator ships, operating throughout the world.</p>
<p>RTF is 55.5 percent by Greek Lavinia Corp, the fourth largest reefer company in the world. New Century Holdings have 22.3 percent and employees 12.6 percent.</p>
<p>Four of its vessels were bought in the summer of 1996 while the rest are from Soviet times.</p>
<p>-- Martinsh Gravitis, Riga newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
