<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="516782" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: U.N. envoy says Zaire's Mobutu, Kabila to meet.</title>
<headline>U.N. envoy says Zaire's Mobutu, Kabila to meet.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's President Mobutu Sese Seko and rebel leader Laurent Kabila have agreed in principle to meet for talks, the U.N.'s special envoy on Zaire announced on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The outcome we have today (is) the agreement in principle by the two parties to meet at the highest level ... to discuss transitional arrangements,&quot; U.N. envoy Mohamed Sahnoun told a news conference.</p>
<p>South African deputy foreign affairs minister Aziz Pahad told the news conference President Nelson Mandela had formally invited Mobutu to meet Kabila for talks in South Africa and these would take place without preconditions set by either side.</p>
<p>It was not clear when the meeting might be held.</p>
<p>Sahnoun said the foes had agreed the ultimate goal of the talks process should be elections for Zaire -- part of a joint declaration issued by the rivals after talks in South Africa earlier this month.</p>
<p>The invitation was conveyed to Mobutu on Thursday by his envoy Honore Ngbanda, who returned home after talks with Mandela on Wednesday, Pahad said.</p>
<p>Rebel leader Kabila also returned to Zaire on Thursday from Cape Town after talks in South Africa with Mandela about the war aimed at unseating Mobutu.</p>
<p>Earlier Mandela told reporters he was confident of a negotiated peace in Zaire, where Kabila's rebel alliance holds half the country and has been demanding Mobutu's resignation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
