<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="516762" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian bonds close mixed, yield curve flattens.</title>
<headline>Canadian bonds close mixed, yield curve flattens.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian bonds closed mixed on Thursday, with the yield curve flattening slightly, as a drop in the Canadian dollar to a two-year low weighed on the short end of the curve, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The weakness in the short end is coming from the Canadian dollar,&quot; said Sheldon Dong, manager of fixed-income research with Midland Walwyn Capital Inc. &quot;I'm surprised that it (the market) is ignoring the dollar completely at the long end.&quot;</p>
<p>Canada's 30-year benchmark bond rose C$0.40 to C$108.60 to yield 7.260 percent.  </p>
<p>The U.S. 30-year bond rose 11/32 to yield 7.07 percent. The spread between the two bonds narrowed to 19 basis points from 22 basis points on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Canada's dollar ended weaker on Thursday at C$1.4005 (US$0.7140) from this morning's open around C$1.3985 (US$0.7150), after reaching a two-year low of C$1.4018 (US$0.7133) in overnight trade.</p>
<p>However, long bonds rallied with Treasuries, which benefited from a jump in U.S. jobless claims and a decline in the Philadelphia Federal Reserve's index of business activity in the manufacturing sector.  </p>
<p>&quot;Today you saw a little bit of benign real sector data with the Philly Fed. So it seems like for the day at least the people in the non-Fed tighening camp won out,&quot; said Harvinder Kalirai, Canadian analyst with New York-based financial analysis firm I.D.E.A.</p>
<p>In new issue news, the Government of Canada said it plans to auction on April 23 a total of C$1.3 billion of bonds with a coupon of 8.0 percent and maturing on June 1, 2027. The Bank of Canada will buy a minimum of C$195 million of the issue.</p>
<p>In other prices, the Canadian 10-year benchmark bond rose C$0.30 to C$102.10 to yield 6.699 percent.  </p>
<p>The U.S. bond rose 8/32 to yield 6.85 percent.</p>
<p>The negative spread between the bonds widened to 15 basis points from 14 basis points on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The three-month cash T-bill yielded 3.20 percent against its U.S. equivalent which yielded 5.29 percent.</p>
<p>((Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
