<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="516740" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST - Australian Sports News - April 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Australian Sports News - April 18.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>The Australian cricket team to tour England next month has been announced, with Mark Taylor retaining the captaincy. Steve Waugh has replaced Ian Healy as vice-captain, and Michael Slater and Ricky Ponting are returning to the national side. Page 22.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a sign of solidarity, the 12 teams aligned to the Australian Rugby League have signed a document of their intentions to play in next year's competition. This will ensure that any talks with Super League for a united competition will be conducted as a united body. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Two New South Wales rugby union players have been quarantined from their team-mates in the lead-up to Saturday's Super 12 game against Queensland. Alistair Murdoch and Daniel Manu have been separated from their team with a stomach virus, and are in serious doubt for the game. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>New South Wales rugby league State of Origin coach Phil Gould has confirmed he is unlikely to remain as coach this year. Gould will hold further talks with Australian Rugby League chief executive Neil Whittaker in the next few days, and Norths coach Pete Louis and Wests coach Tom Raudonikis are the leading contenders for the job. Page 43.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Soccer Australia is continuing with a plan to have the under-23 Olyroos team play in the national league before the Sydney Olympics, despite logistical problems. Extra funding is being sought for the Olyroos before 2000, as the failure of the Olyroos to make the quarter-finals at the Olympics last year cost around $A500,000. Page 43.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Sydney Swans Australian Football League star player Tony Lockett will return to the game after injury this weekend against St Kilda. Lockett is unsure if he will be able to complete the game, but the Swans are confident he can return and help the team back into form. Page 41.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Australian Football team Carlton has offered rival team Collingwood their home ground, Optus Oval, as a venue for its home matches against interstate clubs. Collingwood's home ground, Victoria Park, no longer meets the public's requirements, and cannot hst games that attract large crowds. Page D3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian 500cc motorbike rider Daryl Beattie is looking for a new bike with team Suzuki to make him a contender this season. Before the Japanese Grand Prix this weekend, Beattie just wishes to challenge leading Australian rider Michael Doohan. Page D13.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Top Australian jockey Damien Oliver returned to racing in Australia yesterday after returning from a lucrative season in Hong Kong. Rumours have circulated that Oliver will be forced back to Hong Kong for allegations of corruption, but Oliver denies the story as media hype. Page D13.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE HERALD SUN</p>
<p>Five leading players will return for Australian Football League side Carlton this weekend against Collingwood. Stephen Kernahan, Ang Christou, Matthew Hogg, Fraser Brown and Stephen Silvagni will return for injuries for the important game. Page 102.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Melbourne Australian Football League midfielder Craig Turley yesterday announced his retirement from football due to a debilitating back injury. Turley was a former runner-up in the Brownlow Medal and made 131 appearances in the league, most with the West Coast Eagles between 1989 and 1995. Page 101.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The National Basketball League elects its new commission tomorrow, with an important issue to be discussed being the election of new clubs into the competition. Submissions have been received from the Cazaly Club in Cairns, Hobart and the West Sydney Slammers. Page 90.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>Four Super League players from the Adelaide Rams have been fined a total of $A13,000 by the club and will face court for allegedly assaulting police officers after an incident outside a strip club yesterday. Kurt Wrigley, Jason Donnelly, Dave Boughton an Andrew Pierce will face various offences including disorderly behaviour, loitering and resisting arrest. Page 125.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian soccer coach Terry Venables has declared that age will be no barrier to any player in his team when the World Cup squad is selected shortly. Graham Arnold and Robbie Slater are both over 32 years old but will most likely be selected in the squad. Page 116.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The seven-week Sydney autumn horse racing carnival has reaped nearly $A18 million for the New South Wales government, after an input for promotion of only $A250,000. Total betting sales during the Golden Slipper festival were over $A100 million. Page 118.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
