<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51689" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Le Pen march to go ahead despite French protests.</title>
<headline>Le Pen march to go ahead despite French protests.</headline>
<byline>Thierry Cayol</byline>
<dateline>MARSEILLE, France 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>French extreme-right politician Jean-Marie Le Pen plans to lead a racially-charged march in Marseille on Saturday over the killing of a white teenager by a youth of North African origin, despite an appeal from the dead boy's father.</p>
<p>The centrally-appointed prefect of the region refused to ban the demonstration over what Le Pen called an &quot;anti-French racist murder&quot;, arguing that to prevent it would require a huge police presence inappropriate for a day of mourning.</p>
<p>Le Pen's National Front plans to march in the multiracial southern port a few hours before the funeral of 14-year-old Nicolas Bourgat, despite a plea from the victim's father, a local doctor, against &quot;political exploitation&quot; of his son's death.</p>
<p>A 15-year-old French boy of Arab origin, named only as Ktab, was brought before a judge in Marseille to be charged with stabbing Nicolas to death on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The incident in a city with a big immigrant population came in the midst of controversy over Le Pen's espousal of racial inequality, which led one Socialist opposition politician to call this week for the National Front to be outlawed.</p>
<p>The extreme-right leader has said repeatedly in the last 10 days that it is &quot;a fact&quot; that races are unequal, and has argued that French civilisation is superior. However he has carefully avoided talking of racial inferiority, pointing instead to the prowess of black athletes at the Olympic Games.</p>
<p>Justice Minister Jacques Toubon said on Thursday government lawyers had concluded Le Pen could not be prosecuted for the statements, although some legal experts disputed the decision.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe said later the government would tighten anti-racism laws if necessary to make it possible to prosecute Le Pen for such remarks.</p>
<p>Speaking to reporters in Bordeaux, Juppe said: &quot;I am outraged by the statements that were made. I'm not sure that banning a political party would not be the biggest favour one could do to (Le Pen).</p>
<p>&quot;If the present laws make it possible to prosecute and punish (him), we will invoke them. If not, we will strengthen them, because such statements are unacceptable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>France's political establishment is perplexed as to how to reverse the rise of Le Pen, who won 15 percent in last year's presidential election by blaming immigration for unemployment, crime and insecurity, and calling for three million immigrants to be sent home.</p>
<p>The National Front is vying with Juppe's Gaullist RPR party and the opposition Communists for the working-class vote in the run-up to parliamentary elections in 1998.</p>
<p>Carine Marce of the Sofres opinion research firm said pollsters were constantly being forced to revise their estimates of Le Pen's upper limit in the opinion polls.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1988, when he got 14 percent, people said this was his uppper limit. Then, in 1995, he got 15 percent. The problem is that each time he advances in the polls, people express their shock, but then he goes up one more point,&quot; she told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARSEILLE, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
