<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="516894" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Jiang upbeat on Russia trip, says China no threat.</title>
<headline>Jiang upbeat on Russia trip, says China no threat.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chinese President Jiang Zemin expects &quot;positive results&quot; from a visit to Russia next week that will set the seal on improved ties between the two giant neighbours, Itar-Tass news agency said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I am deeply convinced that my trip to Moscow will be crowned with positive results,&quot; Tass quoted Jiang as saying in an interview with its correspondent in Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be the first top-level meeting since our two countries established an equal, trusting partnership aimed at strategic cooperation in the 21st century,&quot; Jiang said, referring to Yeltsin's visit to Beijing last April.</p>
<p>Jiang, who will meet President Boris Yeltsin and other senior officials during his April 22-26 trip, also dismissed as &quot;nonsense&quot; Western claims that China posed a threat to other countries and said Beijing's top priority was economic growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The assertions of some Western scholars that China, building up its muscles, will create a threat for other countries...is nonsense,&quot; he told Tass.</p>
<p>&quot;China is concentrating its efforts on the development of its economy, on the long-term improvement of its people's standard of living,&quot; Jiang added.</p>
<p>Russia, locked in its own war of words with Western countries over NATO's plans to expand eastwards, sees China as an increasingly important political and economic partner.</p>
<p>On a visit to Beijing this week, Defence Minister Igor Rodionov said Russia opposed Western attempts to pressure China over human rights and other issues.</p>
<p>Jiang and Yeltsin are expected next week to sign a political document setting out their countries' shared views on global issues.</p>
<p>Another highlight of Jiang's visit will be the signing by China, Russia and three Central Asian states -- Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan and Tajikistan -- of an agreement reducing military forces along the former Soviet-Chinese border.</p>
<p>&quot;(This agreement) has a far-reaching significance for the strengthening of neighbourly relations and friendship and for building peace and stability in the region of our 7,000 km-long border,&quot; Tass quoted Jiang as saying.</p>
<p>Russia and China formed a strong alliance in the early 1950s but it degenerated into bitter rivalry for leadership of the communist world and led to border clashes in the late 1960s.</p>
<p>Relations have been warming since Soviet leader Mikhail Gorbachev visited Beijing in 1989. Visits to China by Yeltsin in December 1992 and in April last year continued the improvement in ties and Jiang has hailed a new era in bilateral relations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
