<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="516890" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Vranitzky pushes Albania towards June elections.</title>
<headline>Vranitzky pushes Albania towards June elections.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania moved a step closer to early elections on Thursday as international mediator Franz Vranitzky pursued his mission to restore stability and order.</p>
<p>Vranitzky said leaders of the government and political parties had agreed after two days of talks that early elections should be held on June 29, a breakthrough the former Austrian chancellor called &quot;significant&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that we have achieved some progress today,&quot; said Vranitzky, envoy of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE).</p>
<p>&quot;They are all of the opinion that the elections should take place on June 29.&quot;</p>
<p>About 300 people have been killed and more than 700 injured in a spasm of armed violence that erupted after fraudulent investment schemes collapsed earlier this year, wiping out the life savings of many Albanians.</p>
<p>The uprising in Europe's poorest country began in the south, which remains under the control of rebel committees.</p>
<p>An emergency all-party government created during the height of the crisis in March agreed early elections were crucial to restoring order. But the rival parties have made almost no progress on drafting an election law.</p>
<p>Vranitzky, shuttling across Tirana in his closely-guarded black limousine, said it was unrealistic to expect binding agreements in a matter of hours.</p>
<p>The current crisis in Albania has its roots in a contested election result in the last poll in May 1996.</p>
<p>Rightist President Sali Berisha won 87 percent of the vote but opposition parties refused to accept the results, saying there was widespread fraud. International observers said there were irregularities.</p>
<p>Vranitzky scrapped a visit to the rebel-held south on Thursday, saying he wanted to push forward efforts to set up the elections. But he admitted security was also a factor.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a multinational security mission to protect humanitarian aid convoys spread further across the country as Italian marines reached the key rebel stronghold of Vlore.</p>
<p>About 1,700 Italian, French, Spanish, Greek and Turkish troops have arrived in Albania over the last three days. Romania, Austria and Denmark will also contribute soldiers to the U.N.-backed mission, which will grow to 6,000 within three weeks.</p>
<p>A small force of 25 Italian marines arrived in the port of Vlore, 150 km (90 miles) south of Tirana, to be greeted warmly by a group of about 50 Albanians. Some of the locals shouted &quot;Down with Berisha&quot; while the heavily-armed marines inspected the harbour.</p>
<p>&quot;We are here to protect the aid convoys,&quot; said one Italian soldier as the sound of automatic gunfire in the distance echoed through the port. &quot;This is my job. I am not afraid.&quot;</p>
<p>Lawlessness and chaos still grip Albania.</p>
<p>Dozens of gunmen in the southern town of Lushnje fired wildly in a hospital on Wednesday evening as they grieved over a friend shot dead in an accident. Although no one was hurt, the hospital was badly damaged during the rampage.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no safety here,&quot; hospital director Agim Bezati said. &quot;Everyone has guns.&quot;</p>
<p>In the southern town of Gjirokaster, two men were found shot dead in a luxury car on Thursday morning. Police said the motive was unclear.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
