<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517058" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil's landless march into capital for protest.</title>
<headline>Brazil's landless march into capital for protest.</headline>
<byline>William Schomberg</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Landless peasants marched into the Brazilian capital on Thursday to the cheers of more than 25,000 demonstrators in the biggest protest faced by President Fernando Henrique Cardoso.</p>
<p>About 1,500 members of the Landless Movement (MST) trudged into Brasilia's Ministries Esplanade to end their 750-mile (1,200-km) march carrying rusty farm tools and waving red flags.</p>
<p>They were joined by thousands of trade union members, civil servants, teachers and unemployed workers who oppose Cardoso's plans to privatise state companies and cut public sector jobs. Police said there were between 25,000 and 30,000 protestors.</p>
<p>&quot;The support given to this march shows the disatisfaction of society with the economic and agrarian reform policies of the government,&quot; said MST director Joao Pedro Stedile.</p>
<p>He said the peasants would defy calls from the government to give up their invasions of unused farmland that often lead to bloodshed. More than 100 people have been killed in land conflicts since Cardoso took office in January 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be more and more land occupations. We don't expect the government to carry out proper land reform programme as an act of generosity,&quot; Stedile said.</p>
<p>The protest marked the first anniversary of the killing by police of 19 peasants demanding land. That massacre heaped international criticism on Brazil and spurred Cardoso to declare land reform a priority of his administration.</p>
<p>The MST wants the government to speed up the land reform process, provide more credit to settlers and raise taxes on unused farmland. It is also seeking to bring those responsible for the masscre to justice.</p>
<p>Cardoso, whose popularity remains high but is increasingly under fire for failing to match low inflation with improved social conditions, defended his record on land reform.</p>
<p>&quot;In my government I have settled more people than in any other period of Brazilian history. We have disappropriated 3.4 million hectares, that's the size of Belgium,&quot; the president said in an interview with Globo television.</p>
<p>Cardoso was due to meet with MST leaders on Friday, the first top-level meeting between the government and the movement since August last year. &quot;If we join our hands then we will be able to settle more people,&quot; Cardoso said.</p>
<p>Cardoso also came under attack on Thursday from the Catholic Church for his pro-market policies.</p>
<p>&quot;The impoverishment of the people cannot be accepted as the inevitable price of economic development,&quot; Brazil's National Bishops Conference (CNBB) said in a statement.</p>
<p>The document called for the suspension of the upcoming $5 billion privatisation of mining giant Companhia Vale do Rio Doce and criticised lawmakers for setting a $10,000 cap on their monthly income while millions of workers surive on a minimum wage of $105.</p>
<p>&quot;The violence that permeates all of society is also a consequence of economic policies that created one of the world's most unfair income distributions,&quot; the document said.</p>
<p>In their statement, the bishops urged the government to reconsider its economic development model and called for the adoption of a far-reaching agrarian reform programme.</p>
<p>They said that since Brazil had one of the world's worst income distributions, policies should focus on eradicating illiteracy, fighting hunger and guaranteeing housing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
