<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517034" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia regrets EU warnings on Belarus union.</title>
<headline>Russia regrets EU warnings on Belarus union.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia expressed surprise and regret on Thursday at a threat by the European Parliament not to recognise a union treaty between Moscow and Belarus and dismissed it as political interference.</p>
<p>The European Parliament said in a resolution last Thursday it might block a planned trade and aid pact between the European Union and Belarus if Minsk did not undertake genuine political and economic reform.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks as if this is a document typical of the times when political pressure and interference in the internal affairs of sovereign states was used in international relationships,&quot; a Russian foreign ministry statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;The target and the tone of the resolution in particular cause our surprise and regret.&quot;</p>
<p>It said the European Parliament's resolution had fuelled tension in Belarus and harmed relations between Russia and the European Parliament.</p>
<p>The European Parliament accused Belarus' President Alexander Lukashenko of a &quot;dictatorial style of government&quot;, including in his decision to form a union with Russia, and said this raised questions about EU relations with the former Soviet republics.</p>
<p>It said it would not recognise the union treaty, signed by Lukashenko and Russian President Boris Yeltsin in Moscow on April 2, until the Belarus parliament was consulted.</p>
<p>The union treaty outlines moves towards integration but has little immediate effect in practice.</p>
<p>The Russian foreign ministry said the creation of the union assumed a development of democratic principles in both states and was an expression of the will of the people in Belarus and Russia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
