<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517170" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: FORECAST-Telmex Q1 net seen 91 cents/ADR.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Telmex Q1 net seen 91 cents/ADR.</headline>
<byline>Chris Aspin</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Telephone giant Telefonos de Mexico (Telmex) is expected to post first quarter earnings of 91 cents per ADR, slightly below the same period last year, but analysts believe Mexico's top stock could spring surprises that will give results a more positive look.</p>
<p>The average forecast was calculated from a survey of four telecommunications analysts using a year-end number of outstanding shares of 8.875 billion.  </p>
<p>Three estimates were in the 93-98 cent range. One was below 80 cents, dragging the overall average lower. Telmex's Q1 1996 net was 99 cents/ADR.</p>
<p>Telmex is expected to report its quarterly results next week, probably on April 22 or 23.</p>
<p>Analysts said Telmex's results were difficult to predict for this quarter because of new factors, including the widening of the long distance telephone market to competitors which started on January 1.  </p>
<p>Analysts noted, however, that the impact of Telmex losing market share would be minimal in this quarter because of the phase-by-phase nature of the opening. Expectations are for Telmex to start to feel the heat in Q3 at the earliest.</p>
<p>&quot;Competition has been slow in coming in Mexico and that will help these (Q1) results,&quot; said Paul Aran of James Capel.</p>
<p>Other positive quarterly factors will be revenues from higher local tariffs implemented from January, the impact of interconnection fees paid by competitors and expected solid growth in Telmex's cellular telephone business, analysts said.  </p>
<p>Negative impacts are anticipated from dull line growth and possible once-off items. Telmex reported huge one-time charges in its 1996 results, including a 1.561 billion peso goodwill write-off, which had some analysts growling.</p>
<p>&quot;First quarter earnings should not only reflect the effect of higher local tariffs implemented since the beginning of the year but also the opening of the long-distance market to competition,&quot; Bear Stearns' Rizwan Ali said in a report.  </p>
<p>Ali added that Telmex stands to have extra earnings in the quarter because competitors do not yet have fully fledged networks and are paying to use Telmex's network for interconnecting and transporting signals.</p>
<p>&quot;Though this situation should change going forward ... Telmex should collect substantial fees off its competitors in the first half of 1997,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley's Luis Carvalho was even more upbeat. &quot;We might be surprised by how much they are making on the interconnections,&quot; Carvalho said, adding that market talk is that Telmex could make more money on interconnections than they lose on market share.</p>
<p>Wide-ranging local tariff hikes implemented January 1 also had Bear Stearns' Ali predicting local revenues rising 15 percent in real terms compared to the same period last year.</p>
<p>Telmex's booming cellular business is also seen beefing up revenues and earnings.  </p>
<p>&quot;They want to increase their customer numbers by 50 percent this year, that is an extra 300,000 on the year end client base of around 650,000,&quot; said Andrew Friedman of ING Barings. &quot;That could be one interesting item in this report.&quot;</p>
<p>Other analysts were less optimistic. &quot;...there will be (cellular) growth but not 50 percent, it is too ambitious,&quot; said Robert Hulme of Interacciones brokerage.</p>
<p>On the downside, line growth in the quarter is not seen as bullish as in previous years.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically, we see no year-over-year line growth, it is going to be about flat&quot; said Tony Figuerido of Caspian Research, adding that disconnections will cancel out new connections.</p>
<p>Analysts are also worried about one-time items that caused criticism of Telmex's 1996 year-end results. &quot;Some took them really negatively and worry they could loom again at any time,&quot; said another analyst, who asked to remain anonymous on this issue.</p>
<p>Telmex, as well as its 1.561 billion peso goodwill write-off, also had one-time charges of 895 million pesos for expenses related to the opening of competition and 249 million pesos worth of charitable contributions.</p>
<p>((--Mexico City newsroom 728 7902))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
