<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517181" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>HAITI: FEATURE-Any job will do in Haiti slum, even if it kills.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Any job will do in Haiti slum, even if it kills.</headline>
<byline>Angus MacSwan</byline>
<dateline>CITE SOLEIL, Haiti 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>His body bent almost double between the shafts of a wooden barrow, eyes bulging and muscles straining, a man drags a load through a packed and putrid street in Haiti's Cite Soleil slum.</p>
<p>A friend heaves the barrow, stacked high with sacks of charcoal, from behind as they struggle through streams of sewage, over craters and around open pick-up trucks crammed with passengers. It will take them two hours under beating sun to haul the load from the dock to downtown Port-au-Prince. For this they will make about 30 U.S. cents each.</p>
<p>In the days of French colonial rule in Haiti, plantation owners would work their slaves to death because it was cheaper to import more than to support families. In the nearly 200 years since bloody slave revolts brought Haiti independence, it is hard to believe that life has improved much for the human beasts of burden in Cite Soleil.</p>
<p>&quot;It's killing me. I'd like to quit but I have no choice,&quot; Jocelyn Leptune said, charcoal dust caking his skin and ragged clothes as he made his rounds between dock and barrow. &quot;God only knows how long I can go on,&quot; he said, patting his heart.</p>
<p>He earns half a gourd per sack. If they can load 50 on the barrow they earn 25 gourds ($1.66). After paying 15 gourds to rent the barrow, they are left with 10 gourds between them.</p>
<p>If they are lucky they will get a second load today. The boats come in on Wednesdays and Saturdays, but there is no guarantee they will picked for work.</p>
<p>GOES DAYS WITHOUT WORK</p>
<p>&quot;I can go eight or 10 days without a job,&quot; Leptune said. &quot;When I don't make money I don't eat.&quot;</p>
<p>Haiti is the poorest country in the Americas and Cite Soleil is its heart of darkness, a labryinth of fetid alleys and dank hovels where 200,000 souls are crammed together. Children have runny noses and orange-tinged hair -- a sign of malnutrition. Vermin and chickens pick their way over seas of garbage. Little girls lug buckets of water through the crowds from standpipes provided by foreign aid agencies.</p>
<p>Boys pull at a reporter's sleeve and say they want to go to school. They complain that gangsters are taking control of the streets. Gun battles between rival gangs erupted in February and about 20 people were killed before police and U.N. peacekeepers restored calm.</p>
<p>In November, industrial waste running through ditches caused fires that burned down dozens of houses. Prime Minister Rosny Smarth earned the contempt of the people when he held his fingers over his nose to mask the stench during a visit to the shantytown afterwards.</p>
<p>Life in Cite Soleil has become harder since a U.S.-led invasion in 1994 ousted a military dictatorship and restored Jean-Bertrand Aristide, the champion of the poor, as president. Prices of rice and other staples have gone up and, despite pledges by the government of Aristide's successor, Rene Preval, and by international donors, visible progress in easing poverty is slight.</p>
<p>A study on &quot;The Challenges to Poverty Reduction&quot; prepared for an international donors' meeting held last week in the rather more pleasant suburb of Petionville said it was not likely to come quickly or easily. &quot;The problems are complex, deeply entrenched and enormous in scope,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>DENIED BASIC SERVICES</p>
<p>Most Haitians do not have adequate access to basic services such as education, health, water and sanitation, it said. Life expectancy is 57, the infant mortality rate is 90 per 1,000 births and malnutrition affects about half the children under five. Half the adults are illiterate. Drinking water carries microrganisms, which contribute to more than half the infant deaths, the study said.</p>
<p>World Bank Vice President Javed Bukri told the meeting Haiti's parliament was holding up millions of dollars in international aid because of its failure to approve a national budget. But a number of politicians including Aristide, as well as ordinary people, oppose Preval's privatisation plan, saying it is a foreign-imposed scheme that will lead to more hardship. Grassroots groups have called a series of strikes.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the United States, which calls Haiti a foreign policy success, is anxious that hordes of poor Haitians do not again take to boats to head for Florida. In an exodus in 1994, tens of thousands fled across the sea for U.S. shores.</p>
<p>&quot;The people thought that when Aristide came things would get better, but it has only got worse,&quot; Christy Johnson, a Haitian organising community projects in Cite Soleil, said. &quot;If it doesn't get better soon they will have to eat rocks. And there will come a time when blood wil run. The first people to rise up will be the people of Cite Soleil.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CITE SOLEIL, Haiti"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HAITI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
