<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517280" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Former S.Korean deputy PM faces prosecution inquiry.</title>
<headline>Former S.Korean deputy PM faces prosecution inquiry.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean prosecutors on Thursday asked former deputy prime minister Rha Woong-bae to appear for questioning on Friday in connection with the Hanbo loan scandal, a prosecution official said.</p>
<p>&quot;Prosecutors asked Rha Woong-bae to appear at the prosecution office on Friday morning,&quot; said the official who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Rha served as deputy prime minister in charge of the finance and economy ministry from December 1995 to August 1996.</p>
<p>State prosecutors have been probing politicians who allegedly received money from Hanbo Group founder Chung Tae-soo. Government officials said 33 politicians have been pointed out by Chung.</p>
<p>Among them are 20 lawmakers, including two who are tipped as possible candidates for the ruling New Korea Party in the December presidential election.</p>
<p>The inquiry started last week and so far more than half the politicians have been questioned. Most of them confessed to taking political contributions from Chung but denied returning any favours.</p>
<p>National Assembly speaker Kim Soo-han will also be questioned over allegations he took money from Chung, according to a government official.</p>
<p>Chung told prosecutors he had donated funds to help Kim's parliamentary election campaign in 1992, the official said.</p>
<p>The mayor of Pusan, South Korea's second largest city, was summoned and questioned overnight on Wednesday by prosecutors.</p>
<p>Chung is on trial for bribery and other charges along with nine others, including three close associates of President Kim Young-sam, in connection with the collapse of Hanbo Steel Co in January under a $5.8 billion pile of debt.</p>
<p>Parliament launched its own special probe into the Hanbo scandal last month and began live televised hearings of those linked to the furore.</p>
<p>Kim Hyun-chul, the president's second son, is scheduled to testify on April 25 in the National Assembly. Opposition parties have accused the junior Kim of influence-peddling for Hanbo.</p>
<p>In February, President Kim apologised over the Hanbo loan scandal and for his son's alleged involvement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
