<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517237" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL palm oil ends shortened trading week higher.</title>
<headline>KL palm oil ends shortened trading week higher.</headline>
<text>
<p>PALM OIL FUTURES		 PALM OIL PHYSICAL</p>
<p>Jly (3rd pos) 1,262 rgt/tonne	 Apr (south) 1,330 *</p>
<p>Open/Hi/Low 1,250/1,262/1,249	 prev close 1,325</p>
<p>Prev settlement  1,253		   * sellers prices</p>
<p>PALM OIL FUTURES - Prices drifted quietly and closed higher in shortened trading week despite falls in soyoil. Local gains were due to shortcovering ahead of the long weekend. The market is closed on Friday for Eid al-Adha holiday. July futures contract seen trading between 1,240 and 1,270.</p>
<p>PALM OIL PHYSICAL - Followed the futures trend with interest seen among RBD palm olein and nearby crude palm oil.  </p>
<p>A trader said: &quot;We expect further range trading next week unless there are fresh developments in the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Players will be waiting for news from the third annual Asia Pacific Vegetable Oilseeds and Meals Market Conference next week in Kuala Lumpur, traders said.</p>
<p>Turnover on the futures market fell to 1,396 lots from Thursday's 1,874.  </p>
<p>Third month July futures closed nine ringgit higher at 1,262 ringgit ($502.19) a tonne. The contract is expected to trade between 1,240 and 1,270.</p>
<p>Physicals April (south) crude palm oil was offered at 1,330 ringgit against bids at 1,325, after trading from 1,322.50 to 1,325.</p>
<p>April (central) saw offers at 1,310 with bids at 1,300, with trades at 1,290 and 1,300.</p>
<p>May (south) was offered at 1,325 and bids at 1,320 with earlier trades done from 1,317.50 and 1,320. May (central) saw offers at 1,305 versus bids at 1,297.50.  </p>
<p>Among refined products, May RBD palm oil was offered at $555 a tonne FOB Malaysia, June at $550, and July/Aug/Sep at $542.50.</p>
<p>May RBD palm olein saw offers at $590, June at $582.50 and July/Aug/Sep at $575. May was traded at $585 to $590.</p>
<p>May RBD palm stearin was offered at $435 and May palm fatty acid distillate saw sellers at $290.</p>
<p>--Tan Lee Lee (603-230-7510) ($1=2.5130 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
