<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517300" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Axing of Taiwan public television stirs anger.</title>
<headline>Axing of Taiwan public television stirs anger.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A decision by Taiwan's ruling party to junk plans for public-funded television sparked angry reactions on Thursday, with supporters lamenting the waste of some US$185 million in taxpayers' money.</p>
<p>&quot;Parliament has spent a lot of time to review the Public Television Law and the government had invested a lot of money to buy hardware and train people,&quot; said lawmaker Chen Kuang-fu.</p>
<p>&quot;We must protest and condemn such reckless policy,&quot; Chen said on state-funded television.</p>
<p>A legislative panel of the ruling Nationalist Party, citing budget shortfalls, decided late on Wednesday to withdraw support for the draft law that would have allowed the Public Television Organising Committee to start operating a public channel.</p>
<p>The government set up the committee in 1990, saying Taiwan needed commercial-free, public-interest television like Japan's NHK, the British Broadcasting Corp and the Public Broadcasting System of the United States.</p>
<p>To date, it has spent some T$5.1 billion (US$185 million) to hire some 200 staff, purchase equipment and build studios.</p>
<p>The station had been producing test programming for years but little of it ever reached Taiwan's 21 million people.</p>
<p>Sun Teh-hsiung, chairman of the organising committee, told state radio that the Nationalists' decision was irresponsible, but admitted the chances of reviving the project were small.</p>
<p>&quot;I just hope the government won't auction the television. It's a waste of public resources and will only benefit private interests,&quot; Sun said.</p>
<p>The Nationalist panel did not say how it would handle the 200-strong workforce once the project was dissolved.</p>
<p>Local commentaries said public television was a victim of political struggle.</p>
<p>&quot;The cruel reality is -- culture cannot compete with politics,&quot; the United Daily News said in an editorial.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
