<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517512" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US EPA says 26 states, DC may need emissions cuts.</title>
<headline>US EPA says 26 states, DC may need emissions cuts.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Twenty six states and the District of Columbia may have to cut their pollution more to help other states meet U.S. smog standards, the Environmental Protection Agency said in a letter released Thursday.</p>
<p>But EPA assistant administrator Mary Nichols said the agency would wait for a report in June from the 37-state Ozone Transport Assessment Group before making a final decision on exactly which states would need further emissions reductions.</p>
<p>EPA had intended to issue a final rule calling for new nitrogen oxide emissions cuts by June, before OTAG finished its work, because the group was running behind schedule.  </p>
<p>OTAG was formed two years ago to study how much of an impact flows of nitrogen oxide and volatile organic compounds from region to region were affecting each state's ability to meet federal clean air standards.</p>
<p>Its work is considered to be the most comprehensive U.S. study of pollution flow patterns ever done.</p>
<p>In her April 16 letter to OTAG chairwoman Mary Gade, Nichols said EPA's &quot;preliminary view&quot; was that all the east coast states from Georgia to Maine, plus Alabama, Indiana, Illinois, Kentucky, Michigan, Mississippi, Missouri, Ohio, Tennessee, West Virginia and Wisconsin &quot;will need to make additional emission reductions in order to address significant ozone contributions to the other States.&quot;</p>
<p>The other states in the OTAG study area -- Arkansas, Florida, Iowa, Kansas, Louisiana, Minnesota, Nebraska, North Dakota, Oklahoma, South Dakota, and Texas -- would probably be spared from making new emissions cuts under existing smog standards, Nichols said.</p>
<p>She said EPA was looking at more information and would await OTAG's final recommendations before issuing a final rule, which could affect smoke stack industries and vehicles.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
