<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517593" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Most NYMEX Hub natgas ends up on cash, technicals.</title>
<headline>Most NYMEX Hub natgas ends up on cash, technicals.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas mostly ended higher Thursday in an active session, with front months leading the way on reports of firmer physical prices and more technical buying after an early breakout.</p>
<p>May climbed 6.4 cents to close at $2.069 per million British thermal units after hitting a five-week high at $2.09. June settled 7.8 cents higher at $2.124. Most others ended up.</p>
<p>&quot;We broke through a number of resistance points and caught some people short, but we stopped at a major resistance point and the market is looking very overbought,&quot; said one Midwest trader, noting cash also gained today.  </p>
<p>With open interest now at or near record levels after this week's upmove, some expected pressure tomorrow, as longs bail in front of the weekend.</p>
<p>But chart watchers still expected another test of key resistance in May at $2.095, the intraday high from March 10. They said a break above that level should lead to a test of the $2.16 area. May support points remained at $1.925, $1.88, $1.85 and $1.825.</p>
<p>June, which broke a double top Wednesday at $2.03 and rallied today to an 11-week high of $2.14, also seemed poised to test next resistance at the $2.21-2.23 gap from mid-January.</p>
<p>Fundamental traders remained skeptical of the rally, noting comfortable storage and forecasts next week for more seasonal weather, particularly in the South and along the East Coast.</p>
<p>AGA storage data Wednesday showed overall stocks were still 53 percent above year-ago, with eastern inventories more than double 1996 levels.</p>
<p>In the cash, Gulf Coast prices jumped Thursday by more than a nickel to the $2.05 area. Midcontinent pipes were up a similar amount to the low-$1.90s. New York city gate gas also was quoted more than five cents higher in the low-to-mid $2.40s.</p>
<p>The NYMEX 12-month Henry Hub strip rallied 5.1 cents to $2.235. NYMEX said 71,979 Hub contracts traded, up sharply from Wednesday's revised tally of 46,556.</p>
<p>No NYMEX Permian or Alberta gas contracts traded Thursday.</p>
<p>On KCBT, May finished five cents higher at $1.94, while deferreds ended up by three to six cents. The East/West spread widened by 1.4 cents to 12.9 cents (NYMEX premium). KCBT said 313 lots changed hands, down from Wednesday's total of 348.</p>
<p>((J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
