<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517673" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs, pork bellies end limit up, set new highs.</title>
<headline>CME hogs, pork bellies end limit up, set new highs.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Propelled by strong cash markets, CME hog and pork belly futures alike closed up as much as their respective daily limits with new contract highs set in all months of hogs and 1998 belly contracts.</p>
<p>Hog futures advanced the daily limit of 2.000 cents for the fourth consecutive day with June limit up at 85.450 cents, its new contract high. Pork belly futures finished limit up of 3.000 to 1.325 cents with May through August posting limit gains in the closing range. May ended limit up at 87.550 cents while February and March 1998 contracts set new contract highs of 75.225 and 74.000, respectively.</p>
<p>Hog futures rallied the limit on demand from higher cash markets and technical buy stops as prices continued to move through resistance on the weekly charts. June pushed through the upper end of channel on the charts, traders said.</p>
<p>Analysts noted that hog numbers are beginning to ease on a seasonal basis with added tightness developing in eastern areas as farmers take to fields for spring planting. Continued expectations of increased demand for U.S. pork, reinforced this week by word that Japan is already buying U.S. pork bellies, due to a ban on Taiwan pork, added to strength in the belly pit, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;(Pork) Seasonals are giving us a very good tone,&quot; said Jason Roose, livestock analyst for U.S. Commodities Inc.  </p>
<p>Roose sees good seasonal demand for pork going into the spring and looks for packers to continue aggressively competing for slaughter hogs. But he and other analysts and traders, are starting to anticipate a top in the market. Lean hog futures are already trading at a $64 per cwt live equivalent which is a good place for producers to start putting on hedges.</p>
<p>Other traders noted that cash hogs were expected to go up to $66 from $56 during the seasonal runup and they are getting very close to that level already.</p>
<p>Some profit taking was cited late with July coming off its limit and June ending with only 50 buy stops unfilled.</p>
<p>&quot;We're close to a top,&quot; one hog trader said.</p>
<p>Rand Financials sold June late after buying early long with Rosenthal Collins, Dean Witter and R.J. O'Brien. E.D.&amp;F. Man actively bought August early. In hog options, Lind-Waldock actively sold June 86 calls early and Refco bought December 72 puts. There was no synthetic in June, pit sources said.</p>
<p>Brisk demand in pork belly futures reflected confirmation by Japan trade houses that they were buying U.S. bellies. They told Reuters they will buy U.S. bellies until late May to fill needs into the end of the year due to the Taiwan pork ban.</p>
<p>Traders said the Japan buying and a techncially strong market sent May through February up the daily limit early and futures held at those levels late despite profit taking and speculative selling at times.</p>
<p>They also noted little interest in Friday's USDA Cold Storage report. Although the report is expected to show storings rising above year-earlier levels in March, movement of product into storage since April 1 has been running well below the amount needed to supply peak summer demand. The board needs to go higher to entice storings, they said.</p>
<p>Analysts' expectations on the amount of bellies in cold storage April 1 in the USDA report ranged from 49 million to 53.2 million lbs versus 47.655 million on hand last year.</p>
<p>But belly traders were also looking for a top in that market. A rising cash market will price domestic buyers out of the market, they said.</p>
<p>ABN Chicogo Corp sold July late after buying May early. Smith Barney also sold July while locals bought. LIT division of First Options and Cargill Investor Services bought May early. In belly options, LFG bought May 76 and 78 calls. May synthetic ended at 88.000 and there was no synthetic in August, pit sources said.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
