<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517785" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: DSP Communications falls on outlook.</title>
<headline>DSP Communications falls on outlook.</headline>
<dateline>CUPERTINO, Calif. 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>DSP Communications Inc shares plunged as much as 44 percent Thursday after the cellular phone component maker said it expects lower revenue for at least one quarter as its customers demand a new generation of products.</p>
<p>Shares of DSP, based in Cupertino, Calif., fell 3-1/8 to 7-5/8 in midafternoon trading of 15.4 million shares, making the stock the most active in U.S. markets. Earlier, the shares traded as low as 6, the lowest price in 18 months.  </p>
<p>After the market closed Wednesday, DSP said it expects earnings and revenues for its second quarter will be materially below first quarter levels.</p>
<p>DSP posted first quarter profits of $6.1 million, or $0.13 a share, compared to $3.6 million, or $0.09 a share in the comparable year-ago period. Revenues were $20.3 million, up from 17.3 million in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>The first quarter profit was slightly less than the $0.14 Wall Street was expecting, according to a recent analyst survey by Zacks Investment Research.  </p>
<p>DSP makes the chips and software that control the basic functions of cellular phones and telecommunication equipment.</p>
<p>Currently, DSP supplies Japanese customers with components for cell phones based on the Personal Digital Cellular, or PDC, standard.</p>
<p>The PDC standard, however, faces competition from the more recently introduced CDMA standard, which is cheaper for cellular service providers to use in their networks.</p>
<p>To keep their customers, PDC phone makers are scrambling for the latest generation of PDC components and buying less of DSP's older PDC products.</p>
<p>&quot;Our production for the second quarter will be reduced due to anticipated phase-out of our existing chip sets, as our customers move to new models,&quot; Nathan Hod, DSP chief executive, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Company officials did not return phone calls Thursday.</p>
<p>Investors will have to &quot;sit through this for a couple of quarters and DSP will have to show that they can get the new products to market,&quot; said Jeffrey Schlesinger, analyst at investment bank UBS Securities in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;It doesn't look like they managed the transition,&quot; said Dale Ford, an analyst at market researcher Dataquest.</p>
<p>Based on the poor handling of the transition, DSP's stock was downgraded to &quot;hold&quot; from &quot;buy&quot; by Marc Cabi, analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in New York. Cabi also reduced his earnings forecast for for the third and fourth quarters to $0.08 a share and $0.10 a share, down from $0.20 and $0.23 respectively.</p>
<p>((--Kourosh Karimkhany, in Palo Alto, 415 846 5401))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CUPERTINO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
