<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517950" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Hopeful signs in German bank sector wage talks.</title>
<headline>Hopeful signs in German bank sector wage talks.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Talks between German banking sector trade unions and employers began on Thursday with union officials confident that an agreement could be reached on sick pay entitlements, which banks orginally set out to cut.</p>
<p>Gerhard Renner, chief negotiator of the white-collar worker trade union DAG, said he believed employers were ready to offer a compromise on the issue of sick pay cuts, which provoked large worker protests last year.</p>
<p>The banks ultimately held back from making the cuts, which were allowed by a new federal law, until a wider contractual agreement on the matter could be reached.</p>
<p>German banking and insurance union HBV, DAG's joint negotiator, said before the talks it would also be seeking a cut in the working week to 35 hours from 39 hours and that it was ready to temper its wage demand if progress was made on that issue.</p>
<p>HBV believes such a move would help offset the effects of current job losses among banks, securing 50,000 out of the current 450,000 jobs in the industry.</p>
<p>Renewed debate on reduced working hours has been prompted by a proposal last week by Klaus Zwickel, head of the giant metal and engineering trade union IG Metall, for a 32-hour general working week to help reduce unemployment.</p>
<p>Employer groups have reacted largely negatively to the suggestion, saying that this would only make labour in Germany yet more expensive and thus discourage job creation.</p>
<p>HBV has said however that if employers were willing to come to agreements on working hours, it would also be ready to discuss new working arrangements related to Saturday opening, which German banks are keen to try out.</p>
<p>-- Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
