<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517965" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: McDonnell Douglas sees space lead with Delta4.</title>
<headline>McDonnell Douglas sees space lead with Delta4.</headline>
<byline>Gordon Mackenzie</byline>
<dateline>VENICE, Italy 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>McDonnell Douglas believes its planned fourth version of the Delta satellite launch rocket system will give it a competitive edge in the next century.</p>
<p>McDonnell has yet to launch its Delta 3 rocket, the latest in its range. Flights of existing Delta 2 rockets were postponed after problems with the thermal protection were discovered in January this year.</p>
<p>&quot;With the Delta 4 we are looking at a rocket that really is our reach into the future, our leapfrog into a sound competitive position,&quot; Robert Cowls, general manager of McDonnell Douglas Commercial Delta, told an insurance conference on Thursday.</p>
<p>He said the D4 would come in three versions, light, medium and a heavy version with three propulsion cores to cope with the larger payloads increasingly being sought by industry.</p>
<p>The new model is part of the company's push into the commercial sector and away from the military sector where it gained its expertise.</p>
<p>&quot;Commercial launches have made up one third of our business for the last six years, but we expect them to make up two thirds of our business for the next five years,&quot; Cowls told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Delta 3, which was designed to meet previous business predictions, has 18 firm launch bookings. The first is due to launch in spring next year, Cowls said.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the realisations we made from the recent failure of Delta was how absolutely crucial it is to meet the schedule. I've got some pretty crabby customers who are not able to launch. We now realise the reality of messing up their business plans,&quot; Cowls said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is only one reality -- schedule, schedule, schedule,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Cowls said the next Delta 2 rocket would be launched with a Motorola satellite on May 1, 1997.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Insurance News +44 171 542 2770</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VENICE, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
