<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518122" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sears profits up, stock off on credit card woes.</title>
<headline>Sears profits up, stock off on credit card woes.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Drawbaugh</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sears, Roebuck &amp; Co. reported solid profit and sales gains for the first quarter on Thursday, but Wall Street drove down the stock amid concerns about bad debt and legal problems with bankrupt credit card holders.</p>
<p>The concerns were exacerbated after the U.S. Attorney for Massachusetts said his office filed a civil complaint against Sears to stop &quot;fraudulent&quot; debt collection activities.</p>
<p>U.S. Attorney Donald Stern also said a federal investigation into Sears' practice of collecting debts from its once-bankrupt credit card customers was continuing.</p>
<p>The second-largest U.S. retailer said first-quarter earnings jumped more than 20 percent, thanks to gains in sales of women's sportswear and dresses, children's apparel and footwear. Lawn tractors and mowers also sold briskly as customers prepared for spring, Sears said.</p>
<p>The Hoffman Estates, Ill.-based retailing giant said it earned $182 million, or 46 cents a share, in the first quarter, compared with year-earlier earnings of $151 million, or 36 cents a share. Revenues rose to $8.76 billion from $7.99 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;It was better than what the Street was looking for,&quot; said Skip Helm, retail analyst at the William Blair &amp; Co. brokerage and investment bank in Chicago.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected a profit of about 43 cents per share, according to First Call, a market data firm.</p>
<p>Sears handily topped those expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;In the merchandising end of the business ... they got a nice improvement in the gross margin and costs were well controlled,&quot; said Joseph Ronning, retail analyst at the Brown Brothers Harriman brokerage and investment bank in New York.</p>
<p>Despite the profit gains, two problems depressed Sears' stock, which was off $2 at $46.75 in late trading on the New York Stock Exchange trading.</p>
<p>Sears reported that its U.S. provision for uncollectible charge accounts rose 18.9 percent to $269 million in the first quarter from $227 million a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The increase in account charge-offs reflects the continuation of an industry-wide increase in personal bankruptcies and delinquencies, as well as growth in the credit receivable portfolio,&quot; Sears said.</p>
<p>The rising bad debt rate continues a trend that began last year, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;If there's a concern, I think it lies in credit,&quot; said Judy Meehan, a retail analyst at Parker/Hunter Inc., a brokerage and investment firm in Pittsburgh. &quot;Not just at Sears, but all across the industry, we're seeing increasing delinquency rates and bankruptcies.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition, analysts said uncertainty looms over Sears' exposure to potential legal costs associated with its handling in recent years of debts owed by bankrupt credit card holders.</p>
<p>Sears said it remains unable to estimate the potential costs of the problem. &quot;No provision has been recorded for it in the first quarter, although it may be material to 1997 operating results,&quot; Sears said Thursday.</p>
<p>Sears earlier this month said it exercised &quot;flawed legal judgment&quot; and would refund millions of dollars it collected from bankrupt credit card holders in recent years.</p>
<p>The collections were made in some cases after Sears reached so-called reaffirmation agreements with bankrupt card holders.</p>
<p>U.S. Bankruptcy Court Judge Carol Kenner in Boston said Wednesday that Sears misled some of its bankrupt card holders into believing they had to repay debts to the company, even though their bills had been nullified by the bankruptcy court.</p>
<p>The retailer said it had reached about $400 million in reaffirmation agreements with card holders around the country between 1992 and early 1997. It remains unknown how many of those agreements were improper, analysts said.</p>
<p>Sears reiterated Thursday that it has filed a voluntary nationwide restitution plan regarding the matter. The company said it also was aware that related lawsuits by groups of card holders and Sears shareholders have been filed.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is that nobody can get a handle on how big a write-off they'll have to take when they finally figure out how many of these accounts were not properly reaffirmed,&quot; said David Toung, a retail analyst at Argus Research, an independent research firm in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;On top of that, we don't know what types of penalties the bankruptcy court may levy.... The market is focusing on those uncertainties,&quot; Toung said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
