<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518116" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dell sees 20 percent PC industry growth in '97.</title>
<headline>Dell sees 20 percent PC industry growth in '97.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dell Computer Corp. Chairman Michael Dell said Thursday he expects the worldwide personal computer industry to grow about 20 percent this year, fuelled by new chip technologies such as Intel Corp.'s multimedia processor and the new Pentium II chip.</p>
<p>Dell's prediction tops most industry forecasts. Market researcher International Data Corp, for example, has forecast worldwide PC industry growth of 17 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;This year we expect close to 20 percent growth because of the Pentium II and MMX,&quot; Dell said, after addressing a meeting here. Dell said that for the rest of the decade he expects the PC industry to grow in a range of 15 percent to 20 percent.</p>
<p>He added that his company will continue to outpace industry growth rates, but declined to be more specific.</p>
<p>Chief Financial Officer Tom Meredith also declined to comment on the company's financials at the meeting with Wall Street analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased with our position in the marketplace and we look forward to a very strong year,&quot; Meredith told Reuters.</p>
<p>In his presentation, Meredith highlighted Dell's fiscal 1997 achievements, such as its revenue growth of 47 percent and a 91 percent jump in net income.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a tremendous year,&quot; Meredith said. He also pointed out that Dell's stock was up 246 percent in the past year, vs. Intel's, which was up 112 percent, and Microsoft Corp.'s, which was up 87 percent, through April 11.</p>
<p>Dell stock rose $1.75 to $77 and chip maker Intel rose $4 to $138, both on Nasdaq on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Dell executives, whose company pioneered direct selling via telephone and mail order of PCs to customers and corporations, said Dell Computer is having great success selling computers over the Internet. It is taking in about $5 million in revenues a week as customers build their own &quot;dream machines.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing that could be better ... is mental telepathy,&quot; joked Meredith.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
