<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518232" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - T-bonds must pierce 107-28 to break free.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - T-bonds must pierce 107-28 to break free.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries are poised to push higher but must crack the key 107-28 level before bulls regain the upper hand, technical analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The market could stretch higher, but it won't until it pushes through 107-28,&quot; said Elizabeth Miller, technical analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell. &quot;Then we could see it up a point.&quot;</p>
<p>The T-bond future has found the 107-28 level particularly hard to crack over the last few weeks. The market bounced off a high of 107-28 on April 9, 107-27 on April 15 and 107-23 on Wednesday. By 1139 GMT it was up 7/32 at 107-22. The 30-year long bond was at 94.10 to yield 7.08 percent.</p>
<p>Bill Westgate, vice-president at HSBC Securities here was bullish on Treasuries.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got the beginnings of early technical evidence supporting (a move up) and it's time to get involved,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the trend is turning now and it will therefore now move into an uptrend,&quot; he said, adding the fact the market bounced off its lows for the second day on Wednesday showed it was firmly rejecting lower levels.</p>
<p>A number of secondary technical indicators, useful in confirming any major technical price breaks, back up suggestions the mood in T-bonds has lightened lately.</p>
<p>Stochastics -- or momentum indicators that suggest how much strength is behind a market move -- have turned bullish, said analysts.</p>
<p>A bullish crossover occurs when the percentage K (the ratio of the differnce between the current price and the low of the range, compared to the magnitude of the overall range) is trading above the percentage D (a three-bar moving average of the percentage K values).</p>
<p>Miller said modified stochastics show the percentage K at 48.33 and the percentage D at 32.51.</p>
<p>&quot;I agree that there is a buy signal given by modified stochastics -- but unless it's above the 50 percent area it's not a massively strong signal,&quot; she said, adding it was a subsidiary indicator, second to the price level.</p>
<p>Stavros Loizou, manager of strategic trading at Fuji Bank in London, also expected the market to move higher and agreed the main target was at 107-28.</p>
<p>&quot;I would go with the upside,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On the downside he saw good support at 106-29, Wednesday's low then at 106-23,24 the breakout point from the April 14 high.</p>
<p>Westgate said the relative strength indicator had put in a bullish divergence, which, with the stochastics, was supportive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
