<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518390" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Korean talks adjourn but all sides see progress.</title>
<headline>Korean talks adjourn but all sides see progress.</headline>
<byline>Carol Giacomo</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. and Korean officials held inconclusive talks on Wednesday on bringing Pyongyang into peace negotiations with arch-rival Seoul, but all sides reported progress and said they hoped to settle the issue on Friday.</p>
<p>Negotiators refused to go into detail about why Wednesday's crucial meeting, which U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright had predicted would produce &quot;good news,&quot; left the matter of North Korea's participation in landmark peace talks unresolved.</p>
<p>But chief South Korean negotiator Song Young Shik said the issue of devastating food shortages suffered by the North's Stalinist regime was raised during the day-long meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;We made some encouraging progress. There's still more to be done. We'll meet again on Friday to see if we can continue these discussions and achieve what we set out to do,&quot; chief U.S. negotiator Charles Kartman told reporters.</p>
<p>Kartman, principal deputy assistant secretary of state for East Asian and Pacific Affairs, said &quot;there aren't any real blocks&quot; to famine-threatened North Korea entering into peace talks with the prosperous, democratic South.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point, what we're trying to do is come to agreement about what the agenda and other details might be.&quot;</p>
<p>The meeting at a swanky Mantattan hotel was called to hear Pyongyang's formal response to a year-old U.S.-South Korean proposal for four-party peace talks that would finally close the books on the 1950-53 Korean War by replacing the fraying armistice with a peace treaty. China would also participate.</p>
<p>Song, speaking after the meeting adjourned, said &quot;we expect to have an answer Friday&quot; and was &quot;hopeful&quot; it would be yes.</p>
<p>He denied there were any &quot;problems&quot; and said: &quot;We had a very good discussion ... There was encouraging progress.&quot;</p>
<p>Kim Gye Gwan, North Korea's lead negotiator, also reported progress and said &quot;maybe we can expect something for this coming Friday.&quot; But he added: &quot;Sometimes talks do not end so easily. Sometimes talks can take quite a few days and sometimes they can take months to finish.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier in the day, Albright gave the clearest sign yet that North Korean was on the verge of accepting a proposal that could launch the landmark peace talks by June or July.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect that we in fact might have some good news about the North Koreans' acceptance of four-party talks that deal with the Korean peninsula,&quot; she said in Grand Rapids, Michigan, at the rededication of the President Gerald R. Ford Museum.</p>
<p>Her spokesman, Nicholas Burns, also fuelled optimism that Pyongyang, struggling with devastating food shortages, was about to accept the peace talks proposal.</p>
<p>&quot;The talks are ... going well. We're certainly encouraged by the first few hours of the talks and we hope very much for a positive result from these discussions,&quot; Burns said.</p>
<p>North Korea was also upbeat as the meeting began. &quot;I think we will come out with good results,&quot; Kim told his South Korean counterpart during a picture-taking session with journalists.</p>
<p>Seoul's chief negotiator, Song, was also in a jovial mood, laughing and chatting with Kim about how he hoped the meeting would reflect the warm spring day in New York. North and South Korean delegation leaders, smiling broadly, joined in a three-way handshake with Kartman.</p>
<p>South Korean officials said the morning session involved Pyongyang making a &quot;presentation.&quot;</p>
<p>On the eve of the meeting, Washington announced $15 million in additional food aid for children in North Korea. It said the new donation, bringing total U.S. food aid to Pyongyang to $33.4 million since late 1995, was made because the North's food shortages would reach a critical stage this spring.</p>
<p>The new aid came on top of a $10 million U.S. pledge in February and responded to a U.N. World Food programme appeal for $95.5 million. Despite the make-or-break nature of Wednesday's meeting with the North Koreans, South Korea was still undecided on the size of an aid package for its hunger-stricken rival.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
