<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518508" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. FERC approves El Paso, Columbia settlements.</title>
<headline>U.S. FERC approves El Paso, Columbia settlements.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Federal Energy Regulatory Commission Wednesday approved settlements between three major natural gas pipelines and their customers, ending longstanding disputes.</p>
<p>The biggest settlement involved El Paso Energy Corp unit Tennessee Gas Pipeline Co, ending an old battle over the costs it incurred to get out of gas supply contracts when pipelines were ordered out of the merchant business.</p>
<p>Tennesee agreed to absorb $180 million in gas supply realignment costs, 23.3 percent of costs up to $1.185 billion and all costs above $1.185 billion, with its customers shouldering the rest of the costs.</p>
<p>In a separate settlement resolving a dispute over who should pay for unsubscribed capacity costs on El Paso Natural Gas Co's system, El Paso agreed to absorb 65 percent of the costs and roll 35 percent into customers' rates.</p>
<p>&quot;With these approvals, El Paso Energy Corporation now has a platform which will allow it to participate fully in the development of the dynamic energy industry,&quot; the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>Columbia Gas Transmission Corp reached an agreement with its customers setting its rates through April 1, 2002, coinciding with the expiration of most of its current transportation and storage contracts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
