<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518517" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American Intl to underwrite Internet policy.</title>
<headline>American Intl to underwrite Internet policy.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>American International Group Inc on Wednesday said it was introducing an insurance policy to provide protection against many of the risks of doing business over the Internet and internal corporate networks known as intranets.</p>
<p>The policy, named InsureSite, is being underwritten by member companies of American International and is available through Atlanta-based insurance broker Hamilton Dorsey Alston Co.</p>
<p>The policy was announced at the Risk and Insurance Management Society's annual conference in Atlanta.  </p>
<p>It is part of a broader program that includes World Wide Web certification, which reduces risks and liabilities of maintaining a site on the Web by providing and verifying security standards. Policy-holders whose Web sites are certified by the National Computer Security Association (NCSA) are eligible for premium discounts, American International said.</p>
<p>The InsureSite policy consists of three coverage parts.</p>
<p>Under Customer Funds Security Liability Coverage, the policy responds to a company's third-party liability for loss of money or electronic funds arising out of its covered Web site, Hamilton Dorsey said.  </p>
<p>Another part covers personal injury liability caused by electronic communication of information or a person's unauthorized access to a Web site with limits up to $1.0 million.</p>
<p>The policy also covers direct physical damage to or loss of computer equipment and declared electronic data and media as a result of vandalism, computer virus or other perils.</p>
<p>In addition, it provides reimbursement for the loss of net income, continuing operating expenses and extra expenses incurred while suspended operations are being restored.  </p>
<p>&quot;Existing insurance products were created prior to the widespread use of the Internet and intranets,&quot; said Steven Haase, senior vice president of Hamilton Dorsey.</p>
<p>&quot;Unlike InsureSite, traditional general liability, property, crime and errors and omissions were not designed to respond to the liabilities associated with the use of the Internet and intranets for electronic commerce and other business transactions,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The annual Web site certification process raises security awareness and typically exposes overlooked or neglected threats to an Internet or intranet site, the firms said. It also demonstrates management's efforts to assure site availability, information protection and data integrity.</p>
<p>Certification cost is based on a fee of $8,500 per Web server, with discounts for multiple servers and sites.</p>
<p>&quot;NCSA clearly provides the ongoing, third-party security verification needed to ensure adequate Internet and intranet defense mechanisms,&quot; NCSA president Peter Tippett said.</p>
<p>The NCSA, based in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, is an independent, privately held company.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
