<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518503" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ADT says Western suit has no merit.</title>
<headline>ADT says Western suit has no merit.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>ADT Ltd said Wednesday the lawsuit filed against it by Western Resources was filed to create confusion and has no merit.</p>
<p>&quot;There is absoltuley no merit...the purpose is to create confusion in the market place,&quot; a spokesman for ADT said in an interview..</p>
<p>&quot;Our view is that they are being naughtly little boys,&quot; he said. &quot;Because they're not invited to the party, they're stamping their feet.&quot;</p>
<p>Western Resources said Wednesday it filed a lawsuit in the Supreme Court of Bermuda seeking an order requiring Tyco International Inc's acquisition of ADT be structured to provide appraisal rights to ADT shareholders. Western Resources is an ADT shareholder.</p>
<p>Western Resources said the rights, which give shareholders the right to be paid the fair value of their shares in cash, are valuable to the Tyco/ADT transaction because the value of it depends on Tyco's stock price. Western said Tyco's share price has fluctuated considerably since the merger agreement.</p>
<p>ADT said there are no appraisal rights in the deal and the company is confident the merger will be completed.</p>
<p>&quot;The price of every stock in the U.S. market over the past 10 days has been fluctuating -- I wouldn't point to Tyco,&quot; the spokesman said. &quot;There's no merit. That's just mischievous.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Tyco agreed to buy ADT for about $5.4 billion.</p>
<p>Late last year, Western made an unsolicited cash-and-stock offer for ADT valued at about $3.5 billion. ADT rejected the offer, but earlier this month Western said it extended the expiration of its exchange offer for all outstanding share of ADT to June 17.</p>
<p>((--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
