<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518713" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Insurers warned of space junk threat.</title>
<headline>Insurers warned of space junk threat.</headline>
<byline>Gordon Mackenzie</byline>
<dateline>VENICE, Italy 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of tonnes of orbiting 'space junk' are threatening the safety of spacecraft and creating a real financial risk for insurers on Earth, a space insurance conference heard on Thursday.</p>
<p>Italian insurer Generali says more than two million kilograms of debris has accumulated within 2,000 Km of the Earth's surface since the Soviet Union launched the first 'Sputnik' probe in the late 1950s.</p>
<p>Around 9,500 objects are large enough to be tracked and avoided on space missions, while other fragments are small enough for shields to offer protection. But the high risk comes from thousands of objects too small to track but too large to protect against.</p>
<p>&quot;There are mounting fears about space debris, both in terms of its number and its volume,&quot; said Generali deputy general manager Benito Pagnanelli as he drove the message home to a space insurance conference in Venice on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;NASA is particularly concerned about the consequences on space shuttles, which have sustained damage from contact with debris,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Delegates heard how in the last 16 months, 13 windows of space shuttles have been damaged. They were also told that in July last year a Cerise satellite was struck by part of a motor the size of a suitcase from an Ariane rocket.</p>
<p>Pagnanelli further warned insurers of the dangers of third party liabilities stemming from space junk re-entering the atmosphere and crashing to Earth in populated areas.</p>
<p>&quot;The conventional wisdom was that these things are supposed to burn-up on re-entry, but more than 10,000 objects have re-entered the atmosphere in the last decade,&quot; the conference was told.</p>
<p>The change is in part due to technical advances. Tougher components are increasingly able to survive impact with the atmosphere.</p>
<p>Last year a 225kg part from a Delta rocket crashed in Georgetown, Texas, only 45 metres from a house.</p>
<p>Space debris stems from fragments breaking off during propulsion, released deliberately as part of the mission, or the discarded upper stages of rockets.</p>
<p>Clean-up of space is too costly and dangerous, delegates heard, but stricter rules or economic incentives could be used to alleviate the situation.</p>
<p>Pagnanelli also highlighted predictions from scientists about high intensity meteor storms expected in 1998 and 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;Insurers must evaluate the possible impact on their industry, in case the majority of satellites orbiting the world are affected and the space debris problem is made worse,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Insurance News +44 171 542 2770</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VENICE, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
