<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518779" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Peugeot's Calvet gloomy on French car market.</title>
<headline>Peugeot's Calvet gloomy on French car market.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>PSA Peugeot Citroen chairman Jacques Calvet said on Thursday the post-rebate weakness of the French car market was turning out to be deeper and longer than expected.</p>
<p>He said that orders in France in April would likely be 23 percent to 24 percent lower, extending the gloomy trend of the first quarter when new car sales fell 26.5 percent.</p>
<p>Car sales in France rose 13.6 percent in the first nine months of 1996, boosted by a rebate scheme that ran to the end of September. &quot;We knew there would be a backlash after the rebates ended, but we didn't think that it would be so bad or last so long,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Calvet said the company expected car sales in France this year to fall to 1.89 million units from 2.13 million last year, or a decline of around 11.5 percent. The company had previously forecast a 10 percent drop in the French car market.</p>
<p>The introduction of rebate programmes in Spain and Italy should help the western European market to grow around two percent in 1997, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
