<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518709" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: GREEK PIRAEUSBANK EYES TIGHT-LIPPED SIGMA.</title>
<headline>GREEK PIRAEUSBANK EYES TIGHT-LIPPED SIGMA.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Financial press reports that Piraeus Bank has agreed to acquire a major stake in Athens stock exchange member Sigma Securities were not confirmed by either side.</p>
<p>Sigma's managing director John Marcopoulos, contacted by Reuters in New York, would neither confirm or deny the press reports that have sparked talk in the market.</p>
<p>Asked whether it was a done deal, Marcopoulos said: &quot;No comment for the time being.&quot;</p>
<p>Piraeus Bank president Michael Sallas told Reuters that talks were indeed at a progressed stage but nothing was finalised or signed yet. Discussion would resume after Marcopoulos' return from the U.S.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue has not been finalised. Talks will continue when Mr. Marcopoulos returns,&quot; Sallas told Reuters.</p>
<p>Market watchers say Piraeus Bank's foray into the brokerage business, part of its expansion strategy, is a move that will benefit the bank.</p>
<p>Sigma, one of the leading brokers, has an established brand name, strong foreign clientele and a high market share of the bourse's business.</p>
<p>Based on recent brokers association (SMEHA) statistics it did 7.4 percent of the exchange's trading volume in the first quarter ranking second place among the bourse's 63 member brokers. --George Georgiopoulos, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
