<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518874" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: More British women hold family purse - survey.</title>
<headline>More British women hold family purse - survey.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>British women are increasingly taking control of the household purse strings, a new survey out on Thursday shows.</p>
<p>A poll commissioned by the Goldfish credit card found more than half of the women canvassed -- 52 percent to be exact -- now claim to run the family finances.</p>
<p>But only 38 percent of men agreed with the statement and the survey found that the man of the household tended to keep control of the credit card if nothing else. Nearly half the men surveyed claimed the credit card as their sole preserve.</p>
<p>The survey found women said they are most likely to pay the bills, check bank statements and make major purchase decisions.</p>
<p>Decisions on major purchases are generally made jointly but 29 percent of women said the decision would be theirs alone. Only 16 percent of men agreed.</p>
<p>Women in the north of England and Scotland were most likely to control the money. That is reflected by the fact that men in those regions came closest to agreeing that their partners &quot;wear the trousers&quot; as far as family spending is concerned.</p>
<p>The Goldfish credit card was launched last year by British Gas and HFC Bank, a subsidiary of Household International Inc.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
