<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518925" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Simsmetal says 2nd half remains on track.</title>
<headline>Simsmetal says 2nd half remains on track.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Metals recycler Simsmetal Ltd said on Thursday the improvement in market conditions noted in its half yearly profit had so far been maintained in the second half which began on January 1.</p>
<p>&quot;We have experienced better trading conditions in the second half than in the first half,&quot; chief executive officer John Crabb told reporters at a briefing, although he refused to be drawn on the company's third quarter profit result, due early next week.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't say anything on that. We will be reporting next week and I will stick with what we said at the half yearly,&quot; Crabb said.  </p>
<p>On January 28, the company reported a sharply lower net profit for the six months to December 31 of A$14.07 million, although it said there had been a general improvement in demand and prices for its products. It forecast an improvement in profitability for the second half of the financial year.</p>
<p>On the costs side, Crabb noted that while a new A$11 million plant had just been commissioned at its major St Mary's car breaking and recycling centre in western Sydney, the expected 30 to 40 percent cost savings from the new plant were not expected to flow through in the current financial year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
