<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518991" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: OPINION - Jakarta shares will rebound after polls.</title>
<headline>OPINION - Jakarta shares will rebound after polls.</headline>
<text>
<p>By Simon Francis, Research Analyst</p>
<p>Nomura Indonesia, Jakarta</p>
<p>JAKARTA, April 17 - Investors had driven the index to 712 points in February 1997, a record high, on the back of some of the highest earnings forecasts in the region. Fans of the Elliott Wave theory, who were predicting a correction to between 650 and 630 have been proven right as profit-taking and earnings &quot;disappointments&quot; caused a correction of 11 percent. Barring a sharp decline in political confidence, the market is expected to remain around 630 points until after the May election. Thereafter, a sharp rebound is predicted as political confidence returns and 1997 earnings forecasts come into the frame, the index probably approaching 800 in 1Q98.</p>
<p>The only substantive reason to sell, other than profit-taking of course, occurred when Indosat suggested at an analysts meeting that Telkom's franchise over domestic and international telecommunications may be removed earlier than expected. This was in stark contrast to Telkom's listing prospectus, causing a huge amount of uncertainty. Had the government relaxed Telkom's mandate over the industry, it may have jeopardised the rest of the privatisation programme. Indosat quickly withdrew its statement.</p>
<p>EARNINGS DISAPPOINTMENTS WERE MINOR BUT SUFFICIENT TO TRIGGER CORRECTION</p>
<p>BNI's results were only two percent above consensus. This was deemed insufficient by an equities market now accustomed to strong outperformance of IPO earnings forecasts -- even if analysts were reluctant to push forecasts higher.</p>
<p>Semen Gresik's woes in its tax accounting and a troubled power plant at Tonasa has sent sentiment -- and the stock price -- tumbling although over the medium-term the company has among the best earnings prospects in the market.</p>
<p>Similarly at HM Sampoerna, the 1996 results were 5-6 percent below the consensus. In our view, this should not have surprised the market -- the consensus forecast had been downgraded steadily throughout the year from 510 rupiah (earnings per share) to 460 rupiah.</p>
<p>The remainder of the reporting season will have to pass with no unforseen shocks before earnings will become a driving factor in the market again.</p>
<p>High earnings expectations for 1997 appear to be working against the market despite the fact there have been few real disappointments in 1996 so far. This means that instead of earnings for 1997 being priced into the market in 4Q97, after the 1H97 results are released, investors may wait until they are more confident of the numbers -- probably early 1998.</p>
<p>SEVERAL FACTORS OTHER THAN POLITICS AND MARKETS TO AFFECT MARKET OVER NEXT FEW MONTHS</p>
<p>* A structural shift in savings could direct new capital to the equities market:</p>
<p>The extent of this shift depends on whether pension fund managers perceive that share performance will better returns in Indonesia's bank deposit instruments.</p>
<p>A March directive now allows pension funds to invest in mutual funds. We estimate that this could shift up to US$9.0 billion into mutual funds. Pension money was previously restricted to bank deposits, money market instruments and property.</p>
<p>* But heavy-handed margin trading regulations could subdue local interest:</p>
<p>Margin trading at mostly local houses boosted the proportion of daily trading attributable to local investors around 55 percent from about 35 percent at the beginning of 1996. After a determined effort to increase local interest in the stock market, BAPEPAM now risks losing momentum by introducing rules which would significantly curtail margin trading. BAPEPAM is considering restricting margin trading to those who have one billion rupiah in assets and annual income of 200 million rupiah. Cynically, one might suggest that should the new rules be introduced, the low tax collection rate will be reason enough to end the current margin trading frenzy!</p>
<p>* There is now scope for a further cut in interest rates which could help precipitate a market recovery:</p>
<p>Strong consumer demand and the government's 17 percent credit growth target preclude a sustained reduction in interest rates at present. Bank lending is still rising at around 25 percent per annum. There is, however, more scope than generally assumed. Real interest rates now appear very high given that inflation in the first two months of 1997 fell to 5.1 percent from above 10 percent at the start of 1996.</p>
<p>The key to lower inflation has been BULOG's success in keeping food prices under control during the festive season. BULOG is expected to continue its price control regime at least up to the election next month.</p>
<p>A key reason for cutting interest rates further would be to discourage short-term money inflows. The March 12, 1997 reduction in SBPUs of 50 basis points was not premature. First, short-term fund inflow should drop as the interest rate differential falls, damping money supply growth. Secondly, the rate cut should not stimulate loan growth because in April 1997 the banks' reserve requirement was raised from three percent to five percent. This is estimated to reduce funds available for lending by some 5.8 trillion rupiah as total required reserves are estimated to rise from 8.8 trillion rupiah to 14.6 trillion rupiah.</p>
<p>CONCLUSION</p>
<p>Investors should look out for rebounds in blue-chip stocks after the elections in May and some volatile property sector trading if an interest rate cut looks more imminent.</p>
<p>(NOTE - The views expressed in this article represent the views of the author only. They should not be seen as reflecting the views of Reuters).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
