<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518985" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Dollar wanes in late Tokyo as activity stutters.</title>
<headline>Dollar wanes in late Tokyo as activity stutters.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>0618 GMT     2400 GMT	NYK CLOSE</p>
<p> USD/JPY	   125.47/57    125.80/85     125.78/88</p>
<p> USD/DEM	   1.7250/55    1.7282/87     1.7290/95</p>
<p>--------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The dollar slid further against the yen and mark by late Tokyo trade on Thursday, with activity virtually at a halt as operators took a wait-and-see stance ahead of the release of U.S. trade figures at 1230 GMT.</p>
<p>Concern about Bank of Japan (BOJ) intervention, a rise in Japan's trade surplus with the U.S. and comments by Deputy U.S. Treasury Secretary Lawrence Summers all weighed on the dollar.  </p>
<p>Although dealers said more sales could ensue if the greenback ended Tokyo trade below 125.50 yen, most said they felt Japanese institutional investor interest in buying on dips was likely to prevent much in the way of slides.</p>
<p>&quot;But should the U.S. trade data be poor, the dollar could possibly be sold down as low as 124.50 yen,&quot; one trust bank dealer said, noting that profit-taking was likely to dominate during European trade until the figures were released.</p>
<p>But he added that even if the data showed a wider than expected trade gap, the interest rate differential between Japan and the U.S. should prevent large dollar losses.  </p>
<p>A Reuters poll of economists gave an average forecast of a $10.1 billion deficit in February, against $12.7 billion in January.</p>
<p>The release of Japanese customs-cleared trade data early on Thursday morning showed a smaller-than-expected overall customs-cleared trade surplus in March, which briefly sparked a spurt of buying that took the greenback up to 126 yen.</p>
<p>But its gains were short-lived, as news that Japan's trade surplus with the United States in March rose 11.2 percent from a year earlier to 379.83 billion yen set off sales from interbank dealers, speculators and U.S. funds, dealers said.  </p>
<p>In mid-morning, additional sales were sparked by comments by Deputy U.S. Treasury Secretary Lawrence Summers that domestic-led growth in Japan is crucial to avoid trade friction and the U.S. would react strongly if trade pacts were violated.</p>
<p>But after that the dollar mostly languished near 125.50 yen until mid-afternoon, when some U.S. fund selling of marks for yen, in an attempt to test the 72.50-55 yen downside, pushed it as low as 125.35 yen.</p>
<p>One trust bank dealer said there were some options-linked offers lined up near 125.20 yen, but also that buying could emerge at that point.  </p>
<p>Although overnight statements by senior Japanese Finance Ministry official Eisuke Sakakibara deepened the mood of concern about possible intervention, dealers said it appeared to have been mostly digested by the market as a factor.</p>
<p>He told foreign exchange dealers on Wednesday that Japanese authorities would intervene in foreign exchange markets when appropriate and when they saw that it could be effective.</p>
<p>A dealer with a European bank in Singapore said there could be a correction in the dollar/yen towards 125.00 yen later today.--Singapore newsroom +65 8703083; Elaine Lies in Tokyo +81-3-3432-8806</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
