<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519043" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Palladium lease rates remain at high levels.</title>
<headline>Palladium lease rates remain at high levels.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palladium lease rates remain at high levels, reflecting the metal's tight supply in the spot Zurich market and the lack of Russian sales, Japanese traders said on Thursday.</p>
<p>One month palladium lease rates were quoted at 10 percent to 11 percent on Thursday, down from the very high level of 19 percent hit late last week but up sharply from about three percent earlier this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Lingering uncertainty over the resumption of Russian exports, combined with robust palladium demand from the auto catalyst sector, especially in the United States, were the main reasons behind the continued high lease rates,&quot; an official of a major bullion house said. &quot;The market remains technically squeezed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Traders said volatile trading is likely to continue, with prices and lease rates possibly spiking higher unless the Russian matter is settled.</p>
<p>Russia, the biggest supplier of the metal, has suspended exports since the beginning of this year, and Japanese traders have no word from Russia when talks on resuming sales might be held.</p>
<p>Japanese traders are becoming sceptical over whether Russia would resume exports soon, given the abnormally long suspension.</p>
<p>&quot;Although there are many rumours circulating in the domestic market concerning Russia and many officials in Russia tend to make comments on the palladium shipments to Japan recently, nothing is certain. We don't know what we can believe,&quot; a trading house trader said.</p>
<p>--Tokyo Commodity Desk, +81-3-3432-7431</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
