<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519250" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea's high-speed rail link has safety problems.</title>
<headline>S.Korea's high-speed rail link has safety problems.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A South Korean high-speed railway under construction has structural problems on some of its bridges, which may need to be partially rebuilt, the authority said in a statement seen on Thursday.</p>
<p>News of the defects, which the authority said posed safety problems, battered construction shares on Thursday. The railway will link Seoul with Pusan, running almost the entire length of South Korea from north to south.  </p>
<p>The construction sector's sub-index fell 2.6 percent, or 7.35 points, to 271.31 in early Thursday trading on concerns that many construction firms involved in the project may have to report lower profits in the future because of additional costs required for rebuilding.</p>
<p>The Korea High Speed Rail Construction Authority said five of 37 bridges examined by a U.S. company had been found with &quot;long-term structural and safety problems&quot;.</p>
<p>The examination on the Seoul-Taejon route was conducted by Wiss, Janney, Elstner Associates Inc between last August and January this year.</p>
<p>The authority also said some repairs were necessary at 177 sites, although a further examination was needed to work out details.</p>
<p>-- Seoul Newsroom (822) 727-5646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
