<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519343" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German DAX held back by autos in pre-bourse.</title>
<headline>German DAX held back by autos in pre-bourse.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares were largely unchanged in Thursday pre-bourse trade after Wall Street's renewed gains as trading volumes remain low and dealers noted a pull downwards from losses among auto sector shares.</p>
<p>The IBIS-DAX index of electronic trade gained just 12.33 points to 3,359.87 in pre-bourse, with June DAX futures gaining 12.5 points to 3,369.5.</p>
<p>Daimler Benz fell 2.00 marks, around 1.5 percent, to 133.0 amid the highest volumes of the session as dealers said there was a degree of disappointment at the analysts' meeting following details of its 1996 results on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Shares in BMW, which have rallied in recent weeks, were also lower in early trade, dipping to a low of 1,365 marks from 1,425 marks before coming right back up to trade flat.</p>
<p>BMW chief Bernd Pischetsrieder said on Wedesday that BMW was only expecting &quot;slight&quot; earnings growth in 1997, a comment he clarified as meaning single digit percent growth.</p>
<p>Airline Lufthansa was little moved by a statement from the company saying its 1997 results would be above those in 1996. Its shares edged six pfennigs higher to 22.65.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
