<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519362" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: PRESS DIGEST -Switzerland - April 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST -Switzerland - April 17.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights from Swiss newspapers on Thursday:</p>
<p>NEUE ZUERCHER ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- The Swiss government appointed Rolf Bloch president of the special fund for Holocaust victims that Swiss banks and other private institutions set up earlier this year. Bloch is also president of the Swiss Jewish Federation. The foreign board members for the fund were not elected yet because there was some controversy over what role prominent Nobel prize winner Elie Wiesel would play.</p>
<p>- Swiss textile testing equipment and air conditioning systems maker Zellweger Luwa reported stagnant 1996 figures with a net profit of 27.2 million Swiss francs. The group announced that it would sell its Burkhalter unit, which generated 1996 revenue of 260 million Swiss francs with a workforce of 1,146 employees.</p>
<p>TAGES ANZEIGER</p>
<p>- Swiss medical doctors do not show any commitment to lower health costs in Switzerland, an opinion poll among 610 doctors showed.</p>
<p>- Swiss telecommunication technology group Ascom reported a loss of 128 million Swiss francs in 1996.</p>
<p>- Swiss private bank Vontobel registered a 47 percent boost in 1996 net profit to 60.2 million Swiss francs.</p>
<p>JOURNAL DE GENEVE</p>
<p>- The Swiss government plans to partly privatise its arms production companies.</p>
<p>- Swiss financial systems and information provider Telekurs reported a 1996 net profit of 20.1 million Swiss francs, down from 22.6 million francs in the previous year.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
