<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519380" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Reuters German Advertising &amp; Media Digest - Apr 17.</title>
<headline>Reuters German Advertising &amp; Media Digest - Apr 17.</headline>
<text>
<p>-------------GAM--------------------</p>
<p>REUTERS GERMAN ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA DIGEST</p>
<p>------ April 17, 1997------------------</p>
<p>News from Reuters and the German press on Advertising, Marketing, Brand-name Products, Consumer Trends, Media and the Internet</p>
<p>**********</p>
<p>ADVERTISING &amp; MARKETING:</p>
<p>COLOGNE - Top private network RTL says it has for the first time crossed the three-billion-mark threshold in advertising turnover. The station posted 3.211 billion marks ($1.859 billion) in advertising sales for 1996, up from 2.873 billion marks in the previous year. Net advertising proceeds grew by 4.7 percent to 2.052 billion. Profits climbed to 144.1 million from 102.6 million in 1995. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>HAMBURG - Media and advertising industry representatives have blasted troubled private television station Sat1 for broadcasting a sponsored evening of programming without advertising. Although no one denies that new types of advertising are necessary, says the chairman of the organisation of industries that advertise (OWM), Hans Kratz, it is a mistake to suggest to viewers they can have television without ads. (Reuter)</p>
<p>**********</p>
<p>HAMBURG - Copyright law has drawn media companies, advertising agencies and attorneys into an industry-wide debate. Agencies do not do themselves any favours, says lawyer Paul Hertin, speaking at the OWM convention, in trying to protect advertising concepts with a copyright when so few ideas are actually new. Director of market communications at the Deutsche Bank AG, Hans-Dieter Liesering, says he is constantly in fear of court battles over ownership rights. Yet copyrights provide protection which leads to the improvement of ad agency campaigns, says attorney Eberhard Kolonko. (Reuter)</p>
<p>**********</p>
<p>HAMBURG - Advertising agencies have exhausted their ability to increase efficiency, says the president of the German advertisers' association (GWA), Lothar Leonard, also speaking at the OWM convention. If customers in the industry have an interest in maintaining the existing advertising system, cost spiraling must end, Leonard says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*************************************</p>
<p>MEDIA &amp; INTERNET:</p>
<p>MUNICH - Prosecutors say they have indicted the managing director of the German unit of commercial online service Compuserve in connection with distributing pornography over the Internet. The U.S. company dismisses the charges as groundless. (Reuter)</p>
<p>**********</p>
<p>HAMBURG- German television draws huge advertising revenues but suffers from over-regulation, threatening the future survival of some private channels, the head of Germany's largest private station says. The general manager of the RTL network, Helmut Thoma, speaking at the OWM convention says German commercial television desperately needs more flexible advertising rules for networks to be profitable. (Reuter)</p>
<p>**********</p>
<p>SEATTLE - MSNBC, the joint venture between U.S. companies Microsoft Corp and NBC, has announced it plans to launch a German-language Internet news service in collaboration with Germany's ZDF public television network. (Reuter)</p>
<p>**********</p>
<p>MUNICH - Media giant Bertelsmann AG ranked as the world's second largest media company with turnover of 21 billion marks, says trade magazine &quot;w&amp;v&quot;. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*************************************</p>
<p>BRAND-NAME PRODUCTS &amp; MARKETS:</p>
<p>STUTTGART - Auto and aeronautics group Daimler-Benz AG, reporting a 12 percent rise in first quarter sales, predicts profits could grow strongly by the turn of the century as its restructuring plan takes hold. (Reuter)</p>
<p>**********</p>
<p>HANOVER - Auto maker Volkswagen's chief executive Ferdinand Piech plans to take on luxury class giants Mercedes and BMW by introducing a 400 horsepower sports car, says Auto, Motor, Sport magazine. (Reuter)</p>
<p>**********</p>
<p>BONN - German sports car maker Porsche AG on Wednesday says it expects profits for the current 1996-97 business year to July 31 to be at least double the profits for the first half of the year. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*************************************</p>
<p>PEOPLE NEWS:</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Leader of the Social Democrats (SPD) Oskar Lafontaine will become a member of the managing council of public broadcaster ZDF, says a spokesman of the Rhineland-Palatinate state chancellery. (Frankfurter Rundschau)</p>
<p>*************************************</p>
<p>Deborah Cole, Berlin Newsroom, 49-30-203-98114</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>For further information and news, see Reuters Advertising &amp; Media Briefing. And visit us on the Internet: http://www.bizinfo.reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
