<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519465" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Former Reynolds researcher testifies at Fla. trial.</title>
<headline>Former Reynolds researcher testifies at Fla. trial.</headline>
<byline>June Bell</byline>
<dateline>JACKSONVILLE, Fla 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co research biochemist testified Friday that the company shut down a research project in 1970 when it was making advances in determining whether smoking caused illness.</p>
<p>Joseph Bumgarner, who worked in the company's Biological Research Division from 1967 to 1970, testified about Reynolds' so-called &quot;mouse house&quot; experiments in which rats and rabbits were subjected to cigarette smoke to determine its effects on their health.  </p>
<p>His testimony came on the 10th day of the trial of a wrongful death suit filed against Reynolds by Dana Raulerson, whose sister Jean Connor died of lung cancer at age 49.</p>
<p>Reynolds is a unit of RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp.</p>
<p>Bumgarner, 57, told jurors the experiments, some of which involved rabbits inhaling smoke through a tube directly into the their throats, appeared to be making progress in determining the possible health effects of cigarette smoking.</p>
<p>&quot;We were very excited about what we were doing,&quot; he said. &quot;I thought we made some pretty good advances.  </p>
<p>Without warning, Bumgarner said, the researchers working on the project were called into a conference room in March 1970 and told the project was being shut down.</p>
<p>&quot;We were told that the biological research division was being dissolved,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the researchers were told to turn in their laboratory notebooks, which he believed had been destroyed until he learned in 1992 that a Reynolds' lawyer had copies of them.  </p>
<p>The testimony appeared to advance a theme presented by Raulerson's lawyers to jurors throughout the widely watched trial -- that Reynolds knew smoking was dangerous but hid that knowledge from the public.</p>
<p>The plaintiffs have claimed that the company had a duty to know the dangers of their product and a responsibility to continue research to figure out health risks.</p>
<p>Bumgarner testified that a Reynolds veterinary pathologist had shown him slides that indicated emphysema was present in the tissue of several rabbits used in the experiment.  </p>
<p>On cross-examination, Reynolds attorney Paul Crist displayed a confidential 1969 company memo that indicated three rabbits had died of emphysema but that it was probably because of bronchial pneumonia.</p>
<p>Bumgarner said he disagreed with that finding.</p>
<p>Asked whether the cigarette company should have published its research, Bumgarner said: &quot;With more work, yes, the project should have been published.&quot;</p>
<p>Outside the courtroom, Bumgarner, who was testifying for the first time in a tobacco trial, said he believed the laboratory was shut down because researchers were coming up with test results that linked smoking to illness.</p>
<p>&quot;There's not a doubt in my mind,&quot; he said. &quot;I think what we were doing was making the (Reynolds) legal department very, very nervous.&quot;</p>
<p>Bumgarner, who now works for the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, said he smoked Salem brand cigarettes until about 12 years ago, when he quit after having a heart attack.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JACKSONVILLE, Fla"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
