<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519626" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wyser-Pratte, Spear push Huntsman on Rexene bid.</title>
<headline>Wyser-Pratte, Spear push Huntsman on Rexene bid.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two dissident shareholder groups in chemical company Rexene Corp have written a letter asking Huntsman Corp to make its position clear on whether it can finance the acquisition of Rexene.</p>
<p>Guy P. Wyser-Pratte, president of Wyser-Pratte &amp; Co Inc, and Fred Kambeitz, a partner at Spear, Leeds &amp; Kellogg, wrote to Jon Hunstman saying that while they believed Huntsman should acquire Rexene, Huntsman has not provided enough information to shareholders.  </p>
<p>&quot;For better or worse, investors have doubts about Huntsman's position on Rexene, despite its outstanding record of closing chemical industry acquisitions and your assurances that financing will not be a problem for Huntsman,&quot; the shareholders said.</p>
<p>Huntsman has said it made three offers for Rexene but would no longer deal with the present management.  </p>
<p>Rexene recently announced a Dutch auction tender for 11.5 percent of its own shares at between $14.00 and $16.00 per share and has been fighting off the attentions of Wyser-Pratte and Spear.</p>
<p>The company is to hold a shareholder meeting on April 30 and the dissidents have been trying to oust the incumbent board.</p>
<p>Wyser-Pratte and Spear said that if still interested in acquiring Rexene, privately-held Huntsman should issue a statement that &quot;there are no material financing or due diligence conditions to an acquisition by Huntsman.&quot;</p>
<p>The dissidents also said that Huntsman should meet with two recently-appointed Rexene board members, Richard Perry and Stephen Swid, to explain to them in detail plans for financing.</p>
<p>&quot;As you can see, investors are in a state of confusion. Please help them by clarifying your intentions,&quot; they said in the letter.</p>
<p>No one from Huntsman was immediately available for comment. ((-- David Chance New York Newsroom 212 859 1902))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25140">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
