<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519663" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ehrlich says corrected trade report adds to Q1.</title>
<headline>Ehrlich says corrected trade report adds to Q1.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Commerce Undersecretary Everett Ehrlich on Friday said the reduction in the February trade deficit from what was first reported will add a few tenths of a percent to the estimate of first quarter growth.</p>
<p>Interviewed on Reuters Financial Television, Ehrlich said the GDP number for the first quarter is going to be large, estimating it will show an increase of 4.0 percent or more.</p>
<p>The department on Thursday after correcting for &quot;reporting errors&quot; on oil imports, said the February deficit actually dropped from $12.67 billion in January to $10.4 billion rather than the $11.59 billion reported earlier.  </p>
<p>&quot;It will take GDP estimates up...a few tenths perhaps,&quot; he said, adding that the GDP number for the first quarter is going to be larger that the 3.8 percent growth achieved in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;It could well start with a four from what we see to date,&quot; Ehrlich said.</p>
<p>Asked about the strong dollar, he said that he hoped that the Japanese authorities did not use it as an excuse to back away from reform efforts.</p>
<p>&quot;Our concern about the dollar is that it not be a pretext for a softening commitment for trade liberalization,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said it would be bad news for the Japanese to raise interest rates at this time as suggested by some as a way of strengthening the yen, bringing it more in line with its long term value.</p>
<p>He said this could also be accomplished by deregulation in the financial sector since it would allow capital to flow into Japan.</p>
<p>In the interview, Ehrlich blamed a miscommunication between the Customs Service that accumulates the oil import data although to &quot;some extent it is an artifact of a pencil and paper environment that we've got to leave very soon.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the administration has a plan to automate export and import declarations in a way that would do away with the potential for this kind of error but &quot;Congress needs to fund it and exporters particularly need to embrace it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
