<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519726" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-ENGLISH PREMIER LEAGUE WEEKEND MATCHES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ENGLISH PREMIER LEAGUE WEEKEND MATCHES.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Matches scheduled for this weekend in the English premier league (kick-off times 1400 GMT Saturday unless stated, league positions in brackets):</p>
<p>Arsenal (3) v Blackburn Rovers (14)</p>
<p>Arsenal's late surge for the title continued with a 2-0 win against Leicester last Saturday. They have won five of their last six games. England defender Tony Adams is again doubtful with an ankle injury while midfielder Paul Merson came through a midweek reserve game and is available.</p>
<p>This is Blackburn's second consecutive game against one of the title chasers after their 3-2 defeat by Manchester United last weekend. Coach Tony Parkes is showing interest in Sunderland defender Richard Ord, but his main priority must be to avoid relegation.</p>
<p>Aston Villa (5) v Tottenham Hotspur (9)</p>
<p>Villa are making an impressive late run and seem sure to grab a European place on a weekend when they are celebrating 100 years at Villa Park. Australian goalkeeper Mark Bosnich, who walked out before the 3-1 defeat at Derby after being placed on the bench, is unlikely to play as Michael Oakes continues.</p>
<p>Tottenham, meanwhile, could have up to 13 players out through injuries. Their list includes strikers Chris Armstrong (ankle), Steffen Iversen (cartilage) and winger Ruel Fox (hamstring).</p>
<p>Chelsea (8) v Leicester City (13)</p>
<p>Chelsea lost 3-1 at Newcastle on Wednesday after reaching the FA Cup final by beating Wimbledon 3-0 last Sunday. They have lost their last four league games and coach Ruud Gullit is without the suspended Frank LeBeouf and may opt to rest Italian Gianfranco Zola.</p>
<p>Leicester won their first major trophy since 1964 on Wednesday night when they defeated Middlesbrough 1-0 at Hillsborough in the League Cup final replay. American keeper Kasey Keller will be missing on international duty.</p>
<p>Liverpool (2) v Manchester United (1) (kick-off 1015 GMT)</p>
<p>The biggest game of the season brings together the top two title contenders. Liverpool faltered in their title challenge after a 1-1 draw in the Merseyside derby at Everton on Wednesday and have secured only 12 points from a possible 24. Striker Robbie Fowler, sent off in midweek, plays his last game before a three-match ban.</p>
<p>Manchester United have only two defeats in their last 21 league games. Danish goalkeeper Peter Schmeichel remains doubtful with a back injury but has resumed training with Ryan Giggs, Dennis Irwin and David May.</p>
<p>Middlesbrough (19) v Sunderland (18)</p>
<p>Middlesbrough have to bounce back from their defeat by Leicester in the League Cup replay and focus on their relegation battle in this north-east derby. Coach Bryan Robson's side have 14 points from their last 16 but goalkeeper Mark Schwarzer (shin) and defenders Curtis Fleming (knee) and Italian Gianluca Festa (neck) are doubtful.</p>
<p>Sunderland coach Peter Reid has strikers Alex Rae and Niall Quinn back after suspension and injury respectively and hopes to add to a tally of five points in five games.</p>
<p>Newcastle United (4) v Derby County (10)</p>
<p>Newcastle coach Kenny Dalglish saw his side demolish Chelsea 3-1 in midweek and his side seem certain to secure a European competition place. England striker Les Ferdinand hopes to play after a knee injury in the win as does Irish winger Keith Gillespie who suffered minor concussion.</p>
<p>Derby scored their 10th goal in four games in the 2-1 win against Aston Villa last weekend and have virtually assured their place in the premier league next season. Coach Jim Smith is still without Croatian defender Igor Stimac but Estonian goalkeeper Mart Poom is available after a shoulder injury.</p>
<p>Nottingham Forest (20) v Leeds United (11)</p>
<p>Bottom club Nottingham Forest have not won in their last five home games and have to win all their remaining matches to stand any chance of beating the drop. England defender Stuart Pearce, Welsh striker Dean Saunders and defender Colin Cooper have recovered from knocks while Alf-Inge Haaland serves a one match ban.</p>
<p>Leeds lost 2-0 to Wimbledon in midweek and welcome back defender David Wetherall from a head injury in an otherwise unchanged squad.</p>
<p>Sheffield Wednesday (6) v Wimbledon (7)</p>
<p>Wednesday coach David Pleat has injury worries over defender Des Walker (ligament) and strikers Andy Booth (ankle) and David Hirst (achilles) as his side look to consolidate a 15-game unbeaten home run.</p>
<p>Wimbledon's own European aspirations were rekindled with a 2-0 win against Leeds on Wednesday but could still be without Nigerian striker Efan Ekoku (wrist). Midfielders Robbie Earle and Vinny Jones should be fit after picking up slight injuries in the win.</p>
<p>Southampton (16) v Coventry City (15)</p>
<p>Southampton coach Graeme Souness is expected to be without influential England midfielder Matt Le Tissier for this relegation battle as they attempt to continue their run of four games undefeated.</p>
<p>Coventry, buoyed by their 2-1 victory at Liverpool two weeks ago, have a fully fit squad to choose although England midfielder John Salako is out for the rest of the season. Coach Gordon Strachan, 40, could once again select himself after playing at Anfield.</p>
<p>West Ham United (17) v Everton (12)</p>
<p>West Ham are still thick in the relegation battle despite coach Harry Redknapp's expensive new recruits John Hartson and Paul Kitson scoring crucial goals recently. Julian Dicks (knee), Frank Lampard Jnr. (broken leg) and Danny Williamson (heel operation) could all be out for the season.</p>
<p>Everton, who battled hard for their 1-1 draw against Merseyside rivals Liverpool in midweek have defender Craig Short out after he fell awkwardly on his neck in that game. Ireland defender Terry Phelan (hamstring) and Danish midfielder Claus Thomsen (ankle) face late fitness tests.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
