<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519705" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: EMERGENCY WEATHER CONDITIONS -  WSC - 17-APR.</title>
<headline>EMERGENCY WEATHER CONDITIONS -  WSC - 17-APR.</headline>
<text>
<p>Severe flooding is ongoing in the US North Plains across many river systems. Cool temperatures for one more day keep snowmelt slow. After that, warmer weather will develop, quickening snowmelt, and may lead to even more severe flooding. Also, flooding conditions are expected to develop in Manitoba, Canada, the next several days as temperatures warm and a heavy snowpack melts.  </p>
<p>All Typhoon Warnings and Watches for the Northern Mariana Islands, including Guam, have been dropped. Typhoon Isa, with 125 mph winds, is tracking northwestward, away from the Islands. Further strengthening is expected this period as the system turns more northward, before beginning to weaken late in the period. Shipping will be under extreme risk from this system. It is expected to be about 150-250 miles west of the Mariana islands as it tracks northward during this period.  </p>
<p>Tropical cyclone Ian, with 55 mph winds, is well to the south of the Fiji islands at this time. This system is only a threat to shipping as it stays over open water as it moves towards the east-southeast. It may strengthen a little more during the next 12 hours before it begins to weaken.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
