<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519798" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-RECORD GATE FORECAST AS JUVENTUS FACE BOLOGNA.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-RECORD GATE FORECAST AS JUVENTUS FACE BOLOGNA.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Record box-office takings of $1.2 million dollars are expected for Saturday's Serie A clash between league leaders Juventus and fifth placed Bologna.</p>
<p>Juventus come into this difficult away fixture one week after suffering only their third league defeat of the season when unexpectedly beaten 3-0 by mid-table Udinese in Turin.</p>
<p>That defeat appears to have re-opened the Italian title race with second-placed Parma now only three points behind Juventus.</p>
<p>Hosts Bologna, promoted from division two last summer, have proved the biggest surprise of the year and have had their best season in Serie A since 1971.</p>
<p>Despite Bologna's current good form, Juventus midfielder, Frenchman Zinedine Zidane, was optimistic about Saturday's game, arguing that the Udinese defeat was attributable to the side's exhaustion after spectacular wins against AC Milan and Dutch side Ajax Amsterdam in the same eight day period.</p>
<p>&quot;It's true that the three games in eight days had left us a bit rundown but things are much better now. We'll go to Bologna looking for a win...Given the way things are at the moment, we've no choice but to go for the three points,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Zidane is unworried that one-time relegation zoned Parma have closed the gap to just three points.</p>
<p>&quot;Throughout the season we've been better than Parma and for that reason I'm not worried that the title will get away from us.&quot;</p>
<p>Juventus field a full strength side in Bologna, with Frenchman Didier Deschamps returning to partner Zidane in midfield alongside Angelo Di Livio and Yugoslav Vladimir Jugovic with Croat Alen Boksic and Christian Vieri in attack.</p>
<p>Bologna will be without their injured Russian striker Igor Kolivanov, due to be replaced by Davide Fontolan, but welcome back influential Swedish striker Kennet Andersson.</p>
<p>Bologna midfielder Cristiano Scapolo is under no illusions about the difficulty of his side's task.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very difficult match for us because to hope that Juventus might trip up in another game after the Udinese one is a bit like hoping to find the end of the rainbow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Recent history is against Bologna who last beat Juventus at home 23 years ago, with a 2-1 win in October of 1974, while Juventus were the 1-0 winners when the sides met in Turin in December.</p>
<p>Juventus have asked for the game to be brought forward to Saturday because of their European Cup semifinal against Ajax Amsterdam in Turin on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Juventus take a 2-1 lead into the return leg of their clash with Ajax.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
