<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519813" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - SOUTH AFRICA - APRIL 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - SOUTH AFRICA - APRIL 18.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Friday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- The Basic Conditions of Employment bill proposes improved minimum conditions of employment in a range of areas, but allows greater flexibility to vary these standards through individual and collective bargaining.</p>
<p>- All charges against casino magnate Sol Kerzner and former Cape Town mayor David Bloomberg relating to a two million rand bribe paid to former Transkei homeland leader George Matanzima have been dropped by the attorney-general.</p>
<p>- Anglo American Corp has offered to reduce its 28 percent shareholding in Lonrho -- which was raised from just under 10 percent last October -- to nine percent.</p>
<p>- South Africa is poised for a major foreign relations coup by brokering a meeting between embattled Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko and rebel leader Laurent Kabila, which could happen somewhere in the country as soon as this weekend.</p>
<p>- Government finance figures show substantial overspending occurred in the last fiscal year -- 1.4 billion rand more than the overrun assumed in the budget last month.</p>
<p>- Gold Fields kicked off the gold mining March quarterly reporting season on a sombre note, with the group's aggregate taxed profit before capex sliding 29 percent or 97 million rand to 236 million rand, affected by a lower gold price and a firmer rand.</p>
<p>- A national intelligence agent has told an inquest court that Inkatha Freedom Party official Themba Khoza received an official car from hit-squad policemen to transport weapons they gave him for &quot;third-force&quot; activities.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- Deciduous fruit farmers will be allowed to export their fruit to a market of their choice, using an agent of their choice, for the first time since the 1930s, according to recommendations by the National Agricultural Marketing Council.</p>
<p>- Gold Fields of South Africa, the country's second-largest gold producer, posted a 31.5 percent slump in first quarter profit, hit by a lower gold price and extended Christmas holidays.</p>
<p>- Details of the draft Basic Conditions of Employment bill, which seeks to advance economic development and social justice by establishing and enforcing basic conditions of employment, were released by Labour Minister Tito Mboweni.</p>
<p>- NKH Holdings, a diversified holding company, said it planned to list its extensive food franchising operations and powerful property arm before mid-year.</p>
<p>- Aaron Searll, the chairman of Seardel, said he was spearheading a management buyout which would see the diversified clothing and textiles group delisted or becoming a cash shell.</p>
<p>- - - -  </p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- Hotel and casino magnate Sol Kerzner will not face any charges relating to the alleged payment in 1986 of a two million rand &quot;bribe&quot; intended to secure gambling rights in the then Transkei black homeland.</p>
<p>- President Nelson Mandela's grandson Ntsika Dlamini has appeared in the Johannesburg magistrate's court on fraud and theft charges for trying to cash a 5,000 rand cheque he is alleged to have stolen.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SAKE-BEELD</p>
<p>- The cabinet has approved the draft bill on the basic conditions of employment, which among other things, provides for a shorter minimum working week and increased overtime pay.</p>
<p>- The National Empowerment Consortium is to offer 9.1 million shares in Johnnic -- six percent of the company -- through the Ikageng share scheme for disadvantaged people.</p>
<p>- The Public Investment Commissioner, who carries out investments for the state's pension funds, is to make an offer for the shares which Malbak shareholders will receive next month as a result of the group's unbundling.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MAIL &amp; GUARDIAN</p>
<p>- De Beers has secretly bowed to Zairean rebel demands that it sever ties with President Mobutu Sese Seko's regime, after decades of close partnership with the despot who plundered his country to the brink of collapse.</p>
<p>- Health Minister Nkosazana Zuma has been implicated in a cover-up of circumstances surrounding the deaths of four patients in the care of a Cuban doctor who worked at a South African state hospital.</p>
<p>- In a landmark constitutional judgment, a man convicted of hijacking and attempted murder was released after only 15 months in jail, as he had not been given free legal advice.</p>
<p>--Johannesburg newsroom -27-11-482.1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
