<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519992" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: AB Air aims for low-rate UK-Lisbon cargo.</title>
<headline>AB Air aims for low-rate UK-Lisbon cargo.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>AB Airlines, which plans to start a twice-daily London Gatwick-Lisbon scheduled passenger BAC 1-11 service from May 1, said it will be selling cargo space at the low rate end of the market.</p>
<p>But cargo manager Martin Hawkes said he hoped to keep yields up by attracting high-value shipments such as human remains and also perishables, along with general freight.</p>
<p>&quot;Depending on passenger load, we will have 500 kg to 1.5 tonnes cargo capacity on each flight to sell,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Assuming we can negotiate reasonably priced handling costs at Lisbon, I hope to keep general rates down to about 0.50-0.60 stg per kg,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>AB Airlines is part of the AB Airlines Group, which also incorporates Air Bristol, Air Belfast and AB Shannon.</p>
<p>It has been operating three daily Shannon-Gatwick BAC 1-11 flights since December 1995, said Hawkes.</p>
<p>&quot;These have connected with other carriers' London flights to and from the United States, eastern Europe and the Far East,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We have done particularly well carrying electronic goods manufactured in the mini-Silicon Valley area near Shannon, despite attracting strong competition from truckers and Ryanair, which trucks to and from Dublin,&quot; said Hawkes.</p>
<p>He said he soon hoped to appoint a cargo general sales agent for AB in Lisbon.</p>
<p>-Bob Murphy, Reuters Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+ 44 171 542 7706; fax +5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
