<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="519969" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent closes higher on back of stronger U.S.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent closes higher on back of stronger U.S.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE Brent crude futures closed firmer on Friday having taken support from stronger U.S heating oil and WTI crude for much of the day.</p>
<p>June Brent closed 22 cents up at $17.91 a barrel.</p>
<p>Brent had achieved a short-lived high of $18.13 a barrel shortly after NYMEX opened, but only comfortably traded 10 cents or so below this in what dealers saw as a corrective bounce after recent price erosion.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there was resistance at $18.05 and $18.10 which it never convincingly broke,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;It basically followed WTI in the afternoon which got some support from good gasoline spread buying,&quot; said another.</p>
<p>Further out June Brent resistance was put at $18.23 and $18.50. &quot;The contract has failed four times around $18.49-50,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>May WTI, which expires next week April 22, showed determination to break the key psychological barrier of $20.00 a barrel but fell just short with a high of $19.97. It ended the session at $19.85, up 43 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;$20 is definitely a target, but then it needs to breach $20.05 for it to go much further,&quot; said one trader who was mildly bullish for gains next week ahead of the expiry.</p>
<p>Gasoline was starting to show tentative signs of a desire to be in the limelight gaining 0.75 to $61.45 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>&quot;Its about time it shouldered some responsibility,&quot; said one London trader.</p>
<p>NYMEX heating oil rose 0.40 to 54.40 cents a gallon on the back of colder weather which has tightned supplies.</p>
<p>Earlier, May IPE gas oil ended its session $1.00 a tonne stronger at $163.25 having tracked heating and crude for most of the day. Support was put at $160.00 a tonne and fairly strong resistance at $166.50.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8980</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
