<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520016" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Coffee--Futures rally hoists arabica differentials.</title>
<headline>Coffee--Futures rally hoists arabica differentials.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new rally in New York coffee futures on bullish U.S. stock data lifted washed arabica diffentials this week but robustas were softer on the weight of Far East sales.</p>
<p>The rally sent New York's May contract above the important $2.00 a lb mark for the second time this month. This sidelined many sellers although roaster demand remained strong into the second half of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Roasters still have many price-fixations to be done especially against July,&quot; said one European trader.</p>
<p>The arabica futures were given a boost by news of a smaller-than-expected rise in U.S. March green coffee stocks.</p>
<p>Traders said the falling certified coffee stocks in New York, the possible squeeze on May and the coming strikes in Brazil and Colombia also added fuel to the U.S. rally.</p>
<p>But the negative point is the absence of fund interest and traders said this could be due to the dwindling open position in May.</p>
<p>The market's main concern was whether the planned truck drivers' strike in Colombia over a labour dispute would take place from Sunday and how long it would last.</p>
<p>The government had threatened to outlaw the stoppage but traders pointed out the last crippling strike in January was also illegal.</p>
<p>Colombia is expected to ship 600,000 to 700,000 70-kg bags of coffee in April and one trader said about half of this amount has yet to be shipped.</p>
<p>The port workers strike in Brazil would have little impact on coffee shipments as the strike was unlikely to last long.</p>
<p>In robustas, the cash differentials softened a bit this week as new crop coffee arrived at Indonesian ports although traders noted that the crop could be slightly smaller than the last season due to crop cycle.</p>
<p>But industry interest for robustas was quite limited and roasters were well-covered and were in no hurry to make additional purchases.</p>
<p>Vietnam is also in no rush to sell some 40,000 to 50,000 tonnes left until the next crop in October while Uganda exports have virtually come to a standstill with the crop coming to an end.</p>
<p>Following differentials for some origins:</p>
<p>Brazil 3/4 medium good beans (May-June) 2 cents/lb under NY</p>
<p>July</p>
<p>    Guatamela strictly hard beans (June)    28-30 cents over NY</p>
<p>July</p>
<p>    India Plantation A			    2-3 cents over NY</p>
<p>July</p>
<p>    India Plantation B			    on par with NY July</p>
<p>    Ivory Coast Grade 2 (Apr/May)	    $40 under London CIF</p>
<p>    Indonesian EK1 (May/June/July)	   $220 under London FOB</p>
<p>-- Jalil Hamid, London newsroom +44 171 542 4985 Tuesday, 15 April 1997 14:57:09</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
