<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520108" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African govt to clamp down on counterfeit goods.</title>
<headline>S.African govt to clamp down on counterfeit goods.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new bill aimed at clamping down on trade in counterfeit goods in South Africa has been tabled in parliament by the Department of Trade and Industry.</p>
<p>The bill's memorandum said that counterfeit goods were mostly sold by street vendors in the informal sector who had no fixed places of business and traded on an irregular basis.</p>
<p>&quot;Conventional court proceedings, and more particularly those concerned with the enforcement of intellectual property rights are, generally speaking, ineffective against this manner of trading,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade in counterfeit goods is...fraud and criminal measures remain the most effective means for combating this form of unlawful activity, which may cause considerable damage...to manufacturers or producers of the genuine goods, and is also to the prejudice of consumers.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition, South Africa was obliged in terms of its World Trade Organisation obligations to implement anti-counterfeiting measures.</p>
<p>The bill aims to make it illegal to sell, hire out, exchange, distribute, import or export counterfeit goods, which are defined as &quot;goods unlawfully bearing or embodying a trade mark or the appearance of other goods, or bearing such a prohibited mark.&quot;</p>
<p>Department of Trade and Industry inspectors and the police will have the right to search premises or vehicles for counterfeit goods and seize goods they &quot;reasonably&quot; suspect to be counterfeit.</p>
<p>Seized goods will be held at a special depot and disposed of after the court case.</p>
<p>Penalties for dealing in counterfeit goods will be a fine of up to 5,000 rand per article and/or imprisonment for three years on the first conviction and a fine of up to 10,000 rand and/or five years in prison for the second offence.</p>
<p>Sentences could be reduced if convicted people provided the government with details how the counterfeit goods were imported or made and distributed.</p>
<p>-- Parliamentary newsroom +27 21 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
