<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520238" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish bourse gains in higher trade,seen up Monday.</title>
<headline>Polish bourse gains in higher trade,seen up Monday.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most Polish shares fell in higher turnover on Friday but gains by a few heavyweights pushed the main index up and analysts said further gains were possible on Monday following continuous trade rises.</p>
<p>The main market's WIG index rose 94.8 points, or 0.6 percent, to 16,376.9, and turnover rose 19 percent to 172 million zlotys ($55.5 million) on all three markets as 51 issues fell, 28 rose and 13 were flat.</p>
<p>Analysts said, however, any strong gains were unlikely as the bourse was in a horizontal trend with investor interest shifting to several attractive primary market offerings.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there might be growth (on Monday), as most stocks traded higher in the continuous trade than at fixing, but I think generally we have consolidation phase,&quot; said Ryszard Sikora, an analyst at Bank Slaski brokerage.</p>
<p>Analysts said companies earnings reports for March, most of them due later on Friday could influence individual stock performance, but said their impact on the market as a whole was very limited.</p>
<p>On Monday Kredyt Bank starts its 83-million zloty ($26.8 million) offering and metals trader Impexmetal SA starts initial public offering estimated at 222 million zlotys ($71.6 million).</p>
<p>Analysts also said Thursday and Friday sessions, which did not follow Dow Jones previous day's performance, signalled that recent Polish speculator's trend to imitate Wall Street's daily movements could end.</p>
<p>In the continuous trade eight stocks rose and eight were flat with the WIG 20 index close at 1,635.7 points, one percent higher than at the regular session.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
