<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520299" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria lev dips on short-covering ahead of poll.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria lev dips on short-covering ahead of poll.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bulgarian lev eased to 1,510-1,515 per dollar before midday from the opening 1,500-1,510 on short-covering ahead of Saturday's general elections, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The lev dipped by around 10 per dollar as dollar demand from banks rose on short covering ahead of the poll after recent dollar sales,&quot; a commercial bank dealer said.</p>
<p>Banks hedged protectively against any risks although no reversal in economic reforms launched by the interim cabinet was expected after the elections, traders said.  </p>
<p>The interim cabinet in office since mid-February until after the elections has won pledges of some $1.2 billion from international lenders providing long-term support for the country's move towards a market economy.</p>
<p>Most banks had pared foreign exchange positions recently to profit on high yield government securities and were now short covering, dealers said.</p>
<p>The lev has traded stable between 1,500-1,600 per dollar for more than a month.  </p>
<p>A cut in the Bulgarian National Bank (BNB) main interest rate, effective on Monday, might also have been a factor for today's lev drop but not a significant one, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Yield of lev-denominated instruments would still be higher as no sharp lev fall is anticipated,&quot; another dealer said.</p>
<p>The BNB said it would cut its main interest rate to 8.03 percent monthly from 14.15 percent in line with falling yield on short term government securuities.</p>
<p>The new rate compared with a projected monthly inflation rate for April below the March's 12.3 percent.</p>
<p>-- Anastas Petrov, Sofia Newsroom (++359-2 91188)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
