<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520237" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Warsaw bourse seen capped by primary mkt next week.</title>
<headline>Warsaw bourse seen capped by primary mkt next week.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Warsaw bourse edged up this week but analysts saw next week's large primary offers drawing capital away from the bourse and capping its upside potential.</p>
<p>Analysts said most stocks, trading now at 15.3 times historical earnings on average, looked fairly valued and were unlikely to spur significant growth or suffer sharp falls.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a lot of money (the primary market offers) and there are no reasons for the bourse to move sharper and a sideways drift is most likely,&quot; said Marcin Billewicz of ING Barings. @</p>
<p>On Monday an initial public offer of metals trader Impexmetal SA worth at least 222 million zlotys opens and Kredyt Bank starts its 83-million zloty offering.</p>
<p>Poland's largest paper firm Celuloza Swiecie, which ends its 112.5 million zloty public subscription on Friday will have its shares allotted at a special bourse session on Tuesday and will start regular bourse trade on Friday.</p>
<p>The main WIG index rose 0.7 percent this week to 16,376.9 points on Friday. @</p>
<p>Analysts said this week's better-than-expected inflation figure showing year-on-year consumer price growth down to 16.6 percent could only have a longer-term impact as no interest rate movements were expected until the second half of the year.</p>
<p>Some analysts said the bourse was likely to experience a wave of growth possibly starting late April, before stabilising or even falling ahead of parliamentary elections in September.</p>
<p>Debt-ridden construction firm Espebepe was this week's top gainer, jumping 37.8 percent on hopes that the firm would convince its creditors to accept a new restructuring plan at a May 16 creditors' meeting. @</p>
<p>The week's biggest main market loser was Exbud, which fell 8.1 percent.</p>
<p>Gauge maker Apator SA will start trade on the parallel market on Thursday and Jutrzenka will have its shares transferred to the main market from the parallel market on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Malgorzata Rzepka +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
