<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520337" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - April 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - April 18.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories reported by Hungary's press, based on information by Nepszabadsag's Hungary Around the Clock service. For further details on how to subscribe to Hungary Around the Clock, please contact Monica Kovacs at (361) 351 7142 or fax your request to (361) 351 7141.</p>
<p>ALL PAPERS</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Gyula Horn confirmed to Singapore Premier Goh Chock Tong yesterday that Budapest intends to become a financial and trade centre in Central Europe, and he encouraged further investment.</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Laszlo Kovacs denied on Thursday that Hungary had officially applied for NATO admission, contrary to reports, stressing that NATO decides for itself which countries to invite among its own members.</p>
<p>- An agreement concluded by the Hungarian and Austrian interior ministers in Vienna on Thursday stipulates that citizens of the two countries can spend 90 days without requiring a visa in the other country. An agreement on expulsion was also signed.</p>
<p>- Socialist MP Gabor Kiss yesterday denied a report that he was a source of information for the secret service Operation Birch Tree which gathered data on some prominent party politicians. Nepszabadsag writes today that no official sources denied its report.</p>
<p>- The economic cabinet has finalised the draft bill on pension reform, said Finance Ministry state secretary Laszlo Akar.</p>
<p>- The presidential board of the Health Insurance Authority Thursday voted to ask the cabinet to dismiss Agnes Cser, director general of the Health Insurance Fund.</p>
<p>- Retail and catering turnover totalled HUF 386 billion in January and February, up 5 percent on the same period last year at current prices. However, the quantity of goods sold went down by 12 percent.</p>
<p>- An agreement on the largest loan ever extended to a Hungarian company was signed yesterday by MOL and Sumitomo Bank of Japan. The $500 million syndicated loan agreement also contains the most favourable conditions that a Hungarian concern has ever been able to obtain without the state guaranteeing repayment.</p>
<p>- The Economic Competition Office yesterday slapped a HUF 1 million fine on the insurance company Hungaria for abusing its leading position in the market of compulsory car insurance.</p>
<p>MAGYAR HIRLAP</p>
<p>- More than 30 conservative and Christian parties will send delegates to the Central European Democratic Forum, a three-day function at Lakitelek this weekend.</p>
<p>- From late next month, regional companies can begin trading over the Internet through the services of the American firm Internet Tradeline, said Peter Lorincze, president of the system's Hungarian access provider.</p>
<p>NEPSZABADSAG</p>
<p>- President Franjo Tudjman of Croatia is to pay a two-day official visit to Budapest on April 21-22.</p>
<p>- The Russian state arms trading agency has offered to upgrade Hungary's MIG-21 fighter jets for $400 million.</p>
<p>NAPI GAZDASAG</p>
<p>- The roadshow for shares in the tile manufacturer Zalakeramia starts today.</p>
<p>- The 1997 AGM of Postabank is expected to discuss personnel matters as the mandates of several board members, including managing director Gabor Princz, will expire this year.</p>
<p>- The leasing firm of Creditanstalt, named CA Leasing Rt., officially opened for business yesterday.</p>
<p>- The AGM of the food retail chain Csemege Julius Meinl decided to pay a 14 percent dividend on last year's results in November.</p>
<p>		    -- Budapest newsroom (361) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
