<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520321" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Demand seen for Russian Eurobonds on right terms.</title>
<headline>Demand seen for Russian Eurobonds on right terms.</headline>
<byline>Julie Tolkacheva</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's federal and regional governments have announced a flood of Eurobonds over the rest of the year, but debt analysts say the issues will find a ready market if the terms are right.</p>
<p>&quot;There is not unlimited demand for Russian debt, but there is a strong demand for debt which is priced correctly and is taken to the market at the right time,&quot; Merrill Lynch first vice-president Dan McGovern told Reuters.</p>
<p>Russia's debut $1 billion five-year Eurobond, priced to yield 345 basis points over U.S. Treasuries, was launched in November to a euphoric reception and heavily oversubscribed. On Thursday it was trading at about 300 points over Treasuries.</p>
<p>Encouraged by the success, major Russian regions are jostling with plans to raise funds on the international markets, where money is cheaper than at home.</p>
<p>The federal government, which followed with a well-received mark Eurobond in March, plans a new dollar issue in the next few months and at least one more Eurobond this year, ministers say.</p>
<p>The City of Moscow, St Petersburg and Nizhny Novgorod region are close to launching Eurobonds. Irkutsk and Sverdlovsk regions and Tatarstan republic plan issues in the near future.</p>
<p>But analysts said market conditions had changed substantially since Russia's debut, with funds getting more expensive and investors more cautious.</p>
<p>In March the U.S. Federal Reserve raised interest rates, pushing the fed funds rate up by 25 basis points to 5.50 percent. The markets expect a further hike in May.</p>
<p>David Boren, vice-president, economic and market analysis, at investment bank Salomon Bros in London, said Russian issuers must be ready to pay a higher price.</p>
<p>&quot;With the interest rate environment less favourable for borrowers than it was six months ago issuers now have to face a a possibility they could pay more for the borrowing now than they would six months ago,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he said there were plenty of investors with significant holdings of emerging market assets eager for exposure to new Russian borrowings to diversify their portfolios.</p>
<p>&quot;If the paper is priced appropriately for market conditions then yes, I think there is a strong appetite for Russian risk,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>One analyst with a London bank said it would be difficult for borrowers to place paper on the right terms at the moment because of the uncertain market.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is not so much that it will be expensive, it's just that it will be very, very complicated and volatile and people will be unwilling to buy right now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But no Russian Eurobond is likely before May. The government named SBC Warburg and JP Morgan to lead its next Eurobond only this week, and has yet to approve a law on regional issues.</p>
<p>It has limited the regions allowed to issue Eurobonds to those territories not funded by the federal budget, of which there are only eight this year.</p>
<p>The draft law on regional Eurobonds limits the volume of total issues from each territory to 30 percent of its budget revenues and its total debt-service bill to 15 percent.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch's McGovern estimated 1997 borrowing by the Russian Federation and the regions at about $5 billion, saying the market was ready to digest this volume.</p>
<p>&quot;It is quite a bit, but if it's managed in a careful way it should work quite well,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Brazil, which analysts often compare with Russia, and which has slightly poorer ratings, has been borrowing $7-$8 billion a year on international markets in recent years, McGovern said.</p>
<p>But Boren said the volume of borrowing was not much of a problem at present.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a question more of too much money chasing too few debt than it is of too much debt,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
