<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520561" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Red River swallows communities in Grand Forks.</title>
<headline>Red River swallows communities in Grand Forks.</headline>
<byline>Greg Frost</byline>
<dateline>GRAND FORKS, N.D. 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Red River poured over the top of clay dikes in Grand Forks on Friday, submerging hundreds of homes as a record-setting flood devastated parts of North Dakota.</p>
<p>At nearby East Grand Forks, Minnesota, officials reported a serious breach in one dike and ordered a wide area of downtown and nearby neighborhoods evacuated.</p>
<p>Seventy-five miles upstream at Fargo, officials announced plans to build a back-up dike to fight water advancing over farm fields, but said that 200 to 300 homes would wind up on the wrong side of the revetment, and could be swamped.</p>
<p>&quot;This is sad ... just devastating,&quot; said Grand Forks Mayor Pat Owens as she gazed at murky water gushing down a street and slowly climbing the exteriors of houses in the Lincoln Drive neighborhood.</p>
<p>About 3,000 people, including more than 100 nursing home residents, had been evacuated from that and other nearby Grand Forks neighborthoods before dawn on Friday to the scream of warning sirens.</p>
<p>Many returned on Friday afternoon to watch helplessly as the water advanced through the community.</p>
<p>&quot;That whole area will fill up like a bathtub. There's nothing to stop it,&quot; said Grand Forks Police Lt. Dennis Eggebraaten. He watched as his home of 23 years was swallowed up.</p>
<p>&quot;I managed to get out all our personal stuff -- clothes, rolltop desk, my computer&quot; he said. &quot;If it fills up to the second floor, the house is pretty much shot.&quot;</p>
<p>Emergency shelters filled up, and all schools and all non-emergency businesses were ordered closed on Friday in this city of more than 70,000.</p>
<p>&quot;There are at least 300 homes that will be partially or almost totally submerged, said Byron Sieber, a spokesman for the Grand Forks Emergency Operations Center.</p>
<p>The floods, unleashed by the thaw of a record winter snowfall, have covered thousands of acres in the valley of the Red River of the North along its flat and gently sloping course toward Canada.</p>
<p>The Red River rose to 52.4 feet (15.97 metres) Friday at Grand Forks, nearly three feet (0.9144 metres) beyond a record set in 1897. the National Weather Service said it expected the river to crest at 53 feet (16.15 metres) on Friday night and stay at or near that level for five to seven days.</p>
<p>Flood stage in Grand Forks is 28 feet (8.534 metres).</p>
<p>Streets in downtown Grand Forks were still dry but the river was nearly at the top levees protecting the commercial district.</p>
<p>In Fargo, the state's largest city, officials said they regretfully decided to build a dike running from West Fargo to the Red River to cut off water pouring overland from the south.</p>
<p>&quot;We fully, fully understand the concern and consternation of those who will be south of the dike,&quot; Mayor Bruce Furness told a news conference.</p>
<p>But he said an aerial inspection had found that 50 square miles of farmland south and west of the city was flooded and the water was advancing on Fargo in a flanking move as it headed toward the Red, which forms the city's eastern boundary.</p>
<p>Furness estimated that the city had from 48 to 72 hours to build the earthen dike along city streets.</p>
<p>&quot;If I could buy two feet off the top of the river I'd spend everything I had,&quot; said Dennis Walaker, operations manager for Fargo's Public Works department.</p>
<p>He said the overland flooding headed toward the city was something Fargo had never faced before.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an hour-by-hour situation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Fargo lost one skirmish with the river on Thursday evening when a dike broke, flooding the Oak Grove neighborhood. A Lutheran high school and about 20 homes were flooded.</p>
<p>&quot;I looked to my right and saw that the dike was just like Jello and moving, then it gave away,&quot; said Scott Anderson who was sandbagging when the river punched through. &quot;I didn't even look around. I just got the hell out of there.&quot;</p>
<p>More evacuations were under way on Friday north of Moorhead, Minnesota, across the river from Fargo. Forecasters said the river was nearing a crest along a 100-mile (165-km) stretch, at a level likely to occur only once every 500 years.</p>
<p>In Fargo the Red River hit 39.8 feet (12.12 metres) -- more than 20 feet (6.1 metres) over flood stage.</p>
<p>In Ottawa, Manitoba Premier Gary Filmon said on Thursday the waters of the Red &quot;are rapidly rising and we're expecting substantial damage and substantial cost to Manitoba.&quot;</p>
<p>Canadian military units were being readied for flood duty from Winnipeg southward.</p>
<p>North Dakota was dealing with another problem from the severe winter -- 70,000 dead cattle littering rangeland, their stiff carcasses only now poking out from melting mounds of snow. State officials said National Guard troops using earth moving equipment would be called in to dispose of the animals.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GRAND FORKS, N.D."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
