<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52059" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS - NYMEX gasoline cracks narrow to 2-year low.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - NYMEX gasoline cracks narrow to 2-year low.</headline>
<byline>Harry Milling</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>As crude rises on U.S.-Iraq tension and heating oil prices continue their steep ascent on low distillate stocks, the NYMEX gasoline-to-crude crack has fallen to its narrowest level in two years.</p>
<p>There is no set nadir to a crack spread, so the spread could narrow much further, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I have seen negative heating oil crack spreads,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>At 1350 EDT/1750 GMT the October gasoline-to-crude crack was $2.62 a barrel, the lowest level since mid-October 1994.  </p>
<p>The crack spread is one barometer of a refiner's profitability, reflecting the margin between the refined product and crude. On way for the gasoline crack to widen is for the market to sell crude and buy gasoline.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody wants to be short crude with this market, but when things (in Iraq) settle the gasoline spread should widen,&quot; said Tom Bentz, an analyst with ING Derivatives.</p>
<p>Gasoline's price gains have lagged the rest of the oil complex since the summer holiday travel season, the time when gasoline demand usually peaks, has ended.  </p>
<p>However, traders said the crack may widen as refineries prepare for the winter by increasing heating oil production and decreasing gasoline output.</p>
<p>&quot;The gasoline supply picture is fine for now, but it could eventually tighten as refiners go to heating oil,&quot; said Victor Yu, vice president of Refco Energy Group. Tightened gasoline stocks would send gasoline prices up.</p>
<p>&quot;The turnaround could save the day,&quot; said Gerald Samuels, managing director of ARB Oil, of the effect the change in refinery output schedules could have on the gasoline crack spread.  </p>
<p>&quot;Usually it has bounced up after falling to around $2.50,&quot; said Samuels.</p>
<p>Dealers said gasoline's price traditionally becomes compelling when the crack spread narrows too much.</p>
<p>A significantly narrowed margin could limit production as profitability decreases, traders said.</p>
<p>However, the NYMEX crack spread represents the margin between West Texas Intermediate and NYMEX reformulated gasoline, and many refiners use other crudes, so the narrowing NYMEX crack may not signal a margin problem for refiners generally, traders said.  </p>
<p>The future price direction of the gasoline crack is impacted by the fact that the NYMEX gasoline contract suffers from decreasing liquidity, a result mainly of the confusion which dogged the contract in the wake of the switch by some states to tougher environmental rules in late 1994 which required a switch to reformulated gasoline (RFG).</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk, 212-859-1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
