<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520556" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israelis wait for decision on corruption scandal.</title>
<headline>Israelis wait for decision on corruption scandal.</headline>
<byline>Danny Gur-arieh</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-04-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israelis must wait until Sunday for a decision by state prosecutors that will decide the fate of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government.</p>
<p>State Attorney Edna Arbel said on Friday she expected to complete her review of a police corruption probe against Netanyahu's government and decide whether the prime minister and other top officials would be indicted.</p>
<p>Police this week recommended charging four Israeli officials including Netanyahu, but Israel Television speculated the prime minister would not be indicted.</p>
<p>&quot;We are finishing our work. We are trying to do our best to try to finish this Sunday hopefully and then everyone will know our decision,&quot; Arbel told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;According to today's likely trend, the decision at the state attorney's office is to issue an indictment against Aryeh Deri alone,&quot; said Channel One television reporter Amnon Abramovich.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton said in Washington that the crisis was an internal Israeli matter and must not be allowed to derail stalled Middle East peace efforts.</p>
<p>&quot;They are a great and vibrant democracy and they'll deal with that in their way,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>&quot;We just can't allow anything, anything to derail the peace process and I don't believe we will.&quot;</p>
<p>An indictment against Netanyahu, the first-ever for an Israeli prime minister, could bring down the government led by his Likud party.</p>
<p>The 47-year-old leader, elected 11 months ago by less than a percentage point, has described the influence-peddling scandal as &quot;nonsense&quot; and rejected calls to resign.</p>
<p>Newspaper opinion polls published on Friday showed a majority of Israelis believe he must step down if charged or convicted.</p>
<p>Prosecutors could ignore the police recommendation, included in a 995-page report, that Netanyahu be charged over the appointment of Likud activist Roni Bar-On as attorney general three months ago.</p>
<p>Channel One television set the police probe running by alleging in a report in January that a Netanyahu ally on trial for corruption, politician Aryeh Deri, pushed Bar-On for the job in the hope of winning a plea bargain.</p>
<p>But even if the prime minister is not indicted, a scathing report on the scandal by the state attorney could crumble his ruling coalition of mainly right-wing and religious parties.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if no one is charged, should it become clear that very serious things were done from a public and democratic standpoint, we'll not be able to go on backing such a government and will want early elections,&quot; Yehuda Harel, of the four-member Third Way in Netanyahu's coalition, told army radio.</p>
<p>Other cabinet ministers, including Natan Sharansky of the seven-member Israel Be'aliya party, have said during the course of the 12-week investigation that if the allegations prove true, they will resign.</p>
<p>&quot;We decided not to take any extraordinary measures...as long as there is no decision by the state attorney's office. Immediately afterwards we will meet and make a decision,&quot; said Sharansky after a meeting of his parliamentary faction.</p>
<p>Netanyahu is under no legal obligation to quit if indicted, but High Court judges have ruled in the past that ministers under indictment must step down. Opposition legislators have already said they would petition the court for a similar ruling.</p>
<p>One opinion poll showed 52.6 percent of respondents believed Netanyahu must quit and call elections if indicted. Another showed a similar majority for him to resign if convicted.</p>
<p>The affair has overshadowed a two-day mission by U.S. Middle East envoy Dennis Ross aimed at reviving Israel-PLO peace talks.</p>
<p>Ross left the region on Friday with Palestinians declaring the month-old crisis in peace moves sparked by Israeli settlement construction in Arab East Jerusalem had not abated.</p>
<p>&quot;We still have a major crisis,&quot; said Palestinian negotiator Saeb Erekat.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-04-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
