<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520630" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton says he may ask Dole for a loan.</title>
<headline>Clinton says he may ask Dole for a loan.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>If Bob Dole has any more spare money left after loaning House Speaker Newt Gingrich $300,000, cash-strapped President Clinton would like to be his next customer.</p>
<p>&quot;Actually, I was thinking of calling Sen. Dole this afternoon -- you know, Chelsea is about to go off to college and it's pretty expensive,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>That was the president's tongue-in-cheek response when asked his reaction to the unusual announcement Thursday that Dole had loaned Gingrich $300,000 to pay an ethics fine.</p>
<p>As of the end of 1996, Clinton had unpaid legal bills of more than $2.25 million from the Whitewater affair and other legal proceedings.</p>
<p>His 17-year-old daughter Chelsea is soon to decide which university she will attend next fall.</p>
<p>On a serious note, Clinton said the way Gingrich paid off the ethics fine was an internal matter for the House of Representatives to consider.</p>
<p>&quot;They have certain rules, certain standards, and they will have to decide whether it complies with those rules and standards,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
