<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520666" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: &quot;Smart&quot; cash cards pose law enforcement challenges.</title>
<headline>&quot;Smart&quot; cash cards pose law enforcement challenges.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Smart cards&quot; that store electronic currency have the potential to revolutionize commerce, but the emerging technology poses challenges for the law enforcement community, government officials said Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The same electronic commerce technology that will save time and money is also capable of being abused,&quot; said Peter Toren, senior attorney in the U.S. Justice Department's computer fraud division.</p>
<p>The so-called stored-value cards resemble credit cards but contain a computer chip that can effectively store cash.</p>
<p>Toren, speaking at a conference at American University's law school here, warned that the cards offer the &quot;threat of the perfect counterfeit&quot; because any criminal that can copy them &quot;can create an unending stream of money.&quot;</p>
<p>At the same time, private industry has attempted to address consumers' privacy concerns by developing technology that allows them to retain anonymity when using the cards.</p>
<p>That too will affect the ability of law enforcement officials in their ability to trace criminal activity, said Lucy Morris, assistant director for credit practices at the Federal Trade Commission.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything that is good about these systems ... is bad about them&quot; for financial law enforcement,&quot; added Stephen Kroll, financial crimes enforcement network legal counsel for the U.S. Treasury Department.</p>
<p>Toren noted that the practice of money laundering has become increasingly difficult for criminals but he said the new technology opens new avenues for abuse. &quot;These systems could undo years of hard work in this area,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He called for striking a balance between anonymity and accountability. &quot;Criminals also benefit from anonymity,&quot; Toren said. &quot;We must be able to hold individuals that harm others accountable.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150108">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
