<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520710" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. sees major gaps remaining on Mideast talks.</title>
<headline>U.S. sees major gaps remaining on Mideast talks.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States said Friday that major gaps remained between Israeli and Palestinian positions as special envoy Dennis Ross returned from a mission aimed at reviving stalled peace talks.</p>
<p>&quot;Significant work remains to be done between the Israelis and Palestinians. There are important gaps and divisions that remain between (their) positions,&quot; State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the United States is determined to keep at this and to keep these talks going so that we might find a formula to resume the political negotiations between Israel and the Palestinian Authority,&quot; Burns told reporters.</p>
<p>Ross was returning to Washington Friday after a three-day trip to the region for talks with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu -- now involved in a domestic corruption scandal -- and Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat.</p>
<p>He was attempting to revive talks that have foundered over a new Israeli housing project in traditionally Arab East Jerusalem. Palestinians have demanded that work stop on the project before they will resume the talks.</p>
<p>Burns described Ross's discussions as &quot;very useful&quot; but made clear that the U.S. envoy had never hoped to get the peace talks re-started immediately. &quot;He had no such illusion,&quot; Burns said.</p>
<p>&quot;He wanted to basically move them forward on the ideas that we have put on the table and on their own ideas,&quot; Burns added. But, he said, &quot;we're still not there.&quot;</p>
<p>Burns said one success of the trip had been that Ross had managed to get Israeli and Palestinian security chiefs together with Arafat Thursday evening to discuss cooperation.</p>
<p>After his return Saturday, Ross is due to meet President Bill Clinton and Secretary of State Madeleine Albright to discuss next steps.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
