<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52071" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: LatAm seen safer for foreign oil investments.</title>
<headline>LatAm seen safer for foreign oil investments.</headline>
<byline>Oliver Ludwig</byline>
<dateline>ORLANDO, Fla. 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Latin America, benefiting from a widening wave of democratization and privatization, is becoming increasingly safe for foreign investments in the oil sector, oil industry sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;It keeps getting better and better,&quot; said Allan Kessler, an executive at JP Morgan in New York attending the Latin Oil '96 conference here put on by AIC Conferences.</p>
<p>But many cautioned that while the region as a whole has grown more democratic and more open to foreign investment, it was still key to assess each opportunity separately.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think of this country to country. The opportunities are more attractive in some than in others,&quot; said James Bowe, an attorney with Dewey Ballantine in Washington, D.C. who specializes in infrastructure investment in Latin America.</p>
<p>Topping the list was Venezuela, the likeliest country in which to find oil, given the country's vast reserves and plans to nearly double crude output capacity to 6.3 million barrels per day over the next decade partly through foreign investment.</p>
<p>&quot;1996 is unfolding as Venezuela's year,&quot; Juan Szabo, head of state-owned Petroleos de Venezuela SA's (PDVSA) exploration and production told the meeting.  </p>
<p>Szabo was referring to positive effects of economic restructuring in Venezuela this year that resulted in a $1.4 billion loan from an approving International Monetary Fund, and more recently, declines in inflation and the national debt.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to remain a player in this oil-rich country for long time,&quot; Tom Nicewarner, head of Venezuela operations for Conoco Inc, the subsidiary of DuPont Co, told the meeting. Conoco won rights in January to explore two big tracts in Venezuela, and also has other operations there as well.</p>
<p>But others said Venezuela may not be for everbody, given what they consider tough financial terms to drill there.  </p>
<p>Columbia, currently the Latin American country where oil production is growing the fastest, emerged as another top choice to look for investment opportunities.</p>
<p>But the attractiveness of Columbia's estimated 15 to 20 billion barrels of proven and estimated reserves was tempered to some extent by concerns surrounding repeated guerrilla attacks on oil infrastructure, as well as recent political problems of Columbian President Ernesto Samper.</p>
<p>&quot;Columbia is no bed of roses, but then again, I have never seen a rose garden in the oil patch,&quot; said Lorrie Olivier, of American International Petroleum Corp.  </p>
<p>Lorrie said American International, which now produces 900 bpd at the Chico Ral field in Columbia, said being a &quot;good citizen&quot; goes a long way to minimize problems in Latin America.</p>
<p>But good behavior appears to be useless in the case of Mexico, with executives from outside of Latin America repeatedly expressing regret that exploring for Mexico's vast petroleum riches remains in the realm of hopes and dreams.</p>
<p>Mexico's liberalization efforts are so far concentrated at the downstream end of the natural gas sector, and Mexican officials and executives at the meeting said the oil sector is likely to remain off limits -- perhaps for a decade or more.  </p>
<p>A conspicous absence at the meeting were executives from Argentina's recently-privatized YPF SA. YPF was originally scheduled to make two presentations.</p>
<p>Many foreign executives expressed concern surrounding contract negotiations between Ecuador's new governmment and Maxus Energy, YPF's U.S.-based exploration and production unit</p>
<p>While the two sides appear to be nearing agreement on a new contract for Maxus, executives worried about the apparently- acrimonious tone of the talks, which have included Maxus being banned from further drilling as well as Ecuador's plans to file an environmental damage suit against Maxus.  </p>
<p>Latin American officials said the contract problems were transitional, and that the acrimony was more a reflection of shrewd negotiating rather than political instability.</p>
<p>&quot;You cannot judge Latin America now by what one (politician) says. What you are hearing now is the voice of the democratic process strengthening,&quot; said Luis Sanchez Masi of the Corporacion Andina de Fomento, an international Latin American group that invests in infrastructure projects.  </p>
<p>Indeed, whatever worries, difficulties or hopes persist regarding the future of the region, few doubted the changes that have swept through the region, particularly during the 1990s, were anything less than profound and permanent.</p>
<p>&quot;The old problems of Latin America are well known. But the situation now is totally different than it was before,&quot; said Guillermo Espiga, an executive with Credit Suisse in New York.</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ORLANDO, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
