<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520856" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Conn. utilities face another summer without nukes.</title>
<headline>Conn. utilities face another summer without nukes.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Lewis</byline>
<dateline>HARTFORD 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Connecticut's electric utilities are keeping their cool over meeting power demand on the season's hottest days, despite the continuing shutdown of the giant Millstone nuclear complex and the permanent loss of the Connecticut Yankee plant.</p>
<p>Northeast Utilities is &quot;cautiously optimistic&quot; because it has has had more time to prepare a summer power strategy than last year, when it was caught short by the shutdowns in its nuclear operations, a spokesman said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We've done just about everything we can to be ready for the situation,&quot; Northeast spokesman Tom Shiel said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've spent the past several months improving the transmission system so that we can import more power.&quot; The utility, which serves 1.7 million customers in three states, has installed new capacitors, and has increased power import capability to 2,500 megawatts (MW), from 2,100 MW last year.</p>
<p>Shiel said the company has done extensive maintenance work on its generating facilities, to increase reliability and maximize output.  </p>
<p>All three units at Northeast's Millstone nuclear power station in Waterford, Conn., with combined capacity of 2,700 MW, have been shut since March 1996 amid safety concerns raised by the federal Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC).</p>
<p>Northeast has said it intends to have Millstone unit 3 ready for restart in September, unit 2 in November, and unit 1 in early 1998, pending NRC approval.</p>
<p>In addition, Northeast and its partners last December decided to permanently close the 582 MW Connecticut Yankee nuclear plant in Haddam Neck, Conn.  </p>
<p>Northeast has said it is spending about $35 million a month on replacement power.</p>
<p>The utility expects Connecticut's peak load this summer to be about 5,085 MW, Shiel said. The utility anticipates resources of around 6,585 MW to cover that.</p>
<p>Northeast will be able to load-shift about 340 MW between Connecticut and Massachusetts to relieve some of the burden, Shiel said. Its Western Massachusetts Electric Co. subsidiary is reactivating West Springfield power plants 1 and 2, with a combined 100 MW, to add to the regional power pool, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The potential for a shortage still exists, but we believe that Connecticut is in pretty good shape,&quot; said Fran Mayko, spokeswoman for New Haven-based United Illuminating Co, which has 310,000 customers and capacity of 1,500 MW.</p>
<p>&quot;We're telling customers that we're prepared,&quot; Mayko said. &quot;They should expect voltage reductions this summer... (but) we don't expect to go to rolling blackouts, unless something major happens, (like) a really prolonged heatwave, and a major transmission line fails.&quot;  </p>
<p>She added that Connecticut faces a different scenario this summer than it did last year. &quot;Connecticut's still going to experience a shortage this summer because those nuclear power plants are offline. But now it's become a New England regionwide problem, because Maine Yankee is offline.&quot;</p>
<p>The 910 MW Maine Yankee nuclear plant in Wiscasset, Maine, has been shut since December to correct an electrical cable problem.  </p>
<p>Maine Yankee is 38 percent owned by Central Maine Power Co, 20 percent each by New England Electric System and Northeast Utilities, seven percent by Bangor Hydro-Electric Co, five percent by Maine Public Service Co, and 10 percent by other New England utilities.</p>
<p>William Sheperdson, spokesman for the 98-member New England Power Pool in Holyoke, Mass., said the possibility of summer blackouts in the region is &quot;very remote.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the member utilities are trying to bring back 450 MW of generation by reactivating retired units and upgrading existing plants to produce more.  </p>
<p>Sheperdson said the pool would spend about $15 million to restart some of the old plants.</p>
<p>Pool members will again ask for voluntary curbs on power usage and offer industrial customers discounts for interruptible power contracts.</p>
<p>In addition, &quot;We are working more carefully with neighboring power systems, in New York, Quebec and New Brunswick, to set things up if problems do occur, so we can maximize our assistance,&quot; Sheperdson said.</p>
<p>--Hartford newsroom (860) 727-0224</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1610107">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARTFORD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
