<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520807" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tobacco industry booklet admitted in Florida trial.</title>
<headline>Tobacco industry booklet admitted in Florida trial.</headline>
<byline>June Bell</byline>
<dateline>JACKSONVILLE, Fla 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A 1974 tobacco industry publication that concluded there was no definitive proof that cigarette smoking caused cancer was entered into evidence on Friday at the trial of a wrongful death lawsuit against R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co.</p>
<p>Circuit Judge Bernard Nachman allowed a booklet called &quot;The Cigarette Controversy,&quot; written by the Tobacco Institute, an industry trade group, to be put into evidence over the objections of Reynolds' lawyers, who said it was irrelevant.  </p>
<p>But Nachman said it could only be used by the jury to consider punitive damages.</p>
<p>Plaintiff Dana Raulerson sued the tobacco company on behalf of the estate and children of her sister, Jean Connor, who smoked heavily and died of lung cancer in 1995 at age 49.</p>
<p>The booklet asked the question &quot;Does it (smoking) cause illness -- even death? No one knows.&quot; It concluded that there was no definitive scientific research proving smoking caused cancer.  </p>
<p>The booklet appeared to contradict a Reynolds internal company document already entered as evidence in the trial. The 1962 paper, written by Alan Rodgman, a senior researcher at the tobacco company, said &quot;the amount of evidence accumulated to indict cigarette smoking as a health hazard is overwhelming.&quot;</p>
<p>A key facet of Raulerson's lawsuit against Reynolds is the claim that company executives knew decades ago that cigarette smoking was a health hazard and that they were selling a dangerous product, but deceived the public and continued to sell the product without fixing it.</p>
<p>On Thursday, plaintiff's witness Dr. Victor Roggli, a Duke University forensic pathologist, testified that he was virtually certain Jean Connor died of lung cancer caused by smoking.</p>
<p>Roggli, on the stand again Friday, said the booklet's claim that no one knew whether smoking was a health hazard was untrue.</p>
<p>Lawyers said Raulerson could take the witness stand later Friday. The plaintiffs were expected to wrap up their case by the middle of next week.</p>
<p>R.J. Reynolds is a unit of RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JACKSONVILLE, Fla"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
