<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520810" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. strategists urge looser Iran, Iraq embargo.</title>
<headline>U.S. strategists urge looser Iran, Iraq embargo.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Washington should ease economic sanctions against Iran and Iraq if it wants to spur changes in the two countries, two former U.S. national security advisors said on Friday.</p>
<p>At a time when European nations are considering a tougher line against Iran, and Washington is probing whether Iran was behind the 1996 killing of U.S. troops in Saudi Arabia, Zbigniew Brzezinski and Brent Scowcroft said the Clinton administration should relax its policy of &quot;dual containment.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;In trying to isolate both of the Gulf's regional powers, the policy lacks strategic viability and carries a high financial and diplomatic cost,&quot; they said in an article to be published in the journal Foreign Affairs.</p>
<p>Washington should adjust its policy, in consultation with regional leaders, to give Iran and Iraq incentives to change instead of just punishing them, the advisers to Presidents Jimmy Carter, Gerald Ford and George Bush said. But they told a news briefing the United States must also be ready to take military action when necessary.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is incontrovertible evidence to the effect that Iran has engaged, as a matter of state policy, in terrorist activities against the United States, it should precipitate effective and painful retaliatory action,&quot; Brzezinski said.</p>
<p>Scowcroft said Germany's recent verdict that Iran had ordered the 1992 murder of four Kurdish dissidents in Berlin created the ideal opportunity for the United States and its European allies to devise sturdy joint policies toward Iran.</p>
<p>Sweeping U.S. trade and investment sanctions against Iran should be eased, perhaps to allow some oil and gas investments or trade deals, he said.</p>
<p>By discouraging pipeline routes through Iran, the article said, the administration was hurting long-term U.S. interests in securing energy from Central Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States should do nothing to preclude Central Asia's eventual emergence, nor stand in the way of deals that might facilitate it.&quot;</p>
<p>On Iraq, it said if ongoing Iraqi oil sales for food and medicine work the United States should consider allowing even more sales for humanitarian needs. If not, the fraying international coalition against President Saddam Hussein would collapse out of concern for innocent Iraqi people who have been deprived under global economic sanctions over six and a half years.</p>
<p>&quot;America may have to consider modifying certain aspects of Iraq's economic containment to keep its military straitjacket securely fastened,&quot; the article said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
