<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520969" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital markets closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital markets closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bond futures settled lower on Friday as ongoing speculation about the prospect of an early election or cabinet reshuffle buffeted bonds throughout the session, traders said.</p>
<p>The June contract slumped at the open but found support at 128.52/54 when domestic investors stepped in and traders said the fact the future settled above 128.60 was favourable from a technical point of view.</p>
<p>The main question taxing traders was how much political risk has now been discounted. Many said there was still potential for further declines if a snap election were called.  </p>
<p>Interest rate futures once again bore the brunt of the selling. The June contract survived an early attack but crumpled just before the close as a US fund placed a large sell order boosting daily volume to its highest level for the most liquid contract since August last year.</p>
<p>Traders said caution would prevail ahead of a possible announcement by President Jacques Chirac. Chirac's office has allowed speculation rumble for several days that an early election will be called, and most French newspapers have said in unsourced reports Chirac would make up his mind this weekend.  </p>
<p>&quot;From a market point of view it's been mostly priced in,&quot; Valerie Plagnol, economist at Credit Commercial de France said. However, she said if an election were called bonds could &quot;decline slightly as they price in the chance of the (ruling coalitions) majority being reduced.&quot;</p>
<p>A trader at a US house said &quot;for the most part people are taking about politics. It's kind of hard to say how much is priced in. An election seems risky. I wouldn't be surprised if there were more downside potential.&quot;</p>
<p>Eric Chaney at Morgan Stanley said an election could produce further limited selling, with the franc being worst hit.  </p>
<p>The franc fell against the mark for the second day in succession, reversing nearly all the gains it has made since surging higher on March 27.</p>
<p>One trader said the franc would be hit by political uncertainty in the run up to an early election but it was unlikely there would be any blowout as the Bank of France had become adept at managing franc movements.</p>
<p>It was trading at 3.3698 against the mark compared with a session high of 3.3657 and a high for the week of 3.3615, its strongest level since June 1993.  </p>
<p>The jitters in the French market, weighing notably on the short end of the curve, scuppered the Treasury's chances of selling extra BTANs, offered at the average price of Thursday's auction. It said no non-competitive bids were submitted.</p>
<p>Traders said the cash market was relatively quiet on Friday with the 10-year area continuing to underperform Bunds and the curve flattening further as the short end slumped.</p>
<p>-- David Clarke, Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5542</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
