<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520904" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian minister says terror alert is alarmist.</title>
<headline>Italian minister says terror alert is alarmist.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Interior Minister Giorgio Napolitano said on Friday that media reports of planned attacks in Italy by Islamic extremists were alarmist.</p>
<p>He also said he &quot;had no information on special security measures at airports&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The threat of terrorism has been present for a while, as in other European countries, and security is always high,&quot; Napolitano told journalists after a government meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who spread alarmism harm security,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The minister was reacting to a military intelligence report, leaked to the national news agency ANSA on Thursday, that said Islamic extremists may be preparing to attack targets in Italy, including Pope John Paul and international airports.</p>
<p>Italy went on alert following the reports, which filled newspapers and news bulletins on Friday.</p>
<p>Security sources said measures were increased at airports in Milan and Rome, with police at the capital's Fiumicino airport using explosives experts and sniffer dogs to check aircraft of European, U.S. and Middle Eastern carriers.</p>
<p>An unexploded World War Two grenade was detected by security forces in Florence but police chief Francesco Forleo said it would be &quot;illogical&quot; to link this to the extremist reports.</p>
<p>He said the aged grenade may have been planted as an &quot;act of intimidation&quot; by someone trying to cause a scare.</p>
<p>Napolitano could not confirm the leaked military report, which referred to the crisis in Europe's relations with Iran as the possible spark for attacks by Islamic militants.</p>
<p>&quot;The links between intelligence services are covered in secrecy. You have got something from an indiscretion. I can neither confirm, deny nor comment on that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Vatican Secretary of State Cardinal Angelo Sodano told Italian television on Friday that the Pope, who was seriously injured by a Turkish gunman in 1981, was not &quot;particularly alarmed&quot; by the purported threats.</p>
<p>The 76-year-old Pontiff's spokesman, Joaquin Navarro-Valls, declined to say whether any special precautions had been taken.</p>
<p>&quot;For obvious reasons, we do not comment on reports that concern matters of security,&quot; Navarro-Valls said in a statement.</p>
<p>The Pope's visit last weekend to the predominantly Moslem Bosnian capital Sarajevo was preceded by the discovery of land mines planted along the route of his motorcade.</p>
<p>The Roman Catholic leader continued with his Sarajevo visit despite the discovery of the 23 land mines, planted under a road bridge into Sarajevo from the airport. The mines, attached to a detonator, were defused a few hours before he arrived.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
