<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520906" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy says it still on course to meet EMU targets.</title>
<headline>Italy says it still on course to meet EMU targets.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Hurst</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy insisted on Friday it was on course to meet key targets required for membership of a currency union after European Union (EU) forecasters warned that it could fall wide of the mark.</p>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Walter Veltroni was quoted as saying a mini-budget would do enough to ensure Italy met a public deficit goal of three percent of gross domestic product -- a vital target for joining European economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>&quot;Our commitment from the moment we began working has been to achieve the three percent of deficit to GDP and thus enter Europe. We think the mini-budget is sufficient to meet that objective,&quot; Veltroni told the Italian news agency ANSA.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi's centre-left administration has drawn up a 15.5 trillion lire ($9 billion) supplementary budget in a sustained effort to thrust Italy into the first wave of EMU members in January 1999.</p>
<p>Prodi suffered a setback on Friday when the budget commission of the lower house of Italy's parliament voted against the mini-budget, making it almost inevitable that the government would put the package to a confidence vote.</p>
<p>Veltroni made his remarks after EU sources in Brussels said officials at the European Commission were now forecasting that Italy's deficit would hit 3.2 percent this year, overshooting the target spelt out in the 1991 Maastricht Treaty .</p>
<p>The source said the figure, worked out by officials &quot;at a technical level&quot;, could be altered before the Commission releases its spring forecasts next Wednesday.</p>
<p>Commission forecasters are widely believed to come under pressure from EU member countries when preparing the sensitive forecasts to present them in a flattering light.</p>
<p>Italy is not the only country in trouble over meeting the three percent target. Most independent economists see Germany falling short of the goal as its struggles to overcome sluggish growth.</p>
<p>German EU Commissioner Monika Wulf Mathies said in Frankfurt that even with a budget deficit of 3.2 percent, the Maastricht Treaty did not foresee postponing EMU's scheduled launch date of January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;The number 3.0 percent is not written in the Maastricht Treaty. Currency union is not some numbers lottery but rather a conscious political decision,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Germany has been demanding strict compliance with the targets to protect the credibility of the new euro currency.</p>
<p>The Italian government's latest declaration of intent came at the end of a week of frenzied speculation that France and Germany are cooking up a deal to freeze Italy and Spain out of the EMU's launch.</p>
<p>The EU will decide who makes the grade for monetary union in early 1998. Countries which want to join have to meet key criteria on debt, inflation and budget deficit levels in 1997.</p>
<p>Influential Italian business newspaper Il Sole 24 Ore has reported that Bonn and Paris are working on a plan to keep Italy out of EMU's debut but France, Germany and Italy all denied on Wednesday that any secret deals were afoot to block Italy.</p>
<p>France also issued a strong denial on Friday of reports that President Jacques Chirac had recently told German Chacellor Helmut Kohl he had withdraw support for Italy's drive to join EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sure there is a lot of contingency planning going on among diplomats and maybe this is what is surfacing in the media,&quot; said Daren Williams, an economist at UBS in London.</p>
<p>But a top Italian civil servant said it was dangerous to suggest all would be lost if Italy joined EMU late. The key thing was for the country to be fully prepared whether it made it on time or not, said Tommaso Padoa Schioppa.</p>
<p>Padoa Schioppa, a former number three at the central bank who has taken over as head of stock exchange regulator Consob, said it would be &quot;catastrophic&quot; if Italy did not reach the three percent target without first having taken steps to stabilise the budget permanently.</p>
<p>&quot;But the picture would be different if, having consolidated the process of adjustment for 1998 and following years, we found ourselves at the end of 1997 a few fractions of a point above the three percent,&quot; said Padoa Schippa.</p>
<p>This would enable Italy either to join EMU straightaway or to have a date set for entry later on, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;What Padoa Schioppa says is the really important thing. I don't think it really matters, except for the careers of a few politicians, if Italy joins in 1999 or in 2001,&quot; said Williams.</p>
<p>($ = 1698 Italian Lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
