<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="521195" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: COMEX copper called to open slightly higher.</title>
<headline>COMEX copper called to open slightly higher.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX copper futures were called to open slightly higher Friday in line with LME copper prices after a further 1,350 drawdown in LME warehouse copper stocks to 152,475 tonnes.</p>
<p>COMEX copper stocks rose 780 short tons to 46,388 short tons Thursday.</p>
<p>COMEX May copper was called unchanged to up 0.3 cent from Thursday's settlement of 105.55 cents a lb after trading at 106.25 in overnight ACCESS trade.</p>
<p>Support is seen around 104.00 cents still, with resistance around 108.00 in the near term for May delivery.</p>
<p>But daily momentum oscillators remain weak for COMEX May copper, and the contract's five day moving average remains below its 21-day average and its 55-day average, after the contract retreated from eight-month highs seen in March.</p>
<p>The COMEX May/July spread eased back further Thursday to around 1.00 cents, after easing from around 3.5 cents in March, as tightness in the prompt market has eased.</p>
<p>Copper consumption is forecast to grow in all major economies this year, with growth forecasts revised up to 4.4 percent in 1997 and 4.6 percent in 1998, according to a report Friday from the Economist Intelligence Unit (EIU).</p>
<p>But prices are still seen easing as the supply of refined copper is also seen rising faster than first estimated, leading to a build in stocks.</p>
<p>Global stocks rose by an estimated 25,000 tonnes in 1996, with western stocks falling by about 150,000 tonnes but stocks elsewhere rising by 175,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>The EIU forecast a 1997/98 stock build of 375,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>((Clive McKeef, New York Commodities Desk, +1-212-859-1641))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
