<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52120" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dow plows to intraday record after CPI pleases.</title>
<headline>Dow plows to intraday record after CPI pleases.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>New evidence that consumer prices remain in check sparked a broad rally in stocks that pushed the Dow industrials to record territory at midday.</p>
<p>The U.S. Labor Department reported consumer prices rose a mere 0.1 percent in August, helping the inflation-sensitive bond market to sharp gains which carried over into stocks.</p>
<p>The Dow Industrials soared 71 points, or 1.23 percent, to 5843, smashing the record 5796.1 intraday high set on May 23. The Nasdaq Composite jumped 19 points, or 1.66 percent, to 1185, as technology stocks awakened from their recent slumber.  </p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year U.S. Treasury gained 1-14/32 sending its yield below the psychologically key seven percent level to 6.96 percent.</p>
<p>With the Dow finally able to establish a new high and technology stocks fully participating in the rally, analysts saw signs a new rally could be underway.</p>
<p>&quot;Mood, momentum and money flow are back in gear,&quot; said Alan Ackerman, market strategist at Fahnestock and Co. &quot;This is the magic moment that people have talked so often about, the Dow has broken through 5800 and now some have lifted their sights to 6000.&quot;  </p>
<p>Tech stocks staged a particularly strong rally, sparked by votes of confidence from several investment firms.</p>
<p>SoundView Financial Group raised its recommended short-term weighting on the sector, saying it expected the group to outperform the broader market.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that over the next four to five months technology stocks as measured by the SoundView Index should outperform the broader averages on both a relative and absolute basis,&quot; SoundView's president and market strategist James Townsend said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Industry bellwether International Business Machines Corp jumped 4-3/4 to 122 after Merrill Lynch upgraded it to short-term strong buy with a 12-month target price of 150.</p>
<p>Other technology standouts included Intel Corp, up 2-1/2 to 87-7/8, and Microsoft Corp, up 1-9/16 to 130-3/16. Oracle Corp surged 3-1/4 to 40-3/4 after Alex. Brown upgraded the shares to buy from neutral and Cowen &amp; Co reiterated its strong buy rating on the shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Nasdaq had been lagging and for the moment it seems there's no reason to hold back,&quot; said Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter Ltd.  </p>
<p>Many analysts have viewed the reluctance of investors to re-enter the technology and small-cap arenas as a critical obstacle to the continuation of a bull market rally that has lasted more than five years.</p>
<p>With market sentiment apparently improving, analysts are looking to indices like the technology-laden Nasdaq Composite for signs that there is steam left in the rally.</p>
<p>&quot;When Nasdaq tests its old highs then we'll see where we really are,&quot; Bleier said.</p>
<p>Market breadth also showed marked improvement, with gainers outnumbering losers by three-to-two on the NYSE.  </p>
<p>On Nasdaq, advancing issues ran ahead of decliners by a three-to-two margin.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
