<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="521393" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Copper firmer on LME, Escondida workers strike.</title>
<headline>Copper firmer on LME, Escondida workers strike.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Copper prices perked up above stubborn resistance levels during Friday LME ring and kerb dealings, helping to inject some life and activity into what had been a stagnant complex, traders said.</p>
<p>As kerb trading wound down news emerged that 120 workers at Chile's Escondida mine - the world's largest - were on strike, resulting in prices being marked up afterwards.</p>
<p>Last actual kerb business was $28 a tonne higher at $2,288, but three months was indicated at $2,298/2,300 in the inter-office market.</p>
<p>Although the strike is not expected to disrupt output, some analysts cited caution.</p>
<p>&quot;You never can tell what will happen, and what the striking workers do,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Generally, business remained low-key, with most of the other metals showing some reluctance to move significantly higher, with the charts still sending inconclusive signals.</p>
<p>&quot;Copper's picked up a bit, so that might get things going, but I have to say it has not been that great,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Another 1,350-tonne stock fall in copper, taking the total for the week to 7,200 tonnes, helped prices work upwards, with prices skipping higher once $2,280 was cleared.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the cash/threes backwardation widened also, aiding the trend, with the premium moving out to $43 traded from around $30/35 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, aluminium moved modestly higher, with stocks falling again today, taking the weekly drawdown to 12,375 tonnes. Prices manged to reach $1,557, up $7 from Thursday. Scattered trade in alloy was at steadier levels, and the market ended the kerb at $1,450, up $5.</p>
<p>The nickel market moved higher on some technical covering, finishing the kerb at $7,350, up $80. Tin's movements were similar, and last business was at $5,720, up $35.</p>
<p>The lead and zinc markets were both slow, with prices inching higher. Last lead business was at $636, up $2, while zinc gained $4 at $1,247.</p>
<p>--Martin Hayes, London newsroom, 44 171 542 8080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
