<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="521359" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: THE PROTEUS COLUMN - THE TALK OF ATLANTA.</title>
<headline>THE PROTEUS COLUMN - THE TALK OF ATLANTA.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE PROTEUS COLUMN</p>
<p>In the corner of the exhibition hall at the Georgia World Congress Center in Atlanta this week, companies marked down on a big board their spot for next year's Risk and Insurance Management Society (RIMS) conference in San Diego.</p>
<p>Sedgwick, Willis Corroon and Aon were all down for separate booths.</p>
<p>But whether they'll stay separate by this time next year was one of the big questions on everyone's mind.</p>
<p>The question was almost unavoidable on the floor of the exhibition hall, where the Sedgwick and Willis booths were just a few short rows away.</p>
<p>With Aon buying Alexander &amp; Alexander, Bain Hogg and Minet in the space of just a few months and with Marsh &amp; McLennan buying Johnson &amp; Higgins this year, few believe that Sedgwick and Willis can go it alone for too much longer.</p>
<p>The talk at the cocktail parties and among risk managers circulating past the exhibit booths was whether Sedgwick and Willis would bite the bullet and combine, or whether the seemingly voracious Aon would strike again and buy yet another broker.</p>
<p>Speculation was further fuelled by recent media reports predicting a Sedgwick merger with Willis, while in Europe, Germany's biggest broker Jauch und Huebener has thrown its hat in the ring.</p>
<p>Industry sources said Jauch und Huebener was in talks with Sedgwick, Willis and Marsh McLennan. The German broker confirmed that it's in discussions about its future, but declined to name with whom.</p>
<p>In the wake of recent consolidation, most industry players would probably be surprised if Willis, Sedgwick and Marsh are not in the frame.</p>
<p>A number of risk managers, half expecting an announcement at any moment, stopped by the Reuters booth over the course of the conference in search of the latest news.</p>
<p>Their interest, of course, went beyond just idle curiosity. The broker consolidation leaves them with fewer choices with whom to do business.</p>
<p>And with fewer brokers, some risk managers worried they may not get the same kind of personal attention they can command at present.</p>
<p>Insurers also were anxious about the shake-out, with the potential loss of brokers translating into a loss of business for some of them as the surviving brokers favour some firms over others.</p>
<p>				--OO0OO--</p>
<p>THE PROTEUS COLUMN is an insight piece produced by Reuters journalists based on their own research and interpretations. While it aims to be as accurate and incisive as possible, it does not necessarily reflect the views of Reuters Ltd.</p>
<p>	   **************************************</p>
<p>THE PROTEUS COLUMN appears in the GLOBAL INSURANCE NEWS SUMMARY</p>
<p>every weekday on Reuters Insurance Briefing.</p>
<p>For enquiries, contact -</p>
<p>Gordon Mackenzie, Editor, London</p>
<p>Tel: 44 171 542 2770</p>
<p>Fax 44 171 542 2583</p>
<p>e-mail gordon.mackenzie@reuters.com</p>
<p>John Sanders, News Editor, London</p>
<p>Tel: 44 171 542 2769</p>
<p>e-mail john.sanders@reuters.com</p>
<p>		****************************************</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
