<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="521303" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Judge says Hilton, ITT ruling to come in few days.</title>
<headline>Judge says Hilton, ITT ruling to come in few days.</headline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A federal judge on Thursday said he expects to issue a ruling within a few days on Hilton Hotel Corp's motion to compel an ITT Corp shareholder meeting in mid-May.</p>
<p>Hilton is currently attempting a hostile takeover of ITT and has asked for a shareholder vote on its $6.5 billion bid at ITT's annual meeting, which is traditionally held in mid-May but has yet to be scheduled.</p>
<p>&quot;I'll issue the ruling as soon as I can,&quot; U.S. District Judge Philip Pro told a packed courtroom. He said his decision would most likely be issued sometime next week.  </p>
<p>Hilton has asked the judge to force ITT into holding the meeting in mid-May by arguing ITT's bylaws and Nevada state law require an annual meeting within one year from the previous year's date. But ITT claims its bylaws and state law do not require a mid-May meeting. Indeed, it claims it has 18 months from the previous year's date to hold the conference, which means ITT could hold it as late as November.</p>
<p>To defend against Hilton's bid, ITT has refocused its business plan on core assets in gambling and hotels and has begun selling off some assets. By doing so, ITT said it aims to enhance shareholder value.  </p>
<p>In his oral arguments today, however, Hilton attorney Bernard Nussbaum challenged that assertion. &quot;This fight, it's not about shareholder value, it's about holding onto your job,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He argued ITT's management, led by chairman Rand Araskog, is trying to avoid a shareholder vote on Hilton's $55 per share bid by postponing the meeting.</p>
<p>ITT's attorney Rory Millson countered Nussbaum by saying, &quot;There is no proof the primary purpose of the ITT board is to interfere with a vote. There's no showing of inequity in the (shareholder voting) process, and nothing to say we have skewed that process in any way.</p>
<p>Following the hearing, Nussbaum told Reuters &quot;we believe we are in the right, and we believe the judge knows we are in the right.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman for ITT said it would be premature to comment before the judge issues his ruling.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
