<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="521348" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Explosions, bomb warnings trouble Major's campaign.</title>
<headline>Explosions, bomb warnings trouble Major's campaign.</headline>
<byline>Dan Chung</byline>
<dateline>LEEDS, England 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two blasts and a series of suspected IRA bomb warnings paralysed rail and road traffic in northern England on Friday in what appeared to be the latest attempt by the guerrillas to disrupt Britain's election campaign.</p>
<p>There were small explosions at railway stations in Doncaster and Leeds in northern England. Police said they carried out a controlled explosion on a package they suspected could be a bomb at Stoke station in the northwest.</p>
<p>In Leeds, a large part of the city centre was sealed off after the explosion, for which there was no warning. &quot;It was a loud but relatively small explosion along the trackside in an equipment cabinet,&quot; said a spokesman for the fire brigade.</p>
<p>&quot;As our train went past there was a big bang and everyone started screaming and holding their heads,&quot; a woman passenger told the BBC. There were no reports of any injuries.</p>
<p>Stoke, Doncaster and Crewe railway station were all closed after police were told of telephoned bomb warnings in which the caller gave a codeword known to be used by the outlawed Irish Republican Army (IRA).</p>
<p>A large section of the main M6 motorway, linking southern Britain with the northwest, was also closed after a phone call threatening a bomb explosion.</p>
<p>The M6 closure was near a sports stadium that Prime Minister John Major was due to visit on Friday. &quot;This is not a coincidence, is it?&quot; one aide said.</p>
<p>Major went ahead with his plans to campaign in the north ahead of the May 1 election. A bomb disposal squad was on hand throughout Major's visit.</p>
<p>It was the second time Major's campaign tour has been disrupted by IRA threats. The last was on April 5 when a bomb warning forced the cancellation of the Grand National Horse Race while the prime minister was in the region.</p>
<p>The alerts caused severe disruption in the region, blocking traffic and trains between the north and south and forcing the evacuation of homes and businesses around the threatened areas.</p>
<p>Major pinned the incidents on the IRA, which is battling to end Britain's rule of Northern Ireland and had admitted causing traffic disruption earlier in the campaign for a May 1 election.</p>
<p>&quot;This looks very much at the moment as though this is the work of the IRA showing their usual contempt for people's lives and for property,&quot; Major told his daily news conference.</p>
<p>The IRA also set off a huge explosion in London's financial district in 1992 on the day that Major was re-elected.</p>
<p>Last month, two bombs exploded near Wilmslow railway station in northwest England, but no one was injured, and Semtex bombs were found planted on the M6 earlier this month.</p>
<p>Bomb threats at London railway stations have brought chaos to the capital several times in the past few weeks. The IRA has claimed responsibility for most of the explosions and threats.</p>
<p>The attacks were a typical IRA tactic, causing huge disruption but no loss of life which could threaten any sympathy for their cause.</p>
<p>They followed the arrest last weekend of seven men suspected of involvement of the killing of a British soldier in February</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LEEDS, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
