<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="521357" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Explosions, bomb warnings wreak UK transport chaos.</title>
<headline>Explosions, bomb warnings wreak UK transport chaos.</headline>
<byline>Dan Chung</byline>
<dateline>LEEDS, England 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two blasts and a series of suspected IRA bomb warnings paralysed rail and road traffic in northern England on Friday in what appeared to be the latest attempt by the guerrillas to disrupt a pre-election campaign.</p>
<p>There were small explosions at railway stations in Doncaster and Leeds. Police also said they carried out a controlled explosion on a package they suspected could be a bomb at Stoke station in the northwest.</p>
<p>In Leeds, a large part of the city centre was sealed off after the explosion, for which there was no warning. &quot;It was a loud but relatively small explosion along the trackside in an equipment cabinet,&quot; said a spokesman for the fire brigade.</p>
<p>&quot;As our train went past there was a big bang and everyone started screaming,&quot; a woman passenger told the BBC. There were no reports of any injuries.</p>
<p>Stoke, Doncaster and Crewe railway station were all closed early on Friday after police were told of telephoned bomb warnings in which the caller gave a codeword known to be used by the outlawed Irish Republican Army (IRA).</p>
<p>A large section of the main M6 motorway, linking southern Britain with the northwest, was also closed after a phone call.</p>
<p>The alert caused severe disruption in the region, blocking traffic and trains between the north and south and forcing the evacuation of homes and businesses around the threatened areas.</p>
<p>British Prime Minister John Major pinned the incidents on the IRA, which is battling to end Britain's rule of Northern Ireland and had admitted causing rail and road disruption earlier in Britain's campaign for a May 1 election.</p>
<p>&quot;This looks very much at the moment as though this is the work of the IRA showing their usual contempt for people's lives and for property,&quot; Major told his daily news conference.</p>
<p>The attacks were a typical IRA tactic, causing huge disruption but no loss of life which could threaten any sympathy for their cause.</p>
<p>At Doncaster, there was an explosion at a bridge close to the railway station but no-one was hurt and there was very little damage. The area had already been evacuated.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course it's causing a great deal of disruption,&quot; a police spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Major was due to visit northwest England on Friday as part of his election campaign tour, which was disrupted earlier on April 5 by an IRA threat which forced the cancellation of the Grand National Horse Race.</p>
<p>Last month, two bombs exploded near Wilmslow railway station in northwest England, but no one was injured, and Semtex bombs were found planted on the M6 earlier this month.</p>
<p>Bomb threats at London railway stations have brought chaos to the capital several times in the past few weeks. The IRA claimed responsibility for most of the attacks and threats.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LEEDS, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
