<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="521452" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK March M4 lending cut by reverse repo activity.</title>
<headline>UK March M4 lending cut by reverse repo activity.</headline>
<byline>Cheryl Juckes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>UK March M4 bank and building society lending -- published on Friday -- is actually much stronger than suggested by the headline figure of a seasonally adjusted 4.5 billion stg rise, analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;There were distortions caused by reverse repos, which dropped by 2.5 billion stg,&quot; said HSBC economist Jonathan Loynes.</p>
<p>&quot;If you strip out that then the underlying rise is actually quite strong at 7.0 billion (stg),&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Analysts had been predicting a rise in M4 of around 6.1 billion stg and at first glance the headline rise looked to have undercut this, hinting that M4 lending was finally slowing after its recent surge.</p>
<p>But the underlying picture is actually still likely to worry the Bank of England which has been calling for a pre-emptive rise in official 6.0 percent UK rates to check inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;The M4 figures plus the labour data are the source of upside risk to inflation. There is concern in so far as they haven't shown any signs of slowing,&quot; UBS economist Alex Garrard said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Bank is unlikely to change its advice to an incoming chancellor -- it will continue to press fairly strongly for a rate rise,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Garrard expects the Bank to advise whoever is finance minister after the May 1 election to raise interest rates by 1/4 point, although a rise of 1/2 point is also possible.</p>
<p>Overall adjusted M4 rose 1.0 percent on the month in March and 11.2 percent on the year, above market forecasts of 0.8 and 11.0 percent growth.  </p>
<p>M4 has by no means a perfect record as a predictor of inflation -- witnessed by its demotion from a targeted measure to measure that is merely &quot;monitored&quot; -- but some analysts say it has now been flashing warning signals too consistently to be ignored.</p>
<p>&quot;The measure hints at strong consumer spending over the coming year. By way of an insurance policy, a chancellor would be better off raising rates now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The monitoring range is three to nine percent but, allowing for distortions caused by gilt repo activity, M4 has actually remained stubbornly above 10 percent for a year.  </p>
<p>Royal Bank of Scotland economist Marian Bell said that the monitoring range was in too wide and that the authorities would do well to heed its warning.</p>
<p>&quot;M4 was a fairly reasonable predictor in the last cycle,&quot; Bell said. &quot;Even if there are upward distortions, it's quite hard to argue the current figure down to five or six percent,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She says the monetary aggregate shows the UK authorities have little hope of achieving their target of 2.5 percent or lower on core retail price inflation.  </p>
<p>NatWest Markets UK economist John O'Sullivan said the M4 figures were just reinforcing the picture of strong growth in demand demonstrated in other data.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just another part of the jigsaw. It tells you demand is growing and that you may need to nip that in the bud by raising interest rates,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He expects UK rates to rise by 25 basis points straight after the election and then to rise another 25 basis points fairly rapidly. But he sees 6.5 percent as the peak.</p>
<p>&quot;That should probably be enough to constrain demand,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--London newsroom +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
