<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="521631" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EU forecasters see Italy missing EMU deficit target.</title>
<headline>EU forecasters see Italy missing EMU deficit target.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Gaunt</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Commission officials are forecasting that Italy will miss the key deficit criterion for the single currency this year but analysts and EU insiders expect figures next week to show Germany on target.</p>
<p>A European Union source familiar with the Commission's spring economic forecasts told Reuters on Friday that the latest version of the report showed Italy running a deficit of 3.2 percent of Gross Domestic Product.</p>
<p>That would put Italy above the Maastricht treaty's deficit target of 3.O percent to GDP -- at least on paper, ruling the country out of joining the monetary union at the start on January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>But the source said the figure could change before the Commission releases its forecasts next Wednesday. It had been calculated by officials &quot;at a technical level&quot; and had now been passed higher up the Commission's political hierarchy.</p>
<p>EU officials and market analysts have said previously that Commission forecasters come under heavy pressure when preparing the sensitive forecasts, which indicate how close countries are coming to meeting the economic and monetary union (EMU) criteria.</p>
<p>For example, asked what the forecast for Germany's deficit to GDP would be, the source said: &quot;Probably just where it needs to be.&quot;</p>
<p>It was a suggestion that ways would be found to present the German economy -- which is in danger of failing the Maastricht tests -- in as good a light as possible.</p>
<p>A preliminary Commission forecast published by a Portuguese newspaper on April 10 showed Germany running a deficit of 3.2 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>The same report had Italy at 3.8 percent, indicating that Commission forecasters have already changed their predictions. It was not clear whether this change reflected inclusion of Italy's proposed mini-budget in the calculations.</p>
<p>Italian deputy prime minister Walter Veltroni told the Italian news agency ANSA that the mini-budget would be enough to bring the deficit on target.</p>
<p>Financial analysts say currency markets tend to discount the Commission's forecasts unless they show something that obviously goes against what the Commission, a keen advocate of EMU, would want to report.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the markets take what the Commission says with a pinch of salt,&quot; one London-based currency analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;The assumption is that they will do everything in their power to massage the figures to promote the process of monetary union,&quot; he said. &quot;(But) if they came out with a negative spin then the market might take some notice.&quot;</p>
<p>The Commission denies that it seeks to throw a positive light on the forecasts, emphasising the professionalism and experience of its analysts.</p>
<p>When the Commission issued its last forecasts in November, it was widely reported that both France and Germany would be shown failing the deficit test. In the event both were reported to be just making it.</p>
<p>The November forecasts showed only Britain, Italy and Greece missing the criterion, but included language implying that London and Rome could make it depending on upcoming budget moves.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
