<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="521662" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: NATO-Russia pact hangs in the balance -- diplomats.</title>
<headline>NATO-Russia pact hangs in the balance -- diplomats.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Clayton</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>NATO's drive to clinch a historic pact with Russia before the alliance expands into former communist Europe now hangs in the balance with Moscow demanding strict limits on what any new members can do, NATO diplomats and analysts say.</p>
<p>NATO diplomats believe Russia is attempting to drive a wedge between the western allies in the hope of wringing out some more concessions ahead of a special enlargement summit in Madrid in July, but say the tactic could backfire.</p>
<p>&quot;It is far from certain we will get a deal, the whole issue is now balanced on a knife-edge... the next couple of weeks will be decisive, we are going to go down to the wire on this one,&quot; said one senior diplomat, speaking a day after a visit to Germany by President Boris Yeltsin which failed to bridge the differences.</p>
<p>Moscow is asking for commitments that the new members, most likely Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic, will not be allowed to upgrade the military facilities in any way to bring them in line with other NATO countries.</p>
<p>In addition, Russia wants an explicit commitment from the alliance -- which says it has &quot;no plans, no intention, and no reason&quot; to station nuclear weapons or foreign forces on the territory of new members -- to say it will &quot;never&quot; do so.</p>
<p>&quot;That is totally unacceptable, it would singularise the new members and give them second-class status,&quot; said one NATO official.</p>
<p>NATO says the Russian demands are so stringent they would even jeopardise military exercises under the current Partnership for Peace programme for central and eastern European countries and future Bosnia-style peace operations.</p>
<p>The current alliance-led force in Bosnia has several support units -- manned by U.S. troops -- in Hungary.</p>
<p>&quot;Applicant countries would be worse off than before,&quot; added the official.</p>
<p>Western countries are adamant any new members, all of which want an alliance shield against any future Russian expansionism, must enjoy the rights and privileges of existing members, including NATO's Article 5 security guarantee.</p>
<p>NATO, formed to protect the West against any attack from the former Soviet Union, is based on the principle of collective defence whereby an attack on any one member is considered an attack on all.</p>
<p>At the same time as extending NATO's protective shield to Moscow's former communist satellites, seeking insurance against any new expansionist Russia, the alliance is offering Russia an upgraded relationship.</p>
<p>The first four chapters of a draft NATO-Russia document give Moscow a permanent consulative mechanism, including an ambassador permanently accredited to the alliance's Brussels headquarters and the exchange of military liaison officers.</p>
<p>&quot;We have gone as far as we can go, there is no room for any more substantial concessions,&quot; said one senior military source, adding: &quot;Russia would have a voice, but not a veto in nearly all NATO affairs, unthinkable even a few years ago.&quot;</p>
<p>Russian President Boris Yeltsin flew back from Germany to Russia on Friday after talks with Chancellor Helmut Kohl having said he was optimistic the remaining snags could be cleared up in time for a signing ceremony in Paris on May 27.</p>
<p>Russian Deputy Foreign Minister Alexander Avdeyev told a news conference in Moscow on Friday the agreement would be signed &quot;unless negotiators on the other side thwart this&quot;.</p>
<p>U.S. officials, who say Yeltsin has already backtracked on commitments he made at last month's Helsinki summit with President Bill Clinton, argue Russia is hoping to badger the European allies into more concessions ahead of that date.</p>
<p>They say the May 27 meeting has yet to be confirmed and rule out any likelihood of Clinton attending unless all loose ends have first been tied up.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no chance of Clinton coming unless everything is in the bag in advance, the Russians clearly hope to fudge one or two of the remaining issues,&quot; said one administration source.</p>
<p>The United States, which has pushed enlargement more than any other country, says the issue is beginning to face mounting hostility in Congress.</p>
<p>Diplomats say if any more concessions were made to Russia the charter or pact would be at risk of failing to be ratified.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
