<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="521723" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Markka volatility seen persisting -forex analysts.</title>
<headline>Markka volatility seen persisting -forex analysts.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign investors still hold big positions in the Finnish markka and their efforts to unwind them will keep causing volatility even as economic fundamentals point to the currency strengthening, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>Asked about the outlook for the markka after the Bank of Finland had been seen intervening to brake a sharp slide in the currency against the mark, they said foreign positions built up in winter were still too large to predict the near-term trend.</p>
<p>DEM/FIM this week broke away from recent levels below 3.00 heading towards 3.03. This had prompted the central bank to buy markka for marks, forex dealers and the analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like 3.03 is the upper limit,&quot; one analyst said, guessing at an unspoken &quot;ceiling&quot; which dealers like to believe the central bank would apply.</p>
<p>The markka's weakening trend was halted on Friday after the bank had been seen intervening with DEM/FIM at 3.02. In line with its standard policy the central bank declined comment.</p>
<p>Analysts said that not very much of the estimated 30 billion markka in foreign positions established in January had yet been repatriated: that would point to further volatility.</p>
<p>&quot;DEM/FIM will probably continue to rise, but not at this rate,&quot; a forex dealer said, adding he saw firm resistance at levels between 3.03 and 3.04.</p>
<p>If DEM/FIM hit 3.04 it would be back at the central parity rate at which Finland pegged the markka to the European exchange rate mechanism ERM last October.</p>
<p>Some thought even 3.04 was not necessarily a firm limit.</p>
<p>&quot;If we continue to see a general strengthening of the German mark, then we could see DEM/FIM even up to 3.05,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>But a senior analyst could not see the logic in a weakening scenario, pointing to Finland's strong economic fundamentals. @</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a (weakening) trend,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Next week DEM/FIM could just as well be back to 2.98 levels. If this were a trend, it should be in the opposite direction... Economic fundamentals speak on behalf of a strong markka,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Forecasts by official sources and private research institutes and banks talk of 1997 gross domestic product growth over four percent and continued slow inflation.</p>
<p>More volatility in the markka was the only sure thing ahead, analysts agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;It all depends on what the foreign investors do,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a worry,&quot; another said, adding: &quot;They (foreign investors) are always looking for an alternative. They have been in the markka since January, and not all that much has happened since then.&quot;</p>
<p>--John Acher, Helsinki Newsroom +358-9-680 50 235</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
