<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52182" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Valley National, Midland Bancorp to merge.</title>
<headline>Valley National, Midland Bancorp to merge.</headline>
<dateline>WAYNE, N.J. 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Valley National Bancorp and Midland Bancorporation Inc said on Friday they signed a definitive agreement to merge in an exchange of stock.</p>
<p>According to the agreement, Valley will acquire Midland in a tax-free merger in which each share of Midland common stock will be exchanged for 30 shares of Valley common stock.</p>
<p>Midland has 125,294 shares outstanding, the companies said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>Also, Midland has granted Valley an option to acquire 35,000 shares of Midland's authorized but unissued common stock.  </p>
<p>Valley said the merger was consistent with its strategy to grow in Northern New Jersey through acquisitions. It also said the bank's strategy is to price transactions so that they are accretive to earnings within the first year of combined operations.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the 'in-market' nature of this acquisition, coupled with Midland's relatively high non-interest expenses, should enable Valley to generate significant cost savings within a brief period,&quot; said Gerald Lipkin, Valley's chairman, president and chief executive.</p>
<p>Robert Meyer, Midland's president and chief executive, will join Valley's senior management. Walter Jones III, Midland chairman, and Graham Jones, a board member, also will join Valley's board after the merger, the companies said.</p>
<p>The acquisition, which still needs certain shareholder and regulatory approvals, is expected to close in the first quarter of next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WAYNE, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
