<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="521875" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - April 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - April 18.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company -- CO-OP SUSPENDS TWO EXECUTIVES IN FOOD RETAILING</p>
<p>Two of the most senior executives in the Co-operative Wholesale Society are about to be suspended, following suspicion of a &quot;recent serious breach of trust&quot;. The Co-op said an external investigation had been commissioned into the dealings made by the two since 1994. There is also fear within the group that sensitive information has been leaked recently, giving misleading impressions about its performance.</p>
<p>-- ANGLO AMERICAN OFFERS TO CUT 28 PER CENT STAKE IN LONRHO</p>
<p>Under pressure from the European Commission, South Africa's biggest company, the Anglo American Corporation, has offered to cut its stake in Lonhro to less than 10 per cent. There was concern that any increase in the AAC stake would create excessive concentration of global platinum production. The move comes less than a week before the conclusion of a five month long inquiry into its 360 million sterling purchase of a Lonrho stake was about to end. The offer is expected to be accepted by EU authorities.</p>
<p>-- CREST ACTS TO CURB RISK OF SHARE TRADE GRIDLOCK</p>
<p>The London share trading electronic settlement system, Crest, has taken action to prevent the risk of &quot;gridlock&quot; when shares become available in converting business societies and life assurers next week. Software will be changed and opening hours extended on top of the news that as many as 16 million new shareholders will be entering the market, following the flotation of stocks in Halifax, Woolwich, Norwich Union and many others.</p>
<p>-- BT WINS LANDMARK GERMAN TELECOMS VICTORY</p>
<p>The Dusseldorf high court has ruled that the alliance between France Telecom, US' Sprint and Deutsche Telekom, otherwise known as Global One, is in breach of European competition rules, after it began trading before the EC imposed conditions on it. The ruling is seen as a major victory for BT, who originally took the case to court along with its German partner, industrial group Viag. The court ruled that Deutsche Telekom is liable to pay for costs and damages which could amount to tens of millions of pounds.</p>
<p>-- RAILTRACK PLANS BOOST FOR FREIGHT</p>
<p>Railtrack has come up with a series of plans to boost its freight business, which freight operators claim it is neglecting. Among the proposed measures are increases in freight capacity on major routes, more development of high-speed freight links, and further investment in terminals and information systems. Private investors had been attempting to expand their businesses after British Rail freight loads fell from 136 tonnes to 96 tonnes from 1991-1996.</p>
<p>-- FORD ANNOUNCES SHAKE-UP OF DEALER OPERATIONS</p>
<p>Ford is about to fundamentally change the way it deals with its UK retailers, from previous pressuring of sales at low profit margins to a new emphasis on reducing distribution costs and selling new cars. Less importance will be placed on setting and reaching sales goals as slow revenue is being replaced by tighter cost control and greater value. Ford, which once dominated the UK market with about 30 per cent of the total market, now controls less than 20 per cent.</p>
<p>-- BAE REPAYS 250M STG TO DEVELOP AIRBUS A320</p>
<p>British Aerospace, has reported that it has repayed the 250 million sterling it borrowed from the UK government to help develop its Airbus Industrie A320 aircraft. The aerospace company said interest payments would take the total to 500 million by the year 2000 and the government would receive royalties for each aircraft sold. Airbus is now considering an enlarged version of the A340 aircraft, which would carry 340 people, as well as a 550-seat &quot;super jumbo&quot;, hoped to be part financed by Asian companies.</p>
<p>-- PEARL TO STOP SELLING CASH-COLLECTIONS POLICIES</p>
<p>For the first time in its 133 year history insurance group Pearl Assurance has announced plans to stop selling new policies which require cash collection. Pearl is also terminating the collection of cash premiums from over 120,000 households after it found that costs were greater than the amount being collected. To compensate for this decision they will pay the premiums over the remaining duration of the policy minus its total contributions from the amount paid at maturity.</p>
<p>-- ANGLIAN WATER MAY MAKE 15 MILLION STG PROVISION</p>
<p>Following a review of Anglian Water's international operations it is expected that they will announce a 15 million sterling provision next month at its annual results presentation. Anglian water is one of the latest UK utilities which has been affected by setbacks from overseas, although the extent of the problem is unknown at present. In 1996 the international sector of the company reported a 5.7 million stg operating loss. However finance director Chris Mellor said that revenues are starting to come in from an effluent treatment project in Brazil.</p>
<p>BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
