<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="521977" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian wool prices continue to strengthen.</title>
<headline>Australian wool prices continue to strengthen.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian wool prices reached their highest level in over 18 months at sales in Sydney, Adelaide and Fremantle this week, the Australian Council of Wool Exporters said on Friday.</p>
<p>The eastern market indicator rose 14 cents to 640 cents a kg clean while the western indicator rose nine to 602 cents.</p>
<p>A total of 91,245 bales were offered with a pass-in rate of 8.4 percent, the council said. &quot;The pleasing feature of this week's further strengthening in the wool market was the continuing widespread competition involving local processors and overseas interests including China,&quot;, the council said.  </p>
<p>The Wool International stockpile totalled 1,761,098 bales.</p>
<p>Pastoral group Wesfarmers Dalgety said that as with last week, fine wool prices were the firmest area of the market, particularly for those stylish lots.</p>
<p>The 20 micron price guide in the north rose 32 cents during the week. With the exceptionally large offering of medium to broad wools in Adelaide, these prices remained generally unchanged with 24 to 32u wools moving up or down a few cents.</p>
<p>In the futures market, a total of 235 lots were traded in the 21 micron contract for the week ending April 17.</p>
<p>Open interest decreased by 129 contracts to 762.  </p>
<p>The April 1997 contract rose 19 cents to 755 cents/kg clean.</p>
<p>Sales next week are in Sydney and Melbourne with 56,600 bales rostered for sale.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
