<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="521942" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ long bonds singled out for selling at finish.</title>
<headline>NZ long bonds singled out for selling at finish.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>---------------------(Snapshot at close)------------------------</p>
<p>Figures in brackets compare against previous day's close</p>
<p>FUTURES					  PHYSICAL YIELD (PCT)</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS (JUN) 92.57 (PREV 92.49)  90-DAYS  7.30 (PREV 7.40)</p>
<p>3-YR BONDS   (JUN) 92.07 (PREV 92.05)  02/00    7.81 (PREV 7.85)</p>
<p>10-YR BONDS  (JUN) 91.87 (PREV 91.88)  11/06    8.08 (PREV 8.06)</p>
<p>OVERNIGHT CASH 7.00 PCT   (PREV 7.25)  US 5-YR  6.74 (PREV 6.77)</p>
<p>NZD/USD    0.6909/16 (PREV 0.6881/88)  US 10-YR 6.85 (PREV 6.89)</p>
<p>TWI		    68.70 (PREV 68.46)  US 30-YR 7.07 (PREV 7.10)</p>
<p>-------------------------(April 18)-----------------------------</p>
<p>* NZ yield curve steepens at close as long bonds sold  </p>
<p>* Market thin, light flows drive 11/06 yields higher</p>
<p>* Well-bid short end seen watching TWI for direction next wk</p>
<p>The New Zealand yield curve steepened at Friday's close as the long bonds were singled out for selling pressure and the shorter part of the curve gained ground on a stronger currency.</p>
<p>Dealers said that after the initial move down in yield in the morning on the back of the Kiwi dollar's higher Trade-Weighted Index (TWI), most of the day's price action was in the longer end of the curve.  </p>
<p>The 11/06 maturity ended two basis points higher in yield at 8.08 percent, and dealers said one player had been looking to sell long bonds and switch to shorter dated assets.</p>
<p>&quot;There was also a little bit of selling in the afternoon by some offshore guys -- just small amounts but enough to push a thin market up,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>The 02/00s held onto their gains to finish four basis points stronger at 7.81 percent. The shorter bonds and the money market remained well bid as the TWI climbed 24 points to 68.70.  </p>
<p>New dwelling unit and building consents data out early in the session was weaker than the market had expected, adding to the picture of a slowing economy.</p>
<p>&quot;The new dwellings was soft again, which endorses the CPI and the trend with the retail sales, so that did help the short end a bit,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>He said there was a dearth of economic news on the agenda for next week and the short end of the yield curve would continue to &quot;TWI-watch&quot;.  </p>
<p>Long bonds remain vulnerable to global moves, and with a fragile U.S. Treasury market gearing up for another rate hike when the Federal Reserve next meets in May, it was difficult to pick their direction.</p>
<p>---------------------------(SPREADS)----------------------------</p>
<p>NZD VS	   3 YR	 10 YR	  * NZD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p>USD	   134  (+4)   127  (+6)	* FUTURES     -20  (-3)</p>
<p>CAD	   248  (-3)   141  (+4)	* PHYSICALS    27  (+5)</p>
<p>AUD	   111  (-8)    28  (-3)</p>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>-- Catherine McCaw, Wellington newsroom +64 4 471 4275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
