<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="522159" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo stocks end higher on strong earnings.</title>
<headline>Tokyo stocks end higher on strong earnings.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo stocks closed with solid gains on Friday, as raw-material issues such as steel  0#STL.T and chemicals  0#CHE.T backed by firm earnings continued to attract investors. A rebound in long-strapped financial issues also helped the index, brokers said.</p>
<p>The 225-share Nikkei average climbed 258.73 points or 1.43 percent to end at 18,352.14. June Nikkei futures jumped 320 points to 18,400.</p>
<p>Comments during the noon break by Eisuke Sakakibara, director-general of the Finance Ministry's international finance bureau, had little effect on stocks, they added.  </p>
<p>&quot;The weak yen had propelled buying in electricals and automobiles, and now it's helping raw materials -- this is a second round of buying,&quot; said Hiroyuki Nakai, chief investment strategist at Nikko Securities Co Ltd.</p>
<p>Brokers said a halt of the yen's fall against the dollar kept investors from chasing those blue-chips further, which have already reached high levels, turning their eyes to other lower-priced shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Especially steel and chemicals, which are backed by good earnings and a low PER (price-earnings ratio), are buys,&quot; Nakai said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market was supported by buying backs, as short positions have accumulated in the market lately, and by a new money inflow from investors,&quot; said Kazuo Shiogai, deputy branch manager at ING Baring Securities (Japan) Ltd.</p>
<p>Brokers said pension funds started to buy a wide range of issues as a new financial year started on April 1. The movements also lightened market sentiment, they said.</p>
<p>Market's reaction to a slew of Sakakibara's comments was muted, they said. In the interview, he said that recent forex movements cannot be justified by fundamentals and that G7 cooperation regarding currency markets is intact.  </p>
<p>Sakakibara also said the possibility of Japan's economy contracting is less than people think.</p>
<p>Turnover was 565 million shares on Friday, up from Thursday's 435 million shares.</p>
<p>Winners overwhelmed losers 986 issues to 156, while 97 issues were unchanged.</p>
<p>The broader-based TOPIX index added 20.55 points or 1.50 percent to 1,386.66, while the Nikkei 300 rose 3.67 points or 1.38 percent to end at 268.68.  </p>
<p>The list of heavily traded issues was dominated by steel companies and banks.</p>
<p>Nippon Steel Corp topped the list, with 11.91 million shares traded. The share price gained one yen to 358.</p>
<p>That was followed by Kawasaki Steel Corp, with 9.52 million shares traded, rising seven yen to 371, a new high for the calendar year.</p>
<p>Nippon Credit Bank Ltd was the third heaviest, gaining four yen to 245, followed by Sumitomo Bank Ltd, jumping 100 yen to 1,460, and Sakura Bank Ltd, climbing 19 yen to 690.  </p>
<p>By sector, top percentage gainers were led by fisheries, mining, sea transport, banks, constructions, insurers, iron/steel and real estate.</p>
<p>There are no major declining sectors.</p>
<p>The second section index added 33.36 points to 1,572.53, with 9.34 million shares traded.</p>
<p>The over-the-counter (OTC) index was up 49.61 points at 1,098.58.</p>
<p>-- Hiroko Nakata, Tokyo Equities Desk +81-3-3432-8027</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
