<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52226" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Record Eurobourses await U.S. prices data.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Record Eurobourses await U.S. prices data.</headline>
<byline>Eric Meijer</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's major bourses opened at record highs on Friday, celebrating Wall Street's strength, but then consolidated ahead of much-anticipated U.S. retail sales and prices data.</p>
<p>The Frankfurt and London stock exchanges opened at record levels on Wall Street's 17-point closing gain, which was inspired by benign U.S. wholesale price data on Thursday.</p>
<p>But despite the record levels in Europe, trade was quietly steady until U.S. retail sales and consumer price data are issued at 1230 GMT.</p>
<p>Players across the financial markets are looking for confirmation of the subdued inflation trend seen in Thursday's U.S. wholesale price news.</p>
<p>August consumer prices are seen rising 0.2 percent, the same went for the ex-food and energy index, with August retail sales forecast to rise a bumper 0.7 percent.</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Reserve's Open Market Committee meets on September 24, and markets are desperately speculating where it will drive interest rates.</p>
<p>Some players believe a 0.25 percentage point rise has already been taken as fact in market prices, while others believe the low U.S. inflation trend and the forthcoming presidential election rule out an imminent interest rate rise.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt, German shares traded at bourse record highs in mid-session floor trade, with bullish sentiment boosted by a strong dollar, firm German debt, and Wall Street's strength.</p>
<p>By late morning the DAX index was up about 27 points at 2,597, well above the bourse record of 2,592.65.</p>
<p>In London, shares drifted back from a new record high to be mixed by mid-morning in quiet, cautious trading, dealers said.</p>
<p>With little fresh news to spark activity, shares were marking time as investors caught their breath after Thursday's glut of company results and ahead of the U.S. data later.</p>
<p>Earlier, the FTSE 100 pushed to a new all-time best before slipping back to be 0.2 points lower at 3,932.4. The previous best of 3,933.6 was set on September 10.</p>
<p>In Paris, French shares were a shade softer in midsession as the market digested the week's gains and Thursday's rise of more than one percent.</p>
<p>In currencies, the dollar was sulking, testing session lows against the mark at the European mid-session, dragged down by short-term players unwinding early purchases after a push above key levels failed to flush out buyers, traders said.</p>
<p>Against the yen, the dollar recovered after an early dip below 110 yen in the wake of a smaller-than-expected decline in second quarter Japanese economic growth.</p>
<p>&quot;It might sound silly but the dollar is down because it couldn't go up,&quot; said Alan Collins, head of technical analysis at Merita Bank in London. &quot;It's frustrating when everyone is looking one way. So if it fails to go up there's a lot of scope for disappointment, and that means sell the dollar.&quot;</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1130 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.5120 marks and 110.33 yen compared with late Thursday's 1.5129 and 110.11.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1130 GMT</p>
<p>The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares was down 2.8 at 3,929.8.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index was down 0.97 points up at 2,064.35</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt was 19.80 points up at 2,590.12.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold fixed at $382.80 vs $382.10 on Thursday afternoon and a London close of $382.50. Silver was lightly higher at $5.05, up three cents. Platinum was weaker at $389, down $1.50, and seen vulnerable after breaching $390 support.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
