<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="522414" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bonds/futures.</title>
<headline>Italian bonds/futures.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian bond futures started lower after newspaper reports of a European Commission forecast that Italy is not on target to meet European and Monetary Union (EMU) which in turn weakened the lira, dealers said.</p>
<p>Il Sole 24 Ore said according to forecasts from Brussels due to be released on April 23, Italy's deficit in 1997 is set to be 3.2 percent of GDP. Maastricht criteria outline that a nation's deficit needs to be three percent of output.</p>
<p>&quot;After the strong rises seen this week we are back to worrying about Italy's chances of joining EMU again,&quot; said a trader on the LIFFE market.  </p>
<p>Il Sole said the government of Romano Prodi needs to prepare a new mini-budget for around four trillion lire of deficit cutting measures and accelerate the preparation of the 1998 budget to bring Italy into line with the criteria.</p>
<p>It added that of all 15 European Union nations, only Italy and Greece are currently expected not to meet the Maastricht criteria for EMU.</p>
<p>Dealers added that the EMU worries coupled with the early weakness to other European bond markets had undermined BTPs, but they expected some consolidation as the market looked ahead to Italian CPI figures early next week.  </p>
<p>Il Sole said that the Brussels forecast saw Italy's GDP growth in 1997 at 1.1 percent against the Italian government's own forecast of 1.2 percent growth.</p>
<p>BPT futures had lost early gains on Thursday to close slightly lower after Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer said he was opposed to a softening of the strict EMU criteria and that sustainability of fiscal criteria was a decisive issue.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
