<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="522456" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: FEATURE - Dutch biotech pioneer gears up to go public.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Dutch biotech pioneer gears up to go public.</headline>
<byline>Lien van der Leij</byline>
<text>
<p>LEIDEN, Netherlands, April 18 (Reuter) For Dutch biopharmaceuticals firm Pharming, the international furore unleashed by the recent cloning of Dolly the sheep in Britain sparks a strong sense of deja vu.</p>
<p>Researchers at this campus-based company pioneered the creation of Herman the transgenic bull in 1988, hitting the headlines in a blaze of media soul-searching about the morality of implanting human genes in animals.</p>
<p>While the rest of the world wrangles over the pros and cons of bio-engineering, Pharming has been quietly getting on with the business of modifying animals genetically to produce medicines from their milk, targeting what could prove to be a highly lucrative market.</p>
<p>And now the firm is ready to float on the stock market within the next year.</p>
<p>&quot;The debate raging now in Britain, the U.S. and elsewhere on the morality of bio-engineering started in the Netherlands about nine years ago,&quot; Pharming's corporate communications director Rob Meines said in an interview.</p>
<p>Genetically modified foodstuffs remain controversial but public acceptance of animal bio-technology to create more effective medicines for humans has since become widespread.</p>
<p>Pharming is within a couple of years of launching human lactoferrin derived from cows' milk -- a product which boosts the immune system and could become the company's biggest money-spinner.</p>
<p>The product -- used in the treatment and prevention of stomach infections -- is expected to be introduced in association with foods and dietary aids group Nutricia around the year 2000.</p>
<p>A second product to combat Pompey's disease, an incurable hereditary muscle-wasting illness, could be available by 1999.</p>
<p>Armed with these upbeat prospects for future performance, Pharming is looking to go public after years of government grants, venture capital funding and private share placements.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to seek a stock market listing some time over the next year or so, but we're in no particular hurry as we have sufficient capital,&quot; says Pharming's chief executive officer George Hersbach.</p>
<p>COMPANY VALUATION</p>
<p>Around 60 million guilders ($30.8 million) worth of Pharming shares are currently placed with some 50 to 60 different shareholders around the world, while the company is valued at an estimated 160 million guilders.</p>
<p>Given this international spread, Pharming is mulling a dual listing on NASDAQ and London, while EASDAQ, Nasdaq's recently created European equivalent, is also a possibility.</p>
<p>Until now the firm's backers have seen little cash return on their investments as Pharming -- like its peers in this research-intensive segment -- has a so-called &quot;burn rate&quot; of some six million guilders a year.</p>
<p>&quot;It's more of a book loss, in that we are eating into our financial capital but building up our expertise capital -- we are creating added value,&quot; Meines says.</p>
<p>Tangible evidence of this added value is Pharming's strong worldwide patents position in its field, Hersbach says.</p>
<p>&quot;We have already acquired a patent on the method and its platform, cows, which means that technically we are in a very strong position,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>Consequently Pharming now owns the rights to all pharmaceuticals production based on milk from genetically modified mammals in the U.S., Europe, Canada, Russia, Australia and New Zealand. More patents are pending.</p>
<p>BRIGHT FUTURE FOR BIO-ENGINEERING</p>
<p>In the Netherlands, as elsewhere, the future looks bright for bio-engineering. Recent advances have made it one of the most effective and cost-efficient technologies in making drugs.</p>
<p>According to a recent government report, bio-engineered products will account for around 40 percent of Dutch pharmaceuticals sales in 2010, from some 10 to 15 percent now.</p>
<p>&quot;Pharming already has around 35 new projects targeted, of which two are already in the pipeline,&quot; Hersbach says. &quot;It's a fast-growing industry.&quot;</p>
<p>The nascent boom in bio-technology prompts comparisons with the computer software sector and some analysts predict that bio-techs will take over from high-techs as the preferred choice of smart investors not averse to taking risks.</p>
<p>PROFIT TAKES TIME</p>
<p>But with product development times averaging 10-12 years it's not a sector for those looking to get rich quick.</p>
<p>&quot;After nine years we are now into the final research phase for production of human lactoferrin in cow's milk, and that is relatively fast for the development of this type of product,&quot; Hersbach says.</p>
<p>The final phase involves trials on human subjects. &quot;We hope to start trials with the first human adult patients around June this year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Human lactoferrin is a protein found in the milk of breast-feeding mothers which promotes infant immunity to bacterial infections and stimulates the growth of benign intestinal flora.</p>
<p>The bio-engineered product will be used for treating or preventing bacterial gastro-intestinal infections in patients with reduced immunological resistance, such as AIDS patients or cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy.</p>
<p>&quot;Another application is in clinical formulas for premature babies,&quot; said Hersbach.</p>
<p>Human babies have no in-built immunological resistance at birth, one of the reasons why new mothers are advised to breast feed for at least the first few weeks of life.</p>
<p>Pharming's invention could prove lucrative for Nutricia, a major manufacturer of infant formulas under its own name and brands Cow&amp;Gate, Milupa and Milumil.</p>
<p>However, Hersbach says there are as yet no plans to introduce the product as a standard component of regular over-the-counter infant milk formulas.</p>
<p>&quot;The emphasis is on clinical nutrition,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>Even closer to market is Pharming's product to combat Pompey's disease.</p>
<p>&quot;People suffering from this rare enzyme deficiency cannot properly process one particular carbohydrate,&quot; explained Hersbach. The muscle wasting disease eventually ends in death through heart failure.</p>
<p>Pharming has developed a method to produce the missing enzyme in the milk of genetically-modified rabbits and will invest 30 million guilders in a production facility in the Belgian city of Geel set to come on-line before the millennium.</p>
<p>Given the rarity of the condition -- around five sufferers per 10,000 population in developed countries -- clinical trials will be limited to a relatively small number of patients, Hersbach predicts.</p>
<p>Work on the manufacture of two types of transgenically produced human collagen for tissue repair and treating rheumatoid arthritis is also well-advanced.</p>
<p>&quot;Tangible results from all these efforts are the key to a successful IPO for Pharming,&quot; predicts Hersbach.</p>
<p>And what of Herman, who helped make it all happen?</p>
<p>&quot;He's been put out to pasture long since,&quot; says Hersbach. &quot;Independent tests have shown his general state of health and life expectancy are no different from that of an unmanipulated animal. He's happily retired, I can assure you.&quot;</p>
<p>($ = 1.945 Dutch Guilders)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25670">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
