<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52271" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Gold lease rates rise, but no spike expected.</title>
<headline>Gold lease rates rise, but no spike expected.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Short-term gold lease rates have popped up over the past week, but they were unlikely to rocket higher like last year, dealers and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;You're not going to get the same sort of move this year as you had last year, because people are certainly not going to let themselves become so exposed,&quot; a senior dealer said.</p>
<p>Late last year, the borrowing market tightened sharply under the weight of massive hedging by gold producers, pushing one-month lease rates to record highs of around six percent and gold into unprecedented backwardation.</p>
<p>Since last Friday, one-month lease rates have climbed about 50 basis points to about 1.10/1.60 percent.</p>
<p>Long-term rates, however, have been more stable, rising only about 10 basis points to 1.70/2.20.</p>
<p>&quot;There may be a bit more room on the upside, maybe they'll go up another percentage point,&quot; the dealer added.</p>
<p>Lease rates have risen due to a mixture of factors, dealers and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a combination of producer selling, funds going short and also probably year-end jiggling around by central banks in the light of what happened last year,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Andy Smith, analyst at Union Bank of Switzerland, said the surge in open interest on Comex since Monday closely paralleled the increase in lease rates, indicating funds borrowing gold to go short.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like more than coincidence, the rise in open interest and the rise in lease rates,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dealers said they have seen a modest increase in hedging by producers who feel they may be exposed if prices slide much further.</p>
<p>&quot;The volumes haven't been particularly large, but there have been some worried producers,&quot; one said, adding that it was coming from several sources.</p>
<p>Smith said he didn't know whether producers were active or not, but speculated that there may be some jitters by miners who have not completed their yearly hedging programmes.</p>
<p>&quot;People come back from their holidays and say &quot;If I haven't done my borrowing for over the end of the year I'll do it'. It might be something of that in it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Last year's tightness was exacerbated when producer hedging ocurred at the same time central banks traditionally halted fresh lending during year-end stock-taking and accounting exercises.</p>
<p>This year, banks who function as intermediaries in the borrowing/lending market would be prepared for any tightness and would be covering any exposure well ahead of the year-end, analysts said.</p>
<p>--Eric Onstad, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8065</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
