<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="522907" id="root" date="1997-04-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL ICE HOCKEY-DEVILS, FLYERS GO UP 2-0 IN PLAYOFFS, OTTAWA-BUFFALO TIED.</title>
<headline>NHL ICE HOCKEY-DEVILS, FLYERS GO UP 2-0 IN PLAYOFFS, OTTAWA-BUFFALO TIED.</headline>
<dateline>EAST RUTHERFORD, New Jersey 1997-04-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Jersey Devils and the Philadelphia Flyers took 2-0 leads in their Eastern Conference quarterfinal playoff series on Saturday.</p>
<p>And the Ottawa Senators, with a 3-1 victory, evened their best-of-seven-games series 1-1 against the Buffalo Sabres.</p>
<p>On the Devils ice in East Rutherford, John MacLean scored two of New Jersey's three power-play goals to lead the Devils to a 4-1 victory over the Montreal Canadiens.</p>
<p>Bill Guerin had the other power-play goal for New Jersey, which never scored more than twice with the man advantage in any game during the regular season. The Devils, who finished 23rd in the NHL on the power play, are 4-for-12 in this series.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a different season,&quot; MacLean said. &quot;We struggled in the first game against them on the power play, they scored two shorthanded goals. We kept it a little basic -- move the puck, one pass, two passes and put it on net and see what happens.</p>
<p>&quot;You've got to get as many shots as you can and that's what we tried to do tonight and it was successful.&quot;</p>
<p>Brian Savage had the lone goal for Montreal, which hosts Game Three on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, Trent Klatt's fluke goal with 6:20 remaining gave the Flyers a 3-2 victory over the Pittsburgh Penguins.</p>
<p>Klatt's shot from the low left faceoff circle deflected in front and rolled briefly onto the top of the net. It dropped onto the goal line and goaltender Ken Wregget knocked it in while scrambling to corral it.</p>
<p>Garth Snow made 28 saves in his second straight start for Philadelphia, which also got goals from Joel Otto and John LeClair.</p>
<p>In Buffalo, Ron Tugnutt bounced back from a shaky outing in Game One of the playoffs to stop 23 shots and Daniel Alfredsson had a goal and an assist to lead the Senators past the Sabres.</p>
<p>Tugnutt, who surrendered two third-period goals on just five shots in a 3-1 loss in Game One, was at his best in the middle of the third period. He turned aside a series of Buffalo shots to preserve his first career playoff victory and the first in franchise history.</p>
<p>&quot;We weren't happy after Game One but we also realised that we got our feet wet,&quot; Tugnutt said. &quot;Buffalo showed us what it takes to win. We knew come Game Two we were going to have to change our way of playing the game.&quot;</p>
<p>Andreas Dackell got Ottawa on the board just 2:48 into the game, and Steve Duchesne pushed the advantage to 2-0 at 8:37 of the second period. Duchesne, one of a handful of playoff veterans on the Senators, poked home his own rebound for the eventual game-winner.</p>
<p>After Randy Burridge's second goal of the series halved the deficit midway through the second period, Alfredsson scored just 18 seconds into the third.</p>
<p>&quot;We got a little rambunctious, trying to make hits,&quot; Sabres coach Ted Nolan said. &quot;We just got out of sync a little bit.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EAST RUTHERFORD, New Jersey"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
