<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="522964" id="root" date="1997-04-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: SWIMMING-TWO MORE GOLDS KEEP AUSTRALIA ON TOP.</title>
<headline>SWIMMING-TWO MORE GOLDS KEEP AUSTRALIA ON TOP.</headline>
<byline>Derek Parr</byline>
<dateline>GOTHENBURG, Sweden 1997-04-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Matthew Dunn and Grant Hackett kept Australia winning on the final day of the world short-course swimming championships on Sunday and left them top of the medals table with nine titles.</p>
<p>Dunn, undaunted by a cold, repeated the individual medley golden double he achieved at the last edition of the championships in 1995, completing the job with victory in Sunday's 200 event.</p>
<p>&quot;It's great. I started to get a cold last night and I'm just wiped. I had nothing all day so this is just such a relief,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dunn, who also won a relay gold, was named men's swimmer of the four-day meeting, with American Jenny Thompson earning the women's award for her haul of two golds, two silvers -- one in Sunday's medley relay -- and a 100 butterfly world record.</p>
<p>Shaven-headed 16-year-old Hackett won an absorbing duel with balding German veteran Joerg Hoffmann in the concluding 1,500 metres freestyle, the longest race in the programme.</p>
<p>Hackett ceded the lead to the 27-year-old former world long- course champion after 400 metres but recaptured it with just over 200 metres to go in the 60-length race and won by 1.13 seconds in 14 minutes 39.54 seconds.</p>
<p>&quot;I hurt like hell. I wanted to go out hard and then try to hold him off but he came back at me,&quot; Hackett said.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought he might die towards the end, which he did. So I just went for it.&quot;</p>
<p>Bronze went to Britain's Olympic bronze medallist Graeme Smith.</p>
<p>China claimed two more victories in the final session, thanks to Chen Yan and their 4x100 medley relay quartet, and finished second to the Australians overall with six titles -- all from their resurgent women's team.</p>
<p>Chen pipped Misty Hyman to win the women's 200 backstroke by 0.16 of a second, leaving the fancied American with two silvers -- one in the medley relay -- and three bronzes, but no golds.</p>
<p>Venezuela's Francisco Sanchez and Cuba's Neisser Bent completed golden doubles and Louise Karlsson brought Sweden their third gold of the championships to the roaring approval of more than 5,000 noisy fans packed into the Scandinavium arena.</p>
<p>Sanchez, Saturday's 100 freestyle champion, retained his 50 freestyle crown with victory by 0.23 of a second over 1993 champion Mark Foster of Britain in 21.80.</p>
<p>Bent, added the 100 backstroke title to Friday's 200 crown, overtaking American pacesetter Brian Retterer in the second half of the shorter race to win in a championship record 52.77.</p>
<p>Karlsson just survived a withering attack on the final freestyle leg by Slovakia's Martina Moravcova in the 200 individual medley.</p>
<p>China narrowly missed their third women's relay world record of the meet, falling just 0.10 short in the medley in 3:57.83, with the Americans 1.11 seconds behind.</p>
<p>Germany denied Swedish veteran Anders Holmertz a victorious farewell from the sport, winning the men's 4x100 freestyle relay and withholding gold from the home team by just 0.14 despite a fierce charge by Sweden's Lars Frolander on the anchor leg.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GOTHENBURG, Sweden"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
