<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="523097" id="root" date="1997-04-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peruvians see no progress on hostage crisis talks.</title>
<headline>Peruvians see no progress on hostage crisis talks.</headline>
<byline>Paul Hughes</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-04-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>An opinion poll released on Sunday showed most Peruvians saw little or no progress in talks to end Lima's 124-day-old hostage crisis, which claimed its first major political casualty this weekend.</p>
<p>Nearly nine out of every 10 people questioned by local pollsters Imasen thought negotiations between the government and Marxist rebels holding 72 VIPs in the Japanese ambassador's home had advanced little or not at all.</p>
<p>The poll of 400 people carried out in April and published in La Republica newspaper, showed Peruvians split nearly 50-50 over whether the government should give in to the rebels to bring an end to the four-month siege. The paper did not provide any margin of error for the poll.</p>
<p>The 20-odd Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) gunmen holed up inside the diplomatic mansion are demanding the freedom of about 450 jailed comrades in exchange for their 72 hostages.</p>
<p>President Alberto Fujimori has ruled out this demand but sources say he may be considering freeing some low-level MRTA prisoners to avoid a bloody end to the standoff.</p>
<p>The poll showed 48 percent supported releasing MRTA prisoners not involved in violent attacks while 49 percent said no MRTA inmates should be freed.</p>
<p>The hostage crisis, probably the toughest test of Fujimori's six-year-old government, claimed its first major political victim on Saturday with the resignation of Interior Minister Juan Briones.</p>
<p>Briones, who had held the post since 1991, acknowledged that the dramatic commando-style assault on a cocktail party at the residence on Dec. 17 had been a major embarrassment for security forces.</p>
<p>&quot;We recognise that there were security lapses in the takeover of the Japanese residence,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The MRTA originally held more than 500 hostages but have released most, keeping those they consider most important including the Japanese and Bolivian ambassadors, two Peruvian government ministers, two dozen Japanese diplomats and businessmen and Fujimori's younger brother</p>
<p>Security reports leaked to the media following the assault showed that officials had been warned that an MRTA platoon was in Lima looking to kidnap major political figures to secure the freedom of jailed leaders.</p>
<p>Fujimori had said previously that &quot;heads will roll&quot; once the crisis had ended.</p>
<p>Police chief Ketin Vidal -- a national hero following the capture of Maoist Shining Path guerrilla movement leader Abimael Guzman in 1992 -- also resigned on Saturday.</p>
<p>Fujimori quickly swore in Gen. Cesar Saucedo, previously commander of the second military district that includes Lima, to replace Briones. He made no comment on the resignations.</p>
<p>The security shakeup had little immediate effect on the handling of the hostage crisis with mediators continuing their busy programme of backdoor diplomacy to try to get the MRTA and the government back to the negotiating table they abandoned on March 12.</p>
<p>Nor did a recent controversy surrounding the expulsion of a leading local Red Cross official appear to have affected the Geneva-based organisation's work with the hostages.</p>
<p>Red Cross officials said they were still waiting for an explanation from the government for asking Juan Pedro Schaerer, the organisation's number two representative in Lima, to leave the country last Wednesday.</p>
<p>Though there has been no official explanation for Schaerer's expulsion, a pro-government newspaper reported on Sunday that he had been leaking information to MRTA members outside of the residence. The report, citing unnamed diplomatic sources, was published in the Expreso newspaper which has been consistently critical of the Red Cross since the crisis began.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
