<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="523170" id="root" date="1997-04-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan police set to raid state nuclear firm - report.</title>
<headline>Japan police set to raid state nuclear firm - report.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese police are set to raid the headquarters of a state-run nuclear firm this week over a false report it filed on Japan's worst-ever nuclear accident last month, Kyodo news agency said.</p>
<p>The raids would take place at the Tokyo headquarters of the Power Reactor and Nuclear Fuel Development Corp (PNC) and a nuclear reprocessing plant in Tokaimura, Kyodo, quoting police sources, said late on Saturday.</p>
<p>A fire and explosion on March 11 at the plant in Tokaimura exposed 37 workers to low-level radiation.</p>
<p>The PNC admitted early this month that it had falsified a report about the explosion at Tokaimura on the Pacific coast 100 km (65 miles) northeast of Tokyo.</p>
<p>Police began questioning PNC officials about the doctored report on the Tokaimura explosion after the government's Science and Technology Agency took the rare step of filing a criminal complaint against the firm it oversees.</p>
<p>Neither the police nor the PNC would comment on the report of a possible raid this week.</p>
<p>The science agency's move came two days after the troubled PNC was forced to shut down an advanced thermal reactor called Fugen after it had waited 30 hours before reporting a radiation leak which exposed 11 workers to low-level radiation.</p>
<p>The Science and Technology Agency on Saturday said investigations showed that the Fugen reactor, located on the coast of the Sea of Japan some 350 km (220 miles) west of Tokyo, experienced seven previously unreported cases of radioactive tritium leakage in 1992 and 1993.</p>
<p>The finding followed the PNC's acknowledgement that it did not report 11 separate radiation leaks at the Fugen reactor in the past three years to local authorities.</p>
<p>PNC officials said they did not report the past accidents because the amount of leaked radiation was below the level at which they were legally required to do so. Local government officials said the PNC should have reported the accidents anyway, in accordance with a prior agreement.</p>
<p>The PNC's falsified report on the March accident incorrectly said staff had visually confirmed that a fire had been extinguished at a nuclear waste facility, the firm said.</p>
<p>In fact, no staff had confirmed that the fire had been put out. The fire later flared up and triggered the explosion.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the government ordered Fugen shut down, making it the fourth of the PNC's six main facilities to have been deactivated following accidents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I15000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
