<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="523106" id="root" date="1997-04-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: TIMELINES-Today in History - April 21.</title>
<headline>TIMELINES-Today in History - April 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>BIRTHDAYS</p>
<p>Dutch Naval Surgeon JAN VAN RIEBEECK who started the South African city of Capetown, was born in 1634.</p>
<p>British author CHARLOTTE BRONTE was born in 1816.  She wrote &quot;Villette&quot;, &quot;Shirley&quot; and &quot;Jane Eyre&quot;, and was the eldest of three sisters who all contributed to the arts. </p>
<p>Australian sideshow operator JOSEPH MARCONI was born in 1876. Famous during his life for his sideshows, he also manufactured goanna oil which he claimed cured many diseases. He died trying to stop a street brawl.</p>
<p>Veteran actor ANTHONY QUINN was born in 1915 in Mexico. He won an oscar for his role in &quot;Viva Zapata&quot;.</p>
<p>British photographer NORMAN PARKINSON was born in 1913.  He specialised in photographing fashion and celebrities. </p>
<p>QUEEN ELIZABETH the Second was born in 1926 at 17 Burton street London. Crowned in 1952, she has ruled ever since, and has presided over the break-up of the British Empire.</p>
<p>EVENTS</p>
<p>    1509 :    HENRY the VIII took over the throne of England.</p>
<p>He was to later become famous for the creation of the Church of England and his six wives. </p>
<p>    1856 :    Building workers in Melbourne declare they'll only</p>
<p>work eight hours a day, thus begining 8 hour or Labour Day. While this is the original Labour Day, it is celebrated on different dates in different states, dep*nding on when the eight hour day was declared.</p>
<p>    1901 :    Death of American author MARK TWAIN.  TWAIN wrote</p>
<p>classics like &quot;Tom Sawyer&quot; and &quot;Huckleberry Finn&quot;. Also known for his wit, he'd replied to a report of his death some years before saying, &quot;Reports of my death have been greatly exaggerated.&quot; </p>
<p>    1918 :    Rittmeister Baron MANFRED VON RICHTHOFEN better</p>
<p>known as the RED BARON was killed in action in World War One. The famous fighter pilot shot down 80 Allied aircraft. He gained his nickname by refusing to follow orders to paint his aircraft in camouflage (because he thought it was cowardly) and instead painted it bright scarlet. His squadron followed his lead and through their wild colour schemes soon became known as the &quot;Flying Circus&quot;. The RED BARON was killed by a single bullet while flying in France, the credit originally going to Canadian airman ROY BROWN. Today it is generally accepted he was in fact killed by an Australian soldier who fired on his plane from the ground.</p>
<p>    1946 :    Death of British economist JOHN MAYNARD KEYNES,</p>
<p>who argued high unemployment could only be solved through increased government spending. Many of his views were adopted around the World at the end of the Great Depression and after World War Two.</p>
<p>    1970 :    Western Australian farmer LEN CASEY begins his</p>
<p>battle over moves to apply government quotas on his farm. He sends the government a letter telling them he has seceded from Australia. Just under a year later, he officially declares his farm &quot;Hutt River Province&quot; and adopts the title PRINCE LEONARD. The Prince now flies his own flag, issues his own stamps and money, and has turned Hutt River into a tourist attraction.</p>
<p>    1979 :    The Bjelke-Petersen Government allowed the</p>
<p>unannounced demolition of the historic Bellevue Hotel, under the cover of darkness. </p>
<p>    1989 :    More than 10 thousand Chinese students rallied in</p>
<p>Bejing's Tienanmen Square calling for democracy. The protest lasted until June, when troops moved in and killed more than two and a half thousand demonstrators.</p>
<p>(Compiled from ABC ARCHIVES, ABC RADIO NATIONAL, &quot;On This Day&quot; published by REED INTERNATIONAL BOOKS LIMITED, &quot;The Chronicle Of The 20th Century&quot; published by PENGUIN BOOKS and &quot;Rock And Pop (Day By Day)&quot; published by BLANDFORD BOOKS.)</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
