<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="523370" id="root" date="1997-04-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Sinn Fein calls for votes in UK election.</title>
<headline>Sinn Fein calls for votes in UK election.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Hill</byline>
<dateline>MONAGHAN, Ireland 1997-04-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The IRA's political wing Sinn Fein began its annual conference on Sunday with a call for votes in Britain's May I election to force the next London government to invite it to peace talks.</p>
<p>&quot;Every vote for Sinn Fein increases the pressure on the incoming British government to engage in a process of real and credible negotiations involving all of the parties,&quot; Sinn Fein's chief negotiator, Martin McGuinness, told delegates.</p>
<p>&quot;These are crucial elections in which Sinn Fein can change the political landscape of this country for ever,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein, which shares the Irish Republican Army's goal of ending British rule of Northern Ireland, is barred from Belfast peace talks because of the guerrillas' ending of a 17-month ceasefire in February 1996.</p>
<p>The Irish, British and U.S. governments have all refused to talk to Sinn Fein since the IRA attacks and have vilified the party for its failure to get the guerrillas to restore their ceasefire and end violence for good.</p>
<p>But McGuinness said Sinn Fein was confident of winning up to three parliamentary seats in the British election, which would confront the British and Irish governments with refusing to negotiate with democratically elected representatives.</p>
<p>&quot;A strong mandate for Sinn Fein at the forthcoming elections will make it extremely difficult for either government to ignore our democratic right to represent our electorate in negotiations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;A strong mandate for Sinn Fein will reverberate throughout the corridors of power in Dublin, London and Washington as well as European capitals.</p>
<p>&quot;It will bring untold pressure to bear on the incoming British government and the Irish government to engage in a credible process of inclusive peace negotiations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>McGuinness made no mention of the party's policy of refusing to occupy seats it wins in the British parliament because it would entail allegiance to Britain which it sees as the illegal colonial ruler of northern Ireland.</p>
<p>Nor did he make any hint of a new IRA ceasefire but said only that Sinn Fein wanted the Belfast talks, which group pro-British Unionists and pro-Irish Nationalists, &quot;to take place in a peaceful atmosphere&quot;.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein won 15 percent of votes in an election to an non-executive peace forum in Belfast last June, its best showing in a Northern Ireland poll, and expects that McGuinness and Sinn Fein President Gerry Adams will both win seats on May 1.</p>
<p>It believes that a strong British government will have to invite Sinn Fein to peace talks to restore momentum to a Northern Ireland peace process which slowed to a standstill under Conservative Prime Minister John Major.</p>
<p>The conference, in the Irish border town of Monaghan, takes place 24 hours after the IRA claimed responsibility for two small bombs on British railway networks and a series of bomb hoaxes which created transport havoc last week.</p>
<p>Major and his likely successor, Labour Party leader Tony Blair, both condemned the attacks and said the IRA would get nowhere until it ended violence for good.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONAGHAN, Ireland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
