<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="523412" id="root" date="1997-04-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lott signals optimism on chances of budget deal.</title>
<headline>Lott signals optimism on chances of budget deal.</headline>
<byline>Arshad Mohammed</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott Sunday signalled optimism on the chances for an agreement with President Clinton on balancing the nation's budget by 2002, saying that &quot;the iron is hot&quot; for a deal.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we can come to an agreement,&quot; Lott said on the CNN programme Late Edition with Frank Sesno, adding that he believed it was important to move quickly. &quot;I think the iron is hot.&quot;</p>
<p>Negotiators for Clinton, a Democrat, have been in talks with the budget chairmen from Republican-controlled Congress and their Democratic counterparts for two weeks seeking to hammer out a deal to balance the budget by 2002.</p>
<p>Although they had not reached an accord by Thursday, when the talks broke up, negotiations are expected to resume next Wednesday.</p>
<p>Lott suggested the two sides had made progress on some issues, including the controversial question of how much to cut the popular Medicare health care programme, which Clinton has offered to trim by $100 billion over five years.</p>
<p>Asked if that was enough, Lott replied: &quot;I understand they are still talking about a variety of suggestions that would get it to a higher level. I believe that Medicare is an area that we can reach an agreement. We are very close to that.&quot;</p>
<p>On the question of tax cuts, the Mississippi Republican said: &quot;I want all the tax cuts we can get,&quot; citing reductions in the capital gains and estate taxes, among others.</p>
<p>But unlike at the beginning of the year, when he said he wanted to see more than $150 billion in tax cuts, Lott his time appeared to show some flexibility by not citing a specific number.</p>
<p>Clinton's budget, put forward Feb. 6, proposed tax cuts of $98 billion over five years partly offset by tax increases of $76 billion, leaving a net tax cut of about $22 billion.</p>
<p>Sen. Pete Domenici, the New Mexico Republican who chairs the Senate Budget Committee and is a key player in the budget talks, suggested the two sides had made progress last week, but he shied away from saying that they were close to a deal.</p>
<p>&quot;Look, on these you never know when you're close enough and you've always got second thoughts. It's a tough proposition,&quot; Domenici told the Fox News Sunday programme.</p>
<p>One of the key problems, analysts and officials say, is that it is not clear the negotiators from the Democratic and Republican sides will be able to fashion a deal that will pass muster with their rank-and-file members.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to be very hard to please many people in the Congress with whatever we do,&quot; Domenici said.</p>
<p>A senior administration official said late last week that the hiatus in the talks would allow the White House to consult more closely with the Democrats in Congress, some of whom feel that the president has moved to far to the right.</p>
<p>&quot;They think we've become Republicans,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Republican House Budget Committee chairman John Kasich of Ohio, another key player in the talks, said Saturday there could be an agreement Wednesday or Thursday. If not the Republicans would seek to craft their own budget, he said.</p>
<p>House Minority Leader Dick Gephardt, a Missouri Democrat who is said to be displeased by some of the president's moves toward the centre, told CBS's Face the Nation programme the Republicans were too divided to come up with their own plan.</p>
<p>&quot;Half of the Republicans just want to just give big tax breaks to the wealthiest Americans and the other half want to balance the budget by cutting Medicare and education and the environment too deeply,&quot; said Gephardt, who is widely believed to have presidential ambitions for the 2000 election. &quot;They're hopelessly split, it's why they can't do a budget.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
