<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="523415" id="root" date="1997-04-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bonn denies topping 97 borrowing goal, missing EMU.</title>
<headline>Bonn denies topping 97 borrowing goal, missing EMU.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-04-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bonn government on Sunday denied reports Germany might be excluded from Europe's currency union for blowing its budget targets, but officials admitted more cost-cutting was needed to ensure EMU entry.</p>
<p>&quot;Only the tax estimate, to be released in May, will present new clarity about fiscal affairs,&quot; a Finance Ministry spokesman said, brushing off a report in newspaper Welt am Sonntag that Germany was close to exceeding its borrowing budget for 1997.</p>
<p>The newspaper said that because Bonn's cash deficit in the first three months stood at 40 billion marks ($23.4 billion), the government had already used up most of the 53.4 billion marks it has allowed for its budget deficit for the whole of 1997.</p>
<p>But the ministry spokesman said it was impossible to extrapolate the government's budget deficit for the full year from volatile cash deficits and low tax revenues.</p>
<p>Bonn's net new borrowing -- seen as a better guide to how the budget deficit might turn out -- was 14.3 billion marks in the first quarter, the Bundesbank said this week.</p>
<p>In its April report the central bank also said: &quot;It should be pointed out that the results of the cash accounts -- above all in the early months of the year -- are not a reliable indicator for the budget deficit.&quot;</p>
<p>Debate about Bonn's budget deficit has become a hot topic as high unemployment and sluggish economic growth cast a question mark over whether Germany can reach its 2.9 percent deficit goal this year and qualify for currency union.</p>
<p>While most Bonn officials have publicly said they expect Germany to be among the first nations to qualify for EMU in 1999, Welt am Sonntag said some officials were saying rising debt was &quot;acutely endangering&quot; Germany's EMU membership.</p>
<p>As Germany's qualifications are debated, there is no doubt further cost-cutting is essential, officials say.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel is keeping open his options on ordering another spending freeze, the ministry spokesman said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Peter Rauen, a member of Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrats, told German newspaper Express further savings in social insurance payments were absolutely necessary.</p>
<p>He warned that tax increases would otherwise be inevitable, if Germany wanted to trim its deficit to EMU entry levels.</p>
<p>By cutting social costs by 1.6 percent some 20 billion marks could be saved and &quot;the politicians should be able to make that&quot; Rauen said.</p>
<p>Parliament's finance committee will discuss the budget with Waigel next Wednesday -- the day more talks between the coalition and SPD on planned tax reforms have also been set.</p>
<p>Waigel has proposed to cut 30 billion marks in taxes to increase investment and cut high unemployment costs. The timing of the reforms is critical to remove investor uncertainties and help revive economic growth, independent economists have said.</p>
<p>But Kohl's coalition and the opposition Social Democrats still appear to be miles apart from finding a compromise, with leaders from each side calling the other's proposals a catastrophe at the weekend.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.710 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
