<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52350" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Record Eurobourses stilled by U.S. data.</title>
<headline>Record Eurobourses stilled by U.S. data.</headline>
<byline>Eric Meijer</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's major bourses opened at record highs on Friday, celebrating Wall Street's strength and an interest rate outlook based on steady, non-inflationary growth in the United States.</p>
<p>But despite the record levels, trade was set to be quietly steady until U.S. retail sales and consumer price data is issued at 1230 GMT.</p>
<p>Players across the financial markets were looking for confirmation of the subdued inflation trend seen in Thursday's U.S. wholesale price news.</p>
<p>&quot;The crucial factor for the dollar today will be the release of U.S. retail sales and CPI data, which may be decisive in clarifying market views about the outlook for Fed policy after the FOMC meeting,&quot; said Klaus Baader, currency economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Reserve's Open Market Committee meets on Sept 24, and markets are desperately speculating where it will drive interest rates.</p>
<p>Some players believe a 0.25 percentage point rise has already been taken as fact in market prices, while others believe the low U.S. inflation trend and the forthcoming presidential election rule out an imminent interest rate rise.</p>
<p>Leading British shares edged to a record on Friday after Wall Street closed just short of a new high, ending 17 points up. The FTSE 100 pushed 4.8 points higher at the start to 3,937.4, topping its previous best of 3,933.6 set on September 10. Advancers led decliners two to one.</p>
<p>After a mass of results on Thursday, British company news was thin on the ground, with little to deflect attention from the U.S. numbers. Many players were happy for the chance to catch their breath at the end of a busy week, and the market appeared to have settled a little below the highs.</p>
<p>&quot;The London market's just looking ahead to the U.S. figures later on. Trading will be cautious in front of that but I think a lot of people are still short and we'll probably see some covering of positions pushing us higher,&quot; said a trader, who believed some players who had sold expecting prices to fall would instead see them rising.</p>
<p>German shares opened bourse trading around all-time highs, supported by a strong dollar and buoyed by Thursday's U.S. data and strong Dow close.</p>
<p>Dealers said the index could test 2,600 later if the U.S. data due at 1230 GMT was taken positively. The DAX index opened 21.36 points higher at 2,591.68, in line with electronic IBIS DAX which was also at record levels.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 index started on a firmer footing before slipping back to consolidate below Thursday's close.</p>
<p>Operators believed Paris was on a firming trend, but still lagging, as the bull run continued in other major centres.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index was down 4.3 points while the CAC-40 futures contract was down at 2,067 from 2,070 at Thursday's close.</p>
<p>In currencies, the dollar inched up on the yen in morning trading but the market was quiet ahead of the U.S. data.</p>
<p>August consumer prices were seen rising 0.2 percent, the same went for the ex-food and energy index, with August retail sales forecast to rise a bumper 0.7 percent.</p>
<p>The mark edged lower on the European crosses but mark/Paris was steady at 3.4136 against 3.4130 late on Thursday.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 0930 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.5132 marks and 110.25 yen compared with late Thursday's 1.5129 and 110.11.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 0930 GMT</p>
<p>The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares was down 1.2 at 3,931.4.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index was down 3.98 points up at 2,061.39.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt was 19.80 points up at 2,590.12.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold opened slightly firmer at $382.60 vs London close of $381.90. Little impact seen from U.S. CPI.</p>
<p>Silver was back up to $5.04 vs $5.02.</p>
<p>Platinum was down 75 cents to $389.75.</p>
<p>Palladium was up at $122.00 vs $121.20.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
