<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="523733" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AMCOL core segments improve in Q1.</title>
<headline>AMCOL core segments improve in Q1.</headline>
<dateline>ARLINGTON HEIGHTS, Ill. 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>AMCOL International Corp said Monday results for the first quarter showed improvement over year-ago earnings due to better performances in each of its core segments.</p>
<p>&quot;Each of our core segments -- absorbent polymers, minerals and environmental -- reported higher sales and operating profits in year-over-year first quarter comparisons,&quot; John Hughes, president, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Earlier, AMCOL reported first quarter earnings of $0.16 a share, up from $0.06 a year ago. Sales rose to $107.9 million from $85.5 million.  </p>
<p>Absorbent polymers, representing approximately 43 percent of net sales for the quarter, saw a 41 percent increase in sales to $45.2 million and a 71 percent rise in operating profit to $6.6 million.</p>
<p>The minerals segment, which accounted for approximately 36 percent of net sales, had a 14 percent rise in sales to $39.3 million and an operating profit that more than doubled to $2.2 million.</p>
<p>The environmental segment posted a 20 percent rise in sales to $16.6 million and a 31 percent higher operating profit of $929,000. Transportation operations saw a 34 percent rise in sales to $6.9 million and a 38 percent gain in operating profit to $371,000.</p>
<p>Hughes added that the company's newest area, nanocomposites, remains promising.</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to make important strides toward the start-up of a commercial facility in Aberdeen, Miss., during the third quarter of 1997,&quot; Hughes said. &quot;Initially, this facility will be producing a high-purity clay suitable for inclusion in various commercial plastics.  While we look for some sales of the product in 1997, we anticipate that we will not reach gross profit break-even until some time in 1998.&quot;</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25140">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ARLINGTON HEIGHTS, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
