<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="523857" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-IRWIN WINS SENIORS CHAMPIONSHIPS BY RECORD MARGIN.</title>
<headline>GOLF-IRWIN WINS SENIORS CHAMPIONSHIPS BY RECORD MARGIN.</headline>
<dateline>PALM BEACH GARDENS, Florida 1997-04-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hale Irwin posted the largest margin of victory ever at a Senior Tour event on Sunday, a 12-stroke triumph for his second consecutive $1.2 million PGA Seniors' Championship.</p>
<p>Irwin, who held a seven-stroke lead entering the final round of the second major tournament of the year, fired a 68 Sunday to finish at 14-under 274, 12 shots better than Dale Douglass and 1991 champion Jack Nicklaus.</p>
<p>John Morgan, Jack Kiefer and Gibby Gilbert finished tied for fourth at 1-under. Kiefer shot a 70, Gilbert fired a 71, and Morgan carded his second straight 72.</p>
<p>He won $216,000.</p>
<p>Irwin, 51, became the first repeat winner at the event since Sam Snead in 1972-73, before the Senior PGA Tour was formed.</p>
<p>Irwin, a two-time U.S. Open champion, picked up his third victory of the year and his seventh career Senior Tour title and overtook Gil Morgan and David Graham at the top of the money list with $596,531.</p>
<p>The previous-best victory margin at a Senior event was 11 strokes, shared by Arnold Palmer at the 1985 Senior Tournament Players Championship and Orville Moody at the 1988 Vintage Chrysler Invitational.</p>
<p>Irwin started his round strong by eagling the par-5, 539-yard third hole, hitting a 4-wood to the green before sinking a 35-foot putt. Irwin followed that with a birdie on number four after hitting an 8-iron to within three feet of the cup.</p>
<p>After making the turn, Irwin hit a sand wedge on 10 before tapping in for birdie. His only blemish was on 11, where he three-putted for bogey. He also sank a 12-foot birdie putt on 16 before parring the final two holes.</p>
<p>&quot;My hope today was to continue playing the type of game I had been playing, and that was to be aggressive when I felt the need or the situation arose,&quot; said Irwin.</p>
<p>&quot;I wanted to keep it as simple as possible.  There were few major errors. Most of my mistakes came on the putting green, but I just played exceptionally well today, tee-to-green, and I just never let it get away from me.&quot;</p>
<p>Nicklaus recorded birdies on three, five, 12 and 18, and bogeyed two and six for a final-round 70.</p>
<p>&quot;They'll remember who finished second here just beyond tomorrow morning after reading it in the paper,&quot; said Nicklaus. &quot;On Tuesday, if anybody asks you who finished second they won't have a clue.&quot;</p>
<p>Douglass sank birdie putts on three, six, 11, 15, and 18. His only miscue was a double-bogey on 16, giving him a 69 on the day.</p>
<p>Larry Gilbert, who began the day in second place, struggled to a 75 -- his worst round of the tournament -- to tie for seventh with Bob Charles and first-round leader John Bland at even par.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALM BEACH GARDENS, Florida"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
