<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="523975" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: BUDAPEST GRAINS FUTURES SURGE ON CHICAGO.</title>
<headline>BUDAPEST GRAINS FUTURES SURGE ON CHICAGO.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grains futures continued their week-longe surge on the Budapest Commodity Exchange (BCE) on Monday with all eyes on Chicago trends, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rise was certainly not due to domestic fundamentals, as those would not have affected old (1996) crop prices,&quot; said Janos Szolyka of Swap.</p>
<p>Untraded maize prices went higher by the daily allowed 400 forints for all but March and May 1998.</p>
<p>October and December milling wheat accounted for the lion's share of turnover with 785 contracts out of a meagre grains turnover of 918 contracts or 509.6 million forints.</p>
<p>The above two milling wheat maturities saw trade as their price was freed from the daily limit, Szolyka said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody was prepared to sell at limit-up prices as they expect the rising trend to continue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>October milling wheat rose 800 forints per tonne to 26,800 forints and December finished at 27,810, up 810.</p>
<p>Surging milling wheat prices triggered similar movements in other grains, resulting in identically high feed wheat prices for the August maturity at 24,500 forints.</p>
<p>&quot;This was clearly hysteria as feed wheat just is not worth as much as milling wheat,&quot; Szolyka said. The only traded feed wheat maturity was December which rose 5,180 forints to 26,980.</p>
<p>Szolyka added that as yet unconfirmed market rumours of the European Union stopping grains exports could have also contributed to the general surge.</p>
<p>Feed barley went 2,200 forints higher for the only traded maturity, July.</p>
<p>Lot size= 20,000 kgs</p>
<p>($1=180.44 Hungarian forints)</p>
<p>-- Denes Albert, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
