<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52398" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada banks hit new highs on bond rally, buybacks.</title>
<headline>Canada banks hit new highs on bond rally, buybacks.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian bank stocks soared to new heights on the Toronto Stock Exchange on Friday, boosted by a surging bond market and recent share buybacks.</p>
<p>Shares in Canada's five biggest banks hit 52-week highs after tame U.S. inflation reports sparked a rally in North American debt markets.</p>
<p>Bank of Montreal was the heaviest trader, climbing 0.65 to 34.55 in early afternoon turnover of 2.7 million shares. The stock earlier reached a 52-week peak of 34.65.</p>
<p>&quot;Generally speaking, bank stocks look like they are undervalued,&quot; said Nesbitt Burns Inc analyst Hugh Brown.  </p>
<p>&quot;If bond markets rally it makes them more undervalued and that's good,&quot; Brown said.</p>
<p>Canadian bonds strengthened with U.S. treasuries following the release of weaker-than-expected U.S. economic data which calmed fears of an imminent hike in U.S. interest rates.</p>
<p>Recent share buybacks have also spurred bank stocks to record highs.</p>
<p>Royal Bank of Canada was up 0.80 to 37 on 1.4 million shares after earlier reaching a new high of 37.20.</p>
<p>The country's biggest bank announced plans on Thursday for a massive share repurchase totalling about C$1.1 billion.  </p>
<p>Royal Bank is the latest Canadian bank to plan a huge repurchase.</p>
<p>Toronto-Dominion Bank said in July that it planned to buy back up to 10 percent of its common shares. Last November, Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce launched a program to repurchase about five percent of its stock.</p>
<p>&quot;Most banks in Canada are generating excess capital internally. There are various things you can do with it and one of them is share buybacks,&quot; Brown said.</p>
<p>The Royal Bank and TD repurchases are partly intended to offset the dilutive impact of recent acquisitions.  </p>
<p>Bank of Montreal has bought back about five million shares in the current fiscal year ended October 31.</p>
<p>&quot;If we reach a point where we think that we can't productively use all the shareholder equity in the bank, then we would obviously want to return that equity to our shareholders,&quot; said bank spokesman Joe Barbera.</p>
<p>Bank of Montreal's stock was up 0.60 at 34.50 after earlier reaching a new high of 34.65.</p>
<p>Bank of Nova Scotia said it has not made a major share buyback in recent years, due to the fact that its acquisitions have been small with little dilutive effect.  </p>
<p>&quot;This is something that we continually monitor and evaluate, but we don't have any immediate plans to do a buyback,&quot; said Scotiabank spokeswoman Shelley Jourard.</p>
<p>Bank of Nova Scotia's stock was up 1.15 at 36.20 after reaching a new peak of 36.25 earlier in the session.</p>
<p>Among the other bank stocks, CIBC climbed 0.55 to 47.65 following a high of 47.80. T-D Bank rose 0.35 to 27.30 after a 52-week record of 27.45.</p>
<p>National Bank of Canada, the country's sixth largest bank, also rose, but failed to set a new high. National's stock was up 0.10 at 11.65.</p>
<p>-- Darren Schuettler, Reuters Toronto (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
