<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524021" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS UPDATE- APRIL 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS UPDATE- APRIL 21.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press: IMERISIA</p>
<p>--The particularly satisfactory performance of listed Athens Stock Exchange members last year and so far this year has created optimism and laid the ground for the stock market to stabilise at relatively high levels. Banks are leading the offensive but other firms which have seen profits in the first three months of the year have also encouraged investors.</p>
<p>--Lucas Papademos, the governor of the Bank of Greece, is expected to recommend the speeding up of processes for structural changes, specifically the privatisation programme, as well as measures to reform the social insurance system, in his presentation of the bank's report on the course of the economy, tomorrow.</p>
<p>--Eurobank, Ergobank, Bank of Piraeus, Egnatia Bank and Scotiabank are among those wooing the Bank of Central Greece purchase. Arthur Andersen Consulting will have completed its assessment of the bank's standing by the end of the week.</p>
<p>KATHIMERINI</p>
<p>--The new code of conduct approved and signed by National Economy and Finance Minister Yannos Papandoniou recently places new responsibilities on brokerage firms, banks and any firms offering investment services. The new code, it is hoped, will usher in the principle of &quot;pre-emptive&quot; supervision as all the above will be obliged to examine the intentions of orders to buy and sell that they execute on behalf of their cloients. </p>
<p>--The government's two major partners in &quot;social dialogue&quot; between government, unions and employers - the General Confederation of Workers of Greece and the Association of Greek Industries - have criticised the government for its clumsy handling of the agenda for the talks. </p>
<p>--The Governor of the Bank of Greece Lucas Papademos is expected to make his views on economic developments felt tomorrow when he presents the annual report on the course of the Greek economy. Sources says that Papademos will stress the need for structural measures immediately and that long-term economic policy must continue without interruption. Papademos is expected to stress the need to continue with privatisation, reducing the operational costs of state and public administration, interventions in the social insurance and banking sectors and more flexibility in the job market.</p>
<p>TO VIMA </p>
<p>--In four confidential memoranda sent to the newly-established economic crimes squad SDOE, National Economy and Finance Minister Yannos Papandoniou has set out the framework for the conduct of the surprise audits by the &quot;rambos&quot; of the tax department, calling for emphasis on the evasion of the payment of VAT, the illegal distribution of fuel products and illegal exports and subsidies.</p>
<p>--The government has proposed a plan that will see the lay-off of 3,500 workers in a total of seven ailing firms, to make them more attractive to prospective buyers. The speedier privatisations of these firms is a major priority for the government while the preconditions for the reduction of personnel and the status of the unemployed will be discussed during social dialogue with unions and employers. </p>
<p>--Lower interest rates have become a sore point with insurance companies, particularly those in the automobile sector. Brokers say the returns from investments do not exceed 10 percent while they are being called upon to pay interest rates of up to 24 percent. </p>
<p>ISOTIMIA</p>
<p>--The drachma will have to have a clearly lower parity to enter the exchange rate mechanism in 1999, according to Deutsche Morgan Grenfell's report, released last week. This viewpoint will be taken up, sources say, by Bank of Greece's governor Lucas Papademos on Tuesday when he presents the bank's report on the economy. --Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
