<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524040" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain in mental health crisis, psychiatrists say.</title>
<headline>Britain in mental health crisis, psychiatrists say.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's psychiatrists attacked the government's controversial mental health policies on Tuesday, saying services in some parts of the country were close to breaking point.</p>
<p>The Royal College of Psychiatrists blamed a &quot;fundamental failure in the development and implementation of health policies&quot; for a dwindling number of hospital places for psychiatric patients.</p>
<p>Bed numbers had been cut in half in 15 years, the college said in a statement released just over a week ahead of May 1 parliamentary elections in which the opposition Labour Party are favourites to oust the ruling Conservatives.</p>
<p>The college also said the government had not adequately increased community services meant to help patients released from hospitals under its &quot;care in the community&quot; programme, and said there were staff shortages in key areas.</p>
<p>&quot;The current crisis in community care cannot be allowed to continue. If it worsens, many services will become unsustainable in terms of staffing, safety and public confidence,&quot; Dr Robert Kendell, president of the college, said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be a betrayal of vulnerable patients, committed staff and the general public, who pay for mental health services through taxation, to allow this to happen.&quot;</p>
<p>The organisation, which represents psychiatrists across Britain, called on the government to treat mental health with the same emphasis as physical health and to stop hospital closures.</p>
<p>It also demanded better staff training and a review of the &quot;care in the community&quot; programme in which mentally ill patients are released from hospital and eased back into normal life.</p>
<p>Health workers say the Conservative Party's government programme has caused huge problems for hospital accident and emergency units, designated the first point of contact for mental patients released into the community. They say such patients flood in and often attack workers.</p>
<p>Such patients also make up a large proportion of the homeless sleeping on London's streets, community workers say.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
