<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524158" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Anglo, De Beers in Zaire again to see rebels.</title>
<headline>Anglo, De Beers in Zaire again to see rebels.</headline>
<byline>Marius Bosch</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senior executives of South Africa's Anglo American Corp and De Beers Consolidated Mines Ltd were on their third visit to Zaire on Monday in less than a month to talk with Zaire's rebels.</p>
<p>Anglo spokeswoman Charmane Russell said officials from Anglo and its sister company De Beers left for Goma on Sunday to hold talks with Zairean rebel leader Laurent Kabila's AFDL.</p>
<p>&quot;Anglo and De Beers officials are meeting (the rebels) in Goma. We started the dialogue two weeks ago and it is a continuation of that,&quot; Russell said.</p>
<p>She later said the officials would travel on to Zaire's second city and diamond centre of Lubumbashi. &quot;They probably have gone on to Lubumbashi&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously Anglo still has a watching brief in Zaire, we still have one tender outstanding. We are keeping in contact with what is happening in Zaire,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The visit is the third by Anglo and De Beers officials in less than a month, she added.</p>
<p>Anglo submitted two tenders for the development of Zaire's Kolwezi copper/cobalt talings project and another copper project at Ruashi-Etiole near Zaire's copper capital Lubumbashi.</p>
<p>The Kolwezi project was last week awarded by Kabila's rebels to U.S-based America Mineral Fields Inc (AMF) in a $1 billion deal which also included the planned construction of a 200,000 tonne/year zinc smelter at Kipushi.</p>
<p>Russel said Anglo had no knowledge of reports that the tender for Kolwezi was won by AMF in December.</p>
<p>&quot;We dispute that. We say that as far as we are concerned that certainly is not the case. In fact all parties were invited to re-submit their tenders and the final tenders went in again on April 2,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The embattled government of Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko said last Thursday that it was annulling all contracts between Zaire's state-owned Gecamines (Generale de Carriers et des Mines) and AMF because AMF had &quot;violated the regulations governing the signing of mining contracts and conventions&quot;.</p>
<p>Waging a rebellion against Mobutu's government for six months now, Kabila's AFDL is in control of more than half of Zaire including all mineral-producing areas.</p>
<p>An agreement between AMF and Anglo to jointly develop the Kolwezi project, was cancelled earlier this year.</p>
<p>De Beers held a contract with Mobutu's government to buy the production of state diamond company Societe Miniere de Bakwanga (MIBA) and also maintained five diamond buying offices throughout Zaire.</p>
<p>De Beers -- which controls the world diamond trade through the London-based Central Selling Organisation -- pulled staff out of Kisangani in December and from the diamond capital Mbuji-Mayi a few weeks ago.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27-11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
