<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524273" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatia issues amended mass privatisation list.</title>
<headline>Croatia issues amended mass privatisation list.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatia's privatisation authorities on Monday issued a new, slightly amended list of assets for mass privatisation through vouchers nominally worth around 16 billion kuna.</p>
<p>This compares to roughly 18 billion kuna first slated for the scheme over a month ago. But the most attractive assets in leading shippers, hoteliers and food firms remained on the list.</p>
<p>Some companies have since then been dropped out because of ongoing negotiations with potential strategic investors, Privatisation Minister Ivan Kovac told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;There are also firms involved in lawsuits or probes. They will be added to the list later,&quot; Kovac said.</p>
<p>Trying to dispel fears of the scheme's beneficiaries being shortchanged because of this and while other firms are being revalued, he vowed more firms would gradually be included.</p>
<p>The idea is to offer all the assets that have ended up in the state portfolio because they found no buyers as the economy was privatised in the past six years.</p>
<p>But the present list, announced as &quot;final&quot;, seemed likely to suffer further changes before an estimated 350-400,000 beneficiaries get round to swapping their free vouchers for actual shares from this autumn.</p>
<p>To improve the offer for beneficiaries, mostly war victims who could not participate in privatisation before, the government increased the chunk of the popular chocolate maker Kras to 20.5 percent.</p>
<p>It reduced the offered stake in food concern Podravka to only 3.82 percent from the original 18, after Podravka's ownership and capital structure were revised, officials said.</p>
<p>Total holdings that will be available in exchange for vouchers were put at 20 percent of the former socially-owned companies that entered the privatisation process in 1991.</p>
<p>Utilities and banks were exempt from the process and plans to sell some of them, including the Adriatic crude pipeline, posts and telecommunications, are being mulled only now.</p>
<p>The government has since then got rid of most small and medium-sized enterprises through employee buyouts and some public tenders. -- Kolumbina Bencevic, Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
