<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524204" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Rebels say Sudanese air raid stopped Carter visit.</title>
<headline>Rebels say Sudanese air raid stopped Carter visit.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rebels said a Sudan government warplane bombed a southern town on Sunday, preventing former U.S. president Jimmy Carter from landing there to meet a rebel leader.</p>
<p>Sampson Kwaje, a spokesman for the Sudan People's Liberation Army (SPLA), said a MiG-23 plane dropped four bombs in the town of Yei on Sunday during a visit by Carter's advance team of four Americans.</p>
<p>He said the Americans landed at Yei and had been briefed by SPLA leader John Garang before touring the area and saying that they were satisfied it was safe for Carter to visit on Sunday.</p>
<p>Carter was carrying a message for Garang from Sudanese President Lieutenant-General Omar Hassan al-Bashir, Kwaje said, and had permission from the government to visit the town, seized last month.</p>
<p>&quot;The government then sent a MiG-23 which dropped four bombs in Yei town. Ten minutes later an Antonov bomber arrived and hovered around the airstrip and Yei town apparently with the aim of bombing the advance team plane or even Carter's,&quot; Kwaje said.</p>
<p>&quot;President Carter had meanwhile arrived in Lokichokio in northwestern Kenya so the advance team contacted him and warned him not to fly to Yei because it was being raided,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said the advance team then returned to Nairobi and the SPLA was still waiting to hear whether the Antonov dropped any bombs on Yei and whether there were casualties from the raid.</p>
<p>&quot;Our conclusion is they either wanted to make sure Carter did not meet Garang or they wanted to kill Carter,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Carter and Bashir met in Khartoum on Sunday. Sudanese state television said they had discussed bringing more southern rebel groups into a peace agreement with the Islamist government.</p>
<p>Carter arrived in Ethiopia's capital Addis Ababa on Monday for talks with Prime Minister Meles Zenawi aimed at improving frosty relations between Ethiopia and the Khartoum government.</p>
<p>The former president has been trying to bring together the government and SPLA, fighting since 1983 for greater autonomy of the Christian and animist south from the Moslem, Arabised north.</p>
<p>The government signs a peace agreement with small former rebel groups on Monday at a ceremony in Khartoum to be attended by foreign dignitaries. But the SPLA has refused to halt its war and rejected the pact as a sham agreed by rebel traitors.</p>
<p>The peace agreement provides for a general amnesty. The factions which sign will retain command of their forces for a four-year transitional period, under supervision of the armed forces.</p>
<p>The former rebel forces have already become pro-government militias in the south, harassing the SPLA on Khartoum's behalf.</p>
<p>Rebels launched an offensive this month in northeast Sudan they said was aimed at cutting the road from Khartoum to Port Sudan on the Red Sea, Sudan's main commercial link with the outside world.</p>
<p>The Sudanese government has accused Eritrean, Ethiopian and Ugandan troops of taking part in rebel offensives in the south, east and northeast. The three countries have denied the charges.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
