<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524267" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: NATO treaty will dispel Russia's fears-Rybkin.</title>
<headline>NATO treaty will dispel Russia's fears-Rybkin.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A treaty between Russia and the Atlantic Alliance would allay Moscow's fears over NATO's expansion, the secretary of Russia's Security Council said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia's disquiet over NATO's enlargement will be dispelled by the signing of an agreement between Russia and the North Atlantic Alliance,&quot; PAP news agency reported Ivan Rybkin, one of Boris Yeltsin's top security advisers, as saying.</p>
<p>Earlier on Monday Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin said in Prague that Moscow would remain opposed to NATO's eastward expansion even after the agreement was concluded.</p>
<p>Rybkin, who is one a two-day working visit the Poland, made the remark to journalists following a meeting wtih Marek Siwiec, chief of Poland's presidential Bureau of National Security.</p>
<p>&quot;European security is not possible without Russia... We want a Europe without divisions. In a new and changing Europe we should be together,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to conduct a dialogue with our great neighbour to the East,&quot; Siwiec said. There is no better way to clarify doubts than through direct talks.&quot;</p>
<p>Poland, the Czech Republic and Hungary are expected to be formally invited to join the alliance at NATO's Madrid summit this July.</p>
<p>Moscow has repeatedly equated the planned enlargement  with rolling the NATO war machine up to its borders and insists on a separate treaty giving Moscow a say in the alliance's affairs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
