<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524441" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru's Edegel leads stocks to strong close.</title>
<headline>Peru's Edegel leads stocks to strong close.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong interest in electric utility Edegel dominated trading on the Lima Stock Exchange on Monday, leading share prices to a higher close in moderate trade, brokers said.</p>
<p>Market tendency for the rest of the week was seen as mixed, with interest in individual stocks linked to expectations surrounding first-quarter financial results.</p>
<p>According to preliminary figures, the bolsa's General Index rose 0.56 percent to 1,739.36 points while the blue- chip Selective Index  advanced 0.76 percent to 2,557.11 points.  </p>
<p>Turnover was 30.2 million soles ($11.3 million) on 1,715 trades.</p>
<p>Edegel gained 7.38 percent to 1.31 soles on trading of about 5.5 million shares, overshadowing traditional market leader Telefonica del Peru B stock, which slipped 2.48 percent to 6.30 soles on volume of about 900,000 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest in Edegel shares will be ratified in its balance sheets,&quot; said Augusto Larco, an analyst with the Peruval brokerage.</p>
<p>A total of 25 stocks closed higher, 26 lower and 26 unchanged.</p>
<p>Among other leading stocks, mining company Buenaventura rose 1.67 percent to 21.30 soles on trading of about 8,000 shares, Banco de Credito rose 0.43 percent to 4.68 soles on volume of about 40,000 shares, while brewers Backus y Johnston slipped 0.43 percent to 2.29 soles with about 325,000 shares changing hands.</p>
<p>&quot;From next week we will see the market backing the mining, services and banking sectors after the publication of balance sheets,&quot; said Miguel Torres, an analyst with the Finvest brokerage.</p>
<p>((-- Eduardo Orozco, Lima newsroom, 511 221-2130))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
