<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524480" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentina to issue $2.0 bln Bonte treasury bond.</title>
<headline>Argentina to issue $2.0 bln Bonte treasury bond.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's Undersecretary of Finance Miguel Kiguel said Monday the country is planning to introduce a $2.0 billion Bonte treasury bond.</p>
<p>The bond will be sold in tranches, with the first auction, of $500, due May 6. Subsequent tranches will be sold through auctions later in the year.  </p>
<p>Kiguel also said Argentina is expecting to issue a bond denominated in yen during the second quarter, equivalent to about $400 million.</p>
<p>Additionally, the undersecretary said bonds in pesetas amounting to between $80 million and $100 million will be issued before the end of this month.</p>
<p>&quot;This (the Bonte bond) will change our financing strategy a little. Firstly, because it is the first long bond that will be issued through the market-maker system and because it is a long bond of five years,&quot; Kiguel told journalists.</p>
<p>The longest Bonte currently outstanding is two years.  </p>
<p>Kiguel said he had met with market-makers and agreed on the five-year issue. After the auction of the first tranche, he will meet again with the market-makers to agree on subsequent auction dates.</p>
<p>Introducing a five-year bonte is part of the Economy Ministry's financing strategy of lengthening the maturity of its debt portfolio and building up the local market.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be creating a very liquid local bond with this issue,&quot; Kiguel said.</p>
<p>Apart from the Bonte issue, he said the ministry had no plans of issuing in the dollar sector in the second quarter.  </p>
<p>Kiguel said Argentina is also considering an issue in Italian lire. Within 15 days a decision will be made on whether a lira issue will be placed.</p>
<p>Turning to the recent upgrade of Argentina's credit rating by Standard &amp; Poor's to BB from BB-, Kiguel said: &quot;Argentina has all the economic indicators to be investment grade. With luck we could be investment grade within two years -- I would say between two and five years we will be investment grade.&quot;</p>
<p>BB is two grades below investment-grade.  </p>
<p>Kiguel added that some $3.4 billion of debt remained to be raised in the international markets through the year and $2.5 billion in the local market. Of the $2.5 billion, $2.0 billion will be covered by the new Bonte and $500 million by a Letes Treasury bill issue, probably in October.</p>
<p>((--Axel Bugge, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 541 318-0668))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
