<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524418" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: IMF mission in Almaty to examine Kazakh reforms.</title>
<headline>IMF mission in Almaty to examine Kazakh reforms.</headline>
<dateline>ALMATY 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A mission from the International Monetary Fund arrived in Kazakhstan on Monday where it plans to take a look at its $446 million programme in the oil-rich former Soviet republic, a senior fund official said.</p>
<p>The IMF agreed a $446 million Extended Fund Facility last year and approved a first disbursement in January.</p>
<p>&quot;The objective of the mission is to examine progress under the programme,&quot; David Hoelscher, the fund's resident representative in Kazakhstan, told Reuters on Monday.</p>
<p>Under the programme, the government plans to cut annual inflation to 15-17 percent this year from 28.7 percent in 1996. Industrial growth is targeted at about two percent this year against moderate growth of 0.5 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>However, the Kazakh government, desperate to find cash to meet a mountain of unpaid pensions and wages, wants to increase its budget gap to almost 3.7 percent of gross domestic product from 3.16 percent originally planned.</p>
<p>Pension arrears alone officially total 30 billion tenge ($400 million).</p>
<p>Earlier plans to issue a bond on international markets to find the cash are currently on hold.</p>
<p>--Chris Bird, Almaty Newsroom +7 3272 509410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
