<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524515" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru rebels deny prisoner release shortlist.</title>
<headline>Peru rebels deny prisoner release shortlist.</headline>
<byline>Margaret Orgill</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marxist guerrillas holding 72 hostages since December at the Japanese ambassador's home in Lima denied on Sunday they had asked for just 30 jailed comrades to be freed in exchange for their captives' release.</p>
<p>Local media reported the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels had scaled down dramatically their original demand for freedom for about 450 of their imprisoned fighters.</p>
<p>&quot;We understand from radio information that yesterday an article in (the newspaper) La Republica said we have given a list with the names of 30 of our comrades as a priority demand to be released,&quot; MRTA leader Nestor Cerpa Cartolini told Reuters by walkie talkie from within the booby-trapped residence.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to declare this is not true ... This article is pure speculation.&quot;</p>
<p>The rebels are carrying out delicate, behind-the-scenes talks -- via a three-man garantors' commission -- with President Alberto Fujimori on a solution to the hostage crisis, which has dragged on for 124 days.</p>
<p>The main sticking point in the negotiations has been the rebels' demand for the release of comrades held in top security jails throughout Peru.</p>
<p>Fujimori has steadfastly refused to free any convicted fighters, but sources have said he may consider sentence reductions for low-ranking MRTA prisoners.</p>
<p>Red Cross official Michel Minnig and Canadian Ambassador Anthony Vincent, both members of the commission, spent an hour in the residence on Sunday talking to the MRTA.</p>
<p>The captives, who include the Japanese and Bolivian ambassadors, have been held under the gun by about 20 jungle- trained rebels who swarmed into the building during a cocktail party on Dec 17.</p>
<p>Cerpa said the MRTA has decided to limit medical tests on the captives, all middle-aged, to one check-up a week as none are suffering serious health problems.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no serious (health) problems, which is why we are taking this decision that medical checks will only be carried out once a week,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Red Cross doctors had been carrying out daily checks on the prisoners. Many of the captives are said to be suffering from stress-related diseases such as high blood pressure, heart and stomach problems.</p>
<p>An opinion poll released on Sunday showed Fujimori's popularity has plummeted this month with Peruvians disillusioned by the lack of progress in efforts to free the hostages and by a series of scandals in the security forces.</p>
<p>The survey, by pollsters Apoyo, reported that 38 percent of Peruvians approved of the president's conduct when questioned last week, down sharply from his 48 percent rating in the first week of April.</p>
<p>Disapproval of Fujimori rose to 47 percent from 43 percent at the start of the month, according to the poll of 400 people which was broadcast on Panamericana Television. The channel did not give the margin of error.</p>
<p>The hostage crisis, probably the toughest test of Fujimori's seven-year-old government, claimed its first major political victim on Saturday with the resignation of Interior Minister Juan Briones.</p>
<p>Briones, who had held the post since 1991, acknowledged that the dramatic commando-style assault on Ambassador Morihisa Aoki's home had been a major embarrassment for security forces.</p>
<p>&quot;We recognise that there were security lapses in the takeover of the Japanese residence,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
