<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524521" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: INSIGHT-Aussie on edge over crucial wage deal.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT-Aussie on edge over crucial wage deal.</headline>
<text>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>AUS$ S/Term range  *Support *Restnce *RSI-14 *MA-10  *MA-20</p>
<p>US$ *0.7680/0.7820 *0.7720  *0.7785  *45.87  *0.7784 *0.7802</p>
<p>--------------VIEWS FROM THE MARKET - April 22 -----------------</p>
<p>*Offshore range roughly SU$0.7760/7787</p>
<p>*AUD holding onto most of Monday's 1/2 cent gain but unable to crack resistance beyond $0.7785, making analysts cautious</p>
<p>*Clearance of $0.7820 needed to get a true recovery going, otherwise more sideways trading with risk of yet seeing $0.7680</p>
<p>*Verdict on Living Wage case, at 2.00 pm, could stoke speculation the RBA will ease again, or kill the talk entirely  </p>
<p>By 8.00 am (2200 GMT) the local dollar was sitting at US$0.7770/75 having spent the offshore session fidgeting between US$0.7760 and US$0.7785.</p>
<p>It finished at US$0.7765/70 here Monday after rallying from a US$0.7720, a level which had provided good support recently and was seen as the bulwark the bears had to break.</p>
<p>The target for die-hard bulls was US$0.7820, a breach of which would suggest a more meaningful rally was possible to 79 cents. On the crosses, the European currencies were the big movers with the mark gaining at the French franc's expense after the French government called an early election.  </p>
<p>The local dollar softened slightly on the mark but actually fared better than the U.S. dollar which slipped below 1.7000.</p>
<p>It was steady at 97.45/55 yen and traders expected little investor interest this side of the weekend G7 meeting, which might just produce concerted intervention to rein in US$/yen.</p>
<p>All this may change depending on what the Industrial Relations Commission decides on the Living Wage claim. The country's main trade union body has asked for an 8.75 percent increase in award wages and three annual A$20 per week pay rises for the lower paid. The government argued for a rise of just A$8 a week and the court is likely to come down somewhere between.  </p>
<p>The Reserve Bank, for its part, warned that granting the full claim would add over 1.6 percent to annual wages growth and could ultimately force it to tighten policy to keep underlying inflation in the 2-3 percent target band.</p>
<p>The higher the settlement, therefore, the less chance there would be of another rate cut and the more supportive for the dollar. Analysts, however, expect an award of around A$12 a week which would add only a modest 0.5 percent to wages growth. They felt the RBA could live with a result around there and anything lower would provide more scope for an easing should the bank feel one warranted. -- Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
