<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52469" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOZAMBIQUE: Mozambique, World Bank foresee wildlife paradise.</title>
<headline>Mozambique, World Bank foresee wildlife paradise.</headline>
<byline>Iain Christie</byline>
<dateline>MAPUTO 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dream of a giant nature conservation area straddling the Mozambican and South African border has come a step closer to reality with the Mozambican government's approval of a pilot conservation project.</p>
<p>It could pave the way for the biggest protected wildlife paradise in southern Africa, where animals and the steadily rising numbers of tourists who pay to see them could roam at will, over territory bigger than many European countries.</p>
<p>The scheme calls for creation of three transfrontier conservation areas, including a zone bordering South Africa's sprawling Kruger National Park, one of the oldest and largest reserves in Africa.</p>
<p>A second proposed conservation area south of Maputo borders South Africa's Kwazulu-Natal province and the third is on Mozambique's western border with Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>A brief statement published on Thursday in Maputo said the cabinet had approved the project. The proposal is also backed by a World Bank study which calls for $8.1 million in international finance to support it.</p>
<p>The World Bank report says the project as originally conceived in 1991 foresaw a &quot;transfrontier park focusing on the Kruger Park and adjoining parts of Mozambique&quot;, to expand one of southern Africa's most popular tourist destinations.</p>
<p>The conservation area concept just approved would stop short of simply transforming the territory into a vast game reserve.</p>
<p>&quot;These are areas where human and animal populations have traditionally migrated across or straddled political boundaries. The proposed project is based on this principle but expanded to include integrated conservation and economic development in multiple-use areas,&quot; the study says.</p>
<p>&quot;The project will contribute to poverty reduction by assisting local communities inside and around the conservation areas through capacity-building, land security measures and small-scale conservation and development activities.&quot;</p>
<p>The World Bank also sees a chance for Mozambique -- one of the poorest countries in the world -- to cash in on the boom in wildlife and eco-tourism along a border once scorched by war.</p>
<p>&quot;Information on the Kruger Park indicates that demand for nature/wildlife-based tourism could soon begin to outstrip supply. With a total of 700,000 visitors in 1994, occupancy rates of overnight facilities run at over 70 per cent and the park itself is reaching saturation point,&quot; the report says.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAPUTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOZAMBIQUE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
