<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524649" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Fujitsu to raise OEM sourcing of 16 megabit DRAMs.</title>
<headline>Fujitsu to raise OEM sourcing of 16 megabit DRAMs.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fujitsu Ltd said on Monday it will raise the volume of 16 megabit DRAM memory chips it sources from Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co Ltd on an original equipment manufacturing (OEM) basis.</p>
<p>&quot;Our present supply from the company amounts to about 30 percent. By summer, we expect supply of 40 percent or three million units,&quot; said Fujitsu spokeswoman Noriko Kikuchi.</p>
<p>&quot;In Japan, we will shift to the production of 64 megabit memory chips,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Fujitsu currently produces 300,000 64 megabit memory chips per month in Japan and expects to produce 500,000 a month by next September, she added.</p>
<p>Kikuchi said whether this trend will continue depends on the market.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to see what demand will be like for the 64 megabit memory chips and we have to see how persistent demand for 16 megabit chips will be,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Other chipmakers, such as Toshiba Corp and Hitachi Ltd, however, said they are not necessarily aiming to shift production to other sources.</p>
<p>&quot;The price of 16 megabit chips has stabilised. It (OEM supply) is supplementary. We only ask for the amount that is necessary,&quot; said Makoto Ueda, a spokesman for Toshiba Corp. Toshiba receives OEM supplies from Winbond Electronics Corp, a Taiwanese company.</p>
<p>The Japanese business daily Nihon Keizai Shimbun said in its afternoon edition on Monday that Japan's big chip makers were increasing their OEM supplies of 16 megabit chips from foreign manufacturers due to falling domestic prices.</p>
<p>Nihon Keizai added that, in Japan, the companies would concentrate on the production of the higher-priced next-generation 64 megabit chips.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
