<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524851" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Columbia River hydropower dams start spill Monday.</title>
<headline>Columbia River hydropower dams start spill Monday.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Extra spill at Columbia River hydropower projects will begin at 1800 PDT, the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers reservoir control center in Portland, Ore. said Monday.</p>
<p>Under National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS) requirements, spill will account for 30 to 64 percent of total dam discharges, up to certain maximums, with some projects required to spill around the clock.</p>
<p>The NMFS rules, which apply through late June, are aimed at aiding the annual spring migration of endangered salmon and other fish species.</p>
<p>The Corps, which operates most of the federal dams in the Northwest, expects natural spill to quickly reach, and eventually exceed, the NMFS requirements due to this year's high snowpack volumes.</p>
<p>According to the Northwest River Forecast Center, part of the National Weather Service, inflows to regional dams will range as high as 160 percent of normal this spring.</p>
<p>But cooler than normal temperatures have so for limited runoff volumes, although inflows did pick up considerably over the past weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;Flows are zooming up,&quot; said the Corps spokesman.</p>
<p>April 20 is the planning date for spill to start at Columbia River projects, but the actual implementaion was delayed to Monday evening since the request was not received until late on Friday, the Corps spokesman said.</p>
<p>Projects on the Lower Snake River began to implement required spilling on April 10.</p>
<p>--Los Angeles bureau + 1 213 955 6761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I1610107">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
