<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524857" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Citicorp changes puzzle some.</title>
<headline>Citicorp changes puzzle some.</headline>
<byline>Cal Mankowski</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A series of organizational changes at Citicorp has been puzzling to some on Wall Street but a company insider said Monday such changes have been a continuous process stretching back over decades.</p>
<p>One Wall Street analyst noted that William Campbell has moved quickly to consolidate his power since arriving at Citicorp 15 months ago from Philip Morris USA, the domestic unit of Philip Morris Cos Inc. &quot;He's obviously become very powerful,&quot; said the analyst, who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>One Citicorp executive, Roberta Arena, who would no longer report to chairman and chief executive John Reed but instead to Campbell, announced her intention to retire Friday after Campbell, an executive vice president, was put in charge of both the worldwide cards business and the global retail bank. Arena has headed the cards business and reported directly to Reed.</p>
<p>In another change, Alvaro de Souza, who previously headed private banking worldwide, becomes head of U.S. retail banking.</p>
<p>In March, Rana Talwar, who headed branch banking in the U.S. and Europe, quit to join Standard Chartered Plc.</p>
<p>In the shuffle on Friday, heralded by the posting of an internal memo, Shaukat Aziz, moved from a strategic planning job to the slot occuped by de Souza as head of private banking.</p>
<p>A Citicorp spokesman on Monday confirmed the changes which appeared in various newspapers.</p>
<p>&quot;They're solid people taking the new positions, that's what really counts,&quot; said Robert Albertson, analyst at Goldman, Sachs &amp; Co. &quot;I wouldn't expect any impact on the stock price.&quot; Citicorp is rated a global priority list buy at Goldman, Sachs.</p>
<p>Last week, Citicorp announced a reorganization of its wholesale banking business, which combined capital markets and trading, corporate finance and cross-border finance under a single product management unit.</p>
<p>A Citibank source said that in such a huge organization with 90,000 people one had to be careful about drawing conclusion from any one change. He said such organizational refinements have been going on for years.</p>
<p>As for Campbell specifically, the source said he was brought in because Reed, an outside director at Philip Morris, thought he was the right person to help Citicorp build a strong consumer brand.</p>
<p>As for the oft-raised question of succession at Citicorp, the source said while no one has been designated heir-apparent the company has a number of internal candidates who could be tapped when Reed approaches the mandatory retirement age of 65.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
