<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52491" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Srebrenica refugees bitter at voting conditions.</title>
<headline>Srebrenica refugees bitter at voting conditions.</headline>
<byline>Zoran Radosavljevic</byline>
<dateline>TUZLA, Bosnia 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bosnian Moslem refugees who fled the village of Srebrenica amid reported massacres denounced imminent elections in which they can briefly go home to vote as a deceit and a humiliation.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a big deceit, made by the world, deliberately or not,&quot; Fatima Husejnovic, leader of the Srebrenica women's association, said on Friday.</p>
<p>Srebrenica, a small Moslem enclave in eastern Bosnia, became notorious in July last year when it was overrun by Serb forces who expelled all women and children.</p>
<p>Up to 8,000 Srebrenica men are still unaccounted for and many are feared to have been killed in Serb ambushes while trying to reach Bosnian government territory over wooded hills. Others are believed to have been captured and executed elsewhere.</p>
<p>Serbs have meanwhile re-populated the town. Former Moslem residents, now housed in and around Tuzla, will be allowed to cross ceasefire lines on Saturday and vote in the small village of Podravanje, near Srebrenica.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a complete humiliation,&quot; Husejnovic said. &quot;They are doing this so the world thinks there is freedom of movement in Bosnia but they send us to a chetnik stronghold,&quot; she said. &quot;Before the war we had polling stations in Srebrenica town.&quot;</p>
<p>Chetnik is the name for nationalist Serb militia.</p>
<p>War crimes investigators on Thursday found piles of human bones, skulls and clothes buried at a farm in northeast Bosnia. They believe the mass grave will provide evidence of a massacre of Srebrenica Moslems.</p>
<p>Bosnia's first post-war elections on Saturday are intended to create a democratic basis for a country comprising a Serb entity and a Croat-Moslem federation, in the form of a three-member presidency, a multi-national parliament and separate federation and Serb assemblies.</p>
<p>The Dayton peace treaty, which envisaged the election, promised two million Bosnian refugees the right to return to their homes before voting. But nationalist authorities have blocked them from coming back, sealing the results of ethnic cleansing and military conquest.</p>
<p>Instead the refugees, comprising almost half the electorate, were given the right to go back to their homes on strictly defined routes only for an hour or so on Saturday and vote.</p>
<p>&quot;We would like to go and vote, but in our town, Srebrenica, not a remote village surrounded by woods...I don't think a lot of people will go tomorrow,&quot; said Sead Omerovic, member of a refugee electoral commission in Tuzla.</p>
<p>&quot;First we were supposed to return home and vote later. Now it looks as if we are being forced to vote for something we don't understand, in a place we don't like,&quot; he said. &quot;Therefore I will vote here in Tuzla.&quot;</p>
<p>A member of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), which is charged with organising and supervising the elections, said he did not know who decided the Moslems should vote in Podravanje.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it was suggested by the local (Serb) electoral commission in Srebrenica,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TUZLA, Bosnia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
