<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524932" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: KCBT wheat ends mostly lower in erratic dealings.</title>
<headline>KCBT wheat ends mostly lower in erratic dealings.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>KCBT hard red winter wheat futures reversed in late trading and dropped to a mostly lower close in erratic dealings pending a more accurate determination of crop losses due to a recent freeze in the U.S. Great Plains hard red winter wheat region, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It will still take two weeks to settle on the guesstimates of freeze losses,&quot; a trader said. &quot;You can hear everything and anything and that's why the market was so erratic.&quot;</p>
<p>Fresh 10-month highs were set early on concerns about harsh weather in several key wheat producing regions.</p>
<p>Some traders said a report that U.S. Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman said there was no damage to the Kansas wheat crop north of Interstate 70 may have weighed on the market.</p>
<p>Advances in early trading were led by flooding in the northern U.S. spring wheat growing region, persistent reports of crop losses from a recent freeze in the U.S. Great Plains hard red winter wheat region and apparent worsening drought conditions in key European wheat growing areas.</p>
<p>Nearby May set a new 10-month high of $5.14 per bushel, just below the $5.17 set on June 18, 1996. The contract high for May of $5.75 was set on May 8, 1996.</p>
<p>A new contract high was set early in the day in the September at $4.98, above the previous high of $4.81 set Friday.</p>
<p>KCBT hard red winter wheat futures closed five cents lower to one cent higher, with May down five at $4.94-1/2 and July down 1-1/2 at $4.79-1/2.</p>
<p>Traders cited the loss in Kansas City in its spread relationship with Chicago soft red winter wheat and Minneapolis spring wheat futures.</p>
<p>&quot;This has forced the market to look at the world situation, especially French wheat and U.S. spring, and I think this is why Chicago and Minneapolis gained on Kansas City today,&quot; a trader said. &quot;It's a fast track in here and very erratic, very emotional.&quot;</p>
<p>KCBT wheat futures volume was estimated at 66.925 million bushels, above the 61.850 million traded Friday.</p>
<p>((Sam Nelson 312-408-8721))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
