<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524981" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bond group faults state plan to protect investors.</title>
<headline>Bond group faults state plan to protect investors.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The main trade group for bond underwriters and dealers on Monday faulted a rule written by a group of state securities regulators it says would put too much of a burden on dealers.</p>
<p>The Public Securities Association said it &quot;strongly opposes&quot; a model suitability rule proposed by the North American Securities Administrators Association that aims to protect investors from being sold risky and unsuitable investments.  </p>
<p>&quot;Introducing a new state suitability rule would add to, rather than ameliorate, the complexity, cost and interpretive difficulties that arise due to conflicting state, federal and self regulatory requirements,&quot; the bond group said in an April 18 letter submitted to the state group.</p>
<p>The state regulator group proposed the rules in March, amidst highly publicized losses including Orange County, Calif.'s bankruptcy, which resulted from investments in speculative and volatile government securities.  </p>
<p>&quot;Recent state and municipal fiascos involving unsuitable purchases of derivatives, either directly or through mutual funds, warrants attention to more than the needs of the individual investor,&quot; the state group said in its rule.</p>
<p>The state group is not going to formally consider the rules with its members until November at the earliest, a spokesman there said.  He said the association has delayed consideration because it wants everyone to have a fair chance to provide input.  </p>
<p>The rule calls on dealers to determine whether or not the customer understands the product it is being sold.  Dealers must also ensure that the product is suitable for that customer.</p>
<p>PSA faulted the rule for not distinguishing between institutional and retail customers.  &quot;A broker-dealer would be capable of conducting a suitability analysis only if the broker-dealer had complete knowledge of the institution's portfolio,&quot; the bond trade group wrote.  </p>
<p>Its latest stance is no surprise since members of the dealer community have historically opposed the adoption of suitability rules fearing such a move would put too much onus on dealers and expose them to potential lawsuits.</p>
<p>In fact, a dealer group under the auspices of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York early next month will resume work on model language that would in effect do the opposite of the state regulator document. Called the Principals and Practices for Wholesale Financial Market Transactions, the dealer document would clear dealers of any suitability obligation when dealing with institutional customers.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, this document has not been received warmly by the investment community, including state and local government groups which fear investors would have little legal recourse from rogue brokers pushing unsuitable investments.</p>
<p>((-- Joanne Morrison (202-898-8399))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
