<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524904" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - prices down 1/8 to 1/4.</title>
<headline>U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - prices down 1/8 to 1/4.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Municipal bond prices ended down 1/8 to 1/4 point Monday, while on the new issue side Lehman Brothers said it may postpone a $932 million Port Authority of New York and New Jersey deal until next week.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very quiet today,&quot; a municipal trader said. &quot;It's a Monday. I don't think anyone has any idea where this market is going. We have a decent calendar, so everyone waits for the calendar.&quot;</p>
<p>Even without the Port Authority's deal, which may be delayed to allow institutional investors more time to review sales documents, several other big deals are slated, among them a $543 million New York City Municipal Assistance Corporation deal.</p>
<p>The offering, expected through JP Morgan Securities Inc on Wednesday, has a one-day retail order period set for Tuesday.</p>
<p>Also Wednesday, Goldman Sachs &amp; Co is expected to price s $500 million Chicago School Reform Board of Trustees offering.</p>
<p>On the competitive side, Florida is expected to sell $300 million of Department of Environmental Protection revenue bonds through competitive bidding at 1100 EDT Tuesday.</p>
<p>A trader said while some municipal bond funds apparently have money to spend, they are waiting to see which direction the market takes.</p>
<p>&quot;I think once there's some direction, you'll see the money spent whether it's on the upside or the downside,&quot; he said. &quot;They're just unsure. We have a few accounts that are making a bet that it's going down.&quot;</p>
<p>The trader said he tended to agree with those accounts given the Federal Reserves' apparent &quot;tightening mode.&quot;</p>
<p>Back in Monday's muni cash market, a municipal analyst said high grades ended slightly weaker overall, with longer issues worsening by about two basis points. Dollar bonds closed down 1/8 to 1/4 point, and secondary activity was light.</p>
<p>In debt futures, the June Municipal contract closed down 7/32 at 112-19/32. The June T-bond contract closed down 11/32 at 107-21/32. The MOB spread was 158 ticks.</p>
<p>In the government cash market, the benchmark 30-year bond closed down 14/32 at 94-8/32 to yield 7.09 percent.</p>
<p>--Kathie O'Donnell, 212-859-1655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
