<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525026" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Plaintiff testifies at Fla. Reynolds trial.</title>
<headline>Plaintiff testifies at Fla. Reynolds trial.</headline>
<dateline>JACKSONVILLE, Fla 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dana Raulerson, a smoker who sued R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co. because her sister died of lung cancer, took the witness stand Monday and described her sibling as a heavy smoker even as a teenager.</p>
<p>&quot;Jean, from the very beginning, smoked one cigarette after another,&quot; Raulerson said. &quot;Sometimes I'd see her light one right off the other.&quot;</p>
<p>Raulerson, 42, filed a wrongful death lawsuit against R.J. Reynolds on behalf of the estate and three children of Jean Connor, who died of lung cancer in October 1995 at age 49. The trial is now in its third week.</p>
<p>Raulerson said she remembered entering her sister's bedroom as a child and seeing her play-acting as a smoker, trying to achieve the perfect pose using a pencil for a cigarette.</p>
<p>Raulerson, who smokes a pack a day of Players, a Philip Morris Cos. Inc. brand, did not mention and was not asked about her own pack-a-day smoking habit. She has been using a nicotine patch since the trial began.</p>
<p>One of her attorneys, Greg Maxwell, guided Raulerson through details of her sister's financial affairs, an apparent attempt to lay the groundwork for damages should Reynolds be found liable.</p>
<p>Raulerson said Connor made almost $31,000 as a bank manager in 1994, her last full year of work, and faced a lien of nearly $16,000 for unpaid medical expenses.</p>
<p>Reynolds' lawyer Steve Werber asked Raulerson during a brief cross-examination whether she had discussed with her sister the possible consequences of smoking.</p>
<p>&quot;My sister was pretty much resigned to the fact that she had to smoke, she needed to smoke,&quot; Raulerson said. Werber did not ask Raulerson about her own smoking.</p>
<p>Werber pointed out that Connor quit smoking several weeks before her diagnosis with cancer because she wanted to have plastic surgery and her surgeon refused to do it unless she quit.</p>
<p>&quot;She used the nicotine patch to help her ... and three weeks later she was told she was going to die,&quot; Raulerson said.</p>
<p>The jury also heard from Valerie Dizor, the oldest of Connor's three children. She said her mother smoked constantly and ashtrays were a part of the decor in their home.</p>
<p>&quot;She always had a cigarette in her mouth ... somtimes she forgot she had one (lighted) in the ashtry,&quot; Dizor, a non-smoker, said.</p>
<p>Dizor, 32, recalled her mother's final days, when Connor weighed less than 100 pounds.</p>
<p>&quot;The last words she said were 'I love you,' and she barely got that out,&quot; Dizor said.</p>
<p>The plaintiffs were scheduled to call an advertising expert to the stand later Monday and expected to wrap up their case by midweek.</p>
<p>Reynolds is a unit of RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JACKSONVILLE, Fla"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
