<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525134" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Centre-right would win French election now - poll.</title>
<headline>Centre-right would win French election now - poll.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's ruling centre-right coalition would lose about 160 seats but retain a parliamentary majority if a general election were held now, an opinion poll published on Monday showed.</p>
<p>The SOFRES poll, in the daily newspaper Le Figaro, appeared hours before President Jacques Chirac announced he was dissolving the National Assembly and calling an early parliamentary election for May 25 and June 1.</p>
<p>The survey, conducted last Thursday and Friday, found the Gaullist-dominated coalition would retain 318 of the 478 seats it now holds in the 577-member Assembly elected in 1993.</p>
<p>It would therefore hold onto a comfortable lower house majority, the poll of 1,000 adults found.</p>
<p>Some 60 percent of voters said they had already made up their minds who to vote for, while 40 percent said they could still change their minds.</p>
<p>The poll indicated the following breakdown in seats if an election were held now: centre-right coalition 318; Socialists, ecologists and other non-communist left-wing groups 208; Communists 27 and rightist National Front (FN) two.</p>
<p>France's electoral system is such that the FN has no seats in the assembly now despite commanding the votes of up to 15 percent of the electorate.</p>
<p>Another poll released on Monday showed support for the governing centre-right coalition rose by one point while the left's standing was stable.</p>
<p>A coalition of Chirac's Gaullist Rally for the Republic and the centrist Union for French Democracy would take 40 percent of the vote, up one percentage point from two weeks earlier, the poll by Louis Harris for Valeurs Actuelle showed.</p>
<p>The Socialists would take 26.5 percent of the vote, a 0.5 percentage point increase, the poll showed.</p>
<p>The Communist Party's showing fell by one point to nine percent and left-of-centre environmentalists rose 0.5 points to 8.5 percent in the standings. Two percent would vote for the extreme left party, unchanged from the previous poll.</p>
<p>The combined left of centre parties would reach 46 percent of the vote.</p>
<p>The sampling of 951 people taken on April 18 and 19 showed that Jean-Marie Le Pen's far-right National Front would receive 14 percent of the vote, down one point.</p>
<p>Twenty percent of those questioned said they had not decided who to vote for and 31 percent of those expressing a preference said they could still change their mind.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
