<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525156" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: South Korea delegation leaves four-power talks.</title>
<headline>South Korea delegation leaves four-power talks.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's top negotiators in the proposed four-way peace talks were flying back to Seoul on Monday evening, a spokesman for the country's mission to the United Nations said.</p>
<p>Ji Won Suh said he hesitated to call his delegation's exit a &quot;rupture&quot; of the meetings but he said any further sessions would be held on a working level and would include diplomats from South Korea's Washington embassy.  </p>
<p>&quot;They are flying back, all of them,&quot; he said of the South Korean officials. &quot;They (North Korea) must have realized we cannot regard the so-called acceptance in principle with all those preconditions about four-way talks,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The United States said earlier it would not consider North Korea's demands for food until Pyuongyang clarified its stance on the porposed negotiations, which have been delayed in New York since last Wednesday.</p>
<p>Both U.S. negotiator Charles Kartman and his South Korean counterpart said earlier on Monday they were ready to enter into senior-level talks with the North Korean delegation.</p>
<p>The aim was to hear North Korea's reply to a year-old United States-South Korean proposal for four-party peace talks that would finally close the books on the 1950-53 Korean War and replace a fraying armistice with a peace treaty.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
