<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525237" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French new-crop wheat rises on weather, Chicago.</title>
<headline>French new-crop wheat rises on weather, Chicago.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>French new-crop wheat prices were firmer on Monday amid mounting worries over potential drought damage and surging U.S. wheat prices, dealers said.</p>
<p>During morning trade wheat sold for delivery in Rouen between August and December was paid at 935 francs per tonne, excluding carrying charges, up 10 francs on Friday. But only very small volumes were being traded.</p>
<p>In the afternoon buyers were only bidding 930 francs per tonne for the same delivery period.</p>
<p>Wheat for July delivery to the southwestern port of La Pallice was paid at 950 francs per tonne, unchanged from Friday. There is no carrying charge for July.  </p>
<p>A three-month dry spell has raised fears of drought among French farmers, pushing government officials to impose partial irrigation bans in some departments.</p>
<p>On Friday French weather forecasters predicted another five days without rain.</p>
<p>&quot;Lack of rain and Chicago's rise continue to support the market,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>On Monday concern over freeze damage in hard red winter wheat areas and flood losses in spring wheat areas were pushing U.S. wheat prices higher.</p>
<p>French old crop wheat prices were stable. April delivery into Rouen was bid at 930 francs per tonne and May delivery at 925 francs. Both prices exclude carrying charges.</p>
<p>French milling wheat futures on MATIF were also firmer with the May 97 expiry quoted at 955 francs per tonne, up five francs. Total trade was 22 lots at 1510 GMT.  </p>
<p>French domestic grains are traded on a &quot;July basis,&quot; reflecting their underlying value without the twice-monthly carrying charges which must also be added for delivery periods between August 1 and the end of each July/June crop year.</p>
<p>For 1996/97, the charges are as follows (francs per tonne).</p>
<p>				 1st half	2nd half</p>
<p>    August			3.64	    7.27</p>
<p>    September		  10.91	   14.54</p>
<p>    October		    18.18	   21.81</p>
<p>    November		   25.45	   29.09</p>
<p>    December		   32.72	   36.36</p>
<p>    January		    39.99	   43.63</p>
<p>    February		   47.26	   50.90</p>
<p>    March			54.53	   58.17</p>
<p>    April			61.81	   65.44</p>
<p>    May			  69.08	   72.71</p>
<p>    June			 76.35	   79.98</p>
<p>--Paris newsroom +331 4221 5146</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
