<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525294" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Gujral to take oath as prime minister.</title>
<headline>India's Gujral to take oath as prime minister.</headline>
<byline>Jawed Naqvi</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Inder Kumar Gujral, a scholarly 77-year-old expert on foreign affairs, was set to be sworn in on Monday as India's fourth prime minister in a turbulent political year in the world's biggest democracy.</p>
<p>President Shankar Dayal Sharma was due to administer the oath of office to Gujral, foreign minister in the outgoing United Front government, at 10 a.m. (0430 GMT) in the ornate sandstone presidential palace.</p>
<p>Gujral's appointment as India's 12th prime minister followed three weeks of political upheaval triggered by the Congress party's shock decision last month to withdraw vital support to the 10-month-old centre-left government.</p>
<p>Congress has pledged support to Gujral.</p>
<p>Question marks still lingered over the intentions of a powerful regional constituent of the ruling coalition and the future of the federal budget for 1997/98 (April-March).</p>
<p>A United Front spokesman said outgoing Finance Minister P. Chidambaram, one of the architects of India's economic liberalisation programme and the author of the pathbreaking budget, was certain to retain his job.</p>
<p>But Chidambaram's Tamil Maanila Congress party, piqued at being passed over during wrangling over a successor to caretaker Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda, vowed to pull out of the government while still supporting it in parliament.</p>
<p>A senior United Front official said the coalition was confident of mollifying its sulking constituent before the new cabinet was sworn in on Monday.</p>
<p>Gujral was to face a vote of confidence in the lower house of parliament, the Lok Sabha, on Tuesday at 11 a.m. (0530 GMT), a senior parliamentary official told Reuters.</p>
<p>A scholar with deep experience in foreign affairs, the goatee bearded Gujral was assured victory in the vote as he was backed by the United Front's 178 lawmakers as well as by Congress's 140 in the 542-member lower house.</p>
<p>The parliamentary official, who asked not to be identified, said the Lok Sabha would convene at 11 a.m. (0530 GMT) on Monday and quickly adjourn after paying tribute to veteran political leader Biju Patnaik, who died last week.</p>
<p>Representatives of all political parties were to meet Speaker P.A. Sangma later on Monday to decide when parliament would take up the budget for the 1997/98 fiscal year that began on April 1.</p>
<p>Parliament had been scheduled to discuss the budget this week, but it was not clear whether the formation of a new government would delay consideration of the tax and spending plan which sparked a stock market rally after it was introduced in February.</p>
<p>The United Front and Congress are united perhaps only in their opposition to the largest single party, the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party, which has 193 seats.</p>
<p>The BJP held power for 12 days last May but its leader, Atal Bihari Vajpayee, stepped down as prime minister after failing to muster enough support to win a vote of confidence.</p>
<p>He had succeeded P.V. Narasimha Rao, who quit after his Congress party suffered its worst defeat ever in general elections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
