<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525377" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka stocks end up on strong buying demand.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka stocks end up on strong buying demand.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lankan stocks closed sharply higher on Monday on strong buying interest for the limited quantities os shares available for sale, brokers said.</p>
<p>The all share index continued its rise to end 26.8 points up at 747.8. Price gains led declines 55 to 11.</p>
<p>Development Finance rose 20 rupees to 295 rupees, Hayleys 14.25 to 236.25, National Development Bank 25 to 260 and Aitken Spence 9.75 to 160.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone's quite bullish. There was buying interest across the board,&quot; said Ajit Wanigasekera of Ceylinco Stock Brokers.  </p>
<p>&quot;But volumes were fairly thin because sellers were absent,&quot; Wanigasekera said.</p>
<p>Turnover, supported by 86,000 shares of Hayleys at 236 rupees and 10,300 of Development Finance at 295, was 82.5 million rupees.</p>
<p>&quot;Though profit-taking has already set in, the lack of sellers is holding prices firm. Its a good sign for the market,&quot; Wanigasekera said.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel no need to take profits immediately as we expect the market to climb to the latter half of the 700 range,&quot; said Gihan Rajapakse of CTC Eagle Fund Management.</p>
<p>-- Colombo newsroom (941) 434319</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
