<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525501" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AT&amp;T Q1 headcount up, offsetting down-sizing.</title>
<headline>AT&amp;T Q1 headcount up, offsetting down-sizing.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>AT&amp;T Corp said its increased hiring of customer support staff for marketing of new services and for wireless operations boosted headcount to 134,000, a net rise of 3,600 jobs during the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>The quickened pace of hiring more than offset reductions resulting from the company's ongoing, three-year restructuring plan announced January 2, 1996, the company said.  </p>
<p>To date, 6,100 employees have left the company, primarily in backoffice, corporate support staff functions as part of the plan to reduce the workforce by 17,000 over three years.</p>
<p>Of the 6,100, about 3,500 accepted voluntary buyout offers, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been up-sizing faster than down-sizing since the middle of last year,&quot; said Burke Stinson, an AT&amp;T spokesman, resulting in net increases in employment during each of the last three quarters.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T weathered stiff public criticism by unions and others during 1996 for the plans to slash employment levels. But newly created jobs have more than offset job cutbacks.</p>
<p>The company had 128,400 jobs in its continuing operations at December 31, 1995, a few days before the restructuring plan was announced. By December 1996, the total was 130,400, Stinson said.</p>
<p>The figures do not include staffing levels at businesses that have been sold or spun-off such as AT&amp;T's undersea telecoms cable operations, which it sold to Tyco International Ltd for about $850 million earlier this month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
