<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52557" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania court adjourns Briton baby smuggling case.</title>
<headline>Romania court adjourns Briton baby smuggling case.</headline>
<dateline>ORADEA, Romania 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Romanian court on Friday adjourned for the seventh time the trial of John Boast, a British charity worker accused of smuggling babies out of the country.</p>
<p>Boast's lawyer asked for more time to study a second charge that he bought a two-year-old girl for $60 and took her out of Romania illegally last June for adoption in Britain.</p>
<p>Boast was first arrested in February and charged with complicity in smuggling a 15-month-old baby girl to Britain. He was banned from leaving the country and given bail.</p>
<p>He was re-arrested in May and jailed for the second alleged offence and appeared in the court in the northwestern town of Oradea on Friday handcuffed and wearing prison clothing.</p>
<p>Presiding judge Dumitru Marc adjourned the hearing until October 11.</p>
<p>If found guilty, Boast faces up to five years in prison for the first offence and an additional three years on the second count.</p>
<p>Boast, 46, a self-appointed charity worker from the village of Great Harwood near Accrington in Lancashire, has been visiting Romania since the 1989 revolution, bringing truckloads of humanitarian goods mainly for abandoned children.</p>
<p>Romania determined to crack down on its image as an easy source of children for childless westerners after thousands of babies were taken legally and illegally from gruesome orphanages after the revolution.</p>
<p>British couple Adrian and Bernadette Mooney were tried and convicted in 1994 for trying to smuggle a baby girl out of Romania hidden in their car. Their two-year jail sentence was suspended after President Ion Iliescu intervened.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ORADEA, Romania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
