<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525588" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries open unchanged, tight ranges seen.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries open unchanged, tight ranges seen.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries opened largely unchanged on Monday, with the market expected to stick to narrow ranges amid a dearth of economic news.</p>
<p>Activity is expected to be very light, as the combination of no data and the start of the Passover holiday at sundown is seen keeping most players on the sidelines.</p>
<p>&quot;People are going to be trying to leave early so I imagine we don't do a heck of a lot,&quot; said a head trader at a primary dealership. &quot;The only catalyst that could move us is if the dollar weakens more.&quot;  </p>
<p>In early trading, the 30-year bond was unchanged at 94-22/32 to yield 7.05 percent.</p>
<p>Treasuries had been a bit weaker in the Tokyo and London session during the night, as the dollar came under pressure. Market participants reported light selling overseas in two- and five-year notes.</p>
<p>But the market is said to be lacking direction. Treasuries, for the most part, rallied last week as bond-bullish economic news triggered waves of short-covering, bringing yields down to levels not seen since right after the Federal Reserve raised interest rates in late March.  </p>
<p>Given that the market did so well last week, market participants are unsure what the next trade will be.</p>
<p>&quot;We're still in a rate rising mode, so we can't rally forever,&quot; said the trader.  &quot;Most people have a short bias.  We have to squeeze everyone out.&quot;</p>
<p>Since there are still shorts that may still need to be covered, which could spark another mini-rally.</p>
<p>Yet, the market faces a challenge the next two days in the way of supply.  On Tuesday, the Treasury will sell $17 billion of two-year notes, followed by $12.5 billion of five-year notes on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>LaVorgna, like mamy others, believes the 30-year bond is locked in a 7.00 to 7.25 percent range for the time being. So, since the bond is at the lower end of that range, &quot;the market is ripe for a tape bomb,&quot; in which the market could get caught off guard by hawkish comments from Fed officials.</p>
<p>The lone piece of data on this session's schedule is the March federal budget figure, due at 1400 EDT/1800 GMT. The deficit is seen falling to $30.7 billion, from a $44.01 billion deficit in the prior report, according to a Reuters poll.  </p>
<p>Many agreed that the current levels of 6.42 percent on the when-issued two-year note and 6.72 percent on the when-issued five-year note are too expensive, which, in turn, could push the market down.</p>
<p>&quot;We're now near the highs of the last couple weeks, and given the fact we had a runup last week, it certainly seems that there would be concessions,&quot; said Joe Lavorgna, financial market economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.  &quot;We are still in a bear market.  A lot of people are making the bet that the Fed goes another 50 basis points in the next eight months, which keeps the market under pressure in the short term.&quot;  </p>
<p>Also, Fed vice chair Alice Rivlin is slated to speak at the Employment Policy Foundation's wage and productvity forum in Washington D.C. at 1300 EDT/1700 GMT.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the three-month bill was up one basis point at 5.16 percent, while the six-month and year-bills were unchanged at 5.40 percent and 5.59 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>Two-year notes were unchanged at 99-24/32, yielding 6.39 percent. Five-year notes were up 1/32 at 99-21/32 to yield 6.71 percent, and 10-year notes were up 1/32 at 95-30/32, yielding 6.82 percent.</p>
<p>(( -- Steven Scheer, N.A. Treasury Desk 212-859-1867))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
