<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525623" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Isis starts antisense drug trial.</title>
<headline>Isis starts antisense drug trial.</headline>
<dateline>CARLSBAD, Calif. 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Isis Pharmaceuticals said on Monday it started a multi-center, pivotal quality trial of its ISIS 2302 antisense inhibitor in Crohn's disease, a form of inflammatory bowel disease.</p>
<p>The randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial would enroll 300 patients with steroid-dependent Crohn's disease and would be conducted at about 40 clinical trial sites throughout North America and in Europe, Isis said.  </p>
<p>ISIS 2302 is an antisense inhibitor of a cell adhesion molecule implicated in a range of inflammatory disease and conditions, the company said. It is in Phase II trials in four indications in addition to Crohn's disease, Isis said.</p>
<p>The principal clinical endpoints of this trial were remission, defined as a Crohn's Disease Activity Index score of 150 or lower, and reduction in steroid dependency, Isis said. The trial would take about 18 months to complete and an interim analysis in early 1998 could form the basis for initiation of a second pivotal trial, it said.</p>
<p>In February, Isis presented positive data from a placebo-controlled Phase II trial of ISIS 2302 in Crohn's disease.</p>
<p>This trial would enroll patients with moderately active Crohn's disease who are steroid dependent if they have been off immunosuppressive or experimental drugs for at least 30 days and meet other inclusion criteria, it said.</p>
<p>((New York newsdesk 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARLSBAD, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
