<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525736" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: U.S. Treasuries idle in London ahead of auction.</title>
<headline>U.S. Treasuries idle in London ahead of auction.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries traded in London were steady on Monday, although there were some indications that investors are eyeing switching positions out of Europe into the U.S., traders said.</p>
<p>While analysts said this could be a good trade, they said there was further downside potential in Treasuries before a rally emerges.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a tempting idea, but I think it's premature,&quot; said Teis Knuthsen, international economist at First Chicago in London. &quot;The next big bull market is likely to be the U.S, but there will be further losses before they go up.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. 30-year long bond at 94-21 in London by 1025 GMT, yielding 7.057 percent compared with 94-21 in Tokyo and 94-22 at the New York close.</p>
<p>June T-bond futures were up 2/32 at 108-02 in automated trade.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's holding in quite well,&quot; said a trade at a French house in London. &quot;But there's a very light calendar this week, with only the auction providing much interest.&quot;</p>
<p>No major data were scheduled for release this session, and the market was expected to trade in a narrow range, traders said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Treasury will auction $17.0 billion of two-year notes on Tuesday, and $12.5 billion of five-year notes on Wednesday. Later on Monday $12.0 billion of three- and six-month paper will be auctioned.</p>
<p>&quot;There is unlikely to be any problem absorbing this supply,&quot; said Knuthsen. &quot;There may even be a relief rally afterwards.&quot;</p>
<p>Treasuries were unlikely to rally until monetary policy was tighter, he said although downside could be limited.</p>
<p>He said the one to two year lag in the economy's reaction to a rate hike meant that the quarter percentage point rise seen in March was not expected to do much to cool the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;It will take more than a quarter-point to stop the U.S. supertanker,&quot; he said. &quot;I expect the Fed funds to be at 6.0 percent by the year end.&quot;</p>
<p>Fed funds rate is currently at 5.50 percent.</p>
<p>In the futures market, the trader said some investors had closed out their call options around the 108-00 level on Friday. There is some upside potential to 108-09, and if it gets through there then it will test 108-16, and 109-00.</p>
<p>-- Lisa Wilson, International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6137</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
