<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525790" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Dubai air cargo demand jumps, lifting rates.</title>
<headline>Dubai air cargo demand jumps, lifting rates.</headline>
<byline>Hilary Gush</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>After a slow start to the year Dubai's air cargo market has turned the corner, with business picking up strongly and rates moving up in tandem, a Reuters survey shows.</p>
<p>The survey shows that rates to central Europe and the United States have risen by up to three percent in the past six weeks.</p>
<p>Buoyant demand from Europe, particularly for summer fashions, and rate increases by some carriers introduced with summer schedules are behind the higher tariffs, forwarders, airline managers and sales agents said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is robust. It is back up again after the drop in February during Ramadan and the first Eid,&quot; said a forwarder.</p>
<p>&quot;Things have been going in the right direction, we have seen increases in the yield and prices,&quot; Emirates airline's cargo revenue optimisation manager Pradeep Kumar told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We have recovered from whatever we suffered in the first half of 1996,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Last year was a bad one for ex-Dubai air cargo and business did not improve in the first few months of 1997, exacerbated by the Moslem fasting month of Ramadan, followed by the Eid al-Fitr holiday and the Chinese New Year, which fell almost simultaneously.</p>
<p>&quot;It's booming all around,&quot; said Lufthansa Cargo Arabian peninsula cargo manager Dieter Oppel. &quot;Demand is high now, especially for summer wear for shopping malls in Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>Last month Lufthansa Cargo introduced a four to five percent rate increase out of Dubai, lower than Lufthansa increases in the rest of the world, Oppel said.</p>
<p>&quot;Being a high-capacity and low-rate market, there was no increase to the United States. We did it selectively to central Europe,&quot; Oppel added.</p>
<p>Forwarders and airlines said the market had managed to catch up on any delays caused by recent transport strikes in India.</p>
<p>&quot;It had some impact, but as the strike was so short-lived we have already caught up,&quot; said the operations manager of a large Dubai forwarder in reference to the two-day Indian air traffic controllers strike which was called off on April 12.</p>
<p>The strike had disrupted domestic and international flights and stranded thousands of passengers.</p>
<p>&quot;We made contingency plans by speeding up clearance and delivery to customers in Dubai so the wait was cut. The main impact was on goods coming from the Far East with routing over India, which were delayed,&quot; the forwarder said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our problem was that we did not get any space on the European sector,&quot; said the export manager at another Dubai forwarder, adding that the cargo was booked on carriers transiting Dubai from the Far East.</p>
<p>&quot;We had around 25 tonnes which had to wait in the warehouse for two days before we made alternative plans and put it on another carrier to Europe,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A 10-day strike by Indian truck owners which ended on April 9 affected sea-air cargo movements though Dubai.</p>
<p>Issa Baluch, managing director of forwarders Swift Freight, said there had been a delayed impact of the truckers strike.</p>
<p>&quot;There was an impact on all exports from India. Sea-air shipment dropped, with just a few bits and pieces coming through,&quot; he said, adding most of the affected sea-air shipments were textiles destined for central Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever was delivered to the port area before the strike, came through,&quot; Baluch said, adding there had been a backlog of new bookings.</p>
<p>Sea-air freight is an important part of air cargo shipments out of Dubai. Goods are brought in bulk by sea from the Indian subcontinent and Far East, and are then broken down into smaller packages and sent by air mainly to Europe and the United States.</p>
<p>The sea journey from Bombay to Dubai takes around four days.</p>
<p>Operators said recently higher air freight rates in India could cause a swing higher in Dubai sea-air volumes, which fell consistently in the past year. In March they dropped 25 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Sea-air has fallen over the last year because rates from the source (India) were very low so there was no benefit in using the sea-air movement. Now prices have increased, low value cargo might move back by sea-air,&quot; Emirates' Kumar said.</p>
<p>Reuters calculations put the average rate on shipments to London Heathrow up 13 fils on the early March figure at 4.20 dirhams. Similarly, the average rate to Frankfurt is also firmer at 4.20 dirhams.</p>
<p>To the United States, rates are slightly higher, with an average of 6.50 to JKF from 6.45 a kg six weeks ago, and the rate to Los Angeles at 7.60 dirhams from an average 7.50.</p>
<p>&quot;Our demand is so great to Europe, we don't sell that much to the U.S. market,&quot; Emirates' Kumar said.</p>
<p>To the Far East, the average rates to Singapore and Hong Kong remain flat at four dirhams a kg.</p>
<p>The average rate to Nairobi is also unchanged at 4.15.</p>
<p>&quot;There is good overall demand which we expect will continue. Usually business slows down from May to September, but this year I think we will have good demand throughout, maybe only with a slight slowdown in June/July,&quot; said one airline official.</p>
<p>Forwarders and shippers also expect more airlines to announce the scrapping of fuel surcharges, which have been applied since last November. Last week Dubai-based Emirates said it would drop the surcharge from the UAE from April 16. - Dubai newsroom +9714-626990</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DUBAI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
