<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525765" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Beirut market makes strong start to week.</title>
<headline>Beirut market makes strong start to week.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Beirut Stock Exchange made a strong start to the week after public holidays on Monday with two of the three listed bank shares continuing a price rally amid heavy demand.</p>
<p>Newcomer Bank of Beirut rose to $3.5 from $3.375 bringing its spectacular rise since its April 11 debut to 61 percent over issue price.</p>
<p>Demand for BOB remained high at 1,207,095 but about half Wednesday's 2,543,875. Supply was 253,372 shares, all of which were sold.</p>
<p>&quot;It was an excellent start,&quot; Deputy Manager at Beirut finance house Lebanon Invest Alain Balian told Reuters.</p>
<p>Financial markets closed on Thursday and Friday for the Moslem Eid al-Adha holiday.</p>
<p>Banque Libanaise pour le Commerce rose to $15.5 from $15.125 while Banque Audi was unchanged at $20.</p>
<p>Both shares were in heavy demand and dealers said this would sustain the rise in prices. Demand for BLC totalled 71,374 against a supply of 17,406 while demand for Audi was 50,642 shares against 21,000.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand obviously still exceeds the supply in bank shares. Therefore a further price rise is expected,&quot; Balian said.</p>
<p>BLC and Banque Audi have jumped 38 percent and 33 percent respectively since they made their debuts on December 30 and January 20.</p>
<p>&quot;The parameters are still the same as last week. There are still few alternatives to bank shares and more and more people will continue to get into the market,&quot; Balian added.</p>
<p>A block of 46,015 BOB shares traded on the floor at $3.5. A block of 772 BLC shares traded on the floor at $15. Another block of 20,806 BLC shares traded off the floor at the same price.</p>
<p>The LIBX bank index rose 2.05 percent to 133.78. The BLOM general index rose 0.07 percent to 914.19 and the LISPI rose 0.07 percent to 87.81.</p>
<p>Solidere A and B shares were unchanged at $10.25 and $10.75 respectively.</p>
<p>Eternit rose slightly to $2.0312 from $2.0 on turnover of 10,000 shares. Ciments Libanais was unchanged at $1.2812 on turnover of 20,000 shares.</p>
<p>Total BSE turnover was 451,342 shares compared with 340,813 shares on Wednesday. Value was $2,656,960 from $2,290,210.</p>
<p>There was no trade in Ciments Blancs and Uniceramic.</p>
<p>-Beirut editorial (9611) 745308 602057</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
