<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52582" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: ING Barings upgrades Egis profit forecast.</title>
<headline>ING Barings upgrades Egis profit forecast.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>ING Barings upgraded the net profit forecast of Hungarian pharmaceuticals company Egis Gyogyszergyar Rt and rated its shares as &quot;buy&quot; in a company update.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on the excellent 1H96 figures we have slightly upgraded our net profit forecast from 5.8 billion forints to 6.0 billion forints,&quot; Gabor Sitanyi, London-based analysts for ING Barings said in the September issue of the securities house's &quot;Eastern European Equity Insights&quot; publication.</p>
<p>&quot;This translates into a new 1996 EPS (earnings per share) of 774 forints and a PER (P/E ratio) of 13.2 times.&quot;</p>
<p>The profit was upgraded based on the H1 figures, released on August 7, although the seasonality of the pharmaceutical business means that relatively low turnover and earnings can be expected in the third quarter, Sitanyi added.</p>
<p>&quot;Our recommendation reflects Egis' long-term competitive advantages, as a marketing -- rather than research-oriented -- vertically-integrated, low-cost, generic drug producer,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While Egis' 1996 domestic sales will be characterised by the usual seasonality, export growth remains encouraging in Eastern Europe, Sitanyi said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident that Egis will achieve its target for export sales of $75 million to $80 million in 1996, helped in 4Q96 by the first contribution from the recently acquired Medimpex network in the countries of Commonwealth of Independent States.&quot;</p>
<p>Egis is majority owned by France's Servier S.A. which acquired a 51 percent stake in it last December.</p>
<p>On the Budapest Stock Exchange Egis closed at 11,100 forints on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
