<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525851" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live and feeder cattle seen steady to higher.</title>
<headline>CME live and feeder cattle seen steady to higher.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME live and feeder cattle futures were expected to open steady to 0.200 cent per lb higher, livestock analysts said.</p>
<p>Although initial indications on Friday's monthly USDA Cattle-on-Feed report were neutral, analysts noted that the marketing figure shows feedlot marketings are current. This current status and the discount futures hold to cash, basis June, should lend support. Placements were also under the average of analysts' pre-report estimates, analysts said.</p>
<p>However, lower boxed beef values Friday and expected slow feedlot trade early this week will curb futures gains, they said.  </p>
<p>Friday's cattle on feed report showed April 1 on-feed supplies at feedlots with 1,000 head or more capacity in the seven key states at 107 percent of a year ago versus the average estimate of 107.6 percent. Marketings in March were 101 percent of a year earlier versus the average estimate of 100.6 and placements tallied 102 percent versus 103.3 percent.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle were also expected to show strength, stemming from a higher CME feeder cattle index and continued underlying support from heavy death losses in the Dakotas linked to recent storms and flooding. But higher corn indications may limit any advance, analysts said.</p>
<p>The latest CME feeder cattle index was up $0.37 at $70.85 per cwt.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
