<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525822" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. rescue workers spot pieces from missing plane.</title>
<headline>U.S. rescue workers spot pieces from missing plane.</headline>
<byline>Judith Crosson</byline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-04-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Several pieces of metal protruding from the snow in the Rocky Mountains are &quot;likely&quot; parts of a U.S. warplane that mysteriously disappeared 18 days ago during a routine training mission, an Air Force official said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is our collective judgment that what we have seen is likely to be A-10 aircraft pieces,&quot; Maj.-Gen. Nels Running told a news conference in Eagle, Colorado.</p>
<p>However, Running said there were no signs that the remains of the pilot, Capt. Craig Button were nearby. Because only a few metal pieces were seen, it was not possible to tell what direction the plane was coming from, Running said.</p>
<p>He said there was probably no danger that anyone would reach the four 500-pound (225-kg) conventional Mark 82 bombs the plane was carrying, but that retrieving them would be &quot;one of our prime areas of concern.&quot;</p>
<p>Rescue workers have only viewed the pieces from the air because the area known as the New York Range is so remote, but the metal spotted at an altitude above 12,500 feet (3,810 metres) appeared to be from the plane's interior. &quot;It looks to us military,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rescue workers have flown over the area before, but possibly because of deep snow had not been able to see anything. Running said a new strategy was followed to dispatch helicopters at &quot;near hover&quot; to closely examine the mountain wall.</p>
<p>Running described the pieces spotted as &quot;metal in nature&quot; with gray paint. He said in several areas where the metal was bent it was possible to see the type of &quot;yellowish-greenish&quot; paint used to prevent metal from becoming corroded.</p>
<p>He said weather will determine when it will be possible to approach the rugged cliff and confirm the plane is the missing aircraft. &quot;There is no way to get there easily,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While it must still be confirmed that the pieces come from the missing plane, Running said that radar and other sensors had pointed Sunday to the area where the metal was spotted by a Colorado Air National Guard pilot.</p>
<p>On April 2, the A-10 Thunderbolt broke away from the rear of a three-plane formation during a routine training mission that left Davis-Monthan Air Force Base near Tucson, Arizona.</p>
<p>Air Force officials have been at a loss to explain why Button, 32, left the mission.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
