<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525946" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Infant growth stock market a success-German bourse.</title>
<headline>Infant growth stock market a success-German bourse.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German stock exchange said on Monday the two firms pioneering its fledgling growth stock market had seen notably high share turnover in the first month and stuck to its goal of attracting 20 firms to the scheme.</p>
<p>Mobilcom, a mobile phone service provider, and engineering firm Bertrandt AG both outperformed the over-the-counter market in terms of share activity since taking part in New Market's launch on March 10, the bourse said.</p>
<p>Mobilcom, perhaps predictably attracting more attention because of the high-profile sector to which it belongs, even outdid the MDAX midcap index on transaction numbers.</p>
<p>Modelled on New York's Nasdaq and linked with Nouveau Marche of France, the New Market scheme aims to match small and mid-sized innovative firms with investors willing to accept an element of risk for potential high yields.</p>
<p>The scheme calls on companies to follow more rigid listing and transparency rules than is the norm and in return offers them advice and publicity as well as the services of a so-called &quot;guardian&quot;, similar to a market maker.</p>
<p>According to the first data released on the scheme, turnover in Mobilcom, whose initial listing coincided with the start of the New Market, averaged 18.56 million marks ($10.9 million) a day in the first month, matching volumes among mid-cap index firms.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Bertrandt's turnover was 2.5 million marks, six times higher than the over-the-counter average trades to which the firm would normally be confined.</p>
<p>&quot;The guardians, who offer tradeable prices on inquiry, have more than fulfilled their duties,&quot; the bourse said.</p>
<p>Mobilcom took 66th place in terms of turnover among all listed German shares while Bertrandt had 136th place, the bourse added. Daily transactions in Mobilcom were nearly twice the MDAX norm at 619 versus a mid-cap average of 357.</p>
<p>Issued at 62.50 marks, Mobilcom's shares have almost doubled in price since March 10 to trade at 117.50 marks on Monday.</p>
<p>But Bertrandt, which already traded in Frankfurt before the New Market start, was on Monday at 82.95 marks, having traded in early March just above 90 marks.</p>
<p>In its statement, the bourse said it did not wish to comment on potential new participants in the scheme and was in any case prevented by law from doing so.</p>
<p>&quot;The bourse is sticking by its goal to admit 20 firms to the New Market in (the first) year,&quot; it said. The exchange has in the past said a 20-strong quota was needed to establish a full growth stock index.</p>
<p>--Catherine O'Mahony, Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.703 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
