<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525907" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: French election risks more EU treaty uncertainty.</title>
<headline>French election risks more EU treaty uncertainty.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Gaunt</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A decision by French President Jacques Chirac to call an early parliamentary poll would throw another question mark over European Union treaty negotiations that are already in suspended animation over Britain's election.</p>
<p>Although the debate in France over Europe is nowhere near as polarised as it is in Britain, EU diplomats say an election conducted as the 15-member bloc prepares for a new treaty and a single currency cannot help but confuse the situation.</p>
<p>&quot;Just the mere fact that they have elections and an election campaign means it will be more uncertain where we go,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Chirac was expected to announce an election later on Monday in a bid to secure a parliament that would push through economic measures needed to qualify for economic and monetary union (EMU)</p>
<p>It was not certain on what day an election would be held, but under any scenario it would be over by the June 15 deadline the EU has set for itself to complete the inter-governmental conference (IGC), the bloc's treaty review.</p>
<p>IGC negotiators have been playing a waiting game for most of this year, keeping needed compromises and decisions on treaty changes back until after Britain's general election.</p>
<p>Britain's Labour Party, expected to win the May 1 poll, is considered less antagonistic to the EU than many in the ruling Conservative Party.</p>
<p>Diplomats said they did not expect French elections to change much at the IGC. Most key French negotiating positons are on the table, they said, and the real decisions will not be taken until the Amsterdam summit on June 16-17.</p>
<p>But some expressed concern that as in Britain's election, French politicians could make Europe an campaign issue.</p>
<p>&quot;We're likely to see...slightly more 'Eurosceptic&quot; positions by French candidates. There is a slight risk that this might feed into French negotiating positions,&quot; the diplomat said.</p>
<p>An IGC negotiator said a &quot;hardening&quot; of French positions was possible.</p>
<p>French Socialist leader Lionel Jospin has already taken a more sceptical view of the single currency and the Communist Party can be expected to oppose further transfer of powers to Brussels.</p>
<p>In the IGC itself, France has taken a number of firm positions, for example, over the need to cut the number of European commissioners.</p>
<p>Other countries have put much of this down as negotiating gambits. But an election fought around the need for France to retain a tough stance in Europe could limit Paris' ability to step back when the negotiations call for it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
