<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="526065" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish centrists to quit alliance if EMU chosen.</title>
<headline>Swedish centrists to quit alliance if EMU chosen.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's Centre Party, part of an alliance supporting the minority Social Democratic Party government in parliament, said on Monday it would stop cooperating if the government tried to enter the Economic and Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>Centre Party leader Olof Johansson told a party meeting: &quot;The consequence (of the government saying it would join EMU) would probably be that the chances of cooperation would be weakened and we would separate.&quot;</p>
<p>Johansson said his party would not support a change in Sweden's constitution to permit a single European currency without a referendum.</p>
<p>The government relies on the Centre Party's support for crucial economic and social legislation. Centre Party support is not necessary for EMU participation as the main opposition Moderate Party supports it.</p>
<p>The Social Democrats are split on the issue. Prime Minister Goran Persson has said the party leadership will take a decision this spring.</p>
<p>Political analysts say Persson has been unable to persuade the party to accept EMU and that he is unlikely to announce Sweden will join, instead saying that Sweden will join at a later, unspecified date.</p>
<p>Analysts say Persson may use a May Day speech on May 1, when left wing ideals are traditionally flown high, to announce his view on Swedish EMU membership.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
