<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="526098" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: French election reignites political doubts on EMU.</title>
<headline>French election reignites political doubts on EMU.</headline>
<byline>Henry Engler</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>French parliamentary elections, likely to be called on Monday, will either put Europe's planned common currency firmly on track or provoke more doubts about the project, analysts say.</p>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac is widely expected to call early elections on Monday evening for late May or early June instead of March 1998 as originally scheduled.</p>
<p>If the centre-right coalition clearly holds on to power, it would win an almost free hand for tough budget policies before economic and monetary union's (EMU) planned launch in 1999 and much-needed economic reforms thereafter.</p>
<p>But a strong performance by the Socialists, committed to EMU but opposed to big budget cuts, could cast doubt on the project as a launch would be unthinkable without France -- the main power behind EMU along with Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;If the current majority wins the election the probability for monetary union to start on time is even higher,&quot; said Patrick Mange, economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in Paris.</p>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl's recent decision to stand for re-election in 1998 has bolstered expectations that the single currency, the euro, will begin on schedule.</p>
<p>Recent technical decisions by European Union finance ministers on the blueprint for the euro have also restored confidence in the process.</p>
<p>But with Chirac likely to announce early polls in an address to the French nation, political uncertainty has once again been injected into the EMU process.</p>
<p>Analysts and officials are particularly worried that the Socialists and far right might win a large percentage of parliamentary seats. This would weaken the government's position and fuel doubts on financial markets over austerity measures.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is cohabitation then that's obviously not very good,&quot; said a senior EU official. Cohabitation is the French term for having the president in one party and the lower house of parliament dominated by another.</p>
<p>Many experts believe France will have to raise social security charges in the next few months to cut its 1997 budget deficit close to three percent of gross domestic product -- the Maastricht treaty's target for EMU. The finance ministry denies this.</p>
<p>Under a strong right-wing coalition, higher charges should pose no problem. But the task is likely to be much harder if the right has to negotiate with a hostile opposition aware of weakening public support for EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;In a situation where the governing coalition loses the election, it's extremely difficult to assess the consequences,&quot; said Olivier Davanne, co-director for research at Goldman Sachs in Paris.</p>
<p>Socialist leader Lionel Jospin sternly opposes any additional budget cuts at a time of high unemployment. In a television interview on Sunday he noted that Germany itself was struggling to meet the EMU budget target.</p>
<p>&quot;If to respect the criteria of three percent -- which Germany will probably not respect -- if to do that we have to impose, with the jobless rate we have...a new cure of austerity on the country my answer is no,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But as the Socialists also believe monetary union is in the best interests of France and Europe, some economists believe they could take a more flexible stand on budget cuts to meet EMU criteria in future.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
