<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="526152" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - British business press - April 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - British business press - April 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>-- VICKERS AXES DONATIONS TO THE TORIES</p>
<p>Engineering group Vickers has not renewed the 55,000 stg donation it made to the Conservative Party in 1995. Its annual report shows that there were no political donations last year, and a spokesman said it would not be funding the party in 1997 either. The decision follows news that 100 former corporate donors have axed their contributions since the last election.</p>
<p>-- PFI BOND PACKAGE TO EXTEND M SIX</p>
<p>The M Six motorway extension will be funded by a major bond issue under the government's private finance initiative. A 370 million stg PFI deal to build, design, finance and operate the road from Carlisle to Glasgow for 30 years was awarded to the Autolink consortium of construction groups Amey, Sir Robert McAlpine and Taylor Woodrow. Supporters of PFI say that efficiencies from the private management of the road will make it a cheaper method of funding.</p>
<p>-- CNN IN ADS DEAL WITH LONDON FIRM</p>
<p>The American TV group CNN is to announce that it has selected Sky Sites, a London-based company, to sell the advertising on a special channel broadcasting to air travellers. Sky Sites, formally part of Lord Hollick's MAI group and now owned by French advertising group Havas, believes that airports provide a captive audience of the type of consumer deemed attractive to advertisers.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>-- CREST FACES STERNEST TEST AS ALLIANCE AND LEICESTER FLOATS</p>
<p>The company behind the new stock exchange paperless electronic share settlement system, CrestCo, is claiming to be confident that the system would survive the floatation of Alliance and Leicester. It admitted that the real test will come next Monday when trades are signed off under the five-day settlement rule. Up to 2.2 million new shareholders have the opportunity to sell their shares immediately.</p>
<p>-- CO-OP COULD FACE ONE BILLION STG BID THIS WEEK</p>
<p>Entrepreneur Andrew Regan hopes to have his 1.15 billion stg bid for parts of the Co-operative movement in place by the end of the week. He and his bidding vehicle Galileo face a large legal problem and have until tomorrow to provide information in the High Court of any confidential information on the Co-op obtained from two of its executives who were suspended last week. The judge must then rule that the bid can go ahead.</p>
<p>-- BUSINESS READY FOR A LABOUR GOVERNMENT</p>
<p>Separate surveys from the Institute of Management and Dun &amp; Bradstreet, the business information company, suggest that business believes that the Labour Party will form the next government, and captains of industry are not worried about the prospect of Labour in power. The findings are the first significant figures to support the general business view that while business does not want Labour to win, it expects it to do so.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>-- CORDIANT PLANS THREE-WAY SPLIT</p>
<p>Cordiant, the advertising group founded by the Saatchi brothers, is to split into three groups in an attempt to boost shareholder value and raise standards of service to clients. Investors will be offered shares in the two main advertising groups, Saatchi &amp; Saatchi Advertising Worldwide and Bates Worldwide. Zenith Media is to be split out and owned by the two groups. The future of other group companies, including public relations firm Rowland Worldwide, is unclear.</p>
<p>-- PRIVATISING PENSIONS WOULD NOT COST ANYTHING SAYS THINK TANK</p>
<p>A report by the Adam Smith Institute suggests that state pensions could be privatised immediately at no extra cost to any generation because National Insurance contributions are six times higher than they need to be. The right-wing think tank claims that all future generations would be up to five percent better off if employees saved for their basic pension through private savings schemes.</p>
<p>-- SETBACK FOR CWS PREDATOR</p>
<p>Allied Irish Banks, which was on the verge of concluding a deal to pay 300 million stg to Andrew Regan's investment vehicle Galileo for the banking arm of the Co-operative Wholesale Society, have pulled out of the deal. The banking group became uneasy by the injunction CWS gained against Regan and then by the Co-op's disclosure that it was investigating a two million stg payment made by Regan to an account in the Cayman Islands.</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>-- INSURERS MAY COUGH UP FOR TOBACCO INDUSTRY LAWSUITS</p>
<p>Tobacco industry leaders have begun secret talks with anti- smoking lobby lawyers in the hope of getting immunity from litigation. The insurance industry could face massive claims from tobacco manufacturers seeking to spread the 300 billion dollar cost of settling the large amount of lawsuits in US courts. The compensation will be spread over 25 years and is equivalent to a quarter of the US tobacco industry's annual revenues.</p>
<p>-- BSKYB AND BT SET FOR LANDMARK DIGITAL DEAL</p>
<p>Industry sources claim that BSkyB, the pay-television business which is 40 percent owned by Rupert Murdoch's News International, has announced an agreement with British Telecom. It will create a new company, called Interactive Services Company, to subsidise the cost of set-top boxes that enable viewers to decode digital programme signals. BSkyB will also pledge to offer a digital service before the end of the year despite the delays to the launch of the Astra satellite.</p>
<p>-- UNILEVER FACING REBELLION OVER 800 MILLION STG PENSION FUND SURPLUS</p>
<p>Anglo-Dutch consumer goods giant Unilever is facing a rebellion by pensioners over an 800 million stg pension fund surplus. The Committee of Unilever Pensioners plans to challenge the company's decision to use 300 million stg of the surplus from the fund to pay for a contributions holiday. The pensioners have also complained that they have no representation on the fund's 12-member board of trustees.</p>
<p>($1 = 1.64 stg)</p>
<p>For more information, phone BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
