<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="526402" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs end a bit higher on short-covering by dealers.</title>
<headline>JGBs end a bit higher on short-covering by dealers.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key June 10-year Japanese government bond futures contract ended slightly higher on Monday due to short-covering by dealers, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Traders showed little inclination to trade actively today,&quot; said a trader for a city bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>The June rose slightly on short-covering by dealers prompted by the firmness of cash JGBs and also by the need for position adjustment, the trader said.</p>
<p>The June ended at 126.91, up slightly from Friday's close of 126.85.</p>
<p>Turnover was 17,862 contracts.  </p>
<p>Traders said the market would be focusing on a 10-year JGB auction scheduled on Tuesday, and the possible launch of a straight bond by Tokyo Electric Power Co Inc (TEPCO) later this week.</p>
<p>Traders said the coupon rate of the new issue of 10-year JGBs was likely to be set at a record low of 2.3 percent.</p>
<p>There may be solid demand from investors despite the low coupon rate if the new issues are offered at under par, traders said.</p>
<p>TEPCO is likely to launch about 150 billion yen to 200 billion yen worth of 10-year straight bonds, traders said.  </p>
<p>The transition to a &quot;T-plus-three&quot; rolling settlement system, in which JGB transactions are settled three business days after the trade date, may be contributing somewhat to the firmness of cash JGBs, traders said.</p>
<p>T-plus-three settlement went into effect starting with JGBs traded on Monday. JGB transactions were previously settled seven days after the trade date.</p>
<p>The shorter settlement period may be making dealers reluctant to sell cash JGBs short and may be encouraging buy-backs of cash JGBs, the trader for a city bank's securities unit said.  </p>
<p>The benchmark 182nd JGB yield stood at 2.145 percent as of 0648 GMT, down slightly from Friday's close of 2.155 percent.</p>
<p>Comments by Bank of Japan governor Yasuo Matsushita during a speech opening a two-day meeting of BOJ branch managers on Monday were in line with his previous statements and had little effect on the market, traders said.</p>
<p>Matushita said a temporary slowdown of the economy was inevitable due to the effects of fiscal tightening measures. But Matsushita said that, taking into account positive signs in production, incomes and spending, it was highly likely that the economic recovery would continue after this setback.  </p>
<p>Taking into account such conditions in the economy, it was appropriate for the BOJ to maintain its present monetary policy, Matsushita said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to carry out monetary policy putting emphasis on strengthening the basis for the economic recovery,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Masayuki Kitano, Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-5473-3748</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
