<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="526543" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore shares steady early amid thin volume.</title>
<headline>Singapore shares steady early amid thin volume.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Singapore stock market was firmer early Monday but in thin volume.</p>
<p>Dealers said rises were checked by jitters over Singapore's March non-oil domestic exports, scheduled for release at noon as well as by Sunday's bearish retail sales figures.</p>
<p>A poll of economists by Reuters last week called for domestic non-oil exports to decline 4.5 percent. Economists were uniformly negative with some suggesting a double digit fall.</p>
<p>The benchmark Straits Times Industrials Index (STII) was up 13.87 percent at 2,057.07, helped by institutional buying after the market recovered from striking 25-month lows last week.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade is flat and volumes don't suggest anything except that people are sidelined,&quot; a local brokerage dealer said.</p>
<p>He added overall consensus was for domestic exports to post negative four to 10 percent for March.</p>
<p>Singapore markets were closed on Friday for a public holiday and some of the morning's momentum was attributed to a rise in the Dow on Friday and firmer Malaysian share prices.</p>
<p>Top gainers were Creative Technology, up Singapore 80 cents (US$0.56) to S$19.30 and SPH, up 30 cents to S$12.50 after posting a 9.2 percent half-year profit of S$172.38 million last Thursday.</p>
<p>US$1.00=S$1.44</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
