<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="526681" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Finland - April 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Finland - April 21.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the leading stories in Finnish papers this morning.</p>
<p>HELSINGIN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen supports second Finance Minister Arja Alho's proposal to abolish stamp duty on bank loans, but says he also understands Fininance Minister Sauli Niinisto's concern about the state finances. The issue will be discussed by the government, he says.</p>
<p>- Violence among girls has increased in Finnish schools and the working climate has deteriorated, says school councellor Mervi Mehtio. @</p>
<p>- The Central Organisation of Finnish Trade Unions (SAK) will present today a 26-point programme with proposals to improve employment, for example by cutting income taxes.</p>
<p>- A majority of Finnish-speakers support the country's bilingualism and see the Swedish language as an essential part of society, a Taloustutkimus study shows.</p>
<p>- State alcohol monopoly Alko's subsidiary Primalco will start producing vodka in Poland next week in cooperation with Polish Polmos Zyrardow. @</p>
<p>DEMARI</p>
<p>- President Martti Ahtisaari's popularity has risen; 48 percent of Finns now satisfied with him, poll shows.</p>
<p>TURUN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Finland's national ice hockey team beat the Czech Republic 2 to 1 in Prague on Sunday.</p>
<p>AAMULEHTI</p>
<p>- The Swedish-speaking population is turning into a quiet minority which hides its language, and the group thus causes the main threats against itself, professor Erik Allard said. @</p>
<p>KAUPPALEHTI</p>
<p>- The cooperative banking group has the smallest balance sheet buffers against risk and Alandsbanken has the biggest, comparison of banks shows.</p>
<p>- Stone houses for about one billion markka are expected to change hands this year, survey shows.</p>
<p>- The price of art and antiques is on the rise in the wake of flats and stocks.</p>
<p>- Food industry is mixed about the use of the swan-flag to label domestic goods. @</p>
<p>- KT-Tietokeskus' shareholders decided to change the comapany name to Novo Group and authorise the board to issue new shares representing 13.6 percent of the capital, but managing director says it is premature to talk about a listing.</p>
<p>- Metal industry lobby is considering combining Finnish outstanding claims from Russia into larger packages to be sold internationally, official says.</p>
<p>HUVUSTADSBLADET</p>
<p>- A television campaign has inspired Finns to buy more Finnish goods, a poll by Taloustutkimus shows.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki Newsroom +358-9-680 50 242, news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
