<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="526701" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: New India PM Gujral promises to strengthen reforms.</title>
<headline>New India PM Gujral promises to strengthen reforms.</headline>
<byline>Jawed Naqvi</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's new Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral, a Marxist-turned-social democrat, promisd on Monday to press ahead with open-market economic reforms and pursue peace talks with old foe Pakistan.</p>
<p>Gujral, talking to reporters after he was sworn in by President Shankar Dayal Sharma as the country's 12th prime minister since independence in 1947, said he was confident he would be able to persuade former finance minister P. Chidambaram to join his cabinet.</p>
<p>Chidambaram's regional Tamil Maanila Congress (TMC) party decided on Saturday not to join the new government after the United Front coalition passed over its party chief, G.K. Moopanar, for prime minister in favour of Gujral.</p>
<p>&quot;All the economic policies of the previous government will continue and be strengthened,&quot; Gujral said as he had tea with Sharma at the ornate British-built Presidential Palace.</p>
<p>Asked if his new job would help improve ties with Pakistan, Gujral, foreign minister in ousted prime minister H.D. Deve Gowda's government, said: &quot;All the foreign policy intiatives will continue.&quot;</p>
<p>Gujral said he would keep both foreign and finance ministry portfolios. Politicians said the new prime minister was hoping Chidambaram, popular among investors and an outspoken proponent of liberal economics, would return soon to his old job.</p>
<p>But officials close to the goateed, 77-year-old leader said he was likely to continue to keep the foreign affairs job ahead of crucial talks with Pakistani Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif.</p>
<p>They are expected to meet on the fringes of a summit of the seven-nation South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation (SAARC) starting in the Maldives capital Male on May 12.</p>
<p>Gujral helped to initiate a thaw in the troubled relations between India and Pakistan when their foreign secretaries met in March for the first time in three years.</p>
<p>As foreign minister, he later held talks with his Pakistani counterpart, Gohar Ayub Khan, in New Delhi. The foreign secretaries, the highest ranking civil servants in the foreign ministries, are likely to meet again in Islamabad in May.</p>
<p>Gujral is expected to win a confidence vote set for Tuesday, with the support in the 542-member lower house of his United Front's 178 votes and the Congress Party's 140.</p>
<p>Once that is out of the way, Gujral's next task will be to pilot Chidambaram's investor-friendly budget through parliament.</p>
<p>The budget, which would slash taxes and spur private investment, sparked a rally in share prices after it was introduced in February.</p>
<p>The speaker of the lower house, P.A. Sangma, told reporters Gujral favoured Chidambaram's plan and parliament would take up the budget after April 30 in hopes of passing it by mid-May.</p>
<p>But the rightwing Hindu Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) said Chidambaram's budget was no longer valid.</p>
<p>&quot;Since a new government is coming in, so there will be a fresh budget,&quot; BJP president Lal Krishan Advani said.</p>
<p>Apart from four former TMC ministers and one from his Janata Dal party, Gujral retained the entire outgoing cabinet and said its members would continue to hold their old portfolios. He may appoint a junior foreign minister.</p>
<p>Gujral, who held his first ministerial post in 1966 in Indira Gandhi's government, is the second oldest person to be Indian prime minister. Morarji Desai led the country's first coalition government in 1977 at the age of 81.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
