<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52717" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: FEATURE-Peru Indians rebuild life after savage jungle war.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Peru Indians rebuild life after savage jungle war.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>TANGOSHARI, Peru 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A savage jungle war is over, but not forgotten.</p>
<p>Ashaninka Indian leader Nicolas Sagastizabal fingers a bow and arrow with pride as he recounts his bloody encounters with Maoist guerrilla invaders deep in Peru's Amazon rainforest. &quot;We didn't have much to defend ourselves with, but we gave as good as we got,&quot; recalled Sagastizabal, who lost five family members in a wave of attacks by Shining Path guerrillas on his isolated jungle community in the River Ene valley.</p>
<p>He and fellow Ashaninka warriors used booby-traps, old shotguns and grenades obtained from the army in the desperate defence of their people and to take revenge for the massacres. Sagastizabal says he killed at least a couple of dozen rebels.</p>
<p>Now, after years of fighting, hiding in the jungle and a dramatic airlift to safety, he and his community live in the relative safety of the newly built village of Tangoshari, away from their burned-out former home, Cutivereni. In the idyllic surroundings of their new home the horrors of the recent past are hard to imagine.</p>
<p>Laughing children play naked in brooks that tumble down from densely covered hills. Women with brightly painted faces smoke meat and chop fruit and yucca next to thatched huts built on stilts to protect them from flooding. A cacophany of sounds bears testimony to abundant wildlife in the surrounding jungle as hunters armed with arrows and spears disappear into the foliage at dawn to return with fresh fish and wild boars.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Shining Path) dragged us into a war we didn't want to fight. They forced us to become guerrillas too. Now we just want to live in peace,&quot; Sagastizabal said.</p>
<p>Peace is still a relatively new phenomenon for this and several hundred other Ashaninka communities in Peru's Ene and Tambo river valleys where the eastern slopes of the Andes merge into the western reaches of the Amazon jungle. Around 5,000 Ashaninkas out of an estimated total of 30,000 to 40,000 in the tribe died at the hands of Shining Path in the late 1980s and early 1990s.</p>
<p>The war began in 1986 when Shining Path tried to take over the zone and, on encountering resistance, slaughtered communities and destroyed settlements. Thousands of Ashaninkas were captured for use as slave labour in guerrilla camps or forcibly recruited to fight against their own people.</p>
<p>Testimony from Indian survivors and aid workers tells of mass graves full of dismembered bodies, children with ears and fingers cut off by machetes in &quot;punishment&quot; raids by Shining Path, &quot;people's trials&quot; after which victims were garroted or stabbed to death, and villagers forced one-by-one to cut flesh off a local official tied to an execution post.</p>
<p>Although traditionally a peaceful subsistence tribe, the Ashaninkas, for their part, replied with arrows, spears, machetes and any more modern weapons their rapidly organised self-defence militias could lay their hands on.</p>
<p>&quot;The Ashaninkas fought hard but they took it really badly from Shining Path,&quot; an anti-terrorism police source said. &quot;They were decimated, nearly wiped off the map for good.&quot;</p>
<p>Tragically for the Ashaninkas, their land lay right in the middle of the route between the guerrillas' mountain homeland Ayacucho and the drug-growing Huallaga Valley where Shining Path forged lucrative links with Colombian traffickers. The Ene and Tambo river valleys also provided a natural escape route for the guerrillas into the impenetrable Amazon in case the security forces tried to corner them.</p>
<p>At least for now, after setbacks to Shining Path on a national level and an army offensive last year in the Ene Valley, the worst of the fighting is over in the Ashaninkas' homeland. But the guerrillas, while reduced in number, have not gone away, according to police and military sources.</p>
<p>Shining Path's military leader Oscar Ramirez Durand, alias &quot;Comrade Feliciano,&quot; still hides out in the Ene river valley, and several hundred armed guerrillas move relatively freely around the jungle, the sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;Shining Path's elite is hiding out there because it is one of the most remote zones in Peru, very quiet, with plenty of food available in the jungle and little penetration from the army,&quot; said another anti-terrorism police source.</p>
<p>The rebels' current strategy in the area is to consolidate and extend the control they still have in various Ashaninka communities. Hundreds of Indians are still held in Shining Path's three or four remaining camps, the police said.</p>
<p>While most of the Ashaninka men in Tangoshari, where they arrived in 1992, are more concerned now with planting and hunting food, they still sleep close to their bows, ready to spring into combat if necessary.</p>
<p>&quot;I am afraid the terrorists will find us here eventually. Our men will fight but we and the children will run and hide in the mountains,&quot; said Ashaninka Cecilia Zumaeta. Her husband Mario, a teacher, had his tongue cut out before he was castrated and crucified in a November 1989 raid on Cutivereni by about 60 Shining Path guerrillas.</p>
<p>Beneath the physical scars of war, the Ashaninkas are also struggling with the trauma, especially to the children, and with the internal tensions caused by the return of natives who were forced to fight alongside Shining Path.</p>
<p>&quot;These people have suffered much. I just hope the worst is over,&quot; said Mariano Gagnol, a jovial and charismatic Franciscan priest who lived with the Ashaninkas for two decades. Gagnol, famous for helping arm the Ashaninkas in Cutivereni against Shining Path, organised the airlift and regularly visits Tangoshari from his parish in Lima.</p>
<p>As in all the Ashaninka communities, the people of Tangoshari wear long gowns or &quot;cushmas.&quot; Most cannot speak Spanish, preserve their traditional beliefs in the creator-god Tasorensi and paint their faces in red or orange pigments.</p>
<p>In an ironic echo of the communist philosophy fanatically espoused by Shining Path, the Ashaninkas, whose name means simply The People in their native language, operate an entirely socialist community, sharing resources and exchanging goods and services rather than circulating money.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TANGOSHARI, Peru"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
