<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="527220" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-JAPANESE PITCHING STAR IRABU SET TO JOIN YANKEES.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-JAPANESE PITCHING STAR IRABU SET TO JOIN YANKEES.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese star pitcher Hideki Irabu will finally get his wish to play in Yankee pinstripes after all.</p>
<p>After months of negotiations for the rights to the Japanese hurler, the New York Yankees have reached an agreement with the San Diego Padres for the hard-throwing Irabu, according to New York Mets officials.</p>
<p>The Yankees have yet to officially confirm the deal, which reportedly sends injured outfielder Ruben Rivera, minor-league pitcher Rafael Medina and $3 million to San Diego for Irabu and some minor league prospects.</p>
<p>But the Mets, who also had their sights set on the fireballer, said it was a done deal.</p>
<p>&quot;We made a heck of an offer, the New York Yankees made a heck of an offer and he chose the Yankees,&quot; Mets president Fred Wilpon told reporters Tuesday.</p>
<p>Irabu, who has been called the &quot;Nolan Ryan of Japan&quot; because of an overpowering fastball, has been saying for months that the World Series champion New York Yankees was the only North American team he would play for.</p>
<p>The Padres owned the rights to Irabu as a result of their working agreement with Irabu's Japanese team, the Chiba Lotte Marines. But Irabu said he would sit out the season rather than play for the Padres, or any team but the Yankees.</p>
<p>Despite Irabu's steadfast insistance on playing for the Yankees, the Mets had been aggressively courting the Japanese star.</p>
<p>&quot;We would have liked to have gotten Irabu,&quot; Wilpon said.</p>
<p>The Mets were hoping that Irabu's past association with manager Bobby Valentine would help convince him to play for them. Valentine managed Irabu with Chiba Lotte.</p>
<p>The 27-year-old Irabu led the Japanese Pacific League with a 2.40 ERA last season.</p>
<p>The Padres will have to wait for the services of the 23-year-old Rivera, who is recovering from shoulder surgery that is expected to sideline him until late June.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
