<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="527278" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: HANSAPANK DOMINATES SOLID SHARE TRADE.</title>
<headline>HANSAPANK DOMINATES SOLID SHARE TRADE.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>* Total trade on the Estonian bourse was 75.2 million kroons</p>
<p>versus Monday's 61.6 million kroons.</p>
<p>* The Talse gained 1.56 percent to close on 271.77</p>
<p>* Hansapank's share price was 6.65 kroons stronger</p>
<p>to close on 286.15 kroons on trade of 36.9 million kroons.</p>
<p>* Dealers said that short-term, small investors dominated</p>
<p>trade. Hansapank was helped by follow on from its first quarter</p>
<p>results and by investors positioning themselves on the last day</p>
<p>of cum-dividend trading in the stock.</p>
<p>Hansapank again led a rally on</p>
<p>a busy day's trade on the stock exchange on Tuesday as investors</p>
<p>rushed to buy Hanspank stock on the last day of cum-dividend</p>
<p>trading and in the wake of its good first quarter results.</p>
<p>The Talse rose by 1.56 percent to close on 271.77 kroons</p>
<p>with 67.7 million kroons of shares traded on the main list.</p>
<p>Total market capitalisation was higher at 14.56 billion</p>
<p>kroons compared to Monday's 14.30 billion kroons.</p>
<p>&quot;The day was very busy as people were to trying to get even</p>
<p>the smallest advantage out of the market,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was not the behaviour of long-term investors,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Wednesday is expected to see more sellers and volumes lower.&quot;</p>
<p>Hansapank turned over 36.9 million kroons to dominate trade.</p>
<p>The stock gained 6.65 kroons to close on 286.15 kroons.</p>
<p>Today was the last day of cum-dividend trading and also the</p>
<p>last day for inclusion on the list of share holders for the</p>
<p>bank's bonus share issue.</p>
<p>&quot;The interest in Hansapank was due to the last day for the</p>
<p>cum-dividend trading and people hoping to make a quick profit on</p>
<p>the bonus share issue,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>The bank also benefited from follow-on interest after it</p>
<p>yesterday reported a sharp rise in first quarter profit.</p>
<p>Hoiupank saw trade of 12.5 million kroons of</p>
<p>shares to be stable on 133.00 kroons.</p>
<p>&quot;There was some large sellers on the market, but all the</p>
<p>shares were taken up,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>On the over-the-counter market, total trade was 7.4 million</p>
<p>kroons of shares with diversified industrialist Norma the most</p>
<p>active stock.</p>
<p>Norma traded 2.8 millions kroons of shares to close 2.75</p>
<p>kroons higher on 78.50 kroons.</p>
<p>&quot;The strong interest stayed with Norma after the release of</p>
<p>the final first quarter profit figures, but the volumes on the</p>
<p>free market were quite low,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Norma's adjusted first quarter net profit results were 24.2</p>
<p>million kroons, slightly higher than previously announced.</p>
<p>-- David Mardiste, Tallinn newsroom +372 630 8400</p>
<p>reuters@reuters.ee</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
