<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52724" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-OPINION - Canberra Closeup: Where Howard dares not tread.</title>
<headline>RTRS-OPINION - Canberra Closeup: Where Howard dares not tread.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Jim Middleton (ABC TV Political Correspondent)</p>
<p>Employment Minister Amanda Vanstone has made it something of a habit to step where John Howard would not dare -- and where he wishes she wouldn't.</p>
<p>This week was no different.</p>
<p>With unemployment figures out yesterday, jobs were always going to be central to the week's political debate.</p>
<p>Labor jumped on the prime minister's refusal to set a target for job growth -- an issue he dodged before the election and had been ducking ever since.</p>
<p>Kim Beazley set the tone in question time on Monday by asking Howard: &quot;Why will you set a target for inflation and for cutting small business red tape, but not one for unemployment?&quot;</p>
<p>The prime minister was determined to do everything but answer the question.</p>
<p>However, Beazley was able to take advantage of recently reinstituted supplementary questions to put Howard on the spot again.</p>
<p>The prime minister jutted out his chin and remained defiant.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not going to commit this government to a quantitative target,&quot; he declared.</p>
<p>All very well, but it does not sit well with a leader who has talked of the need to elevate political credibility and honesty.</p>
<p>There is a very practical reason for his obfuscation and and it appears on page 2-24 of budget paper No. 1.</p>
<p>Treasury's official forecast for employment growth this financial year is a meagre 1.5 percent -- not enough to bring about any fall in unemployment.</p>
<p>Even though Howard declared jobs -- especially jobs for the young -- was one of the key issues of the election campaign.</p>
<p>So he must have been particularly pleased when Senator Vanstone volunteered to the 7.30 Report's Kerry O'Brien on Wednesday that the government would lose office if unemployment did not fall.</p>
<p>O'Brien:  &quot;Unemployment will fall?&quot;</p>
<p>Vanstone: &quot;As I've said to you, we won't get re-elected if it doesn't.&quot;</p>
<p>Labor frontbencher Martin Ferguson declared the Employment Minister had done what Howard would not -- set a jobs target.</p>
<p>Kim Beazley saw the opening and chased Howard through it.</p>
<p>The prime minister would not take the bait.</p>
<p>But it may provide a little discomfort for the government in the campaign for the by-election no-one wants -- the upcoming poll in the outer western Sydney seat of Lindsay.</p>
<p>It was caused by the failure of Liberal MP Jackie Kelly to quit the air force -- an office of profit under the crown -- before nominations closed.</p>
<p>One key Liberal strategist suggests -- only half jokingly -- that it would have been better if the Court of Disputed Returns had handed the seas to the defeated member, former Labor minister Ross Free.</p>
<p>&quot;At least we could have gone on about democracy being the loser rather than facing the distraction of yet another campaign with an uncertain outcome,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>Lindsay had been a safe Labor seat -- Kelly gained a swing of more than 11 percent and now has a cushion of 1.6 percent.</p>
<p>Free instigated the action which saw Kelly disqualified.</p>
<p>Some members of his party wish he hadn't. A by-election soon after a tough budget should be a lay-down misere for Labor.</p>
<p>But with the budget generally well received, some Labor MPs fear the poll will become a referendum on Beazley instead.</p>
<p>Already there are mutterings about the way deputy Gareth Evans' confessional apprach to the job is diminishing Beazley's effectiveness.</p>
<p>As one Labor figure put it: &quot;I wish Gareth would just throw the economics textbook away and realise it's a political, not an intellectual contest.&quot;</p>
<p>Labor frontbenchers acknowledge the ALP has had a tougher time finding its feet in opposition than the coalition has had in adjusting to government. Especially since the budget -- and Senator Vanstone notwithstanding.</p>
<p>They acknowledge that this week the government had a genuine question time strategy, counter-attacking Labor over rorting of the research and development syndicate scheme for example.</p>
<p>By the same token, they admit the Labor operation has to become more disciplined to be an effective opposition.</p>
<p>The decision not to keep pressing the government over the rising price of health insurance was identified as one clear mistake.</p>
<p>The Carr government is on the nose in New South Wales State -- about-faces over motorway tolls and on hospital funding are not likely to be forgotten in Sydney's west.</p>
<p>So Lindsay could well be the reverse of the usual by-election.</p>
<p>&quot;Send a message to Bob Carr&quot;, was suggested half-seriously as a possible Liberal slogan by one canny old time campaigner.</p>
<p>It's a message which could give the Liberals more hope in Lindsay than they could have expected a month ago, a message to give Kim Beazley more than a slight case of the shivers.</p>
<p>(Views are those of the author, not those of Reuters)</p>
<p>-- Reuters Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
