<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="527336" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: BETTER CZECH TRADE DATA CHEER ECONOMISTS.</title>
<headline>BETTER CZECH TRADE DATA CHEER ECONOMISTS.</headline>
<byline>Robin Shepherd</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech trade deficit widened only slightly in March to 13.43 billion crowns from a revised 13.42 billion in February, providing for a rare moment of optimism about the country's economic prospects.</p>
<p>The figures, released by the Czech Statistical Bureau (CSU) on Tuesday, were nearly four billion crowns better than expected and brought the deficit for the first quarter to 40.2 billion crowns, compared with a 27.1 billion crown deficit for the same period in 1996.</p>
<p>After the CSU's announcement, the crown strengthened by more than half a percentage point against its mark/dollar basket and some economists said they would radically revise their forecasts for the full year 1997 deficit.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to revise my original forecast from the beginning of this year for the trade deficit from 200 billion crowns to 150-160 billion,&quot; said Kamil Janacek, chief economist at the country's biggest commercial bank, Komercni Banka.</p>
<p>Even the normally tight-lipped Czech central bank said it was pleased with the figures:</p>
<p>&quot;We're quite satisified with the improvement. With any news we try not to be too excited but I think it is good news,&quot; Jan Vit, deputy governer of the Czech National Bank told Reuters.</p>
<p>The better-than-expected figures come just one day after the government moved to curb imports by requiring importers of consumer and agricultural goods to deposit sums equal to 20 percent of the value of their imports in non-interest bearing accounts at Czech banks for 180 days.</p>
<p>The import restrictions were part of a sweeping package of measures announced by the government last week to boost growth, reform the capital markets and generally restore faith in the country's commitment to radical economic reform.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, economists said they were particularly pleased with the improvement in exports, which were 0.6 percent higher in the first quarter than in the same period last year. In January to February exports had actually fallen by 0.4 percent compared with the first two months of 1996.</p>
<p>Janacek said the improvement in exports was mainly due to an improvement in manufacturing output in neighbouring Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;On the export side is the revival of industrial growth in Germany as the primary factor of the growth of exports,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Despite the improvement in exports, imports continued to grow much faster -- by 8.0 percent in the first quarter -- and some analysts cautioned that many uncertain factors would have to come together before talk of a turnaround could be justified.</p>
<p>&quot;If this (new government) package is implemented, including budget cuts, including this import deposit effect...and if this is accompanied by a depreciationg crown...then I believe that the current account deficit in terms of GDP might cease to worsen this year,&quot; said Martin Kupka of Patria Finance.</p>
<p>In 1996, the trade deficit rose to 160 billion crowns from 96 billion the year before pushing the current account deficit to 122 billion from 36 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>In 1996 the Czech Republic had one of the world's highest current account deficits relative to the size of its economy at 8.6 percent of GDP compared with 2.9 percent the year before.</p>
<p>The Czech crown was fixed on Tuesday at 30.237 against the dollar and 17.708 against the mark implying a deviation from the mid-point of its mark/dollar basket of minus 1.17 percent.</p>
<p>On Monday, the central bank fixed the crown at minus 1.73 percent against the basket.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 420-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
