<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="527618" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELARUS: Belarus to buy 180,000 T raw sugar in 1997.</title>
<headline>Belarus to buy 180,000 T raw sugar in 1997.</headline>
<dateline>MINSK 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belarus will buy 180,000 tonnes of raw sugar in 1997 against 150,000 in 1996, Deputy Agriculture Minister Ivan Shakolo said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have already received 42,000 tonnes of raws from Argentina. Today we are holding talks with Cuba about the possibility of trading raws for fertilisers,&quot; Shakolo told a news conference.</p>
<p>Belarus has annual domestic refined sugar needs of about 300,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Shakolo said Belarus held talks with Ukrainian officials last week about imposing a quota on refined sugar imports in 1997. He said he expected to have an official announcement on the matter some time next month.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has to be civilised. Because of inflows of cheap Ukrainian sugar last year we were forced to stop our own production and bring sanctions against imports,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ukraine has been a traditional sugar supplier to Belarus and Russia. Russia has said it will levy a 25 percent duty on Ukrainian sugar imports next month.</p>
<p>The duty is expected to replace an earlier plan to impose an import quota of 1.5 million tonnes on all white sugar imports into Russia in 1997 - including 1.15 million tonnes for Ukraine.</p>
<p>Belarus has also imposed a 25 percent duty on white sugar imports, Shakolo added.</p>
<p>But last month President Alexander Lukashenko removed the duty to make way for imports of 30,000 tonnes from Ukraine to meet domestic needs.</p>
<p>Shakolo said Belarus planned to strike a deal with Germany next month to modernise its four refineries.</p>
<p>&quot;In the future we hope to completely secure the needs of our republic in terms of white sugar production from our own sugar beets,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Belarus sugar beet harvest was one million tonnes in 1996 after 1.14 million tonnes in 1995.</p>
<p>--Kiev Newsroom +380 44 244-9150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINSK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELARUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
