<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52768" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia, Indonesia agree on marine boundary.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia, Indonesia agree on marine boundary.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia and Australia have agreed on the maritime boundary between them, the Australian government said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreement effectively finalises the maritime boundaries between Australia and Indonesia,&quot; Foreign Affairs Minister Alexander Downer said in a statement.  </p>
<p>&quot;The agreement will now be submitted to the Australian and Indonesian governments for formal approval,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Officials had agreed to the three outstanding unsettled boundaries:</p>
<p>--The water column and seabed boundary between Christmas Island, in the Indian Ocean, and Java.</p>
<p>--A western extension of the seabed boundary previously agreed to near Australia's Ashmore and Cartier islands.</p>
<p>--The water column boundary between continental Australia and Indonesia.  </p>
<p>The water column boundary applies to anything swimming in the water, whereas the seabed boundary relates to anything on or under the seabed.</p>
<p>They can differ because it is convenient for the seabed boundary to follow geographical features, such as a trenchline, while the water boundary is best kept in straight lines for ships navigating on the surface.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
