<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52779" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ air controllers won't rule out further strikes.</title>
<headline>NZ air controllers won't rule out further strikes.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Air travel throughout New Zealand returned to normal on Friday after a three-hour morning strike by air traffic controllers but their union was not ruling out the possibility of more stoppages.</p>
<p>&quot;Our position is one of wait and see what happens at the talks tomorrow,&quot; Adam Nicholson, Airline Pilots Association spokesman, told Reuters. Controllers had to give 14 days notice of further strike action.  </p>
<p>Both sides were heading for talks, which had been arranged last week before the strikes, with an independent mediator on Saturday. These were due to last until Wednesday and both sides have agreed not to speak to the press during mediations.</p>
<p>&quot;Airways Corp's position is more extreme than it was last December,&quot; Nicholson said.</p>
<p>But Airways Corp, which employs the controllers, denied this. &quot;We have moved considerably since then. Both sides have revised their positions,&quot; Airways Corp spokeswoman Cynthia Brophy said.  </p>
<p>Air traffic controllers walked off the job in protest over a stalled pay dispute that has been going on for 15 months. Controllers had staged a similar strike on Monday.</p>
<p>Regional provincial services were cut during the 7-10 a.m. strike and services in the main cities reduced. Both Ansett NZ and Air New Zealand cancelled more that half their scheduled flights. International flights were also affected, with several cancelled and departures delayed up to one hour.</p>
<p>Airways Corp have not responded to the strike action.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are deeply disapponted that it has come down to strikes. Strikes are an old fashioned bludgeoning tactic by the union,&quot; Brophy said.</p>
<p>The Airline Pilots Association want a 7.75 percent across the board pay rise, with a collective contract. But Airways Corp want workplace contracts with pay rates related to airports' productivity.</p>
<p>Both sides were optimistic that progress could be made during mediation.  </p>
<p>Air New Zealand and Ansett were calling for a quick resolution to the dispute. &quot;We certainly don't want this to go on as it affects the travelling public, a spokesman for Air New Zealand said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a smaller impact with these limited duration strikes. Business does drop off, people do steer clear of the day. But with the amount of notice, travellers can make alternative arrangements.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
