<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52776" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-OPINION-Louthean on Australia Mining: Perilya.</title>
<headline>RTRS-OPINION-Louthean on Australia Mining: Perilya.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Ross Louthean*</p>
<p>One of the important things for Perilya Mines NL is that the Perth-based company has been through a sizeable learning arc.</p>
<p>It has experienced booms and busts, seen a hot property turn into an embarrasing turkey and has undertaken tough shots that have either come up trumps or show signs of moving in the right direction.</p>
<p>Established just a few months before the stock market crash of October 1987, Perilya, a callow float gained some oomph when the assets (and executives) of Kolmas Resources NL -- a float thwarted by the crash -- were absorbed.</p>
<p>Taking over executive roles were former Homestake Mining Co senior geologists Tim Clifton and Warren Batt. With these two came equity in the Evanston gold project north of Bullfinch in the Yilgarn goldfield of Western Australia and the Island Block alluvial gold project in New Zealand's South Island.</p>
<p>HEMLO AND PERILYA FALL VICTIMS TO SALTING</p>
<p>Perilya showed corporate inovation by luring Noranda Inc of Canada into what was essentially a grubstaking arrangement of financing exploration and acquisitions, essentially leaving Perilya to do the work. This was a model for others to use.</p>
<p>The Noranda subsidiary became Hemlo Mines and eventually merged with Battle Mountan Gold Co.</p>
<p>But not before it slipped on a banana skin along with Perilya, when some spectacular drilling on a greenfield target near the Mount Gibson gold mine in Western Australia resulted in vendors, a group of prospectors, being incarcerated after being found guilty of salting drill material from the leases.</p>
<p>Noranda's share price in North America had a ride, along with Perilya in Australia, before the ruse was revealed.</p>
<p>Investors, singed by the experience, still backed Clifton and his team. The company joined the gold mining league through purchase in 1994 of Homestake Gold of Australia's Fortnum mine, which had been mothballed two years earlier.</p>
<p>MEGA FIRST TO TAKE UP RIGHT TO $8.5 MILLION IN SHARES The Perilya of today has a portfolio reflecting very little of its origins.</p>
<p>Early in August, the company displayed its international dealing skills by striking a deal with Malysia's biggest copper and gold miner, Mamut Copper Mining Sdn Bhd (MCM), to undertake a 50-50 joint venture to explore in Malaysia.</p>
<p>MCM, a subsidiary of listed Mega First Corp Bhd, is to take up a right to $8.5 million worth of shares in Perilya and two tranches of options, giving the Malaysian company the right to 19.9 percent of Perilya.</p>
<p>At the time of the deal, Clifton said it gave Perilya exposure in the highly prospective Central Kalimantan Arc, which hosts the world class Kelian, Mt Muro and Kelian deposits, and stretches from Indonesia into the Malaysian state of Sabah.</p>
<p>EYRES REED THINKS FORTNUM'S COSTS WILL FALL</p>
<p>Perilya has sold out of Evanston, now a project fully controlled by Noble Resources NL, and has since mined out Island Block for useful profit, and as a joint venture with experienced private New Zealand miner March Mining.</p>
<p>It is a steadily improving gold miner in terms of ounces and operating costs at Fortnum, in the Glengarry Basin of Western Australia's north Murchison Goldfield.</p>
<p>Perth stockbroker Eyres Reed and Co, impressed by Perilya's performance and mining of low-grade orebodies, has predicted operating costs will fall into an acceptable minus-A$400.00-an- ounce range, utilising conservative accounting methods.</p>
<p>ISLAND BLOCK'S LIFE IS OVER The broker said reserves at Fortnum and outlying areas at the end of March totalled three million tonnes, at 2.2 grams of gold a tonne, defined with stockpiles and three pit designs.</p>
<p>Eyres Reed has predicted Fortnum will continue to produce at a steady rate of 65,000 ounces over the next three years, with cash production costs next year averaging A$377.00 and ounce, and being in the low A$400.00 range in 1998 and 1999. While Island Block's life is over, Perilya is undertaking a detailed NZ$2.2 million final study on its next project, near the Clutha River in Earnscleugh.</p>
<p>This project may not be in operation for two years, but it could be 20 times the size of Block Island, producing over 50,000 ouces a year.</p>
<p>One of the plays the compay has persisted with, and it now appears to be providing good dividends, is the quest for a clone or the extension of the historic Mount Morgan mine in central Queensland.</p>
<p>THE OLD WAR HORSE YIELDED 8 MILLION OUNCES</p>
<p>This old war horse produced 8 million ounces of gold and 350,000 tonnes of copper and in the bleak gold days of the 1960s was Australia's only significant gold producers -- through tailings retreatment -- outside the fields of Kalgoorlie, Mt Magnet and Norseman.</p>
<p>Eyres Reed said drilling south east of the mine workings has picked up a structure of depth which Perilya thinks may be a down-faulted extension of the old mine system.</p>
<p>In June, the company said drilling under the north eastern wall of the old open cut also has picked up significant mineralisation.  Drill results included some high-grade zinc assays and Perilya said the new find appears similar in style to the find made to the south east.</p>
<p>At the time the company said: &quot;The exploration prize, if this orebody is down-faulted across the Invoka Fault, is substantial.  A successful result from the ongoing programme would lay the foundation for the next stage of significant growth of the company.&quot;</p>
<p>To date, Perilya has resisted joint venture overtures, either to further quantify the target, to improve its market value, or to eventually finance a solo development.</p>
<p>Perilya retains between 30 percent and 47.5 percent equity in a gold prospect at Moyagee, south of Cue in Western Australia's Murchison goldfield, which has been producing some strong drill results. this is an area where regional gold producer Posgold Ltd also has been having some joy.</p>
<p>One of Perilya's other assets is the listed opal explorer Redfire Resources NL, in which it holds 22.75 percent.</p>
<p>Perilya helped finance Redfire, which holds opal licenses of considerable size in northern New South Wales and the Hebel project in southern Queensland.</p>
<p>*Ross Louthean is editor of Paydirt and publisher of Gold Mining Journal, The Australian Mines Handbook and Mineral Resources of New Zealand.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
