<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52781" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Canberra releases telecommunications package.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Canberra releases telecommunications package.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Communications Minister Richard Alston released on Friday draft arrangements for the licensing and regulation of the telecommunications industry after deregulation in July 1997.</p>
<p>Alston said anyone would have the right to install telecommunications infrastructure for their own use and would only require a licence in order to supply services to the public.  </p>
<p>&quot;From July next year, we will have a truly open telecommunications market with no limit on the number of carrier licences which can be issued and no restrictions on the services carriers supply or the technologies they use,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>Alston said the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission (ACCC) would have wide powers to resolve any disputes which might arise.</p>
<p>The communications minister would also have the power to set up principles on which access prices were determined, he said.  </p>
<p>An initial package of legislation addressing radiocommunications and technical regulation matters was released on August 16.</p>
<p>The latest package is the second tranche of the legislation with another, addressing service obligations and industry code arrangements, expected to be released in the near future.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
