<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="528182" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton in familiar spot, sees disaster from air.</title>
<headline>Clinton in familiar spot, sees disaster from air.</headline>
<byline>Arshad Mohammed</byline>
<dateline>GRAND FORKS, N.D. 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton was in familiar territory Tuesday -- looking at the scene of yet another natural disaster from his Marine One helicopter.</p>
<p>In more than four years as president, Clinton has seen floods that in 1993 inundated parts of nine states in the Midwest. He has seen California earthquakes and mudslides. And just weeks ago he saw the damage left in the wake of a string of killer tornadoes in his own home state, Arkansas.</p>
<p>So it was with a practiced eye that he viewed the flood- swollen Red River and the town it submerged, Grand Forks. It was the first time he had ridden his helicopter since suffering a knee injury March 14 that required surgery.</p>
<p>&quot;Look at these homes here!&quot; he said excitedly as Marine One passed over one neighborhood where the water was halfway to the roofs.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a pretty town, too... Right over there, see the burned buildings? ... That's a beautiful old church... The water's all the way over the roof edge here... That's a water treatment plant,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Staring silently at some submerged homes, Clinton shook his head faintly and said: &quot;Every one of those little houses is another life story.&quot;</p>
<p>With him was fellow Arkansan James Lee Witt, director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency. Sitting at Clinton's left knee, he provided a running narration about various sites, background on the flood, offering observations.</p>
<p>&quot;This'll be like building a whole town back,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Witt said flooded homeowners have a lot of work ahead of them.</p>
<p>&quot;Every one I've seen had about a foot of muck inside,&quot; he said of the houses. Owners will have to rip sheetrock off their walls &quot;down to the studs&quot; and then rebuild.</p>
<p>For a time Clinton stared in silence at the scene unfolding below, the fingers of his right hand curled around his chin. Then he pointed out the window.</p>
<p>&quot;Is that where the water treatment facility was?&quot; he asked. Witt said that it was.</p>
<p>The floodwaters flowed quickly over a flat terrain of fertile fields that are prime farming country in the upper Midwest.</p>
<p>Clinton made the observation that floods over cropland raise alkaline in the soil and hurts future crops. Once the waters recede. &quot;they'll just have to test it to see how much it's damaged,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The president could not resist a little gallows humor. After watching out the window a while he turned to a reporter with a grin and said: &quot;The McDonald's is dry!&quot; He paused and added: &quot;The Pizza Hut is too, but you can't get to it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GRAND FORKS, N.D."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
