<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52816" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Central bank spurns preelection comfort for NZ govt.</title>
<headline>Central bank spurns preelection comfort for NZ govt.</headline>
<byline>Simon Louisson</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand's central bank made a series of economic forecasts on Friday distinctly more gloomy than Treasury forecasts published a day earlier.</p>
<p>The forecasts by the independent Reserve Bank dampened hopes for an easing in double digit home lending rates that may have given the ruling conservative National Party a fillip ahead of a general election on October 12.</p>
<p>The bank predicted annual underlying inflation would rise to 2.7 percent in September 1996, slightly higher than its previous prediction, and well outside the government-set target of 0-2 percent.</p>
<p>Bank governor Don Brash dashed financial markets' optimism monetary conditions would be eased to compensate for sharply slower economic growth.</p>
<p>The New Zealand dollar and short-term interest rates rose while the share market took it in its stride and held firm.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the medium-term inflation outlook appears quite encouraging, it still too early for an easing,&quot; Brash said.</p>
<p>&quot;An easing remains off the agenda until conclusive evidence is at hand that inflation will in fact fall away sharply next year and beyond.&quot;</p>
<p>The bank forecast real growth in the March 1997 at 2.0 percent rising to 2.4 percent the following year.</p>
<p>That contrasted with Treasury's forecasts in its pre-election Economic and Fiscal Update of 2.5 percent growth in 1997 and 3.7 percent the following year.</p>
<p>Bank of New Zealand chief economist Tony Alexander said there was also a big difference between the bank's and Treasury's fiscal outlooks.</p>
<p>The RB saw the budget surplus falling to NZ$2.25 billion (US$1.56 billion) in 1997 from $3.3 billion in 1996, and then to $1.89 billion the following year.</p>
<p>In its much more rosy fiscal picture, Treasury saw the record budget surplus for 1995/96 doubling by 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;One would tend to accord a greater degree of independence and reliability, I think, to Reserve Bank economic forecasts than to Treasury economic forecasts any day of the week,&quot; Alexander said.</p>
<p>&quot;But it could also just reflect different assumptions about world growth...I'm not surprised or concerned about the difference between their economic forecasts,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The RB said New Zealand's sustainable growth rate was 2.75 percent, lower than its previous estimates, and lower than Treasury's estimate of 3.5 percent.</p>
<p>Brash said that until there was clear evidence of a drop in inflation pressures he could not sanction any easing.</p>
<p>The housing market has taken much of the blame for inflation breaking the bank's band, and while Brash saw encouraging signs that prices were stabilising, he said the bank would resist any move by banks to cut mortgage lending rates.</p>
<p>Brash would not specify a date for an easing but indicated it would come later in 1997. But economists think it will come earlier as the economic slowdown bites more deeply.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just a case of holding the line in the near term and we still think an easing in policy in early '97, possibly late '96, is still likely,&quot; said ANZ chief economist Paul Stewart.</p>
<p>&quot;We still think that if pressures continue to moderate particularly in the housing market, then there will be some scope for falls in interest rates throughout 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>US$1=NZ$1.44</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
