<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="528261" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. still hopeful N.Korea talks will succeed.</title>
<headline>U.S. still hopeful N.Korea talks will succeed.</headline>
<byline>Carol Giacomo</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The latest U.S.-South Korean experience has proven anew that negotiations with North Korea are always tougher and more tortuous than expected.</p>
<p>A New York meeting that began last week with convivial banter and talk of a &quot;warm spring&quot; between the two Korean enemies collapsed when the senior South Korean negotiator and his team flew back to Seoul after midnight on Monday.</p>
<p>U.S. officials said working-level contacts among the three sides would continue and they remained reasonably confident that the North, which is under severe economic stress and threat of famine, would ultimately agree to enter peace talks.</p>
<p>But the departure of the South Korean delegation from New York adds an element of indefinte uncertainty to the launching of a peace process that last week seemed within early reach. U.S. spokesman Nicholas Burns acknowledged differences remained &quot;and apparently will not be closed quickly.&quot;</p>
<p>On the table is a year-old U.S.-South Korea proposal for four-party peace talks also involving China that seeks to close the books on the 1950-53 Korean War and replace the fraying armistice with a formal peace treaty.</p>
<p>Academic critics like Asia expert Selig Harrison of the Woodrow Wilson Centre say the United States and South Korea risk squandering a unique opportunity to bring stability to the Korean peninsula if they are not willing to offer bold new concessions to Pyongyang.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a great opportunity for a comprehensive package deal in which the United States, South Korea and Japan make clear commitments for food deliveries of 1.5 million tons this year and next year in return for equally binding commitments by North Korea on key security issues including ending missile exports and pulling back (from the border) offensive forces as part of a mutual redeployment,&quot; Harrison said.</p>
<p>He said such inducements were essential for North Korea to win acceptance of the agreement at home because what was being offered was a U.S.-South Korean plan quite different from a peace talks proposal Pyongyang put forward.</p>
<p>Washington is keen to get formal negotiations under way that would defuse tensions on the divided Korean peninsula, the world's most heavily militarized border. Officials insist, however, there are no plans to offer the extra inducements Pyongyang has demanded, including massive new food aid and a lifting of U.S. trade sanctions.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot accept that the issue of food should be a precondition for discussion on the issue of peace,&quot; Burns said. He stressed that peace negotiations were expected to plod along while food aid must be delivered expeditiously to meet the Stalinist country's extreme needs.</p>
<p>But there is more to it than that. The United States, which recently offered $25 million in food aid, feels it has already shown sincere concern for Pyongyang's plight and good faith in delivering on promised help.</p>
<p>South Korea and Japan, the two largest potential donors, have provided some assistance but balked at giving more until North Korea makes a commitment to peace talks.</p>
<p>Moreover, given Pyongyang's zig-zag negotiating style and the inscrutability of its society, there is a reluctance to meet North Korea's maximum demands until its negotiating team actually shows up at the bargaining table.</p>
<p>The past week was another example of the unpredictability of North Korea evident since Washington entered into regular dialogue with the Stalinist state in 1993. U.S. and South Korean officials were led to believe North Korean negotiators were inclined to accept the peace proposal.</p>
<p>When a supposedly crucial meeting opened last Wednesday in New York, the chief South Korean delegate waxed poetic about a &quot;warm spring&quot; and his North Korean counterpart predicted their talks would produce &quot;positive results.&quot;</p>
<p>But while the North Koreans accepted the peace proposal in principle, they conditioned that acceptance on more food aid and lifting U.S. trade sanctions, officials said.</p>
<p>U.S. and South Korean negotiators believe the North Korean delegation understands Washington and Seoul are serious about no concessions before Pyongyang agrees to peace talks.</p>
<p>They suggest the mixed signals on the proposal reflect internal divisions in Pyongyang over taking an action that could have profound repercussions for the regime, which has espoused a strong nationalism and based its existence on combatting enemies South Korea and the United States.</p>
<p>U.S. officials insist they and the South Koreans have given clear indications they are ready to act further on North Korea's concerns and needs -- after Pyongyang joins peace talks. For now, &quot;the ball's in their court,&quot; Burns said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
