<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="528379" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CRP enrollment seen as &quot;huge decision&quot; - USDA.</title>
<headline>CRP enrollment seen as &quot;huge decision&quot; - USDA.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The amount of farmland enrolled in the Conservation Reserve Program will affect U.S. agriculture for the next 10 years, a senior Agriculture Department official said Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;All of us believe this is a huge decision and it will impact what happens to agriculture over the next 10 years,&quot; said Randy Weber, acting associate administrater of the Farm Service Agency.  </p>
<p>The USDA has assigned at least 60 employees to work on the CRP enrollment to meet the May deadline, Weber said in remarks at a meeting of the National Association of Agricultural Journalists.</p>
<p>He declined to comment on how much acreage might be accepted by the USDA, saying it was too early to tell whether as much as 21 million acres would be enrolled.</p>
<p>&quot;It may well be that we think that is the right amount of acreage,&quot; Weber said, referring to the 21 million acre figure. But he added that it was too early for the agency to say how much land might be idled under the program.  </p>
<p>&quot;We want the best quality land with the greatest environmental benefits,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Weber also said that &quot;no decision has been made&quot; about proposals to limit enrollment then hold a second CRP sign-up period for farmers later this year.</p>
<p>Ralph Grossi, president of American Farmland Trust, urged the USDA to go slowly with its CRP enrollment and hold a second sign-up period for farmers in June or July.</p>
<p>&quot;Ten to 12 million acres would be the target for us, contingent upon a second sign-up period this year,&quot; Grossi said at the meeting.  </p>
<p>On Monday, USDA Secretary Dan Glickman reiterated that the agency would notify farmers by the end of May if their land would be accepted for the conservation program. But Congress is considering legislation that would allow farmers now in the CRP a one-year extension.</p>
<p>Ten-year contracts on a total of some 21 million acres now in the CRP are set to expire in September. During last month's sign-up, U.S. farmers offered 25.6 million acres for enrollment in the program.  </p>
<p>Enrollment in the CRP is &quot;the most important economic decision&quot; that the U.S. Agriculture Department will make in the next few years because of its impact on U.S. exports, the head of the National Grain and Feed Association said Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We think there's a lot at stake here,&quot; said Kendell Keith, president of the grain trade group. &quot;This is probably the most important economic decision the secretary (of USDA) will make in the next five years.&quot;  </p>
<p>The grain group has proposed that the USDA cap farm acreage enrollment in the CRP at 12 million acres, rather than the range of up to 21 million acres that others have sought. Unless the amount of new acreage to be idled is limited, the United States could jeopardize its ability to increase farm exports, Keith said at the meeting.</p>
<p>Wheat growers and poultry producers have the most to lose if large amounts of U.S. farmland are idled, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We need the acres, particularly in the wheat area,&quot; Keith said, adding that U.S. wheat yields have not kept pace with other crops. The CRP will have a bigger impact on U.S. trade than expansion of the North American Free Trade Agreement or GATT, he said.</p>
<p>((--Washington commodities desk, 202-898-8467))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
