<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="528494" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tougher dlr talk but no major G7 policy shift seen.</title>
<headline>Tougher dlr talk but no major G7 policy shift seen.</headline>
<byline>Noah Barkin</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Group of Seven economic policymakers will likely voice their concern about a rapidly rising dollar but stop short of any overt shift in exchange rate policy when they converge on Washington this weekend.</p>
<p>Currency market experts expect more rhetoric aimed at slowing the dollar's impressive two-year climb and are banking on slightly stronger statements than those seen at the last G-7 meeting in early February.</p>
<p>But with economic fundamentals still pointing overwhelmingly in the greenback's favor, G-7 officials have limited options.</p>
<p>Analysts said they must communicate their desire to see the pace of dollar appreciation slow, but avoid any dramatic shift in language or policy that would risk a downward reversal in the dollar and create a one-way trade for currency dealers.</p>
<p>&quot;I would be surprised if there is either a new policy commitment or new policy actions that would derive from this weekend's G-7 meetings,&quot; said John Lipsky, chief economist at Chase Manhattan Bank.  </p>
<p>&quot;Even those authorities who may not be comfortable with the dollar's strength are not willing to take action that might seriously alter the outlook.&quot;</p>
<p>Central bankers and finance ministers from the powerful G7 industrial nations -- Britain, Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan and the United States -- will gather next Sunday on the fringes of the International Monetary Fund and World Bank's spring meetings.</p>
<p>The surging dollar, which this month touched a four-and-a-half year high against the yen and a three-year peak against the mark, is expected to be the hot topic of conversation.</p>
<p>In early February, when the dollar was changing hands at roughly 123 yen and 1.6600 marks, G7 policymakers meeting in Berlin offered what many market participants interpreted as a green light for further dollar gains.</p>
<p>The G7 released a relatively tame statement which said major currency misalignments noted in an April 1995 communique had been corrected and that currency stability was desirable.</p>
<p>Given the dollar's continued climb in the wake of the February meeting, the sense of urgency among the G7 and market anticipation of stronger rhetoric have grown.  </p>
<p>Since sinking to a post-World War II low versus the yen in early 1995, the greenback has now risen over 50 percent against the Japanese currency. Over the same time period, the dollar has advanced by almost 30 percent against the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;We can expect statements that are perhaps a little bit stronger than what we saw in February,&quot; said Allen Sinai, chief global economist at Primark Decision Economics in New York. &quot;I think that out of any communique or commentary will be the continued implicit threat of intervention.&quot;</p>
<p>But threats of intervention are likely to remain mere threats.</p>
<p>Among the G7 nations, Japan has been the most vocal in their opposition to further yen weakness -- and by definition further dollar strength. For the Japanese, the weakening of the yen has meant diminished confidence in its asset markets and highlighted skepticism about Japan's economic recovery.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, when the dollar stood near its cycle highs, Japanese Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka called yen fluctuations &quot;obviously excessive&quot; and cautioned that excessive moves would be dealt with &quot;decisively.&quot;</p>
<p>But market observers believe the U.S. and Europe have little interest in actively intervening to curb the dollar.  </p>
<p>With U.S. exports still strong and domestic demand for automobiles healthy, the Clinton administration has had little trouble turning a deaf ear to complaints from Detroit.</p>
<p>And while the robust greenback may have U.S. exporters crying foul, it has also helped dampen U.S. inflationary pressures, attract capital inflows and reduce upward pressure on interest rates.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, for countries like Germany and France, the dollar has provided a boost in export-led growth at a time when strict fiscal discipline is required in the run-up to Economic and Monetary Union.</p>
<p>&quot;The Europeans are not going to be particularly enthusiastic about an intervention policy to weaken the dollar,&quot; said Robert Hormats, vice chairman at Goldman Sachs (International). &quot;And even if there were a major intervention effort it's not clear that it would have much effect because interest rates are so compelling in favor of the dollar.&quot;</p>
<p>Consequently, Hormats said he expected G-7 statements to seize on embryonic evidence of a Japanese economic pickup and focus on the fundamental factors which could cap the dollar in the future.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't think they hold much hope that the fundamentals are going to turn the dollar around anytime soon,&quot; said Hormats.</p>
<p>&quot;But I do think there may be some feeling that six months down the road if there's stronger growth in Japan and Europe and if the U.S. trade imbalance remains large, the combination of the two will lead to a weaker dollar toward the end of the year.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
