<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="528670" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Nissan to open new car plant in Pakistan.</title>
<headline>Nissan to open new car plant in Pakistan.</headline>
<byline>Ibrahim Khan</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's Ghandhara Nissan Ltd will open a car plant in Pakistan on Wednesday to produce 6,000 Nissan Sunny cars a year in collaboration with Japan's Nissan Motor Co Ltd</p>
<p>&quot;The plant capacity is 6,000 units, single-shift, which can be increased as the demand increases,&quot; said a company executive on the eve of the plant's inauguration in Karachi.</p>
<p>The factory can also be used to assemble light commercial vehicles, said the executive, who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>The project cost an estimated 550 million rupees ($13.7 million), comprising 200 million rupees in equity, 275 million in lease financing and 75 million in financing of locally made machinery, he said.</p>
<p>Illahi Bukhsh Soomro, Speaker of the National Assembly (lower house), will inaugurate the unit on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Ghandhara Nissan Ltd was listed on the Karachi Stock Exchange after it went public in 1993. Its 10-rupee share closed 0.30 rupee down at 10.50 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Its sister company Ghandhara Nissan Diesel Ltd has manufactured trucks and buses since 1985, with a local content of 50 percent, the executive said.</p>
<p>He said production of Nissan Sunny cars would start with 31 percent of parts locally made, the same proportion as in cars made by competing companies.</p>
<p>Pakistan's three main established car manufacturers -- Pak-Suzuki Motor Co, Honda Atlas Cars and Indus Motors -- produced 38,436 cars in 1995/96 (July-June) compared to 31,239 in 1994/95, an analyst at KASB &amp; Co Ltd brokerage house said.</p>
<p>Pakistan needed 85,000 cars a year and had installed capacity to make 80,000, he added.</p>
<p>($1.00 = 40.22 rupees) -- Karachi newsroom 9221-5685192</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
