<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="528731" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Saks to buy Barneys, bring it out of Chapter 11.</title>
<headline>Saks to buy Barneys, bring it out of Chapter 11.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Upscale retailer Saks Holdings Inc. said Tuesday it plans to buy Barney's Inc., taking the luxury clothing store group out of bankruptcy with a cash and stock bid valued at $290 million.</p>
<p>The Saks plan has the approval of Tokyo conglomerate Isetan Co., which holds leases on three of Barney's flagship stores.</p>
<p>Saks said it and Isetan will submit their joint plan to a New York bankruptcy court for approval.</p>
<p>Barney's filed for bankruptcy in January 1996 and the retailer, home to exclusive fashions by Armani and other designers, has been involved in acrimonious legal wranglings with Isetan ever since.</p>
<p>Barney's, which grew from humble beginning as a bargain shop for men's and boys' clothing, has grown in recent years into a high-priced fashion trend-setter under the management of the original Barney's grandsons, Gene and Robert Pressman.</p>
<p>In a joint statement, Saks and Isetan said, &quot;We believe the Saks-Isetan Joint Plan offers a global settlement to, and is the most viable resolution for, all parties in the Barney's bankruptcy.</p>
<p>&quot;The combination of Saks and Isetan represents the strongest possible pairing of retailing and real estate expertise,&quot; according to the statement, released in New York.</p>
<p>Saks, owner of Saks Fifth Avenue stores, has had its eye on three of Barney's larger properties -- its stores in New York, Chicago and Beverley Hills.</p>
<p>&quot;The acquisition of Barney's is consistent with Saks' long-term objective of enhancing its presence in the domestic and international luxury goods markets. We expect this strategic investment will be accretive to Saks shareholders,&quot; Saks said.</p>
<p>Under terms of the plan, unsecured creditors would receive about 20 cents on the dollar.</p>
<p>Saks said the investment in Barney's would add to its earnings but it did not provide figures.</p>
<p>Isetan said it agreed to the Saks plan despite having to accept rents &quot;that are substantially below current market rates and the existing lease rates.&quot;</p>
<p>Isetan also said it will report a significant loss on its emergency loans to Barney's affiliated companies, which totalled nearly $200 million.</p>
<p>Separately, Saks estimated that its profits for the first quarter ending May 3 will be a lower than an expected 20 cents per share. In its fiscal fourth quarter, which includes the crucial holiday season, Saks earned $46.7 million, or 73 cents a share.</p>
<p>It said it based the projection on sales trends in March and April and expects to report sales of about $520 million for the quarter, lower than the $465 million posted for the same quarter itn its fiscal 1996.</p>
<p>Saks has 40 department stores, eight resort stores and three stand-alone stores led by its landmark flagship on New York's Fifth Avenue.</p>
<p>Isetan has seven full-scale department stores in the Tokyo area, including its flagship store in Shinjuku and subsidiary stores in Niigata and Shizuoka.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
