<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52876" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Euroyen, JGBs end firm after Japan GDP data.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Euroyen, JGBs end firm after Japan GDP data.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Euroyen futures ended firmer Friday on late buying after a mid-afternoon drop caused by Japan's higher-than-expected Gross Domestic Product.</p>
<p>March Euroyen slid to a low of 99.04 after the Economic Planning Agency reported that GDP fell a real 0.7 percent in the April to June period from the previous quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;The market came off but volume was very thin. It was mainly the local's selling,&quot; said a trader with a U.S. institution.</p>
<p>He added that the larger houses then bought March Euroyen back following the EPA's statement that it hoped the Bank of Japan would maintain its current monetary stance.  </p>
<p>&quot;Overall the Euroyen is still very bullish,&quot; he said, adding that March looked set to test its high of 99.18 and head towards 99.32 eventually.</p>
<p>The contract finished at 99.12 against a CME close at 99.09 on volume of 10,840 lots. Japanese government bond futures for December settled at 121.40 against their previous 121.26.</p>
<p>Eurodollar futures held onto their overnight gains after the release of a weak Producer Price Index, but activity was practically non-existent ahead of the CPI and retail sales data.</p>
<p>The most active December contract finished at 94.00 against its IMM settlement at 93.99 on 8,515 lots.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market has already built in a quarter percent U.S. rate hike. But people are backing off from the expectation that it could be half a percent,&quot; said a trader with another U.S. house.</p>
<p>The Federal Reserve is widely expected to hike its funds rate at its policy-setting meeting on September 24, reversing a 14-month string of three cuts, the last of which was in January.</p>
<p>-- Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
