<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="528990" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Beverly Q1 nursing home admissions rise.</title>
<headline>Beverly Q1 nursing home admissions rise.</headline>
<dateline>FORT SMITH, Ark. 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Beverly Enterprises Inc said Tuesday that first quarter nursing home admissions were up nearly four percent from a year earlier.</p>
<p>Beverly reported first quarter earnings of $0.19 a share, compared to $0.14 in the 1996 first quarter.</p>
<p>Revenues per patient day rose nearly seven percent, but overall occupancy declined 75 basis points, it said.</p>
<p>The company said the comparisons reflect the continuing trend toward shorter stays by higher acuity patients.  </p>
<p>It said more complex treatments for such patients generate higher revenue, which translates into higher operating margins.</p>
<p>Dependency on Medicaid dropped by more than one percentage point for the quarter, Beverly said.</p>
<p>Total operating profits from nursing home operations were up more than 11 percent from the first quarter of 1996, even though the business unit operated 39 fewer facilities.</p>
<p>Beverly said that in 1997 it will build or expand 17 skilled nursing centers, adding more than 800 beds to its capacity, and will begin construction of eight other centers that will add another 890 beds by year-end 1998.</p>
<p>At Beverly Health and Rehabilitation Services, on a same-facility basis, the core business unit achieved a &quot;sharp&quot; increase in operating profits on a three percent increase in revenues, the company said.</p>
<p>The unit's profit margin rose by nearly 150 basis points.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FORT SMITH, Ark."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
