<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="529093" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Scotland's grains look good, weather worries muted.</title>
<headline>Scotland's grains look good, weather worries muted.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scotland's new cereals crop is developing well, with few of the weather worries which have affected parts of England and the western continent, farming experts around the country said.</p>
<p>&quot;Currently we're doing very nicely thank-you,&quot; Dr David Cranstoun of the Scottish Agricultural College told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;If anything this season we're a bit ahead of normal,&quot; he said, pointing out that Scottish grains are normally well behind their English counterparts.</p>
<p>Crops were looking well set up, but there was still a lot to play for.</p>
<p>There had been a period of dry weather, which came to an end over the weekend, with the arrival Sunday of colder, wet weather. The rain had been &quot;just what we needed. We could probably do with a bit more.&quot; Cranstoun said.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't suffered as yet from drought,&quot; one co-op manager in the north of Scotland said. &quot;There's been a reasonable start to spring. It's been warmer than normal and the crops are moving on apace,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>And even if there were a period without rain, Scotland was better placed than England to withstand it. &quot;The water table is not particularly low. There's not the same potential for drought,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another co-op manager, further to the south and east, remarked on a different problem altogether. &quot;Some of our winter crops look quite poor,&quot; he said. The reason was not obvious, but he put it down to early frost in October or November.</p>
<p>&quot;Spring crops look quite good,&quot; he said. But there were concerns over depleted soil moisture reserves.</p>
<p>The area of wheat in Scotland is 107,000 hectares, according to the Scottish Office's December census.</p>
<p>This is 3.7 per cent up on the area a year earlier. The census covers crops sown by December 1, 1996.</p>
<p>The area of barley is up 22.9 per cent at 80,000 hectares. The area of oilseed rape is 6.0 per cent higher at 34,000 hectares.</p>
<p>--Christopher Lyddon, London newsroom +44 171 542 7928</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
