<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52914" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks end week up 1.31 pct on fund buying.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks end week up 1.31 pct on fund buying.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks, rendered directionless by several bouts of profit-taking earlier on Friday, closed the week up as speculators and a support fund bought stocks, brokers said.</p>
<p>The SET index, in negative zone most of the day, began rising steadily in the afternoon and closed up 13.44 points at 1,039.65. The SET-50 index rose 1.28 points to 79.62.</p>
<p>&quot;The index rose after the private rescue fund along with speculators bought shares,&quot; said Lan Pajasalmi of First Asia Securities. This was the third straight day the market finished firm.  </p>
<p>Part of the 15.7 billion baht fund set up by private banks and brokerage houses in August has been invested in the market to boost the battered market since last Friday, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Friday's buying also came as investors believed that there may be some political changes after a no-confidence debate next week,&quot; Lan said.</p>
<p>Opposition parties are expected to attack Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa during the no-confidence debate set to begin in parliament next Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Large capitalised Thai Farmers Bank topped the active list, rising three baht to 170. Cogeneration gained 8.50 to 95.50 while Advanced Info Service rose 14 to 326 and Krung Thai Bank slipped two to 101.</p>
<p>Support is seen at 1,025 points and resistance at 1,046 on Monday, brokers said.</p>
<p>-- Suthep Chawla (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
