<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="529171" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Ldn gold under pressure, platinum holds firm.</title>
<headline>Ldn gold under pressure, platinum holds firm.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold traded sideways on Tuesday after being exhausted by unsuccessful attempts to erode overhead resistance, and was seen backing off towards the lows again.</p>
<p>Platinum stayed firm above $380.00 an ounce amid concerns over delayed Russian supplies leading to a tight forward market.</p>
<p>&quot;With platinum and palladium it can just be one non-delivery that does this,&quot; said one London dealer. &quot;While non-deliveries are taking place the market is going to be tight and well-bid, but the minute they are not then it won't be,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>By 1030 GMT, spot platinum was quoted at $380.75/$381.75, just 25 cents up. Palladium gained 50 cents to $156.00/$157.00.</p>
<p>Analysts saw scope for a rally in platinum to $385.00 while the mystery surrounding Russian exports plagued the market.</p>
<p>Prices were lifted last week by rumours that Moscow might have delayed the delivery of a gold swap for PGM collateralised against a Swiss bank loan. The swap has not been confirmed.</p>
<p>Markets are also unnerved by disruptions caused by delays in Russian exports to Japan, the world's biggest PGM importer. It is still not clear when Russia may begin talks to resume exports delayed since December over supposedly bureaucratic problems.</p>
<p>Platinum prices were still in a backwardation with swap rates at minus four percent, and lease rates around 9-9.5.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is very speculative. We are advising customers to leave it alone,&quot; said one Swiss trader.</p>
<p>Gold was trapped in a thin range but dealers said failure to regain the $345.00 resistance level could force the market down to last week's lows of $337.50.</p>
<p>One dealer noted producer selling at $343.00. He expected that producers were likely to hedge more and further out.</p>
<p>&quot;Each time it gets up there ($343) it gets stopped. It looks like the market is going to go and test lower levels. If it doesn't hold above $336 then I think we'll see it down to $300,&quot; said the dealer.</p>
<p>Technical analyst Karen Jones of Credit Suisse First Boston said if gold could maintain a foothold over $345.00 it would &quot;alleviate downside pressure and at least suggest that it will hold sideways rather than go down.&quot;</p>
<p>Silver edged three cents higher to $4.76/$4.78 an ounce but analysts were watching last week's high of $4.85 to clear the way for a rally.</p>
<p>Failure to hold above the $4.60 area would signal a sell off to $4.33, Jones said.</p>
<p>-- Clelia Oziel, London Newsroom +44-171-542 8071</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
