<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52922" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine wheat stocks rise on bread cancer scare.</title>
<headline>Philippine wheat stocks rise on bread cancer scare.</headline>
<byline>Dolly Aglay</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most Philippine flour millers are likely to stay out of the grain market next week due to a build-up in stocks caused by a slowdown in local bread sales after a cancer scare, traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>Traders said most local millers were fully stocked for the next two months, although one company has invited tenders for two 12,500 tonne-lots of dark northern spring wheat with 13.5 percent and 14 percent protein content and another 10,000 tonnes of western white wheat.  </p>
<p>&quot;The firm rejected all bids in the past two days due to high prices,&quot; said one trader who participated in the bidding.</p>
<p>Traders said local millers had bought 101,900 tonnes of U.S. wheat, including 34,000 tonnes of soft winter wheat diverted from China, in the past two weeks.</p>
<p>Philippine millers said a slowdown in sales of pan de sal, small bread rolls that are a favourite breakfast fare for Filipinos, had affected their flour sales and caused wheat stocks to rise.  </p>
<p>&quot;Bread sales dropped by 20 percent in the past two months due to a cancer scare on pan de sal,&quot; Philippine Association of Flour Millers Inc executive director Ric Pinca told Reuters.</p>
<p>Pinca said fears that potassium bromate, which is used by local bakers to give pan de sal a fluffy texture, might cause cancer, had depressed local bread sales.</p>
<p>Health authorities have given local flour millers and bakers until the end of the month to look for an alternative to potassium bromate.  </p>
<p>PAFMIL and local bakers said they have not found a suitable alternative and that there were no studies to show the use of potassium bromate in small quantities caused cancer in humans.</p>
<p>Traders said the prevailing retail price of hard flour, used in making bread, in Metro Manila was unchanged at 300 pesos ($11.53) per 25 kg this week.</p>
<p>The price of soft flour, used in making cakes and pastries, also remained wedged at 285 pesos ($10.96) per 25 kg.</p>
<p>But domestic corn prices have softened.  </p>
<p>The state-owned National Food Authority said the average retail price of yellow corn dropped to 10.27 pesos (39.5 cents) per kg from 10.38 pesos (39.92 cents) last week, while the average retail price of white corn slipped to 11.22 pesos (43.15 cents) per kg from 11.25 pesos (43.26 cents).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
