<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="529247" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: MOST BANK SHARES UP IN HEAVY BEIRUT TRADE.</title>
<headline>MOST BANK SHARES UP IN HEAVY BEIRUT TRADE.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of Beirut rose to $3.625 on Tuesday from $3.5 and dealers said a 29.61 percent rise in the bank's net profits in the first quarter of 1997 is expected to sustain high demand for the share.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a positive sign. It justifies BOB's current price level and should sustain demand for the share,&quot; Broker-analyst Johnny Yacoub of Financial Funds Advisors said.</p>
<p>BOB said on Monday that its unaudited net profits rose 29.61 percent to $1,593,000 in the first three months of 1997 from $1,229,000 at the end of the first quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>Total BSE turnover more than doubled on Tuesday to 915,701 shares against Monday's 451,342. Value rose to $5,610,320 from $2,656,960.</p>
<p>Banque Libanaise pour le Commerce continued a price rally reaching $15.625 from $15.5 a day earlier while Banque Audi traded at $20 for the fourth day.</p>
<p>The LIBX bank index rose 1.45 percent to 135.72 percent. The BLOM general index fell 0.29 percent to 911.50 and the LISPI fell 0.26 percent to 86.95.</p>
<p>&quot;The LISPI was down despite great interest in the bank shares because of a 4.6 percent decrease in Eternit and a 2.4 percent decrease in Ciments Libanais shares,&quot; Alain Balian, deputy manager at Beirut finance house Lebanon Invest said.</p>
<p>Demand for BOB was 1,152,566 from Monday's 1,207,095. Supply was 629,606 shares, all of which were sold. Monday's turnover was 253,372.</p>
<p>Demand for BLC totalled 46,012 against a supply of 41,512. Turnover was 24,012 shares. Demand for Audi was 55,138 shares against 28,468 shares in supply, all of which were sold.</p>
<p>&quot;The excessive demand for BOB in the first stages of listing signified the high demand for bank shares,&quot; Yacoub said.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand on Audi is still very strong, indicating an upward trend that will be maintained in the long run,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>BOB, BLC and Banque Audi have jumped 67 percent, 39 percent and 33 percent respectively since they made their debuts on April 11, December 30 and January 20.</p>
<p>A block of 10,000 BOB shares traded on the floor at $3.687 while a block of 42,500 Audi shares traded at $20 on the exchange.</p>
<p>Eternit fell to $1.9375 from $2.0312 on turnover of 44,500 shares from 10,000 shares a day earlier. Ciments Libanais was also down at $1.25 from $1.2812 on turnover of 500 shares againt Monday's 20,000 shares.</p>
<p>Solidere A and B shares were unchanged at $10.25 and $10.75 respectively.</p>
<p>There was no trade in Ciments Blancs and Uniceramic.</p>
<p>-Beirut editorial (9611) 745308 602057</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
