<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="529410" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE - Sometimes a mob boss should be nice to the little guys.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Sometimes a mob boss should be nice to the little guys.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>What do you do when the boss gets uppity, his head starts to swell, his suits get too expensive, the media start treating him like a hero and he starts thinking he's the whole &quot;Cosa Nostra&quot;?</p>
<p>Even more importantly, what do you do when you think the boss is trying to set you up and make you take the fall for all his bad business decisions, like rubbing out the previous boss in front of a busy New York steakhouse?</p>
<p>For Salvatore &quot;Sammy the Bull&quot; Gravano, what you do is blow the whistle, turn government informant, sing like a bird and send the boss, Gambino crime family head John Gotti, up the river to the big house for life and then some.</p>
<p>Gravano is the most important mob informant in U.S. history, the man who brought down &quot;the Dapper Don&quot; and who now supposedly has a million-dollar price tag on his head -- if the mob can find him.</p>
<p>He starred in a two-hour interview on ABC that aired last week and is the all-too-willing subject of a book that extols, within limits, his virtues as a whistle-blower and tries to tell you what makes Sammy run.</p>
<p>Peter Maas, author of &quot;Underboss,&quot; a book based on hours of interviews with Gravano, says he turned informant because he got sick of Gotti's megalomania and also because Gotti was setting him up to go to jail for life.</p>
<p>The book is a rare true-life foray into the inner workings of the American Mafia as told by a loyal soldier who rose through the ranks, taking part in 19 killings along the way. But more than that it is the story of the fall of Gotti, whose flamboyant criminality made him a media star.</p>
<p>CELEBRITY STATUS</p>
<p>Few criminals courted the public spotlight as Gotti did, and few thumbed their noses not only at the federal government but at his own bosses as Gotti did. &quot;Underboss&quot; argues that Gotti brought himself down by his arrogance after he took over the Gambino crime family by murdering its boss, Paul Castellano, in 1985.</p>
<p>When the two were charged with murder and racketeering in the early 1990s, Gotti refused to let Gravano have his own lawyer or have his case severed because Gotti planned to blame the worst crimes on his loyal lieutenant and opt for a shorter sentence himself. It was a devastating career move.</p>
<p>Maas says the two mobsters had a frank boss-to-worker discussion in jail one day, after the late-sleeping Gotti finally decided to get out of bed. Gravano said he asked Gotti to let him have a separate trial and was told: &quot;Sammy, a severance? I told you. What would my public think? They would think you don't want to go on trial with me.&quot;</p>
<p>But &quot;The Bull,&quot; furious at the way Gotti was running the crime family, pressed on. &quot;I said, 'You want me to go to prison for the rest of my life without even trying to fight for myself because of what the public may think?'&quot; he told Maas.</p>
<p>GOTTI GIVES WRONG ANSWER</p>
<p>Then, Gravano said, he heard the answer that made him decide to turn informer and change mob history.</p>
<p>&quot;John says, 'Sammy, you got to understand this. It's not about me now. Everything has to be to save Cosa Nostra, which is John Gotti. Cosa Nostra needs John Gotti. You got a problem with that?'&quot;</p>
<p>Sorry John, he did.</p>
<p>This idea that Gotti and Cosa Nostra were one and the same outraged Gravano, who, Maas said, believed that organised crime was based on respect and loyality -- a true fellowship in the business of killing, stealing and skimming off the top.</p>
<p>&quot;Gotti's own megalomania did him in. Sammy always said Gotti was a gambler who only talked about his losses, never his wins, and that deep down he wanted to lose. Gotti would still be around if he didn't thumb his nose at the Feds and didn't try to set Sammy up,&quot; Maas told Reuters.</p>
<p>Gotti, sentenced to life in prison without parole in 1992, might have been free today if he was more sensitive to the needs of his employees -- or, of course, if Sammy had followed orders. But, Maas said, after a lifetime of respecting others in the crime family &quot;the Bull&quot; decided to put his self-respect first.</p>
<p>To the public, Gravano was a rat, the betrayer of a modern-day Robin Hoodlum straight out of &quot;The Godfather&quot; movies. So, Maas says, &quot;Sammy the Bull&quot; decided to colloborate on a book and tell his side.</p>
<p>Maas, whose previous books include the bestseller &quot;Serpico,&quot; says Gravano talked and talked because what he really wanted was his day in the court of public opinion.</p>
<p>The author says Gravano was fairly easy to work with -- telling his tale in a matter-of-fact manner. He did get mad at Maas once and the author says it was a fairly hairy moment.</p>
<p>&quot;His eyes turned blank, like they were all blue. But frankly I had a lot more trouble with other subjects, like Serpico,&quot; Maas said, referring to Frank Serpico, who blew the whistle on corruption in the New York City police department.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
