<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="529528" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Autoliv posts Q1 profit on target, market relieved.</title>
<headline>Autoliv posts Q1 profit on target, market relieved.</headline>
<byline>Birgitta Forsberg</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish car safety equipment group Autoliv released a first quarter profit largely in line with expectations on Tuesday and its share rose in relief.</p>
<p>Autoliv posted a five percent rise in pre-tax profit in the first three months of the year to 316 million crowns following higher sales, further integration and continued cost cutting.</p>
<p>The profit was marginally lower than the expected 319 million crowns found by a Reuter poll of analysts.</p>
<p>The report sent Autoliv's share higher and at 1110 GMT it was changing hands at 292 crowns, up three from its Monday close.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was reassured that the report did not contain any nasty surprises,&quot; Peter Lawrence, analyst at Kleinwort Benson, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Drugs major Astra shocked the market on Monday by reporting a one percent rise in first quarter earnings which was 500 million crowns lower than expected and made players fear more bad news, analysts said.</p>
<p>In addition, there were some worries about the weak French car market having a negative impact on earnings, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Autoliv has warned somewhat of the downturn on the French car market and market players had possibly worried about a weaker than expected profit,&quot; said Gunnar Andersson, analyst at Handelsbanken, explaining the share rise.</p>
<p>Autoliv's sales rose to 3.26 billion crowns from 2.98 billion in the first quarter of 1996 and earnings per share advanced to 3.78 crowns from 3.50 crowns.</p>
<p>Its operating profit rose to 303 million crowns from 284 million, while its operating margin slipped to 9.3 percent from 9.5 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The report did not contain any surprises and at least key figures, such as sales and operating margin, were as expected,&quot; Andersson said.</p>
<p>&quot;Autoliv shows a strong development as the underlying car production was flat or lower on some, for Autoliv important, markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Sales of air bags and steering wheels rose nine percent to 1.6 billion crowns and sales of seat belts, including seat components, rose nine percent to 1.7 billion crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;Sales of seat belt pre-tensioners have kept developing well,&quot; the company said. &quot;In addition, Autoliv's market share for regular seat belts has increased slightly.&quot;</p>
<p>Autoliv is expecting to be able to merge with Morton Automotive Safety Products, the car safety equipment unit of U.S. Morton, in early May, creating Autoliv Inc..</p>
<p>&quot;The merger is very positive and the company will have very good potential,&quot; Andersson said.</p>
<p>-- Birgitta Forsberg, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1006</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
