<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="529939" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: TOCOM precious metals end higher, led by platinum.</title>
<headline>TOCOM precious metals end higher, led by platinum.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo precious metal futures ended mostly higher on Tuesday, led by gains in platinum group metals, as the yen's dip and firmer bullion prices in platinum group metals helped lift prices, traders said.</p>
<p>Gold futures ranged from six yen to eight yen per gram higher. Benchmark February was up seven yen at 1,380 yen.</p>
<p>Platinum futures ranged from 13 yen to 27 yen per gram higher, with benchmark February up 13 yen at 1,484 yen.</p>
<p>&quot;Buying interest in platinum group metals in the spot market remains strong,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>Some traders said the ongoing meeting between visiting Russian central bank officials and several Japanese trade houses this week spooked the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Rumours that the Russian central bank would be able to sell the platinum group metals (PGM) have circulated in the market. We are concerned about in what way Russia resumes the PGM exports,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Platinum and palladium short-term lease rates remained at high levels of 11-12 percent, reflecting a tightening of spot markets, the traders said.  </p>
<p>Selling on price rallies capped the upside of platinum futures, while massive short positions still held by private investors in palladium futures may put further upward pressure on palladium prices, the traders said.</p>
<p>Palladium futures ranged from five yen to 14 yen per gram higher. Benchmark February was up eight yen at 605 yen.</p>
<p>In the spot bullion market, spot gold was quoted at $341.35/65 per ounce in 0739 GMT, against $342.70/343.10 in New York on Monday. Benchmark February silver was up 1.6 yen per 10 grams at 194.7 yen.</p>
<p>--Tokyo Commodity Desk, +81-3-3432-7431</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
