<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="530142" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Dollar firms to 125.50 yen, 1.7010 marks in Tokyo.</title>
<headline>Dollar firms to 125.50 yen, 1.7010 marks in Tokyo.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>ASIAN FOREX ACTIVITY:</p>
<p>0129 GMT</p>
<p>*Dollar firmed to around 125.50 yen and 1.7010 marks in mid-morning Tokyo on buying interest by U.S. funds on dips and short-covering, which in turn pushed mark down against yen.</p>
<p>*Medium-sized Japanese life insurer said to be involved in currency dealing, buying dollars at around 125.30 yen and selling them above 125.50 yen, dealers said.</p>
<p>*Relatively large amount of dollar buying orders at around 1.6950-60 marks helped push dollar higher, although views mixed among dealers over direction of dollar/mark in near term.  </p>
<p>*Political uncertainty ahead of elections in some countries in Europe, such as France and Britain, have encouraged operators to shift to marks as safe-haven currency.</p>
<p>*This strengthened mark against dollar overnight. But some dealers said mark buying for dollar mostly complete.</p>
<p>*&quot;I don't think that the dollar/mark has moved out of 1.700-1.7500 mark range,&quot; said a U.S. bank dealer. &quot;There were relatively solid bids at around 1.6960 marks.&quot;</p>
<p>*Offers detected at around 125.60 yen and above, with many dealers expecting dollar/yen to stay range-bound ahead of G7 nations' meeting on Sunday in Washington.  </p>
<p>0021 GMT</p>
<p>*Dollar edged up against yen in early Tokyo, partly helped by rise in mark/yen rate as some traders sought to cover mark/yen short positions.</p>
<p>*Earlier, dollar fell against mark on selling by short-term players after renewed mark strength pushed dollar/mark rates below 1.70 marks overnight.</p>
<p>*Ministry of Finance (MOF) said Japan will tell Group of Seven (G7) that its trade surplus will not mount and that G7 meeting is to confirm Berlin agreement on foreign exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
