<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="530359" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan seeks to soothe US fears on car trade.</title>
<headline>Japan seeks to soothe US fears on car trade.</headline>
<byline>Linda Sieg</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior Japanese trade official on Tuesday sought to soothe U.S. fears over a potential surge in Japan's trade surplus, predicting that a recent flood of car exports to the United States would not continue unabated.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not think that the present auto export trend will continue in the same manner as we have seen in the first quarter of the year,&quot; Japan's Vice Minister for International Trade Hisashi Hosokawa told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;So in total, if you look at 1997 as a whole, I think in effect that Japanese exports, particularly to the United States, will not be that worrisome,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>U.S. officials have been sounding the alarm over a potential resurgence of Japan's trade surplus.</p>
<p>Worried that Tokyo's efforts to cut its big budget deficit through higher taxes and less public spending will sap its economy, Washington is seeking assurances that Japan's recovery will be powered by domestic demand, not exports.</p>
<p>U.S. Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky said last Friday that she was worried by trade trends that emerged in late 1996 and early 1997, particularly a surge in Japanese car imports into the U.S. market in the first three months of 1997.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka, however, said on Tuesday that there was little cause for concern.</p>
<p>&quot;I would...like to tell them that there are hardly any worries that the surplus will mount, although I cannot say that there is no possibility at all,&quot; Mitsuzuka said, referring to a meeting of Group of Seven (G7) finance ministers and central bankers in Washington this weekend.</p>
<p>Hosokawa, meanwhile, said Japanese car makers' plans to boost output of new products in the United States later this year would help ameliorate the trend of rising car exports -- a key element of the two-way trade gap with the United States.</p>
<p>Economic issues will come up when U.S. President Bill Clinton and Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto meet in Washington on Friday but are unlikely to dominate the talks, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The coming summit meeting...will most likely focus on the political side and security-related issues, but I don't deny that they will also discuss to some extent economic issues,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;That is my prediction -- it's totally up to them -- and yet in light of the present environment surrounding the heads of the two countries, that is my view.&quot;</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry said on Monday that Clinton and Hashimoto would talk about the need for Japan to increase demand for imports from the United States and that there would be &quot;some discussion of trade issues&quot; at the talks.</p>
<p>Hosokawa also said it would be logical to expect Hashimoto to reaffirm his commitment to cutting the red tape critics say strangles Japan's economy when he meets Clinton.</p>
<p>&quot;Logically, a deregulation programme should be of great help to imports to the Japanese market,&quot; he said, adding that Hashimoto was &quot;firmly determined&quot; to carry out economic reforms, including deregulation.</p>
<p>Hosokawa also said the yen's recent weakness might reduce the pressure on some firms to restructure.</p>
<p>&quot;In light of the present yen rate, some companies may well find it easier to be competitive, and yet they need to be further restructured,&quot; he said. &quot;However, in the present environment, such (restructuring) spirit, I'm afraid, might be somewhat lessened.&quot;</p>
<p>The yen has fallen more than 50 percent against the dollar from a post-war high of 79.75 hit on April 19, 1995. The Japanese currency was trading at about 125.73 to the dollar at around midday on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
