<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="530342" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Emerging Europe Advertising &amp; Media Digest - Apr22.</title>
<headline>Emerging Europe Advertising &amp; Media Digest - Apr22.</headline>
<text>
<p>REUTERS EMERGING EUROPE PRESS DIGEST FOR ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA</p>
<p>--------------- April 22, 1997 ------------------</p>
<p>Weekly Press Digest from Central and Eastern Europe on Advertising, Marketing, the Media, the Internet, Brand-name Products and Markets</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>ADVERTISING &amp; MARKETING:</p>
<p>-- Ad agency Marcom and Massprom sends two million Polish households recipes, consumer opinion forms and product information about food company Winiary, which is controlled by Nestle. The mailing will help Winiary get direct customer feedback. (Marketing Polska, April 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Dove Chocolate advertising campaign carried out by Master Foods late last year pushed up Dove's daily sales in November and December by 1,000 percent, the company said. (Marketing Polska, April 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Insurer Nationale Nederlanden has appointed Ceska Reklamnias its marketing communication agency for the Czech market, ending its five-year relatiosnhip with Young &amp; Rubicam Praha. (Strategie News, April 9-16, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- The fifth annual Marketing, Design and Communication trade fair will be held in the Czech Republic's Brno exhibition centre May 20-23. More than 150 exhibitors from four countries will be represented. (Pravo, April 16, 1997)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>MEDIA AND THE INTERNET:</p>
<p>-- In the first three months of 1997 commercials accounted for an average three percent of broadcast time on Hungary's two public service channels. (Vilaggazdasag, April 15, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Cosmopolitan Magazine has launched a Polish edition -- the 31st national edition of the U.S. women's monthly. Cosmopolitan will be published in Poland by a 50-50 joint venture of Hearst Magazines International and Swiss publisher Juerg Marquard. (Dziennik Prawa i Gospodarki, April 17,1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Television channel Prima, has increased its signal in the Czech Republic to 70 perent, its general ratings to seven percent and its prime time ratings to nine percent. Viewers are tuning in for series such as Commissioner Rex, and &quot;It shouldn't happen to a vet&quot;. The most successful programme on Prima is the light-hearted musical contest Carusosou. (Pravo, April 15, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- The Czech Army may be cut off from the Internet because its Internet expert is moving to another job.(Pravo, April 15, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- The last issue of the daily Prazske Noviny was published on March 28. The newspaper was launched in the Czech market last September with a controversial advertising campaign, which sparked complaints about images described as racist and sexist. (Strategie News, April 9-16, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- CRo 1-Radiozurnal is the Czech Republic's most popular radio station. The most read magazines are Playboy and Penthouse, according to a survey from Rapid Dema. (Strategie News, April 9-16, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Cable television channels HBO, Max 1 and Super Max should become more accessible throughout the Czech Republic in April, because they are being connected to the Kabel Plus network and its subsidiaries. (Strategie News, April 9-16, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- A brokerage house for the bank Dom Maklerski Banku Ochrony Srodowiska has started a Stocks OnLine service to give customers access to investment vehicles via the Internet. (Gazeta Bankowa, April 13, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- A trial operation of an electronic system which measures Czech TV watching began on April 17. (Lidove Noviny, April 18,1997)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>BRAND-NAME PRODUCTS AND MARKETS:</p>
<p>-- Glaxo Wellcome has started a free telephone line in Poland providing information on Zovirax, a cold sore ointment which is currently being advertised in women's magazines. (Marketing Polska, April 1997) *********</p>
<p>-- France's Auchan supermarket chain will construct a 26 hectare supermarket and shopping complex worth 120 million zlotys ($38.2 million) on the outskirts of Gdansk, in northern Poland. The chain will set up a further 10 supermarket and shopping centres in urban areas around Poland in the next five years. (Dziennik Prawa i Gospodarki, April 17, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- As part of efforts to fight audio piracy in Bulgaria, Virgin Records, the local representative of Polygram, said it would organise the promotion of the INXS album Elegantly Wasted in Sofia. Representatives of big record companies have begun to launch promotions in Bulgaria, in part to prevent music piracy. (Troud, April 14, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Microsoft Praha s.r.o., the Czech unit of Microsoft, dominates more than 90 percent of the Czech market for operations systems and 75 percent of the market for office applications. The newest product from Microsoft Praha is Microsoft Office 97, of which 160,000 copies have been sold. (Pravo, April 16, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Balirny Douwe Egberts has released a line of new products in the Czech Republic, including tea and instant coffee. The products are part of the company's strategy to create a new image. The company will keep its old slogan -- &quot;Coffee for a moment of comfort -- but will also change the tone of its advertisements. (Strategie News, April 9-16, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Germany's Praktiker supermarket chain will open its first home-improvement megastore in Janki, at the outskirts of Warsaw, in April. The chain plans to open 40 such stores around the country in the next seven years. (Zycie, April 16, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Car sales grew by ten percent in Hungary in the first quarter, with demand for small-sized cars up by almost 90 percent year-on-year. Suzuki held its leading position in the market, followed by Opel and Volkswagen. But car importers say they expect a decline in sales this year. (Vilaggazdasag, April 16,1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- IKEA plans to open a new department store in Budapest and intends to launch a nationwide direct mail service, with a view towards becoming a furniture retailer for all of Hungary, not just the capital. A final decision on the new development can be expected at the end of next month. (Vilaggazdasag, April 15,1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Rabadrinks Kft, which recently acquired a fifty percent stake in Hungarian drinks maker Gyori Likorgyar Rt, plans to start producing and bottling the Martini Bitter brand from the second half of 1997. (Vilaggazdasag, April 17, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Hungary is the largest goose liver producer in the world, with the annual output worth 30 million dollars. Seventy percent of the goose liver production is exported to France. (Napi Gazdasag, April 14, 1997)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>-- Reuters London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2792</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>See more stories on Central and Eastern Europe and the rest of the world on Reuters Advertising &amp; Media Briefing. Why not visit our Internet site at http://www.bizinfo.reuters.com?</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>($ = 30.36 Czech Crowns)</p>
<p>($ = 180.6 Hungarian Forints)</p>
<p>($ = 3.14 Polish Zlotys)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
