<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53053" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Tenaga popularity seen growing again.</title>
<headline>Tenaga popularity seen growing again.</headline>
<byline>Azhar Sukri</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian state-controlled electric utility Tenaga Nasional Bhd, facing a barrage of criticism over the latest nationwide blackout, may have become the blue chip investors hate to love but cannot leave.</p>
<p>Operations of the country's dominant electricity generator and only power distributor are being scrutinised after the second massive blackout in four years plunged peninsular Malaysia into darkness for over 12 hours on Aug. 3.</p>
<p>The stock, which was trading at 10.50 ringgit ($4.20) on July 31, stood at 8.75 ringgit in intraday trading on Friday, just five cents above its year low.</p>
<p>But even though questions are being raised over Tenaga's viability as an efficient and reliable power utility company, fund managers say they cannot afford to completely drop their exposure to the stock.</p>
<p>They note Tenaga, which is about 70 percent owned by the government, is still the second-largest capitalised company on the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange after state-controlled telecommunications utility Telekom Malaysia Bhd.</p>
<p>Telekom's weightage on the Composite Index, which comprises Malaysia's 100 largest companies, amounts to 12 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Tenaga is under no threat of losing its monopoly,&quot; said a foreign fund manager.</p>
<p>Chong Chang Choong, general manager of investments at KL Mutual, a fund management company, said on Friday that he was accumulating Tenaga stock.</p>
<p>&quot;At current levels of around 8.70-8.80 ringgit we feel there is minimal downside potential. We are not an index-linked fund, so until now we have not had Tenaga in our portfolio. But now we are buying Tenaga and reducing our exposure to Telekom.&quot;</p>
<p>Chong is convinced that last month's blackout was a purely technical fault and did not reflect Tenaga's inherent viability.</p>
<p>After the blackout, Tenaga's chief executive Ani Arope was replaced by outsider Ahmad Tajuddin Ali beginning this month. The company has blamed a faulty circuit breaker for the breakdown and U.K. consultant National Grid Group was appointed late last month to review Tenaga's operations.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been a major disappointment,&quot; said a local analyst. Fund managers seem to agree, noting that the overall weightage of Tenaga stock on the benchmark Composite Index had fallen from around 10 percent in 1994 to just 7.5 percent now.</p>
<p>&quot;There are now more companies to choose from, especially if one is looking for 'power' plays. Companies like YTL Bhd and Malakoff Bhd provide good value, but even these are currently fairly priced,&quot; said another foreign fund manager.</p>
<p>When asked about the possibility of Tenaga being restructured, with a total of three separate vehicles being listed, he said, &quot;the split would result in the impact of Tenaga being lowered. Investors could choose to invest only in the most profitable parts of the company.&quot;</p>
<p>The Malaysian government has warned that it is premature to assume such a split, proposed last October, will happen.</p>
<p>&quot;The Ministry of Finance Inc, which has a majority stake in the utility firm, has not made any decision on the restructuring,&quot; Deputy Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim said on Thursday. ($1=2.5 ringgit)</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603 230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
