<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="530598" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IBM strong Q1 fueled by growth businesses.</title>
<headline>IBM strong Q1 fueled by growth businesses.</headline>
<dateline>ARMONK, N.Y. 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>International Business Machines Corp on Wednesday reported better-than-expected first-quarter earnings, surpassing most Wall Street estimates, as its faster-growing businesses offset a decline in mainframes, minicomputers and workstations.</p>
<p>It said its revenues rose five percent to $17.3 billion compared with the first quarter of 1996, but they were up nine percent in constant currency terms, before the impact of the stronger dollar.  </p>
<p>IBM said first-quarter net earnings were $1.2 billion, or $2.37 per share, compared with $2.21 per share in the first quarter of 1996, excluding a charge to cover costs related to two acquisitions in March 1996. Including the charge, year-ago first-quarter earnings were $1.41 per share.</p>
<p>The First Call consensus earnings estimate for the first quarter of 1997 was $2.28 per share.</p>
<p>Lou Gerstner, IBM chairman and chief executive, said: &quot;As expected, our server business was adversely affected by product transitions, most notably within our System/390 division, and by ongoing weakness in Europe.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said the weakness in Europe hurt sales of IBM's AS/400 minicomputer systems. His reference to System/390 alludes to the company's mainframe business.</p>
<p>But he said excellent results in fast-growing businesses more than offset weakness in server computer lines.</p>
<p>&quot;We continued to see strong performance in the first quarter in fast-growth areas including services, personal computers and certain distributed software such as Lotus Notes and Tivoli systems-management products,&quot; Gerstner said.</p>
<p>The top IBM executive also said he was pleased by the results of the company's data-storage business.  </p>
<p>IBM said North American revenues rose 14 percent versus the year-ago first quarter to $7.9 billion. Asia-Pacific revenues rose three percent to $3.4 billion, while Latin America rose two percent to $701 million.</p>
<p>Revenues from IBM's Europe/Middle East/Africa region fell seven percent to $5.3 billlion.</p>
<p>Excluding the effect of currency translation, Asia-Pacific revenues grew 14 percent and Europe/Middle East/Africa was up one percent.  </p>
<p>Hardware sales totaled $7.8 billion in the first quarter, little changed from the same period of 1996, it said.</p>
<p>Personal computer and PC-based server computer revenues increased, while RS/6000 workstation, AS/400 minicomputer and System/390 mainframe revenues fell, the computer maker said.</p>
<p>Revenues from the company's storage business increased by an unspecified amount in part because of strong sales of hard disk drive products.</p>
<p>First-quarter services revenues reached $4.1 billion, a 28 percent increase over the same quarter of 1996. IBM said it signed services deals worth $3 billion in the first quarter.  </p>
<p>Software revenues declined three percent to $2.9 billion in the first quarter versus the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Shipments of Tivoli systems management products used to manage the networked computer systems of large enterprises more than doubled year over year, it said.</p>
<p>The Lotus Notes installed base of users rose by about 1.7 million seats, or computer users, bringing the total installed base of computers running Lotus Notes to 11 million seats.  </p>
<p>It said hardware revenues grew five percent on a constant currency basis, while service revenues rose 34 percent and software revenues rose two percent on that basis.</p>
<p>Maintenance revenues, which are largely associated with servicing IBM's vast mainframe computer business, declined eight percent year over year to $1.6 billion, while revenues from rentals and financing rose four percent to $899 million.</p>
<p>The total gross profit margin slipped to 38.1 percent in the first quarter from 40.9 percent in the first quarter of last year, the company said.  </p>
<p>Total expenses in the first quarter were &quot;essentially flat&quot; compared with the first quarter of 1996. IBM said its expense-to-revenue ratio improved by 1.5 percentage points in the first quarter versus a year ago.</p>
<p>IBM's tax rate was 35.5 percent in the first quarter compared with 39.0 percent in the first quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>It said it spent about $2.0 billion buying back shares during the first quarter, leaving about $800 million remaining under its current share buyback authorization.</p>
<p>The average number of common shares outstanding was reduced to 501.7 million in the latest quarter versus 544.3 million in the year-earlier period.</p>
<p>IBM said its &quot;core&quot; debt, excluding customer financing, was unchanged from the $2.2 billion at the end of 1996. Debt supporting IBM's global credit operations rose $817 million to $21.4 billion from $20.6 billion at the end of 1996.</p>
<p>((-- Eric Auchard, New York newsdesk, 212-859-1736))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ARMONK, N.Y."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
