<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53111" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: FEATURE - Journalist hopes Web can help N.Korea.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Journalist hopes Web can help N.Korea.</headline>
<byline>Allen Wan</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The worst floods to hit North Korea in a century prompted Pyongyang to take the unprecedented step last year of asking for help from the international community, but its pleas were largely ignored.</p>
<p>Little wonder. Better known for playing cat-and-mouse with the West over a suspected nuclear weapons programme, the isolated Stalinist state has few friends in the world.</p>
<p>Even the United States, often at the forefront of various humanitarian causes, offered little assistance to help the North Koreans meet a damages bill estimated at more than $15 billion.</p>
<p>The tepid response infuriated American journalist Bernard Krisher, who decided to take up the cause on the Internet, setting up a homepage for flood relief victims in North Korea.</p>
<p>&quot;When the country was inundated by these floods, I happened to hear on the radio that the United States was giving $25,000. I felt ashamed to be an an American,&quot; Krisher, a former Newsweek bureau chief in Tokyo, said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;I had just become interested in the Internet ... this was a great opportunity to test the web and see through a homepage whether public interest could be generated.&quot;</p>
<p>He gained the attention of web surfers worldwide, including authorities in the U.S. and South Korea which monitor the communist state's every move. The two countries remain technically at war with Pyongyang.</p>
<p>Krisher said the U.S. Treasury Department moved to freeze a U.S. bank account he had set up for flood relief, while South Korean authorities began pressuring individuals and companies to think twice about helping.</p>
<p>The floods last August and September ruined much of North Korea's rice harvest and stocks and destroyed many homes and factories. Despite its philosophy of self-reliance, the North sought international help.</p>
<p>While aid groups dragged their feet, in November Krisher made the first of two trips to Pyongyang taking 1,400 boxes of clothing and blankets.</p>
<p>Instead of treating him as a potential American spy, North Korean officials escorted him throughout the country and allowed him to see severely malnourished children, unusual for a country that has made great efforts to mask serious economic problems.</p>
<p>Krisher said he was able to gain the confidence of the North by avoiding politics and because of his long-standing ties. These stretch back to 1979 when he went to visit then-Prince Norodom Sihanouk, who was in exile from his native Cambodia.</p>
<p>Krisher got his first taste of humanitarian work in Cambodia when he was asked by Sihanouk, who has been restored as monarch, to help in the reconstruction of the country. Krisher now publishes an English-language daily in Phnom Penh.</p>
<p>His experience in Cambodia taught him the importance of making sure aid got into the right hands -- by delivering it personally.</p>
<p>&quot;When I got there, they were polite and let me distribute all this stuff but they basically said this was not the priority. Food, and rice particularly, were the priority.&quot;</p>
<p>Recent visitors to North Korea have said that while there is little sign of starvation, there is widespread hunger and malnutrition.</p>
<p>Krisher said the situation had worsened as recent torrential rains had caused more crop damage. &quot;It hasn't reached a Somalia or post-World War II Japan situation yet, but it could in the next month or two.&quot;</p>
<p>Krisher partly points the finger of blame at the South Korean government which forbids its citizens from dealing with the North without its approval.</p>
<p>In his web site http://shrine.cyber.ad.jp/mrosin/flood (Internet Appeal for North Korean Flood Victims), he urges South Koreans to defy their government.</p>
<p>With $65,000 he collected through his appeal, Krisher was able to buy 260 tonnes of Thai rice for a second trip in March this year, enough to feed 19,500 people for a month.</p>
<p>Krisher is planning to raise $100,000 to buy more than 300 tonnes for his next trip at the end of September or early October. But a lack of funds may derail that plan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
