<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="531191" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MONACO: TENNIS-WIMBLEDON CHAMPION KRAJICEK HAS AMBITIONS ON CLAY.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-WIMBLEDON CHAMPION KRAJICEK HAS AMBITIONS ON CLAY.</headline>
<dateline>MONACO 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wimbledon champion Richard Krajicek demolished last year's French Open finalist Michael Stich in less than an hour at the Monte Carlo Open on Wednesday and said he had strong ambitions on clay this season.</p>
<p>The 25-year-old Dutchman beat the struggling German 6-3 6-0 in 57 minutes and his performance was all the more spectacular as he was just back from Japan after winning the Tokyo indoor tournament last week.</p>
<p>&quot;I was a little bit tired at first and my legs were a little bit stiff but I'm surprised how well I adapted to clay,&quot; the fourth seed said.</p>
<p>After the suprising dismissals of American Pete Sampras and Thomas Muster, Krajicek remains the second highest seed left in the tournament behind Russian Yevgeny Kafelnikov, who beat him in the French Open quarterfinals last year.</p>
<p>&quot;I had not played a match on clay since then. It's like playing on the beach. Your legs are so heavy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Even though his height and big serve have made the Dutchman more of a hard and grass court specialist, Krajicek signalled he would be one to watch on the slow surface last season by reaching the final in Rome, losing only to Muster.</p>
<p>He believes he can do better this year.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel pretty good going into the French Open this season. I think I was one of the best players at the French last year. If only I had not felt so tired in the end of my match against Yevgeny,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kafelnikov went on to win that title.</p>
<p>Krajicek felt adapting to clay was a matter of pace.</p>
<p>&quot;I managed to find the right pace straight away which is good news. You have to be prepared to stay two hours out there, it's much more difficult than Wimbledon,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In Wimbledon, you play quick matches. It's okay.&quot;</p>
<p>Against Stich, also a former Wimbledon champion, Krajicek played a quick match too.</p>
<p>Trailing 3-1, he took the next 11 games.</p>
<p>&quot;I have never seen Michael play so badly. You can tell he's looking for his game right now,&quot; Krajicek said.</p>
<p>South African eighth seed Wayne Ferreira, never a clay expert either, played a bit better than Stich but not well enough against Spanish qualifier Carlos Costa.</p>
<p>Ferreira 6-4 7-6 in less than 90 minutes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MONAC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONACO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MONACO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
