<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="531283" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - CROATIA - APRIL 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - CROATIA - APRIL 23.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Wednesday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- UN Transitional Administrator general Jacques Klein confirms the election results in Eastern Slavonia.</p>
<p>- Inclement weather puts a stop to the sowing of maize, potatoes, soya and sunflower seeds. The tourist Istrian peninsula declares a state of natural disaster.</p>
<p>- Commentary: Does Croatia need a special law against racial hatred? The article comes as a reaction to a request by the Coordination of Jewish Communities in Croatia for legislation against persons inciting religious, racial or national hatred, as well as those who disseminate misinformaton about the fascist crimes against humanity.</p>
<p>- Director of Varteks textile firm Andjelko Herjavec says his company has met two key demands by Levi's to extend its production licence: full privatisation and meeting ecology standards. But all still hinges on a response by Levi's.</p>
<p>- Oesterreichische Volksbank opens a subsidiary in Croatia.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- Inland revenue figures show a decorater filing the highest tax return of 3.8 million kuna in 1996, with a salesman and a dredge owner as runner-ups.</p>
<p>- Voucher privatisaton to commence at the beginning of May and to include Kras, Elka and Dalmacijavino shares.</p>
<p>- The Plomin II thermal power plant, which is being built in cooperation with Germany's RWE, to start operating in 1998, according its supervisory board.</p>
<p>- A 50-centimetre snowfall recorded on Mount Sljeme overlooking Zagreb.</p>
<p>- Foreign investment funds have invested $2.3 billion in Central and Eastern European countries. Croatian securities make up about three percent of that investment.</p>
<p>- Michel Lacombe, the Microsoft Europe deputy president announces, a war against computer piracy in Croatia.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Many people around the world have been disillusioned by the Croatian Democratic Union (HDZ)'s &quot;great election victory&quot;, says Vladimir Seks, deputy speaker of the Croatian parliament and a high-ranking HDZ member, in an interview.</p>
<p>- The parliament to debate a proposed construction of some 1,800 kilometers of roads by the year 2005.</p>
<p>- Croatia's budget deficit has reached 926 million kuna or 0.86 percent of the GDP in the first two months of 1997, according to the Finance Ministry. Overall 1997 deficit projected at 2.63 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>- I don't do business with members of my family or state companies, says Dejan Kosutic, grandson of President Franjo Tudjman and president of the board at Kaptol Banka. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
