<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="531361" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Late bond market prices.</title>
<headline>Late bond market prices.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>This is how major world bond markets were trading in late European business on Wednesday.</p>
<p>GERMANY - German debt prices spent a somewhat uninspired day sitting comfortably in firm ground, gathering pace for another leg up before the end of the week. Analysts said the market, although trading sideways for most of Wednesday's session, had got over the hurdle of new cash paper supply in the past two sessions and the June DTB future now looked ready to break higher. The June Bund future on the London International Financial Futures and Options Exchange (LIFFE) was trading at 100.85, up 0.17 from Tuesday's settlement price.</p>
<p>BRITAIN - Gilts ended marginally in the black but that proved to be a disappointing display given a well-covered auction and a robust, but not startling set of retail sales figures. The June gilt future settled 2/32 higher at 109-15, well below its 109-25 session high. Dealers said weak U.S. T-bond futures proved difficult to shake off. The June long gilt future on LIFFE was trading at 109-17/32, up 4/32 from Tuesday's settlement price.</p>
<p>FRANCE - French bond and interest rate futures settled into a more stable rhythm after four volatile sessions, taking some comfort from a stronger Bund market and an opinion poll showing the ruling centre-right coalition would win the May/June parliamentary election. The June bond future on the MATIF in Paris settled at 128.60, up 0.18. from Tuesday's settlement price.</p>
<p>ITALY - Italian bond futures were firmer but off the day's best levels after two reports from the European Commission and International Monetary Fund which suggested Italy may struggle to join Europe's single currency. The June bond future on LIFFE was trading at 127.45 up 0.11 from Tuesday's settlement price.</p>
<p>UNITED STATES - U.S. Treasury securities prices opened slightly higher Wednesday as players' attention was focused on supply. The U.S. Treasury will auction $12.5 billion of five-year notes Wednesday following a successful sale of two-year paper on Tuesday. Otherwise, no economic data were scheduled for release and trdaers saw a day of little price movement. The June Treasury bond future on the Chicago Board of Trade was trading at 108-2/32, down 2/32 from Tuesday's settlement price. The long bond was quoted to yield 7.06 percent.</p>
<p>JAPAN - TOKYO, April 23 (Reuter) - Key June Japanese government bond (JGB) futures ended Wednesday's Tokyo session down, as dealers liquidated longs on vague market rumours. June ended at an intraday low of 126.60, down from Tuesday's close of 126.98. Turnover was 42,607 lots. In after hours trading the June future on LIFFE was trading at 126.67, down 0.41 from Tuesday's settlement price on the Tokyo Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>EUROBONDS - The Primary market saw a spectrum of currencies tapped amid active issuance on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In dollars, Kyushu Electric Power's $300 million 10-year bond, which was priced to yield 37 basis points over U.S. Treasuries, was holding firm at these levels, a syndicate official at Goldman Sachs said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
