<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="531314" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - April 30.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - April 30.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the major events to have occurred on April 30 in history:</p>
<p>311 - Galerius Valerius Maximianus issued an edict under which Christians were legally recognised in the Roman Empire.</p>
<p>1770 - David Thompson, Canadian explorer, born in London. The first white man to explore the length of the Columbia river, he also mapped large parts of Canada and the American west.</p>
<p>1777 - Johann Karl Freidrich Gauss, regarded as one of the greatest mathematicians of all time, born in Germany.</p>
<p>1789 - George Washington was inaugurated as America's first President.</p>
<p>1803 - France agreed to sell Louisiana to America, the formal handover taking place in December, and on this day in 1812 it joined the United States as the 18th state.</p>
<p>1815 - The Central provinces were designated as the Kingdom of Poland, under Alexander of Russia.</p>
<p>1870 - Hungarian composer Franz Lehar born. He wrote operettas and achieved worldwide recognition for &quot;The Merry Widow&quot;.</p>
<p>1883 - Edouard Manet, French impressionist painter, died. Originally destined for a legal career, he studied art from 1850 and was heavily influenced by Claude Monet.</p>
<p>1883 - Jaroslav Hasek, Czech novelist, born; author of &quot;The Good Soldier of Schweik&quot;, an unfinished sequence of satirical novels.</p>
<p>1893 - Joachim von Ribbentrop, Adolf Hitler's foreign affairs adviser, born. A wine merchant before joining the National Socialist Party in 1932, he was found guilty at Nuremberg in 1945 and executed.</p>
<p>1900 - American railroad engineer Casey Jones died saving passengers as the Cannonball Express was about to crash.</p>
<p>1909 - Juliana, Queen of the Netherlands, born. She was queen from 1948 until this day in 1980, when she abdicated in favour of her eldest daughter, Beatrix.</p>
<p>1934 - Under a new constitution in Austria, a dictatorship was set up under Engelbert Dollfuss.</p>
<p>1936 - Alfred Edward Housman, English poet notably for the collection known as &quot;A Shropshire Lad&quot;, died.</p>
<p>1945 - Adolf Hitler and his wife Eva Braun committed suicide in his underground bunker in Berlin; Russian troops penetrated Berlin, capturing the Reichstag and other government buildings; Allied troops captured Munich and the French crossed the border into Austria.</p>
<p>1946 - King Carl XVI Gustaf of Sweden born. King since 1973, he had much of his constitutional powers taken away by the Social Democrats, who pledged to eventually end the monarchy.</p>
<p>1973 - President Nixon made a television statement on Watergate accepting responsibility for the bugging that took place at the Washington apartment complex in 1972. On this day in 1974, he handed over partial transcripts of tape recordings to the impeachment inquiry.</p>
<p>1975 - In South Vietnam, President Minh announced an unconditional surrender to the Vietcong, ending the 20th Century's longest conflict.</p>
<p>1980 - In London, armed gunmen seized the Iranian Embassy demanding the release of political prisoners in Iran. The siege lasted six days.</p>
<p>1981 - In Poland, the Central Committee of the Communist Party endorsed its Chairman Stanislav Kania's program of reforms.</p>
<p>1982 - Alvaro Magana was chosen to succeed Jose Napoleon Duarte as president of El Salvador.</p>
<p>1989 - 500,000 attended a papal mass in Madagascar where Pope John Paul II beatified Victoire Rasoamanarivo, a 19th century Madagascar woman.</p>
<p>1989 - Sergio Leone, Italian film director, died of a heart attack.</p>
<p>1990 - American hostage Frank Reed was freed in Lebanon after nearly four years in the hands of pro-Iranian kidnappers.</p>
<p>1991 - Major-General Justin Lekhanya, Lesotho's military strongman, was ousted in an army coup.</p>
<p>1992 - NATO appointed U.S. General John Shalikashvili as the new commander of its forces in Europe.</p>
<p>1992 - Mutinous soldiers in Sierra Leone overthrew President Joseph Momoh in a coup.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
