<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="531793" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico rebels condemn &quot;criminal&quot; end to Peru siege.</title>
<headline>Mexico rebels condemn &quot;criminal&quot; end to Peru siege.</headline>
<byline>Michael Stott</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marxist rebels in Mexico condemned on Wednesday the bloody end to Peru's hostage crisis, and vowed to continue their fight to kill capitalism in Latin America.</p>
<p>The Popular Revolutionary Army's (EPR) military command in southern Oaxaca state said in a statement sent to Reuters that local rebel units were &quot;ready for combat&quot; if the EPR leadership decided to strike.</p>
<p>After announcing its presence with a wave of attacks in at least five Mexican states last year, in which at least 30 people died, the EPR has declared a series of cease-fires to concentrate on what it terms &quot;armed propaganda&quot;.</p>
<p>But, less than two weeks before President Bill Clinton is due to make a two-day visit to Mexico City on May 5-7, the Oaxaca EPR unit declared &quot;its commitment to continue to carry out the tasks of the revolution and its readiness for combat to respond to a call from the Central Committee and the General Command of our...EPR&quot;.</p>
<p>President Alberto Fujimori ordered crack troops to storm the besieged Japanese embassy residence in Lima on Tuesday afternoon, ending a 126-day siege.</p>
<p>Seventy-one of the 72 hostages were rescued alive but all 14 Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels died -- something the Mexican guerrillas called an &quot;abominable crime&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The lands of Latin America are once again stained red. The financial oligarchy is full of congratulations. We revolutionaries are in mourning,&quot; the Mexican rebels said.</p>
<p>&quot;The best homage to the murdered (rebels) will be to continue with the struggle for the revolutionary transformation which will bury forever the domination of capital in all of Latin America,&quot; they added.</p>
<p>&quot;The oligarchy should not think that with this type of action they will silence the rebellion and the spirit of struggle and the revolutionary movement of the people of Latin America.&quot;</p>
<p>There was no immediate reaction from Mexico's other guerrilla group, the Indian Zapatista rebels (EZLN) in the southern state of Chiapas.</p>
<p>The Mexican government issued a statement on Tuesday night expressing its &quot;approval and solidarity for the governments of Peru and Japan over the end of the hostage crisis in the Japanese Embassy in Lima&quot;.</p>
<p>But opposition politicians warned the Mexican government not to apply Fujimori-style tactics in Mexico.</p>
<p>&quot;In Mexico we should first use all possibilites for dialogue and prudence and not follow the example of Peru,&quot; National Action Party (PAN) legislator Alejandro Diaz told Reuters. &quot;Mexico should understand that that should not be its path (to follow) in its relations with the EZLN and the EPR&quot;.</p>
<p>The Zapatistas broke off peace talks with the Mexican government last year in protest at what they said was a government refusal to honour promises of greater Indian autonomy. No fresh date has been set for negotiations to resume.</p>
<p>Zapatista leader Subcommander Marcos has been very quiet of late, though reports from Chiapas state suggest that tensions between the rebels and government forces have been rising in recent weeks because of the lack of progress in restarting peace negotiations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
