<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="531715" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru hostages freed in military operation.</title>
<headline>Peru hostages freed in military operation.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peruvian troops stormed the Japanese ambassador's residence in Lima on Tuesday, freeing all but one of the 72 hostages as their Marxist rebel captors were caught off guard while playing soccer.</p>
<p>One hostage -- a supreme court judge -- two soldiers and all 14 guerrillas died in the fierce battle that ended the four-month siege.</p>
<p>Scores of soldiers swarmed into the compound over walls, while others burst into the building from tunnels in an eruption of gunfire and explosions.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no other way out,&quot; President Alberto Fujimori said in a speech after the operation.</p>
<p>He was in triumphant mood, but fought back tears as he announced the death of Peruvian judge Carlos Giusti Acuna and two of the commandos who stormed the house. One of them had been his son Kenji's bodyguard.</p>
<p>Fujimori staked his political career on the decision to send in the troops at 3.23 p.m. local time (2023 GMT) after four months of fruitless negotiations and mutual posturing with the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA).</p>
<p>The troops, who had been preparing for months at a mock-up of the residence, engaged the heavily-armed rebels in a brief but ferocious battle which sent smoke billowing from the building and gunfire and explosions resounding in the air.</p>
<p>Within minutes, the soldiers began bringing out hostages -- most looking dazed but happy, some barely clothed -- before congregating on the roof to celebrate victory and tear down an MRTA flag that had flown defiantly for 126 days.</p>
<p>The rebels originally took 500 hostages, but released most in the early days of the crisis, keeping those they considered their most valuable bargaining chips to obtain their demand for the release of jailed comrades.</p>
<p>Local Panamerican Television quoted police sources as saying the key to the success of the assault that ended Latin America's longest hostage siege was its timing to coincide with the rebels' regular six-a-side soccer games inside the building.</p>
<p>This was confirmed by one of the most prominent hostages, Bolivian Ambassador Jorge Gumucio. &quot;The operation began with the blasting of the floor where they were playing football, and immediately through other additional tunnels the special troops came in,&quot; he told Bolivian state Television Boliviana.</p>
<p>Gumucio added that the hostages knew about the attack 10 minutes before, but he would not say how. &quot;We were waiting for the entry and it was a surgery with some cost,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Fujimori said the military operation was &quot;duly planned as a contingency alternative in the face of events that could damage the physical integrity of some of the hostages.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that after receiving information of what was going on inside &quot;I did not doubt for one single second in giving the order for this operation.&quot; He did not elaborate on what information had prompted the decision.</p>
<p>The 58-year-old Peruvian leader, in the seventh year of a turbulent period in office, added that he did not warn Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto of the operation beforehand because he could not afford to lose time.</p>
<p>&quot;The surprise factor was fundamental,&quot; he said, adding that 140 army and navy commandos took part in the strike. Twenty-five hostages were slightly injured, with Foreign Minister Francisco Tudela and Supreme Court judge Luis Serpa Segura suffering bullet wounds in the ankle and the colon respectively.</p>
<p>&quot;All Peruvians are going to come out strengthened ... today Peru has the conditions to live in peace. We give an example to the international community that there must be no giving in to terror,&quot; Fujimori said.</p>
<p>Hashimoto later told Fujimori he understood his decision to send in troops to end the prolonged siege.</p>
<p>&quot;I told President Fujimori that if I had been in his position I would have done the same,&quot; Hashimoto told a news conference in Tokyo after a brief conversation with Fujimori.</p>
<p>Japanese Ambassador Morihisa Aoki went straight to his office to start work.</p>
<p>It was Aoki's ill-fated cocktail party that the MRTA successfully stormed on Dec. 17.</p>
<p>Masked soldiers waved assault rifles in the air, cheered, sang the national anthem and punched their fists in the air after the 40-minute operation to end Latin America's longest hostage siege.</p>
<p>Fujimori, wearing a bullet-proof vest, arrived at the site immediately afterwards and entered the compound where he was cheered by soldiers.</p>
<p>The freed hostages included a glittering array of government ministers and security force officials, two dozen Japanese businessmen and diplomats, and Fujimori's brother Pedro.</p>
<p>MRTA spokesman Isaac Velazco told Reuters from Hamburg by telephone that the guerrillas would retaliate for the assault by attacking military and economic targets in Peru.</p>
<p>Armed forces and police officials said security had been tightened throughout Lima and the rest of Peru.</p>
<p>The storming of the residence came after negotiations between the Peruvian government and rebels -- mainly through a three-man guarantors committee -- had failed to break the deadlock.</p>
<p>The Cuban-inspired MRTA is the smallest of Peru's two main rebel movements. Violent conflicts unleashed by it and the larger Shining Path movement have cost 30,000 lives and $25 billion in infrastructure damage in Peru since 1980.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
