<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="531863" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: FEATURE-Peru's &quot;faceless&quot; courts leave bitter legacy.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Peru's &quot;faceless&quot; courts leave bitter legacy.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>It was the anonymous voice from behind the one-way mirror that most disconcerted him.</p>
<p>&quot;Are you a terrorist?&quot; came the question, squeaky and barely comprehensible with the deliberate distortion to disguise the speaker's identity.</p>
<p>&quot;No,&quot; replied Peruvian peasant leader Julio Cesar Vasquez, seated on a concrete block in the stark room, lonely and frightened by the strange trial.</p>
<p>&quot;You are a shameless liar. The answer is yes,&quot; said the voice from a loudspeaker in front of the mirror that shielded his unknown accuser. Twenty minutes later the three &quot;faceless&quot; judges sentenced Vasquez to 20 years' imprisonment for alleged membership in the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA).</p>
<p>The trial in January 1994 in the northern Peruvian city of Chiclayo was one of thousands heard in the last five years by Peru's secret courts -- a pillar of government strategy against leftist guerrillas waging a 17-year conflict. President Alberto Fujimori introduced the &quot;faceless&quot; courts in 1992 at the height of the battle against the Marxist MRTA and the larger Shining Path guerrilla movement, a battle that has cost 30,000 lives and $25 billion in infrastructure damage.</p>
<p>Fujimori argued then that traditional courts were failing to convict terrorists through incompetence, corruption or fear. Now 3,800 people are locked up on terrorism charges and violence has diminished considerably, but the government insists the &quot;faceless&quot; system is still needed as a deterrant.</p>
<p>HUMAN RIGHTS GROUPS OPOOSED</p>
<p>Human rights groups say they are a mockery of justice and should be abolished immediately. &quot;The system is abhorrent, perverse and absurd,&quot; Jorge Vega Fernandez, a defence lawyer with local group Aprodeh, said.</p>
<p>Critics paint a picture of the courts as a black farce. Trials are often over in minutes, with convictions based on the word of one informer or evidence obtained after torture, they charge. Judges with little or no experience frequently preside, while defence lawyers barely have a chance to speak or to see evidence beforehand.</p>
<p>The Supreme Military Justice Council, whose secret courts hear the most serious cases of alleged terrorism, flatly rejects the criticisms. &quot;Various distorted or prejudiced judgments have been expressed, with no other basis than hasty or false opinions by groups interested in harming the reputation of the military justice,&quot; it said recently.</p>
<p>Vasquez, whose conviction was based on a statement he never read and was forced to sign after 36 days of torture, was granted a pardon in January last year. He had been victimised because his brother was an MRTA member.</p>
<p>Former defendants and lawyers who have been at secret trials run by the civil judiciary say the accused is forced to kneel to speak into a microphone. Judges fire questions like &quot;What do you think of subversive groups?&quot; or &quot;What do you think of the government?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The cases are very, very difficult. Most judges look for tough sentences,&quot; one judge said, recounting the case of a youth who was sentenced in his court to five years after guerrillas beat him up, stole his car and used it for attacks. &quot;The other two (judges) wanted to give him 20 years ... A decent-looking boy ... his life was destroyed.&quot;</p>
<p>MILITARY JUDGES WEAR BLACK HOODS</p>
<p>He described how he also used a moustache and wig to disguise himself in public. Terrified of reprisals, the &quot;faceless&quot; judges are collected in disguised vehicles at secret locations before being driven to trials held in prisons or military barracks.</p>
<p>In the military's secret court system, the main variation is that judges, rather than hiding behind a screen, generally wear black hoods to cover their faces. &quot;But I have noticed sometimes that they don't even have wrinkles,&quot; said defence lawyer Gloria Cano. &quot;They are supposed to be generals, but, unless they have had surgery I get the impression at times that they pass off new recruits as judges.&quot;</p>
<p>The military's best-known convictions include the leaders of Peru's main guerrilla movements -- Abimael Guzman of the Shining Path and Victor Polay of the MRTA -- and an American woman, Lori Berenson, accused of aiding the MRTA.</p>
<p>The council justifies the continued use of secret courts with the need to protect judges. &quot;The chief basis for the activity of the faceless judges ... is to avoid retaliation from subversive elements against magistrates or their families,&quot; it said in a statement faxed to Reuters.</p>
<p>The government does admit the secret court system has put hundreds of innocent persons behind bars. About 100 prisoners have been released so far thanks to the recommendations of a special panel set up by Fujimori last year to study cases of prisoners falsely convicted of terrorism.</p>
<p>Human rights groups say up to 1,000 more may be wrongly jailed, most convicted by secret courts on flimsy evidence, often obtained by torture.</p>
<p>&quot;The incarceration of hundreds of innocent prisoners charged or convicted of terrorist crimes they did not commit is now an open secret in Peru,&quot; U.S.-based Human Rights Watch said in a report last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Faceless military and civilian courts, conducting secret trials behind prison walls, continue to sentence Peruvians to decades of imprisonment in life-threatening conditions without offering them the basic judicial process guarantees required by international human rights law.&quot;</p>
<p>Some statistics show, however, that the Peruvian secret court system does appear to be improving. While no one walked free from a &quot;faceless&quot; court in 1992, by 1996 only half the trials led to convictions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
