<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="532061" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia's Mahathir, sultan deny candidate dispute.</title>
<headline>Malaysia's Mahathir, sultan deny candidate dispute.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad and a ruling sultan have denied reports of a dispute over the naming of a new state chief minister to replace one who quit in a scandal.</p>
<p>The national news agency Bernama quoted Mahathir as saying late on Tuesday in the northern city of Penang that the sultan of Selangor state, Abdul Aziz Shah, had not interfered in the appointnment of a new chief minister for his state.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know what the sultan told reporters, but the sultan did not inform me of anything,&quot; Bernama quoted Mahathir as telling reporters during visit to Penang. &quot;I think you misheard (what the sultan said).&quot;</p>
<p>The news agency and Malaysian newspapers on Monday quoted Abdul Aziz as saying: &quot;I do not agree with the names submitted to me. Therefore, Dr. Mahathir said it will have to be postponed until I can give my consent.&quot;</p>
<p>However Malaysian newspapers on Wednesday quoted a statement from the Selangor sultan's palace as denying that the sultan had withheld consent to Mahathir's nominee.</p>
<p>&quot;This is because the prime minister has yet to submit the name of the candidate...hence the question of the sultan not consenting did not arise at all,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The reports of a dispute could have created tension between the people and the rulers, the statement added.</p>
<p>Mahathir has locked horns over the years with Malaysia's nine state sultans, who take turns at being king every five years. Four years ago, he led a campaign against privileges and legal immunity accorded to the rulers that led to constitutional amendments curbing their powers.</p>
<p>The sultans have mostly symbolic power under the constitution and their consent to government appointees is usually a formality.</p>
<p>The previous chief minister of Selangor, Muhammad Muhammad Taib, quit his post this month after being charged in an Australian court with trying to bring in nearly $1 million in undeclared cash into Australia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
