<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="532016" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Peru hostage crisis awakes Japan from safe slumber.</title>
<headline>Peru hostage crisis awakes Japan from safe slumber.</headline>
<byline>Eugene Moosa</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan was rudely awakened from a deep security slumber by the Lima hostage drama and now realises complacency made it an easy target of terrorism, security experts and government officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Japan had been mostly free from terrorist attacks since an embarrassing Japanese Red Army hijacking in 1977 and did little besides issuing statements condemning terrorism when the United States, Britain and others suffered such problems.</p>
<p>In 1977 then Japanese Prime Minister Takeo Fukuda earned Japan a reputation for being soft on terrorism when he freed 11 rebels and paid a $6 million ransom to Red Army hijackers at Dhaka saying &quot;the lives of hostages outweighs the earth&quot;. Peruvian Marxists shattered Japan's nonchalance in December when they stormed a cocktail party at the Lima residence of the Japanese ambassador and took hundreds of high-profile hostages.</p>
<p>A last group of 71 hostages was freed in a daring daytime raid by Peruvian commandos on Tuesday having been held for four months. The commandos killed 14 guerrillas and one Peruvian hostage in the assault, in which two soldiers also died.</p>
<p>Atsuyuki Sasa, a former official of Japan's Cabinet Security Bureau and a crisis-management specialist, said the Peru case had opened Japan's eyes.</p>
<p>&quot;After 1977 we were considered an easy target by terrorists,&quot; Sasa said, &quot;because we always surrendered to their illegal demands.</p>
<p>&quot;This Peru crisis changed that and perhaps international terrorists will now think that it will not be easy to make such demands.&quot;</p>
<p>But another expert said Japan had a long way to go before it ranked with other countries in the war against terrorism.</p>
<p>&quot;Japan contributed nothing to the resolution of this crisis,&quot; said Kenichi Ito, international politics professor at Aoyama Guakuin University.</p>
<p>In fact Japan had persistently sought a peaceful, meaning negotiated settlement to the crisis, while maintaining that it would not give in to terrorist demands.</p>
<p>The philosophical difference apparently explains why even though the Peruvian and Japanese governments had been in constant contact since the crisis began, Lima did not notify Tokyo before staging the raid.</p>
<p>&quot;Japan has its hands tied behind the back by this conceptual notion of post-World War Two security,&quot; Ito told Kyodo news agency. &quot;If there were real trust between Peru and Japan, the prime minister would have been notified beforehand.&quot;</p>
<p>In his initial reaction to the Lima raid, which took place early on Wednesday morning Japan time, a clearly irritated and abruptly awoken Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto said he regretted not having been given advance warning of the raid. However he also thanked Peru for taking the gamble in staging the attack.</p>
<p>&quot;It is time Japan matured and realised that peace should not be made a condition for resolving such crises, but that peace is the end goal in issues of national security,&quot; Ito said.</p>
<p>Japan's ability to respond to crises like the embassy siege is complicated by its post-war constitution, which forbids the use of force to settle international disputes.</p>
<p>After the takeover of the Lima residence, the Foreign Ministry tripled the number of locally hired security guards at Japan's 182 embassies and other missions abroad.</p>
<p>But an official at the ministry's anti-terrorist desk said the constitution made it impossible for Japan to follow the example of countries like the United States that stations military guards at its missions.</p>
<p>Analysts described Japan's response to the hostage drama as only the latest recent demonstration of its lack of crisis expertise.</p>
<p>After a January 1995 earthquake which killed more than 5,500 people in the city of Kobe it took then prime minister Tomiichi Murayama several hours to realise that a major natural disaster had hit. For many, it was too late when he ordered troops to rescue thousands trapped under smouldering ruins.</p>
<p>Two months later, the government failed to prevent a religious cult carring out a nerve gas attack on the Tokyo subway despite media reports warning of the possibility of such an attack. The gassing killed 12 people and harmed more than 6,000 others.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
