<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="532117" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Saks stock battered by earnings warning.</title>
<headline>Saks stock battered by earnings warning.</headline>
<byline>Jessica Hall</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>The stock of Saks Holdings Inc. plunged Wednesday after the upscale retailer warned it expected its first quarter earnings to fall well below Wall Street estimates due to soft sales in its catalogue and casual bridge apparel operations.</p>
<p>Saks fell $9.75 to $19.625 and was the second-heaviest traded stock on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said they did not expect Saks earnings outlook to hurt its bid to acquire troubled luxury retailer Barney's Inc.</p>
<p>Saks announced late Tuesday that its earning in its fiscal first quarter ending May 3 would be 20 cents a share, compared with analysts' estimates for earnings of 32 cents a share, according to First Call. In its fiscal fourth quarter, which includes the crucial holiday season, Saks earned $46.7 million, or 73 cents a share.</p>
<p>Saks said its forecast was guided by sales trends in March and April, which have been hampered by continued softness in the Folio catalogue operation.</p>
<p>&quot;Consumers are paying less attention to high fashion,&quot; said Kurt Barnard, president of Barnard's Retail Marketing Report. &quot;Basically, people are not quite as liberal in spending for very expensive fashion, due to economic conditions.&quot;</p>
<p>Barnard added that, &quot;The really very exclusive, upper statosphere has taken it on the chin,&quot; while more mainstream stores like Sears, Roebuck &amp; Co. and TJX Cos. &quot;have been going great guns.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said Saks' first quarter woes also were due to the timing of the Easter holiday.</p>
<p>Retailers often suffer when Easter falls early, when the weather is still cool and consumers do not buy new Easter clothes, said retail analyst Walter Loeb, president of Loeb Associates.</p>
<p>&quot;An early Easter means we lose the whole Spring shopping season. People wait for summer. That means the next quarter could be much stronger for Saks&quot; due to pent-up demand, he said.</p>
<p>Saks' dismal first quarter outlook, however, would not hurt its plan to buy troubled luxury retailer Barney's Inc. for about $290 million, analysts said.</p>
<p>Saks and the Tokyo-based conglomerate Isetan Co., a key Barney's creditor, announced the proposal late Tuesday. Saks said its investment in Barney's would add to earnings, but did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Barney's said it was reviewing the offer, which would take the luxury clothing store group out of bankruptcy.</p>
<p>Isetan holds leases on three of Barney's flagship stores. Saks said it and Isetan will submit their joint plan to a New York bankruptcy court for approval.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
