<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="532178" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New York City jobless rate tops 10 pct - state.</title>
<headline>New York City jobless rate tops 10 pct - state.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York City's jobless rate rose just over 10 percent in March, hitting its highest level since January 1994, primarily because discouraged workers are looking for work again, the state labor department said.</p>
<p>&quot;That's a good portion of it,&quot; said Rod Fortran, labor market analyst with New York State Department of Labor.</p>
<p>Unemployment rates started rising in September, 1995, Fortran said, explaining that that was when the city's monthly jobless rate began climbing when individual months were compared with the year-ago level.</p>
<p>As an economy recovers, workers who had dropped out of the labor market become more confident that jobs are available, so they start looking again, a phenomenon that can drive unemployment rates up. The data for New York City and New York State were not seasonally adjusted.</p>
<p>Throughout the state, however, there was a slight improvment as New York State's unemployment rate edged down one-tenth of a percentage point to 6.8 percent from February, and was level with the year ago. Nonfarm jobs grew by 64,200, while private sector jobs gained 56,500. Job gains were concentrated in business, educational and amusement and recreation services, the labor department said.</p>
<p>For New York City, the job picture continued to look the worst in the Bronx, which saw its unemployment rate gain half a percentage point to 12.6 percent from the previous month. This was the highest level since it hit 13 percent in February, 1993, the state labor department said.</p>
<p>((--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
