<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="532142" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mobil, Chevron report strong earnings; Phillips net drops.</title>
<headline>Mobil, Chevron report strong earnings; Phillips net drops.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mobil Corp. and Chevron Corp. reported higher-than-expected earnings Wednesday due to strong gains in oil prices, while Phillips Petroleum Co.'s profits fell.</p>
<p>Mobil said its operating earnings rose 12 percent to $826.0 million or $2.11 a share vs. year-earlier earnings of $736.0 million or $1.83 a share.</p>
<p>Revenues fell to $16.18 billion from $18.69 billion a year earlier as a result of its refining and marketing alliance with British Petroleum in Europe, the company said.</p>
<p>The Fairfax, Va.-based company said its results were boosted by higher crude oil and natural gas prices.</p>
<p>Average U.S. crude oil prices were $20.92 vs. $18.57 in the first quarter of last year and natural gas prices were $2.75 per thousand cubic feet vs. $2.16.</p>
<p>Mobil said worldwide refining and marketing operating earnings fell $90 million to $150 million as its U.S. operations lost $42 million due to shutdowns at four of its five refineries for maintenance.</p>
<p>Mobil said it had a record quarter in worldwide exploration and production with a $182 million rise in operating earnings to $694 million.</p>
<p>Chemical earnings rose to $85 million from $70 million a year earlier due to stronger sales of polyethylene and paraxylene.</p>
<p>Mobil's stock was off 12.5 cents at $125.75 on the New York Stock Exchange in afternoon trading.</p>
<p>San Francisco-based Chevron said its earnings jumped 35 percent to $831 million, or $1.27 a share, in the first quarter from $616 million, or 94 cents a share, a year earlier.</p>
<p>Revenues were up 8 percent at $11.1 billion vs. $10.3 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Our upstream operations turned in excellent results. Crude oil and natural gas prices on average were higher than a year ago, although they have fallen significantly from year-end 1996 levels,&quot; said Chairman Ken Derr.</p>
<p>&quot;The declining oil and gas prices during the quarter benefited our U.S. downstream and chemicals businesses, as lower feedstock and fuel costs improved product sales margins,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Derr said oil prices have continued to soften in the second quarter. Chevron's stock was 12.5 cents lower at $66.50 on the NYSE.</p>
<p>Phillips Petroleum said its first quarter earnings sank to $227 million, or 86 cents a share, against year ago earnings of $695 million or $2.65 a share. The year ago earnings included a $565 million tax benefit.</p>
<p>Revenues rose to $3.99 billion from $3.60 billion.</p>
<p>The Bartlesville, Okla.-based oil company said higher crude oil and natural gas prices offset a 4 percent drop in production worldwide.</p>
<p>Phillips stock was unchanged at $38.50 on the NYSE.</p>
<p>Conoco said its earnings for the first quarter jumped 55 percent to $331 million vs. year earlier earnings of $214 million on revenues of $5.4 billion against $4.7 billion. The company, a unit of DuPont Co., does not report per share earnings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
