<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="532272" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMC AgriBusiness unit to make up shortfall.</title>
<headline>IMC AgriBusiness unit to make up shortfall.</headline>
<dateline>NORTHBROOK, Ill. 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>IMC Global Inc said Wednesday that it expects its IMC AgriBusiness unit will make up its third-quarter shortfall by fiscal year-end.</p>
<p>IMC AgriBusiness' revenues for the third quarter ended March 31 fell six percent to $139.9 million, while gross margins decreased 11 percent to $22.2 million.</p>
<p>The sales decline was due to the wet and cold spring in the Southeast, which delayed the start of spring planting. Margins were hurt by increased costs, particularly natural gas.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our U.S. retail and dealer organization, IMC AgriBusiness, currently is experiencing strong demand with sales and general business activity ahead of year-ago levels,&quot; IMC Chairman Wendell Bueche said in a statement. &quot;We are optimistic that IMC AgriBusiness will make up its third-quarter shortfall by fiscal year-end.&quot;</p>
<p>IMC-Agrico Crop Nutrients third quarter revenues fell 19 percent to $355.7 million while gross margins dropped 38 percent to $79.9 million. Declines were due to reduced international and domestic demand, as well as lower prices.  </p>
<p>IMC Kalium's third quarter revenues rose 21 percent to $148.3 million and gross margins climbed 30 percent to $55.4 million. Sales improved on strong demand for potash from domestic and international customers, as well as higher prices.</p>
<p>IMC reported third quarter earnings of $0.41 a share, down from $0.66 a year ago before merger-related charges.</p>
<p>&quot;The third quarter weakness we experienced in the world market has proved temporary with domestic and international customers already increasing their purchases of crop nutrients,&quot; Bueche said. &quot;The domestic spring planting season continues to gain momentum and recent new orders for phosphate products from offshore customers have added to our already strong base of contract business.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that domestic demand for crop nutrients is expected to be strong in the fourth quarter as farmers are projected by the U.S. Department of Agriculture to plant about 81.4 million acres of corn, up two percent from 1996, and 68.8 million acres of soybeans, up seven percent.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25130">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NORTHBROOK, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
