<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="532322" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX heat ends up as API data extends strength.</title>
<headline>NYMEX heat ends up as API data extends strength.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX heating oil prices ended higher Wednesday, extending its strength into the middle of spring, after oil inventory data showed a steep decline in distillate stocks following weeks of unseasonably cold weather in the northeastern United States.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was teetering all day, but it was buying in heating oil which held everything together at the end after its more bullish-than-expected stock decline,&quot; said Tim Evans, analyst with Pegasus Econometric Group in New York.</p>
<p>May heating oil settled 0.82 cent higher at 55.65 cents a gallon, gaining 2.17 cents a gallon since last Wednesday.  </p>
<p>June crude ended 14 cents a barrel higher at $19.73 while May gasoline settled 0.03 cent a gallon lower at 61.74 cents.</p>
<p>June crude fell as much as 19 cents in the afternoon tracking losses in gasoline. But, traders were unable to sharpen crude's decline trigerring a bout of short covering in the final minutes of trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>Tuesday evening, the American Petroleum Institute (API) reported distillate stocks, which comprise heating oil and diesel, fell 4.7 million barrels. Traders had been expecting distillate stocks to drop a half million to two million barrels. The API report covers the week ended April 18.</p>
<p>Since early April, unseasonably cold weather in the U.S. Northeast has drained refiners of heating oil supplies, and last week Sun Co said it was left without any heating oil for distributors until later this week.</p>
<p>The U.S. Northeast is the largest heating oil market in the world.</p>
<p>Gasoline prices fell as the API said gasoline production rose to 7.7 million barrels a day, a level that dealers said should make gasoline supply ample for the summer driving season.</p>
<p>Traders also noted that spot gasoline was technically weakened after its session high of 63.10 cents failed before hitting resistance of 63.20 cents, set by Tuesday's spot session high.</p>
<p>-- Harry Milling, New York Energy Desk, 212-859-1761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
