<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="532634" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Germany's Rexrodt sees tough EU ship aid talks.</title>
<headline>Germany's Rexrodt sees tough EU ship aid talks.</headline>
<byline>Bettina Vestring</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt on Wednesday predicted long and difficult EU talks on state aid to east German shipyards, but that the bloc in the end would approve Bonn's support plan.</p>
<p>European Union industry ministers are expected to decide at a meeting in Luxembourg on Thursday a European Commission proposal to give the green light to restructuring aid to ailing German, Spanish and Greek shipyards.</p>
<p>Rexrodt told Reuters it would be a difficult decision but that there were important arguments in favour of approving the German aid, a sum amounting to over a billion marks.</p>
<p>A collapse of the two yards in former east Germany, previously owned by bankrupt Bremer Vulkan, would lead to severe economic difficulties in the concerned regions, he said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to take into account the special situation (in eastern Germany),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The European Commission's proposal to approve the requests of Bonn, Athens and Madrid to grant the support, which has sparked U.S. criticism, needs the backing of a qualified majority of EU member states.</p>
<p>The EU's Nordic member states and Britain have voiced opposition to the plan but they would not by themselves be able to block approval.</p>
<p>Rexrodt indicated that the aid was needed in order to privatise the two shipyards, adding that talks had started with potential investors.</p>
<p>In return for approval of the aid, Germany, Spain and Greece have undertaken not to pay any more rescue or restructuring aid to the shipyards.</p>
<p>The EU executive also insisted on important reductions in production capacity in Germany and Spain and there would be strict monitoring of the conditions imposed on the shipyards.</p>
<p>The problems of MTW-Schiffswerft and Volkswerft Stralsund in former east Germany arose from alleged misuse by Bremer Vulkan of 850 million marks ($496 million) in subsidies intended for them.</p>
<p>Of the needed aid of around one billion marks, 728 million marks would require the approval of EU industry ministers.</p>
<p>In Greece, the proposal would allow Athens to write off 54.5 billion drachmas ($200 million) in debts accumulated by Hellenic shipyards before it was privatised in 1995.</p>
<p>The Spanish support was needed for restructuring public yards to return them to viability by the end of 1998. A large part of the proposed aid, 180 billion pesetas ($1.24 billion), was provided for in an exemption for Spain under the OECD deal.</p>
<p>But a further 135 billion pesetas in interest payments, tax credits and capital injection were also needed.</p>
<p>Rexrodt said he still hoped that the United States would ratify the OECD accord, which is designed to end direct shipbuilding subsidies except social aid, and research and development aid.</p>
<p>Due to difficulties in the Republican-controlled Congress, the United States is the only country which has not yet ratified the 1994 accord within the 29-nation OECD.</p>
<p>($1 = 1.7125 marks)</p>
<p>($1 = 271.6 drachmas)</p>
<p>($1 = 144.4 pesetas)</p>
<p>-- Brussels newsroom +32 2 287 68 11</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
