<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="532659" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Profit-taking wipes sharp gains in India shares.</title>
<headline>Profit-taking wipes sharp gains in India shares.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>**  Indian shares end higher, but off sharp</p>
<p>	  mid-session rally as operators book profits</p>
<p>**  Bombay's benchmark 30-share index up 28.36 pts, 0.75</p>
<p>	  pct to 3,828.99, below 3,864.77 --day's high</p>
<p>**  Reliance most actively traded stock at Bombay</p>
<p>	  exchanges, up two pct on National Stock Exchange</p>
<p>	  due to no-delivery period in new account</p>
<p>**  Foreign funds active bidders in select stocks</p>
<p>**  National exchange index up over one pct at 1,071.05</p>
<p>**  Calcutta share index gains 0.17 pts to 106.32, Madras</p>
<p>	  index down 72.82 pts at 3,630.08</p>
<p>Bombay shares ended with small gains on Wednesday, capping a smart mid-session rally after a round of late profit-taking, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has shown a minor reaction,&quot; said Antony Sequeira, managing director at Arcadia Share &amp; Stock Brokers.</p>
<p>Fresh buying by foreign investors coupled with support from some local funds helped blue chips such as Mahindra &amp; Mahindra, Colgate, MTNL and TELCO close higher, traders said.</p>
<p>New prime minister Inder Kumar Gujral on Tuesday won a parliamentary vote of confidence, ending a three-week political drama that brought India to the brink of a mid-term election.  </p>
<p>&quot;Political stability seems to be there now,&quot; Arcadia's Sequiera said.</p>
<p>The rally in share prices, however, took traders by surprise in the absence of a single major factor triggering the rise.</p>
<p>&quot;The market should be steady and rise slowly,&quot; said Mahendra Doshi, director at LKP Shares &amp; Securities. &quot;Speculators tried to cover short-positions and that pushed up prices.&quot;</p>
<p>Market leader Reliance Industries added nearly two percent to 306.80 rupees at the National Stock Exchange (NSE) after the stock entered a no-delivery account from Wednesday.  </p>
<p>A no-delivery period allows speculators to trade the stock without actual purchase or delivery for one month.</p>
<p>At the Bombay Stock Exchange, Reliance shares fell 1.75 rupees to 306.25, with over 6.81 million shares traded.</p>
<p>The petrochemicals giant on Tuesday said its 1996/97 net climbed to 13.23 billion rupees from 13.05 billion a year ago.</p>
<p>Steel Authority of India Ltd (SAIL) fell after the Steel Ministry forecast a lower net profit for the company in 1996/97. The stock ended 1.75 rupees below the day's high of 24.25.</p>
<p>SAIL's net profit in 1996/97 (April-March) was estimated at 6.53 billion rupees, down from 13.19 billion a year ago.</p>
<p>-- Anshuman Daga, Bombay equities desk +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
