<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="532835" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - Evening Standard -  April 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Evening Standard -  April 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>- WOMAN WHOSE LOVER COST US 250,000 STG</p>
<p>The woman at the centre of a row over an illegal Brazilian immigrant Jose dos Santos, who's stay in Britain has already cost the taxpayer 250,000 stg, has been named as Camilla Ewing.</p>
<p>- WATCHDOG PROMISES TO DEFEND CENTRICA</p>
<p>Ofgas director general Clare Spottiswoode has surprisingly revealed that Centrica, recently demerged supply arm of British Gas  GAS.L, should be excluded from the Labour Party's planned windfall tax on privatised utilities. She said the company had been set up in a competitive market and had no set plans to pay a shareholder dividend.</p>
<p>- JJB SPORTS DROPS TILNEY FOR WARBURG</p>
<p>Dave Whelan, founder and chairman of replica kit and sportswear retailer JJB Sports, defended the dropping of broker Charterhouse Tilney for SBC Warburg saying that the group needed a bigger player after recent successes.</p>
<p>- DIY GROUP OPENS DOORS TO 500 NEW JOBS</p>
<p>Two new London stores in Enfield and Thurrock later this year will create up to 500 jobs according to DIY chain B&amp;Q. The group's recent expansion has been fuelled by the housing market recovery.</p>
<p>- WEAK SPIRITS LEAVE ALLIED WITH A PROFITS HANGOVER</p>
<p>Top brokers Kleinwort Benson and SBC Warburg have recommended investors sell Allied Domecq shares after its recent poor performance compared to rivals. Profits could be hit if Bass walks away from the Carlsberg-Tetley deal.</p>
<p>- For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC on BMC +44 71 377 1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
