<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="532985" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel bonds close higher awaiting interest rates.</title>
<headline>Israel bonds close higher awaiting interest rates.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli bonds closed higher on Wednesday with the market waiting for Bank of Israel's announcement on interest rates on Thursday, traders said. Indices:</p>
<p>* Government bonds general: +0.06 pct to 105.38</p>
<p>* CPI-linked government bonds: +0.07 at 105.42</p>
<p>* Unlinked government bonds (Gilon -- issued for four years): +0.11 pct to 105.38</p>
<p>* Dollar-linked government bonds: -0.15 to 105.22</p>
<p>* Bank of Israel short-term Makam bills: +0.08 to 104.36</p>
<p>Volume was 102 million shekels.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was not affected by the political situation. Now economic factors are influencing the market, such as interest rates tomorrow,&quot; said Gidi Halpern of Meitav Investments and Securities.</p>
<p>The market closed on Sunday for the Jewish holiday of Passover and before prosecutors slapped down police recommendations that Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu be charged with fraud and breach of trust in a corruption scandal. Prosecutors found insufficient evidence to issue the first indictment against an Israeli prime minister.</p>
<p>The Bank of Israel will announce on Thursday its monetary programme for May. Its base rate has remained at an annualised 13.9 percent since the end of February.</p>
<p>&quot;There were rises in most of the bonds with the dollar-linked bonds staying stable because of a slight appreciation of the shekel today,&quot; said Halpern.</p>
<p>&quot;There was good demand for unlinked bonds because many expect there will be a small cut in interest rates tomorrow, around 0.3 percentage point,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand was up for CPI-linked bonds with fluctuating interest and for long-term CPI-linked bonds because yields are quite high,&quot; said a trader at Israel Discount Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The market believes that in the summer months inflation will be down and because of that traders are buying unlinked bonds,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On Monday and Tuesday the stock exchange was closed for the Jewish holiday of Passover.</p>
<p>Note: Makams are zero-coupon unlinked certificates with durations of three months to one year. The Bank of Israel issues Makams to absorb liquidity.</p>
<p>($1 = 3.4 shekels)</p>
<p>- Shoshanna Solomon, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
