<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="532945" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - T-bonds must hold above 108-07 to push up.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - T-bonds must hold above 108-07 to push up.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. T-bonds have the scope to move slightly higher on Wednesday, provided they can hold gains above key resistance around 108-07, technical analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can sustain a break of that level it would help the market to target congestion at 108-30,&quot; said Elizabeth Miller, technical analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell here.</p>
<p>But she added if the market cannot hold gains above 108-07, it may drift back to support at 107-16, then the 107-00 area.</p>
<p>Miller said said 108-07 was the 23.6 percent retracement of a slide on continuation charts from 114-08 on February 18 to 106-12 on April 11. It is also the point where the market has stalled in recent days.</p>
<p>Tom Hobson, director of technical analysis at Merril Lynch here, said the near term directional challenge was neutral to slightly positive.</p>
<p>&quot;Within that environment significant resistance has remained intact and therefore it is the key challenge,&quot; he said. &quot;Those resistance levels are 108-15 and 109-06, which is probably more critical.&quot;</p>
<p>Hobson said 108-15 was a 61.8 percent Fibonacci retracement of the selloff from the March 25 high and 109-06 was the 38.2 percent Fibonacci retracement of the whole two-month decline.</p>
<p>&quot;Those are the key points and they need to be overcome by Friday, otherwise the short term directional risk will shift back to the downside,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>To the downside, Hobson said there was nothing significant until 107-18,16 level, which represents a chart consolidation support area.</p>
<p>&quot;That is where the market bounced yesterday,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is quite a positive bias today, but my overall bias remains negative,&quot; he said adding the recent decline in open interest indicated a more neutral trading environment.</p>
<p>June T-bonds at 1013 GMT were at 108-09, up 5/32.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
