<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53301" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Court overturns FCC ruling on campaign ads.</title>
<headline>Court overturns FCC ruling on campaign ads.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. appeals court on Friday barred TV stations from banishing a candidate's graphic political ads about abortion or other issues to the late-night hours when children are less likely to be watching.</p>
<p>In its decision, the three-judge panel unanimously overturned a 1994 Federal Communications Commission ruling that allowed TV stations to refuse a candidate's wish to run graphic ads on abortion at times when children might be watching.</p>
<p>The agency permitted stations to &quot;channel&quot; the ads to a later time slot. While the FCC's ruling typically applied to anti-abortion messages, the issue has also arisen over racist statements and indecent speech.</p>
<p>&quot;Not only does the power to channel confer on a (station) the power to discriminate between candidates, it can force one of them to back away from what he considers to be the most effective way of presenting his position on a controversial issue...,&quot; Judge James Buckley wrote in the court's opinion.</p>
<p>The court said the FCC violated a provision of communications law requiring TV stations to give candidates for federal office &quot;reasonable access&quot; to the broadcast media.</p>
<p>The court also said the ruling broke the &quot;no censorship&quot; and &quot;equal opportunities&quot; sections of the law by allowing stations to review ads and to discriminate against candidates.</p>
<p>The case stems from an FCC ruling involving a Republican candidate for the U.S. House of Representatives -- Daniel Becker of Georgia -- who wanted to air political ads portraying images of aborted foetuses during a certain time.</p>
<p>A station that showed one of the commercials, WAGA-TV, later asked the FCC for permission to air the ads only at times when children were unlikely to be watching TV. The station had received many viewer complaints about the ad.</p>
<p>Other broadcasters sought a similar ruling from the FCC.</p>
<p>The agency ultimately ruled in favour of the broadcasters, saying that nothing under federal communications law bars a station from channelling a candidates ads if it is done &quot;to protect children&quot;.</p>
<p>The ruling prompted Becker and an interest group -- the Washington Area Citizens Coalition Interested in Viewers' Constitutional Rights (WACCI-VCR) -- to file suit.</p>
<p>&quot;This has nothing to do with the abortion issue itself,&quot; said Andy Schwartzman, executive director of the Media Access Project, a public-interest law firm representing WACCI-VCR.</p>
<p>&quot;What this is about is a citizen's right to solicit the vote of other citizens.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
