<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="533186" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FOCUS-Randgold meets goals, eyes horizon.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Randgold meets goals, eyes horizon.</headline>
<byline>Melanie Cheary</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's Randgold and Exploration Co Ltd has more than met the goals it set itself three years ago and now stands as a focused, world-class mining house, chairman Peter Flack said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Randgold has essentially achieved the ambitious objectives it set itself when the current executive took office in August 1994,&quot; Flack said at the group's March quarter gold quarterly results presentation.</p>
<p>&quot;We are nearing the end of the three year term we set ourselves and we've come a relatively long way in a short time. We've achieved our goals and a lot more besides,&quot; he said in a video transmission from London.</p>
<p>Known for its strategy of sweeping up marginal mines and revamping them into productive assets, Randgold is set to consolidate its South African gold mines, merging interests to create an East Rand and a West Rand operation.</p>
<p>With Durban Roodepoort Deep Ltd as the vehicle, its merger with Blyvooruitzicht Gold Mining Co Ltd and Buffelsfontein Gold Mines Ltd to create a West Rand gold business could be completed by mid-July, Randgold said.</p>
<p>The merger would grow the West Rand operation's market capitalisation to about 1.2 billion rand, would enhance its fund-raising ability for expansion, reduce the pay limit, increase its flexibility and drive it down the cost curve to $300 per ounce and below, the group said.</p>
<p>Randgold's Harmony Gold Mining Co Ltd has also recently made a bid to acquire and merge neighbour The Grootvlei Proprietary Mines Ltd as well as independent Consolidated Modderfontein Mines Ltd.</p>
<p>Replying to a query over Cons Modder's apparent silence over the bid, Randgold said, &quot;There is no problem with Cons Modder and the take-over at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>Harmony has already enriched its asset base by swallowing up Unisel Gold Mines Ltd, the Vermeulenskraal Noord mineral rights, Lydenburg Exploration Ltd and the Saaiplaas mine.</p>
<p>Outside South Africa Randgold has been equally successful with its mining and exploration company Randgold Resources -- due to list in London in June -- making rapid inroads into Africa and announcing encouraging results for projects there.</p>
<p>Randgold Resources announced on Wednesday it had swelled its overall estimated resource base to 10.5 million ounces of gold, of which 6.4 million ounces are attributable. It said its Syama gold mine in Mali reported encouraging results for the quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;Productivity improvement at Syama helped to slash the forecast loss for the quarter from $800,000 to $114,000,&quot; Randgold Resources chief executive Mark Bristow said.</p>
<p>He added that the Syama board had given the go-ahead to a phased capital expenditure programme designed to increase production to 270,000 ounces of gold per year and reduce operating costs to around $210/oz over a two-year period.</p>
<p>But Randgold's Flack said the group would not rest on its laurels. &quot;We're now coming to the end of the three-year term we gave ourselves -- Randgold's existing service agreements with the mines will expire in September this year -- and we've started looking at the future beyond that horizon,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is against this background that we are considering our options. The mines will be presenting their new strategies in June and Randgold itself will be reviewing its strategy the following month,&quot; Flack said.</p>
<p>Randgold's results for the 18 months to end-March 1997 show a net profit of 59.37 million rand. The results are not comparable with those for the year to end-September 1995 because of the change in year end, the inclusion of Syama's acquisition and results and the $48 million convertible bond issue.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
