<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="533261" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss monetary policy seen generous into H2 1997.</title>
<headline>Swiss monetary policy seen generous into H2 1997.</headline>
<byline>Michael Shields</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Swiss National Bank (SNB) will extend its generous monetary policy into the second half of 1997, then shift to a more neutral stance as the stagnant economy slowly picks up speed, economists forecast on Wednesday.</p>
<p>If exports start growing strongly, the central bank could then tighten policy in early 1998, they said, but added the SNB will be loath to boost rates aggressively then if turmoil over Europe's single currency is driving the Swiss franc higher.</p>
<p>The SNB said seasonally adjusted central bank money supply M0 rose an annualised 9.2 percent in the first quarter compared with the fourth quarter of 1996 to an average 32.48 billion francs ($22.2 billion), some 3.5 percent above its medium-term growth target.</p>
<p>The growth partly reflected an inexplicable acceleration in notes in circulation, the SNB said, adding it expected the key money supply figure to reach 32.9 billion in the second quarter, representing slower annualised growth of 7.2 percent.</p>
<p>Economists were also at a loss to explain the sharp rise in banknotes in circulation, but agreed it did not signal the economy was turning up after six years of stagnation.</p>
<p>&quot;It is hard to interpret. I think it is a probably a sign that they (the SNB) are still really expansive,&quot; said Hanspeter Hausherr at SBC Warburg in Zurich.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect that in the second quarter or the start of the third quarter they will move to a more neutral course, that they will not be so expansive, because we also believe that we will then see clearer signs that the economy is picking up.&quot;</p>
<p>The SNB's statement that it expects money supply growth to slow in the second quarter &quot;certainly does not signal a change in monetary policy,&quot; SNB spokesman Werner Abegg said, noting M0 was still expected to grow slightly in the second quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;If we say that, starting from this rather higher than forecast level, we don't expect growth in the second quarter to pick up again markedly, but just slightly...that is not a turn to a more restrictive policy,&quot; he said. &quot;It is accepting that the level is higher now than forecast and we expect it to stay and grow slightly from this higher level.&quot;</p>
<p>Credit Suisse chief economist Alois Bischofberger said he saw the SNB keeping its powder dry for now.</p>
<p>&quot;Monetary policy will not be more expansive than it already is unless the franc rises massively,&quot; he said, referring to the currency's potential role as a safe haven for investors spooked by prospects for a broad Economic and Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a transition to a neutral policy, which I think could come in the course of the second half, and then a more restrictive policy, with interest rate rises in early 1998, unless the EMU discussion leads to (Swiss franc) appreciation, in which case it would probably be postponed,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Bischofberger said the SNB could be forced to cut rates if the mark drops toward 80 Swiss centimes from current levels around 85.40 and from a February 1997 high of 87.77 centimes, a scenario he called improbable but one that cannot be ruled out.</p>
<p>He saw short-term money market rates staying around 1-3/4 to 2.0 percent before edging up later this year on increased demand for credit rather than any tightening move from the SNB.</p>
<p>SNB officials have noted in the past that they cannot maintain indefintely their expansive policy first adopted in early 1995 without running the risk of stoking inflation.</p>
<p>But Bischofberger said the SNB did not have to worry.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no inflationary pressure,&quot; he said, noting import price rises stemming from franc weakness had only a modest impact on consumer prices, the economy had lots of unused capacity and domestic factors pointed toward falling prices.</p>
<p>&quot;We're getting closer and closer to zero (inflation) now for the next few months,&quot; said Alexander Kobler at UBS, noting SNB Vice-chairman Jean-Pierre Roth's comments yesterday that the bank was ready to keep interest rates low for the time being.</p>
<p>Money supply remained below the medium-term target in 1995 and 1996, so the SNB has leeway to watch and wait, he said.</p>
<p>He saw the SNB with a neutral stance in the third or fourth quarter so that M0 grows an average 4.5 percent in 1997. &quot;We expect a gradual slowdown of growth rates in the second quarter and a considerable slowdown in the third and fourth quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>He agreed the SNB would keep the Swiss franc's exchange rate in mind when deciding when to start pushing rates up again.</p>
<p>&quot;The policy will be a mixture of real economic and exchange rate policy,&quot; he said. &quot;They will (accept) some inflation to prevent the exchange rate from appreciating significantly.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Zurich newsroom +41 1 631 7340 ($ = 1.464 Swiss Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
