<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="533260" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Data deluge not to change view on Belgium, analysts.</title>
<headline>Data deluge not to change view on Belgium, analysts.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The past week's deluge of economic forecasts will not lead to any fundamental revision of the bond market's approach to Belgian paper, but other factors might, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The European Commission ended a busy period for number crunchers on Wednesday, predicting Belgium will cut its deficit to 2.7 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) in 1997, well below the three percent required for monetary union and the Belgian government's own 2.9 percent target.</p>
<p>The Commission saw Belgium's economy growing 2.3 percent, above the 2.1 percent taken by the government for its budget.  </p>
<p>The Commission's deficit forecast compared with one from Belgium's semi-governmental Federal Planning Office earlier on Wednesday of 2.5 percent of GDP, a forecast Tuesday from the OECD of 2.9 percent and a National Bank of Belgium (NBB) deficit forecast earlier this month of 2.9 percent. The Planning Office pegged Belgian growth at 2.1 percent, the OECD 2.2 percent and the NBB 2.0 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;There's rather a broad consensus on the outlook for the Belgian economy...I don't think these figures will make a great difference,&quot; Generale Bank's Sylviane Delcuve said. Generale Bank pegs Belgian growth at 2.0 percent and the deficit at 2.9.  </p>
<p>&quot;If there is any reaction it should be positive. The Commission and Federal Planning Office forecasts are below the government's...but we see regularly that one good or bad figure does not really influence the market. There's no hot money in Belgium,&quot; said Kredietbank economist Conrad Fieremans.</p>
<p>J.P.Morgan's Ellen van der Gulik believed the various growth forecasts could prove too optimistic, although this would not impact Belgium's chances of getting its deficit down to EMU levels. &quot;Recent indicators, not the forecasts, have left us disappointed,&quot; she said, citing data on consumer demand. &quot;We might perhaps revise down our 1.9 percent growth forecast.&quot;  </p>
<p>Van der Gulik said the central bank's decision to peg its growth forecast below the governments was a signal that growth might perhaps turn out to be weaker than expected.</p>
<p>&quot;We are seeing that people tend to be reasonably optimistic about growth in Europe. There are only two countries which are disappointing: that is Italy and Belgium,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>However, Belgium's budget, drawn up with a built in safeguard against any rise in interest rates, will not be in danger if monetary tightening starts again in Germany as expected next year, she noted. Van der Gulik said Belgium was only threatened by what may happen in neighbouring France.  </p>
<p>From a bond market perspective, it was more interesting to think about how problems in France might spill over into Belgium, she said. What EMU delay talk might mean and whether the French snap election might be mirrored in Belgium.</p>
<p>&quot;This is what will drive the market in the coming weeks,&quot; van der Gulik said.</p>
<p>Belgian bonds were little changed in late Wednesday trade after the Commission's forecasts, with the yield on the 10-year benchmark OLO at 5.97 percent, its opening level, and the spread over Bunds an unchanged 14 basis points.</p>
<p>-- Nick Antonovics, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6817, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
