<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="533395" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: ECB policy might be more accomodating under EMU.</title>
<headline>ECB policy might be more accomodating under EMU.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Monetary policy under a single European currency might be tilted towards an accomodating stance given tight budget policies, the European Commission said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In a report assessing the international implications of economic and monetary union (EMU), the Commission made several observations about the euro's exchange rate and future exchange rate policies.</p>
<p>The euro's credibility and its value on global markets will depend on a variety of economic factors and policy decisions, the Commission said.</p>
<p>Perhaps most importantly, it noted that monetary policy within the euro area might be more accomodating given the tightness of budget policies and a commitment to reduce high unemployment.</p>
<p>Following are the observations made by the Commission's report:</p>
<p>-- &quot;The economic policy factors which will influence the euro's exchange rate fall into two categories: internal and external. At the European level, the conditions for a stability-oriented monetary policy are set out in the (Maastricht) Treaty. The independence of the European Central Bank and a fiscal policy avoiding excessive deficits are the basis upon which monetary policy will maintain stability and hence sustainable growth.</p>
<p>-- &quot;In the beginning, however, short-term considerations may impact the euro. Such effects may become evident even before the third stage of EMU actually begins and may influence the currencies of likely euro area participants...A balanced policy mix should lead to low long-term interest rates enabling easy monetary conditions at an exchange rate which is appropriate in view of economic conditions.</p>
<p>-- &quot;Considering the economic prospects for the European economy compared to that of the United States, different cyclical positions will impact on the stance of relative economic policies and thus on the exchange rate. Given the Union's objectives to achieve both fiscal consolidation and full employment, this creates conditions for a relatively easy monetary stance in the euro area.</p>
<p>-- &quot;Given that fiscal policy is committed to reducing the deficit towards close to balance or surplus, monetary policy would be able to conduct a fairly accomodative policy without jeopardising its primary objective of price stability.</p>
<p>-- &quot;Among long-term considerations, the euro exchange rate will reflect the functioning of EMU. In particular, the challenge of greater competition must be met by appropriate structural policies. Greater labour market flexibility, tax and social security reform in the direction of the most efficient systems will help the European economy to adapt to global challenges.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
