<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="533466" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Major hits out at Labour plans for Scotland.</title>
<headline>UK's Major hits out at Labour plans for Scotland.</headline>
<byline>Alan Wheatley</byline>
<dateline>INVERNESS, Scotland 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister John Major, buoyed by signs his Conservative party is gaining ground in opinion polls, hit out on Wednesday at the opposition Labour party's plans to set up a separate parliament for Scotland.</p>
<p>At a news conference during an election campaign visit to Scotland, Major said Labour's plans to devolve power to a parliament in Edinburgh would risk jobs and lead speedily to friction with London's parliament and then to fracture from it.</p>
<p>&quot;Would Scotland be weaker or stronger then? Weaker.</p>
<p>&quot;Would Scotland attract more or less investment? Less.</p>
<p>&quot;Would Scotland have a stronger or a weaker voice in the European Union? Weaker.</p>
<p>&quot;And so would the rest of the United Kingdom,&quot; Major said.</p>
<p>He declined to comment on an opinion poll in Wednesday's Guardian newspaper showing a dramatic reduction in Labour's lead ahead of the May 1 parliamentary election to five points from 14 a week before.</p>
<p>&quot;I've never commented on polls.&quot; Major said, adding he was much more concerned with the reaction of voters on the doorstep. &quot;I am very happy with the way the campaign is going and I'm increasingly confident as we move forward towards May the 1st.&quot;</p>
<p>Major attributes his come-from-behind performance to win the last election in 1992 to his staunch defence of Scotland's place in the United Kingdom and is determined to hammer home the same message as the 1997 campaign enters its last eight days.</p>
<p>He attacked Labour's plans for Scotland as confusing, noting that Labour leader Tony Blair had originally called the proposed Edinburgh parliament a powerhouse only to refer to it later as a parish council.</p>
<p>&quot;What we're seeing is the total and complete disintegration of a centrepiece of the Labour party's programme day by day.&quot;</p>
<p>Combined with Labour's plans to cede more sovereignty to Brussels, the result would be a move towards a Europe of the regions with weaker nation states, meaning Britain would be less able to advocate the national interest and win the argument, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This cannot be the right way forward. What is at stake therefore is not just our constitution but what our constitution protects -- our ability to deliver prosperity to our people.</p>
<p>&quot;Scotland has seen investment soar, jobs created and new industry take root. Does Scotland want to throw all this away just when we are on the verge of real success. I think not.&quot;</p>
<p>Scottish secretary Michael Forsyth, flanking Major at the news conference, was even more vivid in his description of the threat from Labour, saying its proposed parliament would ultimately lead to an independent Scottish socialist republic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="INVERNESS, Scotland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
