<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="533456" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: New poll electrifies UK election campaign.</title>
<headline>New poll electrifies UK election campaign.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new poll showing a dramatic fall in the opposition Labour party's lead on Wednesday electrified the campaign for Britain's May 1 election, turning what had seemed to be a certainty into an open race.</p>
<p>The ICM poll in The Guardian newspaper slashed Labour's lead from 14 to just five points, the first time the opposition's advantage has fallen to single figures since November 1993.</p>
<p>Tory strategists said the dramatic change showed Prime Minister John Major's tactic of focussing on Europe and the threat to Britain's sovereignty from Brussels was working.</p>
<p>Labour's foreign affairs spokesman Robin Cook dismissed it, saying: &quot;We're not worried, we know we're comfortably ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;ICM always has a smaller lead than the other polls. We are confident that we're going to enter that last lap ahead and if we work, we can win.&quot;</p>
<p>Labour economics spokesman Gordon Brown pointed to a rolling Gallup poll in Wednesday's Daily Telegraph putting Labour 21 points ahead, an increase in five in a week, saying: &quot;There's so many polls, you have to take them with a pinch of salt.&quot;</p>
<p>But the news sent shockwaves through the Labour leadership, which on Tuesday night said it was frustrated that the campaign was becoming bogged down, boring voters and playing into the hands of the Conservatives.</p>
<p>Labour believes this was exactly Major's intention when he called an eight-week campaign, the longest in 80 years.</p>
<p>Blair tried to break through what aides called the &quot;media wall&quot; on Tuesday night, dispensing with prepared speeches to give an impassioned unscripted appeal for a chance to govern.</p>
<p>&quot;The election is about the soul of this country,&quot; Blair said, calling on 700 supporters in a concert hall to the north to launch a &quot;crusade to change this country for the better&quot; in the eight days left to the May 1 poll.</p>
<p>&quot;On the first of May we do have a choice as a country,&quot; he told the gathering, which was also addressed by rock star Gary Kemp of Spandau Ballet and Anita Roddick, founder and chief executive of the cosmetic company Body Shop.</p>
<p>&quot;We can stay with this discredited, tired, flapped out Conservative Party, divided, hopelessly led, hopelessly unable to face the modern world, or we can choose a better future with a different government that believes that the best of British values are what we need back in this country today,&quot; Blair said.</p>
<p>Launching into a theme aides say will feature increasingly in the final days of the campaign, Blair said the Conservatives would stop at nothing to win a fifth consecutive term of office.</p>
<p>&quot;Their only weapon left is fear, to terrify people, to frighten them, to say that nothing can ever really change, they are all the same, just be cynical,&quot; Blair said.</p>
<p>But the dangers of the tactic became apparent when the Conservatives seized on Blair's off-the-cuff remark that he would cut value added tax on fuel &quot;if we've got room for a tax cut&quot;.</p>
<p>The ruling Party accused him of backing down on a party promise to get rid of the tax, but Labour denied the remark was a change in policy, saying it was just a figure of speech.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
