<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="533538" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Blair urges voters to overcome media cynicism.</title>
<headline>UK's Blair urges voters to overcome media cynicism.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>STEVENAGE, England 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Labour leader Tony Blair made an impassioned appeal to voters late on Tuesday to overcome what close aides see as growing media cynicism surrounding Britain's May 1 election.</p>
<p>In an unscripted speech to around 700 people in a concert hall to the north of London Blair called for a &quot;crusade to change this country for the better&quot; in the eight days left to the May 1 poll.</p>
<p>&quot;On the first of May we do have a choice as a country,&quot; he told the glitzy gathering attended by rock star Gary Kemp of Spandau Ballet and Anita Roddick, founder and chief executive of the cosmetic company Body Shop.</p>
<p>&quot;We can stay with this discredited, tired, flapped out Conservative Party, divided, hopelessly led, hopelessly unable to face the modern world, or we can choose a better future with a different government that believes that the best of British values are what we need back in this country today,&quot; Blair said.</p>
<p>But there was mixed news for Labour from the latest polls.</p>
<p>An ICM poll in The Guardian newspaper showed Labour's lead over the Conservatives had been reduced to just five points, while a rolling Gallup poll in The Daily Telegraph put Labour 21 points ahead, an increase in five from the previous week.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Major has dismissed opinion polls in the past and aides travelling with him on the campaign trail in Scotland said they were not getting carried away by the Guardian poll.</p>
<p>The ICM poll was consistent with private polls showing Labour's lead in single digit with the tide turning in the Conservatives favour, they said.</p>
<p>With just over a week to the election, Blair is growing worried that the campaign is becoming bogged down as he believes was intended by Major when he called an eight-week campaign, the longest in 80 years.</p>
<p>Worried that Labour's poll hefty lead could just wither away as voters become disenchanted with the constant media diet of politics, Blair said, &quot;You see these broadcasts and there is no sense that the election is about the soul of this country.&quot;</p>
<p>He described the election as a &quot;millennium election...that will decide the government to take this country into the 21 century&quot; and promised action on education and health as well as a sure hand on the economic tiller.</p>
<p>The Conservatives seized on Blair's off-the-cuff remark that he would cut VAT (tax) on fuel &quot;if we've got room for a tax cut&quot;.</p>
<p>The ruling Party accused him of backing down on a party promise to get rid of the tax, but Labour denied the remark was a change in policy, saying it was just a figure of speech.</p>
<p>Launching into a theme which aides say will feature increasingly in the final days of the campaign, Blair said voters had to consider the prospect of a fifth Conservative term of office.</p>
<p>They will stop at nothing to continue in power after 18 years. &quot;Their only weapon left is fear, to terrify people, to frighten them, to say that nothing can ever really change, they are all the same, just be cynical,&quot; Blair said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that hope is a stronger weapon than fear and we are going to make hope drive out fear.&quot;</p>
<p>Blair, calling himself a product of the &quot;rock n' roll&quot; generation also sought to reassure older Labour voters that his modernisation of the party had not ditched its traditional values.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STEVENAGE, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
