<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="533609" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: INSTANT VIEW-Australian Q1 inflation data.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW-Australian Q1 inflation data.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's consumer price index (CPI) rose 0.2 percent in the March quarter to be 1.3 percent higher over the year. Underlying inflation rose 0.4 percent in the quarter to be 2.1 percent higher over the past 12 months.</p>
<p>Economists' forecasts had centred on a quarterly rise of 0.1 percent, for an annual rate of 1.2 percent. The underlying rate was expected to have risen 0.4 percent in the quarter to be up 2.1 percent over the year. A selection of economists immediate reactions to the data follows.</p>
<p>JOHN KYRIAKOPOULOS, CHIEF ECONOMIST, J.P. MORGAN:</p>
<p>&quot;The inflation result was bang on what we expected and it was pretty neutral for the markets. It confirms that currently inflation remains low and there are no inflation pressures. So there is no additional news in the number, only confirmation.&quot;</p>
<p>JOHN EDWARDS, CHIEF ECONOMIST, HSBC MARKETS:</p>
<p>&quot;It's slightly more than expected, but a very good result and confirms the pattern of very low inflation in Australia which we expect to see continued in the June quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>CRAIG JAMES, SENIOR ECONOMIST, COLONIAL STATE BANK:</p>
<p>&quot;It was in line with expectations but it was not as good as what the futures market was hoping for. What it says is that low inflation is entrenched in Australia and is likely to stay that way for a good 12 months. It will have to wait until the next employment figures for speculation to resurface on rate cuts.&quot;  </p>
<p>GUY BRUTEN, ECONOMIST, SBC WARBURG:</p>
<p>&quot;It was pretty close to expectations. Underlying inflation at 0.4 (percent) and the annual rate at 2.1 keeps things right at the bottom of the Reserve Bank's target band and that's basically where we'd expect to see underlying inflation staying for most of this year. In concert with the wage result yesterday, I think it underlines the fact that the inflation picture is pretty good in Australia and likely to remain that way for awhile. We're still some way away from the inflation fundamentals deteriorating.&quot;</p>
<p>KAREN PRINGLE, TREASURY ECONOMIST, ANZ BANK:</p>
<p>&quot;These numbers today just confirm what we already knew -- that inflation is currently pretty good and over the next year or so is likely to remain fairly low and at the low end of the Reserve BAnk's range. I guess the issue really is what happens on the activity side. Inflation is not standing in the way of another rate cut ... I think we would need to see activity stall significantly for us to see the Reserve Bank consider cutting rates again, particularly in an environment where the Fed has begun tightening policy.&quot;  </p>
<p>STEPHEN KOUKOULAS, CHIEF ECONOMIST, CITIBANK AUSTRALIA:</p>
<p>&quot;Looking at these numbers the Reserve Bank will be more than happy. It justifies their rate cuts of last year. Whether it warrants another rate cut, I think it is more than just the inflation outcome that is important now, it is where activity is going. And that is where we fast forward to next week's building approvals, retail trade and AWOTE (average weekly ordinary time earnings) numbers. All in all this a great number and clearly locks in the low inflation story.&quot;  </p>
<p>BRUCE HOCKMAN, SENIOR ECONOMIST, DEUTSCHE MORGAN GRENFELL:</p>
<p>&quot;I suppose the critical thing is that it is not really any better than I think most of the market had expected. It leaves the numbers on track for the bottom of the Reserve Bank's target range ... so nothing unexpected in this and not an obstacle to a further easing. The answer lies in activity, but I suspect the market might be underweighting the level of frustration that might be out there with the slowness of unemployment to improve.&quot;</p>
<p>NOMURA RESEARCH INSTITUTE, ANDREW PEASE, SENIOR ECONOMIST:</p>
<p>&quot;It was right on expectations, there were no surprises really. With 8.7 percent unemployment and 2.1 percent inflation, the Reserve Bank could easily cut interest rates and it would have no trouble justifying it. But the thing is what will they do? And my guess is they might leave interest rates unchanged for a long period of time. With yesterday's living wage decision and today's low inflation numbers it seems that they (RBA) are putting an extended period of time on interest rates remaining at six percent.&quot;  </p>
<p>PETER MUNCKTON, SENIOR ECONOMIST, BANKERS TRUST:</p>
<p>&quot;This CPI number was pretty well in the market anyway. Overall it underlines that inflation is very good. It's current standing is at the lower end of the Reserve Bank's band and it's likely to fall under that band in the next quarter, and could well be there the quarter after that. Inflation is looking good. The headline inflation, 1.3 percent to March, will be good if that helps lower inflation expectations out in the community which will improve further chances of maintaining lower inflation over long periods.&quot;</p>
<p>MICHAEL BLYTHE, SENIOR ECONOMIST, COMMONWEALTH BANK:</p>
<p>&quot;We have now had close to six years of inflation comfortable within the Reserve Bank's 2.0 to 3.0 percent range, so it's not a case of a good result, it's more a case of being a normal result. I don't see too much in there that policy makers are going to get too concern about. Given that this outcome was expected for quite a while I don't think it adds much more to the monthly policy equation. Certainly yesterday's wage case decision was the most important for new information on the inflation front.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 651-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
