<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="533635" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila share index climbs 1.86 pct at close.</title>
<headline>Manila share index climbs 1.86 pct at close.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>------------------------- April 23 --------------------------</p>
<p>* Empire,Megaworld bounce back</p>
<p>-------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The Philippine share index snapped out of its two-day plunge on Wednesday, encouraged by the Dow's gains and improved sentiment on two property firms, traders said.</p>
<p>The market finished 53.11 points, or 1.86 percent higher, at 2,913.56</p>
<p>&quot;This is a good comeback from the disaster yesterday. Across-the-board, the mood changed due possibly to the very sharp rise of the Dow,&quot; said Irving Ackerman at I. Ackerman &amp; Co Inc.</p>
<p>Turnover was a substantial 2.58 billion pesos.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market just reacted to Wall Street's phenomenal rise and realisation that the fears on Empire and Megaworld were exaggerated,&quot; said Poch Zamora, dealer at Peregrine Securities.</p>
<p>Empire East Land Holdings Inc and parent firm Megaworld Properties &amp; Holdings Inc which tumbled to lows for the year on Tuesday, bounced back on denials of rumours they were facing bankruptcy.</p>
<p>Megaworld closed at its intra-day high of 4.80 pesos, rising 28 percent.  Empire East, the most heavily traded issue, also ended near its day-high of 4.80 pesos, finishing 1.10 pesos higher, or 30.14 percent, to 4.75 pesos.</p>
<p>Nathan Lozada, assistant vice-president at Philippine Asia Equity, said foreign investors may be back as they are seen dabbling in stocks such as Ayala Land Inc, Manila Electric Co and San Miguel Corp</p>
<p>Despite the gains, traders said market will remain cautious in the coming days and would look to the Dow for direction.</p>
<p>Traders said concerns about oversupply in the property sector would also continue to plague the market.</p>
<p>    -- KATHERINE ESPINA   (63 2) 841-8939 Fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
