<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="533787" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: FUND VIEW - Funds avoid Indian graft, not politics.</title>
<headline>FUND VIEW - Funds avoid Indian graft, not politics.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Davison</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign funds are steering clear of India, and politics has nothing to do with it.</p>
<p>Corruption has eclipsed political upheaval as a reason to avoid India in the minds of many foreign fund managers, despite signs of improvement in the nation's economic fundamentals.</p>
<p>&quot;You can't buy when you want to. You certainly can't sell when you want to,&quot; said Gary Greenberg, deputy managing director at Peregrine Asset Management.</p>
<p>&quot;Movements in the index are always -- and I mean always -- generated by what are called market operators,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Fund managers dismissed last week's political changes in the country as a personal power play.</p>
<p>They said the absence of key economic reformer and former United Front finance minister P. Chidambaram from the new coalition government would have little impact, largely because new Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral has pledged publicly to widen and deepen current economic reforms.</p>
<p>Instead, foreign funds have focused on the difficulties of investing effectively in a tricky but increasingly attractive market -- and most are opting to stay on the sidelines.</p>
<p>In Bombay, earnings per share growth is forecast at about 20 percent this year on multiples of between 10 and 12 times, and the outlook for 1998, according to many funds, is just as good.</p>
<p>&quot;Eighteen to 20 percent for 1997 could be on the high side, but that's not inconsistent with 1998, which brings the multiple down to 10 times,&quot; said Richard Nicholas, managing director at Hambro Pacific Fund Management.</p>
<p>He sees a target of 4,500 for Bombay's Sensex index, which has soared 23 percent so far this year and ended Wednesday's morning session 0.84 points higher at 3,800.63.</p>
<p>The improved performance follows growing opinion that the nation is poised for economic recovery following a cyclical slowdown caused by the lagged effect of tight monetary policy.</p>
<p>But there are powerful disincentives to investing in India despite its attractions, said Stewart Aldcroft, director of sales and marketing at Templeton Investment Management.</p>
<p>Templeton had a &quot;rather indifferent experience&quot; with a US$500 million investment in early 1995, depending on which stockbroker it used, Aldcroft said. On one occasion, it was prevented from selling a stock for 400 days because the registration was controlled by the company owner.</p>
<p>&quot;We then made it plain to any Indian stockbroker who wanted to do business with us that we would only do business within a given time...otherwise we would give them no further business,&quot; Aldcroft said. &quot;This we found to be a remarkable incentive.&quot;</p>
<p>Templeton has much more money it would like to invest in India were it to offer the same sort of trading, registration and custody arrangements available in other markets.</p>
<p>Peregrine's Greenberg said he was prevented from buying a US$150,000 stake in a company with a market capitalisation of more than US$300 million.</p>
<p>&quot;This was not a huge order... The excuse was, 'We could have bought you US$15,000,'&quot; he said.</p>
<p>India would attract much more foreign money if it simply introduced and enforced insider trading laws, he said.</p>
<p>The lack of settlement requirements allows market operators to take a position without settling the account -- and then watch what the market does.</p>
<p>&quot;It's riskless,&quot; Greenberg said. &quot;If they move to...settle within four days, then you'd have a real stock market. When that day comes, it'll be much more interesting,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong News Room (852) 2843 6470</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
