<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="533823" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index jumps in early trade.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index jumps in early trade.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index jumped 165 points, or 1.31 percent, to 12,746 just after the opening bell on Wednesday in line with Wall Street's big gains overnight, brokers said.</p>
<p>The index eased slightly to trade 158 points higher at 12,741 on light trade of less than HK$500 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Wall Street and futures related activity will give us an extra boost today,&quot; said Charles Cheung, executive director at J&amp;A Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;But technically we are still in a trading range of 12,300 to 12,800,&quot; Cheung said.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones Industrial Average soared 173.38 points or 2.6 percent to 6,833.59, the second highest point gain in the index's history.</p>
<p>The April Hang Seng Index futures contract opened 220 points higher at 12,790, then eased to trade 155 points up at 12,725.</p>
<p>&quot;There is resistance at 12,800,&quot; said one futures trader at an U.S. broker.</p>
<p>Market favourites HSBC Holdings, Sun Hung Kai Properties and Hang Seng Bank led the market.</p>
<p>HSBC led the most active table, gaining HK$2.50 to HK$189.50 on trade of HK$140 million and subsidiary Hang Seng Bank rose HK$1.25 to HK$85.75. Sun Hung Kai Properties put on HK$1.25 to HK81.00.</p>
<p>H shares and red chips were also active. Dongfang Electrical advanced HK$0.175 or 8.05 percent, to HK$2.35 but on low volume of only 412,000 shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai Hai Xing jumped to HK$1.62 then eased to trade HK$0.05 higher at HK$1.56.</p>
<p>Red chip favourite China Resources was actively traded rising HK$0.30 to HK$20.35 on trade of about HK$55.58 million.</p>
<p>CITIC Pacific continued its long recovery, gaining HK$0.20 to HK$40.10.</p>
<p>Going against the trend were Tai Cheung Holdings which lost HK$0.15 to HK$6.10 and Founder (HK) which fell HK$0.15 or 2.86 percent to HK$5.10.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
