<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="533851" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian rupiah stable in range trading.</title>
<headline>Indonesian rupiah stable in range trading.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indonesian rupiah was stable against the dollar in range trading on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said volume was thin in the morning, with some players seen trying to cash out from spot dollars on the back of relatively expensive tom/next swaps.</p>
<p>One U.S. bank dealer said spot rupiah ended at 2,419 in New York overnight, triggering operators to cash out in Singapore and Jakarta as tom/next was traded at 0.40/0.45 points.</p>
<p>He said operators were worried over prospects of a tightening after the central bank money market policy was neutral on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>But dealers said liquidity was not really tight. Overnight money eased down to 11.5 percent from 12.0/13.0 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The underlying sentiment remains biddish for the dollar despite some early profit-taking after sharp dollar increases on Tuesday,&quot; the U.S. bank dealer said.</p>
<p>He said the dollar was expected to hover between 2,417 and 2,418 in the morning.</p>
<p>Spot rupiah was at 2,417.25/17.75 at 0200 GMT, compared with an opening of 2,418.5/19.5. Tomorrow and today rupiah were at 2,416.75/17.25 and 2,416.5/17.0, respectively.  </p>
<p>One state bank dealer said the rupiah was engineered down late on Tuesday on liquidity and political factors.</p>
<p>He said the approaching general elections on May 29 would keep the tone biddish on the U.S. currency. However, the rupiah might be supported in the short-term due to month-end factors.</p>
<p>Overnight swap was at 0.4/0.5 points. Another dealer said swap rates inched up slightly following an easing in overnight money, but were sold off later by offshore players.</p>
<p>One-month swaps were at 11.5/12.0, two at 22.5/24.0, three at 34.0/34.5 and six at 71.75/72.75 points.</p>
<p>Bank Indonesia raised its intervention band by one point to 2,403/2,595 and the conversion band at 2,403/2,451 on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
