<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="533945" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek shares stuck in range, seen holding.</title>
<headline>Greek shares stuck in range, seen holding.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek stocks were rangebound in early Wednesday trade with market watchers saying the market was coming to a standstill ahead of the Greek Easter holiday as investors were cautious over the course of macroeconomic indicators.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are getting lazy ahead of the Easter recess. The market shall be calm for a brief period before new information on macroeconomic indicators has an impact,&quot; said analyst Tasos Rapakoulias at Katsoulis Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices already reflect all positive developments and my only concern is over the extent of the drop of CPI-inflation below 6.0 percent in April and the slow growth of fiscal revenues,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Recent rallies in major international stock markets were not expected to have positive percussions on the Athens bourse, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not count on New York's rise for an appreciation in Athens. In fact, past experience has shown that shock waves from foreign markets hit Greece only during bear trends,&quot; said Rapakoulias.</p>
<p>The theme of the day in Athens is the financial performance of industrial blue chips Silver &amp; Baryte and Heracles Cement.</p>
<p>&quot;The day has started with a set of adverse news on two large industrial stocks. Concerns over the impact on Silver &amp; Baryte's bottom line after the recent merger with affiliated Bauxite Parnass are vindicated,&quot; said John Tegopoulos, analyst with Midland-Pantelakis Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;Heracles Cement's profit growth is wiped out on a consolidated level by the performance of recently acquired Chalkis Cement,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Silver &amp; Baryte hit a low of 4,186 drachmas shortly after trading commenced, while Heracles Cement started weak also.</p>
<p>Other analysts said Silver &amp; Baryte's large provisions were a temporary phenomenon and would not affect long-term prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;A dividend per share of 140 drachmas for 1996 is going to reward its investors. Profit growth will resume very soon,&quot; said Rapakoulias.</p>
<p>The Athens general share index was 0.03 percent higher at 1,433.17 from Tuesday's 1,432.97 close after 40 minutes of trade.</p>
<p>Turnover amounted to 2.9 billion drachmas on 1.05 million shares traded. Advancers led decliners 79 to 70 with 29 stocks unchanged on 178 traded.</p>
<p>The Merrill Lynch call spread warrant on OTE with a strike price of 3,800 drachmas was quoted unchanged at 1,081.0 - 1,111.0. Shares of OTE telecom, the underlying, were flat at 6,150 drachmas.</p>
<p>The ING Baring Financial Products American style call warrant based on a basket of six bank stocks was quoted lower at $60.60-$62.21. The strike price is set at $99.60 and the warrants expire October 8, 1997.</p>
<p>The ING Baring Financial Products American- style call warrant on a basket of six blue-chips denominated in drachmas was quoted lower at 2,090-2,284 drachmas.</p>
<p>The strike price is set at 10,000 drachmas and the warrants expire on February 2, 1998.</p>
<p>The recently launched ING Baring American-style second call warrant on a basket of six bank stocks was quoted lower at $12.57-N/O. The strike price is set at $110.0 and the warrants expire April 9 1998.</p>
<p>--Angelos Kiosklis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
