<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53399" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Muni brokers dubious of CBOT's real-time proposal.</title>
<headline>Muni brokers dubious of CBOT's real-time proposal.</headline>
<byline>Al Yoon</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Support from municipal brokers was lukewarm at best this week as Chicago Board of Trade stepped up efforts to provide real-time, identified quotes in the municipal futures contract.</p>
<p>Richard McDermott, president of Chapdelaine &amp; Co, said he was unsure if his firm would support the proposal because details have yet to unfold. But he noted that a similar CBOT real-time service attempted several years ago met little success.</p>
<p>An exchange official Tuesday said CBOT will propose an electronic system for displaying real-time dealer bid and asks for the contract in an effort to add &quot;a little transparency&quot; to the contract.</p>
<p>The idea grew out of a July meeting with members of an industry advisory counsel, the official said.</p>
<p>But McDermott said he was skeptical municipal volume would justify constant, real-time quotes. &quot;It depends on what the whole scenario turns out to be,&quot; McDermott said.</p>
<p>And while players have long complained of contract finagling, McDermott said real-time, indentified quotes would not necessarily address concerns.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's say brokers put quotes up, Goldman, Merrill and others put quotes up, but if someone wants to put bids out anonymously they'd go through their brokers,&quot; he said, adding that he didn't think there was anything wrong with that.</p>
<p>Other participating brokers said institution of real-time quote system would eat away at their own business. Nick Soldo, a broker with Cantor, Fitzgerald Municipal Brokers Inc, said dealers and arbs will simply bypass the brokers broker as they go to hit the bid on an indexed bond.</p>
<p>&quot;If there's a listed bid of 5.92 from one bank, well, if I'm another bank I'm not going to go to Cantor Fitzgerald or any other broker, I'm going straight to that bank,&quot; Soldo said. &quot;Those that don't care to be anonymous are going to go direct, almost on-the-line trading.&quot;</p>
<p>Should the real-time, indentified quotes become reality, Soldo said he &quot;would have to&quot; participate.</p>
<p>Market sources confirmed CBOT officials visited New York brokers on Thursday afternoon to discuss the proposal and other pending changes to the contract. One broker, who asked not to go on record, said after the meeting the CBOT will attempt to institute the real-time system.</p>
<p>The 40 bond index is priced and evaluated by Chapdelaine, Cantor Fitzgerald, J.F. Hartfield &amp; Co, Municipal Partners Inc, Titus &amp; Donnelly Inc and J.J. Kenney Drake Inc.</p>
<p>Even though brokers were reserved at best about the idea, they did concede the proposal would speed trades for the dealer and arbitrage community.</p>
<p>Kevin Walsh, managing director of Smith Barney Inc's municipal arbitrage group, said real time quotes published with brokers names would undoubtedly enhance the efficiency of municipal trade surrounding the index.</p>
<p>Brokers would openly compete to produce the best bids and garner coveted business, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If I'm a broker I want you to see my name because if someone wants to hit the bid they're going to call and sell $2 million into the bid,&quot; he said. &quot;Since they don't publish the names I don't know where to go.&quot;</p>
<p>Chapdelaine's McDermott said dealers &quot;who want to have their bid hit&quot; already press the market for maximum exposure.</p>
<p>--212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
