<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="534050" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FEATURE - WorldSpace to launch digital satellite radio.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - WorldSpace to launch digital satellite radio.</headline>
<byline>Marcel Michelson</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Next year will see the launch of the first of three satellites owned by WorldSpace Inc which aims to offer digital audio broadcasting (DAB) radio through space.</p>
<p>A key step in the project will be taken in the next few months when deals will be signed with electronics manufacturers for the production of small radio sets at a cost of $150.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in final negotiations,&quot; said corporate affairs director John McLaren during a visit to Paris.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect us to sign with some four southeast Asian manufacturers within three months.&quot;</p>
<p>McLaren said that the Asian companies were &quot;technology leaders&quot; to make the radio sets which will be able to receive the &quot;L-band&quot; frequencies of WorldSpace's satellites as well as the more usual FM and AM radio waves.</p>
<p>The $150 price, much higher than the originally planned $100 level, is set to come down to less than $50 and in the long run below $10.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment we are talking about $150 which is obviously expensive for the developing world but this is like FM radios when they started. The beauty of technology is that they are getting cheaper the longer you go on,&quot; McLaren said.</p>
<p>SALES OF RADIO SETS KEY TO SUCCESS</p>
<p>Their sales are key to WorldSpace's success -- without radios there would be nobody to listen to the WorldSpace satellites and Noah Samara's $1 billion gamble would fail.</p>
<p>Samara founded WorldSpace in 1990 and successfully conducted talks in 1992 with the International Telecommunications Union (ITU) to get worldwide permission to use the wavelength between 1,467 and 1,492 Megahertz for digital radio.</p>
<p>He is now chairman and chief executive of what McLaren called &quot;a one billion dollar company&quot; which will not see its first revenues until 1998.</p>
<p>WorldSpace aims to reach 4.6 billion listeners with its three first satellites -- AfriStar which will be launched in June 1998, AsiaStar in December 1998 and Caribstar in June 1999.</p>
<p>The project has a big French involvement. Alcatel Espace, a unit of Alcatel Alsthom, is the key contractor to manufacture the satellites which also involves Matra Marconi Space.</p>
<p>Arianespace will launch the satellites which will be operated from a control centre in Toulouse, southwest France. Franco-Italian semiconductor group SGS-Thomson Microelectronics NV and ITT Intermetall in Germany will produce the first two million Starman chipsets for the radios.</p>
<p>SATELLITES LOWER BROADCASTERS' COSTS</p>
<p>McLaren said that WorldSpace aimed to lease capacity on its satellites to radio broadcasters who could offer high quality programmes in large areas, especially in what is called the developing world.</p>
<p>&quot;The beauty of satellites is that a broadcaster does not have to invest in infrastructure,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The first broadcasters to sign up were Voice of America, Radio Nederland and operators in Kenya, Ghana, Zimbabwe, Korea and Colombia.</p>
<p>McLaren said that at the start, WorldSpace would itself also develop content on the radio including a &quot;World Premier&quot; global radio service without commercials.</p>
<p>The constellation of three satellites will deliver a total of 864 channels of sound which can be configured according to quality needs to up to 108 channels of compact disc compatible quality.</p>
<p>But the first interest in World Star's target markets is not superior quality.</p>
<p>This is a big difference with other Digital Audio Broadcasting (DAB) projects such as the land-based Eureka 147 project for which the first receivers are set to be priced at up to $1,000 each.</p>
<p>Not that WorldSpace shies away from the more affluent markets and their quality concerns.</p>
<p>It has a 20 percent stake in American Mobile Radio Corp (AMRC) which has won an FCC licence for $89.9 million to provide satellite-based Digital Audio Radio Service (DARS) throughout the U.S.</p>
<p>SATELLITES SET FOR LAUNCH</p>
<p>WorldSpace's three satellites, of some 3,000 kg each, will be put in orbit 36,000 km above the equator with stations at 21 degrees east for AfriStar, 95 degrees west for CaribStar and 105 east for AsiaStar.</p>
<p>They will be among the first of an impressive series of satellites to be launched for media and communications in the 21th century.</p>
<p>Motorola's Iridium plans to launch 66 communications satellites. Globalstar, backed by Loral Space, plans 48 satellites for global phone services.</p>
<p>Orbital Sciences Corp want to launch 28 small satellites for pages and monitoring uses.</p>
<p>Teledesic, backed by Bill Gates and Craig McCaw, planned to launch 840 satellites for Internet services.</p>
<p>Alcatel Espace, the maker of WorldSpace's satellites, plans to put a 64-strong constellation of satellites in orbit under the name of Skybridge.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to be busy up there,&quot; MacLaren said, adding that WorldSpace does not rule out launching more satellites later.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
