<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="534000" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Lively German Bunds keen to tackle 101.00 barrier.</title>
<headline>Lively German Bunds keen to tackle 101.00 barrier.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>German June Bund futures were in the mood for another stab at 101.00 resistance on Wednesday but traders said the next hurdle at 101.13 was likely to remain only a hope for now.</p>
<p>After gapping higher at the open, the contract will be well supported on the downside with a hole stretching from 100.79 down to 100.68 on daily price charts.</p>
<p>By 0723 GMT, the June DTB contract was 16 basis points higher at 100.82, just off its earlier high on 100.89. The cash 10-year Bund was at 101.13 for a yield of 5.834 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market is looking pretty healthy this morning, said one futures trader based in London. &quot;We should take a look at the 101.00 area, but the next resistance at 101.13 still looks a bit too far for now.&quot;</p>
<p>Resistance at 101.13 is given by a 50 percent Fibonacci retracement of the decline from 103.20 to 99.06.</p>
<p>In the cash market, traders said that after initial discomfort, the first tranche of the new 10-year Federal bond due August 2007 went down well on Tuesday -- boding well for the second tranche, expected to be around 10 billion marks, which is due to be sold at auction this session.  </p>
<p>Traders said that the Federal Bond Consortium of banks through which the first 5.0 billion mark tranche was issued on Tuesday had got the new paper priced at around 100.575.</p>
<p>Initial quotes early on Wednesday had the 10-year trading at 100.83 for a yield of 5.882, suggesting the paper had been well absorbed and demand remained good.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, analysts said the market was awaiting European Commission forecasts for 1997/8 economic and budgetary performance, due at 0900 GMT. Forecasts for Germany were expected to show it able to reach the 3.0 percent deficit/GDP ratio laid down by Maastricht for the single currency.  </p>
<p>On spreads, the 10-year yield gap between Bunds and T-notes had slimmed to 112 basis points by 0748 GMT from 113 at Tuesday's close. But the German market continued to outperform its Italian counterpart, pushing the 10-year spread out to 180 basis points from 178 late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Kate Kelland, Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 7565 1246</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
