<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="534017" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Finland - April 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Finland - April 23.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the leading stories in Finnish papers this morning.</p>
<p>HELSINGIN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Delaying a decision in parliament on joining EMU until next year is harmful and the EMU transition timetable in general is too loose, says economist Jussi Mustonen at the Confederation of Finnish Industry and Emplyers.</p>
<p>- Annulling Suomi's Pohjola shares in a planned group restructuring is not possible and the shares which give 39</p>
<p>percent stake of votes should be sold, says Jouni Sarkijarvi,</p>
<p>supervisory board member in Suomi.</p>
<p>- MP Risto Kuisma left the Social Democratic Party to form a coalition with the Young Finns.</p>
<p>KAUPPALEHTI</p>
<p>- The new media group formed through the merger of Aamulehti and MTV is the biggest in the country, with higher net sales than rival Sanoma Oy and national broadcaster YLE.</p>
<p>- State support to house construction to be cut to the level of 1995 when it paid 2.5 billion markka less than in 1997. Finance ministry official says cuts due to revived independent financing and to reduce pressures of overheating.</p>
<p>TURUN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Prison guards to stage a one-day wildcat strike today in a protest against shorter working hours.</p>
<p>- Finland's ice hockey team beat Russia 7-1 yesterday in a friendly match ahead of the world championships.</p>
<p>AAMULEHTI</p>
<p>- Finland's ambassador and other EU-ambassadors to Iran will return to Bagdad next week.</p>
<p>- All schools will have data network connections by the year 2000, Minister of Education Olli-Pekka Heinonen says.</p>
<p>- Supreme Court judges say a legal initiative to block their participation in arbitration courts is hasty and based on ignorance.</p>
<p>- Finland should comply with EU directives and have only two lower VAT rates instead of three, says deputy managing director Tarmo Korpela at the Confederation of Finnish Industry and Employers.</p>
<p>- Finland is expected to be among countries listed by the European commission today as meeting criteria for EMU.</p>
<p>DEMARI</p>
<p>- The idea of national funds to work as buffers against economic fluctuations is bad, says Jorma Pellikka, managing director at the Employers' Confederation of Service Industries.</p>
<p>HUVUDSTADSBLADET</p>
<p>- A Supreme Court order to cut Cooperative EKA's deposits by two-thirds is too harsh: the Court lives in a world of its own, professor of public law Lars Eriksson says.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki Newsroom +358-9-680 50 242, news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
