<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53416" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Changing maps show frost-free week in U.S. Midwest.</title>
<headline>Changing maps show frost-free week in U.S. Midwest.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The latest weather maps suggest cool weather next week and through late September, but little or no chance of frost the next 10 days, said meteorologists.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's version (of the maps) does not infer a freeze on the (September) 23 or 24,&quot; said Fred Gesser, meteorologist with Weather Express Inc.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Gesser said maps then suggested a 60 to 70 percent chance of a freeze in much of the Midwest September 23 or 24.  </p>
<p>Gesser and other meteorologists continued to forecast normal to below normal temperatures for the U.S. Midwest next week, with the coldest weather early Friday and expected again early Saturday.</p>
<p>Temperatures dropped into the mid-30s degrees Fahrenheit early today, Friday in southern Minnesota and northern Iowa. Gesser said scattered frost occurred near Mason City, Iowa and Cambridge, Minn., but it was not severe enough to hurt crops.</p>
<p>Meteorologists said the cold will temporarily halt corn and soybean development thus slowing the maturation process.  </p>
<p>&quot;Essentially, it means everything shuts down for the time being, but we don't do any tissue damage so as soon as it warms up, everything will start back up again,&quot; said Dale Farnham, Iowa State University extension agronomist.</p>
<p>He said temperatures above 50 degrees F are needed before the plant begins functioning. A steady warming into the 60s F should allow the plants to make some progress.</p>
<p>High temperatures should range from the mid 60s to mid 70s F beginning tomorrow, Saturday in the western Midwest and spreading to the eastern Midwest Sunday, said Joel Burgio, meteorologist with Weather Services Corp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
