<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="534582" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AIG Q1 general insurance net premiums up.</title>
<headline>AIG Q1 general insurance net premiums up.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>American International Group Inc said first quarter worldwide general insurance net premiums written totalled $3.31 billion, up six percent from a year earlier after the impact of foreign exchange.</p>
<p>Excluding the foreign exchange impact, worldwide general insurance net premiums written rose 8.1 percent.</p>
<p>The combined ratio improved to 96.25 percent in the first quarter from 96.79 percent a year ago, AIG said.</p>
<p>Domestic net premiums written, excluding the risk management business, rose 12.3 percent, AIG said.  </p>
<p>&quot;This was a very good quarter for AIG, as we reported solid growth in all of our major business areas -- general insurance, life insurance and financial services,&quot; AIG Chairman Maurice Greenberg said.</p>
<p>However, he said, &quot;The U.S. market for commodity lines continues to be under price pressures and there still exists too much capacity in terms of capital in the property-casualty field.</p>
<p>&quot;Hence risk selection remains a key AIG priority.&quot;  </p>
<p>Greenberg said AIG announced this quarter a realignment of its domestic brokerage group. The realignment will allow the group to focus more sharply on the needs of its major customer groups, &quot;including middle market commercial accounts, an area in which we foresee substantial growth opportunities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The growing domestic personal lines business had a quarter of solid gains and increased profitability, he said.</p>
<p>International property-casualty had an excellent quarter, with strong underwriting results throughout the Foreign General Group.  </p>
<p>Excluding the impact of foreign exchange, net premiums written increased by 8.0 percent.</p>
<p>AIG said its United Guaranty Corp mortgage guaranty insurance subsidiary had a strong quarter, with very good growth in net premiums written and operating income.</p>
<p>General insurance pretax income before realized capital gains for the first quarter was $569.9 million, an increase of 14.3 percent compared to $498.5 million last year.</p>
<p>General insurance net investment income rose 10.1 percent to $451.1 million from $409.5 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
