<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="534633" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA BASKETBALL-MUTOMBO NAMED DEFENSIVE PLAYER OF THE YEAR.</title>
<headline>NBA BASKETBALL-MUTOMBO NAMED DEFENSIVE PLAYER OF THE YEAR.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Atlanta Hawks centre Dikembe Mutombo, who anchored a team that allowed just 89.4 points per game, was named the NBA's Defensive Player of the Year on Thursday for the second time in three years.</p>
<p>Mutombo, a native of Zaire, received 60 of a possible 115 votes from a media panel throughout the United States and Canada. Gary Payton of the Seattle SuperSonics, who won the award last season, finished second with 25 votes.</p>
<p>The 7-foot-2 (2.18 m) Mutombo helped the Hawks to a 56-26 record and led an Atlanta defence that was fourth in points allowed and third in opponents' shooting percentage (.435).</p>
<p>Mutombo, who also won the award in 1994-95 as a member of the Denver Nuggets, ranked second in the NBA in blocked shots (3.30). He blocked nine shots against Charlotte on December 21 and eight against Boston on December 3.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm appreciative of the fact that I've been honoured for this award,&quot; said Mutombo, who averaged 13.3 points and 11.6 rebounds.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to thank those who voted for me, as well as my teammate Mookie Blaylock, who is also deserving of consideration.&quot;</p>
<p>Blaylock finished third in the balloting with 18 votes.</p>
<p>Ten players received at least one vote for the award, including Scottie Pippen (four) and Michael Jordan (three) of Chicago, Joe Dumars of Detroit, Mario Elie of Houston, Rick Fox of Boston, Horace Grant of Orlando and Seattle's Shawn Kemp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
