<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53465" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: NATO's Solana says Bosnia vote will help stability.</title>
<headline>NATO's Solana says Bosnia vote will help stability.</headline>
<byline>Vera Haller</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>NATO Secretary-General Javier Solana on Friday acknowledged the shortcomings of Bosnia's flawed elections but said the sooner voters had their say the sooner there would be stability.</p>
<p>In a speech to the NATO Defence College in Rome, Solana said Saturday's elections, the first national poll since the end of the Bosnian war, were taking place &quot;under the most difficult of circumstances&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Municipal elections have been postponed to a later date, and of the 2.9 million eligible voters, 1.7 million are either displaced within Bosnia or refugees scattered over 55 countries,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Solana insisted the elections nevertheless had to go forward.</p>
<p>&quot;It is essential that the people of Bosnia and Herzegovina have their say, for after all they hold the key to reconciliation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The sooner responsibility reverts to the people of the country itself, the sooner the institutions of governance can be consolidated.&quot;</p>
<p>The elections are mandated by last year's U.S.-brokered Dayton peace accord, which envisages the creation of a Serb republic and a Moslem-Croat federation within a single Bosnia. Voters will choose a collective presidency, parliament and regional assemblies.</p>
<p>The process has been widely criticised both in Bosnia and abroad for failing to meet Dayton's own terms for freedom of movement, association and expression.</p>
<p>But Solana said there could be no delay in holding the elections. &quot;It is imperative to start the next stage in the democratic development of this young republic...,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Solana told a news conference later on Friday, after meeting Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi, that he would monitor the elections with General George Joulwan, NATO's Supreme Allied Commander Europe, at alliance headquarters in Brussels.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope it will be a happy day,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In his speech on Friday morning, the NATO chief praised the NATO-led peacekeeping force in Bosnia (IFOR), which is charged with implementing the peace accord, for &quot;impressive achievements&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Last December, few believed IFOR could impose its authority in enforcing the implementation of the Dayton accords. Many feared an inevitable slide back to the terror and vicious fighting,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nine months later, the situation has been transformed, due largely to the skill and dedication of the troops on the ground.&quot;</p>
<p>Solana, however, said &quot;peace is fragile&quot; and urged the international community to continue to exert pressure on Bosnian, Croat and Serb leaders to meet their obligations under the Dayton accord.</p>
<p>&quot;In the longer run, it is to be hoped that the carrot will become more important than the stick. That is why we also need to offer rewards, in the form of economic aid and the wider political acceptance by international institutions.&quot;</p>
<p>Solana raised the question of what would happen when IFOR's mandate in Bosnia ran out at the end of the year, saying allied defence ministers would discuss the matter at an informal meeting in Bergen, Norway, on September 25 and 26.</p>
<p>&quot;Although this will not be a decision-making meeting, they will be considering the tasks that remain to be completed from now until December, in particular in supporting the municipal elections,&quot; he said. &quot;These discussions will prepare the ground for later decisions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
