<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="534729" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLISH PM WANTS TO HEAD WIDER COALITION AFTER POLL.</title>
<headline>POLISH PM WANTS TO HEAD WIDER COALITION AFTER POLL.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Barker</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz wants to head a broader government coalition, embracing groups now in opposition, to continue Poland's reforms after elections this year, he said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Asked whether he hoped to resume as premier after the parliamentary polls, Cimoszewicz told Reuters: &quot;This depends to what extent my person could unite various coalition groups, but if there was such a proposition I would be inclined to accept.&quot;</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz, 46, took on his job early last year after his predecessor Jozef Oleksy, a fellow member of the dominant ex-communists in the ruling coalition, quit amid allegations -- later dismissed by prosecutors -- of informing for Moscow.</p>
<p>The forceful, grey-haired lawyer and farmer had the advantage of not having held senior office in the undemocratic old system, toppled in 1989, and is outside the ex-communist core party of his Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) grouping.</p>
<p>This has made him a player in tentative approaches towards links between the ex-communists and parties including the large opposition centrist Union for Freedom (UW) with similar foreign and economic policies but roots in the pre-1989 opposition.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz said that even if the SLD -- which has been in uneasy coalition with the Polish Peasant Party (PSL) for four years -- won enough votes to do without a wider circle of allies, he would still want to involve more parties to secure greater stability and effectiveness in politics.</p>
<p>&quot;Wider understandings are better than narrower ones. If only for this reason, irrespective of arithmetic, I would personally prefer a wider coalition,&quot; he said in an interview.</p>
<p>UW leaders have kept their distance but Cimoszewicz said its leaders had hinted this might change after the polls.</p>
<p>&quot;For me, the basic goal is to guarantee that we will reform the economy as we are doing now, with similar results, that we will not ignore the social costs, and will guarantee Poland's entry to Western economic and social structures,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Singling out the most radical, nationalistic, trends within two strong new opposition groups on the right, Solidarity Election Action (AWS) and the Movement for the Reconstruction of Poland (ROP) Cimoszewicz said the elections were crucial.</p>
<p>&quot;Without exaggeration, Poland's fate could hinge on the result of these elections. Poland could be even more pro-European...or it could become a country that is more xenophobic, closed in on itself,&quot; Cimoszewicz said.</p>
<p>He said the right was using slogans such as &quot;Buy Polish&quot;, or stirring up opposition to land sales to foreigners, which could lead to protectionism, undermine economic progress and make entry talks with the European Union much harder.</p>
<p>Some of the AWS, grouped around the Solidarity union and narrowly trailing the SLD at the head of recent opinion polls, has a pro-Catholic, patriotic stance, a more cautious view of the European Union and different ideas on privatisation.</p>
<p>But its leaders deny it is less reformist than the SLD -- whose chiefs are recent converts to market principles.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz said he would campaign on the coalition's record and had basically met all the economic promises in his inaugural speech -- culminating in a crucial pension reform much of which is now being hurried through parliament.</p>
<p>He said Poland would privatise the giant KGHM copper combine and its biggest bank, Bank Handlowy SA, this year.</p>
<p>He predicted that inflation would reach the budget target of 13 percent year-on-year or go even lower by December, compared with 18.5 percent in December 1996.</p>
<p>He said the government had failed to enact a promised local government reform, because the SLD and PSL disagreed on it.</p>
<p>But overall, he said the message his party plans to drive home in the elections was: &quot;You don't change a winning team.&quot; -- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
