<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="534870" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK natural gas rises in winter in heavy trade volume.</title>
<headline>UK natural gas rises in winter in heavy trade volume.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The UK spot natural gas market saw a huge increase in volumes traded on Thursday, with deals seen across virtually all periods from within the day to summer 1998 and prices rising next winter.</p>
<p>The flexibility mechanism bought at between 11.45 pence and 11.66 pence a therm, dealers said, and this lent good support to prompt prices. Around 2.5 million therms were reported to have traded on the mechanism.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a general upward trend, and the flexibility mechanism is keeping upward pressure on the market,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Winter prices were strongest. First quarter 98 traded as high as 16.10 pence a therm, well above Wednesday's closing range. And February traded as high as 17.30 pence, a level that was also reached on the IPE futures market. Summer 1998 was also stronger, with trade seen at least twice at 11.05 pence a therm.</p>
<p>Deals were seen in each quarter from Q3 97 to Q3 98, with individual months also traded in May, October, November, January and February.</p>
<p>Apart from the winter, the most heavily traded period was the short term, from within the day to the end of April, with a lot of business also seen in early May.</p>
<p>Prices were volatile in the prompt market, influenced by the flexibility mechanism system buy. Trades were seen at both 10.70 pence at St Fergus and 11.50 pence at the NBP, a greater price differential than is represented by capacity charges between the two locations.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been totally fixated by the front end,&quot; said one trader, adding that bid/offer spreads had moved several times over the day. There was some surprise that 11.50 pence was obtained on the within day market, and one dealer pointed out that the buyer must have had an urgent requirement to pay so much given that it was so close to the flexibility mechanism system marginal price of 11.66 pence a therm.</p>
<p>IPE futures saw only 190 lots done, but the trend was the same, with trade centred on the fourth and first quarters at higher prices.</p>
<p>--Sebastian Alison, London Newsroom, +44 171 542 6412</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
