<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="534998" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa rand/bonds opening report.</title>
<headline>S.Africa rand/bonds opening report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bonds edged firmer in thin, jobber-driven early Thursday trade and the market was expected to strengthen further as the day progressed, dealers said.</p>
<p>At 0700 GMT, the key R150 was pegged at 14.775 percent from 14.80 percent late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is looking strong, but the volumes are not huge at the moment. It should pick up later when the institutions and foreign interest comes in,&quot; a senior trader said.</p>
<p>He said local institutions in particular were expected to be buyers later in the day, having been &quot;caught on the wrong foot&quot; recently.</p>
<p>&quot;The institutions were waiting for a kick up (in yields) to pick up some stock at the higher levels. I think they will be looking to pick up some stock at these levels,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Options books were also increasingly coming into play ahead of close-out next Friday, dealers said.</p>
<p>Apart from that, traders said that there was currently little in the market in the way of direction.</p>
<p>The market had absorbed the slightly better-than-expected March CPI data released early on Wednesday, but with March trade data now possibly due out on Friday, dealers said there was little new news in the market to feed on.</p>
<p>The main focus on Friday would be the Reserve Bank's March money supply and credit extension data, which will be released at 1500 GMT, although traders said the market would only react to the data next Tuesday.</p>
<p>South Africa's financial markets are closed on Monday for the Freedom Day holiday.</p>
<p>Money supply growth is expected to show a 15.04 pecent year-on-year rise from February's preliminary 15.82 percent increase and private sector credit extension growth is seen rising 16.50 percent from March last year from a previous 17.34 percent.</p>
<p>On the day, traders said the R150 was expected to trade in a 14.80 to 14.70 percent range.</p>
<p>Bond Exchange figures showed foreigners were net buyers of 464.53 million rand's worth of South African bonds on Wednesday after buying 577.02 million rand's worth on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Nominal cumulative volumes were pegged at 8.05 billion rand from 8.8 billion previously.  </p>
<p>On the currency market, the rand edged weaker in very quiet trade amid short-covering and on the back of a slightly stronger dollar.</p>
<p>At 0707 GMT, the rand was pegged at 4.4500/4530 against the dollar from 4.4445/4475 overnight.</p>
<p>Dealers said that players had gone short dollars overnight with the aim of buying them back this morning in order to pick up the carry cost.</p>
<p>&quot;With the holiday next Monday we've got a five-day run,&quot; a dealers said. &quot;People went short overnight and are now buying back their dollars,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Another trader noted that the dollar's strength overnight had also contributed to the rand's early weakness.</p>
<p>In early European trade, the U.S. unit was trading at 1.7188/93 against the Deutschmark from 1.7125/35 late on Wednesday and at 126.37/42 from 126.15/18 previously.</p>
<p>Against the crosses, the rand was last trading at 28.3623/3927 yen from 28.3485/3901 yen on Wednesday, at 0.3859/3863 marks compared with 0.3854/3858 marks overnight and at 7.2292/2363 against sterling from 7.2188/2281 previously.</p>
<p>Local traders said that on the day, the rand was expected to trade in a 4.4450 to 4.4600 range against the dollar.</p>
<p>Money market rates were quoted unchanged as the shortage held around the 7.3 billion rand level.</p>
<p>Major banks kept their three month deposit rates steady at between 16.40 to 16.45 percent offered, while the 90-day BA rate edged lower to between 15.80 to 15.95 percent from between 15.80 to 16.00 percent.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank said the money market shortage rose to 7.372 billion rand on Wednesday from 7.344 billion rand on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Paul Richardson, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
