<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="534982" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Alcan sees '97 aluminum demand up by 3 pct.</title>
<headline>Alcan sees '97 aluminum demand up by 3 pct.</headline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alcan Aluminium Ltd president and chief executive officer Jacques Bougie said on Thursday that he expects global aluminum demand to increase by three percent in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;We anticipate that demand will increase by about three percent for 1997, even if year-to-date demand has increased about 10 percent,&quot; Bougie told reporters after the company's annual meeting.</p>
<p>Bougie said demand jumped in the first quarter over the year earlier quarter mainly because customers are restocking aluminum in the face of higher aluminum prices.</p>
<p>Bougie said his growth estimate is conservative, but he declined to make a specific forecast on aluminum prices or net profits for 1997. Every US$100-a-tonne fluctuation in the price of aluminum translates into a US$100 million impact on Alcan's net profits, he said.</p>
<p>In its first quarter ended March 31, Alcan earned a net profit of US$143 million or US$0.62 a share, up from a profit of US$125 million or US$0.53 a share in the year earlier quarter.</p>
<p>In his speech to the annual meeting, Bougie said Alcan is not yet at the decision stage on a number of proposed projects. Those include a new 370,000-tonne smelter in Alma, Quebec, a new bauxite mine in Australia, a possible joint venture 240,000-tonne smelting and power project in China, and participation in the partial privatizaition of the aluminum industry in Venezuela.</p>
<p>But Bougie said Alcan has the financial capability to proceed with all the projects at once, if needed, in addition to the US$350 million expansion of the company's Pindamonhangaba aluminum sheet rolling facility in Brazil announced two days ago.</p>
<p>&quot;We could do Alma, Venezuela, Ely bauxite in Australia and Pinda' without a problem. All of them,&quot; Bougie said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a very strong balance sheet. We also have a US$1 billion credit line that was lined up last year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;On top of that, if an attractive acquisition came our way, we would not hesitate. The financial means of Alcan would not be what would stop us, actually,&quot; Bougie said.</p>
<p>Turning to Alcan's lawsuit against the British Columbia government seeking compensation for the government's cancellation of its Kemano Completion Project in 1995, Bougie said he sent a letter to B.C. Premier Glen Clark saying the company would be amenable to an out-of-court settlement. Bougie said he had not heard back from the premier.</p>
<p>Alcan is seeking compensation for the project, which would have added to its hydro-electric generating capacity in the province. Alcan took a US$420 million writedown on the project in 1995.</p>
<p>((Reuters Montreal bureau 514-985-2434))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
