<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="535187" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: MOL bucks bearish Hungarian market.</title>
<headline>MOL bucks bearish Hungarian market.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian share prices drifted lower in calm trading on Thursday pulling the BUX index almost one percent down, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no fresh news today, so everybody watched developments on the U.S. market (on Wednesday),&quot; said Andrea Keresztesi of ABN AMRO Hoare Govett.</p>
<p>The BUX index finished at a preliminary 5,789.04 points, down 51.61 points or 0.88 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said expectations were moving the markets these days, in reference to upcoming share offers and to January-March corporate earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;These expectations move the market, we'll know the underlying trend when the first quarter figures are released and when share offers are completed,&quot; said Gabor Sitanyi, analyst at ING Barings in London.</p>
<p>A roadshow and subscriptions are underway in tile maker Zalakeramia shares. Later in May Hungary will offer stakes in pharmaceuticals Richter. The biggest bite, however, is the upcoming offer in oil company MOL shares.</p>
<p>On Thursday, tile maker Zalakeramia finished unchanged at 8,150 forints with its turnover bolstered by a major deal for 25,000 stocks at 8,150 forint/share.</p>
<p>Pharmaceuticals Egis attracted the spotlight by a surprising fall.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody expected steady to weaker prices, that's what happened, but Egis grabbed attention by quite a substantial fall amid quite big turnover,&quot; Keresztesi said.</p>
<p>Egis lost 250 forints to end at 11,600 forints. &quot;Egis was a little bit overheated, it has risen a lot recently and this rise had attracted sellers,&quot; Keresztesi said.</p>
<p>Oil company MOL remained in focus being the session's most actively traded paper. It bucked the trend and put on 20 forints to end at 3,215.</p>
<p>&quot;It's price around 3,200 forints seems to be stable,&quot; she said, adding &quot;but at least it had not only Hungarian buyers.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said in the past few days that MOL shares were bought mainly by domestic investors who feared they would not be able to buy MOL shares in its upcoming offer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
