<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="535150" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Doubts remain over Russia-China partnership.</title>
<headline>Doubts remain over Russia-China partnership.</headline>
<byline>Oleg Shchedrov</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The presidents of Russia and China are hailing a new era of partnership to shape the post-Cold War world, but their latest rapprochement leaves many questions unanswered.</p>
<p>Russia's Boris Yeltsin and China's Jiang Zemin embraced on Wednesday after signing a declaration outlining their global vision and trumpeted a treaty on Thursday with three Central Asian states as an example of how to seek regional stability.</p>
<p>But the new friednship appears to be driven as much by jealousy of the United States' leading world role and by Moscow's fears of NATO expansion as by mutual love.</p>
<p>&quot;No country should seek hegemony, practise power politics or monopolise international affairs,&quot; said Wednesday's joint declaration, signed in the Kremlin.</p>
<p>The document made no mention of any specific country but there was little doubt the finger was pointed at Washington.</p>
<p>After signing the treaty on troop reductions along the former Sino-Soviet border, Yeltsin took a thinly-veiled dig at NATO's plans, led by Washington, to expand into the former Soviet bloc.</p>
<p>&quot;This agreement is a good example of how to solve tricky and delicate national security issues through building up mutual confidence rather than by building up troops and expanding military blocs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Russian and Chinese officials have repeatedly denied there is a link between the Sino-Russian rapprochement and their countries' problems in relations with the West.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's spokesman, Sergei Yastrzhembsky, made clear that boosting ties with China was a far-reaching strategy to help Russia, which fears it may have missed the boat to European integration and the chance of access to markets closer to home.</p>
<p>&quot;One may talk about a breakthrough in Russian policy in Asia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But the festive mood has been soured somewhat by the scepticism of Russian political experts and media who question the friendship's life expectancy and the price for Russia.</p>
<p>The liberal newspaper Sevodnya noted that the new spring in relations was not the first for the two countries, who formed a strong alliance in the 1950s before their rivalry for supremacy of the communist world intensified in the next two decades.</p>
<p>&quot;The 'great disagreement' that followed the 'great friendship' seems to have taught Moscow that it is better to be friends with Beijing than foes,&quot; Sevodnya wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;But there is one little question to answer,&quot; it added. &quot;What exactly will an average Russian gain from the 'strategic partnership' with China?&quot;</p>
<p>Sevodnya said two painful issues, border demarcation and arms sales, could cause big problems.</p>
<p>Agreements to map out the border line, signed by Russia and China in 1991 and 1994, have prompted fierce protests by regional leaders in Russia's Far East who say the deals were unfair and want them reviewed.</p>
<p>Yeltsin has swept aside the objections and promised Jiang that demarcation will be completed by May.</p>
<p>Sevodnya was also critical of Russia's arms sales to China, which include modern aircrafts and warships and have an estimated value of $1 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Why do we need to arm our neighbour, which has a population which is at least eight times bigger than ours?,&quot; it asked.</p>
<p>Dmitry Trenin, a political and military analyst at the Moscow office of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, asked in the Moscow Times newspaper whether the new friendship could turn out to be a mismatch.</p>
<p>&quot;The relations between Russia and China are characterised by Russia's decline and China's ascendance,&quot; he wrote.</p>
<p>The Nezavisimaya Gazeta newspaper wrote: &quot;So far it is difficult to say whether we need to plunge recklessly into a new alliance with the East just because we are not getting a proper hearing in the West.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
