<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="535147" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAJIKISTAN: Tajiks haunted by poverty, security concerns-poll.</title>
<headline>Tajiks haunted by poverty, security concerns-poll.</headline>
<dateline>DUSHANBE 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poverty and personal security are the top concerns for most citizens of Tajikistan, which is still reeling from a four-year civil war, an opinion poll showed on Thursday.</p>
<p>The poll, involving 1,500 Tajik citizens of different nationalities across the mountainous country bordering China and Afghanistan, showed that 48 percent of them were still expecting the resumption of fighting..</p>
<p>Conducted in the former Soviet republic by the International Foundation for Electoral Systems (IFES) and sponsored by Washington's foreign aid agency USAID, the results of the survey were made public at a news conference.</p>
<p>Last December Tajikistan's secular government and the united Islamist opposition agreed on a ceasefire to end the four-year civil war which left tens of thousands killed and many more displaced.</p>
<p>The truce seems to be holding but the peace is often disturbed by gangs with unknown loyalties and the population is still suffering from the war.</p>
<p>The poll showed that 54 percent of Tajik citizens had been &quot;personally affected&quot; by the fighting.</p>
<p>Nine percent of those polled said their relatives had been killed or wounded, while 18 percent said they had become refugees or moved to other regions of the Central Asian state, fleeing from hostilities in their home areas.</p>
<p>Tajikistan's instability is further aggravated by a severe economic crisis which has cast most people into abject poverty.</p>
<p>The pollsters said that 62 percent of Tajik families had problems providing themselves with enough food. Eighty five percent said life had become harder after Tajikistan became independent in the collapse of the Soviet Union in late 1991.</p>
<p>Market reforms -- well on track in most other former Soviet republics -- had been delayed in Tajikistan, and 65 percent of those polled said they were still working in the state sector.</p>
<p>Sixty percent of the population still prefered &quot;an economy basically controlled by the state&quot;, the pollsters said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TADZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUSHANBE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAJIKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
