<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="535291" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRENCH GUIANA: Violence erupts again in French Guiana.</title>
<headline>Violence erupts again in French Guiana.</headline>
<byline>Alexander Miles</byline>
<dateline>CAYENNE, French Guiana 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Demonstrators clashed with police on Wednesday for the second night in a row to protest the detention of three members of the territory's independence movement, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Paramilitary riot police -- flown in from France to the French Guiana capital of Cayenne -- fired teargas grenades at armed demonstrators who responded with Molotov cocktails.</p>
<p>The riots continued a day after police arrested Jean-Victor Castor and Fabien Canavy, both members of the Guiana Workers Union (UTG).</p>
<p>Jean-Claude Ringuet, a member of the Guiana National Popular Party (PNPG), gave himself up to police after taking refuge for several hours in Cayenne's town hall on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Both the PNPG and UTG favor Guiana's independence from France.</p>
<p>Police cordoned off the city's main boulevard in front of its central police station where the three are being held.</p>
<p>Lawyers for the three said police were planning to transfer them to the French Caribbean island of Martinique. Supporters of the three have vowed to prevent the transfer.</p>
<p>French officials pledged last week to crack down on violence in its South American overseas territory after a new wave of violence last week left two police wounded and several shops ransacked.</p>
<p>They said more than 150 police reinforcements have been flown in from France since the weekend.</p>
<p>The latest violence was triggered by a series of detentions, including that of Alain Michel, a founding member of the PNPG. Michel was detained on April 11 and taken the next day with four others to Martinique aboard a military aircraft.</p>
<p>He was charged with arson and violence against a magistrate when the residence of French Guiana's state prosecutor was attacked last November. In that wave of riots, one person was killed and millions of dollars worth of property was damaged.</p>
<p>Michel faces up to 20 years in prison if convicted, his lawyer said.</p>
<p>French Guiana, on the northeast coast of South America, is the only non-independent territory in the Western Hemisphere mainland. Its economy is heavily dependent on subsidies from France and 23 percent of the population of 150,000 is unemployed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FGNA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAYENNE, French Guiana"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRENCH GUIANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
