<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="535280" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru honors dead as Japan hails &quot;near-perfect&quot; raid.</title>
<headline>Peru honors dead as Japan hails &quot;near-perfect&quot; raid.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peru paid tribute on Thursday to the slain heroes of its hostage crisis and Japan thanked the South American country for the military strike that rescued 71 captive VIPs from its embassy residence.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to offer deep gratitude for the successful resolution of the crisis under your leadership,&quot; Japanese Foreign Minister Yukihiko Ikeda told Peruvian President Alberto Fujimori, according to a Japanese government spokesman.</p>
<p>&quot;The crisis could never have been resolved unless you had the meticulous operation that was near-perfect and miraculous,&quot; Ikeda told Fujimori after the funerals and ceremonies to honour the one hostage and two commandos who died in Tuesday's battle. All 14 Marxist guerrillas were killed in the assault.</p>
<p>When the armed rebels occupied the ambassador's residence in December, Ikeda had travelled to Peru to restrain Fujimori from launching a military assault on the diplomatic compound.</p>
<p>But the Peruvian leader explained on Thursday: &quot;I had no option but to carry out the operation because negotiations were deadlocked. And I regret the deaths of some people.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;I didn't tell the Japanese government about the operation in advance because it was important to launch a timely and quick attack on the terrorists and I want you to understand this.&quot;</p>
<p>Peru's euphoria at the explosive finale to the agonizing four-month hostage siege gave way to grief on Thursday.</p>
<p>Fujimori joined hundreds of soldiers on a hillside cemetery for the burial of army Lt. Raul Jimenez and Lt. Col. Juan Valer in side-by-side graves. The men's families and friends wept as military colleagues read tributes and Fujimori's son Kenji, for whom Valer was a bodyguard, kissed his grave.</p>
<p>&quot;He is a hero to the fatherland, a pride for his wife, an example for youth,&quot; Fujimori said as his 16-year-old son cried at his side.</p>
<p>Seven bullets killed Valer as he was leading Peruvian Foreign Minister Francisco Tudela, the rebels' prize captive, to safety across the roof of the Japanese ambassador's house.</p>
<p>In downtown Lima, the coffin holding Supreme Court judge Carlos Giusti was carried to Peru's Palace of Justice where families, friends and colleagues filed past and left flowers.</p>
<p>Giusti bled to death after being hit by a bullet in the leg -- possibly fired by the military -- in Tuesday's spectacular storming of the residence where the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) guerrillas had held 72 hostages for 126 days.</p>
<p>The bodies of the 14 rebels, including MRTA leader Nestor Cerpa -- all felled by bombs and gunfire in a 40-minute battle -- were taken to a Lima morgue to be collected by their families. But mothers of the guerrillas complained that the morgue was dragging its feet in handing the bodies over.</p>
<p>In Congress, legislators rose to their feet, sang the national anthem and shouted &quot;Long Live Peru!&quot; as five colleagues among the released hostages returned to their seats. &quot;I want to welcome them and salute the integrity shown in four months of captivity,&quot; Congress President Victor Joy Way said.</p>
<p>Ikeda met some of the two dozen Japanese diplomats and businessmen released on Tuesday, and was also due to talk with Japanese Ambassador Morihisa Aoki, host of the ill-fated Dec. 17 cocktail party stormed by the MRTA.</p>
<p>Fujimori decided to launch an assault on Tuesday when the rebels were playing indoor soccer. With the hostages warned via an electronic device, commandos swarmed into the building from all sides and through five tunnels.</p>
<p>MRTA leader Nestor Cerpa shouted: &quot;We've screwed up! We've screwed up!&quot; before he was killed on the mansion's staircase, the daily La Republica reported on Thursday. The paper said the two teenage girls among the guerrilla band shouted at troops to hold fire saying &quot;We Surrender! We Surrender!&quot;</p>
<p>But the order was shoot to kill. And, according to former hostages quoted in some news reports, Peruvian commandos executed one rebel and killed others who gave themselves up.</p>
<p>The successful operation reversed Fujimori's popularity rating overnight, according to the polling agency Apoyo SA. A survey conducted the day after the raid showed his approval level shot up to 67 percent from 38 percent four days ago, the lowest level during his seven years in office.</p>
<p>The raid also gave Peru's military one of the biggest victories ever in its 17-year war with leftist rebels, in which about 30,000 people have died.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
