<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="535568" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Indonesia seen allocating 3.6 mln bbls LSWR in May.</title>
<headline>Indonesia seen allocating 3.6 mln bbls LSWR in May.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's state oil company Pertamina is expected to allocate about 3.6 million barrels of low sulphur waxy residue (LSWR) for lifting in May, industry sources said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Pertamina is also likely to roll over around 500,000 barrels from April, bringing the total May allocation to 4.1 million barrels, they said.</p>
<p>Traders said in April, Pertamina exported a total of 5.1 million barrels. It initially allocated 3.6 million barrels but added another 500,000 barrels after it rolled over part of its March supplies into April.  </p>
<p>Pertamina later allocated a further 1.5 million barrels in April after a fire disrupted one of two 27,500-barrel-per-day hydrocrackers at its Dumai refinery, bringing the total to 5.1 million barrels.</p>
<p>Traders said discussion was thin in the spot market as most traders awaited a clearer price direction after details of the loading schedule for May are released.</p>
<p>They said the arbitrage window to the West is currently open, draining some of the excess supplies in the East Asian markets.  </p>
<p>A Western trader was reported to be seeking a vessel to move about one million barrels of LSWR for late April lifting from Indonesia to the U.S.</p>
<p>They said the current market is soft but might recover when demand from Japan and South Korea increase during summer.</p>
<p>LSWR prices in the Singapore spot market are bid/offered at $15.25/$15.75.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (+65-870 3082)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
