<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53551" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German Bunds soar defying Friday the 13th jitters.</title>
<headline>German Bunds soar defying Friday the 13th jitters.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Bunds bounded higher in active trading at the end of the week powered forward by vanishing fears of an imminent U.S. interest rate hike and proving Friday the 13th was not a bad-luck-day for the markets.</p>
<p>After drifting sideways, albeit at higher levels, over the last several sessions, German Bund futures came to life late on Friday surging nearly 50 basis points after the U.S. released tamer inflation statistics than the markets had expected.</p>
<p>&quot;The sky is the limit,&quot; jubilated one Frankfurt-based futures dealer as the December contract traded Frankfurt's DTB exchange was up 68 basis points at 97.91 by 1502 GMT.  </p>
<p>Dealers said news the U.S. August CPI index was up 0.1 percent while independent economists had forecast at 0.2 percent increase allowed fears to fade that the U.S. Fed would need to raise short-term interest rates very soon.</p>
<p>&quot;Talk that the Fed would need to raise the funds rate by 25 basis points in late September has more or less transmuted into the Fed doesn't need to raise short-term interest rates that soon after all,&quot; another dealer said.</p>
<p>Similarly dealers also said rumblings that the Bundesbank may not be at the end of its easing cycle also fuelled the sharp increase today.  </p>
<p>This week several Bundesbank council members hinted that there may be more room to ease Germany's main money market rate, the repo, or even the discount rate if economic data permit. Similarly the Bundesbank also indicated that the economic recovery was still not pushing ahead with full steam, possibly making another easing even more likely, dealers said.</p>
<p>Additionally news that Chancellor Helmut Kohl's ambitious austerity package sailed through parliament also brightened the market's mood.</p>
<p>Now Bunds are ready to test the 98 level dealers predicted, noting that many investors may still want to join the rally.  </p>
<p>&quot;Despite high volumes, many seem to have missed this rally and are still eager to get on board, so we could move still higher early next week,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>A general lack of selling pressure only confirms the bullish outlook for next week, traders said.</p>
<p>But at some point, dealers said profit-taking will have to set in and then the market could be in for quite a downward jolt, several said.</p>
<p>--Svea Herbst-Bayliss, Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
