<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="535686" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Blue-chips fall after rally fades.</title>
<headline>Blue-chips fall after rally fades.</headline>
<byline>Richard Jacobsen</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue-chip stocks ended lower Thursday, surrendering strong early gains sparked by IBM's robust earnings, as the market was unable to shake off a jump in long-term interest rates.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average fell 20.47 points to close at 6,792.25, having given back a jump of nearly 80 points in the first hour of trading.</p>
<p>In the broader market, declining issues led advances 1,244 to 1,149 on moderately active volume of 485 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Market heavyweight International Business Machines Corp. leaped 11-5/8 to 154 after posting first-quarter profits late on Wednesday that beat expectations on Wall Street.</p>
<p>But lackluster earnings elsewhere and general investor caution weighed on the market, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's not a lot of conviction out there,&quot; said Peter Coolidge, senior equity trader at Brean Murray &amp; Co.</p>
<p>It was the Dow's second consecutive losing session after it soared 173 points on Tuesday, its second biggest daily point rise ever. The blue-chip index fell 21 points on Wednesday.</p>
<p>After losing almost 700 points in a month-long decline since closing at a record high of 7,085.16 on March 11, the Dow has recouped more than 400 points.</p>
<p>But analysts said Thursday's action was a sign the rebound might be running out of steam.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a lot of investors who believe this rally is going to fizzle very quickly,&quot; said Guy Truicko, equity portfolio manager at Unity Management.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected further caution heading into next week when financial markets will be fixated on reports that could indicate the near-term direction of interest rates.</p>
<p>Economic data due next week includes the first quarter's Employment Cost Index and a report on the April jobs report.</p>
<p>Rising interest rates in the Treasury market played a role in dampening enthusiasm for stocks Thursday.</p>
<p>The 30-year Treasury fell 17/32, or $5.31 on a $1,000 bond, raising its yield to 7.13 percent from 7.08 percent at Wednesday's close. The price and yield move in opposite directions.</p>
<p>With investors' focus turning from corporate earnings to interest rates, choppy moves in stocks were likely in coming weeks, market watchers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the least likely thing would be for another major rally,&quot; said John McElroy, principal at 1838 Investment Advisors.</p>
<p>AlliedSignal Inc. fell 3-7/8 to 69-7/8 after it reported first quarter earnings. Analysts cited weakness in the company's chemicals and automotive units.</p>
<p>Procter &amp; Gamble Co. fell 2-1/2 to 123 after it reported quarterly earnings and said its sales were clipped by unfavourable currency translation.</p>
<p>Compaq Computer Corp. rose 2-5/8 to 80-1/8 after the company said its board authorised a buyback of up to 25 million shares of its common stock.</p>
<p>Dow Chemical Co. added 2-1/8 to 81-7/8 after the company reported flat first quarter earnings but said it expects a strong second quarter.</p>
<p>Computer Associates International Inc. jumped 4-3/8 to 48-1/2 after the software company said its fourth quarter earnings will likely be better than Wall Street expected.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq composite index rose 0.96 to 1,228.10.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks fell 2.46 points to 771.18. The American Stock Exchange index was up 0.59 to 543.95.</p>
<p>The NYSE composite index of all listed common stocks fell 1.09 to 403.62. The average share was down 11 cents.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 7,284.896, down 11.997 or 0.16 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
