<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="535614" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL interbank rates volatile in tight market.</title>
<headline>KL interbank rates volatile in tight market.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The one-week interbank rate rebounded as the market tightened further due to funds outflow on Wednesday, dealers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>They said the market had tightened after payment of 500 million ringgit for a Bank Negara bill issue on Wednesday.</p>
<p>One-week money rate rose to 8.10/20 percent from 7.40/50 on Wednesday. Two-week also rose to 8.10/20 percent against 7.50/60.  </p>
<p>But one-month to three-month money at 7.45/50 percent and six-month to one-year money at 7.50/55 were all unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;Yesterday, most people were under the impression that funds were coming in from overseas because of the ringgit's strength. Now that ringgit is weak again, they are borrowing at the high levels,&quot; said a dealer with a Malaysian bank.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, increased activity in the swaps market and a mild rally in the ringgit pulled down the one-week interbank rate to 7.40/50 percent from over 8.0 percent.</p>
<p>Lower swaps rates were also causing banks to borrow overseas and lend locally, the dealers said.</p>
<p>They said the rise of interbank rates over the last two weeks had created several arbitrage opportunities, which were being exploited.</p>
<p>The effective overnight rate in the swaps market worked out to 7.5/6 percent against 8.5/7 in the domestic market. One week money was around 7.4/6 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;These differences are more than sufficient to attract large funds from the overseas markets,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Most dealers said there was no reason for interest rates to come off despite the temporary fall caused by swap funds.</p>
<p>&quot;The market sentiment is still for firm rates because overall the situation is still very tight,&quot; said a dealer with a large Malaysian bank.</p>
<p>He said the maturity of a 500 million ringgit Bank Negara bill on Friday was also unlikely to have much impact.</p>
<p>A 420 million ringgit long-term government bond is also maturing next week.</p>
<p>Interest rate futures on the Malaysia Monetary Exchange eased slightly to reflect the change in spot rates, futures dealers said.</p>
<p>The three-month Kuala Lumpur Interbank Offered Rate (KLIBOR) June contract was down two points to 92.63, or an implied yield of 7.37 percent.</p>
<p>September was down one point to 92.62, or 7.38 percent, and December down two to 92.56, or 7.44 percent.</p>
<p>-- Madhav Reddy (603-230 7509)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
