<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="535935" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ill. planned motor speedway to seek new site.</title>
<headline>Ill. planned motor speedway to seek new site.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Plans to build a $70 million motor speedway at a suburban Chicago airport have stalled, but developers plan to seek another site in the area for the facility, an attorney for the group said Thursday.</p>
<p>The economics of developing a speedway at the DuPage County Airport in West Chicago made the site untenable for the Motorsports Alliance, Indianapolis attorney Phillip Bayt said.</p>
<p>The group had sought to buy up to 722 acres of airport land to develop the 70,000 seat speedway, but the high cost of the land and numerous other obstacles made it unworkable, Bayt said.</p>
<p>The group is &quot;eager&quot; to find a new, more rural, site for the speedway, which developers hope would host two or three major racing events each year, Bayt said.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't optioned anything,&quot; Bayt said. &quot;We are still looking at a variety of different sites.&quot;</p>
<p>The group was approached by numerous landowners during its attempts to develop the airport site and has &quot;a host of sites&quot; to evaluate, Bayt said. Each site may need infrastructure improvements that would be determined later, he noted.</p>
<p>The plans had also faced intense public opposition in West Chicago, where the airport is located.</p>
<p>The alliance includes the Indianapolis Motor Speedway Corp, International Speedway Corp, which owns the Daytona speedway, and John Menard, owner of Menards Inc.</p>
<p>The group had planned a 12- to 14-month construction schedule to hold the first race in 1999, Bayt said. If another site is found in the next three months a late 1999 race could be held, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Our two members that own and operate tracks now have very large patron bases in the Chicagoland area, so we believe with the combination of the media market and our customer bases there now that would be an ideal location for another facility,&quot; Bayt said.</p>
<p>((--David Bailey, 312-408-8647))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
