<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="536134" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EFTA members relaxed about EU big brother.</title>
<headline>EFTA members relaxed about EU big brother.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Chalmers</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fears that the European Free Trade Association's members might be buried by their powerful neighbours in the 15-country EU have proved groundless, EFTA Secretary-General Kjartan Johannsson said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not encountered real difficulties. Of course there was fear that we would be over-ruled by the EU, that we would go from one crisis to another but this has not been the case,&quot; Johannsson told reporters at the launch of EFTA's 1996 report.</p>
<p>He said last year had seen increased cooperation between the EU and the four EFTA countries within the frame of their three-year-old European Economic Area agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;I am convinced that this agreement has been to the mutual benefit of all EEA members. This is a two-way street, the contribution and the benefits are of the same kind,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But a row remains over Norwegian salmon and the threat of EU import duties on allegedly dumped stock.</p>
<p>&quot;Politically speaking, I find it very unacceptable to have a conflict of this kind within the EEA. Ultimately, an issue of this kind has to be settled on a political level,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Looking to the future, Johannsson saw no immediate changes to either the EFTA membership, which comprises Iceland, Liechtenstein, Norway and Switzerland, or to the EEA, which joins the EU's 15 states with the EFTA members bar Switzerland.</p>
<p>Under the EEA, the three non-EU members adopt the bloc's single market laws on free movement of goods, services, people and capital, and cooperate on policy in a range of other areas.</p>
<p>While their membership opens a market of 380 million people in 18 countries, it comes at the price of surrendering anything more than a consultative, non-voting role in drawing up or amending the EU's single market legislation.</p>
<p>Such a sacrifice proved too much for Swiss voters in 1992, when they rejected membership in a referendum.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EFTA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
