<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53623" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - France - Le Monde Sept 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - France - Le Monde Sept 13.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in afternoon daily Le Monde.</p>
<p>FRONT PAGE</p>
<p>-- Justice Minister Jacques Toubon calls for expanded legal recourses to pursue people who promote racism.</p>
<p>His call follows far-right leader Jean-Marie Le Pen's repeated statements that racial inequality was &quot;a fact&quot;.</p>
<p>BUSINESS PAGES</p>
<p>-- 1997 budget to be presented to Parliament on September 18, with a public deficit expected to reach some 278 billion francs. Financial markets may react unfavourably.</p>
<p>-- Banking sector could shed a further 60,000 jobs from now to year 2000. Credit Lyonnais workers demonstrated yesterday against further restructuring plan involving 5,000 job cuts.</p>
<p>-- Debt restructuring talks between Eurotunnel and its bankers in progress, shares rally.</p>
<p>-- French airports expect total safety through cargo controls, by year 2002.</p>
<p>-- Paris bourse to launch new secondary market index on October 1 comprising 140 medium-sized companies.</p>
<p>-- Calls for labour unrest this week in textile, defence sectors and at Credit Lyonnais have not been widely followed.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 42 21 53 81</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
