<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="536212" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French voters say euro threatens jobs, growth.</title>
<headline>French voters say euro threatens jobs, growth.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>French voters, facing a snap parliamentary election, believe that a single European currency favoured by major political parties will threaten jobs and economic growth, an opinion poll said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The survey, by the Louis Harris institute for Valeurs Actuelles magazine, also showed that most voters believed there were alternatives to the centre-right government's economic policies meant to prepare for the single currency from 1999.</p>
<p>And 69 percent of those quizzed favoured a new referendum on the introduction of the euro currency. French voters narrowly approved the Maastricht Treaty on European union, including the currency, in a 1992 referendum.</p>
<p>The survey, taken before President Jacques Chirac on Monday announced the May 25-June 1 election, showed 50 percent reckoned the single currency would fail to help &quot;a return to economic growth&quot;. Forty-three percent disagreed.</p>
<p>Seventy-three percent of 951 people surveyed believed the euro would not help cut unemployment in major European nations, with just 20 percent saying it would. And 71 percent said it would fail to reduce social inequalities, against 23 percent.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe's coalition says its current policies of austerity are essential to enable France to qualify for the euro. The opposition Socialists also favour the currency, but on conditions which include letting Italy and Spain in from the start.</p>
<p>Fifty-eight percent of those polled on April 18 and 19 reckoned the government should radically change economic policy.</p>
<p>Twenty percent believed current policies could be readjusted and just 12 percent saw no alternative to the government's strategy, given budget and European restraints.</p>
<p>The survey also showed voters overwhelmingly in favour of measures such as tax breaks for families with one child, transfer of ownership of cheap housing to long-term tenants and the launch of a huge national bond to finance new businesses.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
