<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="536332" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Nine killed in Pakistan sectarian shooting.</title>
<headline>Nine killed in Pakistan sectarian shooting.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gunmen riding a motorcycle sprayed bullets on a busy market in Pakistan's central province of Punjab on Thursday, killing nine people and wounding three, doctors and police said.</p>
<p>A police official said three gunmen riding on a single motorcycle targeted shopkeepers in the Faisal Bazaar and Rahim Market in the small town, 100 km (60 miles) southwest of southern Punjab's main city of Multan.</p>
<p>&quot;The masked gunmen then drove away from the scene,&quot; Mohammad Aslam of the Khairpur Tameywala Police Station told Reuters. He said the incident appeared to be sectarian violence.</p>
<p>A doctor at the town's Civil Hospital said nine people were killed and three wounded.</p>
<p>Muhammad Younis Suhail said six of the dead belonged to the minority Shi'ite Moslem sect and three from the majority Sunni Moslem sect. &quot;Most of the killed are shopkeepers.&quot;</p>
<p>There was no immediate information about the identity of the gunmen.</p>
<p>The incident follows a series of similar attacks on Shi'ites and Sunnis. Militants of the two sects have blamed each other for the attacks.</p>
<p>Shi'ite Moslems have recently been the target of attacks in Pakistan, particularly in southern Punjab.</p>
<p>A Shi'ite doctor was killed in Lodhran, 75 km (45 miles) from Multan by masked gunmen on April 15</p>
<p>A long running feud between the two sects cost more than 170 lives in Pakistan last year.</p>
<p>Sunnis dominate Pakistan's population of more than 130 million, while Shi'ites represent about 15 percent but are in majority in neighbouring Iran.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
