<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="536324" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan navy chief resigns amid corruption talk.</title>
<headline>Pakistan navy chief resigns amid corruption talk.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's navy chief, Admiral Mansurul Haque, resigned on Thursday after Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif ordered him to do so, official sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;The naval chief was directed by the prime minister to resign after reports appeared in the press suggesting his involvement in corruption,&quot; one official said.</p>
<p>&quot;Exercising his constitutional powers, the prime minister ordered him to tender his immediate resignation,&quot; said the official, who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>It was thought to be the first time in Pakistan's 50-year history that a top commander of any branch of the armed forces has been ordered to resign by a prime minister.</p>
<p>Haque had been the target of criticism in the Pakistani press in connection with a controversial purchase of three Agosta 90-B submarines from France in 1995, signed under the former government led by Benazir Bhutto.</p>
<p>On Wednesday senior navy officers told select reporters no kickbacks had been involved in the submarine deal.</p>
<p>Newspapers quoted an unnamed senior naval officer as saying that Haque was ready to face a court martial if any proof of the charges against him was found.</p>
<p>President Farooq Leghari sacked Bhutto's government in November on disputed charges of corrruption and misrule.</p>
<p>The submarine agreement calls for the first vessel to be wholly built in France and delivered within four years. The second would be assembled in Pakistan and the third would be completely built in the southern port city of Karachi.</p>
<p>The Agosta submarine, built in the French port of Cherbourg, carries torpedoes and SM-39 Exocet anti-ship missiles.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
