<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="536400" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Kashmiris say India's new premier can bring peace.</title>
<headline>Kashmiris say India's new premier can bring peace.</headline>
<byline>Sheikh Mushtaq</byline>
<dateline>SRINAGAR, India 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kashmiri leaders said on Thursday they believed India's new Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral could help normalise relations with Pakistan and bring peace to a Himalayan region torn by years of insurgency.</p>
<p>&quot;If Mr Gujral continues to be prime minister of India for a longer period, I believe he can play a historic role in bringing India and Pakistan closer and solving the Kashmir problem,&quot; popular separatist leader Shabir Ahmad Shah told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;This man I know personally, he is true to his word and can bring peace in South Asia,&quot; Shah said at Srinagar, the summer capital of Jammu and Kashmir state.</p>
<p>&quot;He has met all of us several times and discussed Kashmir with us. He knows our problems better than anybody in India.&quot;</p>
<p>Gujral, sworn in as prime minister on Monday, is one of the most popular Indian leaders in Kashmir.</p>
<p>He was born in 1919 in the Punjab region and is the first Indian prime minister to have his roots in an area that is now part of Pakistan. Pakistani Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif also comes from Punjab.</p>
<p>Gujral has met Kashmiri separatist leaders several times and visited the New Delhi office of the separatist All Parties Hurriyat (Freedom) Conference, Hurriyat officials said.</p>
<p>The disputed Himalayan region of Kashmir is a key issue in talks between India and Pakistan that Gujral, as foreign minister, helped revive last month after three years of impasse. India and Pakistan have fought two wars over Kashmir since 1947.</p>
<p>Gujral, who also holds the foreign and finance portfolios, and Sharif are expected to meet on the sidelines of a regional summit in the Maldives between May 12 and 14.</p>
<p>&quot;Now that both neighbouring countries have prime ministers with Punjabi backgrounds, there should be better understanding between the two, helping Kashmiris to live in peace and dignity,&quot; said Ali Mohammad, a Srinagar school teacher.</p>
<p>Gujral will visit the winter capital of Jammu and Kashmir state, Jammu, on April 27, in what was expected to be his first trip out of the Indian capital since assuming power.</p>
<p>&quot;He is capable of improving Indo-Pak relations, but we are not very optimistic about the change in Kashmir. Time will prove if he can stop geonocide, custodial killings and human rights violations at the hands of Indian security forces in Kashmir,&quot; said Hurriyat chairman Umar Farooq.</p>
<p>&quot;The United Front government is taking care of Kashmir and our government, but Gujral is the man who can stop the bloodshed in the valley. He has a grip over the Kashmir situation,&quot; said Mohammad Shafi Bhat, a senior leader of Kashmir's ruling National Conference party.</p>
<p>Gujral on Tuesday acknowledged in parliament that although elections were held in Jammu and Kashmir last year, the &quot;sorrow&quot; had yet to end. He pledged to take special steps to redress Kashmiris' grievances.</p>
<p>Police and hospitals say more than 20,000 people have died since the separatist revolt began in 1990 in Kashmir.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SRINAGAR, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
