<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53653" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Tortuous path led to Algerian conference.</title>
<headline>Tortuous path led to Algerian conference.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Algerian President Liamine Zeroual is due to open a conference on Saturday to try to end Algeria's crisis sparked by 1992 cancellation of elections dominated by Moslem fundamentalists.</p>
<p>Here are the main milestones leading to the conference:</p>
<p>1994</p>
<p>January - Zeroual appointed head of state, one week after the end of a national conference boycotted by main opposition parties.</p>
<p>August - President starts dialogue with five main opposition parties amid hopes that jailed leaders of radical Islamists might join. Secular opposition parties stay away, accusing Zeroual of trying to reach deal with fundamentalists.</p>
<p>September - Zeroual says Abassi Madani, the detained leader of the Islamic Salvation Front (FIS), had detailed proposals for ending violence. Hopes for a deal collapse after security forces kill Cherif Gousmi, leader of most feared guerrilla movement, the Armed Islamic Group (GIA), and find letter on his body from Madani's deputy Ali Belhadj urging increased killings.</p>
<p>October- Zeroual breaks off talks, says presidential election will be held in 1995. Blasts FIS leaders for &quot;intransigency&quot;.</p>
<p>November - Main opposition groups, including outlawed FIS, start dialogue in Rome under auspices of the Catholic peace group Sant'Egidio.</p>
<p>1995</p>
<p>January - Rome groups sign accord, urging Algerian government to negotiate but laying down preconditions, including release of all political prisoners and pledge from army to stay out of politics. Government rejects this.</p>
<p>November - Zeroual, gambling that Algeria's 29 million people are tired of violence and ready to give him a chance, seeks election in Algeria's first multi-candidate presidential poll. He is elected by more than 60 percent. Turnout is high despite threats by militant groups to kill those going to vote.</p>
<p>1996</p>
<p>April - Zeroual resumes talks with more than 80 politicians and prominent personalities. Radical Islamists are excluded.</p>
<p>May - Zeroual unveils 22-page blueprint of political reforms sent to party leaders. Document outlines plans for proportional representation, a two-chamber parliament and a ban on parties using Islam to gain power. He pledges referendum to be held this year, followed by general elections early in 1997 and local elections later the same year.</p>
<p>Main opposition secular Socialist Forces Front (FFS) party dismisses plan as bid to impose &quot;institutional dictatorship&quot;.</p>
<p>July - Zeroual resumes talks with parties.</p>
<p>August - Talks conclude with draft laws proposed to introduce proportional representation, ban religious parties, and underline that Islam is religion of the state.</p>
<p>September - Zeroual announces September 14 and 15 as dates for conference to adopt his reform plan. Main secular opposition parties, FFS and Rally for Democracy and Culture, announce conference boycott.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
