<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="536956" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: HELSINKI HOLDS MINOR GAINS, SEEN CAUTIOUS.</title>
<headline>HELSINKI HOLDS MINOR GAINS, SEEN CAUTIOUS.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares struggled to hold</p>
<p>minor gains in thin trade on Thursday and brokers saw little</p>
<p>scope for strengthening as many investors remained sidelined</p>
<p>ahead of key first-quarter earnings reports this week and next.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we've had about all the help we are going to have</p>
<p>for today,&quot; one broker said after forestries gained on the Q1</p>
<p>report from Swedish Stora .</p>
<p>Brokers said UPM-Kymmene clearly rose on Stora's</p>
<p>report. It added 1.20 markka to a session high of 116.20 before</p>
<p>settling at 116.00 in fairly lively 28 million markka volume.</p>
<p>Nokia traded up 1.60 markka at 303.60 matching its Wall</p>
<p>Street close after touching 304.50 in lax trade, with investors</p>
<p>playing wait-and-see ahead of Q1 reports from Swedish</p>
<p>Ericsson on Friday and Nokia itself on Tuesday, brokers</p>
<p>said.</p>
<p>Asko rose 0.50 markka to 91.00 in a second straight</p>
<p>day of heavy volume stemming from a few big deals matched</p>
<p>in-house at Evli Securities. Brokers declined to guess at who</p>
<p>the buyers and sellers were.</p>
<p>Nordic Aluminium, in its first day of bourse</p>
<p>trade, came off a high of 55.00 markka to trade at 54.00.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
