<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="536927" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: BELGIAN INTERBREW SEES MORE BUYS, EYES LATAM.</title>
<headline>BELGIAN INTERBREW SEES MORE BUYS, EYES LATAM.</headline>
<dateline>LEUVEN, Belgium 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Interbrew, the large, privately-owned Belgian brewing group, said on Thursday it aimed to grow further through acquisition and brand building while continuing to cut its debt to equity ratio and reducing costs.</p>
<p>&quot;It is only by achieving these objectives that we shall be able to face the threats and capitalise on the opportunities,&quot; board chairman Paul De Keersmaeker told a news conference to present 1996 results.</p>
<p>Interbrew is lookong for acquisitions in Latin America, western, eastern and central Europe and Asia/Pacific, he said.  </p>
<p>Hugo Powell, Interbrew's Chief operating officer for the Americas Region, said the potential for growth in Latin America was excellent.</p>
<p>&quot;Our intention is where practical to have a strong local partner to participate in any transactions we do,&quot; Powell said. &quot;In the next five years we would wish for an important part of our growth to come from Latin America.</p>
<p>Interbrew's Canadian brewing unit Labatt owns 22 percent of a unit of Mexico's FEMSA Cerveza. The Belgian group made its first foray into the Caribbean in 1996 with a joint venture in the Dominican Republic involving Labatt.  </p>
<p>Interbrew said 35 percent of volume now came from emerging markets.</p>
<p>In its existing markets the group aimed to continue growth by building up key lager and speciality brands.</p>
<p>Interbrew made group net profit of 4.1 billion Belgian francs in 1996, when it switched to calender year reporting, compared to a 3.46 billion franc profit for the previous 15 months.</p>
<p>Sales rose to 32.86 million hectolitres from 28.90 million. Labatt, bought in July 1995, was consolidated fully in 1996 figures and for five months of the 1994/1995 period.</p>
<p>Negative elements in 1996 included poor weather throughout the year in Western Europe and Canada and a structural decrease in beer consumption.</p>
<p>As a result the beer market itself had retreated year on year in all markets where Interbrew was operational apart from France and Canada, though Interbrew's market share held steady or increased in most areas.</p>
<p>In Belgium, where competition remained strong, market share was stable at 56 percent. In Canada its volume increased by 2.2 percent in a market that grew by one percent, and Interbrew's market share increased to 46.0 percent from 45.1 percent</p>
<p>The group gained market share in Hungary, Croatia and Romania, while sales of Labatt Blue and the Mexican brands progressed strongly in the United States. Exports and licenced volumes continued double digit growth.</p>
<p>Over 1.6 million hectolitres of Stella Artois was sold in Britain in 1996, an increase of about 20 percent.</p>
<p>Speciality beers Leffe and Hoegaarden gained market share and volume, particularly in Belgium and France.</p>
<p>Interbrew reduced its debt to equity ratio by December 1996 to 1.28 from 1.73 at the end of the previous reporting period thanks to the sale of non-strategic assets.</p>
<p>&quot;1995 was the year of acquisitions, 1996 the year of strengthening,&quot; De Keersmaeker said.</p>
<p>Concerns for the near future included a lack of competitiveness in Europe due to high salary costs and relatively stagnant economies, the trend of governments to increase tax on beer and the continued concentration and power of food distributors in Europe.</p>
<p>-- Lorrayne Smith, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6812, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LEUVEN, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
