<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="536948" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-European stocks hold ground, dollar firm.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-European stocks hold ground, dollar firm.</headline>
<byline>Alister Bull</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading European bourses hovered in positive territory on Thursday despite doubt over Wall Street, while a firm dollar helped Paris advance.</p>
<p>Stocks in London and Frankfurt marked time ahead of New York's open, wary after the Dow Jones industrial average failed to build upon Tuesday's record 173 point gain and fell 21 points overnight to 6,812.72.</p>
<p>But Paris shrugged off such concerns, advancing from the open and holding its rally over the morning.</p>
<p>By 1130 GMT the CAC 40 had pushed ahead by 25 points, or almost one percent, to 2,559, aided by a weaker franc, rising bonds and a technical rally linked to the start of trading for the May stock exchange account.</p>
<p>Political concerns remained in the background, with investors still drawing comfort from an opinion poll on Tuesday that forecast the centre-right coalition of Prime Minister Alain Juppe would retain its majority in snap elections to be held in a matter of weeks.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel shares, celebrating a comprehensive debt-agreement with its banks, also lifted sentiment.</p>
<p>U.S. shares in London gave little clue to the question of whether Wall Street's rally over the last two weeks could be sustained -- a worry heightened by its 2.60 percent jump of Tuesday which marked its second largest one-day gain.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody knows which way to jump. The Dow has come back too fast and people think it could be heading for another fall,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The Dow has clawed back nearly two-thirds of ground lost since it hit a 1997 low of 6,391.69 on April 11.</p>
<p>&quot;This rally has been on the back of good earnings news but once that stops, the market is going to start worrying about interest rates again,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>In the currency markets the dollar maintained its firm stance against European rivals, although activity remained subdued ahead of a Group of Seven meeting in Washington.</p>
<p>European bond markets were also firm, with the Paris  MATIF June bond futures contract gaining ground and German bund yields widening their discount to U.S. treasuries.</p>
<p>But In London the blue chip FTSE 100 hesitated around lower opening levels at 4,385 while Frankfurt remained fractionally ahead at 3.397.</p>
<p>British inflation data earlier lifted the London market, but the Footsie faced a considerable obstacle in advancing much further before the outcome of Britain's general election next week.</p>
<p>A crucial barrier at 4,400 will prove a particular challenge, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's really kicking its heels until the election while keeping an eye on Wall Street,&quot; said BZW's head of European strategy, Richard Kersley.</p>
<p>March CPI, Britain's new measure of consumer price inflation, earlier showed a 1.8 percent yearly rise which strategists said would cap interest rate fears.</p>
<p>The prospect of a rate rise soon after the May 1 general election has dogged the London market for weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;The CPI data should just cap fears of just how rates should rise,&quot; said Kleinwort Benson UK equities strategist, Philip Isherwood. &quot;They'll go up after the election but not significantly.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar perked up from overnight and early European levels, helped by a softer mark on its crosses amid indications of muted German inflation as well as growing expectations of a relatively benign statement on dollar strength from the G7.</p>
<p>&quot;The G7 will keep a top on the dollar but we see a fairly neutral statement,&quot; said Peter Wood, currency trader at Bank of Boston in London.</p>
<p>STOCKS AT 1200 GMT</p>
<p>London's FTSE 100 was down 3.5 at 4384.2.</p>
<p>The Paris CAC-40 index was up 23 .45 at 2556.79.</p>
<p>Frankfurt's DAX index was up 1.41at 3397.36</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1200 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar stood at 1.719 against the mark versus 1.7117 in late European trade on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Against the yen, the dollar was quoted at 126.15 from 126.08.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold fixed just higher at $341.15 from $341.00, clinging above $340.00. Silver rose one cent to 4.72/$4.74.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
