<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="537048" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Euroshares push ahead,ignore Wall Street dip.</title>
<headline>Euroshares push ahead,ignore Wall Street dip.</headline>
<byline>Alister Bull</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's top stock markets edged higher on Thursday, helped by a firm dollar and ignoring Wall Street's overnight setback.</p>
<p>Paris advanced from the start, while London and Frankfurt both reversed opening weakness to post modest morning gains. Buoyant futures markets in all three centres helped sentiment despite the consolidation in New York.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average failed to build upon the previous session's record 173 point rally and closed overnight 20.87 points lower at 6,812.72.</p>
<p>In the currency markets the dollar firmed against European rivals in light trade ahead of a weekend Group of Seven (G7) meeting in Washington.</p>
<p>European bond markets were also firm, with the Paris  MATIF June bond futures contract gaining ground and German bund yields widening their discount to U.S. treasuries.</p>
<p>French shares opened sharply higher, encouraged by franc weakness against the dollar as Eurotunnel shares celebrated a comprehensive debt-agreement with bank lenders, rising by almost four percent to 6.50 francs.</p>
<p>Political concerns remained in the background, with investors still drawing comfort froom an opinion poll on Tuesday that forecast the centre-right coalition of Prime Minister Alain Juppe hanging onto its majorty in snap elections to be held in a matter of weeks.</p>
<p>By 0930 GMT the main CAC 40 index stood 12 points, or almost half a percent higher, at 2.546.</p>
<p>In London the blue chip FTSE 100 opened weaker before recovering to be up 6.6 points at 4,394, buoyed by strong gains in the banking sector and positive news on inflation. But it failed to hold the psychologically key 4,400 points level.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's really kicking its heels until the election while keeping an eye on Wall Street,&quot; said BZW's head of European strategy, Richard Kersley.</p>
<p>On Wednesday the index gained 41.6 points to set a five-week closing high, but was not expected to mount a successful assault on 4,400.</p>
<p>&quot;The upside is limited from here,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;We were happy to follow Wall Street up yesterday but we didn't really kick in and the pressure will come to bear today. We won't be attacking 4,400,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But the market will draw confidence from March CPI, Britain's new measure of consumer price inflation, which showed a 1.8 percent yearly rise which strategists said would cap interest rate fears.</p>
<p>Investors will welcome the news, as the prospect of a rate rise soon after the May 1 general election has dogged the London market for weeks.</p>
<p>The dollar perked up from overnight and early European levels, helped by a softer mark on its crosses amid indications of muted German inflation as well as growing expectations of a relatively benign statement on dollar strength from the G7.</p>
<p>&quot;The G7 will keep a top on the dollar but we see a fairly neutral statement,&quot; said Peter Wood, currency trader at Bank of Boston in London.</p>
<p>STOCKS AT 1000 GMT</p>
<p>London's FTSE 100 was up 6.4 at 4394.1.</p>
<p>The Paris CAC-40 index was up 20 at 2554.</p>
<p>Frankfurt's DAX index was up 6.3 at 3402.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1000 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar stood at 1.720 against the mark versus 1.7117 in late European trade on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Against the yen, the dollar was quoted at 126.28 from 126.08.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold fixed just higher at $341.15 from $341.00, clinging above $340.00. Silver rose one cent to 4.72/$4.74.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
