<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="537193" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. environment agency defends air quality plans.</title>
<headline>U.S. environment agency defends air quality plans.</headline>
<byline>Vicki Allen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Clinton administration's top environmental regulator on Wednesday fended off accusations from House Republicans that her agency acted illegally when it proposed tougher air quality standards.</p>
<p>Republicans on a House Government Reform and Oversight subcommittee said the Environmental Protection Agency violated laws protecting small businesses and communities, and tried to stifle comments from other federal agencies on a proposal that could cost billions of dollars to implement.</p>
<p>But EPA Administrator Carol Browner said the agency strictly followed laws and procedures, and said studies showed stronger standards were needed to protect the public's health.</p>
<p>&quot;EPA is doing precisely what the law -- the Clean Air Act -- tells us to do, and that is protect the public health above all else,&quot; Browner said.</p>
<p>Subcommitee Chairman David McIntosh, a frequent critic of government regulations, said he believed the EPA proposal was &quot;regulatory fraud&quot; and said the agency should start over on it to avoid losing court challenges.</p>
<p>&quot;EPA's violations of regulatory law throw the entire rulemaking into question,&quot; the Indiana Republican said.</p>
<p>The subcommittee's hearing was the latest of several House panel hearings in which Republicans questioned whether the EPA breached rules when it decided to propose stricter health standards against smog and soot pollution.</p>
<p>The agency is to announce a final rule on the standards in July. Browner said she had not reached a final decision, and was still evaluating public comments.</p>
<p>The proposal has raised an uproar among smokestack industries and many state and local governments that say it will cost billions of dollars and will stifle economic growth in areas that have difficulty meeting the new standards.</p>
<p>Industry groups and congressmen opposing the tougher standards have focused on whether science actually shows they would have significant health benefits, and on how the EPA arrived at its proposal.</p>
<p>&quot;It is no great secret ... that the major polluters of America will spend millions and millions of dollars trying to destroy&quot; environmental regulations, Rep. Bernard Sanders, an independent from Vermont, said.</p>
<p>&quot;What kind of country are we if we say we have 15,000 people dying prematurely and 250,000 children becoming ill, and we're not going to do anything about it,&quot; Sanders said.</p>
<p>The EPA estimates stronger soot and smog standards would prevent 15,000 premature deaths each year as well as 250,000 asthma attacks in children.</p>
<p>Responding to the panel's questions, Browner said the agency did not have to analyze how the proposed health standards would affect small businesses because that would be done in later stages when states prepare plans on how to meet the new standards.</p>
<p>She said the EPA may recommend that states give exemptions to small businesses and use other measures to ease effects.</p>
<p>An official who acts as a small business advocate in the Small Business Administration said he felt the EPA should have analyzed potential effects when proposing the standards. But Jere Glover, the SBA's chief counsel for advocacy, said in written testimony it was &quot;a question about which reasonable people can disagree.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
