<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="537393" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - BTPs must top 128.20 to restore bull tone.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - BTPs must top 128.20 to restore bull tone.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>June BTPs are hovering in fairly neutral territory and must close above 128.20 to restore their bullish tone, technical analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Italy is the most neutral of all the European bond markets at the moment,&quot; said Chase analyst Guenter Redeker. &quot;But on balance, I see the market reaching at least 128.20, then the market must decide.&quot;</p>
<p>By 0806 GMT, the June BTP was up 16 basis points at 127.68 after opening at 127.43. Redeker said if the market managed to close above 128.20, it would open up the potential to retest 129.05, the highs on April 15 and 17.  </p>
<p>Above there, plenty of upside potential towards 130.80 would be opened up, said Redeker, ahead of 131.04, the high on February 10.</p>
<p>&quot;The risk in this market is if it isn't able to hold the 126.90,-127.01 band,&quot; said Redeker. The 126.90 level is trend support and 127.01 is the low from April 23.</p>
<p>&quot;If it can't hold that, there is plenty of downside potential, meaning the market could easily retest 124.50.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts at a European bank said BTPs had to close above 128.00 to show more promise for bulls. &quot;Otherwise there could easily be a slump back, with 126.40 the next lower support.&quot;  </p>
<p>By 0831 GMT, June Eurolire were up two basis points at 93.20.</p>
<p>Analysts at the European bank said a slip back through this level would cast doubt on the validity of the recent upbreak.</p>
<p>&quot;But the picture currently stays constructive,&quot; they said. &quot;Thinking big and bullish, the 50 percent retracement level is at 93.38, the 61.8 percent at 93.57.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
