<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="537469" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian parliament rocked by criminal charges.</title>
<headline>Australian parliament rocked by criminal charges.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian politics has been rocked by an unprecedented series of criminal charges and investigations that could see up to five politicians drummed out of the national parliament.</p>
<p>The charges, ranging from fraud to dangerous driving, have hit all sides of politics and sparked counter-accusations of political witch-hunts.</p>
<p>Independent lower house politician Graeme Campbell, the latest to be charged, said on Thursday a police charge of dangerous driving against him was politically motivated.</p>
<p>&quot;The charge of dangerous driving is an absolute victimisation,&quot; Campbell said in a radio interview.</p>
<p>Campbell admits injuring a motorcyclist in an October 1996 traffic accident, but rejects the charge of dangerous driving.</p>
<p>&quot;I certainly damaged him, which I regret, but it was certainly not dangerous driving,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Campbell, a renegade politician from outback Western Australia state who quit the left-leaning Labor opposition party, is the third politician to be charged this month.</p>
<p>Former Labor government health minister Carmen Lawrence was granted bail by a local court in Perth in Western Australia on Thursday on three charges of knowingly giving false evidence to a 1995 special state inquiry.</p>
<p>Lawrence, who pleaded not guilty, stood down as the Labor opposition's environment spokeswoman on Tuesday, but said she would not quit parliament. Like Campbell, she said the charges were &quot;the result of a highly politicised process&quot;.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard's conservative Liberal-National government, which pledged higher parliamentary standards after winning power a year ago, has also been hit by recent scandals.</p>
<p>National Party lower house backbencher Michael Cobb has been charged with fraud over travel and car entitlement claims, while former Liberal upper house member Bob Woods, who quit parliament in March, was charged with fraud over similar allegations.</p>
<p>While independent senator Mal Colston, whose support has been crucial to government reforms, is being investigated by police over allegations he abused travel allowances and faces possible fraud charges.</p>
<p>Colston, Lawrence, Woods and Cobb all deny breaking any law.</p>
<p>Any politician convicted of an offence carrying a penalty of 12 months or more in jail, regardless of their actual sentence, cannot continue to sit in the Australian parliament.</p>
<p>Those convicted also lose their lucrative parliamentary pension savings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
