<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="537573" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul stocks close down led by Jinro units, banks.</title>
<headline>Seoul stocks close down led by Jinro units, banks.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean stocks closed lower on Thursday after trading in positive territory for most of the day as banks lost ground on profit-taking, brokers said.</p>
<p>The composite index closed at 690.80, down 2.25 points. It was off an intraday high of 697.43.</p>
<p>Affiliates of the troubled Jinro Group fell as investors continued to be concerned about the group's future.</p>
<p>Samsung Electronics shares were unmoved by the news that Standard &amp; Poor's had cut Samsung's long-term rating outlook.</p>
<p>New Star Trading fell after Savoy Hotel offered a tender to buy 25.3 percent of New Star in a takeover bid.  </p>
<p>&quot;Selling increased once the index approached the 700-point resistance level,&quot; said analyst Koh Kyung-bae of Hyundai Securities. &quot;Trading was also hit by rumours that several companies besides Jinro were also in financial trouble.&quot;</p>
<p>Samsung Electronics closed flat at 59,600 after rising to 60,500. Standard &amp; Poor's Corp said on Thursday it had cut Samsung's rating outlook to negative from stable.</p>
<p>Jinro Ltd lost 660 won to its daily limit of 7,690. Jinro Industries fell 360 won to its limit of 4,170 and Jinro General Foods by 290 won to 3,620.  </p>
<p>The troubled Jinro Group has said it would sell off some of its property and affiliates to raise cash to pay back its debt, estimated at 3.2 trillion won.</p>
<p>New Star Trading fell 4,900 won to its limit of 57,200. Savoy on Thursday offered to buy 120,785 shares of New Star for 62,500 won per share in a bid to take over New Star.</p>
<p>If successful, Savoy's stake in the garment maker would rise to 50 percent, surpassing the current largest single stake of 29.26 percent held by New Star's president and his family.</p>
<p>--YOO CHOON-SIK (822) 727 5646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
