<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="537526" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Dlr inches up vs yen but gains limited in Tokyo.</title>
<headline>Dlr inches up vs yen but gains limited in Tokyo.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>0300 GMT     2400 GMT	NYK CLOSE</p>
<p> USD/JPY	   126.25/28    126.10/13     126.00/10</p>
<p> USD/DEM	   1.7127/30    1.7125/28     1.7135/40</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The dollar inched up against the yen by Tokyo midday Thursday on short-covering by interbank traders, but its gains were limited as market participants remained reluctant to take up heavy positions ahead of a forthcoming meeting of Group of Seven (G7) officials.</p>
<p>Dealers said exporters were keen to sell dollars around 126.50 yen, keeping the dollar's topside heavy.  </p>
<p>There was talk that life insurers may have been behind late-morning dollar purchases, but most dealers said it was more short-covering by short-term players than anything else.</p>
<p>&quot;Traders do not have a major reason to buy the greenback today,&quot; a trust bank dealer said, adding that the outcome of G7 meeting still has potential to push the greenback down.</p>
<p>Dealers said the greenback is likely to fall should the G7 meeting come up with a stronger-than-expected warning against recent currency movements. &quot;A possible fall in dollars after the G7 meeting depends on whether the outcome is stronger than the one in the last G7 meeting,&quot; one bank dealer said.  </p>
<p>A city bank dealer said: &quot;The dollar could fall sharply if the G7 meeting signals possible joint (dollar-selling) intervention. But otherwise the dollar will be supported near 125 yen with solid bids from institutional investors, even if it falls after the meeting.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said exporters, seen eager to sell dollars before Japan's &quot;Golden Week&quot; holiday next week, were expected to kick in to sell the greenback near 126.50 yen. A trust bank dealer said U.S. funds bought back British pounds for dollars after sterling eased against the dollar overnight, which briefly weighed on dollar/mark rates.  </p>
<p>Sterling fell in overseas trading on Wednesday due to latest British polls that indicated May 1 general elections could be tighter-than-expected. In addition, optimism that Europe's proposed single currency stands a good chance of launching as scheduled in January 1999 weighed on the British pound, while Britain is not slated to join the euro group.</p>
<p>Sterling stood near $1.6280/90 at midday, up from $1.6228/38 at New York close.</p>
<p>In trade against mark, the greenback remained mostly directionless by midday.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-8584</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
