<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="537737" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia Product Swaps-Gas oil drifts, lacks direction.</title>
<headline>Asia Product Swaps-Gas oil drifts, lacks direction.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore gas oil swaps drifted in directionless trade as sustained physical purchases by local traders at current levels has kept prices steady despite falls to crude prices, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market here is isolated now with everything centred around the buying of the two local traders,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>May gas oil swaps were last quoted steady from Wednesday at $25.35/$25.55 per barrel, with June up 15 cents at $24.30/$24.50, brokers said.  </p>
<p>Traders said the market was very quiet with June edging up on the belief by some that the buying spree of the local traders might be extended to at least end April.</p>
<p>Industry sources said the large purchases in the past two months by the traders has kept prices in Singapore well above the other international markets and immune to price fluctuations in the other markets as well as to crude.</p>
<p>&quot;The traders' support has kept prices steady even when crude plunged by over 50 cents recently,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>The local traders have since March 3 bought well over 15 million barrels of physical gas oil for lifting from end March to late May.</p>
<p>The traders on Wednesday bought two 150,000-barrel cargoes at between $26.50 to $27.00 for May loading.</p>
<p>The fuel oil swaps steady with May last quoted at $97.50/$98.50 per tonne.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (+65-870 3093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
