<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53770" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India moves anti-corruption bill in parliament.</title>
<headline>India moves anti-corruption bill in parliament.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indian government on Friday introduced an anti-corruption bill in the lower house of parliament that would set up a watchdog panel to investigate scandals involving parliament deputies and public officials.</p>
<p>It would let the government establish an institution acting as ombudsman to &quot;inquire into allegations of corruption against public functionaries and for matters connected therewith.&quot;</p>
<p>The panel would include an ombudsman (Lokpal) and two members appointed for a five-year period. The ombudsman should be a Supreme court judge, the bill said.</p>
<p>India has been rocked by a series of corruption scandals in recent years, including one in which former prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao and several of his party members have been named.</p>
<p>Federal police have investigated the Rao, 74, in a cheating scandal.</p>
<p>An Indian expatriate, Lakhubhai Pathak, has said he paid $100,000 to Chandraswami, a Hindu holy man and acquaintance of Rao, in a failed attempt to secure a government contract.</p>
<p>Rao has also been in the public eye in connection with a fertiliser import scandal in which one of his sons has been investigated by federal agents. Rao has denied any wrongdoing.</p>
<p>Former communications minister Sukh Ram, a Rao cabinet member, was suspected of involvement in a financial scandal after federal police last month recovered about one million dollars from his residences.</p>
<p>Seven of Rao's ministers and two state governerors resigned in January to face allegations in an $18 million-political bribery scandal after an illegal foreign exchange dealer claimed to have given them money. They all denied wrongdoing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
