<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="537872" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Biggest forestry challenge is capital use - UPM.</title>
<headline>Biggest forestry challenge is capital use - UPM.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Efficient use of capital to create value to shareholders is the biggest challenge for forest industry companies, said Martin Granholm, executive vice president at Finnish forestry major UPM-Kymmene.</p>
<p>In response to a presentation by Merita analyst Pertti Aaltonen late on Wednesday showing that in the past 10 years, only in 1995 had forestry returns on investment been bigger than the cost of capital, Granholm said this was the greatest challenge.</p>
<p>&quot;Management should be a little less interested in investments and a bit more interested in markets,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem with investment calculations is that on the cost side, we always get spot on estimates but markets are difficult to predict,&quot; he said. &quot;And the long-term price trend in all forest industry products I know is falling, steadily&quot;.</p>
<p>Merita's Aaltonen said the problems with creating positive economic value-added has not been a uniquely Finnish problem, but one overall for the industry, which has carried out many poor investments.</p>
<p>In the future, the industry would continue to consolidate globally, Granholm said, pointing to the metal industry where leading companies have global market shares around 10 percent compared to around three percent for the biggest paper makers.</p>
<p>&quot;The key will be not to build new, but to combine,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Granholm said Nordic producers were being challenged in most paper grades by improving qualities of paper including mostly short-fibre pulp made from southern hardwood trees, but he saw a competitive edge in long-fibre papers mostly made of softwood.</p>
<p>&quot;Our belief in the future is based on that softwood cannot be grown anywhere else than in the barren northern area stretching from Canada to Scandinavia and into Russia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Coated fine papers, which include short-fibre pulp made from hardwood such as eucalyptus that grows in the south, are normally more expensive to make and not a substitute to coated mechanical paper grades, unless their prices are very depressed, he said.</p>
<p>In newsprint, recycled paper was also a challenge.</p>
<p>Finnish forestry flagship UPM is the world's largest producer of light-weight-coated (LWC) magazine paper and Europe's largest forest industry group overall.</p>
<p>It is also world leader in uncoated super-calendered (SC) magazine paper.</p>
<p>Granholm said demand for coloured avertising inserts in magazines in Europe and the U.S. would also boost growth in magazine papers, and that overall demand for colour print in Asia would rise as prosperity rose.</p>
<p>Northern producers also had an advantage in some boards which need long-fibre pulp for strength, he added.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +358-9-680 50 242, news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
