<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="537936" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SingTel hits record low as rival grabs market.</title>
<headline>SingTel hits record low as rival grabs market.</headline>
<byline>Nick Edwards</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore Telecommunications Ltd (SingTel) shares hit an all-time low on Thursday on news that its rival mobile phone service had grabbed almost 10 percent of the local market in just three weeks, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's share price weakness is specifically related to the M1 (MobileOne) announcement,&quot; said Timothy Wong, an analyst at Vickers Ballas.</p>
<p>SingTel shares plunged to a record low of Singapore $2.50 (US$1.74) on Thursday before recovering to S$2.54 by the close of business, down eight cents on the day.</p>
<p>&quot;The S$2.50 level was an all time low for SingTel,&quot; said one local analyst, who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>Wong said the fall was sparked by comments by M1 chief executive Neil Montefiore that the company had signed up more than 35,000 subscribers in just three weeks of operations.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want to use the word overwhelming, but the response has been way beyond our expectations,&quot; Montefiore told Reuters in an interview earlier on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;In this first three weeks we must be the most successful entrant into any cellular market either initial, or second, or third, or whatever,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>MobileOne (Asia) Pte Ltd entered the Singapore cellular market on April 1 when mobile phone services were deregulated.</p>
<p>It is the only company to offer an alternative mobile phone service to former monopoly provider, SingTel.</p>
<p>M1 is a joint venture of Singapore Press Holdings, Keppel Telecom, Britain's Cable &amp; Wireless and Hong Kong Telecommunications.</p>
<p>SingTel shares were listed four years ago and hit an all-time high of S$4.10 last year but have since fallen back as the liberalisation of its former monopoly markets loomed.</p>
<p>SingTel is due to lose its monopoly of basic telecommunications services in April 2000.</p>
<p>Several foreign companies, including British Telecom Plc and AT&amp;T have said they may be interested in competing with SingTel from that date.</p>
<p>Another analyst who declined to be identified said the M1 news on Thursday had &quot;aggravated the negative sentiment around SingTel&quot;.</p>
<p>But the analyst said he was confident SingTel's shares would recover once the company announced its 1997 annual results in May -- a sentiment shared by Wong.</p>
<p>&quot;I think things will begin to look up when SingTel publishes its results,&quot; Wong said.</p>
<p>&quot;When management comes out and says something about competition and gives some guidance on how revenues will be affected that will allay some fears,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>SingTel officials were not immediately available for comment on the company's share price or M1's claims for market share.</p>
<p>SingTel and M1 have been engaged in a fierce advertising war in the local media over the last month.</p>
<p>($1 = S$1.44)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
