<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="537966" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Kellogg first quarter earnings fall 24 percent.</title>
<headline>Kellogg first quarter earnings fall 24 percent.</headline>
<byline>Todd Nissen</byline>
<dateline>BATTLE CREEK, Mich. 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kellogg Co., the nation's largest cereal manufacturer, said Friday its earnings tumbled by 24 percent in the first quarter as last year's price cuts continued to hurt profit margins.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, the domestic cereal giant, which makes Rice Krispies and Corn Flakes, said it expects earnings and sales growth to resume in the second quarter after a bruising four quarters of price cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;We fully expect to return to strong growth in the second quarter,&quot; Chairman Arnold Langbo told about 1,700 people who attended the company's annual shareholder meeting Friday at the W.K. Kellogg Auditorium in Battle Creek.</p>
<p>Kellogg's net income for the three months ended March 31 slid to $160.6 million from $206.1 million in the first quarter of 1996. Earnings per share dropped to 77 cents a share from 99 cents, a 22 percent decline, with fewer shares outstanding in the current period from a year ago.</p>
<p>Revenues shrank 5.4 percent to $1.69 billion from $1.79 billion, although global sales volume rose 10 percent, including the Lender's bagel business that was acquired in December. Excluding Lender's, the Battle Creek, Mich.-based company said its global sales volume was up 3 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said the company's second-quarter results face an easy comparison with depressed year-ago earnings, which fell 42 percent from the prior period.</p>
<p>&quot;We can look forward now to a couple of up quarters ... on very easy comparisons,&quot; Goldman Sachs analyst Nomi Ghez said.</p>
<p>&quot;There may be a sense that the worst is over,&quot; BT Securities analyst John O'Neil said. &quot;Starting next quarter, Kellogg should start generating earnings per share increases.&quot;</p>
<p>Langbo said overall the company's performance was encouraging, with strong sales growth in cereal in Asia and Latin America and in convenience foods in North America.</p>
<p>U.S. cereal volume sales improved late in the quarter, Langbo said, and was continuing to grow in April, with market share improvement in both the United States and Britain.</p>
<p>Analysts estimated Kellogg's domestic cereal volume fell about 2 percent in the first quarter, while international volume was up about 2 percent.</p>
<p>Kellogg's stock rose 87.5 cents to $66.875 in consolidated trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>At the shareholder meeting, Langbo said he was extremely pleased with the reception Kellogg's latest product, Cocoa Frosted Flakes, has received since it was introduced March 13. The cereal is only the second time Kellogg's famous Tony the Tiger, who first appeared in 1952, has been used on a cereal package.</p>
<p>&quot;Initial sales have been tremendous,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>After a turbulent year in the United States and Britain, Kellogg's two largest cereal markets, Langbo said the company is solidly positioned for strong long-term growth.</p>
<p>He also said convenience foods will contribute up to 30 percent of Kellogg's total annual sales in 10 years, as the company expands in the United States and overseas. Last year, about 20 percent of Kellogg's $6.68 billion in annual sales came from convenience foods such as Pop-Tarts and Nutri-Grain bars.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BATTLE CREEK, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
