<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="537951" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Smoking foes hail North Carolina ruling.</title>
<headline>Smoking foes hail North Carolina ruling.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anti-smoking advocates in Congress hailed the ruling Friday of a federal judge in North Carolina that the Food and Drug Administration has authority to regulate sales and labeling of cigarettes.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a great day. The tobacco industry can't even win on their home court,&quot; Sen. Frank Lautenberg, a New Jersey Democrat, said at a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;The tobacco companies picked this court in this state,&quot; Sen. Dick Durbin, D-Illinois said. But he added, &quot;The tobacco giant is down but not out. They are still very powerful.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The FDA and the American people prevailed,&quot; Sen. Edward Kennedy, D-Mass., said in a statement. &quot;Tens of thousands of lives may well be saved because of this decision.&quot;</p>
<p>Representative Marty Meehan, D-Mass., said, &quot;The decision is a great victory for America's children.&quot;</p>
<p>The lawmakers said they were confident the judge's ruling that the FDA did not have authority over cigarette advertising would be overturned on appeal. &quot;We can give the FDA statutory authority,&quot; Representative Henry Waxman, D.-Calif., said.</p>
<p>Waxman said any negotiations with the tobacco industry should focus on steps to stop the companies from trying to get children and teenagers to smoke.</p>
<p>Durbin called the decision a victory for President Clinton and former FDA Chairman David Kessler.</p>
<p>Kessler, interviewed on the Cable News Network, said, &quot;This is an historic, landmark decision. For the first time in 30 years since the surgeon general's report (linking smoking to disease), the government can take action. The FDA has jurisdiction.&quot;</p>
<p>But House Commerce Committee Chairman Tom Bliley, a Virginia Republican who opposes anti-tobacco measures, said, &quot;We are just at the beginning of a long and complicated process. I am pleased that Judge Osteen has enjoined further implementation of the FDA regulations until the matter is ultimately resolved by the courts.&quot;</p>
<p>Separately, Kennedy said the reported proposal by the tobacco industry to pay $300 billion over 25 years in exchange for immunity from lawsuits should not be accepted.</p>
<p>&quot;The industry's current settlement proposals are utterly inadequate,&quot; Kennedy said in a Senate speech.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether measured by the scope of regulation to protect the public health or the amount of financial compensation for past wrongs, tobacco company proposals fall far short of a reasonable offer. I am confident that those representing the public interest will never accept such a lopsided settlement. Certainly, no one should think for even a moment that Congress will put its stamp of approval on such an outrageously inadequate plan,&quot; Kennedy said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
