<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="538037" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Westinghouse loss narrows in quarter.</title>
<headline>Westinghouse loss narrows in quarter.</headline>
<byline>Kerri Selland</byline>
<dateline>PITTSBURGH 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Westinghouse Electric Corp. said Friday its losses narrowed in the first quarter as the company's robust CBS Radio group helped offset weakness at its television and industrial businesses.</p>
<p>The company said it lost $151 million, or 23 cents a share, in the quarter, compared with a loss of $181 million, or 41 cents a share, in the 1996 period. Excluding one-time items, the year-earlier loss was $114 million, or 26 cents a share.</p>
<p>Including Infinity Broadcasting, acquired at the end of last year, sales rose 18 percent to $2.2 billion.</p>
<p>Infinity's contribution to earnings was offset by weakness at the company's television network, caused by poor ratings and the way it had to account for program rights.</p>
<p>Westinghouse's media group earned $110 million before interest, taxes and other items, unchanged from the 1996 period.</p>
<p>Sales at CBS Radio surged 18 percent, far outperforming the overall industry. Pretax earnings soared 38 percent to $91 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Radio was spectacular, and I think that reflects strong management and superb assets,&quot; said analyst John Reidy at Smith Barney. &quot;They significantly outperformed the industry by three or four percentage points in terms of revenues.&quot;</p>
<p>At the CBS TV network, earnings fell due to lower audience levels in key demographic categories and higher costs associated with sports and special events.</p>
<p>Television revenues slid 4 percent on a same-station basis. Last year's first-quarter results got a boost from political advertising ahead of the 1996 elections.</p>
<p>Earnings fell at Westinghouse's other media businesses, which include Eyemark and CBS Cable -- formerly Group W Satellite Communications.</p>
<p>The industrial businesses lost $59 million, compared with a $1 million loss excluding special charges in the year-ago period. About $50 million of the loss in the latest period was from re-evaluation of a global energy project, it said.</p>
<p>Operating losses at Power Systems, which includes Power Generation and Energy Systems, grew due to delays in international project closings. Year-ago earnings were also boosted by a large nuclear fuel reload order.</p>
<p>Operating profit at Thermo King, a refrigerated transport unit, grew 4 percent. Westinghouse said profits were enhanced by last year's European acquisitions, lower material costs and greater productivity. Orders rose 5 percent due to a large container order and strong service parts business.</p>
<p>Westinghouse stock fell 62.5 cents to $17.25 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PITTSBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
