<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="538259" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Motorola to expand Land Mobile products plant.</title>
<headline>Motorola to expand Land Mobile products plant.</headline>
<dateline>PLANTATION, Fla. 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Motorola Inc said Friday its Land Mobile Products Sector will build a 250,000-square-foot expansion to its existing 615,000-square-foot facility here.</p>
<p>Motorola, based in Schaumburg, Ill., said the expansion will allow it to consolidate a number of off-site Land Mobile operations in the area. It also will provide additional manufacturing and administrative space to meet growing worldwide demand for Motorola two-way radio products.</p>
<p>As a part of the expansion, Motorola plans to add more than 250 jobs by the end of 1998.  </p>
<p>Motorola said construction is scheduled to begin in June and conclude in the third quarter of 1998. A child care and learning center and a wellness center for Motorola employees will be built on the campus.</p>
<p>&quot;This expansion highlights the growing importance of the Plantation facility in serving our two-way radio customers around the world,&quot; Leif Soderberg, corporate vice president and general manager of Motorola's Radio Products Americas Group, said in a statement.</p>
<p>A variety of digital and analog two-way radios, including iDEN phones, MTS 200O portables, HT1OOO portables, MT1000/MT 200O portables, and ASTRO radios, are manufactured at the Plantation facility.</p>
<p>Proximity to customers also was a very important factor in the decisoin to expand at Plantation. Motorola said the facility is headquarters to the sector's Radio Products Americas Group, which provides two-way radio products to users in the growing market of Latin America as well as the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PLANTATION, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
