<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53834" id="root" date="1996-09-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: CME decision will lure more funds to Taiwan--analysts.</title>
<headline>CME decision will lure more funds to Taiwan--analysts.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-09-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>A decision by Chicago Mercantile Exchange to list futures and options based on the Dow Jones Taiwan Stock Index will attract more foreign funds to Taiwan's stock market, analysts said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Dow Jones said on Thursday that it had licensed CME to list the products,</p>
<p>&quot;With the ability to trade futures and options, more foreign investors will naturally become more interested in the Taiwan stock market, and it will gain more exposure as a result,&quot; said Lin Long-hsien, securities analyst for United Securities.</p>
<p>Dow Jones Taiwan Stock Index is a capitalisation-weighted, broad-based index of 113 of the largest stocks trade on Taiwan Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>CME has said it would add the new products to its Growth and Emerging Markets division but has not set a launch date.</p>
<p>Wang Jieh, an analyst at Foremost Investment, said an increase in foreign investment interest likely would lead to more stable trading in a market currently prone to wild fluctuations.</p>
<p>&quot;The more investors there are in a market, the more stable it should be as the index becomes less likely to be influenced sharply by only a few speculators,&quot; Wang said.</p>
<p>To date this year Taiwan's index has swung between a low of 4,672.67 points and a high of 6,624.69. It closed at 6,464.55 on Saturday.</p>
<p>Despite the emergence of an apparent bull trend, analysts warned that Taiwan's market may become over-dependent on foreign investments, especially if the Securities and Exchange Commission continues to bar domestic derivatives trade.</p>
<p>&quot;If foreigners are allowed to hedge their investments and domestic investors are not, then there is the danger of the market falling too much into the control of foreign hands,&quot; Wang said.</p>
<p>Taiwan currently allows foreign funds to own up to 20 percent of the stock market's total equity. The government has said it would gradually raise the limit.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
