<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="538467" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Closing stock market indices.</title>
<headline>Closing stock market indices.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here is how major stock markets outside the United States ended on Friday.</p>
<p>LONDON - Shares ended lower as pre-election nerves and the possibility of a near-term interest rate rise combined with a weaker opening on Wall Street to halt an eight-day rally in blue chips. The FTSE 100 index of leading shares finished 18.8 points lower at 4,369.7 for a net gain of 59.2 points on the week.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Shares extended their losses in late trade as traders took profits ahead of the weekend and amid concerns about a possible U.S. interest rate hike next month. The 30-share IBIS DAX index dropped 1.1 percent, or 38.92 points to end the day at 3,357.57 points. The DAX index earlier ended bourse trade down 23.26 points at 3,374.10 points, up 29.71 on the week.</p>
<p>PARIS - Stocks finished slightly lower amid political jitters triggered by a poll suggesting a close race between the Socialists and Conservatives in upcoming parliamentary elections. The blue-chip CAC-40 index finished down 3.57 points, or 0.14 percent, at 2,536.26, down 11.30 from Friday week.</p>
<p>ZURICH - Shares left record territory and closed 1.32 percent lower on the Swiss Market Index. Traders said prices were pushed down by a somewhat lower dollar, Wall Street's weak opening and some special situations. The blue-chip SMI dropped 63.6 points at 4,772.5. The all-share SPI lost 26.56 points or 0.87 percent at 3,024.62. This was up 55.4 on the week.</p>
<p>TOKYO - Stocks ended slightly lower as investors squared positions ahead of the weekend. News that Nissan Mutual Life Insurance Co had been ordered to halt its business by the Finance Ministry had a mild impact on the market. The Nikkei average closed 85.21 points or 0.46 percent lower at 18,612.86, a rise of 260.72 points from seven days ago.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Stocks slid in late trade to close lower on heavy turnover as more investors abandoned blue chips in favour of the red-chip sector. The Hang Seng Index closed 81.07 points or 0.64 percent lower at 12,645.76, rising 104.58 on the week.</p>
<p>SYDNEY - The stock market was closed for the ANZAC Day public holiday. On Thursday, the All Ordinaries index closed up 2.4 points at 2,474.7, up 32.3 from last Friday.</p>
<p>JOHANNESBURG - Shares finished the week down, but hectic trade saw the bourse post a new record in terms of turnover and stocks were seen moving firmly into next week. The all-share index ended off 15.9 points at 7,072.0, up 49.8 from last week and industrials lost 19.4 points to 8,406.0, a rise of 89.7 from the previous Friday. Gold shares ended up 4.5 points to 1,235.0 a drop of 12.3 from last week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
