<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="538447" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products end mixed as holidays dampen trade.</title>
<headline>Med oil products end mixed as holidays dampen trade.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediterranean oil products ended mixed on Friday, with trade limited by public holidays in a number of countries including Italy and Portugal.</p>
<p>In the gas oil market attention was riveted on the ever-narrowing arbitrage to Asia, with some wary traders taking a safe view of sitting on the sidelines. The arb appears open by $2 or so, but difficulty in finding tankers could pressure prices lower, traders said.</p>
<p>So far Russian and Italian 0.2 pct cargoes have held onto levels between high fob quotes +$3.50-4.00. Diesel retained strength on tight supplies around fob high EN590 quotes +$2-3.</p>
<p>Med fuel oil prices were steady, although discussion was limited by the regional holidays.</p>
<p>Recent activity has limited the high sulphur cargoes showing available but dealers appeared relaxed, anticipating fresh supplies over the horizon.</p>
<p>Dealers reported demand for bunker spec material in Gibraltar, Spain and the Canary Islands.</p>
<p>Traders were watching for one large cargo to head towards Asia, with some worrying that dramatic product demand in Singapore might collapse, with unpleasant consequences in their home region.</p>
<p>Gasoline was steady as the absence of a number of players dampened trade.</p>
<p>The market was assessed as fairly balanced due to the fact that many players had sought to cover their requirements ahead of the holiday period.</p>
<p>Naphtha was slightly stronger, but the market continued to monitor the double stem loading issue out of Skikda in case the suspension on larger cargoes led to a rise in cargoes being offered into the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>&quot;We won't know until Monday what their decision is,&quot; one trader said. -- London Newsroom, +44 171 542 7714.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
