<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="538521" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada brokers asked to keep Bre-X tapes.</title>
<headline>Canada brokers asked to keep Bre-X tapes.</headline>
<byline>Paul Casciato</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian investment dealers said on Friday that a lobby group's search for taped conversations between dealers and investors about troubled Bre-X Minerals Ltd may be fruitless.</p>
<p>A public interest group representing over 100 Bre-X shareholders said on Friday it has sent letters to several investment dealers urging them to retain tapes of conversations between their employees and clients regarding Bre-X.</p>
<p>Dermod Travis, spokesman for Public Interest Research Associates, said some shareholders fear they may have been misled by their brokers during the sale or purchase of Bre-X shares.</p>
<p>&quot;There is sufficient anectodal information to us in those interviews to have reason to believe that those tape recordings may in fact be pertinent to a variety of issues that will need to be heard,&quot; Travis said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;That could be litigation. It could be litigation against their broker if necessary. It could also simply be a complaint to the IDA (Investment Dealers Association) regarding the behavior of their broker and or the brokerage house,&quot; Travis said.</p>
<p>The IDA, the brokerage industry's self-regulatory body, said on Friday that there are likely no tapes to be saved.</p>
<p>&quot;IDA member firms do not tape conversations at the retail level,&quot; said Sandy Grant, senior vice president of finance and administration for the IDA. &quot;Bre-X shareholders are all retail shareholders,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the only members that might tape retail investors calling up to purchase or sell Bre-X shares would be discount brokers.</p>
<p>&quot;The only members that you might ever see tape (retail trades) are maybe some of the discount brokers because they don't give advice at all,&quot; Grant said.</p>
<p>Some dealers who had received letters from the group said on Friday that they did not tape the conversations of their retail investors and would not keep the tapes if they did.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not tape conversations with our retail clients,&quot; said Martha Durdin, vice president of corporate communications for the Bank of Montreal, which owns investment dealer, Nesbitt Burns.</p>
<p>A Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce spokesman said the bank's retail investment arm is reviewing its tapes and will retain any information it finds on Bre-X conversations.</p>
<p>&quot;What has happened is that CIBC has contacted the Investment Dealers Association...and provided them some assurance that if we find any records that might be relevant we will retain them,&quot; said CIBC spokesman Paul Howard.</p>
<p>Bre-X Minerals became a darling of the Toronto Stock Exchange after its shares skyrocketed from pennies to highs of nearly C$28 a share following its discovery of the Busang deposit, heralded as the century's biggest gold find.</p>
<p>But panic selling of Bre-X shares lopped nearly C$3 billion from the company's stock market value last month when Busang partner Freeport-McMoRan Copper and Gold Inc said its preliminary tests found &quot;insignificant&quot; amounts of gold.</p>
<p>Since then investors have anxiously awaited results of an independent audit by Strathcona Mineral Services Ltd which are expected late next week.</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
