<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53854" id="root" date="1996-09-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US West Coast crudes slide late with NYMEX, diffs.</title>
<headline>US West Coast crudes slide late with NYMEX, diffs.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast light crude prices slid late Friday, tracking a slump in NYMEX prices and falling differentials for Alaska North Slope.</p>
<p>Outright prices for ANS crude dipped 60 cents below Thursday levels to $22.05/22.35 a barrel. WTI fell on news that Iraq would suspend strikes against U.S. warplanes patrolling &quot;no-fly zones.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders reacted cautiously to news late Friday that the U.S. would send 5,000 troops to Kuwait as part of a build-up in the Persian Gulf. They will join 1,200 troops stationed there since August.  </p>
<p>&quot;Most traders went home (Friday) thinking the situation had been diffused,&quot; one after-hours trader said. &quot;But that's the thinking we all had a week ago.&quot;</p>
<p>Light grades in California were poised for further falls late, after BP, a major ANS producer, lowered its sale price by five cents Thursday.</p>
<p>BP sold a full cargo to Chevron Thursday at $2.30 a barrel under October WTI.</p>
<p>And news of crowded storage tanks at the Port of Valdez prompted the Trans-Alaska pipeline to slow throughput by 30 percent early Thursday, traders said.</p>
<p>Another light grade, Line 63, saw its discounts unchanged at WTI minus $2.60/2.50 a barrel.</p>
<p>Prenominations are due to start mid-week and outright values for the grade were $21.85/22.05, down about 40 cents from Thursday.</p>
<p>California heavy grades were flat late after rising Thursday on increased posted prices.</p>
<p>Discounts for Kern River were 50/25 cents under postings, with supplies seen tightening as refineries ran more of the grades.</p>
<p>Greater consumption of heavies came after recent posted prices changes pushed up light grades more steeply than heavies, making the grade more appealing to buy.</p>
<p>Kern River values ranged $15.60/15.90 a barrel, compared to light grade levels in the low $20s.</p>
<p>Values for Wilmington were $17.40/17.50.</p>
<p>-- David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau, +1 213 380 2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
