<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="538519" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada Liberals head for majority, new polls show.</title>
<headline>Canada Liberals head for majority, new polls show.</headline>
<byline>Randall Palmer</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian Prime Minister Jean Chretien's Liberals prepared for a federal election campaign on Friday with polls showing them far enough ahead to assure them another majority government if voting trends held.</p>
<p>A poll by Gallup Canada put the Liberals ahead of all others combined at 55 percent of decided voters, 40 points ahead of the nearest competitor.</p>
<p>Chretien has laid the groundwork to announce his election call in Ottawa on Sunday for June 2 and fly to his hometown of Shawinigan, Quebec, for a rally that night -- and was busy this week making speeches that sounded very campaign-like.</p>
<p>&quot;The election call will be Sunday,&quot; a government official confirmed.</p>
<p>Another survey published on Friday gave the Liberals a margin of nearly 30 points. It was done by Ekos Research Associates between March 18 and April 9 showed the Liberals backed by 41.7 percent of voters versus 12.2 percent for the second-place Conservatives.</p>
<p>It was based on interviews with 1,535 people from a panel of 3,000 randomly selected to participate in a project financed by some federal government departments, provincial governments and the private sector. The survey did not give a margin of error.</p>
<p>The Gallup poll, conducted from April 10-16, carried a margin of error of 3.1 percentage points 19 times out of 20.</p>
<p>It put the Conservatives at 15 percent, the separatist Bloc Quebecois at 11 percent, the right-wing Reform at 10 percent and the leftist New Democratic Party (NDP) at 9 percent.</p>
<p>This marked a switch of three points to the Liberals from the Conservatives since the last Gallup poll a month earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;Jean Chretien's federal Liberals continue to hold a comfortable lead in the hearts and minds of Canadian voters,&quot; the polling organisation said.</p>
<p>In 1993 Chretien swept to 177 of the 295 seats in the House of Commons, and Gallup said he should get another majority if these numbers held until voting day.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, 35 percent of Canadian voters remained undecided, giving some room for play for the opposition.</p>
<p>The Ekos survey put Reform at 10.6 percent of respondents, followed by the Bloc at 8 percent and NDP at 6.5 percent.</p>
<p>The polls do not tell the whole story, since the strength of the Bloc and Reform are concentrated in Quebec and the West respectively, enabling them to hope once again for a plurality in a substantial number of seats as in 1993.</p>
<p>A Groupe Leger and Leger poll, commissioned by Toronto's Globe and Mail and Le Journal de Montreal, found the Liberals doing better than a month earlier but still trailing the Bloc among decided voters at 36.9 percent to 43.1 percent.</p>
<p>Chretien, who has presided over some of the toughest budget cuts in Canadian history, gave a good-news speech on Friday in Toronto that hinted of new spending.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we can say that the light of the tunnel is getting brighter and brighter. This means that we can do more now than just make tough choices on what to cut,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Jean Charest, leader of the once-mighty Conservatives, said Chretien's speech was &quot;empty of fresh ideas.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;On the eve of a federal election call, Canadians expected to hear much more from the government. He passed up a golden opportunity to provide hope and to tell us what his party stands for,&quot; Charest said in a statement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
