<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="538778" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania must restore public order to woo investors.</title>
<headline>Albania must restore public order to woo investors.</headline>
<byline>David Brough</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania needs to restore public order and implement legal reforms urgently in order to recover from an armed insurrection and attract much-needed foreign investment, lawyers and officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Albania must restore public order as a priority in order to bring back foreign investment,&quot; said Mark Erhart of Claes &amp; Tonucci, an international law firm with an office in Tirana.</p>
<p>&quot;Albania needs to continue working on its financial legislation to create a transparent legal framework,&quot; added Erhart, whose company has advised the Albanian government on harmonising its legislation with the European Union.</p>
<p>Albanians staged a rebellion in late February following the collapse of dubious &quot;pyramid&quot; investment schemes in which many had invested their life savings. More than 300 people have been killed in the violence.</p>
<p>Despite the high number of armed police and checkpoints across the Balkan state, enforcement of the law is sketchy and violent incidents involving armed gangs are commonplace.</p>
<p>Justice Minister Spartak Ngjela told Reuters in an interview this month that Albanians did not trust the courts. Six of the 36 court buildings were completely destroyed and another five badly damaged in the violence.</p>
<p>Parliament banned the pyramid schemes in January, but lawyers said that legal loopholes had to be eliminated so that the bogus savings plans could not resurface.</p>
<p>Martin Day, a London-based lawyer seeking to advise Albanians on legal reform, said: &quot;Enforcing legal reforms is vital in order to prevent Albanians from losing their savings.&quot;</p>
<p>Rebel committees which reject the authority of President Sali Berisha have seized control of much of the south. The rebels blame Berisha for the collapse of the pyramid schemes.</p>
<p>Following talks between the all-party government and the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), Albania expects to hold general elections on June 29.</p>
<p>If Albania can resolve its political problems and develop its legislation, it will seek to attract foreign investors, notably in infrastructure projects and tourism.</p>
<p>&quot;If international investors see that positive reforms are being implemented, they will look at Albania again,&quot; Erhart said. &quot;In the longer term, Albania has fantastic potential for investment in tourism. Its biggest challenge is its lack of infrastructure.&quot;</p>
<p>Albania offers tourists a sunny climate, sandy beaches and spectacular, unspoiled mountain scenery, but roads are in appalling condition, and water supplies and the telephone system need to be upgraded.</p>
<p>The low presence of foreign investors today is a holdover from nearly half a century of isolation under Stalinist rule. A large Coca Cola bottling plant operates near Tirana. Some foreign oil companies and hotels have invested in Albania.</p>
<p>Italy, Albania's biggest foreign investor and trading partner, has already created hundreds of thousands of jobs in light industry, textiles and shoes, officials say.</p>
<p>Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi said this week that Italy aimed to organise a conference of donors attended by the World Bank, the International Monetary Fund, European experts and Albanian authorities to discuss economic aid for Albania. No date has yet been set.</p>
<p>Prodi also called for the creation of an international coordination group to work with Albanian authorities to rebuild the judicial, banking and school systems.</p>
<p>Italy is leading an eight-nation security force deploying in Albania to protect aid deliveries to the needy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
