<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="538718" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks dive, market to remain sleepy.</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks dive, market to remain sleepy.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks took a dive in lacklustre trade on Friday as big buyers stayed away from the market and traders said the lull would extend well into next week.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is listless and asleep. It seems to be lacking inspiration,&quot; one trader at the Metroholding brokerage said.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign buyers may be absent... This is a sensitive market and two stronger investors can easily influence the price trend,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Analysts foresaw scarce market activity for next week, due to a national holiday on May 1.</p>
<p>&quot;Many traders are bound to close shop earlier. I just can't see any active trading on Tuesday and Wednesday,&quot; an analyst at the big brokerage said, adding he expected a general market recovery sometime before summer.</p>
<p>Eleven of 18 active isssues fell, three rose and four were flat. Turnover was halved at 1.5 million kuna, volume fell to 3,640 shares from 6,852.</p>
<p>Drugs firm Pliva edged down four kuna to 476, with 688 units sold. Zagrebacka Banka lost 15 kuna to 2,200 on a meagre volume of 13 shares.</p>
<p>Analysts said there was still room for growth of the two fully-listed stocks, especially for Zagrebacka which plans to issue bonds in May.</p>
<p>Only Varazdinska Banka of the three fully-listed issues bucked the downward trend, climbing 1,000 kuna to 44,000 but selling only four shares.</p>
<p>Top gainer was Zagreb's Intercontinental hotel, up five kuna or 3.03 percent to 270 kuna, with 100 units sold.</p>
<p>Leading decliner cable maker Elka lost 19 kuna or 12.67 percent to 131 kuna, with 155 shares changing hands.</p>
<p>Confectioner Kras tumbled 25 kuna to 415 on volume of 288 units.</p>
<p>&quot;News that Kras is definitely listed for voucher privatisation negatively affected its price. This diminished hopes its shares would be floated abroad,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Most active food processor Podravka inched down 0.50 kuna to 305 on volume of 1,462 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Podravka won't see real trading before it releases annual results in May...The rumour is that they are not great, so its price has not been rising,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
