<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="538971" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUATEMALA: World Bank optimistic on Guatemalan economy.</title>
<headline>World Bank optimistic on Guatemalan economy.</headline>
<dateline>GUATEMALA CITY 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The World Bank expects Guatemala's economy to grow four to 4.5 percent this year and to maintain an inflation rate of around 10 percent, a bank representative said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;According to the first quarter results there is no reason to believe that the government will not be able to reach its macroeconomic goals for 1997,&quot; said Jose Roberto Lopez, the World Bank resident representative in Guatemala.</p>
<p>The Guatemalan government has previously set 1997 targets of 4.0 to 4.5 percent growth and 10 percent inflation.</p>
<p>Lopez said positive first quarter indicators include an increase in international reserves of $100 million as well as strong growth in exports and imports during the first quarter.</p>
<p>Guatemala's central bank reported this week that first quarter 1997 exports rose 45 percent over the same 1996 period.</p>
<p>&quot;We also understand that the government is making efforts to reach its fiscal goals,&quot; Lopez said.</p>
<p>According to Lopez, sustained growth would depend on increased consumer credit and a reduction in Guatemala's high interest rates.</p>
<p>He warned that the government should correct volatile interest rates, the too-wide 5-10 percent spread between active and passive interest rates, and slow growth in consumer credit.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest rates continue to be a worrying element because for the private sector to be able to invest it needs clear and stable rules and this means a lowering trend in interest rates should be maintained,&quot; Lopez said.</p>
<p>Average bank interest rates for consumer loans varied between 20 to 30 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Lopez announced on Thursday a $33 million World Bank loan for Guatemala's Education Ministry.</p>
<p>The World Bank loaned Guatemala $60 million in 1996. The institution has promised to make loans of $100 million each year from 1997-1999 to help the country implement peace accords signed in December, which ended 36 years of civil war.</p>
<p>The new loan funds will go for primary schools in rural and poor areas, improving the quality of teaching in rural schools and institutional support for the ministry, Lopez said.</p>
<p>((--Fiona Ortiz, Guatemala City bureau +502 251-5718))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUATEMALA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUATEMALA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
