<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="538942" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Analysts' views on lower Brazil financial taxes.</title>
<headline>Analysts' views on lower Brazil financial taxes.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are comments from economists and traders on Brazil's decision to cut financial transaction taxes on foreign investment in the country.</p>
<p>JOSE MONFORTE, capital markets director at Citibank: &quot;The move is a way to boost the inflow of foreign capital. They want to bring more capital into the country.&quot;</p>
<p>Monforte said Brazilian officials were particularly concerned about attracting more foreign investment following last month's hike in short term U.S. interest rates and Brazil's mounting current account deficit, which is financed by dollar inflows.  </p>
<p>ALCINDO FERREIRA, former Central Bank official and consultant at Trend Analise: &quot;This is a measure that is aimed at creating a comfortable level of reserves to be ready for whatever might happen in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;It helps businesses finance abroad at extremely attractive costs in addition to boosting reserves,&quot; Ferreira said.</p>
<p>He added that the cutting of financial taxes showed the Central Bank was definitely anticipating further increases in international interest rates.  </p>
<p>MARKET REACTION: The new taxes were expected to have no impact on foreign investment in the stock market because taxes on equity investments remained unchanged at zero percent.</p>
<p>But they were expected to draw more foreign flows to the floating interbank market, which was mostly used to send money out of the country rather than bring it in. The tax on transactions in the floating interbank market fell to two percent from seven percent.</p>
<p>&quot;This means the government is lifting all barriers to the entry of foreign capital, including short-term flows. Before it was more selective,&quot; said one forex trader.  </p>
<p>The elimination of taxes on borrowing abroad, including all Eurobond maturities, was seen boosting new issuance slightly, especially for small firms.</p>
<p>Before, Eurobonds with three-year maturities were levied a three percent tax, four-year bonds were taxed two percent and five-year bonds paid a one percent tax.</p>
<p>&quot;For the issuer, it is much better because they don't have to worry about any taxes now. We should see some new supply but it won't be too significant,&quot; said a Eurobond trader in Sao Paulo.</p>
<p>The tax ceiling for Eurobond issues has fallen from five percent to three percent to zero percent over the past year, traders said.</p>
<p>((--John Miller, Sao Paulo newsroom, 5511 248-5414))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
