<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539012" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Bankers see limited Thai rate cut ahead.</title>
<headline>Bankers see limited Thai rate cut ahead.</headline>
<byline>Anchalee Koetsawang</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A strong signal from the Bank of Thailand on Friday that it may allow current high rates to ease could result in a fall of 50-100 basis points this year, bankers and analysts said.</p>
<p>But any cuts would not likely be large enough to help revive Thailand's sluggish economy, wracked by turmoil in the financial sector, they told Reuters.</p>
<p>Thailand has some of the highest rates in the region with the minimum lending rate averaging around 13.25 percent.</p>
<p>The central bank has kept interest rates high to attract foreign funds to finance its current account deficit and to defend the baht against speculative attacks.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan has pressed for interest rates to come down to boost the slowing economy.</p>
<p>And Bank of Thailand Governor Rerngchai Marakanon said on Friday there was a possibility of rates easing as interbank rates in the money market were more stable and pressure on the external balance had eased.</p>
<p>His statement followed the release of monthly data that indicated the economy was flagging further but the current account and trade deficits had improved with the slowdown in the economy and a plunge in imports.</p>
<p>Bankers said the rising cost of funds for Thai borrowers after Moody's downgrade of the nation's credit ratings, uncertainties facing the weakened baht and a need for external savings to finance the current account gap were among constraints limiting any rate cut.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation seems to indicate a trend toward the reduction of interest rates. But the rates are unlikely to drop more than 100 points,&quot; Nimit Nontapunthawat, executive vice president of Bangkok Bank told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;And that rate would only be enough to relieve but not revive the economy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A hundred basis points equals one percentage point.</p>
<p>Overnight interbank rates have stabilised at around eight percent since the beginning of this month after swinging up wildly in March when the authorities revamped the troubled financial sector.</p>
<p>But Rerngchai made it clear he was not willing to allow interbank rates to drop below the current level as the country still needed to induce foreign inflows.</p>
<p>&quot;That is a major constraint which will limit the room for the cuts,&quot; said Supavud Saicheua, an executive at Phatra Thnakit Plc, one of Thailand's largest finance firms.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the pattern of correlation between the interbank rate and lending rate, you can see that the spread between the two stands at four to 4.5 percent over the past four or five years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the interbank rate will not be lower than eight percent, the lending rate drop will not reach 100 basis points,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some bankers expressed doubt that the interest rate cuts could substantially spur growth.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if the rate eventually goes down, the economic slowdown will force commercial banks to be selective in lending anyway,&quot; said an executive at Thai Farmers Bank.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
