<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539075" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: FOCUS-Manila shares seen regressing further.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Manila shares seen regressing further.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine shares dipped at the close on Friday in a session marred by heavy foreign selling and analysts said the negative sentiment on the property and banking sectors is likely to prevail next week.</p>
<p>&quot;More and more foreign investors are jumping into the bandwagon that says the property sector remains vulnerable,&quot; said Raul Ruiz, vice-president at Sun Hung Kai Securities.</p>
<p>Fears the property sector will follow Thailand's property slump that had an adverse effect on their banking sector have been sending local property and banking stocks tumbling.</p>
<p>Industry and government officials including President Fidel Ramos have said the Philippine property sector was not headed for a crash.</p>
<p>Leading the losers on Friday were Empire East Land Holdings Inc and its parent Megaworld Properties &amp; Holdings Inc.</p>
<p>The announcement by Empire East of a buy back of its own shares lifted the stock in mid-session but failed to sustain the gains at close.</p>
<p>The most heavily traded issue for the day, Empire, finished 60 centavos lower at 5.20 pesos while its parent Megaworld shed 30 centavos to 5.40 pesos.</p>
<p>The market also saw a sell-off of mobile phone company Pilipino Telephone Corp due to poor first quarter earnings result.</p>
<p>Value turnover was moderate at 2.3 billion pesos.</p>
<p>&quot;The mood is still very much on the selling side. Comparison of the property market with Thailand is exerting a huge impact on sentiment,&quot; said Nathan Lozada, assistant vice-president at Philippine Asia Equity Securities.</p>
<p>Sun Hung Kai's Ruiz said the release of blue chip Philippine Long Distance Telephone Co's (PLDT) first quarter earnings on Monday, if above expectations, would cheer an otherwise dull market.</p>
<p>&quot;The index will likely move sideways while waiting for further corporate results. We will also follow the Dow's pace,&quot; said Leila Calderon, senior investment analyst at Asian Capital Equities.</p>
<p>The main index will likely trade within the 2,850 to 2,990 band, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;We look forward to first quarter profits of food and telecommunications companies to save this dull market,&quot; All Asia Securities research head Helen Alvarez said.</p>
<p>-- KATHERINE ESPINA (63 2) 841-8939 Fax 817-6267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
