<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539088" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: N.Korea told ending secrecy would help cause.</title>
<headline>N.Korea told ending secrecy would help cause.</headline>
<byline>Paul Eckert</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of a U.S. humanitarian group said on Friday he urged North Korean officials during a tour of the secretive communist state this week to remove obstacles to raising and sending more food, which he said was urgently needed to save thousands of children.</p>
<p>&quot;The North Korean government has -- maybe not intentionally, but unintentionally -- made it difficult for everybody,&quot; said Dean Hirsch, president of World Vision International, a Christian charity which has worked in North Korea since 1995.</p>
<p>Hirsch, who toured districts near the capital of Pyongyang this week, said he told the North Koreans their secrecy made it harder for humanitarian groups to solicit food donations.</p>
<p>He said he told senior Pyongyang officials: &quot;You are making my work extremely difficult by not allowing the press in. You can't say there's a need and then not share (information).&quot;</p>
<p>Hirsch said his hosts appeared to take his advice seriously and said North Korea would cooperate with the United Nations on nutrition surveys. But he said he was not allowed to visit the north of the country, which was hardest hit by floods which wiped out crops for two consecutive years.</p>
<p>Tours of two rural counties near the capital, however, convinced him that time was running out for thousands of hungry children, now scraping by on a diet of 100 grams of rice a day.</p>
<p>&quot;It is only 90 days until starvation in North Korea,&quot; Hirsch told a news conference in Tokyo.</p>
<p>&quot;If massive food aid does not reach them before the end of July, hundreds of thousands of Korean children are possibly and likely to die of disease because their little bodies are so weakened by malnutrition,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>That assessment was based on what Hirsch called &quot;beginning signs of malnutrition&quot;, such as a prevalence of tell-tale illnesses in children, and on North Korean reports of near-zero food stocks as it awaits the harvest of an early barley crop.</p>
<p>&quot;North Korea is in a pre-famine condition. It will escalate very quickly,&quot; he said, because seed crops have been consumed and many people are too weak to work the fields.</p>
<p>At Kumchon County Nursery, a pre-school facility Hirsch visited outside Pyongyang, only 29 children were present out of an enrollment of 135, with the rest of the children too weak or hungry to attend, he said.</p>
<p>Repeated international appeals for food aid to the world's last Stalinist state -- the latest being a U.N. World Food Programme appeal for $95.5 million -- have drawn only a lukewarm response.</p>
<p>Washington pledged $25 million, and Seoul $6 million, in response to the appeal, but other potential donors have held back aid for factors including fears the food aid will go to Pyongyang's military.</p>
<p>Japan said this week Tokyo may not give food aid to North Korea because of a big drug seizure aboard a North Korean freighter and suspicions over Japanese nationals allegedly kidnapped by North Korean agents in the late 1970s and 1980s.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto sounded negative when asked about Japan's aid plans during a flight to Washington for talks with President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>&quot;If North Korea wants humanitarian aid, they should be humane to Japan first,&quot; Hashimoto said.</p>
<p>The United States has taken pains to separate aid from the issue of North Korea's joining peace talks with Seoul, Beijing and Washington to close the books on the 1950-53 Korean War.</p>
<p>But Pyongyang, during tortuous negotiations in New York last week, demanded large-scale food aid and other U.S. concessions in connection with the four-party peace talks.</p>
<p>North Korean media on Thursday said Washington and its allies had &quot;a sinister intention to use the humanitarian issue of food assistance for their political purposes, (to) disarm North Korea and overthrow our socialist system.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
