<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539228" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks fall as caution reigns ahead of key data.</title>
<headline>Stocks fall as caution reigns ahead of key data.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks fell sharply on Friday, as investors braced for a series of economic reports next week that are likely to clarify the outlook for interest rates.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average closed down 53.38 points, or 0.8 percent, to 6,738.87, after sliding more than 60 points earlier in light trading.</p>
<p>The Dow's drop trimmed its gain to 35.32 points for the week, as blue chips dipped in each of the three sessions after jumping 173 points on Tuesday in the 30-stock index's second-largest point gain ever.</p>
<p>In the broader market, declining issues outnumbered gainers by 1,658 to 795 on volume of 414 million the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically, attention is focused on next week,&quot; said Jack Shaughnessy, director of research at Advest, &quot;and next week is truly going to be hell week.&quot;</p>
<p>Investors appeared increasingly reluctant to bid up stocks just ahead of reports on employment and wages, gross domestic product, the National Association of Purchasing Management index and the Employment Cost Index, a key wage inflation gauge.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got a bushel basket of important economic data next week that will largely confirm whether or not (Fed) Chairman Greenspan will follow through with a second monetary tightening,&quot; said Phil Orlando, chief investment officer at Value Line Asset Management.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index fell 18.81 points to 1,209.29, down 13.28 on the week.</p>
<p>Bonds edged lower, with the 30-year Treasury down 4/32, or $1.25 on a $1,000 bond, raising its yield to 7.14 percent from Thursday's close of 7.13 percent. The price and yield move in opposite directions.</p>
<p>Analysts said the fact that investors were again focused on the economy and interest rates meant that stocks' brief bounce, which was inspired by strong quarterly earnings, may be over.</p>
<p>&quot;Earnings have been a plus on balance,&quot; said Greg Nie, technical analyst at Everen Securities. &quot;I'd rather be in a market paying attention to earnings than interest rates.&quot;</p>
<p>The result is likely to be a market that resumes a jagged sideways pattern, they said, with little chance of near-term advances unless there is a clear signal that economic growth is moderating.</p>
<p>Indeed, some on Wall Street argue that even with such a signal, investors are going to have to contend with rising interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;It's our belief that Greenspan has made up his mind to give us three 25 basis point (quarter percentage point) tightenings,&quot; Orlando said. &quot;We don't believe he'll see anything in next week's numbers that will dissuade him.&quot;</p>
<p>The Fed last month raised the federal funds rate, which banks charge each other for short-term loans, by one-quarter of a percentage point in a preemptive strike against inflation.</p>
<p>Analysts widely believe the central bank will raise rates again at the next meeting of its policy-setting arm, the Federal Open Market Committee, in May or its subsequent meeting in July.</p>
<p>The broad trend in corporate earnings remained favourable through the week, with 62 percent of the 385 Standard &amp; Poor's 500 companies that reported earnings before April 24 exceeding Wall Street expectations, according to data provided by I/B/E/S.</p>
<p>Tobacco stocks slumped after a federal judge ruled the Food and Drug Administration had the authority to regulate the sales and labeling of cigarettes. Analysts said the ruling may add to tobacco companies potential costs to settle massive class action litigation.</p>
<p>Philip Morris Cos Inc. fell 2-1/8 to 39-1/2 and RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp. slid 2-3/4 to 28-7/8.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks fell 5.81 points to 765.37, down 0.97 on the week. The American Stock Exchange index edged down 1.12 to 542.83, off 13.18 from last Friday.</p>
<p>The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks fell 3.24 to 400.38. The NYSE Composite fell 3.24 to 400.38.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 7,216.508, off 68.388 or 0.94 percent. It fell 52.958 on the week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
