<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539297" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Missing truck, training missiles found in Texas.</title>
<headline>Missing truck, training missiles found in Texas.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A missing truck loaded with four training missiles was found in West Texas Friday and its driver was taken into custody by the FBI, the Air Force said.</p>
<p>The missiles, which were not equipped with explosive warheads, were found behind a supply store in Ranger, Texas, west of Dallas, Air Force spokesman Lou Timmons said.</p>
<p>&quot;The truck was found at a place called Ranger Supply. We believe the crates containing the missiles are still in place and intact,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The driver, Ronald Dean Coy, was arrested at the Flying J truck stop near Beaumont, east of Houston. Coy faces charges of theft of government property and theft of an interstate shipment and was taken to Atlanta for processing, he said.</p>
<p>The TGM-130 missiles, mock-ups of AGM-130 air-to-ground missiles, were being shipped from Duluth, Ga., to Cannon Air Force Base near Clovus, N.M., for use in Roving Sands '97, a joint tactical air operation that includes about 20,000 troops from the United States, Germany, Canada and The Netherlands.</p>
<p>Mounted on F-15 warplanes, the missiles could seek out targets but could not be fired. &quot;The four missiles never were a threat to anybody,&quot; Timmons said.</p>
<p>The missile shipment had been scheduled to arrive at Cannon AFB April 21, four days after Coy called base officials and said he had been delayed by mechanical problems.</p>
<p>The truck was one of two military shipments reported missing this week. Officials found a truck carrying mortars and machineguns for the military late Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
