<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539234" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</title>
<headline>Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain and oilseed exports reported by USDA and private export sources.</p>
<p>WHEAT SALES - South Korea's Daehan Flour Mills Co Ltd on Friday bought 21,000 tonnes of U.S. No.1 wheat from Japanese trading house Mitsubishi Corp, a Daehan Flour Mills official said. Shipment was set for June 5-July 5 to the western port of Inchon.</p>
<p>- Philippine firms bought 25,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat at an average price of $4.64 per bushel, Manila grains traders said. Traders also said they had received tender invitations for an additional 35,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat later Friday.  </p>
<p>OILSEED SALE - South Korea's National Livestock Cooperatives Federation on Friday bought a total of 21,500 tonnes of oilseeds in tenders, an official with the federation said. The federation bought 5,000 tonnes of palm kernel meal from Toepfer and another 10,000 tonnes from Nidera. The federation also bought 6,500 tonnes of Chinese cottonseed meal from LG International Corp at $166 a tonne C&amp;F, he said.</p>
<p>CORN TENDER - The Commodity Credit Corp of the U.S. Department of Agriculture said Friday it would tender on May 1 for up to 50,000 tonnes of U.S. corn for donation to North Korea. The corn is slated for May 10-30 shipment.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDERS - Pakistan is likely to tender next week for 330,000 tonnes of soft white wheat for May-June delivery, a trade source in Islamabad said on Friday.</p>
<p>The source said the tender, likely to be for wheat of optional origin, would be the first purchase in the new wheat crop year (May-April).</p>
<p>- Jordan was to tender May 1 for 120,000 tonnes of U.S. HRW and/or northern spring wheat for May/June.</p>
<p>SOYBEAN TENDER - CCC was tendering on April 30 for up to 10,000 tonnes of U.S. yellow soybeans for export to Ukraine, May 10-June 5 shipment.  </p>
<p>SOYMEAL TENDER - El Salvador is to tender April 28 for 8,000 to 10,000 tonnes of PL-480 soybean meal for May 7-22 shipment, the buyer's agent said.</p>
<p>COMMODITY TENDER - The Commodity Credit Corp of USDA said it will tender April 29 for pinto beans, sunflower oil, bulgur and wheat-soy blend for donation to Moldova. It seeks 255 tonnes of pinto beans, 605 tonnes of sunflower oil, 510 tonnes of bulgur (cracked wheat), and 255 tonnes of a wheat-soy blend. The beans, bulgur and wheat-soy blend were for June 6-20 shipment and the oil was for June 20-July 5.  </p>
<p>BARLEY TENDER - Turkey on April 29 seeks 150,000 tonnes of barley in three 50,000-tonne shipments. It seeks white feed and malting white barley for May 15-22, June 1-15 and June 1-15 shipment.</p>
<p>RICE TENDER - South Korea plans to hold on Friday an auction to sell 115,200 tonnes of rice to help stabilise domestic supply and ease domestic rice prices, Agriculture and Forestry Ministry officials said.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK - China appeared to have bought at least one cargo of U.S. soybeans and possibly two more on Thursday night, several U.S. exporters said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think at least one cargo has been confirmed&quot; for May/June delivery, one U.S. exporter said. The exporter said one cargo was about 50,000 to 55,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Regarding the other two cargoes, the exporter added, &quot;It was a pretty good guess it was done.&quot;</p>
<p>Soybean futures on the Chicago Board of Trade surged in fast dealings amid the talk about China, traders said.</p>
<p>((Doris Frankel 312-983-7305))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
