<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539392" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bargaining, concessions led to Clinton treaty win.</title>
<headline>Bargaining, concessions led to Clinton treaty win.</headline>
<byline>William Scally</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton's victory in winning Senate approval of the chemical weapons treaty was the product of many weeks of patient bargaining, significant concessions and a willingness to work with conservative Sen. Jesse Helms.</p>
<p>For Clinton and key senators of both parties the payoff on Thursday night was impressive: the treaty won seven more votes than the required two-thirds majority, with support from a majority of Republicans, and Democrats remained rock-solid throughout a series of six crucial votes.</p>
<p>The finale was in contrast to a long deadlock and an embarrassing administration retreat on the treaty last year.</p>
<p>Helms, a North Carolina Republican and chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee, who led conservative opposition to the Chemical Weapons Convention, found some solace in his defeat, listing a series of concessions made by the administration to get the treaty to the full Senate.</p>
<p>Helms and Delaware Democrat Joseph Biden spent scores of hours haggling over provisions that Helms wanted attached to Senate consent to ratification. The challenge for Biden was to placate Helms without torpedoing the treaty.</p>
<p>With administration concurrence, they agreed on 28 conditions relating to such concerns as cost, intelligence sharing, U.S. chemical war defences and protection of confidential business information.</p>
<p>&quot;Make no mistake, this is a dangerous treaty. But it is a little less dangerous thanks to the efforts we made to amend it and deliver the truth to the American people,&quot; Helms said in a statement. Five of his proposed conditions, including four that would have prevented ratification of the treaty, remained in dispute. All were rejected by the Senate.</p>
<p>Only hours before the votes, Clinton clinched the deal with a letter to Sen. Trent Lott paving the way for the Republican Leader to break with his fellow conservatives and reluctantly support a treaty he had previously opposed.</p>
<p>Clinton promised he would be prepared to withdraw from the treaty if two articles in it contributed to proliferation of poison gas or threatened U.S. security.</p>
<p>Lott, announcing his decision, emphasised significant concessions made by the administration outside of the treaty, although officials denied there was any direct linkage.</p>
<p>In concessions that could give it problems in the future, the administration agreed last month to submit to the Senate for its consent modifications to two earlier arms control agreements, something it had previously said it would not do.</p>
<p>The first is an agreement between Clinton and Russian President Boris Yeltsin on the kinds of short-range missile defences allowed by the 1972 Anti-Ballistic Missile Treaty. Republicans say they fear the accord would restrict U.S. anti-missile defences.</p>
<p>&quot;Along with many of my colleagues, I have expressed grave doubts about the wisdom of President Clinton's approach,&quot; Lott told the Senate.</p>
<p>The second agreement is a change in the treaty on Conventional Forces in Europe to adapt it to changed circumstances following the breakup of the Warsaw Pact and Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Lott also hailed progress in talks with the administration on reform of the United Nations and the administration's decision to reorganize the State Department. A Helms bill last year mandating a more sweeping reorganization led to a bitter confrontation with Democrats that was resolved only after months of deadlock that prevented any action by his committee on the chemical weapons treaty.</p>
<p>The treaty finally got to the Senate floor last September, only to be withdrawn at the administration's request when Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole came out against it, making its approval unlikely during a heated election season.</p>
<p>On Wednesday Dole reversed course and announced his support for the treaty at a White House ceremony.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
