<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539399" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Orange County bankruptcy trial enters final stage.</title>
<headline>Orange County bankruptcy trial enters final stage.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA ANA, Calif. 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jurors in the bankruptcy-related trial of former Orange County, Calif., assistant treasurer Matthew Raabe will return to court next week to hear closing arguments as attorneys wrap up the case.</p>
<p>Jurors are scheduled on April 29 to hear final arguments in Santa Ana from both the prosecution and the defense before beginning their deliberations.</p>
<p>The prosecution alleges that Raabe helped to divert nearly $90 million in interest earnings owed to cities, schools and special districts that invested in the county-run portfolio.  </p>
<p>Raabe's attorney, Gary Pohlson, called six defense witnesses earlier this week. Most of them described Raabe was a loyal and hard-working county employee.</p>
<p>Orange County filed for bankruptcy in December 1994 after sustaining losses of more than $1.6 billion on risky investments. The county emerged from bankruptcy last June.</p>
<p>Raabe was one of several Orange County officials to face charges following the bankruptcy.</p>
<p>In April 1995, former Orange County Treasurer Robert Citron pleaded guilty to six felonies for his role in the crisis.  </p>
<p>A judge last November ordered him to spend a year in jail and pay a $100,000 fine, but Citron was later assigned to a community work program instead of jail.</p>
<p>Citron claims that Raabe was the &quot;mastermind&quot; behind a scheme to divert the interest earnings.</p>
<p>Last October, a judge sentenced former Orange County budget director Ronald Rubino to probation for charges stemming from the investment crisis.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA ANA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
