<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539454" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stone cuts pulp, paper output in Q2.</title>
<headline>Stone cuts pulp, paper output in Q2.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stone Container Corp said Friday it expects to remove at least 350,000 tons of pulp and paper production in the second quarter through market-related downtime at its pulp and paper mills.</p>
<p>Stone said the expected reduction in output includes 239,000 tons for inventory balancing purposes.</p>
<p>In the first quarter, 97,000 tons of production were removed, including 72,000 for inventory balancing.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand for our core products remains strong and downtime is returning inventories to more normal levels,&quot; Roger Stone, chairman, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>In addition, Stone-Consolidated Corp, the Canadian company in which Stone Container has a major interest, removed about 43,000 metric tonnes of newsprint and groundwood papers from production during the first quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;In this improving environment, we have implemented a containerboard price increase in Europe, and recently announced a $50 per ton increase in our domestic containerboard products effective June 1,&quot; Stone said.</p>
<p>He added Stone Container also increased market pulp prices effective in May.  </p>
<p>Stone-Consolidated announced a $75 per metric tonne price increase for newsprint that the company believes will be implemented fully in the second quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;I am confident that the process of margin restoration has begun and will continue throughout the year,&quot; Stone said.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, Stone said he foresees a return to more normal market conditions as early as this summer.</p>
<p>Earlier today, Stone Container, a paper, paper packaging and pulp company, reported a first quarter net loss of $96.7 million or $0.99 a share, compared with a year-ago profit of $32.4 million or $0.30 per fully diluted share.</p>
<p>The company said that continued low selling prices for the company's core products led to the loss. It blamed industry-wide overproduction for the low prices.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
