<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539403" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. refiners' margins seen firm through spring.</title>
<headline>U.S. refiners' margins seen firm through spring.</headline>
<byline>Matt Daily</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Healthy U.S. refining margins will keep downstream producers smiling, at least through the spring season, according to analysts.</p>
<p>April margin levels have so far continued the rebound from the poor levels seen through most of 1996, with weak crude oil prices easing input costs for refiners.</p>
<p>&quot;My forecast is for margins to increase at least through the end of May,&quot; said Paulo Nery, senior analyst with Pace Consultants Inc in Houston.</p>
<p>Overall U.S. refining margins dipped slightly for the week ended April 19, according to Paul Ting, analyst with Salomon Brothers Inc. Margins at the factory were $4.85 a barrel on average, down from $4.96 the week before, with the April average at about $4.87.</p>
<p>That represents nearly a $1.00 increase from March levels, which totaled $3.85 for the U.S., according to Ting.</p>
<p>Market analysts put the average break-even point for U.S. refiners at about $3.00 a barrel.</p>
<p>&quot;The trend is going to be up, expecially because of gasoline, which has relatively low stocks,&quot; Nery said.</p>
<p>Gasoline prices, which remain near the lows hit in early April, are expected to rise steadily ahead of the peak-demand summer driving season.</p>
<p>&quot;The underlying factors are pretty good. Gasoline inventories are low -- not critically low, but low,&quot; said Ted Eck, economist with Amoco Corp.</p>
<p>U.S. gasoline stocks sat at 195 million barrels in the latest American Petroleum Institute (API) report, nearly 9 million barrels below the corresponding year-ago figure.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like a good year for demand,&quot; Eck said, with solid U.S. economic growth pushing most forecasts for increases at least two percent above last year's levels. Stable crude oil prices also would benefit refiners, Eck said, since refiners can more easily anticipate their costs.</p>
<p>Margins in the Gulf Coast region took a hit in the latest week, slipping to an average $3.69 a barrel, down $0.25, according to Ting's figures.</p>
<p>The Midwest refiners' margins continued at a healthy clip, racking up an average of $5.72 for the latest week, well above the $3.46 average recorded for the first quarter of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;In the Midwest, Group Three should remain relatively strong, though Chicago is going to lag,&quot; Nery said, since product supplies there should be plentiful.</p>
<p>Ting put California margins for the latest week at $7.67, nearly steady with the previous week but down from the $8.99 mark recorded at the end of March.</p>
<p>The gains in margins in recent weeks has come despite the high levels of refinery operations, put at 93.5 percent of capacity in the API report.</p>
<p>Market watchers expect refineries to keep running at high rates for the next several weeks because of the low gasoline stock levels.</p>
<p>&quot;And 94 percent (of capacity) is not far from what the refineries can do on a sustainable basis,&quot; Eck said.</p>
<p>((--New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1620))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
