<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539557" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian stocks finish higher in day of quiet trade.</title>
<headline>Indian stocks finish higher in day of quiet trade.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>**  (1200 GMT) - Indian shares end with small gains on</p>
<p>	  Friday after a weak start, SBI leads rally</p>
<p>**  Trade largely operator-driven, low volumes</p>
<p>**  Bombay share index up 19.85 pts, or 0.52 pct, at</p>
<p>	  3,825.57, off 3,793.83 low</p>
<p>**  National exchange index up 2.20 pts at 1,069.40</p>
<p>**  Foreign funds buyers in select stocks -- traders</p>
<p>**  Delhi share index gains 1.58 points to 797.67, Madras</p>
<p>	  2.78 pts to 3,658.51 and Calcutta 0.34 pts to 107.39</p>
<p>Indian shares, led by State Bank of India, closed higher on the Bombay exchange on Friday.</p>
<p>The market started weakly, but underlying trends were masked by end-of-week position squaring.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a dull market. Trade was mostly speculator-driven,&quot; said Ketan Jhaveri, chief dealer at Bombay's Kotak Securities, the Indian affiliate of Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>&quot;Buying interest was centred on select blue chips including IPCL, Mahindra &amp; Mahindra, BSES and ONGC.&quot;</p>
<p>SBI jumped 8.50 rupees from a 306.50 low to end with a net gain of 5.75 at 314.75 and traded over six million shares.  </p>
<p>Traders did not attach any particular reason to the rise and said hectic buying by some operators pushed up SBI.</p>
<p>&quot;The rally in this market-favourite stock helped perk up sentiment,&quot; said an equities dealer at a foreign brokerage.</p>
<p>Foreign funds were bidders in blue chips, but trading volumes were low, traders said.</p>
<p>U.S. investment bank Merrill Lynch said on Friday it was moving funds into Indian stock markets from Latin America.</p>
<p>The performance of Indian equities during the next six to nine months could surprise investors, Merrill said in a strategy report titled &quot;As We See It: India on Full Throttle&quot;.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are moving funds into the market at the expense of Latin America,&quot; Merrill said.</p>
<p>&quot;Regionally, we think Korea and Thailand will be important stories going out a year, but there may be a near-term opportunity cost of not exploiting the Indian story.&quot;</p>
<p>But Paribas Capital Markets urged investors to be cautious on Indian stocks if Bombay's index touched 3900-4000 points.</p>
<p>The market is waiting for a crucial Sunday meeting of former finance minister P. Chidambaram's Tamil Maanila Congress (TMC).</p>
<p>The TMC will meet to decide if it wants to rejoin the United Front government after pulling out a week ago.</p>
<p>-- Anshuman Daga, Bombay equities desk +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
