<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539518" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Australian envoy expected to head Iraq arms group.</title>
<headline>Australian envoy expected to head Iraq arms group.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's U.N. ambassador, Richard Butler, is expected to replace Rolf Ekeus as the executive chairman of the U.N. Special Commission in charge of ridding Iraq of weapons of mass destruction, diplomatic and U.N. sources said on Friday.</p>
<p>Barring last minute objections, U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan is expected to announce his appointment formally in the next two weeks, the sources said.</p>
<p>Ekeus has led the commission, known as UNSCOM, since its inception in 1991. He will leave his post in July to become Sweden's ambassador to the United States.</p>
<p>Butler, known for his outspoken comments, has been involved in disarmament affairs since 1983, when he was appointed Australia's first ambassador for disarmament at the Geneva-based Conference on Disarmament.</p>
<p>In 1995 he convened the Canberra Commission on the Elimination of Nuclear Weapons, which produced a landmark report. He also led the fight in 1996 for General Assembly approval of the nuclear test-ban treaty.</p>
<p>He became Australia's U.N. ambassador in 1992 after serving as ambassador to Thailand.</p>
<p>In answer to queries, Butler said the appointment was up to the secretary-general, adding: &quot;I won't comment on what he may decide to do.&quot;</p>
<p>UNSCOM is in charge of eliminating Iraq's nuclear warheads, biological and chemical arms and ballistic missiles. Sanctions against Iraq, imposed after it invaded Kuwait in 1990, cannot be lifted until the commission is satisfied it has accounted for all the dangerous weapons.</p>
<p>Ekeus, on instructions from the Security Council, organised the commission in April 1991. It was considered one of the most efficient bodies in the United Nations.</p>
<p>He has frequently accused Iraq of misleading his weapons inspectors, and in turn has been accused by Baghdad officials of doing Washington's bidding.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
