<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53968" id="root" date="1996-09-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada's east coast braces for Hurricane Hortense.</title>
<headline>Canada's east coast braces for Hurricane Hortense.</headline>
<dateline>HALIFAX 1996-09-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's maritime provinces were pounded on Saturday by large swells, heavy rain and gusty winds and people stockpiled emergency supplies as a weakening Hurricane Hortense swirled toward landfall.</p>
<p>In the early evening on Saturday the hurricane was about 90 miles (150 km) southeast of Halifax, Nova Scotia, and moving at a speed of 28 mph (45 kph), weather experts said.</p>
<p>Hortense was expected to hit north of Halifax about 9 p.m. (0100 GMT Sunday)  and move along Nova Scotia's eastern shoreline for several hours before heading toward Newfoundland.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still considered a class one hurricane, but by the time it reaches land it should be downgraded to a tropical storm,&quot; Brent Baxter, duty officer for the Emergency Measures Organisation, said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>But the hurricane's strong winds and high tides added up to a potentially dangerous situation, Baxter said.</p>
<p>He said coastal areas might experience sustained winds of 50 to 60 mph (80 to 100 kph), with peak gusts ranging to 80 mph (130 kph).</p>
<p>Many Nova Scotians spent the day shopping for extra food and emergency supplies as heavy rains lashed the maritime province for most of the day.</p>
<p>Baxter said telephone and power crews were on standby and coast guard vessels were on alert to aid distressed ships.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody is on standby right now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier in the week the hurricane had sustained winds of up to 120 mph (193 kph) and dumped up to two feet (0.6 meters) of rain on Puerto Rico and the Dominican Republic. Dominican officials put the number of dead as high as 10, with 50 people missing, and 16 people were killed in Puerto Rico.</p>
<p>The Puerto Rican government bought ads in in major U.S. newspapers urging tourists to visit despite the hurricane damage.</p>
<p>&quot;The sun is coming out and our beaches are as beautiful as ever, despite Hurricane Hortense's short visit,&quot; said one of the ads.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HALIFAX"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
