<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="53972" id="root" date="1996-09-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian Shi'ites Moslems say 14 died in protest.</title>
<headline>Nigerian Shi'ites Moslems say 14 died in protest.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-09-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Nigerian Moslem Shi'ite group on Saturday said 14 people died in clashes with police during protests in northern Nigeria.</p>
<p>Police have said there were no casualities during the protests staged in several northern cities after Friday prayers against the arrest of leaders of Shi'ites Moslem sect.</p>
<p>A police spokesman told a radio station that only teargas was used to disperse the protesters. Residents reported the area was calm on Saturday.</p>
<p>But Mohammed Ciroma, a spokesman for the Shi'ites Moslem Brotherhood, said &quot;Eleven people were killed in Zaria city during the protest on Friday and many were severely wounded.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Three more died today from injuries making a total of 14,&quot; he said by telephone from the university town of Zaria, adding that the funerals would take place on Saturday evening in Zaria.</p>
<p>Mainly Moslem northern Nigeria has been the scene of religious riots several times, most recently last month when three people were killed in a clash between rival Moslem sects in Kano, the most populous city in the north.</p>
<p>Local newspapers reported that Friday's protest also took place in Kaduna and Katsina and followed the arrest on Thursday of the Shi'ite leader named as Ibrahim Yaqub El-Zak-Zaky.</p>
<p>A statement by the sect said El-Zak-Zaky and other leaders of the group were arrested by police and taken to an unknown destination after clashes between the sect and Christians in the town of Kafanchan, south of Kaduna.</p>
<p>Kaduna state's new military administrator Lieutenant-Colonel Hammed Ibrahim Ali has vowed to be tough on people who use religion to cause discord.</p>
<p>&quot;If you forment trouble in the name of religion I will get on your back and when I do that nobody can save you,&quot; Ali was quoted as telling the people of the state during a tour of rural areas on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
