<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539851" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: COMEX copper called to open firmer.</title>
<headline>COMEX copper called to open firmer.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX copper futures were called to open firmer Friday, with the a test of the eight-month high set last month still seen possible even though the market is again beginning to look overbought, analysts said.</p>
<p>Renewed tightness in the prompt market, shortcovering by funds, news of a rise in China's copper imports in the first quarter, and the expiry of the COMEX May options Friday were also cited.</p>
<p>COMEX May copper was called unchanged to up 0.2 cent from Thursday's close of 112.35 cents a lb after trading from 112.00 to 112.70 cents on ACCESS.</p>
<p>Resistance for May delivery was pegged around 114.00 cents, a level seen briefly in early March.</p>
<p>The May/July spread has widened sharply again this week to over 2.00 cents, from 1.00 cent in mid-April, while on the LME the cash-to-three months spread was back out around $200 a tonne from below $50 a tonne in mid-April.</p>
<p>LME warehouse copper stocks fell 1,550 tonnes Friday to 145,200 tonnes, while COMEX stocks rose 1,070 short tons Thursday to 51,251 short tons.</p>
<p>China imported 18,954 tonnes of unrefined copper and copper anodes in the first quarter 1997, up 38.7 percent on the same period last year, according to Chinese Customes Dept data.</p>
<p>((Clive McKeef, New York Commodity Desk 212-859-1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
