<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539943" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Liberty says court denied Putnam injunction.</title>
<headline>Liberty says court denied Putnam injunction.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Massachusetts court denied a preliminary injunction against three former executives with Putnam Investments who quit to join Liberty Financial Co Inc and its units, Liberty said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Putnam alleged in a February lawsuit that Kevin O'Shea, the chief executive of Liberty unit Colonial Group and a former Putnam executive, recruited three former colleagues, which violated non-soliciation agreements.</p>
<p>The three executives are James Tambone, Louis Tasiopoulos, both managing directors with Liberty, and Kevin O'Shea, managing director of Colonial Group unit Colonial Investment Services.  </p>
<p>&quot;I am unpersuaded on this record of the likelihood of the plaintiff's (Putnam's) success on the merits of its claim that solicitation in fact took place,&quot; Middlesex Superior Court Judge James McHugh wrote in an opinion released by Liberty.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased and gratified that Judge McHugh's ruling in this case is consistent with our position that no violations of the Putnam non-solicitation agreements occured,&quot; Liberty said in a statement.</p>
<p>A Putnam spokeswoman said the company was confident the court would rule in its favor when the case proceeds.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident and expect our position to be upheld when the facts are fully heard at the court,&quot; said Nancy Fisher.</p>
<p>((Boston bureau (617) 367-4106))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
