<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54006" id="root" date="1996-09-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin has health checks, premier in charge.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin has health checks, premier in charge.</headline>
<byline>Philippa Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin had checks in hospital ahead of a planned heart operation, leaving his prime minister to try to knock a peace deal for rebel Chechnya into acceptable shape for Moscow.</p>
<p>Viktor Chernomyrdin, deputising for Yeltsin during his absence, chaired a meeting of top officials on Saturday to discuss how to stop the two-week-old deal giving too much away to the rebels.</p>
<p>The liberal Nezavisimaya Gazeta newspaper said Chernomyrdin had effectively stepped into the shoes of the president, who has said he will undergo surgery at the end of the month.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a question...of real powers, bringing the prime minister ever closer to the work of the president,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>After Saturday's meeting, Chernomyrdin issued a stern warning to the separatists that Moscow would not let the North Caucasus region -- where an uneasy peace has held for more than three weeks -- split from the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>The statement also sent a message to Yeltsin's outspoken and ambitious security adviser Alexander Lebed, who had agreed with the rebels to put off discussion on the status of Chechnya for five years.</p>
<p>Lebed, who attended Chernomyrdin's meeting, has made no secret of his presidential ambitions and analysts say Moscow's lukewarm response to the deal is partly due to the political capital he has reaped from his dramatic peace mission.</p>
<p>Lebed's profile was boosted again on Saturday when a NATO official said the Western defence alliance had invited the general to visit its Brussels headquarters in November.</p>
<p>Senior Russian officials say the withdrawal of troops sent to Chechnya in December 1994 that was envisaged in Lebed's deal would end up handing power to the rebels, who continue to insist on independence for the war-torn region.</p>
<p>Last week, the military said it had suspended the pullout in a row over the exchange of prisoners of war, although two young Russian conscripts were reunited with their mothers on Saturday.</p>
<p>The rebels said on Saturday they had made plans in case the peace deal did not work out, hinting while confirming their support for peace that they were prepared to fight.</p>
<p>&quot;If this deal meets the same fate as previous ones which were grossly violated, the Chechen side will be forced to take all necessary measures to protect its citizens' lives,&quot; Ekho Moskvy radio quoted rebel spokesman Movladi Udugov as saying.</p>
<p>Russian television reporters covering the government meeting said the cancellation of a promised briefing suggested officials had not been able to agree on how to proceed with Chechnya, where tens of thousands of people have been killed.</p>
<p>The confusion surrounding the peace deal has highlighted the power struggle which has bubbled up during Yeltsin's illness.</p>
<p>Yeltsin underwent his medical checks at the same clinic where his wife Naina was taken for a kidney operation in August.</p>
<p>Presidential aides declined to say whether husband and wife were together and stressed that Yeltsin was undergoing routine checks.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a situation created by an unforeseen event,&quot; a Kremlin spokesman told Reuters. &quot;There is no question of this being an emergency hospitalisation.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
