<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="540040" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: WSOY ASSOCIATE TO OWN 10 PCT OF NEW GROUP.</title>
<headline>WSOY ASSOCIATE TO OWN 10 PCT OF NEW GROUP.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish publishing house WSOY said on Friday that Yhtyneet Kuvalehdet Oy had decided to exchange its shares in commercial TV company MTV Oy for shares in the new media group to be formed through the planned merger of MTV and Aamulehti-yhtyma Oy .</p>
<p>Werner Soderstrom Oy owns 50 percent of Yhtyneet Kuvalehdet, a magazine publisher.</p>
<p>&quot;Yhtyneet Kuvalehdet's holding in MTV equals approximately a 10-percent holding in the new company,&quot; WSOY said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The board of directors of Yhtyneet Kuvalehdet has today made the decision to exchange their MTV shares for shares in the communication company established through the merger of Aamulehti-yhtyma and MTV,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Media group Aamulehti announced earlier this week that it had agreed to merge with MTV. Sweden's Marieberg Tidnings Ab would be the new group's biggest owner with a stake of about 20 percent.</p>
<p>Including full debt conversion and options, Marieberg's stake in Aamulehti is 28.8 percent of shares and 28.45 percent of votes.</p>
<p>Aamulehti shareholders will be entitled to exchange their shares for stock in the new company at one-to-one while MTV shareholders will receive 137.5 shares in the new company for each existing MTV share.</p>
<p>Aamulehti said the new company would apply for a bourse listing. --Helsinki newsroom +358-9-680 50 245, e-mail news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47530">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
