<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="540015" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Anti-smoking groups oppose immunity for companies.</title>
<headline>Anti-smoking groups oppose immunity for companies.</headline>
<byline>Robert Green</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading anti-smoking groups said Thursday they opposed any grant of immunity from civil lawsuits for tobacco manufacturers as part of a settlement with states that are suing the companies.</p>
<p>Talks between top industry executives and anti-tobacco forces began about two weeks ago about a possible settlement of suits by 22 states.</p>
<p>Published reports have said the industry might pay as much as $300 billion over 25 years into a compensation fund for smokers who fall sick with lung cancer and other diseases. In return, the industry would get broad shelter from lawsuits.</p>
<p>&quot;We are opposed to any tobacco settlement in which we are forced to grant the tobacco companies immunity as the price for protecting the health of our children,&quot; Rep. Henry Waxman, D-Calif., said.</p>
<p>He was joined at a news conference by representatives of the American Cancer Society, American Heart Association, American Medical Association and American Lung Association who all opposed granting the tobacco industry immunity from future lawsuits through legislation or other means.</p>
<p>&quot;We simply can't negotiate away our children's future,&quot; said former Food and Drug Administration Commissioner David Kessler. He said he would oppose any settlement that did not grant the FDA authority to regulate the nicotine content of cigarettes and that did not require the industry to disclose its research on nicotine addiction.</p>
<p>White House Press Secretary Mike McCurry said Thursday the White House was monitoring the efforts to reach an out-of-court settlement in order to safeguard the administration's efforts to deter smoking by young people.</p>
<p>Clinton last year gave broad powers to the FDA by approving its contention that nicotine is a drug. That position underpins the FDA's effort to regulate the industry and limit advertising it considers to be aimed at persuading young people to smoke.</p>
<p>White House Deputy Counsel Bruce Lindsey met Wednesday at the White House with Mississippi Attorney General Michael Moore and lawyers representing tobacco companies and plaintiffs suing the industry.</p>
<p>&quot;We remain in contact with the parties. We do not have a specific formal proposal in front of the parties,&quot; McCurry said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the parties are well aware of the president's very strong views on the public health need of curbing tobacco use among young people, and they know that his support would be critical to any outcome that they seek,&quot; McCurry said.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be difficult for (immunity) legislation to pass Congress if it didn't have the president's support,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another White House official, who asked not to be identified, stressed Wednesday that Clinton could not go along with a settlement that would give tobacco companies blanket protection from future civil lawsuits. &quot;We've always said we're against blanket immunity,&quot; said the official.</p>
<p>Last month, Liggett Group, owned by Brooke Group Ltd., became the first major tobacco company to reach a settlement with the states and to admit the health hazards of smoking and that it is addictive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
