<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="540140" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: White sugar stronger on good demand, supply fears.</title>
<headline>White sugar stronger on good demand, supply fears.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>World prices for white sugar have surged to six-month highs as demand picks up and traders fear being caught with sales obligations in August when quality European supply could be tight.</p>
<p>Market sources said trade buying has been mainly responsible for the bull run on the benchmark August futures contract in London although investment fund and speculative players have been noted on both sides of the market.</p>
<p>Physical demand, particularly from Russia but also from Egypt and China, has propped up flagging prices.</p>
<p>&quot;People are adjusting their attitudes -- they think the Russians are nibbling at a little bit. It just looks good,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;I think people are just buying the rumour, hoping that the Russians are going to come and buy some more.&quot;</p>
<p>Prices for August delivery hit a nadir of $295.00 a tonne in mid-January but have since clawed back some of the lost ground, reaching a peak of $317.50 on Thursday -- the highest since last October.</p>
<p>Trade sources said Russian import registrations had already reached up to 450,000 tonnes this year and as much as 225,000 tonnes of raw sugar was already on its way.</p>
<p>Although Russia has bought raw sugar, to be refined internally, which is traded on the New York futures market, traders said the bullish sentiment was still likely to spill over into London.</p>
<p>&quot;If raws are being taken off the world market then people can still get bullish on the whites as there's less sugar around,&quot; said another.</p>
<p>Another fear is that the supply of quality European Union (EU) white sugar will be thin on the ground when deliveries are due against the August contract.</p>
<p>So traders want to avoid being &quot;short&quot;, or holding a sell obligation, as it could be difficult to find sugar.</p>
<p>Most 1996/97 exports will have been completed, while harvesting from the new beet crop normally starts around September, depending on the country.</p>
<p>&quot;There's an old saying in sugar, however long you've been in the trade. Don't ever be short of August,&quot; said another trader.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
