<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="540215" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey prepares to draw up anti-inflation plan.</title>
<headline>Turkey prepares to draw up anti-inflation plan.</headline>
<byline>Servet Yildirim</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey has moved to draw up a plan to tackle high inflation, but as the Islamist-led coalition government came under severe strain economists stressed on Friday that political stability was essential for success.</p>
<p>A technical committee has been set up to decide on a medium-term stabilisation programme to tackle inflation currently running at around 80 per cent, said a senior economy official who declined to be named.</p>
<p>The official said the programme would aim to lower annual inflation to 10 percent over a period of three years.</p>
<p>&quot;A technical committee including senior treasury, planning, central bank and finance ministry officials has been set up to prepare the programme,&quot; said the official.</p>
<p>&quot;Every institution has prepared its own plan. We will come together and discuss them before reaching a final programme which will be able to win support from international financial bodies like the IMF,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;The key question is whether the fall in inflation would be sharp or gradual. It will be determined after studies,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Officials said the IMF asked Turkey to launch a medium-term programme to address the country's persistent economic problems earlier this month when a Fund team paid a consultation visit to Ankara.</p>
<p>State Minister Ufuk Soylemez, who flew to Washington on Friday to attend an IMF-World bank interim committee meeting, is expected to hold talks on the details of the programme with Fund officials.</p>
<p>Planning officials say Turkey might aim to raise $15 to $20 billion of privatisation revenue by end-1999 and to attain an annual growth rate of four to five percent under the programme.</p>
<p>&quot;The programme may contain some measures to increase tax revenues and curb losses of pension funds and monetary tightening,&quot; an official said.</p>
<p>Turkey has been struggling with fiscal imbalances, high inflation, fuelled by budget deficits at over eight percent of gross national product, and widening foreign trade and current account gaps.</p>
<p>Economists question the chance of any programme, citing uncertainities over the future of Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan's coalition government.</p>
<p>&quot;Look at the other examples across the world. Only those programmes implemented by strong governments had been successful,&quot; said a government economist.</p>
<p>Ercan Uygur, an economics professor at Ankara University, said Turkey could not stick by a firm programme for three years under present political and economic uncertainties.</p>
<p>Ankara had shelved a 20-month IMF stand-by programme in late 1995 over a government crisis which dragged the country to early elections.</p>
<p>&quot;Three years is very long time in Turkey. I don't think that Turkey can implement a programme for such a period. It will be suspended on the half way,&quot; Uygur told Reuters.</p>
<p>Erbakan has been locked in a political war of attrition with the secularist armed forces which urged the government to implement tough measures against Islamist activism at a February meeting of the National Security Council (NSC).</p>
<p>The military members of the NSC are expected to increase demands on the reluctant government at a Saturday meeting to implement the measures.</p>
<p>Political concerns, sparked by the dispute, have been keeping financial and capital markets under pressure for two days.</p>
<p>&quot;The political instability hampers the economy, exports, foreign capital inflow,&quot; said Mehmet Yildirim, head of Istanbul's Chamber of Trade, calling parliament to end the crisis soon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
