<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="540209" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turk business chiefs fear politics hurting economy.</title>
<headline>Turk business chiefs fear politics hurting economy.</headline>
<byline>Daren Butler</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish business leaders said on Friday that uncertainty over the future of the Islamist-led coalition served to undermine the economy, and called for rapid action to resolve the political crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;Will the government fall, will it continue, make a decision now,&quot; Mehmet Yildirim, chairman of the Istanbul Chamber of Commerce, said in a call to parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;Exports, the entry of foreign capital, everything is being influenced negatively,&quot; Yildirim told Reuters, adding that instability was preventing economic progress this year.</p>
<p>Renewed doubts about the coalition's future were fuelled on Friday by a newspaper report quoting unnamed cabinet ministers as saying Deputy Prime Minister Tansu Ciller had decided to pull her True Path Party (DYP) out of government.</p>
<p>Ciller denied the report, but members of her 10-month-old alliance with Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan acknowledged the climate of political uncertainty was potentially damaging to the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Economic stability is tied to political stability. Everyone must refrain from behaviour that will cast a shadow over the democratic regime,&quot; State Minister and DYP deputy Ufuk Soylemez was quoted as saying by the state-run Anatolian news agency.</p>
<p>He defended the government's economic record, citing falling interest rates, accelerated privatisation and rising reserves since it came to power last June.</p>
<p>However, business leaders said confidence has waned in the coalition's ability to reform an economy battling with annual inflation of around 80 percent and sustained imbalances in public finances.</p>
<p>The failure to reform a sprawling public sector contributed to downgrades of Turkey's credit rating by five major agencies in recent months, and an IMF delegation warned Turkey about its financial situation during a fortnight of talks this month.</p>
<p>&quot;This government has got to go,&quot; Fuat Miras, the chairman of Turkey's Bourses and Chambers of Commerce Association (TOBB), told Reuters. &quot;In the current climate all the economic balances have begun to break down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This government has reached such a stage in the nation's eyes that there is no trust and nobody can accept this government model,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He forecast there would be a large budget deficit in 1997, despite a promise by Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan to deliver a balanced budget after a 1,218 trillion lira ($1.3 billion) shortfall in 1996.</p>
<p>Ciller's unlikely alliance with Erbakan's Islamist Welfare Party has been shaken by a row over military demands for a crackdown on a religious revival since it came to power.</p>
<p>Military pressure to introduce eight-year compulsory state education has in particular divided the two alliance wings as Welfare (RP) deputies see the plan threatening the role of religious schools in the secular but Moslem country.</p>
<p>&quot;RP has got a knife at its throat. If necessary it will break the coalition,&quot; said Erol Yarar, chairman of the Moslem business assocation MUSIAD, referring to the impasse on eight-year education.</p>
<p>But he said the Turkish business world had become accustomed to a climate of political instability over the past five years and to a certain extent carried on regardless.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as the private sector is concerned we get on with our work while watching the politics,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>For some in the business community, establishing a broader government alliance would resolve political squabbling, which they see dividing the country along secularist and pro-Islamist lines.</p>
<p>&quot;A broadly based government model must be created to say 'stop' to the situation pushing the country today towards a precipice,&quot; the TOBB's Miras said.</p>
<p>Such calls are tempered by many in the financial community who warn that the possibility of early elections could itself destabilise Turkey's volatile financial markets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
