<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54030" id="root" date="1996-09-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bosnia's first post-war elections begin.</title>
<headline>Bosnia's first post-war elections begin.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-09-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polling stations in Bosnia opened on Saturday as the country prepared to vote in its first post-war election, set by last year's Dayton peace accord to try to heal the wounds of war and usher in a democratic future.</p>
<p>Witnesses said most of the 4,600 polling stations across the war-ravaged country appeared to open on time at 7 a.m. (0500 GMT). Early voting was light, with no incidents reported.  </p>
<p>At one polling station in central Sarajevo, seven elderly people were waiting outside as its doors swung open. The first couple to vote said they were refugees from Pale -- the Bosnian Serb stronghold a short drive from Sarajevo.</p>
<p>Bosnian state radio reported that other polling stations across the country had opened on schedule. It proceeded to give citizens instructions on how to vote.</p>
<p>Some 2.9 million Moslems, Croats and Serbs will elect a national presidency and parliament, a president and separate parliament for the Serb Republic, and a parliament and cantonal administrations in the Moslem-Croat Federation.</p>
<p>At a bus depot in Sarajevo, four refugees sat anxiously waiting to be driven back to their old home districts to vote, the first time they have returned since they were driven out by the ethnic cleansing which marked the 3-1/2 war.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
