<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="540499" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany's Transrapid restructures to stay on track.</title>
<headline>Germany's Transrapid restructures to stay on track.</headline>
<byline>Terence Gallagher</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Transrapid rail consortium on Friday restructured its management to keep the magnetic-levitation project on track, although it now expected lower revenues and higher costs than previously forecast.</p>
<p>Jolted by the departure of three construction groups, the Transrapid consortium would now come under the leadership of national railway Deutsche Bahn AG, Transportation Minister Mattias Wissmann said at a news conference.</p>
<p>But Wissmann also said the proposed Hamburg-Berlin line would require 10 percent more than the original nine-billion mark investment cost and would generate annual revenue of 790 million marks by 2010 -- down from an earlier estimate of 1.15 billion marks.</p>
<p>The Transrapid, whose trains glide over a magnetic field at speeds of up to 420 kilometers per hour, has been opposed by opposition parties and environmental groups who doubt whether there is sufficient demand for it in Germany and whether it can justify the six billion marks of state funding Bonn plans to offer for it.</p>
<p>Construction firms Phillip Holzmann, Hochtief and Bilfinger + Berger withdrew from the project under pressure from other partners to reduce costs, a Holzmann spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Existing partners Deutsche Bahn, Thyssen AG, and Siemens AG were negotiating with potential foreign investors and wanted to add another European partner, Wissmann said.</p>
<p>ADtranz -- a venture between car maker Daimler-Benz AG and Swiss-Swedish group ABB on Friday confirmed it would join the group.</p>
<p>&quot;With our participation in (the Transrapid project) we will use the opportunity to maintain and expand our leading role in the German rail industry,&quot; ADtranz chairman and Daimler management board member Eckhard Cordes said.</p>
<p>The consortium was also talking to Anglo-French group GEC-Alsthom, Siemens chief executive Heinrich von Pierer told a news conference in Bonn.</p>
<p>The Sueddeutsche Zeitung reported on Friday that the Transrapid partners would have to inject 500 million marks into the project in the wake of the departure of the the construction groups.</p>
<p>But a Thyssen spokesman told Reuters the shake-up improved the consortium's finances. &quot;The project is now more secure financially,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Transrapid consortium considered the costs associated with the German construction firms were too high, while the three builders saw no room for the cost reductions demanded by the other partners, Holzmann said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been informed that the remaining partners in the consortium will take on the costs of the project themselves,&quot; a Holzmann spokesman said.</p>
<p>Under current planning, construction is due to start in 1998,and operations begin in 2005. The government has said it will cover the costs of the Hamburg-Berlin track, while the private-sector partners develop and operate the train.</p>
<p>Industry officials have said the Transrapid would help Germany keep a technological lead in high-speed rail.</p>
<p>Wissmann said the project would create 18,000 construction jobs. A further 4,400 workers would be needed to operate the system.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, +49-228 2609150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020028">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
