<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="540495" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Jospin refuses four-way election tv debate.</title>
<headline>Jospin refuses four-way election tv debate.</headline>
<dateline>TOULOUSE, France 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Socialist opposition leader Lionel Jospin rejected on Friday a four-way television debate with the leaders of France's other parliamentary parties before next month's election and challenged Prime Minister Alain Juppe to a face-to-face confrontation.</p>
<p>Jospin told reporters several radio and television stations had offered to stage a one-on-one debate between himself and the centre-right prime minister since President Jacques Chirac dissolved parliament on Monday and called a snap election for May 25 and June 1.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't understand why Alain Juppe is rushing to a four-way formula. It is as if he needed a second because he is scared of a direct confrontation with me,&quot; Jospin said on a campaign trip to Toulouse in southwestern France.</p>
<p>&quot;He prefers doubles but I play singles and, in politics, you've got to be straight, clear and defend your positions,&quot; the Socialist leader said.</p>
<p>The Socialist Party said Jospin had turned down an invitation from TF1 television to appear in a four-way debate involving UDF party leader Francois Leotard and Communist Party leader Robert Hue as well as Juppe.</p>
<p>Juppe, Leotard and Hue all said they had accepted the invitation for a debate on May 20, five days before the first round of voting.</p>
<p>The ruling coalition is keen to depict Jospin, leader of the largest opposition party, as dependent on the Communists to win a majority, while the Socialists are keen to focus on Juppe's unpopular record and personality.</p>
<p>A four-way debate would be likely to highlight differences between the Socialists and Communists on the key issue of a single European currency.</p>
<p>The Socialists are in favour of the euro, although they have set conditions and refused further austerity steps if these were needed to reach the strict budget deficit criterion for European monetary union. The Communists oppose a single currency and want a referendum on the issue.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOULOUSE, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
