<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54044" id="root" date="1996-09-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Dalai Lama arrives in Australia, meets Downer.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Dalai Lama arrives in Australia, meets Downer.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-09-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dalai Lama, Tibet's exiled spiritual leader, arrived in Sydney on Saturday following a New Zealand tour that attracted Chinese diplomatic threats.</p>
<p>Australian Foreign Affairs Minister Alexander Downer met the Dalai Lama upon his arrival from New Zealand but immediately said the talks were not official.</p>
<p>&quot;My wife (Nicky) and I as Australian citizens were happy to accede to the request made by the Dalai Lama's party for us to meet with him and I met him in a private capacity and met him as a very distinguished and well known religious leader,&quot; Downer told reporters after the meeting.</p>
<p>Earlier, the Australian opposition demanded that Prime Minister John Howard also meet him.</p>
<p>Chinese Premier Li Peng warned Australia last month against official contact with the Dalai Lama, and Howard is not currently scheduled to meet the Buddhist monk during the two-week visit.</p>
<p>&quot;The New Zealand Prime Minister has now met with the Dalai Lama,&quot; Labor Opposition Foreign Affairs spokesman Laurie Brereton said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;It is high time John Howard told the Australian public whether he will do likewise.&quot;</p>
<p>The Dalai Lama, in exile from his Chinese-controlled country since 1959, met New Zealand Prime Minister Jim Bolger on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But China, insisting the Dalai Lama is leading a pro-independence cause, routinely objects to leaders of other states meeting him.</p>
<p>&quot;We have paid great attention to his (the Dalai Lama's) meetings with New Zealand leaders,&quot; a Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman said on Thursday, adding that they clearly interfered in internal Chinese affairs and would affect relations with New Zealand.</p>
<p>The Dalai Lama is scheduled to visit Melbourne, Canberra and Sydney to attend Buddhist celebrations, make speeches and hold news conferences.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
