<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="540481" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Impact of Nissan Mutual woes may linger in forex.</title>
<headline>Impact of Nissan Mutual woes may linger in forex.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>News reports that Japan's Ministry of Finance (MOF) plans to issue an order to halt operations to Nissan Mutual Life Insurance Co sparked a brief flurry of dollar purchases for yen on Thursday, experts said.</p>
<p>But any lasting effect on currencies depends on whether or not Nissan Mutual Life's difficulties are symptomatic of problems throughout the industry, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;It would have a lasting impact if this spread and became a broader issue in the market than just this one company,&quot; said Ron Leven, a currency strategist at J.P. Morgan.</p>
<p>&quot;They're a very small insurance company,&quot; Leven said. &quot;So, if it's just an isolated event, it doesn't really mean much for anything.&quot;</p>
<p>Jiji Press was among the Japanese news services reporting on Thursday that the MOF was preparing to issue the order to Nissan Mutual. Jiji said the ministry is expected to announce the decision in a few days.</p>
<p>Mainichi newspaper issued a similar story on its newswire.</p>
<p>This would mark the first time since World War II that the MOF has allowed a Japanese insurer to fail.  </p>
<p>Nissan Mutual had announced plans last November to write off five billion yen worth of bad loans in the business year ended March 31.</p>
<p>Experts weighed any potential impact on Bank of Japan (BOJ) monetary policy, as well as on flows in the foreign exchange market should Nissan Mutual fail.  </p>
<p>&quot;So it's safer, I suppose, to stick with the implications for monetary policy, that is the Bank of Japan is inclined to leave rates as low as possible for as long as possible,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The BOJ has kept its official interest rates at record low levels, in part, to help out Japanese financial institutions burdened with bad loans.</p>
<p>J.P. Morgan's Leven said expectations that Nissan Mutual's problems may be symptomatic of a broader problem is likely to lead to some weakness in the financial sector in the Japanese stock market.</p>
<p>This highlights the need for the BOJ to keep rates low, Leven added.</p>
<p>On a macro economic basis, this would be good for the dollar, Leven said. But on the basis of repatriation of flows back to Japan, it is probably negative for the dollar.</p>
<p>((--212-859-1668))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
