<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="540584" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French Gaullist party retires reluctant old guard.</title>
<headline>French Gaullist party retires reluctant old guard.</headline>
<byline>Bernard Edinger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The last &quot;historic&quot; Gaullists -- Resistance leaders and former aides to General Charles de Gaulle -- have been excluded from the RPR Gaullist party's list of parliamentary candidates on age grounds.</p>
<p>The list of candidates for the May 25-June 1 poll published by the Rally for the Republic showed the party had excluded at least 10 outgoing parliamentarians, including a serving cabinet minister and an ex-premier, because they were aged 75 or over.</p>
<p>The party set a rule making 75 the age limit for candidates several months ago to rejuvenate parliamentary ranks.</p>
<p>Three of those affected, including former prime minister Jacques Chaban-Delmas, who is seriously ill, said in advance they would not seek re-election.</p>
<p>But seven others have chosen to defy the party and run again without official backing, including Veterans Affairs Minister Pierre Pasquini. After behind-the-scenes haggling, the RPR has decided not to present candidates against five of them.</p>
<p>These include Pasquini and former defence minister Robert Galley, whose impeccable Gaullist credentials include being a holder of the coveted Order of the Liberation for wartime service in the Free French forces. Galley, son-in-law of the late Gaullist hero Marshal Philippe Leclerc, was De Gaulle's science minister in the 1960s.</p>
<p>Pasquini, himself a former Free French officer, told Reuters on Friday the RPR had promised &quot;old guard&quot; candidates logistical support. &quot;We have the total support of the movement,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Pasquini produced a letter from RPR Secretary-General Jean-Francois Mancel pledging full support, but the party's press office said this did not include money or practical aid.</p>
<p>However, the RPR was on a collision course with two long-time Gaullist figures who refused outright to step down in favour of younger men close to President Jacques Chirac.</p>
<p>Gabriel Kaspereit, 77, a parliamentarian for 36 years, refused to step aside for Pierre Lellouche in Paris.</p>
<p>Jean de Lipkowski, a former deputy foreign minister, said he would stand against the official RPR candidate Didier Quentin, long a personal aide to Chirac.</p>
<p>Lipkowski was active in the wartime Resistance before escaping from occupied France and returning by parachute on D-Day with a French unit of Britain's Special Air Service (SAS).</p>
<p>Gaullist veterans' groups privately expressed bitterness but said they would make no public statements that could jeopardise state backing for such projects as ceremonies later this year to mark the anniversary of Leclerc's death in an air crash in 1947.</p>
<p>No other party has imposed age limits and the oldest serving parliamentarian, 85-year-old Charles Ehrmann, will stand again for the centre-right Union for French Democracy (UDF).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
