<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54059" id="root" date="1996-09-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila vows to turn war zone into investment area.</title>
<headline>Manila vows to turn war zone into investment area.</headline>
<byline>Dolly Aglay</byline>
<dateline>BUTUAN, Philippines 1996-09-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine President Fidel Ramos met business leaders in the southern Mindanao island on Saturday and vowed to turn the impoverished region into an investment haven.</p>
<p>Ramos said he would propose spending 54.9-billion pesos ($2.1 billion) to improve Mindanao's infrastructure and make the country's poorest region more attractive to investors as part of his 1997 budget.</p>
<p>He was speaking at the Mindanao Business Conference, a meeting of local and foreign businessmen being held to review business prospects in the region following the recent peace pact signed by the government and former Philippine Moslem rebel leader Nur Misuari.</p>
<p>Misuari, made head of a semi-autonomous regional government on Friday, accompanied Ramos to the Mindanao business meeting.</p>
<p>Misuari, Moro National Liberation Front (MNLF) chairman, said he would give priority to the construction of roads, airports and seaports in the Autonomous Region of Moslem Mindanao (ARMM).</p>
<p>The ARMM, set up in 1990, covers four Moslem-majority provinces in the southern Philippines.</p>
<p>The Mindanao business leaders gave Ramos 10 resolutions to propel economic development in the region.</p>
<p>The government was asked to improve Mindanao's infrastructure facilities, particularly telecommunications, and allow more foreign airlines to fly directly to the area.</p>
<p>Ramos was also asked to help speed up the entry of foreign Moslem banks to the region and to extend credit to farmers.</p>
<p>&quot;The recent signing of the peace accord has made us look forward to the opportunities brought about by renewed political stability in this portion of the country,&quot; Mindanao Business Conference chairman Sebastian Angliongdo said.</p>
<p>Angliongdo also said the peace accord had lifted the confidence of foreign investors in the area.</p>
<p>&quot;We are determined to put all this backwardness behind us and we believe that after we have reached this very momentous and historical agreement with the government, we are on our way to stabilising peace and order in Mindanao,&quot; Misuari told reporters.</p>
<p>($1 = 26 pesos)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUTUAN, Philippines"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
