<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="540522" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: UN investigators asked to cut text offending Islam.</title>
<headline>UN investigators asked to cut text offending Islam.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chairman of the U.N. Human Rights Commission has asked its investigator on racism to remove a paragraph from his annual report which the 53-member body found offensive to Islam and the Koran, a spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>The paragraph was an extract from an Israeli government review of anti-Semitic trends around the world which the investigator, Maurice Glele-Ahanhanzo of Benin, had cited at length in his report.</p>
<p>It read: &quot;The use of Christian and secular European anti-Semitism motifs in Moslem publications is on the rise, yet at the same time Moslem extremists are turning increasingly to their own religious sources, first and foremost the Qur'an (Koran) as a primary anti-Jewish source.&quot;</p>
<p>Arab countries in the 53-member Commission objected strongly to the phrasing, and the body, which ended its annual six-week session on April 18, agreed by consensus that the paragraph should not have been included in the report.</p>
<p>U.N. spokeswoman Therese Gastaut told a news briefing Commission chairman Miroslav Somol of the Czech Republic had written to Glele-Ahanhanzo asking to be told promptly of the action he planned to take on the decision.</p>
<p>Glele-Ahanhanzo -- who serves as U.N. special rapporteur on contemporary forms of racism, racial discrimination, xenophobia and related intolerance -- cited from several other documents on these issues in his report, including one asserting that Arabs suffered discriminatory treatment in the United States.</p>
<p>But the only objections to the report's content were focussed on the passage referring to the Koran.</p>
<p>In its decision on the paragraph, the Commission expressed &quot;indignation and protest&quot; at the inclusion &quot;of such an offensive reference to Islam and the Holy Qur'an (Koran)&quot;.</p>
<p>The Commission said the passage &quot;should have been excluded from the report&quot; and requested Somol to ask Glele-Ahanhanzo, who is currently in Benin, &quot;to take corrective action in response to this decision&quot;.</p>
<p>The Commission last week passed a separate resolution calling for a major world conference to combat racism by the year 2001, subject to approval by the General Assembly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BENIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
