<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="540626" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: TWA criminal probe centres on missile part - report.</title>
<headline>TWA criminal probe centres on missile part - report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The FBI has dropped all criminal scenarios for the crash of TWA Flight 800 except the possibility that it was hit by a fragment following the explosion of a missile nearby, a French victims' association said on Friday.</p>
<p>Jose Cremades, president of the association, told Reuters after meeting Federal Bureau of Investigation investigators in New York that they had practically finished their probe into the July 1996 crash off New York which killed all 230 people on board.</p>
<p>&quot;The FBI is now working on only one (criminal) hypothesis. It plans to complete its investigation within 90 days,&quot; Cremades said. Other criminal theories -- a bomb or a direct missile hit -- had been abandoned.</p>
<p>Authorities know the jumbo jet's centre fuel tank exploded but have not determined why. Investigators have said mechanical failure, a bomb or a missile may have caused the disaster.</p>
<p>In the absence of an explanation, theories have abounded that a U.S. Navy missile accidentally downed the Boeing 747, but the government has dismissed these claims.</p>
<p>The missile fragment theory first came up earlier this year in congressional hearings with the head of the National Transportation Safety Board.</p>
<p>Cremades added that civilian experts believed the fragment scenario was unlikely. He confirmed that French investigating magistrate Chantal Perdrix may travel to New York in late May to set up contact with U.S. investigators.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
