<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="540616" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Sao Paulo stopover limited impact on ex-Paris Aerolineas cargo.</title>
<headline>Sao Paulo stopover limited impact on ex-Paris Aerolineas cargo.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aerolineas Argentinas' move in adding Sao Paulo to its Paris-Buenos Aires Boeing 747 passenger service will have a limited impact on cargo capacity to the Brazilian city, the airline's French cargo sales agent, Iberia, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Sao Paulo was added to Aerolineas' four-times a week passenger service earlier in April and this now routes Paris/CDG-Madrid-Sao Paulo-Buenos Aires, an Iberia official said.</p>
<p>As far as freight is concerned, the importance of Sao Paulo is really as a fuel stopover, providing a greater payload from Paris and Madrid to Buenos Aires.</p>
<p>The official added: &quot;It is difficult to give precise details as it is only a fortnight since we began selling Sao Paulo from Paris but it will probably only accounts for around 10 percent of capacity on each flight, which can carry between 15 and 16 tonnes,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Buenos Aires, which attracts significantly higher rates than Sao Paulo, will continue to be the focal point of cargo operations, but clearly we will be able to respond to demand for space to Brazil from now on,&quot; he said</p>
<p>Aerolineas also operates a twice weekly Paris-Buenos Aires 747-200 freighter service in conjunction with Air France.</p>
<p>Brazilian airline, Varig recently told Reuters that cargo capacity on its daily Paris-Sao Paulo-Rio passenger service was set to rise significantly from June 2 when an McDonnell Douglas MD-11 will replace a DC-10.</p>
<p>This will at least double cargo lift on the route to between 12 and 14 tonnes capacity on each flight a Varig cargo official said.</p>
<p>In first quarter 1997, air cargo exports from Paris to Sao Paulo totalled 3,550 tonnes, a 49.8 percent rise on the same period last year. -Reuters Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542-7706 Fax+5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
