<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="540798" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Dollar down vs yen in late Tokyo after JGBs slide.</title>
<headline>Dollar down vs yen in late Tokyo after JGBs slide.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>0618 GMT     2400 GMT	NYK CLOSE</p>
<p> USD/JPY	   125.75/85   126.30/33    126.03/13</p>
<p> USD/DEM	   1.7170/75    1.7167/70    1.7145/55</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The dollar slid against the yen in late Tokyo on Friday after a sharp drop in Japanese government bond (JGB) futures, which fell more than one full point. The dollar was higher against the mark.</p>
<p>Probable options-linked sales of dollars for yen, as well as loss-cut sales of marks for yen, also pressured the greenback lower, dealers said.  </p>
<p>The sharp drop in JGBs took the key 10-year futures contract down to close at 125.50 against Thursday's finish of 126.63.</p>
<p>Bond traders said sentiment was hurt by worries that life insurer Nissan Mutual Life Insurance may be forced to sell its assets, that include yen bonds, after the Finance Ministry ordered it in the morning to halt its operations except for servicing current customers.</p>
<p>This triggered fears of higher interest rates, as Japan's low interest rates were blamed for low investment returns that contributed to the firm's overall difficulties.  </p>
<p>Although a vague market rumour was sparked that the Bank of Japan (BOJ) may raise interest rates next month, this was later squelched by BOJ Governor Yasuo Matsushita, when he told a parliamentary panel the central bank would not tighten credit until it had confirmed Japan's economic recovery.</p>
<p>The Nissan Life news had originally sparked some dollar buying in early Tokyo trade, but the greenback's rise was blocked by talk of heavy options-related sales from 126.50 yen, dealers said. They said additional options-linked sales probably occurred in late Tokyo trade, helping push the dollar down against the yen.  </p>
<p>The greenback briefly fell as low as 125.70 yen, and while it later rebounded slightly, it was still below 126 yen by late Tokyo trade.</p>
<p>Dealers have said there were short-term exotic options positions in the market, with large positions of reverse knock-out options thought to have been taken with strike prices around 124 yen and knock-out prices of 127 to 127.30 yen.</p>
<p>Dealers said holders of the options were rumoured to have been be selling the dollar when it neared 127 yen to prevent their option positions being knocked out.  </p>
<p>Until JGBs fell in late trade, the greenback had been moving narrowly around 126.20 yen, with activity quiet as few operators were interested in actively taking on new positions ahead of a meeting between U.S. President Clinton and Japanese Prime Minister Hashimoto later on Friday, and the Group of Seven (G7) meeting on Sunday.</p>
<p>The dollar rose against the mark in late Tokyo, but dealers said this was mainly due to sales of marks for yen. The German currency slipped to around 73.32/35 yen by late Tokyo compared to 73.49 yen at midday. Much of the slide appeared to be due to loss-cut sales after it broke below 73.45 yen, dealers said.  </p>
<p>The mark's losses against the yen also pressured the dollar against the yen.</p>
<p>Additional selling of dollars for yen was detected from exporters, with some offers from securities firms at 126.30-35 yen, a trust bank dealer said.</p>
<p>Some offers were also likely to have come from Singapore-based overseas operators, a trust bank dealer said.</p>
<p>-- Elaine Lies in Tokyo +81-3-3432-8806</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
