<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54103" id="root" date="1996-09-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Palestinians plan to reopen a Hebron market.</title>
<headline>Palestinians plan to reopen a Hebron market.</headline>
<dateline>HEBRON, West Bank 1996-09-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian officials met on Saturday in Hebron and decided to reopen a market in the West Bank town closed since 1994 when a Jewish settler shot dead 29 Arab worshippers at the nearby Tomb of the Patriarchs.</p>
<p>&quot;We will go on Monday and we will reopen shops there,&quot; said Hebron Mayor Mustafa Natshe. &quot;The Taba agreement we signed last year with Israel says it should be reopened, but Israel keeps delaying. Israel does not implement what was agreed upon.&quot;</p>
<p>The fruit and vegetable market is situated near the Jewish settlement of Avraham Aveenu. After the meeting, Palestinian officials said they anticipated problems on Monday re-opening the market.</p>
<p>Under an accord signed with the PLO, Israel had agreed to redeploy its troops from Hebron in March but delayed the move after a series of Islamic suicide bombings. Hebron is the only West Bank city with a Jewish settler population.</p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, elected in May, opposed the Hebron deal made by his predecessor Shimon Peres and says he wants to revise the plan to safeguard about 400 Jewish settlers who live among the more than 100,000 Palestinians.</p>
<p>Palestinians view a troop withdrawal as a litmus test for Netanyahu's intentions on Middle Est peace moves and reject any renegotiation of the Hebron agreement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HEBRON, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
