<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541026" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: U.S. to announce easier visa policy for HK - radio.</title>
<headline>U.S. to announce easier visa policy for HK - radio.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States is about to announce a relaxed visa policy for Hong Kong people after the British-ruled territory reverts to Chinese control in July, Hong Kong radio said on Friday.</p>
<p>A formal announcement would be made by U.S. Consul-General Richard Boucher and Hong Kong Immigration Director Regina Ip later in the day, the government radio station said.</p>
<p>It said it was expected that Washington would put holders of future Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (SAR) passports to be issued after the handover on an equal footing with limited British travel documents held by some Hong Kong people now.</p>
<p>This would mean Hong Kong residents who use SAR passports would have relatively quick access to U.S. multiple-entry visas, making travel much easier, the radio said.</p>
<p>The two million holders of British National Overseas passports enjoy this right now.</p>
<p>But most of the rest of Hong Kong's 6.4 million population who have to travel on other Hong Kong documents, such as the Certificate of Identity, have until now faced tough visa requirements.</p>
<p>They will be eligible for the new SAR passport.</p>
<p>Hong Kong reverts to China on July 1 after more than 150 years of British colonial rule.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
