<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54121" id="root" date="1996-09-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Saddam surprises again, stepping back from brink.</title>
<headline>Saddam surprises again, stepping back from brink.</headline>
<byline>Dominic Evans</byline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-09-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saddam Hussein seems to have bowed to U.S. might by halting attacks on planes in Iraqi no-fly zones but his apparent concession may scupper U.S. attempts to rally its allies against him, analysts said on Saturday.</p>
<p>They said it was not clear if Saddam's latest manoeuvring, on the brink of military showdown with Washington, was a sign of weakness or opportunism.</p>
<p>Whatever his motive, the Iraqi leader had once again shown himself to be a master of unpredictability.</p>
<p>&quot;One has to be cautious. I'm not sure Saddam Hussein himself has decided his strategy right now,&quot; said a Western diplomat who follows Iraq closely.</p>
<p>Analysts said Saddam may well have been surprised by U.S. President Bill Clinton's resolve to face up to Baghdad by sending thousands of troops and a formidable air and naval force to the Gulf.</p>
<p>But by stopping attacks on U.S. and allied warplanes flying over Iraq's northern and southern no-fly zones, Saddam has limited Washington's chances of bringing that overwhelming military superiority into play.</p>
<p>&quot;He may have miscalculated the Americans...but at the same time he has now wrong-footed them,&quot; said London-based Middle East expert John Roberts. &quot;The Americans have got all their toys in place and no one to play with.&quot;</p>
<p>The United States, which launched punitive missile strikes last week in response to Saddam's military foray into the northern city of Arbil, said it would be watching for &quot;actions not statements&quot; from Iraq.</p>
<p>Iraqi exiles in Jordan said Saddam was responding to the only kind of warning he understood -- brute force -- and that the threat of U.S. action may force him to keep his head down.</p>
<p>&quot;Saddam builds his own position on the reaction of others,&quot; said Haroun Mohamed, spokesman for the Iraqi National Accord opposition group in Jordan. &quot;It appears that yesterday he finally realised that the U.S. preparations were serious.&quot;</p>
<p>Diplomats said Saddam's next move may be influenced by how much he feels he has gained from his alliance with Kurdish faction leader Massoud Barzani, whose forces swept through Arbil and Sulaimaniya this month to take control of northern Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;If Saddam feels he's won in the north and Barzani is a reliable ally, he may think it's worth backing down (with the U.S.,&quot; one diplomat said.</p>
<p>Others warned against trying to second-guess the Iraqi leader, who led his country into eight years of destructive war with Iran before his 1990 invasion of Kuwait and defeat in the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>They said as long as he could be seen to be standing up to the United States once again, Saddam might take the risk of facing a few more bombs and missiles.</p>
<p>&quot;His victory doesn't depend on winning militarily,&quot; one diplomat said.</p>
<p>&quot;We keep thinking we are dealing with Saddam as a rational leader,&quot; said Roberts. &quot;We are not.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are dealing with a myth he constructed about himself as a fighter for Arab rights against the wicked imperialist West. The more he challenges the U.S., the more this myth is fed.&quot;</p>
<p>But he added that Saddam may have finally learned a lesson from his 1990 invasion of Kuwait, when a partial withdrawal from the emirate could have fatally split the U.S.-led coalition which rallied against Baghdad.</p>
<p>&quot;For the first time he could be realising that two steps forward followed by one step back makes sense. If that's the case, it makes him all the more dangerous an enemy,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
