<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541336" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Buba's Hesse sees scope for EMU deficit overshoot.</title>
<headline>Buba's Hesse sees scope for EMU deficit overshoot.</headline>
<dateline>WILHELMSHAVEN, Germany 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bundesbank council member Helmut Hesse said on Thursday European Union political leaders had room to allow a small overshoot of the Maastricht Treaty's deficit criterion which sets a reference level of three percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>&quot;The deficit criterion will not be regarded as fulfilled or not fulfilled by looking at the statistics. It will be a political decision,&quot; Hesse told reporters after holding a speech on monetary union in this northern town.</p>
<p>&quot;The political leaders have a certain scope for interpretation but I am convinced that scope cannot be large becuase that would cast doubt in the financial markets and... would give the euro a difficult start.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if a deficit rate of 3.1 percent or 3.2 percent would still be acceptable to allow a country to qualify for the single currency, Hesse said: &quot;It is not up to the Bundesbank to decide on the whether, when and how. If a decision was taken to allow 3.1 percent, I would look at the reasons and see if they are convincing. If they were, I would say okay.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;I can't say where the border lies between acceptable or unacceptable. I would say the scope is very narrow.&quot;</p>
<p>Hesse also said there was much to suggest that the EU population could be sure that the euro would be solid.</p>
<p>He noted that European heads of state and government had stressed at their summit meeting in Dublin last December that the convergence criteria must be applied strictly to guarantee that the euro would be a hard currency.</p>
<p>Hesse also said that doubts about the stability of the euro could be countered &quot;if the procedure to fix the entry rates with which the individual currency will join the monetary union was stated at an early date.&quot;  </p>
<p>Several independent economists have cast doubt on Germany's ability to meet the deficit criterion exactly in 1997 -- the key year for deciding which countries will take part in monetary union.</p>
<p>Hesse also said that the Bundesbank's central policy council wants to continue with its &quot;steady hand policy&quot; on interest rates if conditions allow but he added that the Bundesbank reviewed its monetary policy every 14 days.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WILHELMSHAVEN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
