<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541350" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey's Ciller to pull out of government - paper.</title>
<headline>Turkey's Ciller to pull out of government - paper.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leading Turkish newspaper said on Friday that Tansu Ciller, the deputy prime minister, would pull her True Path Party (DYP) out of the governing coalition with Islamists in a row over religious activism.</p>
<p>The Yeni Yuzyil daily quoted unnamed cabinet ministers as saying conservative Ciller, also the foreign minister, had decided to quit the 10-month-old government. True Path officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>&quot;The feeling among the DYP is that Ciller has definitely decided to pull out,&quot; wrote Yeni Yuzyil columnist Bilal Cetin, a leading political analyst.</p>
<p>Turkish stocks dropped 4.9 percent on Thursday on fears the alliance with Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan's Welfare Party was crumbling. Ciller's faction is uneasy at Welfare's failure to implement an anti-Islamist crackdown demanded by the army.</p>
<p>Erbakan, secularist Turkey's first Islamist leader, will face the generals at a meeting of the National Security Council on Saturday that has been billed as a showdown.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
