<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541356" id="root" date="1997-04-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-FAXON USES SWING TIP TO SHARE GREENSBORO LEAD WITH KITE.</title>
<headline>GOLF-FAXON USES SWING TIP TO SHARE GREENSBORO LEAD WITH KITE.</headline>
<dateline>GREENSBORO, North Carolina 1997-04-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brad Faxon, boosted by an unsolicited swing tip from a television commentator, fired a seven-under-par 65 Saturday to tie Tom Kite for the lead after three rounds of the Greater Greensboro Chrysler Classic.</p>
<p>Faxon reeled off six birdies in an eight-hole stretch in ideal conditions at Forest Oaks, which in the absence of any significant breeze played about as easily as possible.</p>
<p>Joint halfway leader Kite had an impressive stretch of his own, compiling four birdies in six holes on his way to a 67.</p>
<p>Faxon and Kite were at 14-under 202 with one round left, three strokes ahead of fellow-Americans Robert Damron (67), Jerry Kelly (68), Kirk Triplett (69) and South African Ernie Els (67).</p>
<p>With a forecast for inclement weather for Sunday, Faxon and Kite both felt an extra urgency to take the lead, aware of the possibility that the final round could be washed out.</p>
<p>&quot;I got off to a slow start, then made a putt from off the green (for a birdie at the fourth),&quot; Faxon said. &quot;After that I hit every iron shot at the flag.</p>
<p>&quot;It was the best I've hit my iron shots in a long time. I felt all I had to do was aim and shoot. I knew it was right on the range. My irons were radar-like.&quot;</p>
<p>Faxon could thank Bob Kostis, after receiving a tip Friday from the instructor-turned-television commentator.</p>
<p>&quot;He told me my left shoulder wasn't getting behind the ball,&quot; explained Faxon, who won at New Orleans three weeks ago, missed the cut at the Masters, then finished second at Hilton Head Island last week.</p>
<p>Kite, winless on the PGA Tour for more than four years, moved within sight of his 20th victory with a tidy round that included just one bogey.</p>
<p>&quot;This was an important round. We don't know whether it was moving day or final day,&quot; he said. &quot;I knew what Brad had shot. I knew I had to make some birdies and make them quick.</p>
<p>&quot;It was great to play well, get back in contention and hit some wonderful iron shots when I knew I had to. I'm really happy with my game.</p>
<p>&quot;It's hitting on just about all cylinders. I'm feeling good. I've got the right amount of nervousness.&quot;</p>
<p>A victory here would boost Kite to just outside the top 10 on the U.S. Ryder Cup standings. Kite is captain of the U.S. team that will try to regain the cup from Europe in September, and he reiterated that he did not know whether he would play, even if he qualified.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know if it's feasible to be a playing captain,&quot; Kite said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GREENSBORO, North Carolina"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
