<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541310" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Switzerland - April 25.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Switzerland - April 25.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights from Swiss newspapers on Friday:</p>
<p>NEUE ZUERCHER ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- Three-day special session of Swiss parliament starting next Monday will debate a government-proposed package of investment spending and tax cuts aimed at reviving the economy after seven years of stagnation. The package would have the federal government put up 561 million Swiss francs as the nucleus of a total 2.4 billion francs including cantonal administrations.</p>
<p>- The Vatican is moving Archbishop Karl-Josef Rauber, apostolic nuncio in Bern, to Budapest as envoy there. No reason was given. Rauber came to Switzerland in 1991 at the request of Swiss bishops to help settle a conflict between Chur Bishop Wolfgang Haas and the Chur lay organisations. But the conflict over Haas' style of leadership has countinued to escalate.</p>
<p>TAGES ANZEIGER</p>
<p>- Swiss cabinet may propose giving Federal Prosecutor Carla Del Ponte authority to take over from start to finish in cases of major business crime, including leading the trial in court. Earlier proposals to widen federal jurisdiction had been limited to giving Del Ponte the lead in investigating big business crimes but left the trials to local prosecutors.</p>
<p>- Swiss government decided to preserve a railway track between Lucerne and Lenzburg although a bus connection would be much cheaper. But the restoration work will be reduced to a minimum and cost 200 million instead of 600 million Swiss francs.</p>
<p>- Swiss federal debt totaled 88 billion Swiss francs in 1996. Since 1990, Swiss federal debt have doubled.</p>
<p>- Swiss Greenpeace branch said it will launch a national referendum to ban genetically manipulated food.</p>
<p>JOURNAL DE GENEVE</p>
<p>- Swiss Federal Office for Communication presented plans that would allow two additional competitors on the Swiss mobile telephone market, which will be opened on Janary 1, 1998.</p>
<p>- Swiss government submitted a new offer to the European Union on finishing bilateral talsk on land traffic rules. Sources say in the offer, Berne lowers its previous minimum price of 600 Swiss francs per lorry in transit fees. The EU has said the levy cannot go over 340 Swiss francs.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
