<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541354" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine banks still strong but haunted.</title>
<headline>Philippine banks still strong but haunted.</headline>
<byline>Ramoncito dela Cruz</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The financial stability of Philippine commercial banks remains solid despite jitters over booming loans, fears of a property market collapse and troubles at one thrift bank, industry leaders said on Friday.</p>
<p>The bogey of increasing bad debts, especially after a property and consumer lending spree, has cast some doubts on the sustainability of the sector's income growth.</p>
<p>The loan portfolio of some 50 commercial banks surged nearly 61 percent last year to 1.21 trillion pesos ($45 billion), Central Bank data shows. Total resources grew 51.3 percent last year to 1.93 trillion pesos.</p>
<p>Central Bank deputy governor Alberto Reyes said the growth in the loan portfolio of banks was due to the influx of 10 more foreign banks as well as an increase in local banks.</p>
<p>&quot;However, we do extensive evaluations on the quality of the loan portfolio every quarter... There's no report yet that these are found to be of poor quality,&quot; Reyes told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>The past due debt ratio of banks has declined in recent years to 3.04 percent by the end of 1996 from 3.23 percent in 1995 and 3.67 percent in 1994, according to Central Bank data.</p>
<p>Consumer loans as a percentage of the total loan portfolio have been kept to between one and two percent, although the past due ratio doubled to 5.88 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>International Monetary Fund (IMF) resident representative David Nellor said a recent increase in the minimum capital of banks should strengthen the banking system.</p>
<p>The most prominent alarm has come from the international credit rating group Moody's Investor Service, which last week counselled banks to maintain a cautious and prudent approach to avoid problems that accompany excessive growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The risk is that the Philipine banks (and corporations) may end up paying the same price of excessive growth and leverage that some other Asian banking systems are paying -- notably Thailand, Korea, and Japan -- after the 'bubble economy' bursts,&quot; Moody's said in its report.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a point well-taken, but banks, by nature, have always been cautious,&quot; Philippine National Bank senior executive vice president Valentin Araneta told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's always useful to learn from elsewhere. But we should not panic. It should be used more as useful warning device. It's not as though it's here tomorrow,&quot; the president of the Philippine Commercial International Bank, Rafael Buenaventura, said.</p>
<p>BPI Capital Corp president Jose Facundo agreed, saying that the banks were in fact under-leveraged. &quot;But to some extent, it's good that it's being talked about. People are, all of the sudden, shaken up,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Buenaventura said a series of minor incidents that had shaken banks -- including a debt moratorium sought by leading sugar miller Victorias Milling Corp and the temporary closure of a savings and mortgage bank, Monte de Piedad Savings and Mortgage Bank -- had not affected the industry as a whole.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not a reflection that the sky is falling. The banking sector continues to be strong. This particular bank, in a sense, is a victim to its own follies,&quot; Finance Secretary Roberto de Ocampo told reporters, refering to Monte de Piedad's problems. ($ =26.30)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
