<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541477" id="root" date="1997-04-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Blow for Major as best-selling paper backs Labour.</title>
<headline>Blow for Major as best-selling paper backs Labour.</headline>
<byline>David Ljunggren</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Beleaguered Prime Minister John Major was dealt a fresh blow on Saturday when Britain's best-selling Sunday newspaper deserted him for the opposition Labour party, clear favourite to win May 1 elections.</p>
<p>The News of the World, which sells around 4.5 million copies a week, said Major was no longer fit to rule Britain and should make way for Labour leader Tony Blair.</p>
<p>It is the second newspaper owned by media magnate Rupert Murdoch to switch from the ruling Conservatives, who have been in power for 18 years.</p>
<p>&quot;We back Blair, the man for the new millennium&quot; declared the newspaper in its front-page headline.</p>
<p>&quot;Britain is crying out for strong and moral leadership. John Major has provided neither,&quot; it said in an editorial which was made available to Reuters on Saturday ahead of publication.</p>
<p>Labour were further boosted when an opinion poll in the Sunday Mirror newspaper -- also released on Saturday -- gave them a hefty 24-point lead.</p>
<p>If Labour can maintain the double-digit lead it has enjoyed in every poll bar one during the five week campaign, Blair will be prime minister with a huge parliamentary majority.</p>
<p>The News of the World, which backed the Conservatives at the last three elections, accused Major of being too weak to stop either his party splitting over policy towards Europe or a series of scandals over sleaze.</p>
<p>&quot;His inability to make crucial decisions on Europe has irreparably divided the party,&quot; the paper said.</p>
<p>&quot;His weakness at dealing with infighting and political sleaze has brought nationwide contempt for a man who is simply incapable of being prime minister.&quot;</p>
<p>The tabloid Sun, Britain's best-selling daily newspaper, has already announced it is backing Labour.</p>
<p>The final weekend before polling brought no respite from bitter exchanges as the two parties traded charges that the other could not be trusted in power.</p>
<p>Labour hammered away at what it sees as a key weakness of the Conservatives -- voters' fears that it could put tax on food and other essentials.</p>
<p>But Major claimed the vibrant economy his party had created would disappear if Blair replaced him as prime minister after May 1, raising public spending, introducing a national minimum wage and giving trade unions greater powers.</p>
<p>The two parties united on only one thing -- their determination not to allow the Irish Republican Army to disrupt Thursday's poll.</p>
<p>Following a spate of incidents on the British mainland, the government has sent election officials instructions on how to deal with any bomb threats they may receive.</p>
<p>Conservative efforts to stage a dramatic last-week recovery in their electoral fortunes were hampered by newspaper reports of a rift at the top of the party over campaign tactics. Major dismissed the stories.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
