<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541513" id="root" date="1997-04-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Pope in Prague to urge European Christian unity.</title>
<headline>Pope in Prague to urge European Christian unity.</headline>
<byline>Nigel Stephenson</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-04-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pope John Paul, a day after calling for a religious rebirth in the Czech Republic, marks the 1,000th anniversary on Sunday of the death of a Czech saint seen as a symbol of European Christian unity.</p>
<p>The 76-year-old Pontiff is to hold an open air mass in Prague to commemorate the millenium of St Adalbert, the first bishop of Czech origin, who also took the gospel to the Pope's native Poland.</p>
<p>He is expected to evoke the saint, known as Vojtech in Czech, in an appeal for Europeans to seek unity in their common Christian roots.</p>
<p>After the mass on Prague's Letna Plain, scene of Soviet-era military parades and later of huge anti-communist protests, he is likely to press the cause of unity when he presides at an ecumenical service in the city's St Vitus Cathedral.</p>
<p>He called at a mass attended by some 50,000 mainly young people in the town of Hradec Kralove on Saturday for a revival of religion in the highly-secular Czech Republic.</p>
<p>&quot;The church needs you,&quot; the Pope told the crowd who braved drizzle in the 12th century town, 100 km (60 miles) east of Prague, to see him.</p>
<p>&quot;After 40 years of attempts to silence her, she (the church) is experiencing here among you a wonderful revival, even in the midst of many difficulties,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;You are living in a situation that, under certain aspects, is like the situation of the first Christians,&quot; he said, adding that young people had to spread the faith again.</p>
<p>The Pope, who has suffered a series of health problems in recent years, looked in relatively good form, reading his sermon in Czech and making several jokes.</p>
<p>After returning by helicopter to Prague, which he has visited three times since the fall of communism in 1989, he held private talks with Czech President Vaclav Havel and his wife Dagmar in Prague Castle.</p>
<p>At a later meeting with the sick and members of religious communities, he urged Czech leaders to be sensitive to the suffering in society.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to address a pressing appeal to the nation's leaders to be constantly sensitive to situations of suffering present in today's society,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Pope, who influenced events that led to the collapse of communism in Eastern Europe, has frequently cautioned against excessive materialism and he warned on Friday against hedonism imported from the West.</p>
<p>Havel, a former dissident playwright imprisoned by the communists and seen by many as the nation's conscience, has also spoken against importing Western junk culture and called for spiritual rebirth in a secular society.</p>
<p>The Pope, on the last day of his visit, also meets  Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus on Sunday for talks likely to touch on the thorny issue of the restitution of church property.</p>
<p>Church-state relations in communist Czechoslovakia, which split into the Czech and Slovak republics in 1993, were among the worst in the old East bloc and many church buildings were seized.</p>
<p>The church is still trying to secure the return of the lost property and Klaus has said he wants the issue resolved.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
