<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541545" id="root" date="1997-04-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Developing nations want better terms for debtors.</title>
<headline>Developing nations want better terms for debtors.</headline>
<byline>Peter Bate</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Developing countries, worried about falling levels of foreign aid, will seek more flexible terms for a new international initiative to ease the debt burden of the world's poorest nations.</p>
<p>A draft communique of the Group of 24 -- representing states in Asia, Africa and Latin America -- said the Highly Indebted Poor Countries Initiative (HIPC) should also kick in &quot;Terms (for the poor countries) should be made more flexible to enable more of the indebted countries to reach debt sustainability as early as possible,&quot; said the communique, which was obtained by Reuters on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;The time frames involved in getting countries to the decision and completion points need to be shortened, particularly for those that have already established strong performance track records.&quot;</p>
<p>The poor countries initiative was launched six months ago by the World Bank and the International Monetary Fund to reward poor countries that are carrying out tough economic reforms by providing them with debt relief.</p>
<p>Up to 25 countries, most in Africa, could benefit from the plan, which may cost multilateral and bilateral creditors as much as $7.7 billion.</p>
<p>Uganda was the first country to get agreement on a HIPC deal. On Wednesday the World Bank and the IMF agreed to support a plan that will cut its $3.4 billion debt by one fifth next April.</p>
<p>Other countries could face a wait of up to three years after the debt relief programs are approved and critics of the initiative complain that these rules mean the agreement could come late to be of much use.</p>
<p>World Bank President James Wolfensohn strongly defended the debt relief initiative, saying he was proud of what had been accomplished and dismayed by the attacks.</p>
<p>&quot;I was hoping in my dreams that when all this happened I would get a standing ovation,&quot; he told reporters on Friday. &quot;Instead of which people say, 'You're a son of a bitch.'&quot;</p>
<p>The G24 draft communique also noted that aid contributions from richer nations were inadequate, and urged them to provide more resources. It added that the IMF should consider selling some its gold reserves to supplement those contributions.</p>
<p>Developing countries believe that private capital flows cannot replace aid from industrialized nations and international organizations, which last year dropped to its lowest level in a decade.</p>
<p>&quot;The absence of adequate official development assistance funds would adversely affect the growth potential of recipient countries and would exacerbate migratory pressures on countries with better prospects,&quot; they warned.</p>
<p>Private capital movement to developing countries reached a record $200 billion last year, although almost 80 percent of it went to just a dozen countries.</p>
<p>Net official flows to developing countries were actually negative last year, against the $31 billion that they received in 1995, according to the IMF.</p>
<p>The G24 communique is due to be released on Sunday by ministers attending the IMF-World Bank spring meeting.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
