<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541731" id="root" date="1997-04-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.S. envoy Richardson may go to Zaire soon.</title>
<headline>U.S. envoy Richardson may go to Zaire soon.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-04-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bill Richardson, the U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, is expected to pay a surprise visit to Zaire shortly in an effort to get peace negotiations started, diplomats said.</p>
<p>U.S. sources said Richardson would be out of town next week. But on Friday they would not disclose his destination nor comment on the reports.</p>
<p>But the envoys, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said Richardson was likely to leave early in the week and that he hoped to see both Zairian President Mobuto Sese Seko and rebel leader Laurant Kabila.</p>
<p>A possible trip to Zaire would be in character for Richardson, who has carried out sensitive missions for the Clinton administration in Burma, Haiti and Iraq. He went to North Korea last November to nail down a nuclear agreement and win the release of a young American detained for three months on espionage charges.</p>
<p>The United States, Britain and France, among other nations, have been under pressure from Kofi Annan and his envoy, Mohammed Sahnoun, to use their influence to coax Kaibla and Mobutu to the negotiating table.</p>
<p>Sahnoun was reported by U.N. sources to be hopeful that talks could take place and wanted the United States to intervene in getting direct negotiations started.</p>
<p>Libreville, the capitol of Gabon, is the current frontrunner for such talks, although Brazzaville, Congo and Luanda, Rwanda are also being considered so that Mobutu, suffering from cancer, would not have to travel far.</p>
<p>Kabila also has faced a worldwide outcry after his forces in eastern Zaire refused to allow U.N. humanitarian groups to bring food to tens of thousands of Rwandan refugees caught amid Zaire's civil war.</p>
<p>He told Reuters in the southern city of Lubumbashi on Saturday that he was going to Kisangani, the main city of northeast Zaire, this weekend to tackle the crisis in person.</p>
<p>U.N. aid agency officials say that the rebels, who control the eastern half of Zaire, have chased the unwanted Rwandan Hutus out of camps from which relief groups and reporters are banned, driving them into the jungle to starve.</p>
<p>Annan has accused the rebels of instituting a policy of &quot;slow extermination,&quot; and in Geneva a U.N. World Food Program spokeswoman, drawing a comparison with Hitler's Germany, said: &quot;The expression 'Final Solution' is not exaggerated.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of the refugees fled in 1994 in fear of reprisals for the Hutu-led genocide of 800,000 Tutsis and Hutu moderates. In their midst were armed militia, widely regarded as killers in their homeland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
