<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541706" id="root" date="1997-04-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French premier under fire as poll puts him ahead.</title>
<headline>French premier under fire as poll puts him ahead.</headline>
<byline>Alister Doyle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe came under fire from a former close ally on Saturday as a poll showed the centre-right coalition would keep power in a snap parliamentary election with a clear but reduced majority.</p>
<p>Former interior minister Charles Pasqua, who has opposed a single European currency favoured by Juppe's government, said France needed a radical shift in policy for the May 25-June 1 National Assembly election.</p>
<p>&quot;The start of this campaign does not seem to match the challenges,&quot; Pasqua told about 500 supporters in a theatre in a Paris suburb in the most overt sniping yet at Juppe from a senior member of his Rally for the Republic (RPR) party.</p>
<p>&quot;The French people must be rallied around a new policy,&quot; he said. He said France was trapped in pincers of unpopular budget austerity, aimed at helping France qualify for a single European currency from 1999, and damaging market liberalisation.</p>
<p>Pasqua said France's 12.8 percent unemployment rate was the main issue. He did not mention Juppe by name and ended by urging his followers to give full backing to RPR candidates.</p>
<p>Pasqua, who was interior minister from 1993-95 and a leader of the &quot;no&quot; campaign when voters approved the Maastricht Treaty on European union in a 1992 referendum, also said voters should be consulted again on the single currency, the euro.</p>
<p>An IFOP survey showed the centre-right coalition would keep a pared National Assembly majority where it now has 464 of 577 seats -- a relief for Juppe and conservative President Jacques Chirac after a previous survey showed a far closer race.</p>
<p>Chirac, risking his presidency by calling the elections, says he wants to give France a new impulse, partly to enable it to join a single European currency from a position of strength.</p>
<p>The survey, to be published on Sunday in the Journal du Dimanche, showed the RPR-UDF coalition would win between 311 and 331 seats, the Socialists between 200 and 220, Communists between 19 and 25, and the far-right National Front up to three.</p>
<p>Opposition Socialist leader Lionel Jospin, trying to shake off a professorial air, spent the day in Cintegabelle, the south-western constituency where he is seeking election. He chatted with locals and bought lily of the valley in a market.</p>
<p>Juppe spent the day in the nearby city of Bordeaux where he is mayor, like Jospin on a first day campaigning for his personal election. Juppe strolled the streets and admired a group of children dressed as cartoon characters.</p>
<p>Jospin reiterated charges that Chirac and Juppe were covering up the true size of France's budget deficit and staging the election early in hopes of clearing the decks for a new bout of austerity cuts to qualify for the single currency.</p>
<p>&quot;The first measure we will decide is an audit of the financial situation and of the economic and social accounts of the country,&quot; Jospin told the Journal du Dimanche. &quot;We must establish the reality.&quot;</p>
<p>The government has said that France is on track with current policies to meet criteria for the euro.</p>
<p>Juppe reiterated a challenge to Jospin to agree to a four-way television debate on May 20 together with UDF leader Francois Leotard and Communist Robert Hue. He said it would be &quot;very interesting&quot; to hear Jospin and Hue's views -- Hue is opposed to a single European currency while Jospin is in favour.</p>
<p>Hue also held a first meeeting in his constituency of Argenteuil near Paris and told voters to choose Communists to avoid a &quot;new turn of the screws&quot; of austerity by Juppe.</p>
<p>Extreme-right leader Jean Marie Le Pen, accusing Chirac of trying to destroy his anti-immigrant National Front party, said he would launch an aggressive campaign aimed at smashing the mould of French politics.</p>
<p>He said the Front would campaign under the slogan &quot;Get them Out!&quot; -- referring to incumbents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
