<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541722" id="root" date="1997-04-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Duesseldorf airport settles with insurers.</title>
<headline>Duesseldorf airport settles with insurers.</headline>
<dateline>DUESSELDORF, Germany 1997-04-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Duesseldorf airport's operating company and six insurers have agreed an out-of-court settlement over a fire insurance claim from a 1996 blaze which destroyed large parts of the airport, the leading insurer said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The blaze, which killed 17 people, was one of the worst fire catastrophes in German post-war history.</p>
<p>The airport company will now receive 245 million marks ($142 million) &quot;within days&quot;, Provinzial-Feuerversicherungsanstalt der Rheinprovinz said on Saturday. The airport's supervisory board had agreed to the settlement on 25 April.</p>
<p>The settlement is considerably below the 350 million marks originally estimated for the loss, and also far less than the rebuilding costs.</p>
<p>However, the high costs of rebuilding parts of the airport are partly due to a different design and to higher safety standards, introduced at the insistence of the authorities, Provinzial said.</p>
<p>The six insurers had made reserves totalling 350 million marks, but had also argued that they might not be obliged to pay at all as they said the airport had broken a number of safety rules and was therefore in breach of contract.</p>
<p>Provinzial carried 40 percent of the risk.</p>
<p>Three other unlisted insurers are part of the consortium: Landschaftliche Brandkasse Hannover with 20 percent and Westfaelische Provinzial-Feuersozietaet of Muenster and Provinzial Brandkasse Versicherungsanstalt Schleswig-Holstein of Kiel with 10 percent each.</p>
<p>In addition publicly quoted insurers Wuerttembergische Versicherung AG, Stuttgart, and Nordstern Versicherungs-AG, Cologne, each carry 10 percent.</p>
<p>The companies have reinsured most of the risk. Experts believe that the reinsurers will pay more than 90 percent of the total.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Provinzial had said it was now also paying the liability claims of the victims' families.</p>
<p>In 1996, advances of up to 70,000 marks had been paid, but further payments were delayed by legal problems, as the airport did not admit liability. The insurers will now pay regardless.</p>
<p>Provinzial said it expected the liability claims to total less than 20 million marks.</p>
<p>Baggage and other small claims totalled less than one million marks and were settled shortly after the fire.</p>
<p>Other claims, not directly fire-related, against other insurers from Deutsche Lufthansa AG's loss-of-profit insurance and from shops in the airport are also being settled. They total around 70 million marks.</p>
<p>-- Bonn newsroom +49-228-26097160 ($ = 1.727 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUESSELDORF, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
