<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54204" id="root" date="1996-09-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Britons work longest hours in Europe - Swedish study.</title>
<headline>Britons work longest hours in Europe - Swedish study.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-09-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britons work the longest hours in Europe, according to a study by Sweden's central statistics bureau published on Saturday.</p>
<p>Statistics Sweden said Britons on average worked 43.8 hours a week in 1995, excluding overtime.</p>
<p>Portugal came second in the list working an average 41.9 hours a week, said the report, published in Swedish newspaper Dagens Nyheter. Swedes were third, working 40.7 hours, which the study said added up to two and a half weeks a year more than 10 years ago.</p>
<p>Greece was fourth with 40.8 hours but this included overtime while the other countries surveyed involved only basic hours. Spaniards worked 40.6 hours, the Irish and French 40.1 hours, and Germans 39.9 hours.</p>
<p>Ninth was Luxembourg with 39.8 hours, the Netherlands notched up 39.6 hours, Denmark 39.5 hours, Norway 38.8 hours, Italy 38.6 hours, and Finland 38.4 hours.</p>
<p>Belgians came last, working on average 38.4 hours a week.</p>
<p>The report is to be officially released later this month. REUTER  140935 GMT sep 96</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
