<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="542025" id="root" date="1997-04-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Grupo Financiero Serfin posts Q1 profit.</title>
<headline>Grupo Financiero Serfin posts Q1 profit.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-04-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's Grupo Financiero Serfin SA de CV said on Sunday that its first quarter 1997 profits totaled 46 million pesos, or US$0.01 a share.</p>
<p>New accounting principles in Mexico for 1997 changed how results are reported and are not comparable to 1996 figures.</p>
<p>For all of 1996, Grupo Financiero Serfin reported a loss of 7.0 billion pesos, or US$2.04 per ADR. Results for last year's first quarter were not immediately available.  </p>
<p>A Reuters' forecast of seven banking analysts had predicted a quarterly profit at the group level of $0.04 per ADR.</p>
<p>Banca Serfin, a publicly traded unit of Grupo Financiero Serfin, reported a net loss of 30 million pesos, while Operadora de Bolsa Serfin, the group's brokerage unit, posted a net profit of 77 million, Serfin said in a statement.</p>
<p>The bank unit's ratio of allowance for loan losses to past due loans was 58.5 percent at the end of the first quarter, while its capitalization index was 13.2 percent, it said.  </p>
<p>Serfin said its bank unit's net interest margin during the third quarter was 3.2 percent, a level the bank said was very close to its break-even point.</p>
<p>Serfin said it created no new reserves against bad loans during the quarter. &quot;Banca Serfin considers its actual levels of reserves in regard to its loan portfolio quality to be adequate,&quot; it said in the statement.</p>
<p>The bank unit reported operating income of 40 million during the first quarter.  </p>
<p>&quot;As a result of the new Mexican accounting principles, however, the amount of past due loans held by UDIs trusts increased, thereby resulting in a net loss...&quot; the group said.</p>
<p>UDIs are inflation indexed units used by Mexican banks as part of their lending portfolio.</p>
<p>The bank said its core deposits at the end of the quarter were 26.903 billion pesos, compared to 26.849 billion pesos at the end of last year.</p>
<p>The group added that it planned to offer banking services at some 450 stores at Mexican retailer Grupo Elektra at the end of the second quarter.</p>
<p>Serfin was perhaps the hardest hit of the major Mexican banks by the 1994-1995 peso crisis. During the past year, it was forced to sell billions of dollars in loans to the government in exchange for stock that gave the government a chunk of the formerly state-owned bank.</p>
<p>Serfin agreed in principle during March to sell a 19.9 percent equity stake in the group to HSBC Holding Plc. at a value estimated at about $300 million.</p>
<p>((--David Luhnow, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9565))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
