<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="542093" id="root" date="1997-04-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK's Tung, China discuss young Chinese illegals.</title>
<headline>HK's Tung, China discuss young Chinese illegals.</headline>
<byline>Carrie Lee</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-04-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's future leader Tung Chee-hwa urged parents on Sunday to resist the temptation to smuggle their China-born children into the territory.</p>
<p>He was speaking at a news conference in Hong Kong after returning from a meeting at which he discussed ways of stemming the tide of illegal child immigrants with Guangdong provincial governor Lu Ruihua and other senior Chinese officials.</p>
<p>&quot;They should not take the risk of sneaking into Hong Kong,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The majority of children spirited into Hong Kong come from the southern province of Guangdong, which borders on Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Tung said his office would map out a policy on how to handle the flood of these children.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to review the whole situation in light of law, in light of humilitarian consideration and in light of our ability to take up,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Fears of a sudden influx of Chinese children have escalated in recent months as their number has soared on rumours of an amnesty after Britain hands Hong Kong back to China after more than 150 years of colonial rule.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no amnesty, not today nor tomorrow,&quot; Tung said, reiterating earlier statements.</p>
<p>Hundreds of Hong Kong parents pay human smugglers, known as snakeheads, to spirit their China-born children into the British colony.</p>
<p>Hong Kong operates a quota system, allowing 150 mainland-born people, 66 of them children, into Hong Kong each day to join their families here.</p>
<p>Social workers estimate that 30,000 to 130,000 children living in China are eligible to be reunited with their families in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Most of them were fathered by Hong Kong men and born to mainland Chinese women. Both the mother and the children have to apply for residency rights to join their husbands in Hong Kong -- a process which can take years.</p>
<p>Under Hong Kong's post-colonial constitution, a Chinese child will have right of abode here after July 1 if, at the time, one of his parents is a permanent Hong Kong resident.</p>
<p>Earlier last week, immigration officials, in an unusual use of force, plucked an eight-year-old girl and her mother, both illegal immigrants, from their home and deported them to China.</p>
<p>Scores of demonstrators protested outside Tung's office on Saturday over plans to curb civil liberties after the handover.</p>
<p>His proposed legislative amendements to curtail civil freedoms would require prior approval for street protests and would ban the foreign funding of Hong Kong political parties.</p>
<p>Elsie Leung, the future secretary of justice, said the amendments must be in place by the handover.</p>
<p>On Saturday, members of the China-appointed provisional legislature, which will replace the current elected legislature upon the handover, challenged Tung's proposals during a meeting in southern China's Shenzhen across the border.</p>
<p>A member said restrictions on street demonstrations represented political regression, while another questioned whether Tung's 1992 donation of 50,000 sterling (US$81,500) to Britain's Conservative Party ran counter to his own proposed ban on foreign funding to local political groups.</p>
<p>Tung has said the thriving capitalist enclave needed the amendments to strike a balance between civil liberties and social stability.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
