<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="542134" id="root" date="1997-04-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Sino-British row over HK's airport - chronology.</title>
<headline>Sino-British row over HK's airport - chronology.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-04-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>For more than five years, Britain and China locked horns over Hong Kong's new airport, turning the US$20.3-billion project into arguably the world's most expensive political football.</p>
<p>But Hong Kong quietly got on with the construction and on Sunday, the spectacular Tsing Ma suspension bridge, a vital link to the new airport, was due to be opened to the crack of fireworks by former British prime minister Margaret Thatcher.</p>
<p>The following is a chronology of the airport dispute.</p>
<p>DECEMBER 19, 1984 - Britain and China sign a Joint Declaration under which London promises to return Hong Kong in 1997 and Beijing promises that the territory will keep its present lifestyle and a high degree of autonomy for 50 years.</p>
<p>JUNE 4, 1989 - Chinese forces kill protesters near Beijing's Tiananmen Square, provoking mass protests in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>OCTOBER 11, 1989 - Then Governor David Wilson unveils the ambitious port and airport development plan to cost HK$127 billion (US$16.3 billion). The project is billed as a demonstration of confidence in Hong Kong's future and the first runway would be ready by 1997.</p>
<p>China immediately warns Hong Kong it has reservations and may not give the approvals needed for Hong Kong to tap the capital markets to fund the airport.</p>
<p>JUNE 15, 1990 - Provisional Airport Authority inaugurated.</p>
<p>JANUARY 20-23, 1991 - Then Governor Sir David Wilson visits Beijing but fails to secure breakthrough on airport funding.</p>
<p>MARCH 3-14 1991 - Director of China's Hong Kong and Macau Affairs Office, Lu Ping, visits Hong Kong and discusses airport.</p>
<p>APRIL 3-8, 1991 - British Foreign Minister Douglas Hurd visits Beijing and fails to secure breakthough on airport.</p>
<p>April 24 - Hong Kong begins land clearance on Chek Lap Kok, site of the new airport.</p>
<p>JUNE 27 - British foreign affairs advisor and former ambassador to China Percy Cradock flies to Beijing. Hammers out basis of agreement, arranges visit to China by British Prime Minister John Major, the first major head of government to visit since the Tiananmen Square crackdown.</p>
<p>SEPTEMBER 3, 1991 - Major and Chinese Premier Li Peng sign a Memorandum of Understanding. The signing effectively gives China a say in all key decisions connected to the airport and other business affairs spanning 1997.</p>
<p>MAY 1992 - China rejects first Hong Kong funding plan.</p>
<p>JULY 7, 1992 - Chris Patten is sworn in as the 28th governor of Hong Kong.</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 1992 - Legislative Council approves equity advance to start site formation work at Chek Lap Kok.</p>
<p>JUNE 24, 1994 - Britain and China negotiators agree to draft a minute on funding, expected to take a few days. Drafting drags on for more than five months.</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 4, 1994 - Drafting is concluded. Chinese and British negotiators sign broad funding funding agreement.</p>
<p>JUNE 29, 1995 - Sino-British negotiators agree in principle on Financial Support Agreements, the documents guaranteeing funding repayments</p>
<p>JUNE 30, 1995 - Britain and China sign Financial Support Agreements</p>
<p>MAY 30, 1996 - Britain and China agree to build a second runway at Chek Lap Kok following smooth negotiations</p>
<p>FEBRUARY, 19, 1997 - First airplane lands at Chek Lap Kok, work begins on calibrating instruments ahead of planned opening in April 1998.</p>
<p>APRIL 27, 1997 - Former prime minister Margaret Thatcher opens Tsing Ma suspension bridge, key road and rail link to the offshore airport.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020006">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
