<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="542119" id="root" date="1997-04-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: N.Korea to top Japan minister's agenda in Seoul.</title>
<headline>N.Korea to top Japan minister's agenda in Seoul.</headline>
<byline>Jane Lee</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-04-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A three-day visit to Seoul by Japan's defense minister is expected to focus on regional security as concern mounts over a possible military threat by North Korea, South Korean officials said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The South Korean National Defence Ministry said Fumio Kyuma and his counterpart, Kim Dong-jin, on Monday would discuss &quot;the current situation on the Korean peninsula and security in the region along with ways to enhance cooperation between the two militaries&quot;.</p>
<p>A top Pyongyang defector was quoted last week as saying North Korea poses a threat to the south and to Japan. North Korean leaders have been growing increasingly desperate as their country slides into famine.</p>
<p>Japanese parliamentary sources said the ministers were expected to discuss in detail North Korea's war footing, especially its long-range missiles.</p>
<p>On April 14, Japanese Foreign Minister Yukihiko Ikeda told parliament there were unconfirmed reports that North Korea may have deployed Rodong-1 ballistic missiles, capable of hitting all parts of Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not that we confirmed this,&quot; Ikeda said, &quot;but there are reports that (North Korea) has developed missiles with a range of more than 1,000 km (625 miles). There are certain reports that some of them have been deployed.&quot;</p>
<p>It was the first time a Japanese government official commented publicly on the possibility that North Korea may have completed development of the Rodong-1 missile.</p>
<p>To top the threat, Pyongyang's top defector, Hwang Jang-yop, who arrived in Seoul last Sunday, was quoted on Tuesday in a local daily as saying North Korea could turn the capitalist South into a &quot;sea of flames&quot; and scorch Japan in a nuclear attack if the United States tried to intervene.</p>
<p>Hwang's report, published in the Chosun Ilbo, did not make it clear whether the North already possessed nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>The United Nations' nuclear watch dog, the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA), has never been able to confirm whether the North has a nuclear device, but insists it has fissionable material it is not owning up to. The North has refused inspectors the right to check its atomic sites.</p>
<p>A South Korean defence ministry spokesman told Reuters that politics would not be part of the visiting Kyuma's agenda.</p>
<p>But, there is still simmering resentment against Japan, which occupied the Korean peninsula for 35 years until 1945.</p>
<p>South Korean women who were forced into sexual slavery by the Japanese army during World War Two and referred to as &quot;comfort women&quot; are still demanding an official apology from Tokyo.</p>
<p>And ownership of a scattering of rocky islets off South Korea's east coast is another thorny issue.</p>
<p>Kyuma's visit follows the docking by Japanese warships last September in the southern port of Pusan -- the first such docking since World War Two.</p>
<p>That visit was meant as a good will gesture between the two countries, but it sparked criticism by anti-Japanese groups.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
