<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54225" id="root" date="1996-09-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Scandals cause rift between India's Rao, reformer. [CORRECTED 14:45 GMT]</title>
<headline>Scandals cause rift between India's Rao, reformer. [CORRECTED 14:45 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Narayanan Madhavan</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-09-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Corruption scandals surrounding India's Congress party have caused a rift between former Prime Minister P.V. Narasimha Rao and his economic reforms architect, Manmohan Singh, analysts said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;Caesar's wife should be above suspicion,&quot; Singh was quoted as saying in a rare political speech on Friday at a closed-door meeting of party lawmakers to discuss corruption scandals that have hit the image of senior leaders including Rao.</p>
<p>The remark suggested that senior party leaders should be transparently above corruption charges.</p>
<p>Analysts said the remark by Singh, who was finance minister in Rao's government which lost power in general elections this year, did not mean the two had fallen out, but showed a concern linked to Singh's own reputation for personal integrity.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a strong feeling in the party (against corruption). He is only giving vent to it,&quot; political columnist Kewal Varma told Reuters. &quot;One indication is that he is breaking away from Rao.&quot;</p>
<p>The Economic Times described Singh's remarks as a &quot;bonus&quot; for party dissidents who want Rao replaced as Congress president.</p>
<p>Rao took charge of the party, which has ruled India for all but four years since independence from Britain in 1947, after the assassination of former Prime Minister Rajiv Gandhi in 1991.</p>
<p>Newspapers said Singh made his remark on Friday while speaking on charges of corruption against former Communications Minister Sukh Ram, whom the party suspended after police raided his homes last month and found cash worth $1.0 million (Corrects amount found from $10 million).</p>
<p>Sukh Ram, currently in England, denies wrongdoing but has yet to explain the seizure.</p>
<p>Seven other ministers in Rao's government resigned this year to face bribes-for-favours charges in an $18 milion illegal foreign exchange scandal that became a key campaign issue during the April/May general elections this year.</p>
<p>Subsequently, Rao was accused by police in a vote-buying scandal linked to the 1993 no-confidence motion in parliament that his then-minority government won by a wafer-thin margin.</p>
<p>Rao faces a court summons he has contested in a &quot;cheating case&quot;. The case centres on allegations by an expatriate businessman that he paid $100,000 to a Rao acquaintance in 1983 in a failed bid to win a state contract.</p>
<p>The Central Bureau of Investigation also questioned Rao's son this year over a $40-million kickback scandal linked to fertiliser imports from Turkey.</p>
<p>Singh, who played a major part in instituting the economic reforms began by Rao in 1991, is not a career politician and has a clean image.</p>
<p>&quot;It may very well be that the party turns to him (at this juncture),&quot; political analyst Pran Chopra of the Centre for Policy Research told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't rule it  out,&quot; he said about talks of a rift with Rao, but added Singh could not have been accusing his leader.</p>
<p>&quot;His personal relationship (with Rao) and his temperament is such that he would not raise anything without substantial evidence.&quot;</p>
<p>But in the current  crisis faced by the party, Rao was an obvious target, he said. &quot;The situation is such that it (Singh's speech) automatically reflects on Rao.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
