<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="542286" id="root" date="1997-04-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany's Jagoda-97 jobless levels to remain high.</title>
<headline>Germany's Jagoda-97 jobless levels to remain high.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-04-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Labour Office President Bernhard Jagoda said on Sunday that he did not expect any significant fall in the average unemployment figure for Germany in 1997, but he did expect the employment situation to improve.</p>
<p>Jagoda said on German radio that he believed it was realistic to expect that the average jobless levels for 1997 would be four million or above, but said that levels of unemployment in the current quarter were very high.  </p>
<p>He said that the Labour Office needed more funding based on forecasts by economic institutes of an average jobless figure of 4.2 to 4.3 million unemployed.</p>
<p>The introduction of a shorter, 32-hour working week was not enough to solve the problem of unemployment in Germany, though it would help in some sectors. Flexible solutions needed to be found, Jagoda said.</p>
<p>Unadjusted unemployment -- the most politically sensitive jobs number in Germany -- fell in March to 4.48 million from 4.67 million in February, which was the highest since 1933. The seasonally-adjusted figure fell by 15,000 to 4.30 million.</p>
<p>The German government has based its plan to cut borrowing this year to meet the Maastricht treaty budget deficit goal of three percent of GDP, and thereby qualify for Europe's single currency, on a view that joblessness will average 4.2 million.</p>
<p>((--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
