<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="542259" id="root" date="1997-04-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Summit on volunteerism begins in Philadelphia.</title>
<headline>Summit on volunteerism begins in Philadelphia.</headline>
<byline>Randall Mikkelsen</byline>
<dateline>PHILADELPHIA 1997-04-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A three-day &quot;Presidents' Summit&quot; on volunteerism got underway on Sunday with an outdoor sunrise prayer service and a project to build a neighbourhood playground in a day.</p>
<p>Local pastors speaking at the service urged that the enthusiasm generated by the summit continue in their gritty northwest Philadelphia neighbourhood, which was to be visited and spruced up by U.S. President Bill Clinton, retired Gen. Colin Powell, and thousands of volunteers.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a beautiful day that the Lord has allowed the president to come to our community,&quot; said Pastor Kevin Simmons of the Taylor Memorial Baptist Church as the morning broke clear and warm.</p>
<p>&quot;But we've got to work hard even after he goes home,&quot; Simmons said, speaking at a park where volunteers began building a new playground to replace a dilapidated one nearby.</p>
<p>An estimated five thousand volunteers were enlisted to clean up an eight-mile stretch of Philadelphia's Germantown Ave. in the first day of a three-day &quot;summit&quot; to encourage volunteerism in support of America's youth living in poverty.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to turn America on for the next three days by showing what we can do,&quot; Powell said here on Saturday in preliminary festivities.</p>
<p>Clinton, Powell, and former Presidents Gerald Ford, Jimmy Carter and George Bush were to speak at a kickoff rally in the Marcus Foster sports stadium later on Sunday morning.</p>
<p>They were to join sports and entertainment stars, and corporate leaders in working with the volunteers along Germantown Ave. to remove graffiti, clean up vacant lots and build the playground.</p>
<p>&quot;Citizen service is neighbour helping neighbour,&quot; Clinton said in his weekly radio address on Saturday. &quot;It's part-time volunteers and full-time community service workers. It's communities coming together to solve common problems. And it is an essential part of what it means to be an American.&quot;</p>
<p>The summit aims to encourage more volunteerism in support of an estimated 15 million American children living in poverty, with a target of improving living conditions for two million of them by the year 2000.</p>
<p>This would require, on top of existing volunteer efforts, about one million Americans devoting an average of one day a week, said Terry Williams, a partner in McKinsey &amp; Co., a consulting firm that prepared a study on economic aspects of the summit for its organisers.</p>
<p>Joe Rubin, one of the volunteers helping to build the playground, said of the summit and its aims. &quot;I'm cynical, but I'm impressed.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said neighbourhood improvement projects need money as well as manpower. &quot;I don't think it's a lack of volunteers, I think it's more so a lack of funds,&quot; he said. &quot;Up to this point there obviously hasn't been much, and if there was it hasn't been channelled correctly.&quot;</p>
<p>Williams said an estimated 45 percent of Americans spend an average of five hours a week in volunteer service. But efforts also need to be refocused to helping youths before they get in trouble, he added. &quot;Very little is going into this subject today,&quot; Williams told Reuters.</p>
<p>The study estimated that meeting the goals of the summit would cost roughly $15 billion and produce some $89 billion in benefits in reducing problems such as drug and alcohol abuse, failure to complete high school, crime and unemployment.</p>
<p>Stuart Shapiro, chief organiser of the summit, acknowledged that the goal of assisting two million children was modest in comparison with the number needing help. &quot;It's a first step,&quot; he said. &quot;It's an achievable goal.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHILADELPHIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
