<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="542510" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - Republic sees '97 EPS of $0.70.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Republic sees '97 EPS of $0.70.</headline>
<byline>Michael Connor</byline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Quickly expanding Republic Industries should meet full-year 1997 share-profit estimates of $0.70, Republic chief financial officer Mike Karsher said on Monday.</p>
<p>All four Republic segments, including car retailing, performed well in the first quarter and the diversified services group expects to accelerate the pace of openings of its AutoNation used-car superstores in 1997, Karsher told Reuters.  </p>
<p>But Karsher cautioned the four or five new superstores being added to the 1997 schedule would not add to 1997 full-year profits since the outlets typically incur initial losses until sales volume picks up.</p>
<p>Republic is on an acquisition campaign. In the past six months it bought major car-rental agencies such as Alamo and car dealerships in many parts of the United States.</p>
<p>For the first quarter, Republic reported a doubling of share profits to $0.08 from the same period in 1996.</p>
<p>Karsher said the share profits were $0.01 higher than a consensus of Wall Street analysts forecasts.  </p>
<p>Net income grew even faster to $28.9 million from $12.4 million as revenues rose to $1.504 billion from $1.016 billion.</p>
<p>The company has greatly expanded its share base with its stock-swap acquistions and had average shares outstanding in the first quarter of 374 million, up from 283 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;All four business segments had very good quarters,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Republic has opened three AutoNation stores so far in 1997 and had planned to open 10 more this year, but was adding four or five stores.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased with the performance of the AutoNation stores,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Beyond auto sales and rentals, Republic sells security services and operates waste haulage businesses.</p>
<p>-- Miami newsroom - 305-374-5013.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I92110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
