<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54284" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: U.S. Treasury official talks of close Taiwan ties.</title>
<headline>U.S. Treasury official talks of close Taiwan ties.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Deputy Treasury Secretary Lawrence Summers on Sunday said Washington's economic ties with Taipei were becoming increasingly close.</p>
<p>Summers, the highest ranking U.S. official to visit the island since 1994, arrived in Taiwan on Saturday for Monday's one-day trade talks with Taiwanese officials.</p>
<p>Summers and his delegation were scheduled to meet vice economics minister Hsu Ke-sheng and other economic and foreign affairs officials in the one-day talks.</p>
<p>&quot;I very much am looking forward to our economic dialogue. Our economic relations are increasingly close, and I think we will have a lot to discuss and to work together,&quot; Summers said on state television.</p>
<p>He did not specify which issues the two sides plan to discuss.</p>
<p>Summers is the first ministerial-level U.S. official to visit Taiwan since Transportation Secretary Federico Pena came to the island in December 1994.</p>
<p>Washington switched diplomatic recognition to China's communist government from Taipei in 1979, keeping only unofficial ties with Taiwan.</p>
<p>Beijing considers Taiwan a rebel-held island in China and strongly opposes official contacts with Taipei.</p>
<p>The delegation headed by Summers includes officials from the U.S. Treasury, State, Trade and Commerce departments and the Federal Reserve. They are scheduled to leave on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Taiwan and China have been separated by a civil war in 1949 and only 30 countries recognise Taiwan's Republic of China government instead of Beijing's communist government. China vows to attack Taiwan if it tries to declare independence.</p>
<p>A visit by Taiwan's President Lee Teng-hui to the United States in 1995 sparked outrage in Beijing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
