<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54285" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China says plans to cut fiscal deficit.</title>
<headline>China says plans to cut fiscal deficit.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chinese Finance Minister Liu Zhongli said China had mapped out a plan to gradally cut its fiscal deficit, the South China Morning said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Liu, in comments reported in the South China Morning Post, said the Chinese government aimed to keep the deficit at no more than three percent of the budget.</p>
<p>&quot;Our total deficit should not exceed three percent of the budget,&quot; the Post quoted Liu as saying. The paper said his remarks were an edited version of an interview that will appear in the Germany daily Handelsblatt.</p>
<p>&quot;It currently floats around three percent and we are working hard to lower this figure,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Liu said China expects to cut its deficit by eight percent this year to 61.4 billion yuan from 66.2 billion last year.</p>
<p>&quot;By the year 2000, we want to cut the deficit by 10 to 20 billion yuan,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course this doesn't solve the problem as we have an accumulated debt burden from past years and this includes not only the servicing of the principal but also the interest.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked whether China would venture into international bond markets in the future, the finance minister said China would not be very active.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't need to be very active on the international bond markets as we can make use of the investment money and the savings here,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;To the question as to which markets we prefer we look at Hong Kong, Tokyo, London and Germany and take into consideration the currency, the interest rates and the issuing costs,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Liu also said investment had not faltered after the central government abolished tax privileges for joint venture companies.</p>
<p>&quot;We have conducted a survey. Major international players thought it was only natural for a country to do this,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;They really don't care about adjustments of customs duties and the reduction of duties for imported capital goods. They care about the markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Liu said planners were also struggling with the issue of reforming state-owned companies, many of which are vastly overstaffed and losing money.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to smash the iron rice pot,&quot; he said, in a reference to the welfare for life programme that is offered by Chinese state companies.</p>
<p>Massive payouts for employee welfare are hobbling many state firms as they try to modernise in the wake of economic reforms and an influx of leaner, better-funded foreign competitors.</p>
<p>While private western companies often respond to bloated debt or spending by cutting staff, that option is politically sensitive for Chinese firms run by the state.</p>
<p>&quot;They (state enterprises) must be told that if they fail in the long term they will go bankrupt,&quot; Liu said.</p>
<p>&quot;But before we have a social security in place it is difficult. That's the reason we hesitate to really reform the state-owned enterprises. Only if we have the social security system in place can we separate government and business.&quot;</p>
<p>When asked what was his biggest headache aside from the sick state sector, Liu replied: &quot;Too many people ask me for favours and money. They want a faster, quicker development and civil servants want bigger salaries like in all the other countries.</p>
<p>&quot;It won't be easy.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
