<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="542897" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: G7 appreciates Italy progress - Ciampi.</title>
<headline>G7 appreciates Italy progress - Ciampi.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Group of Seven industrial nations on Sunday expressed appreciation for Italy's progress in reducing the budget deficit, its success in abating inflation, and its solid economy, but noted the slow pace of the recovery, Italian Treasury Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi said.</p>
<p>At a news conference following the G7 meeting, Ciampi said Italy's partners expressed confidence that it will continue to pursue its structural efforts towards containing the deficit.  </p>
<p>&quot;The G7 partners expressed appreciation for the curtailment of inflation, the solidity of the Italian economy, but also noted the slow rhythm of its recovery compared to the other European countries. They expressed confidence that Italy will continue its structural efforts to reduce the budget deficit, and that there might eventually be a more expansive monetary policy&quot; Ciampi said.</p>
<p>Ciampi dismissed criticism that Italy will still be a couple of tenths of a point short of the 3 pct deficit-to-GDP target needed by year-end to be in the first group of countries taking part in the European single currency.  </p>
<p>&quot;There has been great appreciation for the very strong reduction of the budget deficit ... There has been enormous progress. The judgment (of the G7) is positive.&quot;</p>
<p>The European Commission has forecast a 3.2 percent deficit/GDP ratio for Italy in 1997, while the International Monetary Fund, in its World Economic Outlook, sees a 3.3 percent ratio.  </p>
<p>&quot;These are only forecasts. We have accelerated the process of reducing the deficit by bringing forward to 1997 the 3.0 percent goal we had initially set for 1998. This acceleration brought advantages, increasing the country's credibility and accelerating the drop in interest rates&quot; Ciampi said.</p>
<p>The forecasts &quot;reflect the fact that in order to bridge the gap and reach the target by year-end we have had to take one-off budget measures. That 'pontoon' will be replaced by an iron bridge,&quot; Ciampi said.</p>
<p>Both the IMF and the European Commission have asked Italy for more structural deficit cutting measures.  </p>
<p>Ciampi stated that Italy &quot;has eradicated the major causes of inflation. The 1.7 percent inflation rate indicated for April (from 2.2 percent in March) is not a chance event.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he would not view negatively a reform of the Value Added Tax, in line with European Union directives, as inflation would not suffer.</p>
<p>&quot;There would be a statistical effect only,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bank of Italy Governor Antonio Fazio, however, disagreed with this view.</p>
<p>&quot;I would be very worried by an increase of the VAT rate aimed at reducing the budget deficit, unless they are minor adjustments,&quot; Fazio said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
