<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54299" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Foreign funds seen overweight in Thai stocks.</title>
<headline>Foreign funds seen overweight in Thai stocks.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Davison</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign funds remain overweight in Thai stocks despite expectations of further declines following last week's partial recovery, investment managers in Hong Kong said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The market would have some upside if everyone was out, but everybody's not out, they're in,&quot; said Aaron Henderson, vice president of Asian research for BT Fund Managers.</p>
<p>The SET index recovered to close 13.44 points higher at 1,039.65 on Friday, continuing a three-day bounce from Tuesday's three-year low of 975.51.</p>
<p>&quot;Whichever way you cut it, global emerging markets or Asian or ASEAN dedicated funds, people are still overweight in Thailand,&quot; said David Semple, regional strategist with Peregrine Investment in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Although last week's turnaround was welcome relief after a nine-day sell-off, most of the buying came from a private sector rescue fund set up by banks and brokers, who stood to lose heavily on loans if the market sank below 900, experts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It'll take a while for this to end. There might be a technical bounce but no real recovery,&quot; Semple said.</p>
<p>Short-term forecasts for Thailand stocks were uniformly negative. Foreign funds were net buyers of Thai stocks between January and July, starting to sell only in August.</p>
<p>The sell-off halted this month, but foreign share premiums fell slightly last week, suggesting that selling could be about to resume.</p>
<p>This indicates the private sector rescue fund will provide a welcome opportunity for foreign fund managers keen to unwind holdings, but foreign funds usually seek longer-term returns, in excess of 12 months, and might find value at these levels.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there is some potential for foreign selling but I don't think the downside is that great,&quot; Semple said.</p>
<p>But there are concerns that the current crisis could worsen and compromise longer-term valuations, particularly if corporate earnings in the banking sector exceed the worst expectations.</p>
<p>Despite reassuring words from Thai authorities last week, observers are worried that the banks are in trouble.</p>
<p>Banks, which make up 60 percent of the market according to some estimates, were already carrying weak property loans when falling markets called other corporate assets into question, one market source in Hong Kong said.</p>
<p>Banks now face a margin squeeze after interest rate increases to counter attacks on the baht, which has been battered by rumours of a devaluation despite government denials.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is not necessarily on provisioning. It's on collateral,&quot; said one analyst. &quot;If these loans go bad, what about the collateral? This will take out the peripheral players.&quot;</p>
<p>Because the banking sector is so crucial, most analysts expect intervention to keep the SET index above 900, even though some said fundamentals suggested 800 was a more appropriate level.</p>
<p>&quot;Earnings are going to go down this year and next, and that is not yet accepted by the market,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Thailand is already under siege from negative economic and political forces. Slowing growth and exports widened the current account deficit, prompting the devaluation rumours and a short-term debt rating downgrade.</p>
<p>The uncertainty was heightened by an impending no-confidence motion against the prime minister.</p>
<p>Debate on the motion is expected to begin on September 18 and although the government controls 209 of the 391 seats in parliament, political infighting between some coalition partners has left a question mark over which way the vote will go.</p>
<p>&quot;Until there are clear signs of a turnaround in the economy or some decisive action on the political front, we won't get much improvement (in the stock market),&quot; said Annabel Betz, regional economist with ING Barings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
