<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="543034" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: LATVIA-VITRANSAUTO SEES TOUGH 1997.</title>
<headline>LATVIA-VITRANSAUTO SEES TOUGH 1997.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Transport company Vitransauto said on Monday that it sees a tough 1997 ahead but hopes to keep its position on the market.</p>
<p>The company's 1997 budget forecasts 29,000 lats of profit on some 3.9 million lats of turnover against a 1996 profit of 22,000 lats on 3.7 million lats of turnover.</p>
<p>&quot;Shareholders on Saturday approved slightly higher profit and turnover firgures for 1997 but it will be a tough year,&quot; Uldis Berzinsh, Vitransauto manager, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not received any investment and trucks are getting older while technical requirements get tougher both in the EU and Russia,&quot; Berzinsh said.</p>
<p>Vitransauto in 1996 had 30 percent of its transport business with Russia and 70 percent with west European countries.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not plan any major changes in this repect and hope to keep our current volumes,&quot; Berzinsh said.</p>
<p>He also said that the controlling stake held by the Visbija trading company was still under debate after the company went bankrupt.</p>
<p>&quot;Visbija, which held a 60 percent stake, announced about its liquidation last October,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is now a matter for the lawyers to arrange for an auction of its stake,&quot; Berzinsh said.</p>
<p>Vitransauto, apart from Naruta confectionery, is among the few privatised companies whose controling stake owners become insolvent before the sell-off programme was completed.</p>
<p>- Martinsh Gravitis, Riga Newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
