<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="543128" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE cocoa ends down, further drift lower seen.</title>
<headline>LIFFE cocoa ends down, further drift lower seen.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>LIFFE cocoa futures ended lower, with switches dominating light trade on Monday.</p>
<p>May closed down 13 stg at 1,020 stg per tonne and July lost 10 to 1,044. Total volume was at 3,439 contracts, with nearby switches grabbing most of the trade.</p>
<p>May/July spreads changed hands the most times, followed by July/September, as traders rolled forward positions before first delivery day on May 1. July notched 1,456 lots, May grabbed 876 and September tallied 797.</p>
<p>Because July closed a stg below its old resistance level of about 1,045, some traders expected further weakness in the near-term. With outright volume so low and an upcoming three-day weekend, traders said cocoa lacked the momentum to push up through Friday's high of 1,061 and the April 2 peak of 1,065.</p>
<p>They also said New York's failure to follow through on Friday and close higher weighed on London. CSCE July was hit by a late wave of speculative profit-taking on Friday.</p>
<p>Some analysts also said speculators had liquidated fewer long positions than expected, based on the CFTC's weekly Committment of Traders report released late on Friday. They said that could keep prices under pressure.</p>
<p>The CFTC's two-week report is due after New York's close on Monday.</p>
<p>But other analysts were waiting for July to break support on a closing basis near 1,031 before turning more bearish.</p>
<p>Unless that level breaks, they saw cocoa in a near-term range as traders awaited more news of the Ivory Coast crop.</p>
<p>Industry sources in Abidjan predicted on Monday that the Ivorian 1996/97 main crop (Oct-April) would exceed a million tonnes but not match 1.04 to 1.05 million tonnes seen in last year's record season.</p>
<p>Local analysts pegged preliminary mid-crop (May-Sept) estimates at 180,000 tonnes. But those forecasts could be revised depending on rainfall.</p>
<p>The Weather Services Corp's forecast this morning was for showers to end tonight in Nigeria and West Africa but to redevelop on Tuesday with 50- to 60-percent coverage.</p>
<p>In options, no contracts traded.</p>
<p>--Medora Lee +44 171 542 8072</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
