<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="543236" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Perky dollar offers lucrative bond trading opportunities.</title>
<headline>Perky dollar offers lucrative bond trading opportunities.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Scott</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The relentless rise of the U.S. dollar, unchecked by weekend comments from the Group of Seven, offers a number of lucrative spread trading opportunities for the bond investors, strategists said on Monday.</p>
<p>There's still money to made from yen/dollar yield trades, peripheral Europe looks set to outperform core and U.S. Treasuries can gain ground on Bunds, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;You can still make a lot of money on these yen finance trades as long as the dollar stays where it is,&quot; said Yamaichi international bond strategist Adam Chester.</p>
<p>&quot;You're borrowing money for around one to three percent in the yen market and just on yield pick-up if you put that in Treasuries you can get seven percent.&quot;</p>
<p>Chester said the benefits of that trade would unravel if intervention reversed the dollar's rise, or if Treasuries sold off on uncomfortable U.S. data.</p>
<p>The U.S. dollar surged on Monday after a weekend meeting of the Group of Seven (G7) nations agreed on a surprisingly low-key statement that dealers took as a signal the U.S. currency's rise was not over.</p>
<p>They said on Sunday that major currency misalignments had been corrected and that excessive currency volatility and deviations from fundamentals were undesirable.</p>
<p>By late morning, the dollar was at 126.75/85 against the yen, off its overnight high of 127.10. Dollar/mark was at 1.7318/23, down from 1.7395 overnight.</p>
<p>Chester said such dollar strength argued for near term outperformance by U.S. Treasuries over Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;At 116 basis points, the Treasury/Bund spread looks to be good value at these levels,&quot; he said, but added risks remained for the long bond as it braced itself for a fraught week littered with data.</p>
<p>Credit Suisse First Boston bond strategist David Keeble said Scandinavian bonds may emerge as winners in the present period of dollar strength.</p>
<p>&quot;Where you're looking for most gains to come will probably be in the high yielder type play -- on the proviso that politics don't turn badly there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the dollar rises, these spreads tend to narrow.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Scandinavian debt looked favourable, especially for those investors who wanted to steer clear of Italy, and added Swedish bonds in particular offered some hefty pick-ups over Germany at present.</p>
<p>&quot;But if you really want to take on risk buy Italy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Keeble said in terms of Treasuries versus European bonds as a whole, he expected U.S. outperformance.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that spread will narrow down to 105 basis points in the next two to three weeks,&quot; he said. By 1130 GMT, the Treasury/Bund spread was at 116 basis points.</p>
<p>Sonja Gibbs, senior bond strategist at Nomura International here, also said continued strength in the dollar should be good for European peripherals.</p>
<p>She added there was still life in Japanese Government Bond (JGB) versus U.S. Treasury carry trades.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there's still good potential in carry trades, not necessarily to put on new ones, but to let the old ones go,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;Long live the carry trade.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
