<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="543237" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: German jet, diesel tender unlikely to move market.</title>
<headline>German jet, diesel tender unlikely to move market.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's oil stocks agency tender to buy around 500,000 tonnes of jet fuel and diesel is unlikely to move spot prices because deliveries will be spread over several months, traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Its nothing when you see deliveries from mid-May through to end September,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Dealers said material would be sourced from both the ARA barge and cargo market.</p>
<p>&quot;When you're talking about maybe 100,000 tonnes from the barge market (for one product) and 150,000 tonnes from the cargo market it can't really impact over the three to four month period,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>The Erdoelbevorrattungsverband (EBV) confirmed on Monday that it has tendered to buy 250,000 tonnes of jet and 250,000 tonnes of diesel.</p>
<p>Traders said the majority of material is to be delivered into northen locations - Bremen, Hamburg and Rostock with small quantities required into Bavaria and eastern Germany.</p>
<p>The deadline for bids is Tuesday, May 6.</p>
<p>-- Matthew Jones, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8980</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
