<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="543231" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EUROPEAN INVESTORS SEEN TURNING TO JUNK BONDS.</title>
<headline>EUROPEAN INVESTORS SEEN TURNING TO JUNK BONDS.</headline>
<byline>Aline van Duyn</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Frustrated by miserly yields in core markets, European investors are turning to high-risk company debt, a shift which could help create a European junk bond market worth up to $30 billion a year.</p>
<p>Bankers said on Monday returns on investment grade bonds had fallen so low, that demand for high-yielding junk bonds in European currencies was set to take off.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen the starting pistol going off for the race,&quot; John Wotowicz, head of Morgan Stanley's European high yield capital markets group, said.</p>
<p>Two junk bonds issued in April, worth a combined 325 million marks, set the tone by offering investors more than nine percent per year. That dwarfed the more usual five or six percent paid out on mark bonds from top-grade borrowers such as governments and blue chip companies.</p>
<p>&quot;We will see substantial new issue activity in European currencies in the next 12 to 24 months,&quot; Wotowicz said, adding issuance could total $1.5 billion by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch estimates the European junk bond market could grow to $20 billion or $30 billion per year over time. The U.S. junk bond market, which has had a resurgence following scandals in the 1980s, is worth more than $200 billion. The trend, if it does gain pace, would mark a shift in investor attitudes. European investors are traditionally conservative and wary of credit risk.</p>
<p>But as Europe's efforts to form a single currency have reduced currency risk and cut returns on top-rated debt from countries such as Spain and Italy, some investors are embracing credit risk to boost returns.</p>
<p>&quot;In the last year we have seen a greater interest in spread (high-yield corporate) products,&quot; said David Munves, Eurobond strategist at Lehman Brothers.</p>
<p>&quot;The European investor base is more oriented towards them because there is less scope to make money on currency plays,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The gap between German and Italian government bond yields currently is around 1.75 percentage points, down from 4.75 points at the start of 1996.</p>
<p>The first European company to issue a mark junk bond, so-called because the paper is not rated or is well below investment grade, was Geberit International.</p>
<p>Geberit is a European sanitary plumbing systems maker, and the family-held firm was recently taken over by British venture fund Doughty Hanson &amp; Co in a leveraged buyout.</p>
<p>In three to five years' time an initial public offering (IPO) by Geberit is expected, Doughty Hanson said. The 150 million marks raised from the deal were used to fund the leveraged buyout.</p>
<p>Exide Holdings Europe, part of American Exide Corp which makes automotive and industrial batteries, followed with a 175 million mark bond.</p>
<p>In May, a 200 million mark issue is due for Impress Metal Packaging to finance the merger of the metal packaging units of Pechiney SA and Schmalbach-Lubeca AG.</p>
<p>Impress Metal Packaging will be formed when the units are merged.</p>
<p>&quot;A year or so ago these companies would have issued in dollars and swapped (the funds) into marks,' said Michael Ridley, director of fixed income syndicate at Salomon Brothers in London. Nowadays, there is enough appetite for mark debt that such capital-hungry companies can come to the market without having to borrow in dollars and then do an interest rate currency swap, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;European businesses have a natural requirement for marks, and we expect to see at least one such deal per month,&quot; he said. Another incentive, from the borrowers' viewpoint, is cutting financing costs.</p>
<p>Swaps for low-rated or un-rated companies are expensive because they have to compensate their swap counterparty for taking on the credit risk.</p>
<p>Junk bonds launched in Europe offer investors the same yield as similar transactions issued in dollars, but companies benefit from not having to buy a swap.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a wide array of companies who want to go into the high-yield market but whose sole restricting item has been their inability to get the deal done in a European currency,&quot; Wotowicz at Morgan Stanley said.</p>
<p>The U.S. high-yield bond market has around $210 billion outstanding, compared with around $840 billion in the investment grade U.S. fixed-income sector, according to Lehman Brothers. Still, Europe's junk bond aspirations are still embryonic set against more seasoned markets. The overall Eurobond market, which includes just about any currency, raised more than $670 billion last year, according to data from Capital DATA Bondware.</p>
<p>&quot;We could see between $2.0 billion to $3.0 billion equivalent (of junk) launched in European currencies this year, a nice start but still small relative to the total market,&quot; Munves at Lehman Brothers said. So far, issuance is limited to marks but bankers say that will change. Bonds issued in Italian lira and sterling are seen as the next likely candidates.</p>
<p>&quot;At the end of the day we will see a true multi-currency market in Europe, but that will take a bit of time,&quot; Wotowicz said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7748</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
