<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="543205" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Standard Life to apply for banking licence.</title>
<headline>UK's Standard Life to apply for banking licence.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>British mutual life assurance company Standard Life said on Monday it would apply to the Bank of England for a banking licence with a view to attracting personal savings and providing mortgages.</p>
<p>In a statement, the Edinburgh-based group said it hoped Standard Life Banking Services Ltd, which would in time employ around 200 people, would be in the market &quot;by the end of the year&quot;, reflecting the time it would take to receive BoE authority and to write the necessary systems.  </p>
<p>A week ago the mutual group said reports that it was about to launch a new banking operation were &quot;pure speculation&quot;. The opening of services such as savings, personal loans and mortgages will follow similar moves by Prudential Corp and Scottish Widows.</p>
<p>Standard Life said the move followed the appointment earlier this year of Jim Spowart who was formerly managing director of Direct Line Financial Services.</p>
<p>Spowart, now Standard Life's general manager banking services, said the group was &quot;capable of becoming one of the major players in the personal banking and mortgage lending sectors&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We shall build on Standard Life's existing reputation and with sophisticated and tailor-made computer systems will provide benefits to customers in the shape of extremely competitive products,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
