<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="543344" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenya Power ends electricity rationing.</title>
<headline>Kenya Power ends electricity rationing.</headline>
<byline>Wambui Chege</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenya Power &amp; Lighting Co said on Monday it had ended seven months of power rationing after heavy rains improved water levels in main supply stations and repair work on key installations neared an end.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we've relaxed everything. There is no rationing in the country,&quot; said KPLC spokesman Mike Njeru.</p>
<p>British industrial power group W H Allen said it had supplied at least five of a total eight power units for the Nairobi South Power Station, one of three independent power producers licensed in recent months to help ease shortages.</p>
<p>The Allen contract is worth 20 million pounds ($32.4 million). An Allen spokesman said the first unit would produce power in June.</p>
<p>&quot;Five of the eight power units are already in Nairobi and our team is helping install them,&quot; the spokesman said, adding that the company would enter a separate agreement on maintenance and other services.</p>
<p>Malaysian company Westmont will produce power off a barge at the port of Mombasa. It also expected to be ready in June.</p>
<p>Plans for the third power producer have not been announced.</p>
<p>The diesel-powered Nairobi South Power Station will contribute 44.5 megawatts to the national grid while Westmont will account for another 43 megawatts, said KPLC's Njeru, who saw shortages as history from June onwards.</p>
<p>Njeru said heavy rains had helped KPLC step up generation by around 40 megawatts. Completion of repairs at the main Kiambere and Kipevu power stations should help rectify the power problems in due course, another executive at KPLC told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;But even if we run the full hydro-stations, there'll still be a shortfall and we'll have to ration a few industry users in Nairobi,&quot; he said, giving the period as three hours at night.</p>
<p>Business leaders complain that rationing disrupts business and the government advises major hotels to install generators.</p>
<p>Top of the list of investor concerns on Kenya, in a survey issued by Governor Micah Cheserem's Central Bank of Kenya, is dilapidated and inadequate infrastructure.</p>
<p>Kenya's capacity generated oscillates between 570 and 650 megawatts while installed capacity is 784 megawatts. The deficiency is blamed mainly on poor weather, poor maintenance and constant breakdowns.</p>
<p>Kenya has officially rationed power since September but before then outages were common.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
