<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="543352" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Nairobi bourse index edges upwards in modest trade.</title>
<headline>Nairobi bourse index edges upwards in modest trade.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Nairobi Stock Exchange 20-share index lifted marginally on Monday on modest gains in key shares across the board, bourse officials said.</p>
<p>The index went up 17.96 points to close at 3394.57.</p>
<p>Turnover was posted at 12.6 million shillings on 478,850 shares from 9.712 million shillings on 251,994 shares on Friday.</p>
<p>National carrier Kenya Airways closed at 8.40 from 8.05 while Uchumi Supermarket gained 1.0 to 38.25.</p>
<p>Nation Printers &amp; Publishers was unchanged at 154.</p>
<p>Brooke Bond was unchanged at 123 while Rea Vipingo Plantations closed at 9.05 unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;No special lots were traded. Today's trading was normal -- like for a Monday, dull,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're entering into the second quarter of the year, there is not much excitement and most prices are expected to remain low,&quot; a market analyst said.</p>
<p>Barclays Bank edged up to 103 from 102 while Kenya Commercial Bank gained a shilling to close at 86.</p>
<p>Kenya Power &amp; Lighting was unchanged at 124 while Total Kenya closed at 65 from 64.50.</p>
<p>Foreigners bought 3,200 shares of National Industrial Credit at 50 unchanged and 10,000 shares of East African Portland Cement at 39.25 from 38.25.</p>
<p>The Central Bank of Kenya floating rate treasury bonds traded 50,000 shillings at 102.3762 percent from 102.2028 percent on Friday.</p>
<p>($1=54 shillings).</p>
<p>--Wambui Chege, Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
