<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="543364" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FEATURE-Leaking borders cost S.African economy dear.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Leaking borders cost S.African economy dear.</headline>
<byline>Paul Harris</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Early in April a woman hitch-hiked from Mozambique to Johannesburg hauling three carrier bags stuffed with 500 crabs destined for the plush seafood restaurants of South Africa's biggest city.</p>
<p>She was arrested for having no permit for the stinking cargo, thus avoiding a potentially nasty outbreak of food poisoning. But economists say her journey illustrates a far more serious problem than upsetting the stomachs of a few diners -- the ease of smuggling.</p>
<p>There are no reliable estimates for how much smuggling costs South Africa's economy in terms of lost government revenue and hitting the sales of legitimate business. But most experts agree it does billions of rands worth of damage.</p>
<p>Last year Portnet, the port authority for South Africa's six ports, estimated theft and smuggling at its ports cost the country about 12 billion rand ($2.7 billion) a year.</p>
<p>But South African customs estimates that about 75 percent of all goods smuggled come over the land borders so the total figures must be much higher.</p>
<p>SMUGGLING A HUGE PROBLEM THAT HITS BUSINESS</p>
<p>&quot;The main point is disruption to South African business by illegal imports. It is a huge problem,&quot; said Ben van Rensburg, economist at the South African Chamber of Business (Sacob).</p>
<p>The main goods smuggled in are tobacco, alcoholic drinks and electrical goods such as televisions and video recorders. But clothes and luxury goods such as perfumes are also leaking in from neighbouring countries.</p>
<p>Van Rensburg says the tide of illegal goods swamping the country undercuts local businesses and is in danger of breeding a culture whereby customs laws are often ignored.</p>
<p>&quot;It makes it difficult for business and the whole economy to make the transition from the old South Africa to where we want to be in the new South Africa,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The reasons for the upsurge in smuggling lie in the re-entry of South Africa back into the world economy after its first all-race elections of 1994 finally nailed the coffin lid down on the apartheid system.</p>
<p>After the polls goods started to flow freely over the borders, swamping a customs and excise service used to years of economic boycott.</p>
<p>&quot;Before 1994 the country was living in isolation. But there was an upsurge in business afterwards from cargo goods to passenger boats,&quot; said Sihle Mbongwa, Portnet head of security.</p>
<p>WILDERNESS LAND BORDERS OFFER EASY ACCESS</p>
<p>Portnet admits that some of its own officials are involved in the trade as South Africa battles to deal with crime in a public sector where wages are low and the corrupting legacy of the old apartheid ways is still felt.</p>
<p>The nature of South Africa's borders is also a problem. The frontier snakes through trackless bush and mountains alongside Mozambique, Swaziland, Zimbabwe, Botswana, Lesotho and Namibia.</p>
<p>It is a border that African National Congress fighters easily penetrated when battling the former white-run state. Now the smugglers are slipping over with impunity.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the sort of border where you can go and drive across the veld (bush) if you really don't want to go through customs,&quot; van Rensburg said.</p>
<p>But economists and figures in the customs service say progress is being made to halt the flow of goods and are guardedly optimistic about the future.</p>
<p>One of the main proposals is to cut the number of points of entry for commercial goods. This will tighten security and allow customs to spread its staff and resources more effectively.</p>
<p>Recommendations currently before cabinet suggest limiting the clearing of commercial traffic to only 19 of South Africa's 52 border posts and only eight of its 36 airports.</p>
<p>Allowances are planned for local requirements under strict controls, but the bulk of commercial goods would be turned back from airports and border posts that had not been designated.</p>
<p>The plans have been welcomed by business.</p>
<p>&quot;It enjoys (Sacob) support as long as they are not reduced to the point where the system becomes inefficient,&quot; van Rensburg said.</p>
<p>The customs service thinks the plan will start cutting into the smugglers' trade. &quot;It is a good idea...it will tackle the problem. I am optimistic this situation will get better,&quot; said Chris Barnard, chief director of Customs and Excise.</p>
<p>SECURITY SYSTEM TO BE TIGHTENED</p>
<p>Customs also plans other measures centred on scrapping the easily forged stamps and paper permits for an electronic system similar to bar codes used on supermarket goods.</p>
<p>Eventually it is hoped to link all customs facilities from border posts, ports and airports on one computer network to allow rapid and accurate checking of all goods.</p>
<p>The first step is a set of lines linking Portnet and rail network Spoornet to customs offices. The first link, in Johannesburg, will go online in May this year. It will allow the electronic transfer of cargo release messages and aims to slash documentation fraud.</p>
<p>Portnet is also carrying out a review of its operations and aims to upgrade security at Durban -- South Africa's biggest port. Mbongwa said he had travelled to Britain's Felixstowe port and France to learn from security methods used abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not want to reinvent the wheel. I have no doubt tighter security will see this get better,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mbongwa added that stopping smuggled goods -- whether fridges or hard drugs -- at the port of entry was vital for the good of the country's economic health and combatting crime.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a lot cheaper to catch goods at the port then it is to chase them later on the street,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
