<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="543441" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech cbank says its forex reserves over $12bln.</title>
<headline>Czech cbank says its forex reserves over $12bln.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech National Bank (CNB) said on Monday that according to preliminary data its foreign exchange reserves at the end of March were more than $12 billion compared with $11.7 billion at the end of February.</p>
<p>&quot;Preliminarily, I can tell you that the level (of reserves) is stable and represents at the end of March more than $12 billion,&quot; CNB press spokesman Martin Svehla told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Earlier in the day, CNB board member Ludek Niedemeyer said that the central bank was not discussing a cut in interest rates, that the weakening of the crown seen early on Monday was not based on fundamentals and that the CNB was prepared to support the crown if necessary.</p>
<p>Svehla repeated Niedermeyer's remarks stresing that the CNB would would not hesitate to intervene if the need arose.</p>
<p>&quot;We are always ready to stand behind the crown,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>After Niedermeyer's remarks, the crown rose to -2.92 percent against the mid-point of its mark/dollar basket, compared with around -3.8 percent at its lowest point on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Robin Shepherd, Prague Newsroom, 420-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
