<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="543495" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: FOCUS-Brazil CVRD sell-off hits legal minefield.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Brazil CVRD sell-off hits legal minefield.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Michael Christie</p>
<p>Brazil Monday braced for Latin America's largest ever privatization, with police fencing off the Rio de Janeiro bolsa and a small army of government lawyers preparing to tackle a host of legal challenges.</p>
<p>Today a judge in the northeastern states of Maranhao and another in Ceara granted injunctions against the sale of mining giant Companhia Vale do Rio Doce (CVRD), bringing to three the court orders so far suspending Tuesday's scheduled auction.  </p>
<p>Unconfirmed wire reports said another court in Rio had also granted an injunction.</p>
<p>&quot;They aren't a problem. The injunctions were only to be expected and we have the lawyers in place to successfully appeal them before the auction,&quot; said an aide to Planning Minister Antonio Kandir.</p>
<p>The privatization of CVRD, the world's largest iron ore exporter, should raise at least $5.0 billion for the government's coffers once completed. A controlling 45 percent of voting shares valued at $2.8 billion is slated to be sold Tuesday.  </p>
<p>CVRD's Carajas mine, deep in the Amazon rain forest, holds the world's largest iron ore deposit, estimated at 18 billion tonnes, while CVRD also mines considerable amounts of copper, gold and manganese.</p>
<p>If the sale goes ahead without hitch, and government officials say a slight delay caused by court cases would not affect investor interest, it will also confirm President Fernando Henrique Cardoso's commitment to reforming the economy.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are not going to change the date of the auction,&quot; Cardoso insisted on Sunday after holding a mini-summit with Argentine President Carlos Menem in Rio.</p>
<p>But before Brasilia can start rejoicing, it will have to weave its way through a minefield of court cases.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Supreme Federal Tribunal (STF), the country's highest court, said it would hold a full session Monday afternoon to judge the constitutionality of the sale.</p>
<p>Throughout the country, some 140 government lawyers flown around in four specially hired jets prepared Monday to challenge up to 100 other applications for injunctions.  </p>
<p>In Rio alone, there were about 19 court cases, justice officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;The courts are a separate power, of course,&quot; said Kandir's aide. &quot;But we're sure we can win the appeals in good time.&quot;</p>
<p>Opponents of the privatization, ranging from former presidents Jose Sarney and Itamar Franco to all of the country's Catholic bishops, have called for a giant demonstration outside the Rio stock exchange on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Officials said 600 riot police would protect the bolsa. The square in front of the exchange was fenced off on Monday.  </p>
<p>Marcelo Sereno, first secretary of Latin America's largest trade union confederation, the CUT, said he expected 5,000 people to turn up.</p>
<p>&quot;It'll be huge,&quot; he told Reuters at a smaller protest held Monday outside the headquarters of National Development Bank (BNDES), which runs Brazil's privatization program.</p>
<p>The protest is also likely to turn violent, Sereno said.</p>
<p>On Sunday, some 200 demonstrators booing Cardoso as he ended his meeting with Menem were forcefully dispersed by police firing tear gas grenades and wading into the crowd with batons.  </p>
<p>&quot;We intend to hold a peaceful protest. But judging from the operation the police are planning, it seems likely there will be some clashes,&quot; said Sereno.</p>
<p>((-- Rio newsroom 55-21-5074151))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
