<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="543406" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albanians want international help to recover dead.</title>
<headline>Albanians want international help to recover dead.</headline>
<byline>Belinda Goldsmith</byline>
<dateline>VLORE, Albania 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanians in the rebel-held southern port of Vlore put aside their guns on Monday for a rally to commemorate the victims of a tragic shipping accident and to call for international help to recover the bodies.</p>
<p>Rally organisers said an estimated 103 people drowned a month ago when a ship carrying Albanians fleeing the troubled Balkan state collided with an Italian navy frigate 30 miles off Brindisi in southern Italy and sank.</p>
<p>&quot;We're asking all the world's humanitarian organisations to recover the bodies so our relatives can rest in peace in their homeland,&quot; Aferdita Bani, a spokeswoman for a group of victims' relatives, told 5,000 people gathered in the main square.</p>
<p>&quot;This would be a consolation for us, the families, so we can have a place where we can go to talk to them.&quot;</p>
<p>Vlore residents called on Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi, who visited the grief-stricken town on April 13, to honour his pledge to help recover the bodies and to investigate the accident that many blame on the Italian boat.</p>
<p>After a minute's silence, the victims' widows and mothers, dressed in black and carrying lit candles, led the procession along Vlore's palm-lined boulevard, to the entrance of the port. Only one gunman was seen among the crowd.</p>
<p>Over the past week 850 Italian and Greek soldiers, part of a multi-national force assigned to Albania to oversee aid deliveries, have secured the port, blocking thousands of Albanians who have been trying to escape the violent unrest.</p>
<p>Over 13,000 illegal refugees have fled by ship to Italy or into neighbouring Greece since Albanians took to the streets, angered by the loss of savings in fraudulent investment funds.</p>
<p>Rebels armed with guns looted from state arsenals blame President Sali Berisha for the funds disaster and have taken control of much of southern Albania.</p>
<p>On Sunday Italian authorities at Barletta rescued 517 Albanians who were crammed into a vessel built for no more than 50 people. The ship had taken 26 hours to cross the Adriatic, setting sail from Shengjin near Shkoder in northern Albania.</p>
<p>Friends and relatives of the victims of last month's tragedy were in tears, some crying hysterically, other fainting, as they walked along a jetty, clutching white lilies and red roses that they threw out to sea for the dead.</p>
<p>Thirty friends of victim Fiqiri Sula, a 30-year-old engineer, were among the mourners to pay their respects to their friend and his five relatives, including a two-year-old nephew, who died in the tragedy.</p>
<p>Work colleague Maksim Beta said Sula and his relatives had paid 800,000 Lek ($500) each for passage on the ship.</p>
<p>&quot;We had been friends for five years. He was a good man. It was tragic that this was his fate,&quot; Beta told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;But a month has passed and nothing has been done to recover the bodies. We want action.&quot;</p>
<p>As distraught relatives were led away from the jetty, the lone gunman stood on the end of the pier and fired a volley of shots into the air to bid farewell to the victims.</p>
<p>Heavily armed Italian soldiers watched from a distance but made no move. The only police in Vlore have been relegated to directing traffic.</p>
<p>&quot;The people are in control in this town and this is not going to change in the near future,&quot; Lieutenant Commander Stefano Cappellaro told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VLORE, Albania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
