<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="543491" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: FEATURE - Bulgaria's stags become unfair game for poachers.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Bulgaria's stags become unfair game for poachers.</headline>
<byline>Liliana Semerdjieva</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's growing income from big game hunting is threatened by poachers who are driven by poverty to kill, for a few dollars' worth of meat, stags whose antlers could fetch thousands as rich hunters' trophies.</p>
<p>&quot;Our big problem is poaching and for the last two years we have had a drastic fall in the numbers of royal stag,&quot; Konstantin Ikonomov, the Foresty Committee's new chairman, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Bulgaria had 22,539 royal stags in 1996, 14 percent fewer than in 1995. Yet in 1996 legal hunters killed only 490 royal stags in state-owned estates, officials said.</p>
<p>Ikonomov said poachers were selling venison to newly opened private factories and restaurants, making only about half a million levs ($327) from the 70 kg (155 lb) or so of venison from a single animal.</p>
<p>The antlers are wasted because poachers cannot sell them -- but a set weighing more than 10 kg (22 lb) would fetch more than 10,000 marks ($6,000) from a foreign hunter who shot them.</p>
<p>After a legal kill the Forestry Committee exports the venison, sending some 50 tonnes abroad in 1996, mainly to Germany and Austria.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreigners are coming here for antlers, while Bulgarians are poaching for meat,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Not all the poachers are in it for the cash. Some of Bulgaria's nouveaux riches, thriving despite a bankrupt economy, have taken to the sport with as much relish as the country's former communist leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;In the past, communist party leaders killed the game. Now the new rich have replaced them with their four-wheel-drive vehicles and expensive guns,&quot; Ikonomov said.</p>
<p>Forestry police who patrol the hunting grounds have even caught poachers armed with Kalashnikovs, automatic rifles which tilt the odds in favour of the most inept hunter, he added.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's former communist dictator Todor Zhivkov and his aides loved to hunt. Luxurious hunting lodges were built for him to receive guests from other East bloc countries, including Romania's Nicolae Ceausescu and his wife Elena.</p>
<p>GAME HUNTING A SOURCE OF HARD CURRENCY</p>
<p>Bulgaria's high quality game has become a lucrative source of hard currency. More than 30 percent of the mountainous Balkan country is covered with forest.</p>
<p>Last year, the state-run business earned more than 4.5 million marks ($2.7 million) from 1,500 visiting hunters and game meat exports, said Roumen Yankulov, head of the Forestry Committee's Hunting Department.</p>
<p>Apart from royal stag and chamois, brown bear is another attraction for foreign hunters. The Forestry Committee has so far issued permits for five brown bears to be shot, Yankulov said.</p>
<p>&quot;The number of bears to be shot depends on the level of our reserves, and about 10 bears can be killed per year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In contrast to the high fees which the state charges foreign hunters to shoot such animals, it sometimes pays Bulgarian hunters a reward for killing wolves. Yankulov said the number of wolves had grown so large they posed a public menace and gunmen were rewarded for shooting them.</p>
<p>Foreign hunters pay some 1,500 marks ($900) for seven days' food and lodging and a guide.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of our clients fly to Sofia in their private planes and we take them by helicopter to one of our 31 state-owned estates and 160 state forestries,&quot; Ikonomov said.</p>
<p>Most of the visitors are from western Europe, 70 percent from Germany. In the last two years hunters from the United States have also begun to show interest.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest is growing and hunters have started coming with their families. We are planning to develop village tourism so that they can stay in peasants' houses near the hunting areas,&quot; Ikonomov said.</p>
<p>He said prices and taxes would rise in June when Bulgaria introduces a strict monetary regime demanded by international lenders, and pegs the lev to the dollar or the mark.</p>
<p>The committee is planning to increase the number of visiting hunters but not at the expense of controlling and regulating the amount of game killed, Ikonomov said.</p>
<p>The committee photographs the forests from the air in March and April, when game can easily be spotted among the bare trees and counted, Ikonomov said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
