<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54371" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-INTERNATIONAL TEAM CHARGES BACK IN PRESIDENTS CUP.</title>
<headline>GOLF-INTERNATIONAL TEAM CHARGES BACK IN PRESIDENTS CUP.</headline>
<dateline>GAINESVILLE, Virginia 1996-09-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International team, facing the possibility of a lopsided defeat, responded to the challenge to pull within one point of the United States after the second day of the Presidents Cup matches on Saturday.</p>
<p>The United States led by five points after Friday's matches, but clung to a slim one-point advantage, 10-1/2 to 9-1/2, going into Sunday's 12 final-day singles matches.</p>
<p>The Internationals won three of the five fourball (better ball) matches in beautiful weather at the Robert Trent Jones Golf Club Saturday morning, then did even better in the afternoon, winning four of five foursomes (alternate shot).</p>
<p>&quot;I'm part of a very happy team,&quot; said International captain Peter Thomson. &quot;The event has suddenly come alive. It's a real contest between two very even teams.</p>
<p>&quot;Our fellows were shocked the first day. They came out with a better attitude and were much more effective today.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. captain Arnold Palmer was not exactly shocked at the International fightback.</p>
<p>&quot;It would have been very, very unusual if either team had run away with this,&quot; he said. &quot;I'm saddened we're not further ahead, but we expected a good match and we're getting it.&quot;</p>
<p>International player Nick Price raved about the quality of the competition. &quot;Pars aren't going to win out there. The course is soft and it's giving us an opportunity to fly at the flag,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Why don't the American guys play like this in the Ryder Cup. The Europeans wouldn't have a chance.&quot;</p>
<p>The biggest surprise of the foursomes was the victory by out-of-form Internationals Peter Senior and David Frost, who dusted off the highly-regarded U.S. pairing of Corey Pavin and Phil Mickelson.</p>
<p>Senior and Frost were 4 up after just five holes, and held on to win 3 and 2.</p>
<p>In the match behind, Internationals Frank Nobilo and Robert Allenby were never behind as they also won 3 and 2 over Davis Love and Mark Brooks.</p>
<p>Nick Price and Mark McNulty were behind early in their match against Americans Kenny Perry and Justin Leonard, but fought back to win 3 and 1.</p>
<p>The Internationals also won the next match, but only barely as Greg Norman and Ernie Els held on to beat Tom Lehman and Steve Stricker 1 up.</p>
<p>Lehman had a chance to halve the match, but his 12-foot birdie putt at the final hole narrowly missed.</p>
<p>In the final match of the day, the U.S. team salvaged its only win of the afternoon as Mark O'Meara and Scott Hoch fended off Steve Elkington and Vijay Singh 1 up.</p>
<p>O'Meara hit a dreadful drive at the last, but redeemed himself after Hoch had missed the green by floating an outstanding recovery shot within inches of the cup.</p>
<p>Elkington, who earlier had holed out from the fairway to eagle the par-four third hole, had a chance to halve the match, but just missed his 20-foot birdie putt.</p>
<p>After two days, the only two players with perfect records were Americans Mark O'Meara (4-0-0) and David Duval (3-0-0).</p>
<p>The best International records were held by Ernie Els and Mark McNulty, both of whom had two wins, one tie and one loss.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GAINESVILLE, Virginia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
