<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="544016" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Compaq strategy to fuel lower PC prices.</title>
<headline>Compaq strategy to fuel lower PC prices.</headline>
<byline>Therese Poletti</byline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Compaq Computer Corp is embarking on another major re-engineering of its business that its executives say will lead to lower PC prices, higher profit margins and even more market share in its quest to become one of the world's top three computer vendors.</p>
<p>This summer, the world's largest PC manufacturer will introduce its first PC products to implement its new build-to- order and build-to-configure manufacturing strategy, whereby Compaq will build its computers as they are ordered by customers, instead of manufacturing in advance based on forecasts.</p>
<p>Compaq executives here said that this re-engineering of its business is more important than its 1992 launch of lower-cost PCs, a move that reverberated throughout the PC industry and helped Compaq leapfrog International Business Machines Corp as the number one maker of PCs.</p>
<p>&quot;It is much more important to us than what we did in 1992,&quot; said Earl Mason, Compaq's chief financial officer, in an interview. &quot;It will significantly grow our market share and our profits.&quot;</p>
<p>Mason declined to specify how much this move to revamp and lower its manufacturing costs will boost future profits, but he said that it will begin to take effect in the third quarter and be fully in place by year-end.</p>
<p>Mason said with its new manufacturing strategy - where its resellers and distributors will only carry a maximum of two weeks inventory instead of five weeks - Compaq will have the most competitively priced products in the industry, as it addresses the competitive threat of the direct marketers Dell Computer Corp and Gateway 2000 Inc.</p>
<p>Compaq said it will be able to offer products at 10 to 15 to 20 percent lower than current prices with this new model.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question that it will lower prices,&quot; said Jim Schraith, vice president and general manager of North America. &quot;We will become much more competitive and in some categories the price leader.&quot;</p>
<p>Schraith also said that he expects Compaq's competition to re-examine how they work with the companies that resell and distribute their products.</p>
<p>In its current business model, Compaq ships a certain number of PCs to its distributors and resellers in configurations that it believes the market wants. Then, these resellers, based on orders from customers, sometimes have to add new parts or reconfigure the boxes themselves -  for example, swapping a one gigabyte hard disk drive for a two gigabyte drive, or more memory chips. This second reconfiguration adds extra costs to the product.</p>
<p>Another example is when Compaq ships a certain number of PCs with Pentium chips at speeds of 160 megahertz, and the model that becomes more popular is the 200 megahertz.</p>
<p>Now, when a product isn't selling to forecast, Compaq cuts prices to help move the inventory out of the distribution channel, but it also has to pay its resellers and dealers for price protection, because they have already purchased the products from Compaq to be sold at the higher prices.</p>
<p>With fewer weeks on inventory on hand, Compaq's price protection payments will decline. Compaq's returns policy will also change so that it will only accept returns from its distributors of products that are dead on arrival.</p>
<p>Both Compaq and its resellers will also be able to take advantage of the fluctuations in component prices, such as the lower costs in microprocessors.</p>
<p>Mason said that the lower prices will not lead to lower overall profits at Compaq, because the drop in prices will also fuel strong demand for its products. &quot;We will have the most competitively priced products and that will create a tremendous pull out of the channel,&quot; he said, adding that the current model is somewhat like a &quot;bulldozer pushing all its products&quot; to its resellers.</p>
<p>Many Wall Street analysts are concerned that Compaq's re- engineering will cause a big shake-up in its business, and that its lower prices will hurt profits. Mason said that he believes Wall Street does not fully understand what Compaq is doing and that its plan, plus increased sales of higher margin products such as servers and networking products, will fuel margin growth.</p>
<p>Currently, Compaq's gross profit margins are among the highest in the PC industry, at 24.5 percent of revenues in Q1. &quot;My guess is you will see us rewrite our 10Q,&quot; Mason said, referring to Compaq's quarterly filing with the Securities and Exchange commission, where the company targets margins in the 23 to 25 percent range. &quot;When you see this thing go over 25, you will see us rewrite the 10Q,&quot; he said, but he declined to be more specific.</p>
<p>Amid its move to a new manufacturing model, rumors have been swirling that Compaq, in an effort to be more competitive with Dell and Gateway, was looking at buying one of its rivals. It recently held talks with Micron Electronics Inc about a merger, Micron said, although no offer was received. Compaq is also rumored to have talked to Gateway 2000.</p>
<p>Mason and other Compaq executives declined to comment on mergers and acquisitions and they said that Compaq remains committed to its resellers and distributors. Mason, who has been at Compaq for one year, said he has looked at about 100 companies, and that &quot;very few companies make it through my test.&quot;</p>
<p>Mason said he plans to continue to use Compaq's big cash pile, which was about $4.7 billion at the end of first quarter, to grow the company. Compaq also announced a share buyback plan at its annual meeting last week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
