<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="544217" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AmEx signals no dividend increase in sight.</title>
<headline>AmEx signals no dividend increase in sight.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>American Express Co Chairman and Chief Executive Harvey Golub, in response to a shareholder's question at the annual meeting Monday, signaled that the company was unlikely to increase the dividend on its common stock anytime soon.</p>
<p>Golub said investors who wanted cash had the option of selling a portion of their shares.</p>
<p>A company spokesman told a reporter after the meeting that American Express has favored share repurchases over a higher dividend payout in part because of the tax consequences.  </p>
<p>In his remarks, Golub said the total return on the company's stock last year exceeded the benchmarks of the Dow Jones industrial average, the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 stock index and the S&amp;P financials.</p>
<p>In his prepared remarks, Golub said the company last year continued to build its card business and now had franchise or network arrangements in 20 countries.</p>
<p>In response to a question, Golub said Warren Buffett, who through his companies owned 10.5 percent of the stock, would be welcome on the board but Buffett had conflicts. &quot;We would love to have him on the board,&quot; Golub said.  </p>
<p>Four shareholder proposals, including one on cumulative voting and another on environmental principles, were defeated. Management had recommended a vote against all four.</p>
<p>Shareholders approved all management nominees for director, certification of outside auditors, and a proposal to amend the certificate of incorporation. The change in the incorporation certificate deletes provisions related to three series of preferred stock that are no longer outstanding.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
