<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="544324" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French business leader urges a slimmer state.</title>
<headline>French business leader urges a slimmer state.</headline>
<dateline>TOULOUSE, France 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jean Gandois, the chairman of France's employers' federation CNPF, called on Monday for a slimmer state focused on &quot;essential missions.&quot;</p>
<p>Gandois, in a speech to business leaders in the southern city of Toulouse, also reaffirmed his support for European monetary union and smaller public and social welfare deficits.</p>
<p>&quot;The state must stop spreading itself thin and instead must refocus its efforts on its essential role. Its most important tasks are not insignificant -- to educate, administer justice, assure public safety inside and outside of the country and protect against the most serious harm caused by social exclusion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rest should be up to individuals and business to undertake. There is no other solution,&quot; Gandois said. &quot;All those who believe that the state can protect its citizens against the winds of competition are mistaken.&quot;</p>
<p>The speech, delivered just weeks ahead of France's May 25-June 1 parliamentary election, appeared to mirror recent statements by President Jacques Chirac also urging a smaller role for the French state.</p>
<p>But Gandois insisted that his &quot;personal convictions ... should not be mistaken for political positions.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question of my being converted to a particular ideology, whichever that might be,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOULOUSE, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
