<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="544364" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bonds/futures.</title>
<headline>Italian bonds/futures.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian bond futures were showing gains of nearly a full point as a bullish mood returned to the market helped by a strong lira and comforting words by Treasury minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi from Washington, dealers said.</p>
<p>With no strong words to restrain the dollar from the weekend G7 meeting, the dollar remained firmer and so helped the lira, while the centre-left government did not appear to have done as badly as some had forecast in local elections at the weekend.</p>
<p>Provisional results showed opposition parties lead in the key northern cities of Milan and Turin, but gave government allies a boost in the provinces.  </p>
<p>Both political blocs claimed success on Monday from weekend local elections, but the hard-left government allies Communist Refoundation secured around 10 percent of vote in Milan and Turin, and immediately demanded concessions from the government for its endorsement in the second round of voting in May.</p>
<p>Dealers said that Ciampi speaking from Washington had again expressed confidence that Italy would make EMU on time, and said one-off measures in the 1997 financial budget would be replaced by permanent ones in later years.</p>
<p>&quot;Ciampi was hinting at structural measures and that's what the market wanted to hear,&quot; said one dealer.  </p>
<p>BTPs had fallened sharply on LIFFE on Friday when Italy was closed for a holiday, so dealers said that there was signs of a technical bounce once trading got underway.</p>
<p>Debate started in the lower Chamber of Deputies on Italy's 1997 mini-budget, although voting is seen some days away. Dealers said the government might put the measure to a confidence vote after it recent defeat in the Chamber's budget commission.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
