<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="544307" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Children feared dead after Zaire hospital raid.</title>
<headline>Children feared dead after Zaire hospital raid.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aid agency officials said on Monday they feared some 50 sick Rwandan Hutu refugee children had been killed after they were seized at a hospital by soldiers in a rebel-held area of eastern Zaire at the weekend.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF) described the incident, which happened on Saturday at Lwiro, some 30 kilometres (22 miles) north of Bukavu near the Rwandan border, as &quot;an act of utmost barbarism&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Judging from what we've heard, I think it's unlikely that we're going to find these children alive,&quot; UNICEF spokesman in Geneva Patrick McCormick told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said that assessment was shared by a representative of the British-based charity Save the Children, running a malnutrition programme at Lwiro, who had talked to the hospital's director earlier in the day.</p>
<p>The director had described how the children, all suffering from severe malnutrition, had been hauled out of the building and thrown or herded into trucks after some 20 uniformed men drove into the village at dawn and stormed the hospital.</p>
<p>Hospital staff, some of whom were beaten by the soldiers when they tried to protect the children, had recognised a man leading the operation as the commander of a rebel detachment in the nearby town of Katana, McCormick said.</p>
<p>The U.N. refugee agency UNHCR had delivered a protest on behalf of all relief organisations operating in the region to the local authorities put in place by the rebel Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire.</p>
<p>The authorities had promised they would set up a commission of inquiry, McCormick said, citing accounts from both UNICEF and Save the Children representatives. UNICEF was funding the programme at the hospital.</p>
<p>Several adult refugees with the children, who had been picked up by aid agencies wandering lost and hungry in different parts of the region, were also taken away. But staff had managed to hide two of the youngsters.</p>
<p>Lwiro is in an area close to camps where hundreds of thousands of Rwandan Hutu refugees had lived for over two years until last November when the Tutsi-dominated Alliance seized control in the region and Zairean army troops fled.</p>
<p>Some two million Hutus fled Rwanda in the summer of 1994, fearing retribution after the country's then Hutu army and civilian militias launched a campaign of genocide against the minority Tutsis, killing up to 800,000, but were then defeated by the forces of the Tutsi-led Rwandan Patriotic Front.</p>
<p>Although many of the refugees returned to Rwanda at the end of last year, up to 300,000 fled westward before the advance of the Tutsi-dominated rebels.</p>
<p>United Nations Secretary-General Kofi Annan has accused the Alliance -- fighting to overthrow Zaire's President Mobutu Sese Seko -- of deliberately starving some 100,000 refugees who had been in camps near the city of Kisangani.</p>
<p>There were allegations earlier that the rebels had killed large numbers of refugees in the area of Bukavu and Goma at the start of their uprising in November and December last year. The U.N. has set up an investigation into these charges.</p>
<p>Alliance leader Laurent Kabila has denied the allegations, and at the weekend fiercely rejected the U.N. chief's charges over the Kisangani refugees, saying the rebels were the target of an international campaign of disinformation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
