<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="544646" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Kloeckner &amp; Co to restructure, focus on PCs, steel.</title>
<headline>Kloeckner &amp; Co to restructure, focus on PCs, steel.</headline>
<dateline>DUISBURG, Germany 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>German trading and services group Kloeckner &amp; Co AG, a subsidiary of diversified industry group Viag AG, said on Monday it planned to sell two of its five divisions and refocus its business.</p>
<p>The company said in a statement that its future business would concentrate on steel and metals trading activities and that it would transfer its personal computer products unit Computer 2000 to the Viag group.  </p>
<p>Kloeckner &amp; Co said that the move should be seen in the context of Viag's policy goal to concentrate on businesses where it can have a leadership position in the marketplace.</p>
<p>Only Kloeckner &amp; Co's steel and metal trading activities and the Computer 2000 group fulfil this goal, while the chemical, textile and mobile construction units did not.</p>
<p>These activities &quot;will be brought into strong partnerships with a perspective for the future. It is intended to give the corresponding pattern industrial leadership. The long term goal is to sell the divisions,&quot; said a Kloeckner &amp; Co spokesman.</p>
<p>As a result of these organisational changes, Kloeckner &amp; Co will no longer need to provide a holding company to manage its steel and metals trading businesses and Computer 2000.</p>
<p>The PC unit will instead be separated from Kloeckner &amp; Co and the two companies will be placed in the Viag group's logistics division.</p>
<p>Viag will then take over direct control of Computer 2000 and the logistics division will consist of Kloeckner &amp; Co, Computer 2000 and Kuehne &amp; Nagel.</p>
<p>The restructuring should be completed within the next 12 months, the company said.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, 49 228 26097 150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUISBURG, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
