<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="544714" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's Prodi faces hard bargaining with communists.</title>
<headline>Italy's Prodi faces hard bargaining with communists.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Hurst</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi will find it even harder to enact badly needed welfare reforms after his parliamentary ally, hard-left Communist Refoundation, made strong gains in Italian local elections, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;The pivotal role of the Communists has increased and it now finds itself with more bargaining power in dealings with the government,&quot; said Riccardo Barbieri, an economist with Morgan Stanley in London.</p>
<p>The government relies on support from Refoundation in the lower house of parliament where the centre-left coalition is short of an overall majority.</p>
<p>Fausto Bertinotti, who earlier this month brought the government to the brink of collapse when he voted against sending Italian troops to Albania, has said he firmly opposes any roll-back of Italy's welfare state.</p>
<p>Prodi, desperate to secure a berth for Italy in the first wave of members of a planned European currency union, wants to prune pensions and other welfare benefits to bring about a lasting improvement in state finances.</p>
<p>&quot;We can expect Communist Refoundation to raise the stakes with Prodi. We may see increased political volatility in the months ahead,&quot; said Francesco Giordano, an economist with Credit Suisse First Boston.</p>
<p>The centre-right Freedom Alliance was ahead in mayoral races in the key northern cities of Milan and Turin after the first round of voting with Prodi's Olive Tree coalition trailing in both cities, according to early results released on Monday.</p>
<p>Communist Refoundation fielded its own candidates in both cities and other local constituencies and won strong support.</p>
<p>Basking in the warm glow of electoral success, Bertinotti was quick to remind the government that he will fight hard to defend his electoral constituency -- made up of the low paid and the elderly who fear they have most to lose from welfare reform.</p>
<p>The results were &quot;an important confirmation from a significant part of the electorate of the approach to pursue towards welfare reforms avoid any (spending) cuts,&quot; Bertinotti told reporters.</p>
<p>Newspapers reported at the weekend that the government was hoping to reap savings by ironing out big discrepancies in pension benefits between different categories of employees in the public sector.</p>
<p>A plan to tax pensions paid out to people who took early retirement is also under consideration, the reports said.</p>
<p>The Olive Tree coalition's chances of winning in Milan or Turin in the second round run-off on May 11 looked increasingly slim unless it changed its strategy and struck a deal with the Communists to campaign jointly.</p>
<p>&quot;If you extrapolate from these results the Olive Tree would lose almost everywhere in national elections without the backing of Communist Refoundation,&quot; said Barbieri</p>
<p>Despite the setback at the polls, Prodi may have got off relatively lightly in view of the hefty dose of economic belt-tightening that has been inflicted on the public as Italy struggles to qualify for currency union membership.</p>
<p>&quot;The Olive Tree has not done so very badly if you consider the unpopularity of its policies,&quot; said Lorenzo Stanca, chief economist at Credito Italiano in Milan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
