<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="545020" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ's Lion Nathan hit by first half slump.</title>
<headline>NZ's Lion Nathan hit by first half slump.</headline>
<byline>James Gray</byline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lion Nathan Ltd said on Monday it was confident of a better second half result but analysts said the brewer faced a tough task as it goes head-to-head with Australia's Foster's Brewing Group.</p>
<p>Lion earlier reported a 21 percent earnings slump for the first half to NZ$72.2 million (US$50 million), mostly due to intense competition on both sides of the Tasman and a slightly higher tax rate.</p>
<p>Chief executive Douglas Myers also blamed anti drink-drive campaigns, decreased discretionary spending brought on by the growth in gambling on both sides of the Tasman, and a poor summer in Auckland.</p>
<p>&quot;The key to it is really Australia, and it's really whether they can match it with Foster's,&quot; analyst John Cairns at Cavill White Securities said.</p>
<p>Myers also said a more centralised management structure, marrying the interests of its five regional brewing interests in Australia, would pay dividends under the stewardship of new manager Gordon Cairns.</p>
<p>But he acknowledged at a news conference that, with hindsight, the company should have moved two or three years earlier in reorganising its Australian operations.</p>
<p>These represent over 70 percent of its assets and have suffered market share losses in recent years.</p>
<p>Annualised Australian market share was 41.1 percent by the end of February against 42 percent six months earlier, but Myers said data from March indicated an improved performance.</p>
<p>&quot;Once you start seeing the initiatives come through you may start seeing some of the benefits in terms of earnings as well as cash flows,&quot; Peter Sigley at brokers SBC Warburg said.</p>
<p>A depressed result, under a &quot;do nothing&quot; scenario, would have been very telling, he said.</p>
<p>Lion said the prospect of supermarket sales of beer under revamped New Zealand liquor laws could stimulate consumption.</p>
<p>As a big player in liquor retailing, the company said it would see how any change pans out over the next two years before it makes any decision about disposing of its retail operations.</p>
<p>Its Australian joint venture with Pepsico, which turned in a loss of just over NZ$5.0 million, remained a problem but Sigley said it was not intractable.</p>
<p>Analysts said the obvious solution was an amalgamation of the venture with Cadbury Schweppes in Australia. Such a deal would be difficult, Sigley added, but it was nevertheless logically sound.</p>
<p>&quot;At the end of the day both parties have got to be sensible and some sort of deal will be nutted out to the benefit of both,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>One analyst, who declined to be indentified, said Lion had hung on to market share at a cost.</p>
<p>&quot;What they are really banking on is getting strong growth coming up through the core brands,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But at their NZ$3.42 close, down six cents on the day, Lion's shares remained fully priced according to most brokers valuations. &quot;Our recommendation would be to hold, but it's very much a matter of wait and see,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>(US$1=NZ$1.44)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
