<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="545016" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks end lower after U.S. markets sag.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks end lower after U.S. markets sag.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>-----------------(Snapshot 4.25 p.m./0625 GMT)-----------------</p>
<p>AORD		2461.70  -13.00   DJIA  cl	6738.87  -53.38</p>
<p>SPI Futures	  2460     -20   US 30yr cl	 7.14   +0.06</p>
<p>10yrbond futs    92.005  -0.105   Gold NY 342.15 Lon fix 342.25</p>
<p>AUD	   0.7768 (Fri 0.7758)   CRB Index cl   248.27   +0.83</p>
<p>NIKKEI	   18670.37  +57.51   FTSE cl	 4369.70  -18.80</p>
<p>S&amp;P500(Globex)   768.60   -0.30   NZSE40	  2240.22  -13.35</p>
<p>--------------------------(April 28)---------------------------</p>
<p>*Stocks trail softer U.S. markets lower, options exercises inflate otherwise modest volumes. Volume 342.99 million, A$1.4 bln value, 1,014 stocks traded, 289 steady, 301 up, 424 down.</p>
<p>The Australian share market closed lower on Monday, trailing softer U.S. markets lower in a day of light, choppy trade.</p>
<p>Turnover figures were inflated by A$773 million of pre-opening trades related to April series options exercises.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index ended 13.0 points lower at 2,461.7.</p>
<p>June share price index futures were 20 points lower at 2,460, a 1.7 point discount to the underlying index.</p>
<p>Trade was generally quiet, with the local market playing catchup to two days of Wall Street weakness after the ANZAC day holiday weekend.  </p>
<p>&quot;It was pretty quiet and predictable,&quot; said broker Mark Pervan of Daiwa Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been watching the U.S. markets pretty closely.&quot;</p>
<p>Others echoed these sentiments, expressing no surprise at the modest losses incurred on the day.</p>
<p>&quot;We called it 10 or so points lower and it's done pretty close to that. The market has been pretty soft for most of the day,&quot; said a Sydney-based dealer.</p>
<p>National Australia Bank (NAB) featured among the banks, topping turnover with 27 million shares traded, over 24 million of them in option exercises before the market opened.  </p>
<p>NAB shares ended 11 cents higher at A$17.18 after touching a record high A$17.30 with brokers attributing the strength to its continued attraction to yield-hungry investors and newspaper reports about its bid for the News South Wales public service funds manager, Axiom Funds Management.</p>
<p>Bellwether BHP ended eight cents lower at A$17.38, with newspaper reports the company was closer to selling its 36 percent stake in Foster's Brewing and was about to wind down its Newcastle steelworks having had little impact.</p>
<p>However, brokers said any resolution of the two long running issues was likely to boost the company's outlook.  </p>
<p>Media giant News Corporation, lost over three percent to A$5.867, feeling the impact of a sharp fall in its ADRs late last week. Talk of a delayed release of its &quot;Titanic&quot; feature, reputedly the most expensive movie ever made, also dampened sentiment.</p>
<p>Base metals miner North Ltd posted a nine month net profit of A$89.2 million and forecast a higher full year result. Its shares ended 11 cents higher at A$4.44.</p>
<p>At the smaller end, Tap Oil shares jumped 18 cents to A$1.39, the rise fuelled by an well-received drilling report from its Woollybutt well, offshore Western Australia.  </p>
<p>Falls outnumbered rises by a ratio of about seven to five, while about 29 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
<p>FUTURES/OPTIONS - Futures trade saw solid activity levels, while options trade was light. Total options traded 24,569. Turnover in June SPI contracts totalled 7,025.</p>
<p>In other local markets, Australian bond yields rose as the market became nervous ahead of this week's barrage of data, particularly out of the U.S., continuing last week's retracement from two month lows.</p>
<p>By 5.10 p.m. (0710 GMT), 10 year T-bonds were yielding 7.96 percent, up on Thursday's 7.87 percent.  </p>
<p>The Australian dollar bounced back Monday as early U.S. and Japan sales were soaked up by Asian and exporter bids catching bears in a nasty short squeeze.</p>
<p>By 5.10 p.m. (0710 GMT), the local dollar was reclining at US$0.7773/85 after dipping as deep as US$0.7734 this morning. It was also up on the US$0.7756/61 level held late Thursday before the local market shut for the ANZAC Day holiday on Friday.</p>
<p>------------------------(TECHNICALS)------------------------</p>
<p>Short-term range    Support   Restnce   RSI-14  MA-10  MA-20</p>
<p>AORD   2440/2475     2450	2475	69.55   2431   2404</p>
<p>SPI    2440/2480     2460	2480	62.27   2439   2399</p>
<p>------------------------KEY ACTIVES-------------------------</p>
<p>*BHP A$17.38 (-.08) 17.30/17.48 Vol: 9,081,738</p>
<p>Bellwether in choppy trade,Foster's sale,steel result may boost</p>
<p>*CRA A$19.00 (-.10) 18.97/19.12 Vol: 2,422,301</p>
<p>*WMC A$7.60 (-.136) 7.58/7.719 Vol: 5,058,535</p>
<p>Miners dip with market, options exercise boost turnover.</p>
<p>*NAB A$17.18 (+.11) 16.98/17.30 Vol: 27,041,510</p>
<p>Big bank helps sector outperform softer market.</p>
<p>*News Corp A$5.867 (-.136) 5.85/5.95 Vol: 4,893,001</p>
<p>Media giant plays catchup after ADRs dropped last week.</p>
<p>*North A$4.44 (+.11) 4.317/4.45 Vol: 10,436,469</p>
<p>Nine month profit, upbeat outlook boosts base metals miner.</p>
<p>*Tap Oil A$1.39 (+.18) 1.29/1.39 Vol: 1,845,414</p>
<p>Drilling report boosts junior oil and gas explorer.</p>
<p>--Walter Watson 61-2 9373 1810</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
