<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="545172" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: TOCOM precious metals end firmer as yen dips.</title>
<headline>TOCOM precious metals end firmer as yen dips.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yen-based Tokyo precious metals futures ended higher on Monday, reflecting the yen's weakness against the dollar and firmer bullion prices, traders said.</p>
<p>Gold prices ranged from 14 yen to 17 yen per gram firmer, with most-active benchmark April ending up 16 yen at 1,387 yen.</p>
<p>Platinum futures ranged from eight yen to 18 yen per gram higher. Benchmark April finished up nine yen at 1,478 yen.</p>
<p>Activity was lacklustre ahead of a Japanese market holiday on Tuesday. &quot;Market players were tending to close positions before the holiday, as uncertainty over currency direction after G7 meeting limited fresh transactions,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>Spot gold was quoted at $341.60/90 per ounce at 0736 GMT, against $341.90/342.40 in New York on Friday.</p>
<p>A protracted delay in Russian exports of platinum group metals (PGM) to Japan lifted platinum group metals, especially palladium, the traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Private investors are waiting for a chance to cover their massive short positions in palladium futures. But it is unlikely palladium prices will fall sharply unless the PGM situation with Russia resolves itself,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Palladium short-term lease rates -- the cost of borrowing the metal -- jumped to about 20 percent.  </p>
<p>Platinum short-term lease rates remained high at around 12 percent. &quot;High lease rates of platinum group metals made traders wary of building fresh shorts in the spot market, and activity was mainly dominated by inter-month trade at TOCOM,&quot; one trader said. Palladium futures ranged from four yen to 22 yen per gram higher. Benchmark April was up six yen at 603 yen.</p>
<p>Platinum futures ranged from eight yen to 18 yen per gram higher. Benchmark April was up nine yen at 1,478 yen.</p>
<p>Benchmark April silver was up 2.1 yen per 10 grams at 195.2 yen. The TOCOM precious metals market will be closed on Tuesday on a national holiday. Trading will resume on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
