<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="545282" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks ease in thin trade by lunch.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks ease in thin trade by lunch.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Battered Thai stocks declined in thin trade by the lunch break on Monday as investors sold some large capitalised bank, communication and energy issues, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors sold on worries that first quarter earnings of listed firms, which are going to start being released next week, would be poor. They believe that key economic indicators, especially exports, released by the central bank last week, weren't impressive,&quot; said Bunsom Kesapradist of Asia Credit.</p>
<p>The composite SET index lost 6.59 points to 677.41 on 859 million baht turnover by the midday break.  </p>
<p>Brokers said the market continued its slump from last week as investors thought first quarter earnings of companies in other sectors would be poor like those of banks and finance firms which were released last week.</p>
<p>Most of the major sectors retreated by the break. The banking sector topped the list in terms of value, falling 0.59 percent, followed by the communication sector, which declined 1.50 percent.</p>
<p>Krung Thai Bank topped the active list, falling 0.75 baht to 34.25. TelecomAsia lost one to 40.</p>
<p>-- Suthep Chawla (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
