<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="545486" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - April 28.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - April 28.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Egyptian press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-AHRAM</p>
<p>- Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak will intensify contacts in the coming weeks to push the Middle East peace process and reactivate investment in Egypt. Mubarak's talks in Saudi Arabia will be followed by meetings with UAE President Sheikh Zaid, Syrian President Assad, Morocco's King Hassan and a tour of Eastern Europe and Asia. Mubarak receives a letter from ruler of Bahrain.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Kamal Ganzouri, 11 ministers and seven governors hold a meeting to follow up Ganzouri's Asian tour. Setting up a free zone in the Gulf of Suez was discussed during the meeting.</p>
<p>AL-AKHBAR</p>
<p>- Mubarak tells reporters during his return trip from Saudi Arabia: Good relations with our Arab neighbours is part of Egypt's national security.</p>
<p>- Egypt has decided to give cheques worth 8,344 pounds ($2,458) as compensation to &quot;grade A&quot; Gulf War victims. The payout has been stipulated by the United Nations.</p>
<p>- Egypt and Libya discuss making a $1 billion deal, setting up a joint construction company and a factory to make household appliances.</p>
<p>- Irani Foreign Minister Ali Akbar Velayati is expected to come to Cairo early next month on a short visit.</p>
<p>AL-GOMHURIA</p>
<p>- Mubarak says that Israel must stop settlement building before Palestinian President Yasser Arafat, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Jordan's King Hussein meet.</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +202 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
