<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54549" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SURINAM: New Surinam chief to seek help from former foes.</title>
<headline>New Surinam chief to seek help from former foes.</headline>
<dateline>PARAMARIBO, Surinam 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Surinam's new President Jules Wijdenbosch, who is backed by former military strongman Desi Bouterse, took office on Sunday and vowed to seek cooperation with his former political foes.</p>
<p>&quot;In our policy we will not distinguish between political colour because the crisis does not either,&quot; Wijdenbosch said during his acceptance speech.</p>
<p>Wijdenbosch, 55, won a narrow presidential runoff against former President Ronald Venetiaan last week to bring Bouterse's National Democratic Party (NDP) its first ever victory at the polls.</p>
<p>In a long speech short on specifics, Wijdenbosch said his government would launch a 100-day &quot;crisis project&quot; while continuing talks with society leaders to work on a longer-term programme.</p>
<p>Wijdenbosch, who held key posts in Bouterse's military governments of the 1980s, said the crisis project would tackle rising crime, housing shortages, education and infrastructure.</p>
<p>&quot;With true and inspiring leadership the nation will be built,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wijdenbosch's victory has led to fears at home and abroad that the former Dutch colony will return to the dark years of the 1980s when Surinam became internationally isolated.</p>
<p>Surinam, a multi-racial country of 400,000, endured two military coups, seven years of dictatorship and widespread guerrilla activity in the last two decades.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SURM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARAMARIBO, Surinam"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SURINAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
