<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="545580" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE - High-tech companies battle for skilled employees.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - High-tech companies battle for skilled employees.</headline>
<byline>Susan Nadeau</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>High-technology companies, plagued with rising salaries and diminishing numbers of computer programmers and engineers, are looking for new ways to find and keep their teams.</p>
<p>In the fast-paced, ever-changing field, companies are looking for new ways to lure skilled candidates to their offices.</p>
<p>The Internet craze spurred many companies to move into the high-technology field while the number of skilled newcomers has fallen. Industry sources say the battle for employees is intensifying as companies in all industries look for programmers to fix Year 2000 bugs in computer systems.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to enter a horrendous bidding war,&quot; Peter Mauro, a marketing representative manager for consulting firm C.W. Costello &amp; Associates, said at a course on Year 2000 solutions.</p>
<p>At a recent lunch for Chicago business leaders, Motorola's chief executive Christopher Galvin spoke of his plans to renew his high-technology company. But when asked what keeps him awake at night, Galvin said: &quot;Can we keep our team together? All of us (technology companies) have this problem.&quot;</p>
<p>In fact, Galvin said Motorola begins recruiting future employees at 14, through its summer camp and weekend technology programmes.</p>
<p>DECLINE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE GRADUATES</p>
<p>According to a study by the Information Technology Association of America (ITAA) released in late February, the number of students graduating with first degrees in computer science fell by 43 percent in 1994 compared with 1986, to 24,200 from 42,195.</p>
<p>ITAA surveyed large and mid-sized U.S. companies and found about 190,000 vacant information technology jobs nationwide, including one open position for every 10 information technology employees at tech-related companies.</p>
<p>Some 82 percent of the companies surveyed said they expected to expand their technology staff, while 68 percent cited a lack of skilled and trained workers as a barrier to growth.</p>
<p>&quot;We can anticipate further increases in the salaries of IT (information technology) workers,&quot; ITAA said. &quot;At a certain level, in a global market, U.S. companies risk their profitability if they must pay individuals premiums beyond that which customers are willing to pay for the product or service those employees produce.&quot;</p>
<p>LOOKING ABROAD</p>
<p>Many U.S. companies are looking outside the United States for talent. Casey Cowell, chief executive of U.S. Robotics Corp, said his company purchased a Tel Aviv facility in part for the staff. 3Com Corp, which has agreed to buy U.S. Robotics, also purchased a Tel Aviv company.</p>
<p>DePaul University of Chicago said its Student and Career Development Centre receives 150 calls and faxes a month from companies seeking to recruit graduates from its School of Computer Science, Telecommunications and Information Systems.</p>
<p>Starting salaries in the field currently range from $36,000 to $38,000, DePaul said, and students with master's degrees can expect up to $45,000 a year to start.</p>
<p>&quot;Competition for people with computer expertise has increased so much that some companies are offering signing bonuses in addition to the attractive salary offers,&quot; said Joan Quinn, assistant director of the employment centre.</p>
<p>She said 60 to 70 percent of graduates are expected to have job offers by the time they graduate, and nearly 100 percent within six months of graduation. Some students even get offers midway through their study programmes.</p>
<p>TURNING TO PROFESSIONAL HEAD HUNTERS</p>
<p>Many companies turn to professional recruiters or head hunters, who have reportedly resorted on occasion to handing out business cards in the car parks of high-tech companies in Silicon Valley.</p>
<p>Jesus Bustamante, an electronic information specialist for the Web Design Group in Chicago, said he receives at least five calls a week, many at home in the evening, from head hunters hoping to recruit him for jobs across the country or to get the names of his friends in the industry.</p>
<p>&quot;Sometimes the only way to get back to my dinner is to give them the name of someone else -- who I'm pretty sure isn't looking for a job either,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Surprisingly, the battle for skilled employees has spurred some unlikely bedfellows. A consortium of some 14 companies make up the Talent Alliance, which among other things gives members access to each other's key workers for projects.</p>
<p>Members of the group include AT&amp;T Corp Corp, GTE Corp , Lucent Technologies Inc, NCR Corp and Unisys Corp. The companies intend to jointly develop and share training programmes. The group has a job-matching web site, accessible with a password given to member companies' employees, which includes helpful tips for job hunting and lists of available jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;The high-tech industry had naturally some of the first companies to sign up, because of the shortage that they have in qualified talent,&quot; said Jeannette Galvanek, chief executive of Talent Alliance, herself on loan from AT&amp;T.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
