<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54583" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: No large scale lay-offs planned - BNZ.</title>
<headline>No large scale lay-offs planned - BNZ.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jobs will be shed at the Bank of New Zealand over the next year, but no big lay-offs are planned, managing director Gordon Wheaton said on Monday.</p>
<p>Alliance leader Jim Anderton said at the weekend that the bank planned to lay off 1000 staff after the October 12 election as it switched to greater electronic banking.</p>
<p>Wheaton said the bank had shed about 220 employees through branch closures over the past year.</p>
<p>More branches would be closed over the next year but there was no plan for large-scale redundancies in what he described as an &quot;evolutionary process&quot;.  </p>
<p>&quot;We don't have a plan to shed a vast number of jobs,&quot; Wheaton said on National Radio.</p>
<p>&quot;Some outlets will close. There will be job losses but nothing like the 1000 jobs.&quot;</p>
<p>At March 31, the BNZ employed 5,725 staff at 289 branches, from 5,681 at 299 branches a year earlier.</p>
<p>Wheaton said the jobs at risk over the next years were mainly at unprofitable branches and outlets.</p>
<p>How many jobs were lost would depend on the uptake of alternative delivery systems.  </p>
<p>&quot;What we would like to see are customers taking up the alternative delivery mechanisms like telephone banking and said.</p>
<p>Wheaton said that of the 220 jobs lost last year, most of those employees were retained in other positions within the bank.</p>
<p>Anderton said the banking industry was heading for an &quot;employment catastrophe&quot; as it switched to greater electronic banking.  </p>
<p>&quot;The banks are pushing the change to reduce their costs. The principal reduction in costs will be the axing of jobs as counter staff are made redundant and branches are closed.&quot; Pushing his party's economic policy, Anderton said if technological changes were going to cost thousands of jobs, opportunities should be created in other sectors.</p>
<p>&quot;There has to be a far greater emphasis in economic policy on employment creation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Last week Westpac announced it would axe 105 existing administrative managers over the next 18 months as part of the amalgamation of its operations with those of Trust Bank.  </p>
<p>National Bank last month announced cost-cutting measures including shedding staff.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
