<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="545978" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: SOCCER-ISRAEL DUMP FIVE PLAYERS BEFORE CYPRUS GAME.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ISRAEL DUMP FIVE PLAYERS BEFORE CYPRUS GAME.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel coach Shlomo Scharf threw five players out of his 20-man squad on Tuesday for breaking a team curfew ahead of a World Cup qualifier against Cyprus.</p>
<p>The five -- four first-choice players and a former captain -- had gone to a movie without informing Scharf. They failed to return to the team's hotel north of Tel Aviv in time for the curfew, squad officials said.</p>
<p>The ousted first-team players are midfielders Haim Revivo of Spanish side Celta Vigo, Avi Nimni of Maccabi Tel Aviv, left-back Felix Halfon of Hapoel Tel Aviv and right-back David Amsalem of league leaders Betar Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The fifth man dumped from the squad, Nir Klinger, a former captain who plays for Maccabi Tel Aviv, had not been expected to start the match.</p>
<p>&quot;We went to see a movie. It's a kind of therapy for us. We didn't go out to have a good time or to a disco. It looks like the situation is irreversible -- what a pity,&quot; Klinger told Israel Radio.</p>
<p>&quot;It was all just a big misunderstanding, but perhaps our mistake was that we did not inform the coach,&quot; Nimni told the radio.</p>
<p>With Tottenham's Ronnie Rosenthal also ruled out after an injury during training on Monday, the Israel side will take on a drastic new look for Wednesday's tie in Tel Aviv.</p>
<p>Scharf immediately drafted in three new players -- Reuven Atar and Avishai Janno of Maccabi Haifa and Shai Holtzman of Hapoel Beersheba. All have previous international experience.</p>
<p>The revised starting lineup now looks to be more attacking in nature -- two strikers will be used -- as Israel strive to ensure a win.</p>
<p>Anything less will not be enough to maintain their quest to qualify for the World Cup finals ahead of either Bulgaria or Russia in European group five.</p>
<p>Teams (probable):</p>
<p>Israel - Rafi Cohen, Alon Harazi or Avishai Janno, Moshe Glam, Amir Shelah, Arik Bennado, Alon Hazan, Tal Banin (captain), Itzik Zohar, Eyal Berkovic, Eli Ohana, Alon Mizrahi</p>
<p>Cyprus - to be announced</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
