<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54592" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST - Malaysia - Sept 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malaysia - Sept 16.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Monday's Malaysian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>NEW STRAITS TIMES</p>
<p>- Malaysia will play a major role in the development of renewable energy resources in the absence of a strong commitment from the West towards international efforts in this area, Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad said.</p>
<p>- The Malaysian Medical Association today expressed concern over weaknesses in the health screening procedures for foreign workers which are posing a threat to public health.</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- The Finance Ministry has ordered six ministries and one department to buck up as they have continued to show poor financial management. The seven are the education, agriculture, works, information, rural development and home ministries and the Law and Justice Division in the Prime Minister's department.</p>
<p>- All roads leading to Kuala Lumpur and highways in the Klang Valley will be subjected to toll charges in six to seven years, Works Minister Samy Vellu said.</p>
<p>BUSINESS TIMES</p>
<p>- Soon-to-be-privatised national railroad concern KTM Bhd has been described by executive chairman C. Selvarajah as being &quot;clearly under capitalised.&quot;</p>
<p>- Cellular Communications Network Sdn Bhd, owned by Technology Resources Industries Bhd (TRI), is undergoing a restructuring exercise that will allow each company within the group to operate as an independent entity.</p>
<p>- Malaysian investments in non-infrastructure projects in Cambodia rose 40.43 percent in the first eight months of the year.</p>
<p>- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
