<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54617" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Typhoon Violet approaches Taiwan.</title>
<headline>Typhoon Violet approaches Taiwan.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Medium strength Typhoon Violet is approaching Taiwan from the southeastern sea and a warning to ships may be issued by Sunday afternoon, the island's Central Weather Bureau said.</p>
<p>Violet, located 820 km (508 miles) southeast of southern Taiwan on Sunday morning, was moving northwest at 11 kph (7 mph) toward the island with maximum sustained winds of 144 kph (89 mph) and gusts of up to 180 kph (112 mph).</p>
<p>&quot;We may issue a sea warning by this afternoon, and we urge ships on southeastern sea to watch out for choppy waves,&quot; a bureau official said by telephone.</p>
<p>If Violet maintains its current movement, it would move to 610 km (378 miles) southeast of southern Taiwan by Monday morning, the official said.</p>
<p>It was too early to tell if the typhoon would score a direct hit on the island, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;The typhoon may bring torrential rains to southern and southeastern parts, but it probably will not reach the western side,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Four typhoons have battered Taiwan so far this year, killing a total of 48 people and causing about T$24 billion (US$870 million) in damage. ($ = T$27.5)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
