<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="546279" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: South African &quot;Grey Diplomat&quot; awaits Zairean talks.</title>
<headline>South African &quot;Grey Diplomat&quot; awaits Zairean talks.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The SAS Outeniqua, bought at a fire-sale price from Russia in 1993, is the depleted South African Navy's newest, biggest and ugliest ship -- dubbed &quot;the Grey Diplomat&quot; for its humanitarian missions.</p>
<p>Now it is reported to be waiting off the West African coast to serve as a platform for the first face-to-face peace talks between President Mobutu Sese Seko of Zaire and his rebel rival, Laurent Kabila.</p>
<p>Captain Fred Marais said the 166-metre (545-foot) ship has two luxury suites on either side of the accommodation block awkwardly perched near the bow of the 21,025-tonne ice-breaker.</p>
<p>And the galley will be able to serve the Zairean rivals and their host, President Nelson Mandela, food as good as they will get anywhere.</p>
<p>&quot;For a naval vessel, she's really quite comfortable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The mid-section of the slate-grey vessel is an almost clear space for cargo work of container transport, and a pad on the stern could handle most medium-sized helicopters, he added.</p>
<p>The Outeniqua, named for a mountain range inshore from the Indian Ocean port of Mossel Bay, was built by Russia as a commercial ice-breaker with military specifications.</p>
<p>Initially called the Juvent, the two-year-old ship was bought for $12.8 million, which South African defence analysts estimated was around a third of its replacement cost.</p>
<p>The ship carries two Puma helicopters and is capable of a modest 17.5 knots. As a support vessel for South Africa's permanent Antarctic expedition, it is ideal with an ice-breaking capability designed to help clear Russia's northern sea lanes.</p>
<p>The Outeniqua and the supply ship Drakensberg are the South African Navy's only full-sized vessels. The rest are locally built patrol boats and a small fleet of Israeli gunboats.</p>
<p>In 1993 the Outeniqua -- which boasts a well-equipped hospital -- delivered to Trieste in Italy a 130-bed portable field hospital donated by the country's Moslem community to fellow Moslems in Bosnia.</p>
<p>The ship spent its commissioning cruise delivering medical supplies to Indian Ocean islands and has made regular voyages to the country's Antarctic base.</p>
<p>In 1995, the Outeniqua transported 2,000 former political prisoners to a reunion with Mandela on Robben Island in Cape Town's Table Bay.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
