<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="546241" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Thousands more evacuate from Red River flood.</title>
<headline>Thousands more evacuate from Red River flood.</headline>
<byline>Gilbert Le Gras</byline>
<dateline>WINNIPEG, Manitoba 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Officials ordered another 4,200 residents of Winnipeg to evacuate by Tuesday night amid fears a hastily built dike in the south of the city may buckle under the pressure of the flooding Red River.</p>
<p>&quot;The water has reached a certain level and we will no longer take risks with people,&quot; Winnipeg Mayor Susan Thompson said as she issued an evacuation order to south end residents threatened by the worst flood in 145 years.</p>
<p>Winnipeg, Manitoba's capital and largest city, has 650,000 residents.</p>
<p>Twenty miles (32 km) south at Ste. Agathe, 37 emergency workers were rescued by soldiers after a dike breach early on Tuesday submerged the town under six feet (two metres) of silty brown Red River water. No one was injured, Emergency Management Organisation spokeswoman Cynthia Webster said.</p>
<p>Ring dikes around seven other towns held, she added.</p>
<p>Peter Doerksen, 58, was one of the last of Ste. Agathe's 477 people to flee when walls of water crashed through the dike and flooded the town in 45 minutes. &quot;When Grand Forks got hit, it was an unbelievable scenario then when you saw it on TV and read about it. This could not supposedly happen in Manitoba. It did,&quot; Doerksen said.</p>
<p>Dike breaches in Grand Forks, North Dakota, forced 90 percent of the city's 50,000 residents from their homes 10 days ago.</p>
<p>Some 17,000 Manitobans have been forced from their homes in towns and farms in the region. More than 4,200 evacuees have sought refuge at a Winnipeg sports arena.</p>
<p>Laura Rance prepared to evacuate after she was ordered to leave her home in Sanford, southwest of Winnipeg, by Tuesday night along with 2,000 other rural residents. &quot;People are really anxious. We weren't supposed to get water here so there's a sense of injustice. This took people by surprise,&quot; Rance said after moving furniture from her basement.</p>
<p>Her home and Winnipeg's south end were defended by a 25-mile (40 km) earthen wall being thrown together just south of Sanford, but engineers feared it might not withstand the onslaught of what is now being called &quot;The Red Sea.&quot;</p>
<p>Work crews began reinforcing a highway surrounding the city as a last line of defence for 10,000 people living in the city's southwest. In other parts of the city, Winnipeggers put their faith in a massive ditch built in 1968 to divert high Red River waters around its limits. The ditch was built after a flood in 1950 forced the evacuation of 100,000 people.</p>
<p>People forced from their southern Manitoba homes streamed in to register with the Red Cross for flood relief and temporary accommodations at a Winnipeg sports arena where families, many of whose houses and businesses were swamped, were given food, health care and vouchers to buy groceries.</p>
<p>Blake Scott, one of many city employees coordinating the evacuation centre, said the upheaval had left most people tense and weary. &quot;Some people have been worried about the river itself -- they've been working in it, around it. They're worried about their families, where they are going to stay, eating -- their liveihood is not there right now,&quot; Scott said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINNIPEG, Manitoba"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
