<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54626" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Low prices threaten China natgas production - paper.</title>
<headline>Low prices threaten China natgas production - paper.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's low, state-set natural gas prices are failing to cover production costs, threatening development of the country's huge natural gas reserves and throwing into doubt ambitious output targets, state media said.</p>
<p>Without reform of state gas prices, onshore production was likely to grow by 25 percent by 2000, instead of the 56 percent growth expected, the China Daily Business Weekly said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite universal recognition of the abundance and cleanliness of natural gas, its development and utilisation in China faces a bumpy road,&quot; the official newspaper said.</p>
<p>Low prices could cut production, forcing a rise in imports and foreign currency expenditure, it quoted unnamed senior industry executives as saying.  </p>
<p>The state regulates prices for most gas marketed by onshore producers, while the offshore sector was permitted to sell its natural gas at market prices, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Only with further pricing reform can enthusiasm in natural gas exploration and development by enleashed,&quot; it quoted unidentified experts as saying.</p>
<p>Gas reserves in China could total around 40 trillion cubic metres, but reserves of only two trillion cubic metres had been confirmed so far.</p>
<p>Price reform was urgently needed for the onshore sector, which accounted for 94 percent of China's output and produced 16 billion cubic metres of gas in 1995, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
