<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="546283" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Jobs, black managers SAfrican priorities - Ramaphosa. [CORRECTED 18:54 GMT]</title>
<headline>Jobs, black managers SAfrican priorities - Ramaphosa. [CORRECTED 18:54 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A drive to dilute white control of South Africa's economy needs to produce real jobs and black management of companies if it is to succeed, one of the country's leading black businessmen said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Cyril Ramaphosa, a former unionist and politician who moved into business last year after his prospects of succeeding Nelson Mandela as president faded, said growing black ownership of holding companies was not enough.</p>
<p>&quot;Ownership without management control can actually be meaningless,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The challenge is how to make sure we get our hands on the levers not only of ownership power but management and operational power,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Ramaphosa is deputy executive chairman of New Africa Investment Ltd, one of South Africa's largest black empowerment companies, which in recent months has taken a controlling stakes in and Johnnies Industrial Corporation -- of which he is chairman (corrects by removing reference to JCI).</p>
<p>About nine percent of the economy is now owned by black investment companies but many of the firms they control are still white-run. The change of ownership has not brought new factories or new jobs for millions of unemployed blacks.</p>
<p>Ramaphosa told reporters that creating jobs was a priority and called for a national jobs summit. He said he hoped by the turn of the century that many black-owned companies would have blacks in top management positions.</p>
<p>Ramaphosa, former National Union of Mineworkers leader and one of the chief negotiators for Mandela's African National Congress in the transition to black majority rule up to 1994, said he had no plans to return to politics.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
