<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54632" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Touring Perry tries to rally Gulf Arabs against Iraq.</title>
<headline>Touring Perry tries to rally Gulf Arabs against Iraq.</headline>
<byline>William Maclean</byline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry toured Saudi Arabia, Kuwait and Bahrain on Sunday to rally Gulf Arab support for an American military buildup aimed at averting potential trouble from Gulf War foe Iraq.</p>
<p>In Kuwait, the only Arab state to openly support the American show of force, Perry said the United States &quot;will take whatever action is necessary&quot; to enforce an expanded southern Iraqi no-fly zone and to protect U.S. pilots patrolling it.</p>
<p>Asked if more U.S. strikes against Iraq were still possible, Perry told a news conference: &quot;Yes it is still a possibility.&quot;</p>
<p>Later in Bahrain Perry said Iraq had rebuilt air defence units and fired six missiles at U.S. warplanes since U.S. missile strikes against Iraq in early September.</p>
<p>He said Washington would send 23 F-16 warplanes to Bahrain &quot;as part of the military force we have in this area, generally that is providing security and stability for the whole region.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;For the security of this region, to continue Operation Southern Watch -- that is the linchpin of security and stability in this region,&quot; Perry said in Bahrain, referring to air patrols of the Western-imposed air exclusion zone.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not tolerate this threat to our pilots,&quot; Perry said, adding Washington stood &quot;shoulder to shoulder&quot; with Saudi Arabia and Kuwait during heightened tension with Baghdad.</p>
<p>Perry began the trip in Saudi Arabia, the most powerful Gulf Arab state and world's largest oil exporter, and returned there the same day in the evening to consult with King Fahd.</p>
<p>A U.S. official confirmed that Perry had arrived in Jeddah but gave no further information.</p>
<p>Saudi Defence Minister Prince Sultan bin Abdul-Aziz said he did not expect a new U.S. strike against Iraq after Baghdad's decision announced on Friday to suspend its air defence attacks on U.S. and allies warplanes.</p>
<p>Asked if he expected a military confrontation between the United States and Iraq after the Iraqi move, Prince Sultan told reporters: &quot;No. I do not think so.&quot;</p>
<p>His remarks appeared to echo U.S. ambassador Madeleine Albright who said in the Unied States Washington would not be pressed into &quot;overreacting&quot; to Iraq, and Iraq appeared unlikely to do anything that would provoke a new U.S. attack.</p>
<p>But in Kuwait Perry dismissed the Iraqi pledge to abandon attacks on U.S. patrolling the southern and northern zones, saying: &quot;We cannot rely on (President) Saddam Hussein's promises.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said they expected Perry would restate the case to the Saudis for containing an unrepentant Iraq six years after it invaded and occupied Kuwait. Gulf Arab states spent tens of billions of dollars to fund the U.S.-led multinational coalition that ejected Iraqi troops from Kuwait in the Gulf War.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia, eager thus far not to appear as being directly involved in the current U.S. military buildup in the Gulf, has so far kept silent about Perry's visit.</p>
<p>Perry said he had asked Kuwait's emir, Sheikh Jaber al-Ahmad al-Sabah, for permission to proceed with a plan announced by Washington on Friday to deploy several thousand more U.S. troops in the Gulf state.</p>
<p>The emir had replied that Kuwait would respond after Kuwait's Supreme Defence Council discussed it, Perry added.</p>
<p>Perry said Saddam posed a danger not only in northern Iraq, where his forces attacked Kurds last month, but could also &quot;move to coerce or even attack his neighbours to the south&quot;</p>
<p>Kuwait, grateful to Washington for leading the 1991 Gulf War that liberated it from a seven-month Iraqi occupation, is so far the only Arab country to support Washington in its latest standoff with Saddam.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BAHRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
