<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="546472" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Police guard schools as Tirana edges back to normal.</title>
<headline>Police guard schools as Tirana edges back to normal.</headline>
<byline>Belinda Goldsmith</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Schools reopened in Tirana on Tuesday under the protection of armed police as the Albanian capital struggled to return to normal after two months of chaos.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Bashkim Fino, of an interim all-party government bridging the gap to a general election expected on June 29, told national television an 8pm-6am curfew imposed across Albania in early March may be relaxed this week to 10pm.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is Tirana is much calmer now,&quot; said police officer Arben Romani, on guard at Tirana's Emin Duraku Primary School with a Kalashnikov resting on his right shoulder.</p>
<p>Children, bored after two months at home, ran eagerly through school gates on Tuesday morning while parents watched anxiously from behind the fence.</p>
<p>&quot;I am really glad the schools are open again but I am a bit worried,&quot; said Vera, whose eight-year-old daughter Genta attends the Edith Durham Primary School in the city centre.</p>
<p>&quot;My daughter was awake early this morning as she was so excited about going back to school. They have all got bored at home, watching TV and reading.</p>
<p>&quot;The main thing we are worried about is other children bringing guns into the school.&quot;</p>
<p>Schools throughout Albania were closed on March 3 when a state of emergency was declared across the country.</p>
<p>Albanians, angered over the loss of savings in fraudulent investment funds, took to the streets demanding the resignation of President Sali Berisha and looting state arsenals as army and police officers fled.</p>
<p>Unofficial estimates suggest around one million guns are now spread across Albania's 3.4 million people and over 300 people have been killed in the violence, many shot accidentally.</p>
<p>Kristo Gjokrusha, headmaster of Emin Duraku school that has 890 pupils aged between six and 14, said teachers had remained in the schools during the uprising to protect the limited resources they have.</p>
<p>He said it would have been impossible to reopen the schools without armed protection. Even with police on duty some parents were too scared to allow the children back.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone has a Kalashnikov and we are worried about security,&quot; Gjokrusha told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Parents fear other children could bring guns to school with them.&quot;</p>
<p>Schools hours have been shortened, with classes ending at 3pm instead of 4.30pm, in a bid to reassure parents about their childrens' safety.</p>
<p>The term has been lengthened by a month, now ending on June 21, to try to make up for some of the lost time.</p>
<p>Teachers have also decided that no-one will be given bad grades.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to stimulate the pupils,&quot; Gjokrusha said.</p>
<p>Ten-year-old Irisa Simo has written to U.S. President Bill Clinton to ask for his help.</p>
<p>&quot;I want him to know the situation here and would like to talk to him personally to ask him to do what he can to get our schools running again,&quot; Irisa told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It is alright to have an armed policeman at our school gate but I really think we should have two.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
