<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="546522" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico central bank inflation fight key to growth.</title>
<headline>Mexico central bank inflation fight key to growth.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's central bank reiterated on Tuesday that fighting inflation is the best way it can aid economic growth and help create jobs and boost real salaries.</p>
<p>&quot;The annual inflation rate showed a clear tendency downwards,&quot; the central bank said in its annual report for 1996, adding its policies also helped drive down inflationary expectations.</p>
<p>In 1996, the annual inflation rate, measured by the consumer price index, was 27.7 percent, after reaching 51.97 percent in 1995.  </p>
<p>In its yearly report, Banco de Mexico said its fight against inflation would also help create a greater pool of savings in Mexico, thus helping to weaken market forces as the principle influence on interest rates.</p>
<p>Lower inflation also was a spur for investment.</p>
<p>&quot;In these conditions, foreign and domestic savers can see with greater certainty the real returns they obtain by investing in financial instruments denominated in the local currency,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Moreover, as prices stabilize, savers will be more ready to hold onto longer-term instruments.&quot;  </p>
<p>The central bank said consumption and investment also made significant contributions to the economy in 1996, adding to the growth in exports.</p>
<p>It noted financial and exchange markets stabilized substantially last year, saying that peso volatility against the dollar was &quot;reduced in a considerable manner.&quot;</p>
<p>The bank said a better macroeconomic picture, as well better perspectives on the economy improved the conditions under which Mexico obtained funds on international capital markets.  </p>
<p>The central bank noted that the rise of net international assets by some $5.864 billion during the year was due to increased external debt placements, a higher price of oil that bumped up net reveneus for PEMEX and the dollar option plan that the bank put into place mid-year.</p>
<p>The bank said that, through the dollar option plan, it obtained $909 million in the year, by exercising options worth $930 million that it offered from August to December.</p>
<p>Banco de Mexico said the results of allowing the currency to float could at the end of 1994 &quot;could be considered positive.&quot;</p>
<p>It noted there had been fears a floating exchange rate would lead to market volatility.</p>
<p>&quot;The evolution shown by the exchange rate from the start of 1996 did not correspond to this fear,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>((--Robert Kozak, Mexico City newsroom +525 728 9559))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
