<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54666" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwait plans for elections despite Iraq flap.</title>
<headline>Kuwait plans for elections despite Iraq flap.</headline>
<byline>Inal Ersan</byline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kuwait's parliamentary elections will go ahead as planned on October 7 despite heightened tension with former occupier Baghdad, officials said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The country's interior ministry announced the names of 251 men running for parliament in the second national assembly elections since the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>Saturday was the deadline for registration to compete in the elections. About 80 of the candidates are serving or former members of parliament.</p>
<p>The fortunes of the 50-seat chamber are watched closely around the Gulf by liberals who see it as a potential model for other states in the region in generations to come. Women may not vote or stand for election.</p>
<p>Commentators say the government headed by the ruling Sabah family is working hard to wrest control of the chamber from liberal and Islamist opposition MPs who have scored stinging attacks on official policy since the last elections in 1992.</p>
<p>The opposition has secured more parliamentary control over state funds and sought more elected MPs serving in the cabinet headed by Prime Minister Sheikh Saad al-Abdulla al-Sabah.</p>
<p>It has also used the assembly to criticise Kuwaiti leaders for alleged failings in the 1980s and in 1990, notably the crisis with Iraq that culminated in Baghdad's 1990 invasion.</p>
<p>Whatever the outcome of the all-male elections the prime minister is by tradition a member of the Sabah, but his cabinet choice usually reflects the assembly's political complexion.</p>
<p>Two members are elected from each of 25 constituencies. Political parties are banned but the authorities tolerate a range of groups that act much as parties at election time.</p>
<p>There are some 107,169 listed voters from the Kuwaiti citizen population of almost 700,000. Kuwait's total population is around two million, the majority of whom are foreign workers.</p>
<p>Kuwaitis say tension with Iraq over enforcement of a Western-imposed no-fly zone has made security an election issue, but add economic problems like unemployment are still uppermost in people's minds.</p>
<p>Eight Stealth bombers landed in Kuwait on Friday for a possible military strike against Iraq to punish Baghdad for firing missiles last week at U.S. warplanes patrolling a southern Iraqi no-fly zone.</p>
<p>Kuwait allows civilian males born to Kuwaiti fathers to vote. Military personnel, policemen, women, Kuwaitis naturalised less than two decades ago and foreign residents cannot vote.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
