<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="546651" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: FEATURE-Mexico warrior of the left in last stand.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Mexico warrior of the left in last stand.</headline>
<byline>Michael Stott</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Like the Aztec warrior whose name he bears, Cuauhtemoc Cardenas is a stubborn fighter.</p>
<p>After losing presidential elections in 1988 and 1994, the veteran warrior of Mexico's left is making what analysts consider could be his last stand: a bid to win the first-ever election for mayor of Mexico City. Victory would put Cardenas and his Party of the Democratic Revolution (PRD) on the road to winning the presidency in 2000; defeat would probably end his chances of winning high office, political analysts say.</p>
<p>Cardenas was so concerned about failing that he consulted a leading pollster about his chances against specific opposition candidates before agreeing to run, a political source told Reuters.</p>
<p>Hoping to woo younger voters, the 62-year-old candidate has attempted to smile more and shake off the wooden image that cost him support in the 1994 presidential campaign. A snappy Web site (http::/www.cardenas97.org.mx) offers computer buffs the chance to download the campaign programme, enter discussion groups or e-mail the candidate.</p>
<p>Three recent opinion polls have put Cardenas ahead of his two main challengers for the July 6 vote; surveys by organisations closer to the government put him behind. But, in a country with a long history of electoral fraud, winning popular support is not the only battle.</p>
<p>VOTERS DOUBT HONEST ELECTION</p>
<p>A survey by Indemerc/Louis Harris in March found 30 percent of Mexico City residents believe the election will be a &quot;total fraud,&quot; 21 percent predict a &quot;high level of fraud&quot; by the long-ruling Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI), and only 12 percent think the vote will be totally clean.</p>
<p>Cardenas knows all about electoral fraud. His 1988 bid for the presidency was thwarted when official computers crashed after early returns showed him ahead. When the count resumed, the PRI's Carlos Salinas de Gortari was ahead and was finally awarded the election. The government denied any cheating.</p>
<p>&quot;I trust that this time, in 1997, we are not going to find ourselves in the same situation as in 1988,&quot; Cardenas told Reuters in an interview. &quot;That's the commitment the president (Ernesto Zedillo) has made and I hope he will stick to it.&quot;</p>
<p>Indemerc pollsters said one of the most often-heard opinions about the campaign was &quot;let's see whether this time they'll let Cuauhtemoc win&quot; -- indicating that popular memories of the 1988 alleged fraud remain strong.</p>
<p>Memories are important for Cuauhtemoc, a man who combines two of the most important names in Mexican history. His first name is that of the last Aztec leader who led his troops to a brave, bloody and disastrous final defeat against the Spanish conquistadors in 1521; his surname evokes his father Lazaro, who ruled Mexico from 1934-40 and is remembered as the country's most popular president this century.</p>
<p>A CHANCE TO FIX POTHOLES</p>
<p>Should Cardenas win the mayoral vote, more prosaic tasks lie ahead: fixing potholed roads, improving refuse collection, cleaning up the notoriously corrupt police force and reducing Mexico City's choking, lung-destroying air pollution.</p>
<p>He proposes promoting public transport more vigorously, rooting out corruption, improving pay and training for police and directing more money toward housing, health and infrastructure for the poor.</p>
<p>He will also ask the federal government to take on the $1.7 billion debt the city has run up under the PRI mayors of the past, but he promises junior and middle-level members of the current PRI-dominated administration will keep their jobs under him if they can prove their honesty and competence.</p>
<p>But Cardenas admits the powers of the new Mexico City mayor will be severely limited. Zedillo's government agreed to allow residents of the capital to elect their mayor for the first time since the 1910-17 Mexican Revolution as part of a package of reforms to strengthen democracy -- but with limits.</p>
<p>The victor will have two key appointments -- the police chief and the chief prosecutor -- decided for him by Zedillo, and he will govern only the Federal District, less than half of the urban sprawl commonly referred to as Mexico City. The rest is governed by the State of Mexico, which surrounds the Federal District to the north, east and west.</p>
<p>At three years, the new mayor's term will only be half that of state governors, and he will not be allowed to borrow money for the city without Zedillo's express agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;Many things are still left to the discretion of the (central) authorities,&quot; Cardenas conceded. &quot;But we can make a difference. We believe all the city's problems do have a solution.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
