<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="546695" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ's Glenbrook must prove BHP wrong to survive - CEO.</title>
<headline>NZ's Glenbrook must prove BHP wrong to survive - CEO.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>BHP NZ Steel chief executive Malcolm Burns has said on Wednesday he will fight to keep the billion-dollar Glenbrook steel plant open in the face of owner BHP's decision to close it.</p>
<p>BHP announced yesterday a sweeping reorganisation of its steelmaking in Australia and said the Glenbrook plant south of Auckland would be closed within 10 years.</p>
<p>The plant could be closed earlier, perhaps within two years, if returns did not improve, BHP Steel chief executive Rod McNeilly said.  </p>
<p>Burns said a decision on closing steelmaking at Glenbrook could be made as early as 1999.</p>
<p>He said the $27 million upgrading of the plants' number one melter would still go ahead. The challenge to the workforce and management at NZ Steel was to prove BHP wrong.</p>
<p>However, Burns said BHP's analysis of Glenbrook's inherent problems as being too small, based on unusual technology and with formidable exchange rate and depressed market problems, was sensible.</p>
<p>Steel sales this calendar year had declined quite sharply, and the appreciation in the exchange rate had continued.  </p>
<p>&quot;If the exchange rate keeps going the way it has in recent years, in the end there will be nothing we here at the Glenbrook site can do. It is just wiping so much revenue off there is just no way you can keep up in cost reductions.&quot;</p>
<p>McNeilly said BHP NZ Steel was making a single-digit return on capital, and BHP wanted to see double digits at the end of 18 months.</p>
<p>The Glenbrook operation, south of Auckland, was &quot;sub-scale&quot; and had been under &quot;increasing pressure from a deteriorating domestic market, depressed international steel prices and a strong New Zealand dollar,&quot; McNeilly said.  </p>
<p>&quot;In addition, New Zealand Steel's steelmaking facilities are based on a relatively complex technology. While we have significantly enhanced the plant's potential by doubling productivity in the last five years and investing in new metal-coating facilities, it is difficult to envisage the replacement of the plant's steelmaking facilities at the end of their current life, estimated to be no more than 10 years.</p>
<p>&quot;Indeed, should business conditions not improve, it is entirely possible that the steelmaking facilities will close earlier.&quot;  </p>
<p>BHP NZ announced plans to cut 600 of the 1600 staff last October but got the green light to invest in the new $27 million melter after persuading Melbourne head office that $50 million a year could be shaved off costs.</p>
<p>The new melter was said to extend the life of the plant by up to 15 years.</p>
<p>BHP NZ exports about 60 percent of the plant's 750,000 tonnes annual production. Exports are split equally between North America, Australia, Japan, Southeast Asia and the Pacific.  </p>
<p>Last month Burns said the strength of the dollar was threatening the business, improving the price competitiveness of steel from Eastern Europe, Japan, South America, and Korea.</p>
<p>Burns said staff numbers would almost reach 1200 by the end of next month, and in the next two years numbers would fall to about 1000.</p>
<p>BHP could pull the plug on the steelmaking plant at any time though there would be a substantial financial cost to doing so, he said.</p>
<p>If steelmaking ceased, coating and painting would probably continue and would employ between 200 and 300 people.  </p>
<p>The Glenbrook smelter has had a chequered career since it opened in the 1970s using special technology to make steel from the local iron sands.</p>
<p>The government wrote off $1.5 billion before selling New Zealand Steel in 1987 for $327 million to Equiticorp in a deal that led to Equiticorp founder Alan Hawkins being charged over the purchase.</p>
<p>BHP bought into the company in 1989 along with Steel and Tube, Fisher and Paykel and ANZ Bank, buying out the other shareholders in 1991.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
