<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="546874" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Dubai moves to deter share concentration.</title>
<headline>Dubai moves to deter share concentration.</headline>
<byline>Youssef Kassem</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dubai has stepped in to deter proxy share buying, a move which analysts say highlights hurdles to widening the investor base and turning the United Arab Emirates' fledgling stock market into a viable, official bourse.</p>
<p>The UAE member state this week announced its intention to wipe out proxy buying, a widespread practice which officials believe is behind a monopoly on shares by a select few investors in the small, unregulated market.</p>
<p>&quot;The proxy issue is not new. It is common in all Gulf states,&quot; said one broker active in the 40 billion dirham ($10.9 billion) capitalised market in which only nationals can trade.</p>
<p>Proxy purchases, locally defined as share buying in the name of other UAE nationals by using their identity cards, are used to overcome low share allotment in initial public offerings (IPOs).</p>
<p>Brokers say most new issues since 1992 have been heavily oversubscribed amid limited local investment opportunities and assured rapid appreciation in share prices soon after listing.</p>
<p>The UAE is trying to diversify from reliance on oil and give the private sector a bigger role in its state-dominated economy.</p>
<p>Measures to curb the proxy practice surfaced only this week with Dubai Crown Prince Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid al-Maktoum instructing the new one billion dirham Emaar Properties to halt proxy buying in its IPO.</p>
<p>Sheikh Mohammed said the practice denied small investors with limited savings the opportunity to participate in the stock market ahead of an official bourse, expected later this year.</p>
<p>Brokers said despite Dubai's stated intentions, the task would be difficult and most shares would continue to be concentrated in the hands of a few big investors.</p>
<p>&quot;What big investors don't get in the IPO, they will buy from the market after listing, anyway,&quot; said one such investor.</p>
<p>The official WAM news agency said thousands of proxy buying cases were detected by Emaar founders who would sift through applications to ensure that subscribers to 500 shares -- the minimum application -- got what they had applied for.</p>
<p>Two thirds of Emaar's capital is open to the public. The rest is held by founders, including the Dubai government with a 10 percent stake. This means Emaar can only accept a maximum of around 130,000 applications of 500 shares each.</p>
<p>But bankers managing the issue said they had received more than 180,000 applications worth about 3.3 billion dirhams, which puts the fate of about 50,000 applications in question.</p>
<p>Analysts say all the subscriptions complied with UAE law, in spite of the proxy practice.</p>
<p>&quot;The founders' committee is faced with a legal dilemma...all applications were made by or in the name of nationals who have the right by law to buy and sell shares,&quot; said one broker. &quot;How can the committee determine whether a UAE national had paid for an identification document to buy into Emaar?&quot; he asked.</p>
<p>A UAE newspaper columnist said big investors were taking advantage of less-affluent nationals by offering them money for the use of their IDs. Foreigners are also believed to have bought shares in the name of UAE nationals, analysts said.</p>
<p>They said applications with different names but the same mailing details could be questioned. But one trader said this could be misleading as nationals often share mailing addresses.</p>
<p>Analysts said some subscribers who had borrowed millions from banks to finance purchases might incur losses related to interest due on the bank loans.</p>
<p>($1=3.67 dirhams)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DUBAI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
