<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="546950" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: World Bank profit squeeze threatens aid to poor.</title>
<headline>World Bank profit squeeze threatens aid to poor.</headline>
<byline>Peter Bate</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>World Bank President James Wolfensohn on Tuesday warned economic policymakers that the development institution's net profits were set to drop sharply, leaving less money to help the world's poor.</p>
<p>The warning, which came on the final day of the lending agency's semi-annual meeting, was made before the joint International Monetary Fund and World Bank Development Committee, made up of rich and poor countries.</p>
<p>The Bank earned about $1.2 billion last year, which it used for a combination of purposes. Some was put into reserves. Some was used to reduce interest rate charges for borrowers or to help fund low-cost loans for the world's poorest nations.</p>
<p>But the bank's profits are falling partly because it is earning less on the tens of billions of dollars it lends to developing countries and former Communist bloc nations.</p>
<p>Moreover, it intends to use some of its future profits to finance its share of a new international plan to provide relief to debt-ridden poor countries that have adopted tough economic plans set by the International Monetary Fund.</p>
<p>Up to 20 countries -- many in Africa - - are expected to qualify for help under the plan, which could cost creditors as much as $8.4 billion.</p>
<p>Developing nations, worried about falling levels of foreign aid, last week urged the World Bank and IMF to adopt more flexible terms for the new initiative, which will not benefit many poor countries for years.</p>
<p>But IMF Managing Director Michel Camdessus rejected that that during the week of meetings, saying: &quot;We do not foresee any significant change of regime in the next few years.&quot;</p>
<p>Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin, who also spoke to the panel, urged the World Bank to concentrate its support on helping poor nations that were committed to sound economic policies and poverty reduction.</p>
<p>The aim should be to increase the effectiveness of scarce development assistance, he said, adding that priority should be given to helping the poor and protecting the environment.</p>
<p>&quot;Excessive military expenditures and subsidies for inefficient state-owned enterprises should be substantially reduced,&quot; Rubin declared.</p>
<p>The discussion of global poverty was also heard on Capital Hill on Tuesday, not far from where global policymakers were meeting, as Clinton administration officials and congressmen discussed ways to bring economic well-being to sub-Saharan Africa.</p>
<p>In an unusual alliance across party lines, Republican House Speaker Newt Gingrich agreed with Clinton that the United States needed a new economic policy for an area long neglected by the superpowers.</p>
<p>Gingrich, in testimony at a House Ways and Means Committee hearing, said the initiatives offered a chance for the United States to form a partnership with African nations.</p>
<p>&quot;We have an opportunity to form a genuine partnership,&quot; he said, adding that the United States should tell Africans, &quot;We want to work with you on the right economic policies.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky, in remarks to the congressional committee, also called for a more aggressive effort in Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;In an increasingly competitive global economy, the United States cannot afford to neglect a largely untapped market of some 600-million-plus people, and the world cannot afford to see a vast region marginalized,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Rubin, in his remarks before the joint IMF-World Bank panel, painted a hopeful picture on the outlook for helping the world's poor.  &quot;As we approach the 21st century, we are well positioned to reduce global poverty and encourage sustainable growth,&quot; he told the delegates.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
