<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54698" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton admits Saddam stronger than at war's end.</title>
<headline>Clinton admits Saddam stronger than at war's end.</headline>
<byline>Jim Wolf</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton admitted on Sunday that Iraqi President Saddam Hussein was in better shape now than at the end of the Gulf War, but voiced confidence a U.S. military buildup would keep him in check.</p>
<p>He said he expected Kuwait to welcome up to 5,000 additional U.S. Army troops in response to what Washington regards as renewed Iraqi aggressiveness, despite Kuwait's initial hesitation.</p>
<p>Senior U.S. officials said they attached scant importance to Iraq's announcement on Friday that it would stop firing at U.S. and allied warplanes policing &quot;no fly&quot; zones over northern and southern Iraq.</p>
<p>Answering reporters' questions on the White House lawn before leaving on a campaign trip, Clinton said of Saddam: &quot;I believe that he's in better shape than he was the day after the Gulf War in 1991.&quot;</p>
<p>Referring to Saddam's &quot;increased aggressiveness,&quot; Clinton said the expanded southern no-fly zone was designed to curb Iraq's ability to threaten U.S. oil-producing allies such as Kuwait and Saudi Arabia, &quot;and I think we will achieve that.&quot;</p>
<p>Army Gen. John Shalikashvili, chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, said Iraq was still moving antiaircraft defenses in the south &quot;trying to hide them from us.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;What we are seeing on the ground is sort of a mixed story,&quot; Shalikashvili said on ABC's &quot;This Week with David Brinkley.&quot; &quot;The intelligence is in fact mixed about what Saddam is doing with his missile sites.&quot;</p>
<p>The United States has warned Iraq that it would exact a price for any effort to repair missile sites damaged by 44 U.S. cruise missiles fired this month at air defenses in the south. The latest showdown with Iraq began Aug. 31 when Saddam's forces surged into a Kurdish enclave in the north at the request of one side in factional fighting.</p>
<p>Secretary of State Warren Christopher declined to spell out whether the United States was demanding Saddam withdraw antiaircraft defenses in the south to avoid further attack.</p>
<p>&quot;We've given certain warnings to Saddam Hussein, I'm not going to be specific as to what they are,&quot; he said on CBS' &quot;Face the Nation.&quot;</p>
<p>Christopher added that the United States had told Iraq it planned to police the expanded &quot;no fly&quot; zone in the south which it extended this month to the outskirts of Baghdad.</p>
<p>Madeleine Albright, the U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, said Saddam seemed unlikely to provoke a renewed attack by newly strengthened U.S. forces, and the United States would not be pressed into &quot;overreacting.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It looks as though Saddam Hussein is not going to do anything else,&quot; she said on NBC's &quot;Meet the Press.&quot;</p>
<p>In an apparent effort to head off U.S. preparations for a fresh punitive strike, Iraq said on Friday it was suspending &quot;military reaction&quot; to U.S. and allied warplanes enforcing &quot;no fly&quot; zones in northern and southern Iraq.</p>
<p>On Sunday, the Pentagon delayed plans for the possible deployment of thousands of Army troops to join the buildup in and around the Gulf while Kuwait considered the request.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that there is no problem here, based on what I know,&quot; Clinton told reporters. &quot;I think that what happened was that the decision on the movements that we had made actually became public before we had done our regular consultation and the Kuwaitis had done their regular review.&quot;</p>
<p>Shalikashvili said he expected Kuwait &quot;to let us know very shortly that they will be delighted to receive those troops.&quot;</p>
<p>The troops from Fort Hood in Texas had been alerted on Friday night for possible deployment to the Gulf on Sunday. The Pentagon has also ordered a second aircraft carrier to the region, sent eight F-117A Stealth bombers to Kuwait and transferred B-52 bombers to the British base at Diego Garcia in the Indian Ocean Island.</p>
<p>Defense Secretary William Perry, shuttling between Gulf allies and Turkey to consult on Iraq policy, said Bahrain, another U.S. Gulf ally, had agreed to let the United States base 23 F-16 warplanes there.</p>
<p>Asked if more U.S. strikes against Iraq were still possible, Perry told a news conference on a brief visit to Kuwait: &quot;Yes, it is still a possibility.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
