<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="546905" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tobacco must propose pact without total immunity.</title>
<headline>Tobacco must propose pact without total immunity.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Gail Appleson, Law Correspondent</p>
<p>State attorneys general suing the tobacco industry agree that any settlement with manufacturers will not grant total immunity from lawsuits and say the pressure is on cigarette makers to propose an acceptable plan.</p>
<p>&quot;The bottom line is that the tobacco industry wants a settlement...they've run out of friends and they've run out of time,&quot; said James Tierney, a former Maine attorney general who is helping coordinate the group's strategy.</p>
<p>He said the attorneys general, who met on Monday, agreed there would be no blanket immunity but would listen to other proposals from cigarette makers.</p>
<p>Tierney said it was up to the tobacco industry, not the attorneys general, to come up with a settlement proposal.</p>
<p>&quot;The pressure is on the industry,&quot; he said. &quot;The strength of the process is being driven by what's going on in the courtroom and in public opinion, both of which are turning away from the tobacco industry.&quot;</p>
<p>Representatives from major tobacco companies began talks with the attorneys general earlier this month and they are expected to resume negotiations as soon as Monday.</p>
<p>A total of 24 attorneys general have sued the industry to recoup Medicaid costs for treating smokers. Several other states are expected to join the battle soon.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, five Democratic senators asked Attorney General Janet Reno Tuesday to join the battle by seeking to recoup the federal government's cost of treating smoking-related illnesses.</p>
<p>In a letter to Reno, the senators estimated the government spent about $20 billion a year through Medicare, Medicaid and other federal programmes on health care for tobacco-related illness.</p>
<p>Texas Attorney General Dan Morales said he was willing to listen to settlement proposals granting tobacco firms limited immunity for past alleged misdeeds, but not the future.</p>
<p>Massachusetts Attorney General Scott Harshbarger said he was willing to discuss &quot;creative ways of approaching civil liabilities for past conduct and future conduct&quot; with the tobacco companies.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll see if they want predictablity or immunity. (And if it is immunity) we're not going to talk long on that issue,&quot; Harshbarger said.</p>
<p>The pressure on cigarette makers to find a solution to mounting legal problems grew on Friday when a federal judge in Greensboro, N.C., the home court chosen by the industry, ruled that the Food and Drug Administration has the authority to regulate tobacco as a drug.</p>
<p>Although the judge said the agency lacked jurisdiction to control advertising aimed at youths, on Monday the Supreme Court refused to hear a challenge to a Baltimore law that bans cigarette and liquor ads on many billboards.</p>
<p>By refusing to take the case, the nation's highest court left in place a ruling that supports the governments's authority to limit advertising that can affect children.</p>
<p>The rulings are just the latest examples of the turn in the tide against the industry, which had for years been able to claim that it never paid a cent in damages.</p>
<p>Last summer, a Jacksonville, Fla. jury awarded $750,000 against Brown &amp; Williamson Tobacco Corp., a unit of B.A.T Industries Plc. Now, the same plaintiff's lawyer is trying a case against R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co., a unit of RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp., and he has filed about 300 other individual suits.</p>
<p>In addition, Liggett Group, the smallest of the tobacco companies and a unit of Brooke Group Ltd., has agreed to a broad settlement with the attorneys general that included turning over internal documents that could prove damaging to the rest of the industry in the Medicaid and other suits.</p>
<p>Louisiana Attorney General Richard Ieyoub said he believes Congress will draft legislation acceptable to states that will regulate the tobacco industry once the companies settle suits filed by individual states.</p>
<p>To be acceptable, Ieyoub said federal legislation must end marketing tobacco products to children, require cigarette makers to fully disclose the health effects of smoking, and establish federal regulatory oversight of the industry.</p>
<p>&quot;These guys are slippery. We've got to make sure we nail them down in a legislative act,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
