<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="547095" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BHP Copper in situ project nears permiting.</title>
<headline>BHP Copper in situ project nears permiting.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>BHP Copper is close to obtaining permits for what it calls the world's first greenfield commercial in situ leaching copper project, due on stream next year in Arizona if final go-ahead is given, project manager John Kline said.</p>
<p>&quot;The project is moving along rather well. At this point, the results are encouraging,&quot; Kline said.</p>
<p>BHP is looking to produce 60 to 80 million pounds of copper a year from the project, a miniscule amount when compared to total world production.</p>
<p>In situ leaching is used extensively in Kazakhstan, the U.S. and elsewhere to produce uranium more cheaply than conventional mining.</p>
<p>But Kline envisioned clusters of such projects on similar orebodies rather than one big facility.</p>
<p>&quot;We are just waiting for the signing of the permits, probably in the next couple of months,&quot; Kline said.</p>
<p>Permit conditions will then have to be met and the project operated on a limited basis, along with completion of costing.</p>
<p>&quot;Then there will be a decision on whether to proceed or not,&quot; Kline said. All this will take six to nine months.</p>
<p>The copper resource at Florence, Arizona, estimated by BHP at a billion pounds of recoverable metal, is under flat cotton and alfalfa farmland.</p>
<p>With in situ leaching, holes are drilled into the copper oxide deposit, and weak sulphuric acid pumped down the holes. Copper containing solution rises to the surface, is tapped and turned into cathode at a solvent extraction, electrowinning plant (SX/EW).</p>
<p>BHP produces copper from in situ leaching at San Manuel and Miami East, but this forms part of traditional mines.</p>
<p>ASARCO is also continuing with its Santa Cruz in situ project, 40 miles west from BHP.</p>
<p>An ASARCO spokesman said Santa Cruz was still only a test project though an SX/EW plant has been completed at the site and copper recovered from the leaching process.</p>
<p>Inmet Mining Corp's in situ project at Copper Range in White Pine, Michigan was suspended last October due to regulatory uncertainty. The Environmental Protection Agency is considering a permit for the project.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Inmet) are meeting much more difficulties up there, but I believe we have pretty good support here,&quot; Kline said.</p>
<p>Jochen Tilk, Copper Range mine manager, said it appeared likely that the EPA would grant a permit but much would depend on what conditions were tied to it, and only then will Inmet decide whether to go ahead.</p>
<p>Tilk said the EPA indicated a draft document would be issued in July for comment, with a final outcome by November.</p>
<p>&quot;But this schedule looks a bit aggressive,&quot; Tilk said.</p>
<p>((Huw Jones, New York Commodity Desk 212-859-1646))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
