<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="547192" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Global financial regulation has its limits - Greenspan.</title>
<headline>Global financial regulation has its limits - Greenspan.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Rich Miller, U.S. Economics Correspondent</p>
<p>Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan admitted on Tuesday that regulators might lack the expertise to oversee large global financial firms, but he saw no need for a radical change in supervision.</p>
<p>In a speech to the Institute of International Finance, the U.S. central bank chief said regulators should not try to prevent all bank failures, just stop them from becoming widespread.</p>
<p>&quot;For the most part, these failures are a normal and important part of the market process and provide discipline,&quot; Greenspan said.</p>
<p>The Fed chief said central banks should only act to bail out troubled commercial banks in the rarest of circumstances when an economic catastrophe is threatened.</p>
<p>&quot;Such a subsidy should be reserved only for the rarest of disasters,&quot; Greenspan said. Otherwise, it would encourage recklessness among financial institutions that gambled on being bailed out by their central bank.</p>
<p>Greenspan questioned whether supervisors have the expertise and the resources to provide &quot;meaningful&quot; oversight of the risks taken by large, diversified, global financial institutions.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the Fed chief opposed any radical change in the current framework of international supervision, arguing that continued, steady improvement in oversight was the best strategy to try to ensure financial stability.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not believe that the need for a radical change in our framework for the supervision of internationally active financial firms has been demonstrated,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Greenspan said the globalization of finance brought on by technological advance has been both a blessing and a curse for the international financial system.</p>
<p>The growth of computer technology that has speeded up global financial transactions has &quot;increased the potential for more rapid and widespread disruption,&quot; the Fed chief said.</p>
<p>But technology has also helped supervisors and financial institutions to better assess and manage risk, he noted.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
