<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54728" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Huge pro-Italy march puts Bossi in shade.</title>
<headline>Huge pro-Italy march puts Bossi in shade.</headline>
<byline>Michela Mastrodonato</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least 150,000 Italians marched for unity on Sunday at a far-right rally held to answer northern separatist Umberto Bossi and his push for &quot;independence&quot;.</p>
<p>The size of the peaceful demonstration in Milan dwarfed a series of sparsely-attended rallies held since Friday along the River Po, the route of a symbol-laden &quot;March to the Sea&quot; which Bossi had hoped would draw more than one million followers.</p>
<p>As Bossi headed for the canal city of Venice to proclaim his would-be &quot;republic of Padania&quot; later on Sunday, a mass of marchers sporting the red, white and green of the Italian flag thronged the streets of Milan, the north's largest city.</p>
<p>&quot;Italy is here. It won't be insulted and it won't be divided,&quot; Gianfranco Fini, leader of the hard right National Alliance party, told a sea of people packed into a central square.</p>
<p>&quot;Secession and division are an insult to history and an insult to reason,&quot; Fini said.</p>
<p>As the crowd waved Italian flags and sang the national anthem, he said Bossi's trek across Italy from the source of the Po to the Adriatic had become a &quot;farce&quot; and urged court action following a call by Bossi for formation of a separatist militia.</p>
<p>Police estimated that more than 150,000 people from all over Italy had joined the demonstration in Milan, the country's financial capital and headquarters of Bossi's Northern League.</p>
<p>Organisers put the turnout at 250,000.</p>
<p>Smaller pro-unity rallies also took place on the Po itself, including at San Benedetto Po, where Greens party supporters flew a string of balloons across the river, and at Piacenza, where one banner read: &quot;Free the North, but from the League&quot;.</p>
<p>Bossi, who was planning to lead a flotilla of small boats to Venice on the last leg of his quasi-religious pilgrimage, brushed off the scant show of support for his secessionist drive by accusing the media of lies.</p>
<p>&quot;They can't set the Carabinieri (paramilitary police) on us so they're relying on the press to spread disinformation,&quot; Bossi told a small rally near the Po town of Pavia on Sunday.</p>
<p>Bossi has promised a peaceful push for independence for his ill-defined &quot;state&quot;, which would encompass the richest regions of Italy, but he said on Saturday that one of &quot;Padania's&quot; first acts would be to recruit volunteer militiamen.</p>
<p>&quot;If force is needed, and it is possible that it will be needed, from Monday the provisional government will take care of that with voluntary recruitment of a national guard,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The implicit threat of violence brought a warning from President Oscar Luigi Scalfaro on Sunday that while Italy would guarantee free speech it would not tolerate illegality.</p>
<p>Bossi's League has built its appeal on deep discontent in the north with high taxes and stifling centralised bureaucracy coupled with disillusionment with mainstream political parties.</p>
<p>It won an unexpected 10.6 percent of votes at last April's general election but failed to wrest the balance of power in parliament, a defeat Bossi's critics say explains his switch to a secessionist from a federalist agenda.</p>
<p>Bossi's challenge to Italian unity has solidified support for federal reform across the spectrum from the centre-left government to the opposition.</p>
<p>&quot;Unity and autonomy must travel together in our country,&quot; Prime Minister Romano Prodi said on Sunday. &quot;I'm not interested in Bossi...Federalism is born from concrete facts&quot;.</p>
<p>He said Bossi's hopes of a &quot;triumphant march&quot; had fallen flat, a view echoed by ordinary Italians.</p>
<p>&quot;We had more people here for our annual boat race,&quot; said Ivo Caramaschi, the boat club chairman in the Po town of Borgoforte, where only about 1,000 people had gathered for one of a string of pro-secession rallies planned by the League for Sunday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
