<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="547210" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Muted employer costs, fewer orders spur market rally.</title>
<headline>Muted employer costs, fewer orders spur market rally.</headline>
<byline>Glenn Somerville</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Modestly higher first-quarter employment costs and a drop in March orders for manufactured goods, reported by the government on Tuesday, triggered a market rally on hopes inflation risks were waning.</p>
<p>Analysts said the reports suggested the economy, while still expanding, might not be as close to overheating as feared. That might encourage Federal Reserve policymakers to hold off on more interest-rate rises in May.</p>
<p>The Labour Department said its Employment Cost Index showed that nearly flat costs for company-supplied benefits like health care between January and March offset higher wage and salary costs to restrain the index's increase to 0.6 percent.</p>
<p>That was an improvement from a 0.8 percent rise during last year's fourth quarter.</p>
<p>The index measures combined wage and benefit rises that eventually get passed on in costs and so are a measure of potential price changes.</p>
<p>Separately, the Commerce Department said March orders for durable goods dropped across the board by 3 percent to a seasonally adjusted $171.5 billion. It was the biggest monthly decline since a 3.6 percent fall last August.</p>
<p>The reports ignited rallies in financial markets, muting concerns that the Fed might already be on a course of successive short-term interest-rate rises to curb demand.</p>
<p>The central bank's policysetting Federal Open Market Committee boosted rates by a quarter percentage point on March 25 and meets again on May 20.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average was up 104 points in mid-afternoon at 6,887, and the benchmark 30-year Treasury bond shot up more than 1-1/4 points. The bond's yield, which moves in the opposite direction and has an impact on long-term borrowing charges, moved down to 7 percent from 7.11 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The froth seems to have been kicked out of the manufacturing sector, at least while the employment cost index is extremely well-behaved,&quot; said Robert Dederick, economic consultant to Northern Trust Co. in Chicago.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an economy that is just continuing to be the best that it can be,&quot; he said, performing remarkably smoothly in its seventh year of uninterrupted expansion from the last recession in 1990-91.</p>
<p>U.S. companies have been able to slow their benefit costs in recent years by shifting more costs onto their employees and using cheaper managed care plans. But some Fed officials and private economists caution that employers have saved about as much as they can this way, so costs may rebound.</p>
<p>Nonethless, economist Anthony Chan of Banc One Investment Advisors in Columbus, Ohio, said the bright first-quarter performance does not make a case for immediate rate rises.</p>
<p>&quot;This report, I think, argues for complancency rather than for immediate urgency on the part of policymakers,&quot; Chan said.</p>
<p>The report on durable goods -- costly items like cars and appliances intended to last three years or more -- showed slacker demand for every major category.</p>
<p>Transportation orders fell 4.3 percent in March to a seasonally adjusted $37.5 billion after a 7.3 percent decline in February. The department said that orders fell for both new aircraft and parts and for new cars and parts.</p>
<p>The biggest percentage decline occurred in orders for electronic and electrical equipment, down 5.9 percent to $28.8 billion following a 7.7 percent increase in February.</p>
<p>The Commerce Department said orders were softer for communications equipment and for electronic components.</p>
<p>A third report on Tuesday, from the private Conference Board in New York, found a slight fallback in consumer confidence during April from March.</p>
<p>Lynn Franco, associate director of the Conference Board's consumer research centre, said the index decline to 116.8 from 118.5 in March was &quot;not worrisome.&quot; She noted expectations remained relatively buoyant, a positive indicator that was &quot;signaling further expansion in the months ahead.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
