<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="547254" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Reservist charged with stealing from Marine Corps.</title>
<headline>Reservist charged with stealing from Marine Corps.</headline>
<dateline>DEERFIELD BEACH, Fla. 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. Marine Corps reservist has been jailed in Florida after investigators found military weapons and anti-government literature in two of his storage units, police said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Donald Kornse, 31, was charged with theft of government property after investigators, acting on a tip from his estranged wife, found smoke grenades, 2,000 rounds of ammunition for M-16 rifles, three guns and military clothing including gas masks, helmets and flak jackets.</p>
<p>They said they also found anti-government literature and pamphlets that one investigator described to the Fort Lauderdale Sun-Sentinel newspaper as &quot;survivalist stuff.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Broward County Sheriff's Office said the items had been found last week and the case was turned over to government investigators after it was learned that Kornse was a reserve corporal at the Naval and Marine Corps Reserve Centre in West Palm Beach. &quot;We were initially involved in the investigation but we ultimately turned him over to the federal authorities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Federal court documents related to the case were made available Monday in U.S. District Court in Fort Lauderdale. Investigators said they were tipped off by Kornse's estranged wife that he had been stealing weapons from the Marine Corps while training as a reservist.</p>
<p>Kornse was being held without bail at the North Dade Correctional Facility.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DEERFIELD BEACH, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
