<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="547354" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French right unites, left papers over cracks.</title>
<headline>French right unites, left papers over cracks.</headline>
<byline>Paul Taylor</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's centre-right coalition on Tuesday staged a show of unity, issuing an artfully vague manifesto while left-wing opposition leaders glossed over stark differences on Europe to sign a joint election pact.</p>
<p>In a platform entitled &quot;A new impulse for France&quot;, the ruling coalition pledged to stabilise public spending, pursue tax cuts and promote talks on shorter working hours if, as polls predict, it wins the May 25-June 1 parliamentary election.</p>
<p>The latest opinion poll released on Tuesday suggested the government held only a slim lead over the left in voting intentions and would win a reduced majority of National Assembly seats, confirming a series of surveys over the last week.</p>
<p>Socialist leader Lionel Jospin and Communist leader Robert Hue met and issued a joint declaration pledging a shift to a 35-hour working week without loss of pay, the creation of 700,000 youth jobs and a halt to privatisation.</p>
<p>But they stopped short of a common programme for government and did not even try to reconcile their differences over a single European currency, which the Socialists conditionally accept and the Communists oppose.</p>
<p>Presenting the centre-right manifesto, Prime Minister Alain Juppe vowed to modernise the state, free up private initiative, renovate the social welfare system and &quot;make France the motor of a citizens' Europe&quot;.</p>
<p>But hours later, outgoing Gaullist Assembly speaker Philippe Seguin cracked the facade of harmony with a speech denouncing what he called the ultra-liberal logic of the rush to European monetary union.</p>
<p>Distancing himself from fellow Gaullist Juppe's programme, Seguin said the fight against unemployment should be at the heart of the campaign and at the centre of government policy.</p>
<p>He lamented that in response to rising unemployment, &quot;people everywhere are mouthing words that seem meaningless: convergence criteria, flexibility, globalisation, federalism&quot;. Such slogans were &quot;alibis for inaction disguised as promises of a radiant future&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>Juppe said a re-elected government would present to parliament in its first 40 days a five-year plan for holding the increase in public spending to less than the rate of inflation.</p>
<p>Apart from populist pledges to cut the number of ministries to 15 and limit the number of elected offices politicians may hold, the manifesto was strikingly short of detailed proposals.</p>
<p>It avoided specific commitments on taxes, saying only that the coalition would &quot;accentuate the reduction of social welfare charges on lower salaries in exchange for the creation of jobs...continue the reduction of income tax and launch a reform of the professional (business) tax&quot;.</p>
<p>Defending the lack of specifics, Juppe told a news conference: &quot;We are not running a campaign for accountants.&quot;</p>
<p>He said France faced a strategic choice between more economic freedom and lower taxes on the one hand, and higher public spending and regulation on the other.</p>
<p>The joint Socialist-Communist declaration said: &quot;The fight against unemployment and for jobs is an absolute priority.&quot;</p>
<p>It called for wage increases and said: &quot;Together, we reject the idea that people be asked to make new sacrifices.&quot;</p>
<p>The declaration sidestepped the issue of whether Communist ministers would enter a Socialist-led cabinet if the left won. Jospin said he was not opposed in principle but junior partners in government would have to bow to the senior party on policy.</p>
<p>A CSA institute poll suggested the coalition's lead over the left had narrowed in the last week to about 40 seats in the 577-seat Assembly.</p>
<p>It forecast the centre-right would win 296, the Socialists and ecologists 237, the Communists 21 and the extreme-right National Front one of the 555 seats in metropolitan France. Coalition supporters hold most of the 22 seats in overseas departments and territories.</p>
<p>Another poll on Tuesday found widespread indifference among voters, more than one third of whom said that neither the centre-right nor the left would address their concerns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
