<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="547313" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Seattle-Tacoma becomes economic leader - report.</title>
<headline>Seattle-Tacoma becomes economic leader - report.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Surging commercial aircraft orders and increased production and hiring in aerospace transformed Seattle-Tacoma into one of the strongest metro economies in the United States, according to a report released Tuesday.</p>
<p>Employment in the Seattle-Tacoma area was up 5.0 percent from a year ago, Bank of America regional economist Howard Roth said in the report.</p>
<p>The improved job market has boosted personal income as well as home and retail sales, he said.  </p>
<p>Total manufacturing jobs in Seattle-Tacoma grew nearly 11 percent from February 1996 to February 1997 after falling more than 2.0 percent in the previous year period, the report said.</p>
<p>Employers in both manufacturing and the services sector are now finding it difficult to find qualified employees, the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;With increases in commercial aircraft production and computer services expanding further this year, labor markets in Seattle-Tacoma will remain tight for some time,&quot; Roth said.</p>
<p>The report, titled &quot;Economic &amp; Business Outlook -- 1997 Regional Outlook,&quot; was produced by the Economics and Policy Research Department at Bank of America, a unit of BankAmerica Corp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
