<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54759" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's unity under attack from Bossi.</title>
<headline>Italy's unity under attack from Bossi.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy, which faces a drive for northern independence from secessionist leader Umberto Bossi, was established as single country only in 1861 and it took a further decade for unification to be completed.</p>
<p>Following is a brief overview of its historical foundations.</p>
<p>* Mid-6th century AD - Final disintegration of Roman empire.</p>
<p>* 9th century - Break up of Carolingian Empire sparks foundation of many rival states</p>
<p>* End 15th century - Florence, Milan and Venice organise themselves as powerful independent states. South and central Italy divided into Kingdom of Naples and the Roman Catholic Church's Papal States</p>
<p>* Mid-16th century - Spain controls Sicily, Naples, Sardinia and Milan until start of 18th century</p>
<p>* Early 17th century - Lombardy, Mantua, Naples, Sardinia come under Austrian control</p>
<p>* 1796 - France invades Italy under Napoleon. Finally gains control of peninsula by 1810</p>
<p>* 1815 - Peace settlement after fall of Napoleon at Waterloo gives Austria control of much of the peninsula</p>
<p>* 1830s-40s - Growth of national feeling against Austria in movement to reform and unite Italy known as the &quot;risorgimento&quot;</p>
<p>* Late 1850s - Count Camillo Cavour, prime minister of Piedmont, formally raises question of Italian unity</p>
<p>* 1859 - Austria declares war on powerful Piedmont region and France</p>
<p>* 1860 - Bologna, Parma, Modena, Tuscany unite with Piedmont. Irregular soldier Giuseppe Garibaldi, joined by 1,000 red-shirted volunteers, sails from Genoa to Sicily and Naples with mission to unify Italy</p>
<p>* 1861 - Kingdom of Italy proclaimed with Turin as capital</p>
<p>* 1870 - Piedmont takes Rome to complete unity of Italy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
