<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="547715" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU to launch debate on food laws.</title>
<headline>EU to launch debate on food laws.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission is set to launch a debate on Wednesday on how to ensure that European Union food laws both protect consumers and promote cross-border trade.</p>
<p>The European Union executive is expected to adopt a &quot;green paper&quot;, or discussion document, on food policy that places a heavy emphasis on public health, reflecting its sensitivity to criticism that the EU mishandled the mad cow disease crisis.</p>
<p>While the paper was promised several years ago as an initiative to streamline EU food regulations, it now says that &quot;simplification cannot be allowed to result in a reduction in the level of protection of public health or consumer protection,&quot; according to a summary obtained by Reuters.</p>
<p>When foods pose a health danger, the EU should take protective measures based on scientific evidence, inspections and testing, it says, adding, &quot;the importance of an independent source of advice which will command public respect is crucial&quot;.</p>
<p>The Commission asks for comments on possible changes to EU procedures for controlling &quot;zoonoses&quot; -- diseases that can be passed from animals to humans.</p>
<p>That could involve making all those involved in food production liable for ensuring that all food placed on the market is safe, it said.</p>
<p>On labelling -- one of the biggest controversies surrounding the introduction of genetically modified foods in the EU -- the paper calls for an approach that ensures that consumers receive all useful information but not unnecessary details.</p>
<p>It notes that EU laws do not require production methods to be labelled unless they change the characteristics of the finished product -- which does not always apply to genetically modified foods.</p>
<p>But it says consumer interest in the question could warrant setting up an EU framework for voluntary labelling schemes.</p>
<p>Despite concern over consumer safety, the Commission argues that a simplified approach to food laws can be justified in some cases.</p>
<p>It says simplified procedures would make it easier to adapt EU rules to new scientific findings and notes that it has already started work on streamlining EU food hygiene regulations.</p>
<p>The paper was delayed until now partly because of an internal argument in the Commission over whether it should cover agricultural products or only processed foods.</p>
<p>The text now insists that the regulatory approach should cover the whole food chain &quot;from the stable to the table&quot;, but asks whether the two categories of goods should be covered by the same set of rules.</p>
<p>-- Suzanne Perry, Brussels Newsroom 32 2 287 6800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
