<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54787" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada consortium plans first native-owned bank.</title>
<headline>Canada consortium plans first native-owned bank.</headline>
<byline>Darren Schuettler</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Canadian bank and a regional Indian group said on Monday they planned to form the country's first native-owned bank to help Canada's aboriginal people become more financially self-sufficient.</p>
<p>The First Nations Bank of Canada is expected to begin operating in Saskatchewan in late 1996 -- pending approval from federal regulators.</p>
<p>The group plans to expand across Canada with a fully array of banking services offered to aboriginal and non-aboriginal customers.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to grow in the area of finance and this is a step toward our own self-determination as First Nations peoples,&quot; Roy Bird, chairman of the Saskatchewan Indian Equity Foundation Inc. (SIEF), said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>The consortium includes the SIEF, the Federation of Saskatchewan Indians Inc. and the Toronto-Dominion Bank, Canada's fifth largest bank.</p>
<p>Toronto-Dominion is investing C$8 million ($5.8 million) in start-up capital with the SIEF providing an additional C$2 million ($1.5 million).</p>
<p>SIEF said its 75 percent share of the operating profit will be reinvested in the bank. The group also plans a share issue.</p>
<p>Bird said common shares in the new bank will be sold to aboriginal investors only. Preferred shares will be offered to both aboriginal and non-aboriginal investors.</p>
<p>He said the bank will be entirely aboriginally owned and controlled within 10 years.</p>
<p>&quot;We will probably follow the same format as other banks, but the advantage we have is that we have a better understanding of aboriginal communities and of the difficulty that some of our people have in obtaining credit,&quot; Bird said.</p>
<p>The idea for the First Nations Bank was born in the early 1980s when the SIEF was formed as Canada's first aboriginal capital corporation.</p>
<p>In the past 15 years, SIEF has loaned more than C$30 million ($22 million) to Saskatchewan-based First Nations businesses with a loan loss rate of just over 1 percent.</p>
<p>But SIEF has been restricted to term lending under Canada's Bank Act, which regulates the country's financial services industry.</p>
<p>By tying up with Toronto-Dominion, the new bank can offer an array of banking services, including credit cards, checking, savings and other deposit accounts and a range of lending options.</p>
<p>&quot;We're bringing that to the table and the (SIEF) are bringing the customers,&quot; John Leckie, Toronto-Dominion's senior vice-president of business banking services, said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
