<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548056" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bond markets breathe sigh of relief after US data.</title>
<headline>Bond markets breathe sigh of relief after US data.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Scott</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Benign employment cost data in the U.S. on Tuesday triggered a wave of relief in global bond markets as the bear tone that has suffocated trade recently began to lift.</p>
<p>&quot;This is helping Treasury bulls and European bulls on the back of that,&quot; said Huw Roberts, European bond strategist at NatWest Capital Markets here. &quot;But we've still got to get over the GDP and payrolls data later in the week.&quot;</p>
<p>Michael Burke, bond strategist at Citibank in London, was similarly cautious about the market.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's very positive and will no doubt affect interest rate expectations with regard to the May 20 FOMC meeting,&quot; said Burke. &quot;But I think it's important to bear in mind that we have a very full data menu ahead of us and expectations could easily turn around 180 degrees.&quot;</p>
<p>Treasuries surged on the data, which showed employment costs in the first quarter rose 0.6 percent against forecasts for a 0.9 percent gain. Durable goods orders in March separately showed a 3.0 percent fall, the biggest drop since August 1996.</p>
<p>June T-bonds rose more than 1-1/2 points to its highest price in almost five weeks at 108-29 in whippy trade.  </p>
<p>By 1304 GMT, the June contract was at 108-25, up 1-12/32 on the day. June Bunds on LIFFE were at 100.95, up 0.54, LIFFE gilts were at 109-24, up 22/32, and the notionnel contract on the Matif was at 128.90, up 0.58.</p>
<p>Mark Capleton, international bond strategist at Barclays de Zoete Wedd in London, said there would be nervousness about potentially strong numbers coming out of the U.S. later in the week but from a risk/reward viewpoint bonds did not look bad.</p>
<p>&quot;The balance of risks is to be worried about inflation but I think sufficient risk premium is priced into Treasuries to compensate you for that,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>He said he was optimistic while long bond yields were still above seven percent. The benchmark 30-year yield fell sharply to just above seven percent after the data from around 7.10.</p>
<p>Capleton said the market would remain preoccupied with the big interest rate question but that signs from the U.S. labour market were encouraging. &quot;Everybody's asking the question, How much tightening is necessary to moderate growth?&quot;</p>
<p>But he said the U.S. corporate sector had proved itself able to manage unit labour costs better than other Group of Three members, and it was still an open question as to how much wage increases translated into inflation.  </p>
<p>Citibank's Burke said payrolls should show a rise but were not likely throw the market off. First quarter GDP data could be the wild card of the week's barrage of figures, however.</p>
<p>&quot;Not only will it be strong but the advance indicators will be very strong and final demand is running ahead of both production and any build up in inventories which will be strong pointers for the second quarter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Real GDP is due at 1230 GMT on Wednesday and is expected to show an annualised rise of  4.1 percent in the first quarter.</p>
<p>Burke added he still expected the Fed to raise interest rates at the next meeting.  </p>
<p>&quot;It would take very subdued data both in the GDP and payrolls to alter that view,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>NatWest's Roberts agreed it was a little too early for confirmed Treasury bulls to celebrate.</p>
<p>&quot;We could see Treasuries performing very well and they did outperform in Europe, but this comes with a certain health warning because we've got so many more obstacles to get over yet,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- International bonds unit +44 171 542 8682</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
