<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548073" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Copper LME spread narrowed after match-off, trader.</title>
<headline>Copper LME spread narrowed after match-off, trader.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Monday's dramatic collapse in copper's backwardation on the London Metal Exchange (LME) - with the spread more than halving - may have been because of an off-market match-off, traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The speed and ferocity of the contraction in cash/May and cash/threes suggests that the tightness had been defused by the major long and short coming to an agreement, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically, the way the market went one can assume that - whether it happened is another matter, though,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Prior to Monday's second official ring, copper's cash to three months backwardation was as high as $210 as a series of highly sensitive prompt dates approached.</p>
<p>The nearby squeeze had been relentless, with major investment houses said to be on the long side of the market.</p>
<p>But if there was a match-off, or &quot;ring-out&quot;, between a long and a short the heat would have been taken out of the market almost immediately.</p>
<p>Cash/threes contracted viciously, and by Tuesday midday was either side of $70, while cash/May eased from $100 Monday to $5 today.</p>
<p>Traders said it was impossible to be sure what had taken place and why, partly because of the expansion in LME trading that has taken place over the last decade.</p>
<p>Major off-market players now account for vast amounts of business, which would not necessarily end up being transacted on the LME floor, other than what is not netted off.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no way of knowing for sure (that it was a &quot;ring-out&quot;). It just looks that way,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>Others were unsure, meanwhile, saying the tightness could flare up again, as the May/three months spread remains fairly high.</p>
<p>Some said that the short market position is perpetually being rolled forward. It dates back to end-October 1996, and may now be residing at the end of July, they said.</p>
<p>Also, short-term fundamantals suggest that short selling copper will be a risky venture.</p>
<p>Chile's Escondida and Quebrada Blanca mines are suffering from strikes. There are disputes in North America, while the giant Kennecott smelter in Utah is closed for repairs.</p>
<p>Against this backdrop LME stocks are falling, and there is the ever-present possibility of major Chinese purchases if the price is right.</p>
<p>--Martin Hayes, London Newsroom 44 171 542 8080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
