<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548047" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK soccer stands at commercial crossroads - experts.</title>
<headline>UK soccer stands at commercial crossroads - experts.</headline>
<byline>Keith Weir</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>English soccer, a commercial success story in recent years, faces hard choices as it seeks to maximise earnings without destroying the sport's structure, delegates told an industry conference on Tuesday.</p>
<p>English premier league clubs could soon earn an average of 30 million pounds ($48.7 million) per year from the sale of television rights on a pay-per-view basis, Robin Welch of European broadcast group Canal Plus told the Soccerex 97 conference.</p>
<p>That figure would dwarf the eight million pounds per year which an average premier league club is expected to earn from next season under a new television deal with BSkyB.</p>
<p>But Welch, a non-executive director of Leeds United, provoked groans from the audience when he floated the idea of abolishing promotion and relegation and a U.S. style sale of franchises to areas of England without a premier league club.</p>
<p>These ideas, which he said were purely personal ones, reflect some of the thinking among the financiers of the city of London.</p>
<p>City institutions have become increasingly enthusiastic about investing in floated soccer clubs as the game has shed its old-fashioned image and gone through a boom in recent years but want to protect their money.</p>
<p>&quot;You need assurances. You can't put 30 million pounds into something that will disappear,&quot; Welch said.</p>
<p>Sunderland and Southampton, two of Britain's 16 floated soccer clubs, have seen their share prices fall in value in recent weeks over fear of relegation from the elite 20- club premier league.</p>
<p>Football Association commercial director Phil Carling said promotion and relegation were essential.</p>
<p>&quot;They are part of the fabric of the game. It is competitive, that is the whole point about it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The introduction of pay-per-view is seen as the next great money spinner for English soccer, although no date has been set for its launch. It is already up and running in Italy and France. England is expected to follow suit within a few years.</p>
<p>But the clubs were warned that pay-per-view could reduce crowds at matches, particularly the number of away supporters, and destroy the atmosphere for those at the stadium and those watching at home.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course it needs away fans. It needs a vibrant atmosphere to make it a TV event,&quot; said Alex Fynn, a former marketing executive and respected writer on the game.</p>
<p>Arsenal vice-chairman David Dein, whose club has not yet joined the stock market, was also cautious on pay-per-view.</p>
<p>&quot;I strongly advocate waiting to see what happens with the models on the continent. I would urge everybody connected to be very careful before jumping in,&quot; he said. ($ = 0.615 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741112">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
