<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548048" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LME copper jumpy, seeks way forward.</title>
<headline>LME copper jumpy, seeks way forward.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Copper spreads failed to staunch their seepage on Tuesday morning in unsettled activity, but tightness could reappear, traders said.</p>
<p>The three months market regained some poise, however, finishing the morning kerb $4 firmer at $2,370, but other metals were mixed within recent ranges.</p>
<p>After Monday's dramatic collapse in the backwardation in nearby dates, the market began mulling over when another bout of constriction might hit.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it's all over...We may have overdone it on the upside, but now we may be overdoing the other way,&quot; one floor trader said.</p>
<p>The cash/May spread, where the bulk of tight dates had been concentrated, looked like it might go into contango after trading up to a $100 backwardation the previous day. It was bid level at one point, but lurched back to be bid at an $11 backwardation by the end of the morning kerb in thin, volatile trading.</p>
<p>The cash/threes narrowed to a $65 backwardation at one point, but edged out again to be last indicated at $75/$80, compared to $80/$90 Monday evening and $210 at the height of the squeeze.</p>
<p>Traders were divided on whether an off-market deal had been struck between a big long and a major short. Some said the vicious contraction in spreads on Monday pointed to such a deal but others were not convinced.</p>
<p>&quot;There may have simply been fewer shorts and less tonnage needed this time,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever happened, now the thing to do is to figure out how far forward the shorts rolled over,&quot; another said.</p>
<p>Many traders believed strong fundamentals will keep the market on the boil, even if it needs a consolidation period after its frenzied rise. &quot;We may have $30 to $50 on the downside, but I think we could have one or two hundred on the upside,&quot; one said, referring to the three months market.</p>
<p>Workers are still on strike at Escondida in Chile, another set of Chilean miners are due to walk off their jobs on Wednesday, the Kennecott smelter is down for maintenance and a dispute still simmers at the Phelps Dodge Chino operations.</p>
<p>Aluminium kept a tight grasp at its higher levels, gravitating towards its next resistance level at $1,642.</p>
<p>Prices finished $7.50 firmer at $1,636.</p>
<p>A consolidation period was now due before prices could attack higher targets, including $1,650, analysts said.</p>
<p>The cash/threes was holding steady at a $25/$26 contango while the threes/average 1998 narrowed to a $2 backwardation, versus about $10 on Monday.</p>
<p>Nickel and tin lost more ground while lead and zinc held to tight ranges.</p>
<p>Nickel settled $60 easier at $7,400, testing the 10-day moving average just below there.</p>
<p>Tin broke below $5,700 to end the morning with a loss of $40 at $5,675 and nearing the $5,660 support level.</p>
<p>Lead lost $2 to $628 while zinc gained $3 to $1,270.</p>
<p>Alloy was little changed at $1,507/12.</p>
<p>--Eric Onstad, London Newsroom ++44 171 542 8065</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
