<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548175" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: Anbari calls on UN to double Iraq oil sale to $4 bln.</title>
<headline>Anbari calls on UN to double Iraq oil sale to $4 bln.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraqi envoy Abdul Amir al-Anbari on Tuesday called on the United Nations to double the financial ceiling for Iraq's humanitarian oil sales.</p>
<p>Anbari, chief Iraqi negotiator of the oil-for-food agreement which saw Iraqi exports resume in December, said the U.N. should allow Iraq sales worth $4 billion when the deal comes up for renewal in early June.</p>
<p>&quot;The financial ceiling must be lifted to at least twice (double), that is, four billion for six months to be calculated as the net proceeds of oil sales, that is the contract price minus the operation and inland transportation costs,&quot; al-Anbari told an industry conference.</p>
<p>Anbari is now Iraq's ambassador to the U.N. Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organisation (UNESCO).</p>
<p>Under the oil sale accord Iraq is permitted to sell $2 billion worth of crude over a six-month period to June 7 to buy food and medicine to alleviate hardship from sanctions imposed on Baghdad after it invaded Kuwait in August 1990.</p>
<p>U.N. Secretary General Kofi Annan has said he expects the Security Council to renew the sale before the June expiry.</p>
<p>U.N. diplomats have said they expect the accord to rollover for another six months at the current $2 billion oil sales limits.</p>
<p>Portions of the oil receipts are earmarked for U.N. expenses and retribution costs related to the Gulf war.</p>
<p>A further $142 million is allowed to pay Turkish pipeline fees.</p>
<p>Anbari said approval of food contracts for distribution in Iraq continued to badly lag the oil sale.</p>
<p>&quot;Probably 20 out of more than 300 contracts for the purchase of food, medicine and civilian supplies covered by the distribution plan have been approved,&quot; al-Anbari said.</p>
<p>Should renewal of the arrangement take place it was imperative that a week or two be allocated to settling the pending civilian orders, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
