<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548101" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Guardian Royal says Q1 results satisfactory.</title>
<headline>Guardian Royal says Q1 results satisfactory.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Guardian Royal Exchange Plc on Tuesday told the annual general meeting that the group's first quarter results were &quot;satisfactory&quot;.  </p>
<p>&quot;As you are aware we do not declare our results on a quarterly basis, but we feel that you will be interested to know that the first quarter results of this year are satisfactory,&quot; the group said in a statement.</p>
<p>In February, the insurance group blamed competition and bad weather when reporting a 17 percent fall in trading profits for 1996 to 281 million stg.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a clear strategy for the future together with the infrastructure and management capabilities to grow the business organically and by acquisition,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>The group is keen to expand its involvement in the life and health markets both in the UK and overseas. But while a strong balance sheet allows it to do so, the group emphasised that it would not be tempted to may too much for any business.</p>
<p>Guardian Royal said it remains unhappy about the lack of industry consensus over some accountancy practices, particularly over the treatment of realised and unrealised gains, and the valuation of shareholders' interest in life funds -- which amounted to 302 million stg at the year end.</p>
<p>&quot;We are, however, optimistic that a resolution to these issues will be forthcoming before too long,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>The group also said that after legal and accountancy advice, it did not include equalisation reserves in the balance sheet as liabilities.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 4365</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
