<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548686" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Seven to buy US$39 million more MGM stock.</title>
<headline>Seven to buy US$39 million more MGM stock.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian-based television and film group the Seven Network Ltd said on Tuesday it would subscribe for US$39 million in common Metro Goldwyn Mayer (MGM) stock to pay for MGM's $573 million purchase of the Metromedia group's studio and film library.</p>
<p>Seven said its joint venture partner in MGM, Kirk Kerkorian's Tracinda Corp, would subscribe for $US321 million in MGM stock to pay for the deal.</p>
<p>The deal involved MGM paying $360 million in cash, assuming $200 in debt and assuming $13 million in current liabilities for Metromedia, Seven said.  </p>
<p>Seven said that despite the unequal immediate contribution from the MGM partners towards the Metromedia purchase, all aspects of their MGM joint venture remained in place.</p>
<p>&quot;All aspects of Seven's joint venture agreement with Tracinda Corporation in relation to the acquisition of MGM last July will remain in place,&quot; Seven said.</p>
<p>&quot;Seven retains 50 percent of the voting rights of MGM and will continue to have three seats on the seven director board of MGM,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Seven also said it intended to take up its option to acquire $100 million in preferred stock from Tracinda Corp in July.  </p>
<p>Seven said the primary asset in the Metromedia deal was a 2,200 title film library, which included titles such as Dances with Wolves, Silence of the Lambs, Wuthering Heights and The Best Years of Our Lives.</p>
<p>&quot;The combined Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, United Artists, Orion Pictures and Samuel Goldwyn Company film library will rank as the largest post-1948 film library in the world,&quot; Seven said.</p>
<p>It said the acquisition would have a direct and immediate positive impact on MGM cash flow and through a restructuring of MGM's balance sheet would increase working capital and lower the cost of capital.  </p>
<p>It would also increase cost efficiencies through the removal of duplicated overhead infrastructure.</p>
<p>Seven Chairman Kerry Stokes said in a statement the purchase of the Metromedia assets would significantly strengthen MGM.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased with the progress of our investment. The past nine months has seen MGM, under its new ownership and strong management, put in place the plans for its future development in film and television production and distribution,&quot; Stokes said.  </p>
<p>He said the acquisition of Orion Pictures and The Samuel Goldwyn Company from Metromedia was on &quot;extremely favourable terms&quot; and would provide the platform for the MGM's future development.</p>
<p>&quot;Orion Pictures and The Samuel Goldwyn Company are cash-flow positive, have strong and profitable libraries and combined with the MGM-United Artists library will position MGM as the world's leading provider of programming content,&quot; Stokes said.</p>
<p>Stokes also outlined MGM's plans for the next two years.  </p>
<p>Production had started on MGM's next James Bond movie, Tomorrow Never Dies and a production schedule for releasing eight movies in 1997 was well-advanced.</p>
<p>The projects included an animatronic feature film called Warriors of Virtue, Lawrence Fishburne and Andy Garcia in Hoodlum, Andie McDowell and Gabriel Byrne in a Wim Wenders film called The End of Violence, and the wide distribution of Hurricane.</p>
<p>&quot;Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer's release schedule in 1998 encompasses thirteen titles, four of which are distribution-only,&quot; Seven said.  </p>
<p>&quot;In television, the company has two new series in production -- Fame LA and Stargate,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Seven and Tracinda agreed in July last year to buy MGM for US$1.3 billion.</p>
<p>Seven's shares were up 14 cents at A$4.75 at 3.35 p.m. (0535 GMT).</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
