<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548799" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: LME copper tipped to fall after squeeze unravels.</title>
<headline>LME copper tipped to fall after squeeze unravels.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>London Metal Exchange (LME) copper prices are seen falling slowly later on Tuesday after a technical squeeze on nearby supplies fell apart, dealers said.</p>
<p>The cash/threes backwardation, which had hit US$210 recently, was seen in Asian trade at arond $85/95 against a close on Monday in London of $87/97. Another trader pegged the backwardation here at $90/100.</p>
<p>&quot;It (copper) should come off. I think the squeeze is done,&quot; a dealer for a metal trading company said. &quot;Prices are going to probably slide lower.&quot;  </p>
<p>Three month copper was quoted by the trade at 0200 GMT at $2,365/70 a tonne against the late quote in London on Monday of $2,367/69.</p>
<p>But LME metal brokers Brandeis said falling LME copper stocks and supply problems in Chile, the world's largest producer, raises &quot;the potential for the spreads to flare out again, particularly as the period of tightness is said to extend towards early May dates.&quot;</p>
<p>LME copper stocks reached 141,800 tonnes yesterday, down nearly 20,000 tonnes from the level three weeks ago of about 160,000 tonnes.  </p>
<p>Traders said any drop in copper prices may be temporary because of possible supply problems due to labour unrest in the Escondida mine in northern Chile and a decision by workers at the Quebrada Blanca mine on the Chilean-Bolivian border to go on strike from April 30.</p>
<p>&quot;The problems in Chile will underpin copper prices for the next two to three weeks,&quot; the general manager of a Japanese metal trading company said. &quot;I think copper will get stronger.&quot;  </p>
<p>Quebrada Blanca is owned by Canada's Cominco Ltd and Teck Resources International. Escondida is owned by Broken Hill Proprietary and RTZ-CRA.</p>
<p>The rest of the base metals business in Asia slowed down due to the Golden Week holiday season in Japan and the May 1 holiday observed in other countries around the region.</p>
<p>China has not been seen selling any copper in the market and will probably wait for the following week before making any moves, dealers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese are absent from the market at the moment,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Singapore-based traders were also monitoring copper stocks in the LME warehouse in the city state.</p>
<p>Copper stocks here reached 19,825 tonnes on Monday, down from a peak in late February of 56,475 tonnes. Far East dealers said LME copper stocks should dip 2,000-4,000 tonnes when the stocks report is released at 0800 GMT.</p>
<p>-- Rene Pastor, Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
