<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548766" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Western diesel exports to Asia slows down.</title>
<headline>Western diesel exports to Asia slows down.</headline>
<byline>Raj Rajendran</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The flow of diesel cargoes from the West to Asia is easing amid concerns of slow regional demand and the resurgence of domestic supplies as refineries return from maintenance, industry sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still going to see exports but it won't be like second half April,&quot; one oil major said.</p>
<p>Traders said currently about four or five mid-sized cargoes of around 50,000 tonnes each are poised to leave the West for arrival in June.  </p>
<p>Diesel exports from the West peaked during this period with more than two million tonnes shipped to the region for arrival from mid-April to May, traders said.</p>
<p>The exports were drawn to this region following an unprecedented buying spree by independent Singapore-based company Hin Leong Trading, who together with two other traders bought nearly 18 million barrels of diesel since March 3.</p>
<p>The purchases, valued at around US$500 million, triggered the largest flood of diesel exports from the West to Asia in recent memory, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Europe is not that long right now,&quot; one trader remarked.  </p>
<p>&quot;The arbitrage is open but it is not huge. But the timing is a bit late, cargoes will only arrive after mid-June. The market is ready to buy for mid-June.&quot;</p>
<p>The diesel price differential between Asia and Europe was about $30 per tonne at its peak in March, compared to $18 at present, making it less lucrative to ship in cargoes.</p>
<p>The market's unwillingness to buy cargoes for June arrival to Asia is reflected in the forward swaps market where prices in May is much higher at about $1.00 per barrel above June.</p>
<p>&quot;There still are a lot of sceptics and that is shown in the backwardation,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>Traders said the scepticism was also partly fuelled by Hin Leong's recent actions where the company has consistently bought cargoes at lower prices.</p>
<p>At the start of the buying spree, Hin Leong paid about $28.50 per barrel and prices have continually slipped since then and in recent days they paid around $26.00.</p>
<p>&quot;Hin Leong is bringing the market down gradually,&quot; a trader said. &quot;The arbitrage is gradually being closed.&quot;</p>
<p>As a result, there is little incentive for other traders to ship large volumes from the West as the rewards are small.  </p>
<p>Apart from the price slide, traders were also now unwilling to take big positions simply on the basis that Hin Leong would extend its purchases to include cargoes for mid-June delivery.</p>
<p>Other traders said Hin Leong might also be winding down its buying position, pointing to recent large swap sales by the local trader to hedge its physical purchases as evidence.</p>
<p>&quot;If they were going to continue bidding the market up, they would not have sold so much paper (swaps),&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The trading uncertainties aside, some traders also pointed to the restart of regional refineries after the spring turnaround season as another reason for reduced imports.  </p>
<p>Several Asian refineries were shut down over the March-May period for scheduled maintenance which led to an estimated loss of 20-30 percent in regional output, traders said.</p>
<p>One trader said China, the region's largest diesel consumer, imported 2.06 million tonnes of diesel in the first quarter compared to 4.6 million for the whole of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;I think China is going to slow down its imports in the second quarter as refineries there come back from turnaround,&quot; he said. Three Chinese refineries are due to re-start in May.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (+65-870 3093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
