<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548857" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Yuan ends up at a 10-week high against US dollar.</title>
<headline>Yuan ends up at a 10-week high against US dollar.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chinese yuan closed up at a 10-week high close of 8.2938 on Tuesday from Monday's 8.2955 against the U.S. dollar in Shanghai due to speculative buying in the last few minutes of trading, traders said.</p>
<p>It was the highest close since February 18 when the yuan ended at 8.2926.</p>
<p>The weighted average price on Monday was 8.2949.</p>
<p>Dealers said that despite the speculation, the yuan's rise on Tuesday strengthened the pro-yuan sentiment which has prevail ed in the market in the recent weeks.  </p>
<p>The yuan opened much higher at an intraday high of 8.2860 and fell quickly to hit a low of 8.2950 early in trading.</p>
<p>It then moved around 8.2945 for most of the session before speculative buying set in to push it up again.</p>
<p>Trading was less active than Monday with most business done at 8.2945, traders said.</p>
<p>One dealer said the high opening was possibly due to one transaction but it had a positive impact on the yuan's upward trend throughout the rest of the session.</p>
<p>&quot;The opening boosted confidence even though the yuan could not stand firm at such a high level,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;This was reflected in the fact that most of today's business was done above the key 8.2950 level,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A second dealer said reduced intervention by the People's Bank of China was another factor for the yuan's rise today.</p>
<p>&quot;Recently, the central bank has done little to depress the yuan, which has made yuan buying active,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected the yuan to move between 8.2940 and 8.2950 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The yuan ended up at 6.5360 from 6.5410 against 100 Japanese yen and up at an intraday high of 1.0698 from 1.0713 against the Hong Kong dollar. -- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
