<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548848" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: South Korean oil products flood Asia.</title>
<headline>South Korean oil products flood Asia.</headline>
<byline>Jean Yoon</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean refiners are flooding Asia with oil products following a flurry of refinery expansions last year and a slowdown in domestic consumption, industry analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>South Korea's petroleum products exports jumped 91 percent to 55.6 million barrels in the first quarter of 1997 against 29.1 million a year before, according to the Ministry of Trade, Industry and Energy.</p>
<p>Analysts said refiners were likely to maintain high double-digit growth for the rest of this year with domestic demand expected to remain low.</p>
<p>&quot;The main reason behind the rise is a refining capacity increase and slower domestic demand,&quot; said George Goundry, an energy analyst at HG Asia.</p>
<p>He forecast exports growth of 50-90 percent for the first half and 30-50 percent for the second half.</p>
<p>Analysts said refiners had no choice but to dump products onto the Asian market.</p>
<p>South Korea's refining capacity rose to 2.44 million barrels per day (bpd) by the end of 1996, from 1.82 million at the end of 1995.</p>
<p>Last year, Hyundai Oil Refinery Co added 200,000-bpd of refining capacity, Yukong Ltd 200,000 bpd and LG-Caltex Oil Corp 220,000 bpd.</p>
<p>Yukong, the nation's largest oil refiner with a 810,000-bpd capacity, expanded its exports by 355 percent to 9.37 million barrels in the first two months from 2.06 million a year ago, according to data provided by the state-run Korea Petroleum Development Corp (PEDCO).</p>
<p>LG-Caltex raised it by 278 percent to 4.54 million barrels and Hyundai by 729 percent to 5.10 million.</p>
<p>&quot;With local consumption shrinking, refiners are more pressured to sell products abroad,&quot; said Kim Sang-bae, an energy analyst at Ssangyong Investment Securities.</p>
<p>Domestic demand slipped 0.4 percent to 204.0 million barrels in the first quarter of 1997 from 204.8 million a year earlier. In comparison, consumption rose 9.6 percent in the first quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>The Energy Ministry cited slower industrial growth, an active energy conservation campaign and higher demand for liquefied natural gas as the prime reasons for the slide in domestic demand.</p>
<p>Analysts said the government was also encouraging oil products exports to help improve the ballooning current account deficit.</p>
<p>They said the Korean refiners were betting on China and Japan to consume much of their surplus this year, while casting around for new markets in Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>China, South Korea's biggest export market, purchased 13.04 million barrels of oil products from South Korea in the first two months of this year against 3.18 million a year ago, according to PEDCO.</p>
<p>Japan was the second largest buyer, with Hong Kong tailing behind.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
