<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548813" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia minority party halts rallies after clash.</title>
<headline>Indonesia minority party halts rallies after clash.</headline>
<byline>Jim Della-Giacoma</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The minority Indonesian Democratic party (PDI), already hit by a damaging split, might cancel election campaigning in the second city of Surabaya after a brawl between party rivals, reports said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Witnesses said a rally on Monday was abandoned after the speakers' stage was destroyed in fighting between supporters of the government-backed PDI faction led by deputy parliamentary speaker Surjadi and backers of ousted party leader Megawati Sukarnoputri.</p>
<p>&quot;If the situation continues like this, we will have to cancel campaigning in Surabaya,&quot; Bachtiar Balukh, head of the official PDI faction in the city, told reporters.</p>
<p>It was the first major incident in an otherwise peaceful start to the April 27-May 23 campaign for local and national elections. The polls are being held on May 29.</p>
<p>Despite widespread local reporting of the clash, money market dealers said the rupiah continued rising against the dollar in slow Tuesday morning trade.</p>
<p>Spot rupiah rose to a high of 2,422.75 from an opening of 2,426.75 before settling at 2,425.37 by mid-morning. The stock market was off nearly 8.83 points, or 1.35 percent, at 647.7, but this was attributed to suspension of an active stock and profit-taking.</p>
<p>The Christian-National PDI, the ruling Golkar and the Moslem-oriented United Development Party (PPP) are the only three parties legally permitted to contest the poll for the 425 elected seats in the House of Representatives. The other 75 seats are reserved for the military, which does not vote.</p>
<p>The three parties competing for nearly 125 million potential votes have agreed to campaign each day in separate areas of the country, a sprawling archipelago stretching 5,000 km (3,000 miles) along the equator.</p>
<p>The official Antara news agency said the PDI rally in Surabaya turned into a &quot;massive brawl&quot; after a Megawati supporter seized a microphone on the stage and shouted &quot;Long live Megawati&quot; before being restrained by party security officials.</p>
<p>Witnesses said stones were then thrown at the stage, causing significant damage before security forces arrived and dispersed the crowd.</p>
<p>Megawati has called on her supporters to stay away from the election campaign, which began on Sunday, in a bid to prevent violence.</p>
<p>The PDI has been split since government-backed party rebels led by former leader Surjadi ousted Megawati as party head in June last year. The PDI in Surabaya continued to operate with two rival party branches.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
