<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548972" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: FEATURE - Israeli satellite company spans the globe.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Israeli satellite company spans the globe.</headline>
<byline>Tova Cohen</byline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Every 20 minutes a Gilat satellite terminal is installed somewhere in the world, says Yoel Gat, chairman and chief executive of Gilat Satellite Networks Inc.</p>
<p>The success of one of Israel's leading high-tech companies, founded just 10 years ago, is reflected in its share price, which has jumped 50 percent on Nasdaq since November.</p>
<p>Gat said he prefers a gradual, steady rise in the share price rather than sudden jumps. &quot;I'm looking to build a base where the stock will gradually go up...I don't want to commit to 50 percent forever. We have to manage the expectations of everyone. If growth is too fast you will pay in the long run.&quot;</p>
<p>Despite Gat's conservative approach, Smith Barney analyst Elliot Prince has set a 12-month price target of $50 and rates the shares a buy. Prince estimates Gilat will earn $1.57 a share in 1997 and $2.00 in 1998 against $1.22 (excluding an $8 million acquisition charge) in 1996.</p>
<p>Gat attributes the stock's success to the company's ability to meet Wall Street's expectations consistently since an initial public offering in 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;We have high predictability and have been able to do well because of that. We have a good name, when we come to the street we can raise money, people trust us,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gilat was founded by a group of Israeli army veterans that includes Gat and Gilat president Amriam Levinberg. As engineers, they worked on army research and development programmes.</p>
<p>THREE LINES OF PRODUCTS</p>
<p>The company has three lines of products: data delivery, voice and Internet product lines. Its service delivers data for stock exchanges in 15 countries including Argentina, China, Israel and Thailand.</p>
<p>Gilat has become the world's second-largest provider of VSAT (very small aperture terminal) satellite earth stations.</p>
<p>According to Comsys, an independent British research firm, Gilat had more than 37 percent of world market share in 1996, up from 15 percent in 1994. Hughes Network Systems, Gilat's biggest competitor, accounted for 44 percent, down from 53 in 1994.</p>
<p>Gilat does 33 percent of its business in the United States, 10 to 15 percent in China and 20 percent in Western Europe.</p>
<p>Gat said the biggest potential for growth is in countries such as Brazil, China, India, Indonesia and Russia.</p>
<p>&quot;These countries have a lot of regions, a lot of area, with poor or non-existent telephone infrastructure,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While Gilat has not yet begun sales in the Arab Middle East, it is a region the company may pursue aggressively, when the political climate is right.</p>
<p>PEACE PROCESS DIVIDENDS</p>
<p>The peace process has opened new doors for Gilat, especially in Moslem Asia. &quot;In the last two years we have started to sell to Indonesia, which was a dream beforehand.&quot; Gat said.</p>
<p>The company has also begun discussions with Malaysia but success there, as well as more rapid growth in Indonesia, is contingent on the peace process moving forward, Gat said.</p>
<p>Gilat has formed alliances to develop products with several major international players. It has a strategic relationship with Gtech, providing VSATs for lottery systems, including those in Britain and Brazil.</p>
<p>Gilat also provides the hardware for the two-way interactive Skystar Advantage, while General Electric Co's GE Spacenet provides the software. The system is used, for example, by the Rite Aid chain's 3,500 drugstores for credit and prescription verification and inventory control.</p>
<p>&quot;More than 50 percent of our sales are driven through alliances. But in the last few years, even though sales of alliances are growing, the percentage of direct sales is growing as well,&quot; Gat said.</p>
<p>THREE PARID GROWTH AREAS</p>
<p>The company has targeted three product areas for rapid growth -- paging, satellite pay phones and the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope by 1998 that 50 percent of our sales will go to these markets,&quot; Gat said.</p>
<p>To achieve that goal, Gilat in January made its first acquisition, that of competitor Skydata Inc of Florida.</p>
<p>&quot;They were stronger than we were in the paging market,&quot; said Gat. &quot;It was a big growth opportunity. Also, we didn't have any foothold in Latin America, only sporadic sales...We multiplied their product offering and bought ourselves distribution into Latin America overnight.&quot;</p>
<p>As a result of the acquisition, Samsung Corp and Matra Marconi Space France Sa, which were major investors in Skydata, now hold a combined six percent of Gilat.</p>
<p>The company's founders own 20 percent of Gilat while Israeli holding giant IDB controls 15 percent.</p>
<p>MORE ACQUISITIONS PLANNED</p>
<p>Asked if Gilat plans more acquisitions, Gat replied: &quot;In general yes. We are a very conservative company and would feel comfortable after the integration with Skydata is complete.&quot;</p>
<p>In the field of satellite pay phones, Gat said Gilat has the edge over its competitors. Because the cost of its equipment is lower, it can provide service for 15 cents per minute compared with $1 to $3 for the competition.</p>
<p>In the Internet arena, Gilat initiated a consortium in Israel of 25 companies including Motorola, VocalTec and Checkpoint. With backing from Israel's Chief Scientist's Office, the group is building infrastructre to support broadband Internet.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
