<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="548974" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O.Licht - Daily coffee report.</title>
<headline>F.O.Licht - Daily coffee report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from commodity statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>COFFEE -- World market for April 28, 1997</p>
<p>Robusta futures in London closed lower across the board with front-month May coming under selling pressure before the first tender day and the implementation of the exchange grading rules. May lost $40 to close at $1,550 per tonne, while July gave up $28 to close at $1,600 per tonne. Traders said that pending a sharp movement in New York, the London market is likely to stay in its current trading range with the upside being capped by origin selling notably from Indonesia. The amount of coffee being graded so far in April has been quite large. By April 28 2,431 5-tonne lots were graded, of which 1,515 were untenderable.</p>
<p>There was also talk that a larger European trade house was seeking to tender a large quantity of Thai robusta coffee against LIFFE's May contract. Arabica futures closed mostly higher but conditions were a bit calmer than in recent sessions. Benchmark July closed 3.15 cents/lb higher at 196.40 cents/lb, while September gained 1.65 cents/lb to close at 178.35 cents/lb. The May/July switch, a barometer of nearby availability widened to 23.85 cents/lb from 23.10 cents/lb at the close on Friday. The steady decline of CSCE certified coffee stocks from a build up of more than 83,000 60-kg bags three weeks ago has helped fuel supply fears.</p>
<p>All eyes are on the Brazilian 1997/98 crop as the country approaches winter. Traders said that Brazilian coffee seems to be available in advance of the new harvest which has put pressure on Brazilian differentials and could cap any price rise. However, all other coffee remains in very tight supply.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>COLOMBIA - The head of Colombia's National Coffee Growers' Federation, Jorge Cardenas, said that Colombia's coffee stocks could fall to 3.5 million 60-kg bags in September 1997 from 6 million bags held the same month a year ago. Coffee production in 1996/97 (October/September) is estimated at 10 million bags, slightly lower than previous estimates and well below the 13 million bags produced in 1995/96. Cardenas said production in 1997/98 could be smaller than average but declined to give a precise figure.</p>
<p>HONDURAS - According to the Honduran Coffee Institute coffee production in 1996/97 (October/September) reached 2.108 million 60-kg bags, down from 1.910 million bags produced in 1995/96 and 2.092 million bags produced in 1994/95.</p>
<p>SWEDEN - Sweden imported 191,309 bags of coffee in November 1996, significantly up on last year's figure of 128,580 bags. That brought total imports in since the beginning of 1996 up to 1.961 million bags, 28 percent more than was imported the same period in 1995. Total imports in calendar year 1995 dropped by 13 percent to 1.648 million bags. Main suppliers of green coffee in January/November 1996 were Kenya (130,400 vs 120,700 bags), Guatemala (184,800 vs 165,300 bags), Brazil (438,300 vs 423,400 bags) and Colombia (420,900 vs 346,200 bags).</p>
<p>The country exported 201,500 bags of coffee in January/November 1996, 7 percent more than was exported the same period in 1995. Total exports in calendar year 1995 dropped by 9 percent to 204,700 bags.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
