<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="549112" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French Advertising &amp; Media Digest - Apr 29.</title>
<headline>French Advertising &amp; Media Digest - Apr 29.</headline>
<text>
<p>--------------------FAM------------------</p>
<p>REUTERS FRENCH ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA DIGEST</p>
<p>-----------------April 29, 1997----------</p>
<p>News from Reuters and the French press on Advertising, Marketing, the Media, the Internet, Brands and Products and Consumer Trends.</p>
<p>************************************************************</p>
<p>ADVERTISING &amp; MARKETING:</p>
<p>PARIS - The Lotus baby is back. Bates France has created a humorous new spot for the toilet paper brand with toddlers dressed up as company executives to vaunt the merits of Lotus toilet rolls. (Le Figaro)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - Music radio station NRJ says it had the second largest share of the French radio advertising market in the first quarter, with 18 percent against RTL's 24 percent and 18 percent for general station Europe 1. (Reuter)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>MEDIA &amp; THE INTERNET:</p>
<p>PARIS - French music station RTL 2 says it needs extra transmitters for its development and will reach breakeven in 1998. (La Tribune)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - Cinema entries fell 19 percent in the 1997 first quarter compared with the first quarter of 1996, but spring looks more promising and there was a slight recovery in April (La Tribune).</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - A new French weekly news magazine, Marianne, has been launched with an anti-government satirical slant and financed independently of any established publishing group, its founders said.(Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - Serge Dassault, chairman of Dassault Aviation, has taken</p>
<p>the new weekly news magazine Marianne to court (Le Figaro).</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - French bank Societe Generale confirms it has been hired</p>
<p>by Bouygues to find a buyer for Bouygues' film production unit</p>
<p>Ciby 2000. (Reuter)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>BRANDS NAME PRODUCTS &amp; MARKETS:</p>
<p>PARIS - Euro Disney, operator of the Disneyland Paris theme park, reports its loss for the first half of the 1996/97 year widened as debt charges rose faster than operating income.</p>
<p>(Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - The restructuring of France's defence sector and the key role of state-owned Aerospatiale in the process are complicating moves by the European Airbus consortium to become a limited liability company, analysts say. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - Renault chairman Louis Schweitzer has created two management units, a Mercosur unit for the South American business and a light commercial vehicles unit to carry out group strategies, the company says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>Paris Editorial, Sue Landau</p>
<p>Tel (33) 1 42 21 53 33</p>
<p>Fax (33) 1 42 36 10 72</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>Reuters is also on the Internet:</p>
<p>http://www.Bizinfo.reuters.com</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
