<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="549218" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wisconsin Central gets union notice.</title>
<headline>Wisconsin Central gets union notice.</headline>
<dateline>ROSEMONT, Ill. 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wisconsin Central Transportation Corp said Wednesday that its locomotive engineers and conductors may be offered union representation and that past attempts have failed.</p>
<p>Wisconsin Central Ltd, a wholly owned subsidiary of WCTC, has been notified by the National Mediation Board that it has received applications filed on behalf of the Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers and the United Transportation Union to conduct a representation election for locomotive engineers and conductors. About 600 to 700 employees would be fall into those work categories, a company spokesman said.  </p>
<p>&quot;WCL has had several other unionization attempts in the past, all of which were unsuccessful,&quot; said Wisconsin Central Transportation President Edward Burkhardt in a statement.</p>
<p>On Wednesday the company reported its 1997 first quarter earnings rose 119 percent from the same period a year ago to $17.6 million or $0.35 a share. Net income in the first quarter of 1996 was reduced by $1.5 million or $0.03 due to costs related to a March 4, 1996 derailment in Weyauwega, Wis.</p>
<p>Operating revenues for the first quarter of 1997 reached a record $80.3 million, up 22.8 percent from a year-ago.</p>
<p>Volume increased 19.8 percent to a record of more than 137,500 carloads, compared with the year-ago period. These gains reflect higher volumes in woodpulp, clay products, sand, stone and minerals, steel and intermodal shipments and the January 27, 1997 acquisition of the Duck Creek North lines from the Union Pacific Railroad Co, it said.</p>
<p>Operating expenses for the first quarter of 1997 rose $4.6 million to $65.2 million due to higher labor and equipment rents resulting from higher volumes and a Safety Compliance Agreement entered into with the Federal Railroad Administration in February 1997, it said. Increased expenses were also due to higher fuel prices and depreciation.</p>
<p>	  ((Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROSEMONT, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
