<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="549751" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Paul McCartney returns to Beatle roots in new album.</title>
<headline>Paul McCartney returns to Beatle roots in new album.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paul McCartney returns to his Beatle roots in his new album, his first in four years, which features his wife and son and Ringo Starr.</p>
<p>In a rare interview before the release of &quot;Flaming Pie&quot;, which takes its name from Beatles mythology, McCartney spoke of his grief after John Lennon was murdered by a crazed fan in New York 17 years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;I loved him,&quot; he told Reuters Television at his recording studio in southeastern England.</p>
<p>McCartney said that he and Lennon, one of the most successful songwriting teams this century, could produce chart topping tunes in three hours and they rarely came away from a session without a new song.</p>
<p>&quot;The memories are really great. It's terrible what happened to him.&quot;</p>
<p>McCartney wrote most of 14 songs featured on the album, which was inspired by &quot;The Beatles Anthology&quot;. It's a family affair which includes McCartney's wife Linda, who has been battling against breast cancer, his 19-year-old son James, as well as a guest appearance by Starr.</p>
<p>The singer, who was knighted by Queen Elizabeth this year, paid tribute to Linda, who has rarely been seen in public since she was diagnosed with cancer almost two years ago. Their marriage is one of the most successful in the entertainment business.</p>
<p>&quot;I went for her in a big way,&quot; he said about their first meeting. We've never looked back.&quot;</p>
<p>Making &quot;The Beatle Anthology&quot; brought back memories of how much he enjoyed the group's early days and convinced him to release what he describes as his &quot;home-made&quot; album.</p>
<p>The catchy, toe-tapping tunes are a deliberate return to the Beatles' early sound. After the group broke up McCartney said he consciously tried to develop a different style.</p>
<p>&quot;I turned my back on it,&quot; he said. &quot;But then I started to miss it. I started to think it's a style I like so why not get back to it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
