<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="549777" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Galileo wound up but Britain's CWS to pursue claim.</title>
<headline>Galileo wound up but Britain's CWS to pursue claim.</headline>
<byline>Alexander Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Galileo, the firm which last week failed in its 1.2 billion pound ($2 billion) bid for Britain's Co-operative Wholesale Society (CWS), was finally wound up on Wednesday, its liquidator said.</p>
<p>Jason Elles, the partner at accountants Ernst &amp; Young appointed as liquidator, said there were enough assets to pay off creditors. He did not give any detail of who the creditors were or how much they were owed but CWS said it would be lodging a claim.</p>
<p>In a related development, British investment bank Schroders sought to clarify its relationship with Galileo and Lanica Trust, the company run by 31-year-old entrepreneur Andrew Regan.</p>
<p>Schroders said it had never seen any of the confidential Co-op documents leaked by CWS manager Allan Green, who was suspended and later dismissed by CWS, to Regan and his backers.</p>
<p>These papers, which included profit forecasts and minutes of board meetings, effectively scuppered the bid attempt when CWS gained a court order prohibiting their use. The withdrawal of a key financial backer also hastened its demise.</p>
<p>Schroders said it was purely a portfolio investor in the firms, although three employees of Schroder Investment Management had invested in Lanica before knowing about plans to form Galileo.</p>
<p>The firm said its combined total investment in Lanica and Galileo was below two million pounds.</p>
<p>A Schroders spokesman said its investment management arm had considered withdrawing from Galileo when the controversy over the documents arose but was &quot;trumped&quot; by the fact that it was being put into solvent liquidation.</p>
<p>Elles is expected to review Galileo's situation, including outstanding legal claims against it.</p>
<p>&quot;There are sufficient assets to repay the creditors in full and enable a return to be made to shareholders,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The move was not unexpected and followed a Galileo board meeting to wind up the business with the agreement of its shareholders.</p>
<p>Galileo, an offshoot of Regan's Guernsey-based investment trust Lanica, is the subject of a High Court order and punitive costs were last week awarded against Galileo, Lanica, Regan, Green and David Lyons, Galileo's chief executive.</p>
<p>The process of going through a company's books and its assets can often take up to a year but CWS said it intends registering its interest with the liquidator and &quot;will be lodging a contingency claim with them as creditors&quot;.</p>
<p>A CWS spokeswoman also told Reuters that the 153-year old mutually-owned supermarkets-to-funeral parlours group would be pursuing Lanica Trust, Green, Regan and Galileo chairman David Lyons &quot;vigorously through the courts&quot; in a damages claim.</p>
<p>Neither the Co-op or others involved in the saga were surprised by the decision to bring Galileo to an end. &quot;It was set up solely as a bidding vehicle,&quot; said one banking source, adding that it had assets of around 10 million pounds.</p>
<p>It has not yet emerged how much British merchant bank Hambros, which on Monday apologised unreservedly to CWS for backing the bid, will be paid in advisory fees for assisting the attempt.</p>
<p>Hambros has said it will not comment beyond a short statement made on Monday, although it has emerged that there was a substantial financial element to its settlement with CWS.</p>
<p>Regan, Galileo's chairman, has not commented on the failed bid although sources said he was in favour of winding up the bidding vehicle and returning assets to shareholders.</p>
<p>Apart from Schroders Investment Management, fund group Jupiter and stockbrokers Killik &amp; Co were both shareholders in Galileo.</p>
<p>The affair is now set to rumble on in the courts, with CWS pursuing private actions and Britain's Serious Fraud Office (SFO) probing a controversial 2.4 million pound payment to a third party in an earlier deal between a company run by Regan and the CWS in 1995. ($ = 0.614 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
