<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="549859" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada pioneers take U.S. laser market by storm. [CORRECTED 23:22 GMT]</title>
<headline>Canada pioneers take U.S. laser market by storm. [CORRECTED 23:22 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Andrea Hopkins</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Laser eye surgery has begun living up to its hype in the United States and companies that refined their techniques in Canada are taking the market by storm.</p>
<p>Billed as the &quot;throw away your glasses&quot; answer to poor vision, photo-refractive keratectomies (PRKs) are aimed at an estimated 60 million shortsighted Americans who may be candidates for the surgery. A further 90 million Americans could join the market as U.S regulations open up to allow for treatment of more eye conditions.</p>
<p>Propelled by expanding regulatory approval, the number of PRKs performed in the United States is expected to double or triple in 1997 after a lacklustre inaugural year, driving competitors into a risky market worth up to C$4 billion ($2.9 billion) annually.</p>
<p>The surgery, a 90-second outpatient procedure, uses a cool laser to reshape the surface of the eye and correct poor vision permanently. More than 500,000 people worldwide have had the surgery, with 94 percent walking out of the clinic with vision of 20/40 or better -- good enough to drive without spectacles.</p>
<p>U.S AND CANADIAN FIRMS LEAD THE MARKET</p>
<p>Leading the charge into the market are Canadian and U.S. firms who used Canada's five-year regulatory head start to learn the ropes ahead of U.S. Food and Drug Administration approval, which came in October 1995.</p>
<p>Toronto-based TLC Laser Centre Inc ) opened its first Canadian clinic in Windsor, Ontario in September 1993, followed by three more sites. It leapt into the U.S. market after FDA approval, opening or acquiring 23 clinics in 14 months.</p>
<p>&quot;The benefit of being in Canada is that we had three years of operating experience before the U.S. was open, so we got a lot of the operational issues out of the way,&quot; said TLC Chief Financial Officer Ken Pelissero.</p>
<p>He said TLC's Canadian clinics helped bankroll the U.S. expansion and boosted the balance sheet, since it takes most U.S. clinics 12 to 18 months to become profitable.</p>
<p>John Klobnak, chief executive of St Louis-based LaserVision Centres Inc, said Canada was the best training ground for U.S. expansion because &quot;it's probably the closest thing to America you can get.&quot;</p>
<p>LaserVision launched six Canadian clinics in 1991 before expanding to Europe and the United States, where it has opened 50 centres in 25 states since FDA approval.</p>
<p>Klobnak said the expansion was successful because he was able to make mistakes, particularly on the financial side of the business, before tackling the huge U.S. market.</p>
<p>&quot;We didn't make a lot of mistakes in America that we had already made in other countries...I don't think a lot of people really understood the actual costs involved in running all these lasers. I knew it totally. A lot of our competitors are still making those rookie mistakes,&quot; Klobnak said.</p>
<p>THE COSTS</p>
<p>Firms can expect to pay $500,000 for the laser equipment and about $34,600 in annual service fees.</p>
<p>In addition, the two U.S. manufacturers of the Excimer laser, Waltham, Massachusetts-based Summit Technology and Santa Clara, California-based VISX, collect a $250 per-use royalty fee every time a doctor performs a PRK in the United States with either company's laser.</p>
<p>Selling the procedure, which costs patients about $2000 per eye, is not cheap either. The surgery is not covered by most health insurance plans in Canada and the United States.</p>
<p>Irving Arons, an industry consultant based in Peabody, Massachusetts, said it took the average patient nine months to take the plunge, at an advertising cost of up to US$250 each.</p>
<p>SHAKY START FOR U.S MARKET</p>
<p>Predications that pent-up U.S. demand would spur as many as 375,000 operations in the first year after approvals, proved wildly off the mark. Analysts said about 75,000 operations took place in 1996. They blamed the market failure on the early FDA restrictions, which cut into the pool of surgery candidates.</p>
<p>Current regulations allow surgeons to correct moderate myopia and astigmatism, an irregular curvature of the eye, but restrict the treatment of severe myopia and hyperopia.</p>
<p>Approval for hyperopia, or longsight, is thought to be about a year away.</p>
<p>(Corrects to update with FDA approval of astigmatism.)</p>
<p>All of the procedures are available in Canada, Europe, South America and much of Asia.</p>
<p>Canada's open regulatory environment allowed firms to treat American patients and train surgeons before FDA approval. A steady stream of both continue to travel north for procedures still restricted in the United States.</p>
<p>Beacon Eye Inc established its flagship Toronto practice about a year before FDA approval and focused much of its energy on attracting U.S. patients unwilling to wait for it.</p>
<p>The strategy resulted in increased revenues and a source of U.S. patient referrals in a business where word-of-mouth is of prime importance.</p>
<p>&quot;(Our) Toronto facility gave us a way to start seeding some satisfied patients into those U.S. markets where we were eventually going to expand,&quot; Beacon Chief Executive Keith Moore told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said that more than 1,000 surgeons looking to enter the PRK field or practice procedures not yet cleared by the FDA had been trained at the clinic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
