<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="549893" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Southern Africa wary about where Zaire headed.</title>
<headline>Southern Africa wary about where Zaire headed.</headline>
<byline>Lesley Wroughton</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's rebel leader Laurent Kabila is intent on winning power either on the battlefield or in negotiations, but his southern neighbours are wary of what that holds for their region.</p>
<p>Kabila, a former Marxist who has battled President Mobutu Sese Seko for more than three decades, has seized control of around one-half of the mineral-rich country in a seven-month military campaign.</p>
<p>But, with Zaire in disarray and in desperate need of economic rebuilding, analysts are inevitably cautious about the country's prospects under him.</p>
<p>There's little doubt about the potential for business and southern African countries, among others, eagerly eye increased ties.</p>
<p>South African Mining giant Anglo American Corp. has recently shown interest in copper and cobalt projects. And Kabila's rebel alliance, without being in power, has already awarded America Mineral Fields Inc. a $1 billion mining deal.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, southern African states are worried about how best to help stabilise their neighbour, Africa's third largest country.</p>
<p>Some observers believe a Zaire wanting to dig itself out of its economic mess might again seek membership of the 12-nation Southern African Development Community (SADC) -- a trade bloc of Zaire's more stable southern neighbours.</p>
<p>The Mobutu government has twice sought SADC membership, but was turned down both times.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the so-called rebels have any other agenda at the moment except deposing Mr Mobutu and this is ... (a) worrying factor because they don't seem to have a political agenda,&quot; said SADC deputy executive secretary Lengolo Monyake.</p>
<p>&quot;This is supposed to be southern Africa and by introducing Zaire, that would be stretching the concept of southern Africa a litte too far,&quot; he said in an interview.</p>
<p>Zaire shares long borders with SADC members Angola, Tanzania and Zambia. Other members are South Africa, Botswana, Zimbabwe, Namibia, Mozambique, Lesotho, Swaziland, Mauritius and Malawi.</p>
<p>Political analysts say instability in Zaire and deep-rooted ethnic divisions which periodically surface will continue to keep it at arm's length from his neighbours.</p>
<p>&quot;The SADC debate around Zaire will go on for a while before one sees confidence in Kabila and Zaire from its neighbours,&quot; said Vernon Seymour of the Centre for Southern African Studies in Cape Town.</p>
<p>This month saw the inauguration of a unity government in SADC member Angola after two decades of civil war, and the trade group has touted its recent stability as a drawcard for investors.</p>
<p>An African economist said official trade between the SADC and Zaire was limited and it would make sense if a new Zairean government sought membership in the SADC -- a move which could help it overcome regional trade and tariff barriers.</p>
<p>&quot;Southern Zaire, especially Shaba province, is effectively already part of the SADC because it transports its cobalt and copper through the SADC.</p>
<p>&quot;Once Angola gets itself together there is no doubt that Zaire also will use it as another SADC transport route for its minerals,&quot; the economist said.</p>
<p>Other business links include busy informal trade between Zaire and Zambia, and Mobutu's government signed a deal with the SADC to share hydroelectric power from the Zaire river.</p>
<p>&quot;The only direct connection we have with Zaire as SADC is in the power field... The power pool will work to ensure there is one continuous coverage of energy throughout the region,&quot; SADC's Monyake said.</p>
<p>South Africa is Zaire's biggest SADC trade partner and its exports were worth about $209 million over the first 11 months of last year -- mainly foodstuffs and mining gear.</p>
<p>Zaire's exports to South Africa over the same period totalled $113 million, mainly copper and cobalt from the southern Shaba province, which is the country's economic backbone and is now controlled by Kabila's forces.</p>
<p>Security analysts said the presence of thousands of Zairean refugees in SADC countries was unsettling to regional stability.</p>
<p>However, an end to the Mobutu era was likely to ease tensions over Zaire's support for the former Angolan rebel movement UNITA, which used Zaire as a route for illegal diamond trading and as its supply base.</p>
<p>Richard Cornwell, of the Pretoria-based Africa Institute, said Mobutu's troubles in Zaire had helped hasten a settlement in Angola.</p>
<p>&quot;UNITA appears to have become more amenable to participating in the (Angolan) government of national unity after what has been happening in Zaire,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG, South Africa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
