<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="549822" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: APV saw heavy trade ahead Tuesday bid news.</title>
<headline>APV saw heavy trade ahead Tuesday bid news.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trading volume in APV Plc shares soared ahead of an announcement on Tuesday that the engineering group had been approached about a possible takeover.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, April 29, turnover rocketed to 14.835 million shares, just prior to the 1530 GMT statement in which APV said the approach &quot;may or may not lead to a takeover bid.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We've seen some good two-way institutional activity in the stock the past few days,&quot; one market maker said. &quot;It's difficult to know if it's one big buyer or several players.&quot;</p>
<p>APV, which makes specialist equipment, principally for the food and beverage industries, saw an average 9.25 million shares changed hands over the past three sessions compared with a 200-day moving average volume of 950,000.</p>
<p>Over the past five trading sessions around 14 percent of APV's issued share capital had changed hands but as of Wednesday the company's registrar had not published any names of any group which may have a notifiable interest.</p>
<p>Under UK securities rules, any group with three  percent or more of a FTSE listed firm's shares must notify the company's registrars. The company is then obliged to inform the London Stock Exchange(LSE)by the end of the following business day.</p>
<p>But the purchaser does not have to show his hand until settlement day, which can delay notification by at least five days.</p>
<p>&quot;It can theoretically be even longer, depending on what settlement arrangement the purchaser has with his broker,&quot; an LSE spokesman said.</p>
<p>APV said it had not yet been notified of any large purchaser but noted trading volume had been well above normal over the past few days.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't know who is buying the shares. We don't know if it is one group or several people,&quot; APV company secretary Robert MacDonald told Reuters.</p>
<p>On March 20, the group said its financial performance in 1996 did not meet its objectives as it disclosed that full-year pre-tax profits fell to 15.0 million stg in that year from 26.9 million in 1995.</p>
<p>But APV said it was &quot;better positioned&quot; to improve its financial position in 1997, &quot;despite stiff competition and uncertain market conditions.&quot;</p>
<p>APV shares were up 16p to 87p in a volume of about 3.62 million shares by 1510 GMT.</p>
<p>--Dale Faulken, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32440">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
