<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="549905" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: U.S. envoy and Mobutu meet again.</title>
<headline>U.S. envoy and Mobutu meet again.</headline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. envoy Bill Richardson held fresh talks with Zaire's President Mobutu Sese Seko on Wednesday as part of efforts to salvage a face-to-face meeting between the veteran strongman and rebel leader Laurent Kabila.</p>
<p>Witnesses and Zairean officials said the talks resumed in the capital Kinshasa at Mobutu's presidential villa in the heavily guarded Tshatshi military camp on the banks of the Zaire River.</p>
<p>Earlier, Kabila appealed to the international community to force Mobutu to attend talks at sea to avoid a battle for the teeming capital of five million people.</p>
<p>&quot;We remain committed to the talks despite our military advantage but the international community must now put pressure on Mobutu and force him to come to talks at sea,&quot; Kabila told Reuters in Zaire's second city of Lubumbashi.</p>
<p>A diplomat travelling with Richardson said earlier that Mobutu, who had prostate cancer surgery in Europe in August, had turned down a South African offer to host the talks at sea off Zaire on one of its navy ships.</p>
<p>Kabila told Reuters on Wednesday that he would not go to Gabon, a venue preferred by Mobutu and encouraged by the United States, for security reasons.</p>
<p>The rebels control over half the sprawling Central African nation and are marching on Kinshasa.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
