<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="549916" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire rebel chief appeals for pressure on Mobutu.</title>
<headline>Zaire rebel chief appeals for pressure on Mobutu.</headline>
<dateline>LUBUMBASHI, Zaire 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire rebel leader Laurent Kabila appealed on Wednesday to the international community to force President Mobutu Sese Seko to attend talks at sea to avoid a battle for Kinshasa.</p>
<p>Kabila, head of the Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire (ADFL), told Reuters he would not go to Gabon, a venue preferred by Mobutu and encouraged by the United States, for security reasons.  </p>
<p>&quot;We remain committed to the talks despite our military advantage but the international community must now put pressure on Mobutu and force him to come to talks at sea,&quot; Kabila said.</p>
<p>&quot;Only talks will avoid a battle for Kinshasa. But if Mobutu cannot come to talks then it is business as usual for us. It means we will have to take Kinshasa,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Kabila said he had totally rejected Mobutu's preferred venue, Gabon, for security reasons.</p>
<p>Although a U.S. diplomat said on Tuesday Mobutu had refused talks on a South African ship, Mobutu's son and spokesman Nzanga Mobutu declined on Wednesday to rule out talks off the coast of Zaire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GABON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUBUMBASHI, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
