<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55008" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Debate heats up over US jobless rate and inflation.</title>
<headline>Debate heats up over US jobless rate and inflation.</headline>
<byline>Caren Bohan</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A central question the Federal Reserve will consider at an upcoming meeting on interest rates is whether an unemployment rate close to 5 percent poses the threat of higher inflation.</p>
<p>Fed policy makers have become increasingly concerned about that risk even as a number of economists have played down the potential for a pickup in inflation.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are definitely in a danger zone from the Federal Reserve's perspective,&quot; said Brad DeLong, economist at the University of California at Berkeley. &quot;They have been teetering on the edge of raising rates but the the drop in the unemployment rate will probably push them over it.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. jobless rate fell in August to 5.1 percent from 5.4 percent in July.</p>
<p>Concerns about inflation stem from economic theories holding that when the unemployment rate falls below its so-called &quot;natural&quot; rate, wages begin to rise, putting upward pressure on inflation.  </p>
<p>Until recently, a 6 percent jobless rate was widely viewed as the magic number. Now that inflation has remained tame, despite a jobless rate below 6 percent for two years, a number of analysts believe the natural rate is lower but there is no consensus on the exact level.</p>
<p>&quot;Many economists agree that the natural rate has come down,&quot; said Rob Valletta, an economist at the Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco. &quot;Attempts to estimate it can't be done with any degree of confidence.&quot;</p>
<p>Fed Governor Lawrence Lindsey, among several Fed officials to express concern about the inflation implications of the low unemployment rate, said in an interview with Reuters Friday that as the rate nears 5 percent, the odds of higher inflation become prohibitive.</p>
<p>He stopped short of revealing whether he would vote to support an interest-rate rise at the central bank's next meeting on Sept. 24 but many analysts see a 25-basis-point credit tightening as a strong prospect.  </p>
<p>Given the uncertainty and the mild inflation experienced so far, Robert Gordon, an economist at Northwestern University who is an expert on the natural rate theory, has urged the Fed to test the lower limits of unemployment.</p>
<p>&quot;I do think there is a case to be made for the Fed taking this as a time to use the economy has a controlled experiment,&quot; Gordon said on Friday during a panel discussion moderated by Fed Governor Laurence Meyer.</p>
<p>&quot;There just isn't enough indication in the tea leaves ... to say that there's really a big case to be made for creating more unemployment,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Two Clinton administration officials, Labor Secretary Robert Reich and Joseph Stiglitz, chairman of the White House Council of Economic Advisers, last week also made the case for tolerating low unemployment. The officials stressed, though, that their comments were not a discussion of Fed policy.</p>
<p>Reich pointed to structural changes that he said suggest why the economy can sustain a lower level of unemployment than previously assumed without risking inflation.</p>
<p>For his part, Stiglitz highlighted the tame inflation, saying there was some evidence that &quot;inflationary pressures are not as great as many fear.&quot;  </p>
<p>Economist Barry Bosworth of the Brookings Institution said the administration no doubt would like to see the central bank refrain from raising rates ahead of the November election.</p>
<p>Yet he cautioned that the Fed would be making a mistake if it followed the administration's advice.</p>
<p>&quot;It is time to make sure unemployment does not go any lower,&quot; Bosworth said. &quot;The risks are not evenly balanced. You are trading off small gains in unemployment against the risk of a short-term recession.&quot;</p>
<p>Bosworth said a downturn could arise if inflation eventually moves higher and the Fed has to act aggressively to combat it. &quot;As long as we can stop inflation from accelerating, this expansion can keep going on,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
