<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550039" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Wider Slovak trade gap corners cen bank -analysts.</title>
<headline>Wider Slovak trade gap corners cen bank -analysts.</headline>
<byline>Peter Javurek</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovakia's trade deficit widened in the first quarter, as widely anticipated, and eliminated any room the central bank may have had for easing monetary policy.</p>
<p>The Slovak Statistical Bureau (SUSR) said on Wednesday the trade gap for the first three months of the year hit 15.894 billion crowns, up from a 15.440 billion crown shortfall for the same period in 1996.</p>
<p>Analysts said that given pressure on the trade balance from government plans for extensive infrastructure projects which will need to import technology equipment heavily, the central bank has little room to loosen its tight monetary policy.</p>
<p>&quot;To achieve the ideal goal stated in the NBS monetary programme of trade deficit of five percent to GDP will be a tough job,&quot; Martin Barto, an analyst from ING Barings told Reuters.</p>
<p>He pointed to the fact that the first quarter deficit already accounted for about 2.5 percent of the projected 1997 GDP.</p>
<p>Last week, central bank (NBS) Governor Vladimir Masar said the central bank might ease its policy if the trade balance shows a positive trend and that the goal of a deficit of five percent of GDP appears achievable.</p>
<p>Masar said the NBS could lower minimum reserve requirements or soften foreign exchange position curbs which were implemented to curb foreign funds in local banking sector.</p>
<p>Analysts said the government will most likely ease budgetary pressures by cutting some of its ambitious spending plans, giving the NBS room to manoeuvre with its monetary policy.</p>
<p>Auto imports fell 45.0 percent, year-on-year, after the government re-installed a 17.5 percent duty on imports of new cars with bigger engines from the beginning of this year.</p>
<p>SUSR said exports totalled 69.517 billion crowns, an increase of 12.2 percent over January-March 1996.</p>
<p>Imports, led by a 36.3 percent rise in equipment and engines and a 19.0 percent rise in crude materials, rose by 10 percent year-on-year in the first two months of 1997, totalling 85.411 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Technological imports for upgrading the ageing Jaslovske Bohunice nuclear power plant and the completion of the Mochovce nuclear power plant also figured heavily into the deficit.</p>
<p>Metals, iron and rolled steel were the most important export, rising 3.8 percent year-on-year, while the fastest rising item on export side was automobiles, which were up 79.4 percent against January-March period of 1996.</p>
<p>The Czech Republic remained Slovakia's main trading partner, accounting for 28.2 percent of exports and 23.2 percent of imports.</p>
<p>Exports to Germany accounted for 24.5 percent, followed by Austria and Poland, with 6.2 and 5.7 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 421-7-521-8402</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
