<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55015" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. EIA sees winter fuels in short supply.</title>
<headline>U.S. EIA sees winter fuels in short supply.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. refiners are unlikely to be able to fill heating oil inventories ahead of this winter rapidly enough to avoid a steep price rise, Energy Information Administration chief Jay Hakes warned on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The high need for distillate in July (whether through U.S. demand or exports), coupled with only modest production, is giving rise to growing concerns over distillate stock levels for the upcoming winter,&quot; Hakes said in materials prepared for a presentation to the National Association of State Energy Officials.  </p>
<p>&quot;Colder weather kept stocks low through last winter, and they have still not recovered,&quot; Hakes said.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices this winter will likely be higher than prices last winter due both to higher crude oil prices and potentially stronger price spreads over the price of crude oil,&quot; EIA said.</p>
<p>At the end of August U.S. stocks were 21 million barrels or 16 percent lower than the five-year average for the month, and 20 million barrels of that deficit was on the East Coast, which makes up most of the U.S. winter heating fuel market.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is unlikely that the shortfall will be made up at this late date,&quot; according to the summary of key points Hakes was due to make at the state energy officials' annual meeting in Biloxi, Mississippi.</p>
<p>To raise stocks to more than 120 million barrels by the end of November, when inventories normally peak, distillate production would have to be strong, exports would have to be lower than normal and imports higher than normal, EIA said.</p>
<p>&quot;Relying on strong production and imports makes us much more vulnerable to price runups if any supply difficulties occur,&quot; EIA warned.  </p>
<p>The East Coast could not necessarily count on imports, because Europe would likely need all of its own supply for heating oil and new low sulfur diesel requirements.</p>
<p>&quot;Competition for available distillate supplies in the Atlantic Basin will likely be strong,&quot; Hakes said.</p>
<p>U.S. propane and natural gas stocks were also lower than normal for this time of year, according to EIA.</p>
<p>Propane inventories at the end of August were at a 25-year low and about 11 percent lower than last year.  </p>
<p>While natural gas storage had started low, inventories were rapidly being filled, and EIA expected them to reach about 2.7-2.8 trillion cubic feet by November 1.</p>
<p>Net withdrawals from natural gas storage over the last five winters had ranged from 1.8 to 2.3 Tcf, EIA said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
