<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550137" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - April 30.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - April 30.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Serbian and Montenegrin press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>			    - SERBIA -</p>
<p>POLITIKA</p>
<p>- European Union grants trade facilities to Yugoslavia in recognition for a series of moves by Belgrade towards democratisation and strengthening of peace in the region. The Yugoslav Foreign Ministry welcomed the decision as an important step towards the promotion and further development of cooperation.</p>
<p>- Restitution and denationalisation of property are a pre-condition for a just privatisation, says Miroljub Hadzic assistant to the Serbian Privatisation Minister.</p>
<p>- Pancevo petrochemical plant Petrohemija is building a new factory, equipment is supplied and financed by two Swiss factories.</p>
<p>- Serbian government submits draft law on concessions to parliament determining how rights will be granted to domestic and foreign firms for the use of natural resources and other public goods.</p>
<p>- Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic can run again in presidential elections because he did not use his first five-year mandate fully, says Serbian deputy prime minister Ratko Markovic.</p>
<p>- Opposition Serbian Renewal Movement (SPO) will start election campaign independently, says president Vuk Draskovic. President of Democratic Party (DS) Zoran Djindjic sees this as a move to leave opposition coalition Zajedno.</p>
<p>- Kosovo Albanian leaders expect to hold parliamentary and presidential elections for the self-proclaimed republic of Kosovo end of May or early June.</p>
<p>- Yugoslav-Albanian border is secure, says Yugoslav army.</p>
<p>- There will be no printing of money without cover, says Yugoslav National Bank Vice-governor Ratko Banovic.</p>
<p>- Spring sowing which was delayed by the weather is in full swing, says Serbian agriculture minister Jovan Babovic.</p>
<p>NASA BORBA</p>
<p>- Montenegrin parliament session set for May 16.</p>
<p>- Independent trade union Nezavisnost will organise a demonstration on Labour Day together with the student protest and the independent pensioner's association.</p>
<p>- Former Yugoslav Prime Minister and businessman Milan Panic accepts to take part in opposition coalition Zajedno.</p>
<p>- Serbian Deputy Prime Minister Ratko Markovic says Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic can run again for presidential elections. A third mandate would be in violation of the constitution, say Democratic Party president Zoran Djindjic and Civic Alliance top legal adviser Dragor Hiber.</p>
<p>- Yugoslavia faces a historic soccer match against Spain that will decide its participation in the world championship afer four-year international isolation.</p>
<p>VECERNJE NOVOSTI</p>
<p>- Yugoslavia's new president has to be elected by July 26 and Serbia's by December 20.</p>
<p>BORBA</p>
<p>- Acting President of the Serbian Chamber of Commerce Momir Pavlicevic says return of EU facilities to Yugoslavia is a big step forward for the domestic economy and expects exports to EU to be worth $1.5 billion this year, twice more than in 1996.</p>
<p>			     - MONTENEGRO -</p>
<p>POBJEDA</p>
<p>- Events in Montenegro and its ruling Democratic Party of Socialists created the impression that everything that happened is the result of a planned action to discipline the Montenegrin prime minister and his replacement, says Montenegrin Parliament Speaker Svetozar Marovic.</p>
<p>- Teachers' striking committee agrees with Education Minister Dragan Kujovic to halt strike.</p>
<p>- There are no more fractions in the People's Party, says president Novak Kilibarda.</p>
<p>MONITOR</p>
<p>- The majority of supporters of Prime Minister Milo Djukanovic outside the Democratic Party of Socialists do not support him for his commitment to the Serbian-Montenegrin federation but because of his government's reformist course, editorial.</p>
<p>- Podgorica medical school to enrol first students in autumn.</p>
<p>- An unnamed source says the Montenegrin government will set up a company putting airports of Tivat and Podgorica under its control. -- Belgrade newsroom + 381 11 222 4305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
