<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550244" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil real ends soft, drops 0.24 pct in April.</title>
<headline>Brazil real ends soft, drops 0.24 pct in April.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's real closed 1.0635 per dollar, down 0.07 percent on the day and 0.24 percent for the month in the commercial foreign exchange market, dealers said.</p>
<p>Earlier today the Central Bank depreciated the mini-band by 0.09 percent to between 1.0635 and 1.0685 reais per dollar. The mini-band was lowered 0.61 percent during April, compared with a decline of 0.57 percent in March.</p>
<p>The real's fall was smaller than the mini-band's depreciation because the local currency ended March a little lower than normal thanks to a low supply of dollars in the market at that time, dealers said.</p>
<p>During the last few days in April, dollar inflows increased and some banks decided to hold onto dollars to sell them today, the last day of the month, in order to arbitrage with them in the forex futures market, dealers said.</p>
<p>In the interbank floating rate market, the real closed at 1.0686 per greenback, down 0.09 percent on the day and 0.57 percent on the month.</p>
<p>In the parallel market, the real fell 0.44 percent in the day, closing at 1.137 per dollar, but rose 0.26 for the month.</p>
<p>((-- Alexandre Caverni, Sao Paulo newsroon, 55 11 2485418))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
