<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550295" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico sets up new anti-drug agency. [CORRECTED 00:38 GMT 1/5]</title>
<headline>Mexico sets up new anti-drug agency. [CORRECTED 00:38 GMT 1/5]</headline>
<byline>Dan Trotta</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico said on Wednesday it had scrapped its top anti-drug agency, tarnished by scandal, and replaced it with a new body of highly trained agents who will be checked rigorously for drug use and corruption.</p>
<p>Attorney General Jorge Madrazo Cuellar told a news conference the new agency, the Special Prosecutor's Office for Crimes Against Health, would begin work immediately. Drug trafficking offences are termed crimes against health in Mexico.</p>
<p>The new agency replaces the National Institute for Drug Combat (INCD), which was created just four years ago amid great fanfare by former president Carlos Salinas de Gortari.</p>
<p>(Corrects year agency founded.)</p>
<p>The INCD, an arm of the Attorney General's Office, fell under a cloud when its chief, Gen. Jesus Gutierrez Rebollo, was arrested in February and charged with taking bribes from Mexico's most wanted drug lord, Amado Carrillo Fuentes. Recognising the high level of corruption and inefficiency within the Attorney General's Office (PGR), Madrazo said this was a first step toward a comprehensive &quot;reorganization, purification and cleaning up of the institution.&quot; &quot;The fundamental objective of the reform...consists of replacing the INCD...and the creation in its place of the Special Prosecutor's Office for Crimes Against Health as a centralized organ of the Attorney General's Office,&quot; Madrazo said.</p>
<p>The announcement came five days before U.S. President Bill Clinton was due to arrive in Mexico for a visit that will include discussions on fighting drugs.</p>
<p>Washington has applied heavy pressure on Mexico in recent years to root out drug corruption and stop narcotics smuggling across the border. But despite constant pledges and new programmes, anti-drug agents say the flow of cocaine, marijuana and heroin continues hardly checked.</p>
<p>Madrazo vigorously denied the steps taken on Wednesday were a concession to the United States, saying the process began when he was named to his post on Dec. 2, two months before Clinton's visit was announced.</p>
<p>&quot;It has absolutely nothing to do with the bilateral relationship,&quot; Madrazo said.</p>
<p>Claiming the changes were more than cosmetic, Madrazo said the main difference between the new organisation and the INCD was that potential agents would be subjected to a vigorous battery of tests before being hired and would receive constant and intense training to assure professionalism.</p>
<p>They would also receive handsome salary and benefits packages in the hope they would resist the temptation of bribes, he said.</p>
<p>U.S. anti-drug officials claim international drug traffickers spend $6 billion a year bribing Mexican officials for safe passage of their illicit cargo, this in a country where constant small bribes to policemen and minor officials are an institution.</p>
<p>Agents of the notoriously corrupt PGR, the INCD, the army and others are welcome to apply for work with the new agency, Madrazo said, but will come under scrutiny that will include home visits and background checks to guard against corruption.</p>
<p>Madrazo said of 107 applicants who have taken the entrance exams, which include drug and psychological tests, 60 passed. &quot;This means that 60 people will initiate this basic cell, this new group, for the fight against drugs,&quot; Madrazo said. The INCD had about 1,200 agents.</p>
<p>Madrazo told reporters the new anti-drug organisation would be headed by Mariano Herran Salvatti, the career prosecutor who replaced Gutierrez Rebollo at the INCD.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
