<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550308" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian rebels said to suffer heavy casualties.</title>
<headline>Colombian rebels said to suffer heavy casualties.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's leading leftist rebel group has suffered heavy casualties in fighting that has raged since Sunday in a mountainous area just east of Bogota, authorities said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The guerrillas have had numerous casualties, you can count about 50 between the dead and wounded,&quot; Gen. Humberto Uscategui Ramirez, commander of the 7th Army Brigade, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The rebels have been carrying off their dead and wounded on more than 20 mules,&quot; he added, saying the casualties were being ferried from the combat zone outside the small town of Medina into the rugged Cordillera Oriental mountain chain.</p>
<p>Medina is located in the foothills of the Andean mountains, about 40 miles (70 km) east of Bogota.</p>
<p>Army troops backed by helicopter gunships and air force bombers have been battling two separate columns of Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) rebels in the rural outskirts of Medina since Sunday.</p>
<p>Uscategui said &quot;intense&quot; combat continued in the area on Wednesday but he declined further comment, saying only that no more than four soldiers had been killed so far.</p>
<p>There was no independent confirmation of the rebel casualty toll. But Uscategui's remarks appeared to indicate that government forces in and around Medina had dealt the FARC its worst defeat in any single combat zone in months.</p>
<p>Military sources said last week that at least 50 soliders and 140 guerrillas had died in fighting across the country during the first three months of the year.</p>
<p>The FARC. which evolved from peasant militias in 1948, was officially formed as a pro-Soviet group in 1964 and is considered Latin America's largest and oldest guerrilla group.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
