<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550368" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News - May 1.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News - May 1.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Government and industry sources confirmed yesterday the Australia Pacific Airports Corp - a consortium of the British Airports Authority, AMP and Axiom Funds Management - and the Amsterdam Schiphol-Commonweatlh Bank consortium are hot favourites to win the rights to purchase the Melbourne and Brisbane airports respectively. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Addressing the Committee for the Economic Development of Australia yesterday, Brierley Investments chairman Bob Matthew said the Howard Government has achieved an &quot;as yet uninspiring rate of progress on economic reform&quot;. Matthew criticised the Federal Goernment's policy limiting foreign ownership of the Fairfax newspaper group to 25 per cent. Page 4.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a move that increased tensions between the Federal and Queensland Governments, Prime Minister John Howard yesterday suggested that the work of the Queensland Government under Premier Rob Borbidge, rather than any Wik backlash, would be to blame for anyloss of voter support in the State. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The powerful Queensland Mining Council is outraged by comments made by Queensland Premier Rob Borbidge, who suggested the mining industry's preference in the Wik debate was for legislative extinguishment of native title. The Council claims it has been misepresented. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard said yesterday he realises Australians are feeling insecure and uncertain, and said this was the reason behind the increasing support for Independent MP Pauline Hanson's One Nation party. However, Howard dismissed claims by Quensland Premier Rob Borbidge that Hanson's supporters are former supporters of the Coalition. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard yesterday denied any deals involving Australia's cross-media ownership rules had been struck to allow media magnate Kerry Packer to takeover the Fairfax newspaper group. While Howard was careful not to commit to any position, i seems the media rules will be &quot;relaxed&quot; to allow Packer's deal to go ahead. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australia's biggest investor, the AMP Society, yesterday committed to a A$12 billion stock market listing by the second half of next year that will see its 2.2 million policy holders receive a cash return of about A$5,000 each. As part of its transformaton, AMP will also diversify into banking. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Outgoing Victorian Governor Richard McGarvie has warned Australian democracy will face problems if the president of a Republic is elected by either Parliament or the people. He says the debate over the Republic appears to have &quot;lost its way&quot; by neglectin fundamental democratic safeguards. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>As Prime Minister John Howard yesterday defended BHP's decision to shut down its Newcastle steelworks, unions, the State Governments, and even the Coalition back bench pressured the Federal Government to take a more active stance on industry policy.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>New South Wales Police Royal Commission Justice James Wood says the legal profession must investigate the roles lawyers are playing in protecting corruption in the State. In his first interview since the Commission began, Wood admitted the task of the Comission was more difficult than he had expected. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Strong property and share markets have contributed A$500 million to the New South Wales Government, allowing it to deliver its second successive Budget surplus and feed further money into hospitals and education. However, next Tuesday's State Budget will see a rise in taxes and charges to cover a A$430 million spending blowout. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Under a plan yet to become public, the Waste Service will close the controversial Castlereagh toxic waste tip in December by fast-tracing a A$15 million expansion of its hazardous waste facility in the heart of the site of the Sydney Olympics. The closure of the plant comes despite the fact the plant is facing prosecution in the Land and Environment Court. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Under a decision believed to have been made in the last two days, AMP Society and British airport company BAA plc will purchase Melbourne Airport in a deal worth more than A$1.3 billion. The deal will see Tullamarine in private hands by the middle of theyear, and will mean more shops and industrial development for the airport. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A study commissioned by the City of Melbourne has found Melbourne's Queen Victoria Market should pick up A$15.7 million in extra business by 2000 on the back of the opening of the Crown Casino. However, the study added that the western end of the city cold develop into a seedy red light district. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>It has been revealed former Victorian Health Minister Marie Tehan was advised by a senior officer in her department, Jennifer Williams, to hold an inquiry into the ambulance service's contact for a computer dispatch system with Intergraph as far back as Nvember 1993. Williams' memo followed complaints by a competing firm for the lucrative deal. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian Council of Social Service will be using the latest full employment figures, to be released before the Federal Budget, to lobby the Federal Government to fulfil its promise of creating &quot;real&quot; jobs for Australia. ACOSS said the Budget needed to produce action, otherwise Australia would suffer from a new wave of city poverty, long-term unemployment, and a new era of the working poor. Page 3.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
