<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550427" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China bans Zhang Yimou film from Cannes.</title>
<headline>China bans Zhang Yimou film from Cannes.</headline>
<byline>Benjamin Kang Lim</byline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>China has banned the latest movie by internationally acclaimed Chinese director Zhang Yimou from competing in the Cannes film festival, industry sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The Ministry of Radio, Film and Television and the Film Bureau will not allow Zhang Yimou's 'Keep Cool' to be sent to Cannes,&quot; a film industry source told Reuters.</p>
<p>There was no official explanation for the ban on the film, which is competing for the Golden Palm award at the Cannes festival in France on May 7-18.</p>
<p>Zhang and film officials could not immediately be reached for comment.</p>
<p>&quot;Keep Cool&quot; is a comedy about a man who falls in love with a woman and is beaten up by her business associates.</p>
<p>It was not known if the film's makers would find a way to circumvent the ban and compete.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be sent to Cannes through other channels even without government permission,&quot; the film industry source said.</p>
<p>&quot;Zhang Yimou has not made up his mind yet whether to send the film to Cannes or not,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>A second source said Zhang was unlikely to send the state-financed film to Cannes and risk the ire of China's film officials because &quot;Keep Cool&quot; had already been approved for local screening.</p>
<p>Another film industry expert said the film may have been withdrawn because it was thought unlikely to win.</p>
<p>It is not Zhang's first brush with Chinese officials, who frown on independent-minded film-makers.</p>
<p>Chinese authorities have criticised previous films by Zhang, who first triumphed in the West in 1988 with &quot;Red Sorghum&quot;, for portraying China as backward in films for Western audiences.</p>
<p>Zhang's tale of four concubines, &quot;Raise the Red Lantern&quot;, took the Silver Lion award at Venice in 1991 and was nominated for an Oscar as best foreign film.</p>
<p>Judges at Cannes showered honours on Zhang's &quot;To Live&quot; in 1994. Ge You won the best actor award for his role in the film, which tracks the sorrows and struggles of a family through the upheavals that followed the 1949 Communist revolution.</p>
<p>But Chinese censors did not like &quot;To Live&quot; and refused to allow Zhang to attend the Cannes festival after the movie was shown there without their permission.</p>
<p>As punishment, Zhang was told all his future films must be entirely produced and funded in China, where money is scarce and technology backward.</p>
<p>Chinese authorities told Zhang not to attend the New York Film Festival in 1995 where his film &quot;Shanghai Triad&quot; was chosen for the coveted opening slot at the event. Beijing was angered after the festival showed a documentary about the bloody 1989 crackdown on student-led pro-democracy demonstrations.</p>
<p>Chinese newspapers have accused Zhang and some other award-winning film directors of pandering to international judges.</p>
<p>China's movie mandarins have axed a number of controversial films in recent months as part of a crusade to resurrect socialist ethics, or &quot;spiritual civilisation&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
