<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550539" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Israeli woman stabbed in Jordan, lightly wounded.</title>
<headline>Israeli woman stabbed in Jordan, lightly wounded.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Israeli woman was stabbed in northern Jordan by an &quot;unbalanced man&quot; on Wednesday but was only lightly wounded, officials said.</p>
<p>A doctor at the Yarmouk Health Centre near the city of Irbid said the 30-year-old woman was treated for a knife wound in the stomach but was released after less than an hour.</p>
<p>He said the incident took place near the popular tourist site of Umm Queis, an old Roman city overlooking the Sea of Galilee and the Golan Heights.</p>
<p>Umm Qeis is just a few km (miles) from the border area of Baqoura, leased to Israel under a 1994 peace treaty, where a Jordanian soldier shot dead seven Israeli schoolgirls in March.</p>
<p>Information Minister Samir Mutawae said the woman was attacked after she became separated from a group of Israeli tourists. After treatment she was well enough to enjoy an impromptu lunch with Jordan's Tourism Minister Aqel Beltaji, he said.</p>
<p>He said the attacker had been apprehended and would be charged.</p>
<p>&quot;An unbalanced man tried to hurt her. I don't think he knew she was an Israeli,&quot; Mutawae told Reuters. &quot;It was superficial (and) she continued her journey and had lunch with the minister of tourism.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
