<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550538" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish sect members get three year jail terms.</title>
<headline>Turkish sect members get three year jail terms.</headline>
<byline>Elif Unal</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Turkish court sentenced 113 Islamist sect members to three years in prison on Wednesday for challenging the official secularist order, judge Orhan Karadeniz said.</p>
<p>&quot;They were sentenced for being a member of an illegal organisation against the constitutional system,&quot; said Cuneyt Toraman, a defence lawyer.</p>
<p>The Islamists, members of the esoteric Aczmendi sect, had been charged with forming an illegal group, insulting Turkey's secularist founder Mustafa Kemal Ataturk and breaking a ban on Islamic dress.</p>
<p>The court sentenced 113 of the sect members to three years each in jail, six of the defendants to four years and three to 20 months, the court said.</p>
<p>One defendant was acquitted, the trial of another two was continuing and three more were to be tried by another court.</p>
<p>The military-dominated National Security Council has ordered Turkey's Islamist-led government to crack down on religious activism, including the secretive Moslem sects or brotherhood.</p>
<p>A small number of relatives of the Aczimendi defendants showed their disappointment and sadness at the verdict outside the courtroom.</p>
<p>&quot;This is unjust, I hope those who reached this verdict will face the same injustice for their children one day,&quot; said one relative. Police tried to calm the quietly protesting relatives and asked them to leave the court building.</p>
<p>Only one defendant, in a long blue shirt and baggy trousers, appeared in the courtroom. The others stayed away after an earlier court demand that they refrain from wearing their characteristic dark flowing robes and turbans.</p>
<p>The court last month imposed a nominal fine on the Aczmendi defendants for wearing their religious clothes at the trial rather than the western-style clothes generally worn in Turkey.</p>
<p>The Aczmendis grow long hair wrapped in turbans and carry staffs in what they say is imitation of the Prophet Mohammad. They were detained at a rowdy ceremony in Ankara last year in which they clashed with police.</p>
<p>They were also accused of insulting the founder of modern Turkey, Mustafa Kemal Ataturk, during &quot;zikr&quot;, a ceremony at which sect members dance themselves into a frenzy.</p>
<p>Ataturk outlawed Islamic sects in the 1920s but the groups have quietly flourished again in recent years.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, a senior general said the army's fight with Islamists was a matter of &quot;life or death&quot; for Turkey.</p>
<p>Turkey's first Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan came to power last June at the head of a coalition with conservatives. However, the form of Islam he represents is far milder than that of the Aczmendis.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
