<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550541" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turk opposition leave anti-Islamist fight to army.</title>
<headline>Turk opposition leave anti-Islamist fight to army.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Bell</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's divided opposition was at odds on Wednesday over plans to topple the Islamist-led government, leaving a growing campaign against religious activists to the acsendant security apparatus.</p>
<p>Main opposition leader Mesut Yilmaz rejected a challenge from Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan to settle a dispute over the role of Islam at the ballot box.</p>
<p>&quot;Elections are the last resort in a democracy...all the alternatives have not been exhausted in this parliament,&quot; Anatolian news agency quoted Yilmaz as telling MPs from his conservative Motherland Party.</p>
<p>Ankara state security court was not so hesitant to take on Islamists. A panel of three judges, including a military officer, jailed more than 100 Moslem sect members for three years for challenging the secularist order.</p>
<p>&quot;They were sentenced for being members of an illegal organisation against the constitutional system,&quot; said Cuneyt Toraman, a defence lawyer.</p>
<p>The accused, members of the esoteric Aczmendi sect, had been charged with forming an illegal group, insulting Turkey's secularist founder Kemal Ataturk and wearing Islamic dress.</p>
<p>Aczmendis, whose brand of Islam is much more severe than that of Erbakan and most Turks, grow long hair wrapped in turbans and carry staffs in what they say is imitation of the Prophet Mohammad.</p>
<p>They were detained at a rowdy ceremony in Ankara last year after a clash with police.</p>
<p>A senior general said on Tuesday that stamping out Islamists was a matter of &quot;life or death&quot; for republican Turkey.</p>
<p>Erbakan, modern Turkey's first Islamist leader, has indicated he was in favour of early polls to let the nation be the judge of that.</p>
<p>But Yilmaz, a former prime minister, said the electoral system would favour Erbakan's Islam-based Welfare Party.</p>
<p>&quot;Going to elections with today's election law, population count and voting districts would be sabotaging democracy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Welfare narrowly won polls in late 1995 with 21 percent of the vote and rules in coalition with pro-Western secularist Tansu Ciller's True Path Party.</p>
<p>Analysts say the Islamists' slice of the vote may have increased since the last polls but figures are hard to come by.</p>
<p>Veteran left-wing leader Bulent Ecevit acknowledged that Yilmaz had only loosely agreed to a plan to replace Erbakan's shaky administration with a secularist alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;Yilmaz found the idea of a broad-based government too ambitious,&quot; Ecevit told MPs from his Democratic Left Party.</p>
<p>He also said leftist rival Deniz Baykal had not given a clear reply in a round of talks on Tuesday to his call for a shadow government that would oust Erbakan without elections.</p>
<p>Economic analysts say the Turkish markets fear snap polls more than a swift solution to the crisis through parliamentary wranglings.</p>
<p>Stocks in Istanbul were down 0.56 percent at Wednesday's close but trading was light. Brokers said many investors have run for the sidelines amid mounting uncertainty.</p>
<p>Turkey was without a proper government for nine months until Welfare stepped in last June.</p>
<p>The military has toppled three governments in the last 37 years but it has said it will not stage a coup this time around for fear of upsetting NATO member Turkey's Western allies.</p>
<p>In the last week, police have closed dozens of unlicensed illegal religious education centres and Ankara state security court put a top Moslem preacher close to Welfare on trial for allegedly advocating harsh Islamic rule in Turkey.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
