<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55066" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: General Mills Q1 worldwide unit volume up.</title>
<headline>General Mills Q1 worldwide unit volume up.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Mills Inc said Monday its worldwide unit volume grew four percent in the first quarter ended August 25.</p>
<p>In the United States, total domestic unit volume rose three percent in the quarter. This followed an 11 percent gain in U.S. volume in the fourth quarter of fiscal 1996 that included shipments supporting early June merchandising programs built around the company's sponsorship of the U.S. Olympic team, General Mills added.  </p>
<p>General Mills said quarterly market shares increased for most of its major businesses.</p>
<p>Big G cereal volume grew nearly four percent in the quarter, and its market share measured in pounds grew by more than one percentage point to 23.7 percent.</p>
<p>General Mills said Frosted Cheerios and extensions of its Wheaties line introduced in 1996 performed well, and additional volume was generated by its special Team USA Cheerios introduced as part of its Olympics sponsorship.</p>
<p>It added that overall cereal category volume grew 2.1 percent in the quarter, measuring sales in all outlets.  </p>
<p>General Mills said its Helper dinner mixes recorded a 12 percent volume gain and a two point market share increase for the first quarter. Yogurt volume grew 13 percent, with combined market share for its Yoplait and Colombo products setting a record of nearly 24 percent.</p>
<p>The new line of Betty Crocker Sweet Rewards reduced-fat and fat-free dessert mixes and continued strength of Whipped Deluxe ready-to-spread frosting drove six percent volume growth and a one point increase in market share for Betty Crocker desserts, the company added.  </p>
<p>It added that, as expected, snacks volume was five percent below last year's first quarter, which included unusually strong back-to-school merchandising.</p>
<p>General Mills said second quarter snack volume should be strong, including the launch of Golden Grahams Treats snack bars, with combined snacks volume for the first half expected to exceed last year.</p>
<p>Among other new products, the previously announced Betty Crocker Cinnamon Streusel and Dutch Apple cereals began shipping September 16, General Mills said. The new French Toast Crunch cereal is being introduced to the trade for shipment beginning in mid-October.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
