<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550664" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Year 1999 seen as time to test for year 2000 bugs.</title>
<headline>Year 1999 seen as time to test for year 2000 bugs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. securities industry is aiming to have computer overhauls ready for testing in the year 1999 as Wall Street gets ready to meet the challenge of the year 2000 date, Michael Tiernan, vice president of information technology at Credit Suisse First Boston told a panel Wednesday.</p>
<p>Tiernan, who heads the Securities Industry Association's (SIA) Data Management Division Year 2000 Committee said if three months of tests begin in March, 1999, that would leave six months to deal with whatever contingencies come up.</p>
<p>Tiernan and other speakers on the panel, part of a week-long Reuters World '97 event sponsored by Reuters Holdings Plc warned that the &quot;millennium bug&quot; that business and govrnment are working feverishly to exterminate has the potential to be a very serious problem.</p>
<p>Richard Hunter, research director for applications development technologies at Gartner Group Inc, said the cost of dealing with the bug is likely to be in the $300-$600 billion range worldwide.</p>
<p>He said a recent report by Gartner, a research group, showed that only one of every eight companies surveyed has a plan in place for dealing with the issue.</p>
<p>But the panelists said not only must companies work to get their own systems ready for 2000 but they must make sure anybody with whom they exchange data is also prepared.</p>
<p>&quot;The industry is completely connected,&quot; said Maggie Parent, a principal with Morgan Stanley Group Inc. She noted that Wall Street firms have computers which are inter-connected with those of counter-parties in trading, custodian banks, and others.</p>
<p>Henry Guttman, an attorney with Simpson Thacher &amp; Bartlett, said while lawsuits would be inevitable if there are failures and people suffer economic injury, his &quot;business advice&quot; was that companies and their suppliers work in a spirit of &quot;cooperative efforts&quot; and &quot;shared understanding.&quot;</p>
<p>David Ure, executive director for global technical development and strategy at Reuters, said his company is thinking about an inititaive for clients that might be called &quot;millennium checks.&quot; He said while clients would pay for it, Reuters was not viewing it as a &quot;revenue opportunity.&quot;</p>
<p>He also said Reuters has not given an estimate of what it will spend to deal with the millennium bug.</p>
<p>Hunter said that lately a &quot;six-digit&quot; solution has been becoming &quot;increasingly common&quot; in part because it is viewed as less expensive.</p>
<p>He said by remaining with a six-digit date the actual information stored on databases will not be modified, but instead logic will be inserted into the programs using the data to interpret it and treat as if it were an eight-digit date. But he said $300 billion is the still the &quot;rock bottom&quot; estimate of what it will cost to get computers ready for the millennium.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
