<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550772" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX crude ends off after bearish PDVSA comments.</title>
<headline>NYMEX crude ends off after bearish PDVSA comments.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX crude ended lower Wednesday after a top official at Venezuela's state oil company renewed his country's call for a change in the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries' (OPEC) quota system.</p>
<p>&quot;We were running out of steam especially at the last half hour of trade. It was probably a combination of the products expiry and the comments made by PDVSA,&quot; said Tom Bentz, analyst with ING Derivatives in New York.</p>
<p>May heating oil ended 0.84 cent a gallon lower at 58.07 cents. June crude ended 23 cents a barrel lower at $20.21.  </p>
<p>May gasoline bucked declines, settling 0.55 cent up at 63.91 cents a gallon, though still off its session high of 64.50 cents.</p>
<p>Heating oil ended its six session winning streak as the expiry in the May refined product contract forced traders with long positions to roll into the June contract.</p>
<p>&quot;When the products turned around, and gasoline failed to hold its gains, crude just followed along with it. But, it's important to note that heat did not give up all its gains leading up to the expiry,&quot; said Jim Fiedler, trader with E. D. &amp; F. Man International Inc in New York.</p>
<p>Prompt heating oil had risen 3.55 cents in the last six sessions amid tight supply in the New York Harbor.</p>
<p>Juan Szabo, exploration and production coordinator for Petroleos de Venezuela SA (PDVSA), said OPEC needs to consider production from non-OPEC countries and the effect of increasing worldwide demand, when it sets quotas for its members.</p>
<p>&quot;Everytime OPEC makes a reduction in quotas, someone else puts production on the market,&quot; he said at a conference in Houston. &quot;Logic says if you have a growth of demand, by logic the quota system is not effective.&quot;</p>
<p>Prompt gasoline held onto positive territory after the U.S. Department of Energy's (DOE) Energy Information Administration (EIA) said Wednesday that for the week ended April 25 reformulated gasoline (RFG) stocks, the gasoline deliverable against the NYMEX contract, declined 1.7 million barrels.</p>
<p>The American Petroleum Institute (API) said in its own report Tuesday that RFG stocks dropped 2.0 million barrels in the Northeast, the primary RFG market.</p>
<p>-- Harry Milling, New York Energy Desk, 212-859-1761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
