<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550813" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OPTIONS - FX vols stagnant as dlr stalls near highs.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - FX vols stagnant as dlr stalls near highs.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatilities for dollar-pair options were stagnant in U.S. trading as the greenback's early rally fizzled out a little short of recent highs, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone is basically dollar-bullish, but there's so much concern about political factors that they can't keep on buying at the higher end,&quot; said Kyoko Hiramatsu, a senior dealer at Bank of Yokohama in New York. &quot;There's so much temptation to take profit.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar was circling the 127-yen area in mid-afternoon U.S. trading, just below its mid-April high near 127.20.  </p>
<p>One-month dollar/yen implied volatility stood at 8.5/8.7 percent, up 0.1 point from late Tuesday. Risk reversals, the put/call pricing differential, were steady at around par.</p>
<p>Traders said one of the dampers on volatilities was a huge reverse knock-out option -- some $2.5 billion worth, according to some accounts -- with a barrier price of around 127.40 yen that expires on Thursday. Such exotic options tend to supply gamma to the interbank community and prompt selling in short-dated options.</p>
<p>&quot;There seems to be a lot of long-gamma positions out there,&quot; said a U.S. bank trader in California.  </p>
<p>The California trader noted, however, that the exotic option's expiration at 1000 EDT/1400 GMT on Thursday could remove the downward pressure and lead to a spike up in dollar/yen.</p>
<p>That was a distinct possibility, particularly with the April U.S. employment report due out Friday, agreed Hiramatsu at Bank of Yokohama.</p>
<p>&quot;People who had been selling the dollar to defend the trigger level could start buying back,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Dollar/mark volatilities were flat as the dollar was stayed below Monday's 37-month high of 1.7389 marks.  </p>
<p>One-month dollar/mark volatility was pegged at 8.4/8.6 percent, virtually unchanged. Risk reversals were also steady, with one-month 25-delta 0.1/0.4 point skewed toward mark puts.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, sterling volatilities looked hapless despite Thursday's U.K. general elections.</p>
<p>&quot;One-week is better bid than a few days ago, of course, but 8-1/4 percent is not what you would consider a very firm volatility for a country that's going into elections,&quot; the California trader said.</p>
<p>One-week cable volatility stood at 7.7/8.7 percent and one-month at 7.4/7.7, both marginally above Tuesday's levels.  </p>
<p>&quot;Cable (spot) yesterday went up to $1.6330 and this morning we came down to $1.6185, so that's giving us something like 12-percent in intraday volatility,&quot; he said, adding that he thought cable options looked undervalued.</p>
<p>He also noted that the $1.62-area had proved to be a strong support level for sterling and a declining trendline came in in the lower-$1.63 area.</p>
<p>&quot;We're forming some kind of a triangle in technicals,&quot; he said. &quot;We could see some action if Labor actually wins (in the elections).&quot;</p>
<p>-- Shin Kishima/Chicago Derivatives Desk ((312-408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
