<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="551071" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French shares close up 1.41 pct, Rhone jumps.</title>
<headline>French shares close up 1.41 pct, Rhone jumps.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>French shares closed sharply higher on Wednesday in big volume boosted by options expiry after it shrugged off a decline in the afternoon on stronger than expected U.S. economic growth.</p>
<p>The Bourse, which is closed on Thursday for the May Day holiday, started with a 1.47 percent gain, building on Tuesday's two percent advance due to a jump on Wall Street as data on labour costs and durable goods dispelled inflation fears.</p>
<p>But a rise in first quarter U.S. GDP, the biggest rise for more than nine years, pulled shares back to trade nearly flat in the afternoon.  </p>
<p>Wall Street's early advances, a strong dollar and comments by U.S Commerce Under Secretary Everett Ehrlich that there was no sign of inflation, helped shartes.</p>
<p>The CAC-40 index closed up 1.41 percent at 2639.46, a rise of 36.60 points, but remained below the opening high of 2,641.18. April CAC-40 futures were 16.5 points higher at 2,621.5. Volume was 9.6 billion francs of which 7.4 billion was in CAC-40 stocks.</p>
<p>* Rhone-Poulenc was the star of the day. It closed up 4.47 percent at 196.30 francs, below an opening jump of 9.1 percent.  </p>
<p>The company reported a 6.5 percent rise in first quarter net income -- one of the first French companies to issue their 1997 first quarter data -- which was in line with expectations.</p>
<p>The market was impressed by the company sticking to its forecast of a 20 percent increase in 1997 earnings per share, before exceptionals, despite the costs of a recall at its Cention unit. These costs are likely to be exceptional charges.</p>
<p>Paribas maintained its strong buy on Rhone-Poulenc and Cheuvreux de Virieu put Rhone on its recommended list, dropping Legrand, down 0.91 percent at 985 francs.  </p>
<p>* Sommer-Allibert, up 0.73 percent at 1,379 francs saw more than two percent of its share capital change hands after a series of block trades in the morning.</p>
<p>* Online information service provider Infonie, down 27.01 percent at 100 francs, tumbled on an unexpectedly large 1996 loss and a planned capital increase.</p>
<p>* Pinault-Printemps,up 2.21 percent at 2,455, said its first quarter shares were 5.9 percent up.</p>
<p>* GAN fell 3.5 percent at 138 francs in the second day after it reported a bigger than expected 5.7 billion francs 1996 loss. The share had already lost five percent on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>* Groupe Paribas rose 0.03 percent to close at 368.10 francs a share after several block trades involving more than three million shares were made following Tuesday's close, market sources said.</p>
<p>Traders said the deal could be linked to the tax credit for the 1996 dividend which goes ex-dividend on May 5.</p>
<p>There have also been market rumours Paribas could undergo a financial restructuring, merge with Cie Bancaire or carry out some other major transaction to finance a big overseas acquisition.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
