<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="551010" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Le Pen to stage May Day rally, seek influence vote. [CORRECTED 23:28 GMT]</title>
<headline>Le Pen to stage May Day rally, seek influence vote. [CORRECTED 23:28 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Alister Doyle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Far-right French leader Jean-Marie Le Pen leads a May Day rally of his anti-immigrant party in Paris on Thursday (corrects from Wednesday) seeking to influence a snap parliamentary election in which he will not run.</p>
<p>France's three biggest unions, deeply at odds on issues like a single European currency and the need for economic reforms, also plan a ragged display of unity with their first Labour Day march in the capital in 14 years.</p>
<p>The unions, two of which brought France to a virtual standstill with 24 days of strikes in late 1995, plan to denounce record unemployment and racism before the May 25-June 1 election to the National Assembly.</p>
<p>National Front leader Le Pen, who wants to deport three million immigrants, will give a speech at the Paris Opera at midday (1000 GMT) to rally his supporters and commemorate one of the Front's symbols, 15th century heroine Joan of Arc.</p>
<p>So far the election campaign has been largely polarised between the centre-right coalition of Prime Minister Alain Juppe and the opposition Socialists led by Lionel Jospin -- with Le Pen seizing few headlines with his xenophobic extremism.</p>
<p>The 68-year-old former parachutist said on Wednesday night he would not run in the election, in which opinion polls show that his party can expect to win a handful of seats at best even though it has support from about 15 percent of voters.</p>
<p>Le Pen, denying he feared he would lose authority if he ran and failed to win, accused conservative President Jacques Chirac of trying to muzzle spreading political sleaze scandals by calling the election almost 10 months early.</p>
<p>He said Chirac should resign if the centre-right coalition lost. &quot;I will not present myself for legislative elections, thinking that I will have better things to do in preparing for possible presidential elections,&quot; Le Pen said.</p>
<p>Chirac has ruled out resigning before the end of his seven-year term in 2002 even if the left wins.</p>
<p>Even though he will not run, Le Pen's followers will influence the outcome as swing voters in many districts on the second round.</p>
<p>Under France's voting system, candidates win a seat outright if they get 50 percent of the vote on May 25. If no one does, candidates with 12.5 percent or more go on to the June 1 run-off.</p>
<p>Le Pen paid a backhanded compliment to Jospin, defeated by Chirac in the 1995 presidential election. &quot;The policies led by Mr Chirac have probably been worse than those Mr Jospin might have had,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The remark echoed comments during the 1995 election, when Le Pen gave his supporters no recommendations on how to vote in the run-off and himself voted blank. Le Pen opposes a single European currency, saying it threatens the very existence of France.</p>
<p>The union march is backed by the national leadership of the pro-Socialist CFDT and the Communist-led CGT but merely by the Paris branch of the independent Force Ouvriere (FO).</p>
<p>FO leader Marc Blondel, who planned to march instead in the south-western city of Bordeaux, said the planned march was &quot;more to do with politics than unions&quot; and said he did not share the same views as either the CGT or the CFDT.</p>
<p>The FO and the CGT spearheaded the crippling 24-day wave of strikes in late 1995, mainly triggered by health care curbs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
