<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="551122" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Grasim faces shrinking margins.</title>
<headline>India's Grasim faces shrinking margins.</headline>
<byline>Ranjit Gangadharan</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The profit growth of diversified Grasim Industries Ltd in 1997/98 (April-March) is likely to be hurt by shrinking margins, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;With bleak business prospects in its cement and steel businesses, we do not see the company's performance improving significantly in the first half of 1997/98,&quot; Rajesh Mayani, analyst at James Capel B&amp;K said.</p>
<p>An analyst at a European securities firm said weak commodity prices would hamper profit growth at Grasim, flagship firm of the Aditya Birla group.</p>
<p>World prices of viscose staple fibre (VSF), a textile raw material, had risen 5-8 percent recently but Grasim had little room to raise its own prices due to sluggish domestic demand, analysts said.</p>
<p>Grasim is one of the world's biggest producers of VSF. It also makes cement, sponge iron and caustic soda.</p>
<p>However, the company said it expected an improved performance in 1997/98.</p>
<p>&quot;The company expects better performance in 1997/98 both in terms of sales turnover and profitability,&quot; Grasim said.</p>
<p>&quot;The optimism stems from the company's multipronged efforts towards modernisation, expansion and taking care of infrastructural contingencies across major divisions,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>The firm said on Wednesday its net profits fell to 2.74 billion rupees ($76.62 million) in the year ended March 31, 1997, from 3.32 billion rupees a year ago.</p>
<p>Analysts attributed the fall to poor demand for VSF, cement and sponge iron, as well as production disruptions and higher costs.</p>
<p>Consensus estimates in a Reuters poll of analysts had placed net profit at 2.99 billion rupees for 1996/97.</p>
<p>Profits would have been even worse if not for 600 million rupees in capital gains arising from the sale of investments, an analyst with a European securities firm said.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected income from other sources to be halved to one billion rupees but the capital gains boosted it to 1.53 billion rupees in 1996/97. Other income was 2.11 billion rupees in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Shortages of water and electricity hampered the company's operations. VSF output fell to 155,385 tonnes in 1996/97 from 162,470 tonnes a year earlier due to a water shortage caused by late monsoon rains, which resulted in the loss of 46 production days.</p>
<p>In response, the company has set up a reservoir at its Nagda plant in central Madhya Pradesh state.</p>
<p>VSF accounts for 60 percent of Grasim's profits and 40 percent of total sales.</p>
<p>Grasim expects in the third quarter of 1997 to commission a 30,000 tonnes-a-year VSF plant in western Gujarat state. The plant will eventually have a capacity to produce 60,000 tonnes annually and will generate all of its own power.</p>
<p>Production of cement rose 25.4 percent to 4.1 million tonnes in 1996/97 from 3.27 million tonnes a year ago, but price realisations were lower.</p>
<p>Analysts expect little improvement in cement realisations during 1997/98 because of oversupply, especially in the regions where Grasim's plants are located.</p>
<p>Output of sponge iron jumped 103.3 percent to 706,510 tonnes against 347,513 tonnes in a shutdown-marred 1995/96. Analysts said the plant's capacity was 750,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Grasim raised $90 million and $100 million, respectively, in 1992 and 1994 through global depositary receipt issues overseas, but a third issue for $125 million had to be called off in 1996/97 due to poor market conditions.</p>
<p>($1.0=35.76 rupees)</p>
<p>--Bombay newsroom +91-22-265-9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I26000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
