<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="551415" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cincinnati Purchasing Managers say April growth up.</title>
<headline>Cincinnati Purchasing Managers say April growth up.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Cincinnati chapter of the National Association of Purchasing Management said on Wednesday its April report showed business activity in the area was slightly stronger from March.</p>
<p>The group said growth was reflected in the report's new orders, backlog of orders and dollars spent by purchasing components.</p>
<p>New orders rose to 27 in April, from 18 in March, but was below the three-month average.  However, new orders, as well as the production and employment components, remain higher than the three-year average.</p>
<p>Employment rose to 20, from March's 12, but the group said employment in the area &quot;does not seem to be adding significant pressure on service prices.&quot;</p>
<p>Commodity prices fell to 16 in April, from 18 in March.</p>
<p>&quot;This index continues to show stability with a low rate of increase for a six-month period, indicating at this point the strength in the economy is not resulting in alarming levels of higher prices,&quot; the group said. ((Derivatives desk 312-408-8750))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
