<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55149" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-TABAREZ GETS DREADED &quot;VOTE OF CONFIDENCE&quot; AT MILAN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-TABAREZ GETS DREADED &quot;VOTE OF CONFIDENCE&quot; AT MILAN.</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Milan's new Uruguayan coach Oscar Tabarez heard the words every manager fears on Monday after one of the worst weeks in his club's recent history.</p>
<p>After their 2-1 defeat at Sampdoria on Sunday which followed their home defeat to Porto in the European Champions League, Tabarez was given a resounding vote of confidence by Milan owner Silvio Berlusconi.</p>
<p>As is well known in football, wholesome praise from the boss is often the prelude to coach's dismissal.</p>
<p>Berlusconi, who also praised Tabarez after Wednesday's defeat said: &quot;Tabarez has my total support. I spoke to him just after the game and told him not to worry about the criticism that would be coming his way. Milan appears to have lost its athletic sheen. Perhaps there's a sense of complacency, of relaxation after so many years of success.&quot;</p>
<p>Milan's two most recent defeats plus a 2-1 loss to Fiorentina in the pre-season Italian SuperCup prompted media commentators on Monday to define the champions as a side already in serious trouble.</p>
<p>&quot;Milan are in crisis, absolute, painful and deep crisis, a pyschological crisis, a results crisis, a squad crisis...</p>
<p>&quot;That which was once the strongest defence in the world has become a pathetic colander&quot;, wrote the Turin daily, &quot;La Stampa&quot;.</p>
<p>Speaking after the defeat, however, Tabarez argued that the tactical and personnel changes he implemented had not effected the outcome.</p>
<p>&quot;The tactical line-up was not the problem, you can't just reduce everything to one reason alone...I have arrived to coach the established Milan squad and I am trying to implant a new style and perhaps the players haven't yet got used to the new mix&quot;</p>
<p>Englishman Bobby Robson was another unhappy coach even though his Barcelona team top the Spanish League after three matches.</p>
<p>Robson was critical of his side, which, he said, continues to rely on the individual qualities of its multi-billion peseta summer-signings.</p>
<p>&quot;Barcelona cannot and should not play like that. We've lost two points rather than winning one,&quot; said Robson after the 1-1 draw at Racing Santander, in which striker Ronaldo and goalkeeper Vitor Baia had shone, in contrast to the dullness of the team's overall play.</p>
<p>Robson is still shuffling his cards -- having used 18 players in just three league games -- to find a winning combination.</p>
<p>The main worry at French League leaders Paris St Germain was whether their impressive start to the season would continue after an injury to international goalkeeper Bernard Lama.</p>
<p>Lama injured a knee after stopping a penalty in PSG's 1-0 victory at Cannes on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope it's not too serious. If we have not let in a single goal since the start of the season, Bernard is the one to thank. He has been on a high since the league resumed,&quot; said defender Alain Roche.</p>
<p>Lama was to undergo medical checks on Monday to determine how serious the injury was.</p>
<p>Paris lead Bordeaux, the other unbeaten team in the league, by two points. Bordeaux, spurred by a rejuvenated Jean-Pierre Papin, are the early season sensations. Despite losing Christophe Dugarry, Zinedine Zidane, Richard Witschge and Bixente Lizarazu this year, they have yet to lose a match and crushed Lille 3-0 on Saturday.</p>
<p>There was a familiar name at the top of the English League on Sunday -- Liverpool. They beat Leicester 3-0 with Czech Patrick Berger making an immediate impact scoring twice after coming on as a second half substitute.</p>
<p>But the one club dominating the headlines in England were Arsenal, whose skipper Tony Adams admitted to being an alcoholic at the weekend.</p>
<p>Arsenal officially announce Frenchman Arsene Wenger as their new manager on Monday and he urgently needs to impose some stability on the club that was once perceived as the epitome of the establishment but which has reeled from scandal to scandal in recent years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="URU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
