<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="551525" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida &quot;Virgin Mary&quot; building may become shrine.</title>
<headline>Florida &quot;Virgin Mary&quot; building may become shrine.</headline>
<dateline>CLEARWATER, Fla. 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Florida office building that has drawn more than a million people to view a shimmering image they believe is the Virgin Mary will become a permanent shrine if the building's owner has his way.</p>
<p>Police have estimated that some 1.5 million people have flocked to the nondescript building to kneel and pray or merely stare at a large rainbow-colored image on its glass siding that resembles a woman's profile -- to believers, the outline of the Virgin Mary.</p>
<p>Experts said the image were created by mineral deposits from water on the building's side.</p>
<p>But Mike Krizmanich, the owner of the building, said he believes the apparition is a gift from God to be protected and shared. He told Tuesday's Tampa Tribune that he planned to turn the building into a permanent home for the apparition and use its inside office space for a spiritual purpose.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know how I wound up with it,&quot; he told the paper.</p>
<p>Krizmanich's Seminole Finance Corp. was housed in the $1.3 million building until the business was sold this year. But he said he did not want to sell the building, even to a religious organization, and prefers to set up the shrine himself.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CLEARWATER, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
