<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="551635" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Racal set for make-or-break strategy revamp.</title>
<headline>Racal set for make-or-break strategy revamp.</headline>
<byline>Edna Fernandes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pressure is mounting on Racal Electronics Plc to pacify angry investors who have already suffered two profit warnings since December and a share price slump of over 100 pence in what was supposed to be a turnaround year.</p>
<p>The first warning came as an unwelcome surprise just before Christmas. The second just a few weeks ago left shareholders fuming.</p>
<p>Now Racal knows it must come up with something which will satisfy shareholders who have already had their patience tested, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Analysts said Racal had a number of strategic options. After failing to deliver its promises in the past, Racal must now provide concrete evidence by its June 3 results that shareholder value will be realised before long.</p>
<p>The April 18 profit warning, due to a poor showing at its data products division, means year-end profits could be as low as 40 million pounds ($65 million), leading to a wave of downgrades from the current average forecast of 53.5 million.</p>
<p>&quot;This year's profits are seen at 40 million. That is not good enough for a group with turnover of 1.1 billion pounds,&quot; said Mike Styles, analyst at Credit Lyonnais Laing.</p>
<p>One possible route available to Racal is a break-up of the group, spinning off parts which many analysts say are worth more split than bound together.</p>
<p>Racal already has a track record of successful spin-offs. It demerged Vodafone Group Plc, the mobile phone operator in 1991, which is now worth 1.4 billion stg. It also floated off Chubb Security which was recently clinched in an agreed takeover by Williams Holdings Plc for 1.1 billion.</p>
<p>Henderson Crosthwaite analyst Brian Newman put the valuation of the remaining sum parts of Racal at 855 million pounds or 300 pence per share.</p>
<p>That compares with the current market capitalisation of 688 million and a shareprice of 238 pence per share, down three and a half.</p>
<p>Shares were at 345 pence a year ago. Looking at its relative perofrmance, Reuters 3000 data showed over the last six months Racal has underperformed the sector by six percent and the FT All Share index by 20 percent.</p>
<p>Natwest Securities pitches the  break-up share value at  267 pence. Its analyst research team says &quot;the stock does not appear immediately attractive on an earnings basis given the risk to forecasts&quot;.</p>
<p>But Natwest concluded &quot;In the short term we believe management are focused on delivering value.&quot;</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch analyst Andrew Clifton echoes the sentiments. Despite a cautious outlook for the current financial year and the dire conclusion that 40 percent of group assets will generate no return this year he sees &quot;a definite improvement over the medium term.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe a sum of parts approach is more appropriate,&quot; estimating the total value at 300-320 pence per share.</p>
<p>Spin-offs or a break-up are not the only options to return shareholder value, with some analysts also pointing to the possibility of partnerships to grow key businesses.</p>
<p>Styles said many of the divisions were too small to spin-off. He suggests that Racal is more likely to seek equity partners to expand some of its businesses, bearing in mind the constraints of its high gearing level.</p>
<p>But if the group failed to get the right kind of partner deals, it could consider selling off businesses on a selective basis.</p>
<p>He said the sum-value approach may even under-estimate the potential proceeds from sales because &quot;some of Racal's companies could go for quite a lot more to the right buyer.&quot;</p>
<p>The biggest part of the business is network services which includes British Rail Telecoms, the nationwide network bought under the sell-off the national rail network.</p>
<p>It is the world's largest data network provider with top blue-chip customers. Some believe this could be a prime target partner for telecom firms desperate to expand in network services. AT &amp; T of the U.S. is one name mentioned.</p>
<p>The radio unit, responsible for the profit warning in December, is already under review and was recently chosen as part of a wider consortium to tender for the Ministry of Defence two billion pounds battlefield radio contract. If the consortium wins it could see a further 2-3 billion in additional export sales.</p>
<p>Data Products is seen as having good products and an attractive target for interested buyers, said Styles, though it has been a loss maker.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the defence business is performing well, said Racal. Other smaller units are energy and specialised busiesses.</p>
<p>The group remain tight-lipped ahead of the results, but suggests that investor concerns will be addressed in the results statement when a strategic report will be given.</p>
<p>One company source concedes the June 3 results must provide evidence of progress to deliver shareholder value soon. With investors burned twice, some are likely to adopt a &quot;three-strikes and you're out&quot; policy. ($ = 0.614 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34330">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
