<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55178" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-LEHMAN AND JONES TO REPRESENT U.S. IN WORLD CUP.</title>
<headline>GOLF-LEHMAN AND JONES TO REPRESENT U.S. IN WORLD CUP.</headline>
<dateline>CINCINNATI, Ohio 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Open champion Tom Lehman and U.S. Open champion Steve Jones will represent the United States in the 42nd World Cup of Golf at Erinvale Golf Club near Cape Town, South Africa, organisers announced on Monday.</p>
<p>The Lehman/Jones partnership represents the first time in the history of the World Cup that the winners of the world's two most coveted Open championships will play together.</p>
<p>Jones, 37, won the U.S. Open title in June at Oakland Hills Country Club by one stroke over Lehman and Davis Love III. Lehman, also 37, came back one month later to win the British Open at Royal Lytham and St Annes.</p>
<p>Jones and Lehman have a tough act to follow. Fred Couples and Love teamed up to win the last four World Cups, beginning in 1992 in Madrid and running through last year's tournament in China.</p>
<p>&quot;I've always known that to be able to play for your country is something extra special,&quot; Jones said in a prepared statement. &quot;It will be a great thrill to be able to play in the World Cup with Tom, who is one of my best friends.</p>
<p>&quot;Besides, there isn't any doubt that Tom is one of the best players in the world.&quot;</p>
<p>Lehman said: &quot;I think we'll make a good team because Steve is such a good friend. I can't think of anybody I'd rather play with, so it will be a great week.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm looking forward to playing in South Africa because I played on the South African tour for three years (1988-1990),&quot; Lehman added. &quot;It will be fun to go back because part of my golfing roots are there.&quot;</p>
<p>Two-man teams from 32 countries will compete for the World Cup on a course designed by Gary Player, who represented South Africa in 16 World Cups and won in 1965 with Harold Henning.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CINCINNATI, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
