<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="551859" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYC to demand more taxes from Port Authority-paper.</title>
<headline>NYC to demand more taxes from Port Authority-paper.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York City will sue Port Authority of New York and New Jersey to prevent it from selling or leasing World Trade Center unless the transaction involves an increase in property taxes paid to the city, York York Times reported Wednesday, quoting city administration officials.</p>
<p>John Dyson, chairman of the Mayor's Council of Economic Advisors, told the Times that the threat of the lawsuit was intended to make clear to Port Authority board members that the city would fight any attempt to pass along the benfits of sharply reduced taxes to a private landlord or management compnay, the Times reported.</p>
<p>Benefits have been extended to the Trade Center since it was built in 1960s.</p>
<p>The city is concerned that it would not get its fair share in the sale or lease of the World Trade Center, Dyson told the Times.</p>
<p>Port Authority officials were taken by surpise by the Dyson comments, the Times reported.</p>
<p>&quot;All of this is premature,&quot; said Kathy Donovan, a Port Authority board member.</p>
<p>Mark Hatfield, the authority's director of communications, told the Times several options remained open for the World Trade Center.</p>
<p>&quot;I can assure you the board's deliberations will take into account the Mayor's issues,&quot; Hatfield told the Times.</p>
<p>The Times reported a decision on the center could be made within two months, quoting a Port Authority officials who declined to be named.</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
