<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="551829" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Friend testifies McVeigh planned Okla. bombing.</title>
<headline>Friend testifies McVeigh planned Okla. bombing.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Wulfhorst</byline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Timothy McVeigh, angry over the 1993 assault on the Branch Davidian cult compound in Waco, Texas, decided to blow up the Oklahoma City federal building because he believed agents from the Waco raid were inside, a key prosecution witness testified on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Lori Fortier, who is testifying with immunity from prosecution at the accused bomber's murder and conspiracy trial, said McVeigh was an old friend who told her he planned to build a bomb with racing fuel and ammonium nitrate in barrels inside a rented truck.</p>
<p>McVeigh is accused of setting off the huge truck bomb that destroyed the Alfred P. Murrah federal building on April 19, 1995 and killed 168 people.</p>
<p>McVeigh was upset about the FBI assault on the Branch Davidian compound and he believed &quot;the government had murdered the people at Waco,&quot; Fortier testified. As vengeance, McVeigh decided to &quot;take action against the government&quot; and bomb the Murrah building.</p>
<p>&quot;He said it was an easy target and it was a building that housed some of the people involved in the Waco raid,&quot; she testified.</p>
<p>Branch Davidian cult leader David Koresh and about 80 followers died in flames after a botched FBI raid on their Waco compound on April 19, 1993. Since then Waco has been a rallying cry of the right-wing militia movement and it was on the two-year anniversary of the Waco raid that the Oklahoma City bombing occurred.</p>
<p>Fortier, whose husband Michael also is among the prosecution's witnesses in the case, said McVeigh illustrated how he would build the bomb by using Campbell's soup cans on the floor of her trailer in Kingman, Arizona.</p>
<p>&quot;He placed the cans on the floor in the same arrangement he would place them in the truck,&quot; she said, adding that he told her, &quot;it would get the most impact that way.&quot;</p>
<p>Fortier, dressed in a conservative charcoal gray suit with a black velvet collar with her dark brown hair cut above her shoulders, said she did not try to dissuade McVeigh because she did not believe he was capable of the bombing.</p>
<p>But she said she now feels responsible, knew it was McVeigh when the bomb went off and believes she could have stopped it.</p>
<p>As she said, &quot;I wish I could have stopped it,&quot; her calm voice broke and she buried her head in her hands for a moment.</p>
<p>Outside the courtroom, Jannie Coverdale, whose two young grandsons Elijah and Aaron died in the bombing, said Fortier's words made her angry.</p>
<p>&quot;She knows all it would have taken was one phone call,&quot; said Coverdale.</p>
<p>McVeigh watched impassively, as he has throughout his trial that began last week. He has pleaded not guilty and faces the death penalty if convicted.</p>
<p>Asked at the end of the day if Fortier's testimony was damaging to his client, defence attorney Stephen Jones said, &quot;Wait until tomorrow and ask me then.&quot;</p>
<p>Fortier faces what is likely to be a tough cross- examination by McVeigh's defence team on Wednesday morning.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, she described in great detail knowing McVeigh for about eight years. He and her husband met in the Army, she said, and had remained friends.</p>
<p>Michael Fortier has admitted in a plea agreement with the government that he knew about McVeigh's alleged plans and did nothing to stop him. He has not yet testified and is expected to be one of the prosecution's most incriminating witnesses.</p>
<p>His wife also said she helped McVeigh make a fake driver's license he allegedly used to rent the truck for the bombing.</p>
<p>She said McVeigh told her he had compiled explosives, including some stolen from a quarry in Kansas, and that Terry Nichols, who will be tried separately in the case, was going to mix the bomb.</p>
<p>She said McVeigh grew sullen when her husband refused to agree to plans to pick him up in Las Vegas after the bombing. She also said Nichols grew frightened about the planned bombing.  &quot;Terry wanted out,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The anonymous jury also saw a blackened, twisted rear axle from the rented truck. An identification number from the axle led authorities to a Junction City, Kansas, rental agency, where prosecutors say McVeigh rented the truck for the bombing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
