<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="551862" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Police try to coax Texas separatists to surrender.</title>
<headline>Police try to coax Texas separatists to surrender.</headline>
<byline>Kieran Murray</byline>
<dateline>FORT DAVIS, Texas 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police tried to coax armed Texas separatists out of their mountain hideout as a tense standoff entered its fourth day on Wednesday, but the group's leader showed no sign of surrendering.</p>
<p>Richard McLaren, self-styled &quot;ambassador&quot; for the Republic of Texas group, said he had diplomatic immunity and wanted to negotiate directly with U.S. Attorney General Janet Reno rather than Texas state troopers.</p>
<p>Even as officials said they were optimistic McLaren and 12 of his followers would soon surrender, the Republic's volatile leader said he was prepared to die in his fight to win independence for Texas.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not going to be pulled out like the Freemen. Those boys, if you notice, haven't got a trial yet ... so, we're not going to get screwed and tattooed like everyone else,&quot; McLaren told KHOU-TV in Houston in an interview late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Freemen anti-government militia group surrendered to police after a long standoff at their Montana ranch last year.</p>
<p>McLaren and his followers, who believe Texas is a sovereign nation and that they form its provisional government, holed up in a ramshackle compound they named their &quot;embassy&quot; in the remote Davis Mountains of west Texas.</p>
<p>They were surrounded by at least 120 heavily armed police officers who were poised to arrest the group by force if McLaren did not surrender. Six Republic members faced charges of criminal activity and aggravated kidnapping.</p>
<p>Police had far superior firepower and got some extra help on Tuesday when two 13-ton armoured personnel carriers -- called &quot;Bubba 1&quot; and &quot;Bubba 2&quot; -- rumbled into the area, sent on loan by an east Texas sheriff.</p>
<p>Officials said the carriers were quickly put to use to pick up legal documents that McLaren sent out to his attorney. They did not say what was in the documents.</p>
<p>Texas Department of Public Safety spokesman Mike Cox said negotiations to end the siege were at &quot;a sensitive stage but progressing well.&quot; He declined to detail the talks but McLaren was believed to be demanding the release of a jailed Republic member and a statewide referendum on whether Texas should secede from the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;We are dealing with some very complex issues which take time and people working together to resolve,&quot; Cox said.</p>
<p>McLaren's message, however, was very different. The 43-year-old vintner from Missouri said his dream of an independent Texas was already a reality because he had filed papers declaring the republic with the United Nations.</p>
<p>&quot;This is our country, last week the last U.N. filing was done. We are under self-governance. We're in a state of war,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He also said militia forces were gathering in the area to defend his government, a claim ridiculed by state officials.</p>
<p>Some of McLaren's neighbours inside the 6,000-acre Fort Davis Resort retirement community said they believed he has stored gasoline tanks and plans to start a huge wildfire across the wooded mountains if police move in on him.</p>
<p>The standoff began on Sunday when Republic members grabbed two hostages from a nearby home in retaliation for the arrest of their security chief, Robert Scheidt, on weapons possession charges. One of the hostages was injured when the Republic members shot their way into his house but both captives were later released in a swap for Scheidt.</p>
<p>The Republic of Texas was formed in late 1995 and claims to have thousands of members and ties to anti-government militias.</p>
<p>McLaren was charged with contempt of court in December for failing to appear in federal court on charges related to bogus liens issued by the Republic. Since then he and several followers have holed up inside the compound, which is about 200 miles (320 km) southeast of El Paso, Texas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FORT DAVIS, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
