<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="551944" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS - Jobless fall helps Juppe on way into election.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Jobless fall helps Juppe on way into election.</headline>
<byline>Brian Love</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>French unemployment fell slightly for a second month running in March, giving Prime Minister Alain Juppe a badly needed weapon to combat voter dismay at his record on jobs ahead of a parliamentary election next month.</p>
<p>Jobless numbers fell by 4,800 to 3.09 million, with a marked dip among young people, according to labour ministry data issued on Wednesday, But the jobless rate based on International Labour Organisation (ILO) criteria stayed at a record 12.8 percent.</p>
<p>The last jobs figures before the May 25/June 1 election were seized on by the centre-right government to declare an end to a steady rise in the unemployment rate which has blighted Juppe since he promised a war on joblessness two years ago.</p>
<p>When Conservative President Jacques Chirac took power in May 1995, Juppe said his entire work programme would be devoted to jobs. &quot;We want to be judged, when the time comes, on our ability to stimulate in France a deep and durable movement to create jobs, he said at the time.</p>
<p>The ILO unemployment rate back then was 11.5 percent and hit the 12.8 percent record in February.</p>
<p>But Wednesday data, coming after a February fall of 7,500, gave the government a welcome lift in its campaign battle with opposition Socialists, allowing the ruling coalition to say the unemployment trend should go into reverse later this year with the help of better economic growth.</p>
<p>&quot;One can consider that since the last quarter of 1996, the rise in unemployment has been stopped,&quot; labour minister Jacques Barrot told reporters after a weekly cabinet meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;What's certain is that, with economic growth setting a pace of about 2.5 percent for the year, we will should see a regular decline in unemployment in the second half of the year,&quot; Alain Lamassoure, the official government spokesman, said.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister says that the figures show unemployment has stabilised and there is an improvement in employment, especially among the young,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The labour ministry said the fall in March unemployment was most marked among the young, where the number out of work fell by 7,600 or 1.3 percent in March, and especially among young men, where it fell 1.8 percent.</p>
<p>Economists said the latest figure was clearly good news for the ruling coalition -- which opinion polls predict should win the election with a reduced majority -- but they were sceptical about jobless data issued so soon before an election.</p>
<p>There will be no further job figures until June 2, a day after the second-round election runoff.</p>
<p>Unemployment at the end of March was 0.2 percent lower than in February but 2.2 percent up on the same stage a year earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;In an electoral campaign environment these figures have to be taken with a pinch of salt. It looks like unemployment data is not meant to interfere with the campaign,&quot; said JP Morgan economist David Naude. &quot;Needless to say in the current environment these figures are of little informative value.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It's not quite as stark as in the U.K. (Britain) but it's the same situation in that the headline numbers are not behaving in the same way as the ILO numbers. It's clear the labour market in France is still pretty soft,&quot; said Sean Shepley, economist at CS First Boston.</p>
<p>The number out of work when based in ILO measures actually rose 0.2 percent in march and was 4.6 percent up year-on-year.</p>
<p>March saw a rise in the number of long-term unemployed, with those out of work for a year or more rising 0.2 percent to more than 1.1 million. They account for one in three jobless.</p>
<p>Shepley was referring to criticism by many analysts that extensive changes to the way British jobless totals are measured mean that monthly figures greatly exaggerate the health of the British economy.</p>
<p>The European Commission said last week it was forecasting French unemployment of 12.5 percent for 1997 and 12.1 percent unemployment in 1998. The International Monetary Fund said last week it was predicting French unemployment at 12.8 percent this year and 12.3 percent next year.</p>
<p>Opinion polls show the electorate is deeply depressed about unemployment and does not believe the single European currency will help. The left is trying to capitalise and saying Juppe has neglected employment in his deficit-reduction drive to qualify France for European monetary union.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
