<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="551919" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Calif. researchers link gene to Down's syndrome.</title>
<headline>Calif. researchers link gene to Down's syndrome.</headline>
<dateline>BERKELEY, Calif. 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>California researchers said on Tuesday they had identified a major genetic factor contributing to mental retardation in people with Down's syndrome.</p>
<p>Working with mice bred to carry segments of human chromosome 21 in their DNA, scientists at the Ernest Orlando Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory in Berkeley linked learning deficits to the gene DYRK.</p>
<p>Any deviation from the normal complement of two copies of this gene appears to impair the ability to learn, the researchers said.</p>
<p>The findings of the researchers, led by Edward Rubin and Desmond Smith, geneticists with the Berkeley lab's life sciences division, were published in the May 1 edition of the scientific journal Nature Genetics.</p>
<p>&quot;Our work suggests that you need exactly two copies of DYRK for normal development,&quot; Rubin, who heads biology research for the lab's Human Genome Center, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Down's syndrome occurs in about one of every 800 newborns, with the incidence increasing markedly in the children born to women over 35, the Berkeley lab said. It is the leading genetic cause of mental retardation and is associated with a shorter-than-average life expectancy of 55 years, it said.</p>
<p>Most people with Down's syndrome carry a complete extra copy of chromosome 21 in all of their cells. But there are rare forms of Down's syndrome in which only part of chromosome 21 is present in triplicate.</p>
<p>Smith and Rubin bred a series of mice containing different adjacent segments of human chromosome 21.</p>
<p>To identify which gene was responsible for mental retardation, they assessed the learning and memory skills of their genetically altered mice using a standardized test.</p>
<p>The strain of mouse that performed most poorly on the test carried a human DYRK gene in addition to a pair of mouse DYRK genes, the researchers found. They also said that DYRK is almost identical to a fruit fly gene that also plays a role in learning.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously a large leap of faith must be taken to equate learning in flies to that in humans,&quot; Rubin said.</p>
<p>&quot;However, the corresponding findings in both flies and mice ... support the idea that altered expression of this gene (DYRK) may be an important contributor to the learning defects in humans with Down syndrome,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Berkeley lab is a U.S. Department of Energy national laboratory managed by the University of California.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERKELEY, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
