<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="551959" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Helsinki builds on gains in lively volume.</title>
<headline>Helsinki builds on gains in lively volume.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish shares ended higher on Wednesday despite stronger than expected U.S. Q1 GDP growth data which hit U.S. bonds, brokers said. Trade was lively as Nokia extended gains after its first quarter report.</p>
<p>The general HEX index closed up 0.11 percent at 2,933.76 points but the FOX derivatives and portfolio benchmark fell 0.13 percent to 1,018.18 points.</p>
<p>Volume was a lively 830 million markka, with 42 percent in Nokia which was up 2.50 markka at 324.40.</p>
<p>&quot;The market dipped, but on the whole it took (the U.S. data) quite calmly,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Friday was expected to be quiet with many operators taking a day off between May Day holiday on Thursday and the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;Friday will be precisely the kind of day that the U.S. market determines it will be,&quot; one broker said. &quot;We're now staring at the U.S. (30-year) bond.&quot;</p>
<p>Rautaruukki eased 0.90 to 45.60 markka, still well above its 42.00 markka offering price in solid volume, and brokers said international interest remained strong.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been several brokers involved and the deals have not been concentrated on the lead managers, so it looks like there is some genuine interest in the share,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Asko was lively as holding company Lanor continued to sell shares, cutting its stake to 11 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
