<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55203" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICA MINE OWNERS DEFEND TRAPS FOR GOLD THIEVES.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICA MINE OWNERS DEFEND TRAPS FOR GOLD THIEVES.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African mines called on Monday for a revision of a draft law to ensure that police could continue to use traps in their fight against gold theft costing the country an estimated 1.5 billion rand a year.</p>
<p>&quot;The trapping system should be retained as a lawful method of combatting crime,&quot; the Chamber of Mines, representing owners of most of the country's mines, said in a submission to parliament's justice committee.</p>
<p>The committee is holding public hearings on a package of bills designed to bolster the fight against organised crime, fraud and the drugs trade.</p>
<p>The chamber estimated that up to 30 tonnes of unrefined gold worth about 1.5 billion rand was stolen from the country's mines every year.</p>
<p>It said the losses, equal to about 34 percent of the industry's 1995 operating profit, affected shareholders directly because the full cost of production had been paid on the stolen gold.</p>
<p>&quot;From these figures, it is apparent that the theft of gold represents a very real threat to the viability of the gold mining industry itself.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential damage to the economy and the social cost of this crime is self-evident,&quot; the chamber said.</p>
<p>The Criminal Procedure Amendment Bill proposes to regulate the use of traps to make them legal in terms of the country's new constitution and to protect the civil rights of the victim.</p>
<p>The chamber proposed a number of changes including indemnity from prosecution for anyone involved in setting the trap for crimes necessary to make the operation effective.</p>
<p>The chamber supported provisions to prevent abuse of the trapping system, but added:</p>
<p>&quot;The court should nevertheless have a discretion to admit evidence which has been improperly obtained...where such evidence is in the interest of justice,&quot; the chamber said,</p>
<p>The mine-owners also opposed a provision allowing a court to balance the offence against the personal circumstances of the accused.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that the personal, economic or professional circumstances of the accused made him more susceptible to the commission of the offence does not appear to be relevant.</p>
<p>&quot;...impecuniosity may reduce the moral guilt of the accused, but does not deprive his act of unlawfulness,&quot; the chamber said.</p>
<p>-- Brendan Boyle, Parliamentary newsroom, +27 21 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
