<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55204" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: APARTHEID KILLER BEGINS TO NAME NAMES.</title>
<headline>APARTHEID KILLER BEGINS TO NAME NAMES.</headline>
<byline>Robyn Green</byline>
<dateline>PRETORIA 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A convicted apartheid assassin took the stand on Monday in a South African court and began to implicate the security chiefs who gave his orders.</p>
<p>Eugene de Kock, found guilty last month of six murders and scores of lesser crimes committed while he led a notorious death-squad unit, told the packed Pretoria Supreme Court that the brutality of bush warfare turned him into a hardened killer.</p>
<p>The gruesome executions of counter-insurgency comrades with whom he was fighting black guerrillas in neighbouring Rhodesia, now Zimbabwe, in the early 1970s, had turned him.</p>
<p>&quot;It made me decide: you shoot first and ask questions later,&quot; de Kock, 47, said.</p>
<p>Cabinet ministers from President Nelson Mandela's African National Congress were among those crammed into the court where he was testifying for the first time in his trial, in the hope of convincing the judge to pass a lenient sentence.</p>
<p>De Kock, who said he was apartheid's most effective assassin, has also applied to Archbishop Desmond Tutu's &quot;truth commission&quot; for an amnesty. That would depend partly on his telling all -- which he has reportedly pledged to do.</p>
<p>South African media say de Kock, whose victims included Winnie Mandela's driver, has vowed to take down with him the superiors who gave him his orders during the campaign to divide and discredit opponents of white minority rule.</p>
<p>Safety and Security Minister Sydney Mufamadi and Deputy National Intelligence Minister Joe Nhlanhla sat in court to hear what he has to say and who he names.</p>
<p>De Kock named his first name on Monday, but not one that shook the country.</p>
<p>He said a little-known General Dreyer had ordered him to execute three black guerrillas in South-West Africa, now Namibia, another place where de Kock served in a notorious counter-insurgency unit in the 1970s.</p>
<p>Anti-apartheid activists are hoping that de Kock will spill the beans on better known senior officials of ex-president F.W. de Klerk's last white government.</p>
<p>The only one to face justice so far is former defence minister Magnus Malan, whose trial for alleged complicity in a 1987 massacre of 13 men, women and children is nearing its end.</p>
<p>Lawyers who have defended de Kock during his 18-month trial have said he is suffering from post-traumatic stress disorder and that they may make use of this in mitigation.</p>
<p>The career policeman, arrested shortly after the all-race elections in 1994 buried apartheid, said his disciplinarian father raised him in a strict religious and nationalistic way.</p>
<p>But he said he had not been a racist and had been annoyed by the double standards the South African forces showed towards its own men during the wars in Rhodesia and South-West Africa.</p>
<p>If he called from the field for help for a wounded operative, radio control would ask if he was black or white.</p>
<p>&quot;(Only) if they were white, they would sent the helicopters very quickly. That sort of thing was unacceptable to me,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe I loved people too much. I did not see them as blacks but as human beings.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRETORIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
