<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="552104" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German wheat withstands price pressure, sellers up.</title>
<headline>German wheat withstands price pressure, sellers up.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>German old and new crop wheat is offered quietly steadier, although rains across Europe have exerted downward pressure on prices, brokers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Sellers are reluctant and European milling industries will need to replace more local wheat with German origin because of anticipated harvest losses,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>&quot;This combination is boosting the price despite the current demand lull.&quot;</p>
<p>Prices in Britain, Spain, Portugal and some parts of France have fallen because of the weather.</p>
<p>Global prices are still high and the European Union decision to tax wheat exports -- while adding to worldwide tightness -- is calming the internal market.</p>
<p>Brokers said this would eventually reduce local prices.</p>
<p>Old crop barley and rye volumes were very scarce because they had been largely sold to feed manufacturers and intervention stores, brokers said.</p>
<p>New crop wheat negotiations had not started because initial levels were in a high 285-307.50 marks/tonne range, fob Baltic.</p>
<p>The Hamburg grain exchange this week raised its spot bread wheat price (12.5 percent, 220 Hagberg) by 2.50 marks to 287.50 marks a tonne free Hamburg.</p>
<p>But it left the spot feed wheat price unchanged at 280.</p>
<p>Fob Baltic sellers raised nominal first half May delivery wheat by between 1.00 and 2.50 marks versus April delivery but this reflected implied holding costs.</p>
<p>They quoted 12 percent protein wheat at 287.50-302.50 marks and 13/14 percent protein at 293.50-321 marks.</p>
<p>Limited fob Baltic barley offers were unchanged at 273.50 marks spot while rye sellers were at 270-275.</p>
<p>New crop wheat fob Baltic was offered in a 286-307.50 marks range and fob Rostock at 292.50-315, depending on dates, quality and shipment sizes.</p>
<p>--Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
