<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="552296" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Dlr steady after tight range trade in late Tokyo.</title>
<headline>Dlr steady after tight range trade in late Tokyo.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>0621 GMT     2400 GMT	NYK CLOSE</p>
<p> USD/JPY	   126.86/96    126.91/94     126.89/94</p>
<p> USD/DEM	   1.7233/38    1.7256/59     1.7240/50</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The dollar moved steadily against the yen after trading in a range around 126.80-127.00 yen by late Tokyo on Wednesday. It was sandwiched between bids from Japanese operators and option-linked sales, dealers said.</p>
<p>Trading energy ebbed in the afternoon amid an absence of decisive factors. Action mostly focused on option-related trade, they said.  </p>
<p>The dollar failed to clearly break through 127 yen as option-linked sales, mostly by interbank dealers, to avoid hitting knock-out options points near 127.30 yen limited its advance, dealers said.</p>
<p>But they said buy-back interest from those dealers also kept the greenback solid on the downside.</p>
<p>Other factors to cap the dollar's advance were rises in the yield of the key 182nd 10-year Japanese government bond and in Tokyo stocks, dealers said. &quot;We are closely watching a rise in Japanese long-term interest rates,&quot; a dealer said. The 182nd JGB yield was 2.350 percent at 0640 GMT against Monday's 2.295.  </p>
<p>Tokyo stocks surged upwards, with a rally mostly inspired by a surge on Wall Street on Tuesday. The Nikkei average of 225 leading shares ended up 480.75 points at 19,151.12.</p>
<p>In the morning, the greenback was well-bid versus the yen despite falls against the mark overnight in reaction to weaker-than-expected U.S. economic data, which dulled expectations of a near-term rise in U.S. interest rates.</p>
<p>Dealers said trust banks were actively buying dollars, probably on behalf of investment trust firms and pension funds. Mark buying for yen in cross-trade in late morning also supported the greenback versus the yen, they said.  </p>
<p>The mark rose as high as around 73.79 yen in late morning trade after stop-loss mark buying was set off near 73.60-65 yen. This dragged the dollar down against the mark briefly, while pushing up the dollar against the yen, dealers said.</p>
<p>The mark stood around 73.57/60 yen at 0704 GMT, compared with 73.55 yen in early Tokyo trading.</p>
<p>Lingering worries about possible dollar-selling intervention if the dollar manages to advance above 127 yen continued to weigh on the dollar against the yen. But a city bank dealer said: &quot;While we are concerned about it, it's unlikely that intervention will take place.&quot;  </p>
<p>One bank dealer said comments by former MOF official Toyoo Gyohten that the yen had fallen too far blocked the dollar's rise in the morning. &quot;The current level of the Japanese yen is excessively weak,&quot; Gyohten said in Washington.</p>
<p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin repeated his mantra that a strong dollar is in U.S. interests but said he shared Japanese concerns on a weak yen. But the impact from these comments was limited. Singapore dealers said the dollar looked well-bid on the downside and was unlikely to fall below 1.7150 marks and 126.50 yen. -- Singapore newsroom +65-8703080, Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-8584</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
