<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55221" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: OECD CALLS FOR SPEED UP IN SLOVAK BANKING REFORMS.</title>
<headline>OECD CALLS FOR SPEED UP IN SLOVAK BANKING REFORMS.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Develepment (OECD) on Monday said Slovakia's banking sector needed to reform more quickly to create a fully-effective financial system.</p>
<p>&quot;In view of the high concentration of lending and deposit activity in three main banks, the large burden of bad debts and the slow pace of adjustment, the state of the banking sector in Slovakia remains a cause for concern,&quot; OECD said in its first full economic survey devoted to Slovakia.</p>
<p>The club of the world's richest economies said the reliance of Slovak business development on domestically-generated funds rather than on foreign capital made bank reforms even more important.</p>
<p>The survey said the rather slow decline in retail lending rates in 1995 and early 1996 indicated still relatively limited competition in the banking sector.</p>
<p>The OECD said it expects the privatisation of the country's three main banks to play one of the major roles in allowing banks to compete on more equal terms.</p>
<p>Commenting on the pace of the restructuring of commercial banks loan portfolios, the OECD said resolving the problem would take several years.</p>
<p>Payments are overdue on 173 billion crowns, or 38 percent of bank credits, including 90 billion written off as losses. The banks appear to have acknowledged the extent of the problem, the OECD said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the main banks have made substantial provisions and reserve funds for bad debts, they have been helped by their market dominance and ability to maintain high interest margins,&quot; OECD said.</p>
<p>&quot;This solution is not expected to last and the restructuring of the banking sector will require financial participation by the state,&quot; it added. -- Peter Laca, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OECD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
