<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="552211" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Bustan says opens chick pea pool in Australia.</title>
<headline>Bustan says opens chick pea pool in Australia.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Commodities trader Bustan International Pty Ltd has opened a chick pea pool for 1996/97 crop stocks still held in the Australian states of Victoria and South Australia (SA), it said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The pool would have a guaranteed first payment and would allow growers to benefit from current high prices, it said in a statement.</p>
<p>Bustan managing director Alan Winney said this was an indication of increased marketing alternatives that grain, oilseed and pulse growers could expect in the future.  </p>
<p>Cotton growers had had pool alternatives run by private companies for years. With changes occurring in grain marketing, growers should have more choices, he said.</p>
<p>The Bustan chick pea pool would try to maximise sales prices and return proceeds to the pool, he said. &quot;We believe ... our marketing staff are able to match anyone in the marketplace,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Bustan chick pea pool has an estimated pool equity of A$320 to A$340 a tonne delivered the ports of Portland or Wallaroo.  </p>
<p>A guaranteed first payment of A$300 a tonne delivered port would be made within 30 days of receipt into the pool, he said.</p>
<p>Estimated pool equity updates would be made monthly with the pool expected to be wound up in six months. Bustan anticipated running seasonal pools for various cereals, pulse and oilseed crops during the 1997/98 season, he said.</p>
<p>If the current Victorian and South Australian government reviews of barley marketing legislation allowed, Bustan would &quot;look to offer growers a pool option&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
