<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="552226" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: FORECAST-Australian retail trade to post strong Q1.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Australian retail trade to post strong Q1.</headline>
<byline>John Mair</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian retail trade has staged a remarkable turnaround in the first three months of 1997, and its strength is one of the key arguments against the need for another official rate cut, economists believe.</p>
<p>The March data, due on Friday, is expected to show flat retail trade, but strong rises in Janaury and February mean that real retail trade should have risen strongly in the first quarter, reversing a disappointing Christmas period.  </p>
<p>Real retail trade is expected to have risen 2.4 percent in the March quarter, after falling by 1.3 percent in the December quarter. Forecasts range from a rise of 1.5 to 2.8 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;When you look through the volatility there, the December quarter was unrealistically weak, the March quarter is probably unrealistically strong, but nevertheless the trend is for a gradual pick up in that retail trade figure,&quot; Axiom Funds Management senior economist Matthew Drennan said.  </p>
<p>Given the strength in motor vehicle registrations and expected continued strength in spending on services, private sector demand is expected to make a solid contribution to March quarter growth, data for which is due on June 4.</p>
<p>In monthly terms, median forecasts centre on a flat result and range from a 1.0 percent fall to a 1.3 percent rise.</p>
<p>However, a flat result would be seen confirming the strength seen in retail spending so far this year, as it would follow rises of 0.8 percent in February and 2.7 percent in Janaury.  </p>
<p>In a week with trade, wages and building approvals data also being released, some analysts saw retail trade as the most important data given its status as a forward looking indicator.</p>
<p>ANZ Treasury senior economist David de Garis said he was looking for a small rise in March, which on top of the rises in January and February, would lead to a strong quarterly rise.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of that is of course a bounceback from the December quarter, but anecdotal reports suggest that business conditions have improved a little bit in the March quarter, so there is a bit of a trend improvement there,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The retail strength is seen as a key reason why official rates are likely to stay on hold, despite some expectations of a cut following weak employment data and continued low inflation.</p>
<p>Along with signs of improvement in the housing sector, stronger consumer spending is seen have beneficial effects on both employment and the economy through 1997.</p>
<p>Not all are bullish on retail trade however, with some attributing the strength so far in 1997 to changes in spending patterns not yet reflected in seasonal adjustment factors.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is unlikely that the pace of retail trade will maintain its momentum into March,&quot; said Societe Generale economist Glenn Maguire, forecasting a 1.0 percent fall in the month.</p>
<p>&quot;Retail trade grew very strongly in the first two months of 1997 reflecting a shift in consumer spending patterns to post Christmas and continued discounting by retailers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Against that, some saw retail trade remaining boosted in March by fact that the Easter period fell totally in the month, with the correction to 1997's early strength occuring in April.</p>
<p>Recent data, and March forecasts, are detailed below.  </p>
<p>Retail Trade	  Oct     Nov     Dec     Jan     Feb   Mar(f)</p>
<p>    A$ million    10,164  10,235  10,128  10,406  10,492  10,492</p>
<p>    pct m/m	   +1.1    +0.7    -1.0    +2.7    +0.8    flat</p>
<p>    pct y/y	   +2.6    +2.4    +0.8    +2.6    +3.3    +3.0</p>
<p>Real Retail	 Q4 95   Q1 96   Q2 96   Q3 96   Q4 96 Q1 97(f)</p>
<p>    A$ million   25,526  25,851  25,728  25,886  25,555   26,169</p>
<p>    pct q/q	  +0.7    +1.3    -0.5    +0.6    -1.3     +2.4</p>
<p>    pct y/y	  +4.5    +5.1    +2.9    +2.2    +0.1     +1.2</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
