<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="552388" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai B shares end up on domestic buying.</title>
<headline>Shanghai B shares end up on domestic buying.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai B shares ended up strongly on Wednesday mainly due to buying of Pudong property shares by domestic institutions, brokers said.</p>
<p>The B share index surged 1.863 points or 2.08 percent to 91.219 points on volume of 38.678 million shares worth $22.391 million, compared with $19.544 million on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Domestic investors bought heavily into smaller Pudong property shares which are now looking cheap compared to Shanghai Lujiazui Finance &amp; Trade Zone Development, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said market sentiment appeared to be strengthening.  </p>
<p>&quot;Active buying in Pudong shares overwhelmed some unwinding selling ahead of the long Labour Day holiday, which boosted market sentiment,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is no negative news during the holiday, the index will test 100 points after the holiday,&quot; another broker said.</p>
<p>All 43 B shares traded, with 24 up, three flat and 16 down.</p>
<p>Pudong real estate firm Shanghai Waigaoqiao Free Trade Zone Development was the star on domestic buying, surging $0.056 or 9.15 percent to $0.668 on volume of 3.0 million shares.  </p>
<p>Shanghai Kaikai Industrial was the most actively traded on institutional window-dressing buying, jumping $0.030 or 6.52 percent to $0.490 on volume of 3.6 million shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai's A share index ended firmer on active selective buying with market sentiment bullish, brokers said.</p>
<p>The index rose 17.417 points or 1.21 percent to 1,456.503 points on volume of 757.6 million shares worth 10.2 billion yuan.</p>
<p>The SSE30 blue chip index closed up 45.105 points or 1.14 percent to 3,989.350 points.  </p>
<p>Xiamen Titan Stock was the star, up 1.28 yuan or 10.01 percent to 14.06 percent on 1.1 million shares.</p>
<p>--Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
