<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="552533" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine shares take fresh hammering.</title>
<headline>Philippine shares take fresh hammering.</headline>
<byline>Katherine Espina</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine shares took a fresh hammering on Wednesday, sending the index to new two-year lows as fears of poor company earnings frightened off more investors.</p>
<p>The Manila main stock market index dropped in heavy mid-morning trade and at 0335 GMT was down 47.18 points or 1.74 percent at 2,661.26, its lowest level since early 1995.</p>
<p>The market has been in decline since it hit a record high in February and investors have grown increasingly worried that the Philippines may be on the way to repeating the property and banking problems that have hit Thailand so hard.</p>
<p>The index is now more than 20 percent below its February peak.</p>
<p>Traders blamed the latest fall on the flight of foreign investors -- who account for about two-thirds of the market -- dismayed at the mixture of dull to dismal first quarter profits at a number of the country's leading companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Sentiment is very weak due to companies' profits that were below expectations,&quot; said Lawrence de Leon, analyst at Dharmala Securities Phils.</p>
<p>There was selling in B shares, which are open to foreigners, of food and drinks giant San Miguel Corp and Manila Electric Co, both of which came up with disappointing earnings.</p>
<p>If anything the leap overnight on Wall Street was an additional incentive for investors to pull out of the weak Philippine market and move into the United States, trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not only us. It seems like the whole region has lost its lustre,&quot; Joey Roxas, president of Eagle Equities, said.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreigners have been in Asia since 1993. They are going back to other markets,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Many share analysts warn that it will take some time for the Manila share market to recover from its current downturn, despite the relatively strong fundamentals of the economy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
