<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="552755" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: INTERVIEW-Internet phone calls seen revolutionary.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Internet phone calls seen revolutionary.</headline>
<byline>Nick Edwards</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Telecommunications companies must adapt or die in the face of the competitive threat from Internet telephone services that could offer land-line quality calls within two years, a senior executive said on Wedensday.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now there's a lot of hype and the quality is not there yet, but that's going to change very quickly in the next two years and so will the industry,&quot; Jeff Hurmuses, Asia Pacific managing director of Polycom Inc, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Telephone over the Internet won't be able to offer a local service for free, but nearly free,&quot; and that will bring tremendous changes in its wake, said Hurmuses, whose company is the biggest in the teleconferencing market.</p>
<p>He said Internet software tie-ups, service adaptions and hardware alterations would have to be made as customer demands changed.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential is huge,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Unveiling a new desktop audioconferencing system that allows conference calls through personal computers (PCs) via the Internet, Hurmuses said tremendous pent-up demand for Internet telephony in Asia would force the pace of change.</p>
<p>Polycom began work on its Internet phone system after a request from microchip maker Intel Corp for a system that could link its own computers to audioconferencing hardware. After two years and about US$3.0 million of research and development spending, Polycom's product links direct to a computer needing no licence as a telecommunications device.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said the business conference call market for Internet telephony already stood at 300,000 units globally, which could extend rapidly into the domestic market as prices for the technology come down, Hurmuses said.</p>
<p>&quot;We may see these guys (telephone companies) doing deals with software people because to get on the Internet on the phone you've got to get on the Internet first,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In your bill they'll be a diskette that will load the software and then they'll try to push some more services like conference calling,&quot; added Ted Fagenson, Polycom product marketing director.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a new standard connector for PCs, the universal serial bus (UBS) and all of the PC and telephone guys are trying to plug into it,&quot; Fagenson said.</p>
<p>&quot;The belief from some is that eventually the telephone is going to go away as people say 'why can't I use my PC all the time?'&quot;</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703011)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
