<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="552865" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lead market braced to lose some of its luster.</title>
<headline>Lead market braced to lose some of its luster.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lead demand will rise in the second half of the year as the new battery season kicks in, but the year will end with more metal than is needed, Tom Schnull, manager of lead sales at Canada's Noranda Mining &amp; Exploration said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Western world market will see a small surplus develop this year and that will grow a little bit in 1998 and 1999,&quot; Schnull told Reuters.</p>
<p>Lead company officials were in Washington to attend the U.S. Lead Industries Association annual meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand is still good and will average two percent a year,&quot; Schnull added.</p>
<p>A &quot;reasonable&quot; price of 25 to 30 cents per pound will remain through the rest of the year, Schnull said. LME cash settled at about 28 cents a lb Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Premiums are a little bit softer, but even if the prices don't pick up that much, I expect spot premiums to pick up somewhat,&quot; Schnull said.</p>
<p>Stephanie Knott, senior client liaison with Credit Lyonnais Rouse, told the LIA meeting that London Metal Exchange lead stocks have failed to show a large increase despite a sharp fall in European car registrations.</p>
<p>Auto batteries are the biggest consumer of lead.</p>
<p>However, lead producer stocks have risen strongly, as producers try to keep metal off LME to stop any further erosion in physical market premiums, Knott said.</p>
<p>She said there was also still some unhappiness with the LME as a price setter because of its unpredictability. &quot;There remains a residual fear that the market could be manipulated,&quot; Knott said.</p>
<p>Noranda expected to produce 115,000 tonnes of lead at the company's Belledune smelter this year, up from 110,000 tonnes in 1996, with a goal of 120,000 tonnes, perhaps next year, Schnull said.</p>
<p>Cominco's new smelter at Trail is ramping up with the goal of reaching 100,000 tonnes. &quot;We hope to reach 120,000 tonnes with this new process,&quot; company officials at the meeting said.</p>
<p>Trail's new smelter replaces an older plant.</p>
<p>Malcolm Nordstrom of RSR Corp said the company was finding it difficult to get enough spent auto batteries whose price have now risen to 9.0 to 9.5 cents per pound.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very tight, there is none,&quot; Nordstrom said. &quot;It's a tough market. Lead is too cheap and scrap is too expensive.&quot;</p>
<p>RSR's secondary lead plants in New York, California and Indianapolis were operating at 8,000, 8,500 and 9,000 short tons per month respectively.</p>
<p>GNB Technologies, part of Australia's Pacific Dunlop, said its new secondary lead smelter in Columbus, Georgia, was now able to operate at full capacity of 60,000 short tons a year on some days and the big glitches which plagued the A$40-$50 plant initially have been resolved.</p>
<p>&quot;We are on our way to full capacity and all the major challenges have been met,&quot; Steve Emmons, manager of GNB's environmental and health assurance said.</p>
<p>The GNB smelter replaces a 20,000 short ton plant which has now been shut.</p>
<p>((Huw Jones, New York Commodity Desk 212-859-1646))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
