<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55283" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: World metal prices take another hit.</title>
<headline>World metal prices take another hit.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>World industrial metal prices took another turn for the worse on Monday, extending recent declines as bearish sentiment swamped the market.</p>
<p>Traders said consumer interest for all metals remained soft despite low prices, scotching hopes of a pick-up in demand during the traditionally busy September buying period.</p>
<p>Aluminium, used mainly in transport and packaging, slumped to a 2-1/2 year low of $1,414 a tonne on the London Metal Exchange (LME), down $22 from Friday's closing levels.</p>
<p>Rising stocks and only sporadic buying interest left the market vulnerable to further losses, traders said.</p>
<p>Recent stock increases also weighed on the lead market, which slumped three percent, or $24 to $785.</p>
<p>Nickel fell to a 2-1/2 week low of $7,350 despite weekend production cutbacks at Inco's plant in Manitoba, Canada, while tin matched Friday's six-week nadir of $6,110.</p>
<p>Copper and zinc were less volatile, finishing the day with limited losses.</p>
<p>In other commodity markets there was good news for those concerned about the risk of high food and oil prices fuelling inflation.</p>
<p>Chicago soybeans broke below the key $8.00-a-bushel barrier, with November slipping 13 cents to $7.89. Wheat futures were seven cents lower at $4.22.</p>
<p>Oil was also weaker as tensions in the Middle East appeared to be easing.</p>
<p>The nearby futures contract for the benchmark North Sea Brent Blend on the International Petroleum Exchange in London was trading below $22.40 per barrel compared with a post-Gulf War high at $24.39 on September 12.</p>
<p>In the tropical commodity markets, sugar values slumped in relatively thin trade, cocoa edged higher and coffee was mixed.</p>
<p>The London Commodity Exchange (LCE) is now trading under the London International Financial Futures (LIFFE) banner after a merger of these two markets that took effect on Monday.</p>
<p>The goal of the merger was to rescue the smaller LCE from a likely U.S. takeover and promote trading in grains in Europe.</p>
<p>In precious metals palladium was trading alost at the lowest in three years at 120.50/121.50 an ounce. Dealers cited slack demand and plentiful supply.</p>
<p>Some key commodity prices as at 1600 GMT on Monday -</p>
<p>						 Monday	    Friday</p>
<p> Gold ($/ounce)			 382.85	    383.05</p>
<p>    IPE Brent ($/barrel) (Oct)	  22.39	     24.22</p>
<p>(Ldn Metal Exchange)</p>
<p>    COPPER (three months/tonne)    1,862.00	  1,870.00</p>
<p>    ALUMINIUM			    1,414.00	  1,435.00</p>
<p>(Ldn futures)</p>
<p>    COFFEE ($/tonne) (Nov)	   1,530.00	  1,534.00</p>
<p>    COCOA (sterling/tonne) (Dec)     994.00	    989.00</p>
<p>    WHITE SUGAR ($/tonne) (Oct)	333.00	    338.00</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
