<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55285" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE gas oil ends weak as calmer Mideast hits Brent.</title>
<headline>IPE gas oil ends weak as calmer Mideast hits Brent.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE gas oil futures ended about $8 a tonne weaker and near session lows on Monday after Brent slid in response to an easing of Middle East tension which had pushed crude to five-year highs last week, brokers said.</p>
<p>Oct gas oil closed at $213.75 a tonne, down $8 from Friday's close and only 75 cents above the low for the session.</p>
<p>Dealers said gas oil fell sharply in line with Brent but the underlying picture of tight stocks in the approach to winter was continuing to provide solid fundamental support.</p>
<p>The prompt Oct/Nov backwardation recovered from an early 50-cent loss to end unchanged at +$6 a tonne.  </p>
<p>&quot;The spread slipped early to +$5.50 but it's done very little since then,&quot; said a broker.</p>
<p>Nov Brent touched a low of $22.32 a barrel before recovering to $22.40 by 1645 GMT, still 73 cents down from Friday's close.</p>
<p>Crude was expected to stay on the defensive after the U.S. backed away from further missile attacks against Iraq and Baghdad said it would no longer fire at U.S. and allied warplanes enforcing &quot;no-fly&quot; zones over Iraq.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton said the U.S. did not seek a confrontation with Iraq but did not say whether that meant he would forego immediate air strikes.  </p>
<p>Dealers said a weaker Brent-WTI arbitrage helped depress IPE futures but the market remained generally cautious.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody's really going short in case another headline comes out and they can't get it back,&quot; said a broker.</p>
<p>Kuwait approved a U.S. request to deploy extra ground troops there to expand the U.S. military presence.</p>
<p>Prompt Brent was driven to a post-Gulf War peak of $24.39 last Thursday amid widespread expectation of further U.S. military action against Iraq in retaliation for missile attacks against planes patrolling the &quot;no-fly&quot; zones.</p>
<p>-- Mark Thompson, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7930</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
