<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="552878" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Late rally boosted emerging market debts in U.S..</title>
<headline>Late rally boosted emerging market debts in U.S..</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A surge of late buying inspired by the strength in U.S. Treasuries lifted prices of emerging market bonds, traders said.</p>
<p>Spreads over Treasuries narrowed for most issues, led by a reduction of about 30 basis points for Venezuela papers, they said.</p>
<p>The volume was light because of the May Day holiday in many nations, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;People are changing their minds a little bit, that we are moving into a bull market and some people don't want to miss that and want to position a bid into that,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>But some other traders were more circumspect.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very quiet. Nobody knows what's going to happen with the U.S. budget, and everybody's waiting for tomorrow's (payrolls) number,&quot; another one trader said.</p>
<p>The U.S. April employment data are scheduled for release at 830 EDT/1230 GMT. Analysts, on average, expected a rise of 211,000 in the non-farm payrolls and the unemployment rate holding steady at 5.2 percent.</p>
<p>Venezuela pars jumped a whopping 1-1/8 to 73-1/2 bid despite the recent announcement of a 44-percent increase in the official minimum wage.  </p>
<p>&quot;Probably the market has anticipated some of this negative news and has over-reacted in the sense that DCBs went to a spread level of 500 basis points over,&quot; said Kurt Schmid, head of proprietary trading at SBC Warburg.</p>
<p>Venezuela DCBs rose 3/4 to 88-7/8 bid.</p>
<p>Venezuela Bradys have underperformed the market until the latest bounce, which Schmidt thought was &quot;more than justified&quot; by the country's relatively good credit.</p>
<p>Argentina built on its recent upward momentum, with Par bonds rising 1-1/8 to 66-1/4 bid. FRBs gained 1/2 to 92-1/4.  </p>
<p>Brazil and Mexico lagged among major Latins. Brazil C, rose 1/2 to 76-1/4 bid.</p>
<p>Mexico Pars and Mexico Discount each added 1/4 to bid 72-3/4 and 88-3/4 respectively.</p>
<p>((-- Scott Gerlach -212-859-1868))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
