<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="552969" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY precious metals end higher on moderate volumes.</title>
<headline>NY precious metals end higher on moderate volumes.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX and NYMEX precious metals futures recovered from some early weakness to end higher Thursday on moderate volumes, helped by some shortcovering by locals and funds, traders said.</p>
<p>But the May Day holiday in continental Europe Thursday and the Golden Week holidays in Japan are seen limiting activity this week.  </p>
<p>&quot;The professional gold market is very bearish and the market may go to new lows, but at prices below $340 an ounce we're seeing very solid demand by investors for coins and precious metal investment products,&quot; said Leonard Kaplan, a senior broker with MONEX in California, one of the largest U.S. retailers of precious metal investment products.</p>
<p>&quot;We're seeing some significant coin purchases, not so much from the man-on-the street buying 20 or 20 coins, but the smarter retail investor who is buying 500-800 coins at a time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>COMEX June gold ended up 50 cents at $341.70 an ounce, after seeing a $340.40-342.90 range. Estimated total COMEX gold volume was 24,000 contracts.</p>
<p>June gold has found support just above $340.00 an ounce every day this week, analysts noted, after slipping to a new contract low at $339.50 last week, when spot gold prices tested January's four year low around 4336.00.</p>
<p>Daily momentum oscillators were also suggesting the downtrend was runing out of steam for now, analysts noted, with little further speculative shorting noted by the funds in the past few days.</p>
<p>In the bullion market, spot gold ended quoted $340.15/65 midday, compared to the London Thursday afternoon fix at $339.25 and the New York close Wednesday around $339.30/80.</p>
<p>Physical offtake remained good in the Far East and through Dubai with refineries reporting lengthening processing times, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold refineries look to have very full order books, with the U.S. refinery premium over London gold about 20 cents right now, and its higher in Canada, but when gold slid under $340 an ounce recently, the refinery premium went up 60 cents an ounce,&quot; Kaplan said.</p>
<p>But despite good physical offtake the U.S. dollar price of gold in the wholesale market was not responding, suggesting supply was coming from undisclosed European central bank activity, analysts said.</p>
<p>In news Thursday, Portugal's central bank said it carried out a number of gold swaps in late 1996 but had not sold any gold.</p>
<p>The latest IMF data showed Portugal's gold reserves dropped by 1.06 million ounces in January to 14.4 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The significance of Portuguese admisssion is that it means they have joined the list of European central banks that have decided to mobilize their gold reserves,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>Renewed concerns about central bank gold sales, Australian producer hedging, and renewed shorting by funds drove gold prices down to test four year lows last week just below $340 an ounce.</p>
<p>COMEX July silver also found some support Thursday, ending up 7.5 cents at $4.768 an ounce after trading a $4.670-4.800 range.</p>
<p>Open interest in COMEX silver fell sharply again Wednesday, sliding 6,085 contracts to 85,543 lots, its lowest level since January 1996, as funds liquidate positions with volatility subsiding, analysts said.</p>
<p>NYMEX July platinum closed up $3.50 at $374.00 an ounce, while NYMEX June palladium gained 80 cents to end at $157.00.</p>
<p>Rhodium prices were bid around $275.00, after following other PGM's up in the past two months.</p>
<p>email: clive.mckeef @ reuters.com</p>
<p>((Clive McKeef, New York Commodities Desk, 212-859-1641))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
