<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55297" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Commodity turnover to rise shortly on LIFFE - Sucden.</title>
<headline>Commodity turnover to rise shortly on LIFFE - Sucden.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turnover and awareness of London commodity markets will increase substantially even before financial and commodity futures are co-housed under the new LIFFE banner, Michael Overlander, managing director at UK brokers Sucden said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;A year from now there will be a marked improvement in the volumes compared to today and that will be due to LIFFE's (London's International Finanical Futures and Options Exchange) imput, whether or not we are co-housed,&quot; Overlander said.</p>
<p>The 40-year old London Commodity Exchange (LCE) and the fast-paced LIFFE exchanges officially merged on Monday, creating the only organisation in the world to trade a complete range of financial, agricultural, soft and equity futures and options.</p>
<p>The merger of the two exchanges was secured after LIFFE offered 10.3 million stg for the LCE.</p>
<p>&quot;LIFFE has a heck of a lot to show us (commodity markets),&quot; Overlander said adding that since LIFFE was founded its volumes have soared whilst volumes in commodity trading have fallen.</p>
<p>&quot;LIFFE has demonstrated to the whole world that they know how to run a decent and hugely successful exchange,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>--Julia Meehan, London newsroom +4471 542 79 28</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
