<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553169" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: ROMANIA CHIEF SPY RESIGNS AMID ATTACKS.</title>
<headline>ROMANIA CHIEF SPY RESIGNS AMID ATTACKS.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of Romania's intelligence service said on Wednesday his decision to quit was final and denied suggestions he had done so under pressure.</p>
<p>Virgil Magureanu formally announced his departure during a parliamentary debate on the activities of the post-Communist Romanian Intelligence Service punctuated by allegations that the agency was engaged in illegal activities.</p>
<p>&quot;My decision to resign is final,&quot; Magureanu told a joint session of parliament's two chambers. &quot;The resignation is not the result of any pressure or blackmail. I felt that my mandate was over after seven years at the head of the SRI.&quot;</p>
<p>Magureanu, a former officer in the communist-era Securitate secret police, had first announced his intention to quit last November before reformist President Emil Constantinescu defeated ex-communist Ion Iliescu in presidential elections.</p>
<p>He was one of several witnesses filmed attending the summary trial of dictator Nicolae Ceausescu and his wife Elena after they had fled Bucharest during the December 1989 uprising against communist rule. Both were executed on Christmas day.</p>
<p>Magrueanu's spokesman last week confirmed his intention to quit and did nothing to deny suggestions in the press that diplomats had called for his departure to help Romania's remote bid to win early admission to NATO.</p>
<p>Romania has launched a diplomatic offensive since the election to be included in NATO's first expansion wave in July alongside favoured Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>During a day of stormy debate, parliamentarians from virtually all parties accused the intelligence service of illegal wire tapping and working against market reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;The appointment of Magureanu at the head of the SRI was a terrible blunder, with long-term consequences,&quot; said Senator Ion Badea, of the nationalist Greater Romania Party.</p>
<p>Nicolae Galbeni, head of a commission probing the intelligence service, said the agency had &quot;projected a vision of national catastrophe&quot; to block government plans to speed up reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;Many pieces of information coming from the SRI show a anti-Western attitude and amount to discreet propaganda for promoting economic isolation,&quot; Galbeni said.</p>
<p>He said the commission, empowered only to make recommendations, had found that the agency had taped phone conversations with journalists and politicians without legal authorisation. REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
