<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553222" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSTANT VIEW - Market comments on British election.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - Market comments on British election.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following is a selection  of analysts' reactions to exit polls for Britain's May 1 election pointing to a landslide victory for opposition Labour party.</p>
<p>For a full breakdown of election news -  GB/ELEX</p>
<p>JEREMY HAWKINS, SENIOR ECONOMIC ADVISOR, BANK OF AMERICA</p>
<p>2115 GMT - &quot;The main thing is the market wants to see a majority...the first round impact is relief that we're not going to get either a very small majority or a hung parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;If these polls actually translate into actual numbers then very quickly markets are going to want to see (Labour leader) Tony Blair put his money where his mouth is -- they'll need to show some kind of policy credibility very quickly in terms of a hike in the base rate and ideally a tight budget as well&quot;</p>
<p>STEVE SCOTT, GILTS ANALYST, DRESDNER KLEINWORT BENSON</p>
<p>2115 GMT - &quot;I've got a feeling the market is going to find it difficult to distinguish between a majority of 100 or 150, just as long as any fear of a hung parliament has vanished.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
