<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553399" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Seeds of discontent find fertile soil in Peru.</title>
<headline>Seeds of discontent find fertile soil in Peru.</headline>
<byline>Paul de Bendern</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poverty and social inequality still provide the seeds for revolutionary activity in Peru, but the country's remnant guerrilla groups have failed to capitalise on the widespread discontent, analysts said.</p>
<p>They warned, however, that despite the government's crushing of the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement's (MRTA) four-month hostage siege last week, rebel activity would likely continue in coming years.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an apartheid in this country on the economic and political level,&quot; said Hernando de Soto, director of Lima's private Institute of Liberty and Democracy and a former adviser to the government. &quot;As long as that exists, there is ground to plant the seeds (of rebellion).&quot;</p>
<p>Although rebel violence has waned in recent years, Peru has failed to end 17 years of bloodshed. Conflicts unleashed by the MRTA and the larger Maoist Shining Path have left more than 30,000 people dead and $25 billion infrastructure damage.</p>
<p>Beginning in 1990, President Alberto Fujimori's government adopted ruthless policies to cut down the rebels, but the 126-day hostage siege at the Japanese ambassador's home in Lima showed the revolutionary dream of a group that boasts fewer than 200 armed members can still grab world headlines.</p>
<p>Triumphant in the past, Fujimori has been careful not to overplay last week's success in which all but one of the 72 hostages were freed alive and all 14 guerrillas killed. &quot;It could be that (terrorism) is not defeated,&quot; he warned after his troops stormed the residence and overpowered the rebels.</p>
<p>Analysts say the threat of further violence will continue as long as the majority of Peruvians remain poor and marginalized, giving rebels more recruits for revolution.</p>
<p>&quot;There are various ways to counteract subversion and one of those is to solve the social problems, particularly hunger and misery. Otherwise there's the risk that subversion increases,&quot; said Congressman Javier Alva Orlandini of the opposition party Popular Action.</p>
<p>With the MRTA threatening reprisals, and Shining Path known to be regrouping at a grass-roots level, Peruvians are worried about more violence. &quot;By the very fact that the MRTA was able to seize the hostages in December, you cannot rule out the possibility of further terrorist acts,&quot; Carlos Ivan Degregori, a Peruvian guerrilla authority, said.</p>
<p>De Soto said: &quot;We are not scared of what they (guerrillas) are today but what they could potentially be in the future.&quot;</p>
<p>According to official figures, 19 percent of this South American nation of 24 million people live in extreme poverty, while 47 percent are affected by poverty. Non-governmental organisations put the figures much higher.</p>
<p>In Lima, about half of the eight million inhabitants live in shantytowns ringing the capital where water is scarce and garbage dumps are raked over for scraps of food. But the worst poverty is in highland or jungle provinces where illiterate peasants live at subsistence level in primitive communities.</p>
<p>Analysts said the rebel groups have not won popular sympathy because of their ideology of violence, victims of which have been mostly from the ranks of Peru's poor.</p>
<p>The latest attempt by the MRTA to voice its views has demonstrated to the Peruvian people their lack of a well-shaped strategy to solve the country's economic woes.</p>
<p>While their demands included improving the economic condition of the poor, the driving motive for their dramatic action was to press for release of imprisoned colleagues.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
