<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553306" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Confusion over Zaire talks; rebels advance.</title>
<headline>Confusion over Zaire talks; rebels advance.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Kotch</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Mobutu Sese Seko of Zaire and rebel leader Laurent Kabila prepared on Thursday for face-to-face talks at sea with South Africa's Nelson Mandela amid confusion over the timing of the meeting.</p>
<p>Mobutu's camp said the talks would focus on a peaceful transition with elections open to all, Kabila's camp insisted that the veteran strongman must stand down after more than three decades in power.</p>
<p>But as the civil war rivals and mediators variously announced that the talks would start on Friday, Saturday and Sunday, the rebel advance on the capital Kinshasa continued.</p>
<p>&quot;The talks will just be about Mobutu and what we do with him. Our uncompromising demand is that he leaves power and we shall look after him,&quot; Kabila said before leaving his Lubumbashi headquarters for talks in neighbouring countries.</p>
<p>&quot;There can be no ceasefire or indeed elections in this country until Mobutu and all he represents is removed and thrown away,&quot; Kabila added.</p>
<p>There was no indication Mobutu, who seized power in 1965 but is sick with cancer, was ready to step down -- although rebel &quot;foreign minister&quot; Bizima Karaha said the veteran president had agreed to discuss his departure.</p>
<p>&quot;We are happy that Mobutu has agreed to come and negotiate one and only one thing: his departure from power,&quot; Karaha said.</p>
<p>U.S. envoy Bill Richardson, who helped persuade Mobutu and Kabila to meet, told reporters in Kinshasa on Wednesday there were no preconditions for the talks.</p>
<p>Mandela said through a spokesman that he would chair the face-to-face talks on Friday aboard a South African naval vessel in international waters off the coast of West Africa.</p>
<p>Mobutu's son Nzanga said the talks had been postponed until Saturday. Karaha said Kabila could only attend on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think following that meeting there will be other negotiations that will bring I hope a peaceful transition that will lead to elections,&quot; Nzanga Mobutu told BBC radio.</p>
<p>Honore Ngbanda, Mobutu's security advisor and hitherto chief negotiator, envisaged talks on &quot;a peaceful transition leading to transparent and democratic elections that exclude no-one&quot;.</p>
<p>Kabila's rebels, who took up arms in October, say they expect to take the capital over the next 10 to 15 days. They now control over a half of the sprawling Central African nation -- including all its main cities outside the capital.</p>
<p>Residents of Kenge, just 200 km (125 miles) from Kinshasa, said the army had retreated and that the town was calm and waiting for the rebels to arrive -- a familiar pattern in the seven-month campaign.</p>
<p>Residents of Kikwit, the rebels forward base for their march on Kinshasa, said an expected rebel airlift into the town had not begun but that reinforcements had been arriving by truck.</p>
<p>The war has trapped Hutu refugees, who fled Rwanda fearing reprisals after the 1994 genocide of Tutsis. Critics accuse Zaire's Tutsi-dominated rebels of killing refugees -- or at least leaving them to die.</p>
<p>International efforts to repatriate the Hutus gathered pace. A U.N. refugee agency official said 1,438 were flown out of Zaire's third city of Kisangani on seven flights on Thursday to Rwanda's capital or its southern town of Cyangugu.</p>
<p>Thousands of other Hutus, many with appalling injuries, streamed back to camps south of Kisangani as U.N. agencies struggled to clear a backlog of those waiting to be airlifted.</p>
<p>Aid workers at Biaro camp, 41 km (25 miles) south of Kisangani, said they could not keep up with a flood of refugees returning to camps they fled in terror after attacks last week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
