<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553378" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin offers Russians Mayday congratulations.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin offers Russians Mayday congratulations.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian President Boris Yeltsin offered Mayday congratulations to his countrymen on Thursday and told the opposition its freedom to condemn him was one of the achievements of his reforms.</p>
<p>He said in a pre-recorded radio address many people would use the four-day holiday to rest and work at their garden plots.</p>
<p>&quot;Others, out of habit, will go to rallies with flags and slogans. They will condemn authorities, condemn the president,&quot; Yeltsin said.</p>
<p>&quot;They have the right to do so and this is what we have fought for. For the citizens' right to decide themselves what they want to do, both on working days and on holidays.&quot;</p>
<p>As Yeltsin's short address was broadcast, thousands of demonstrators started a march in the centre of Moscow led by the communists under the slogan &quot;Russia will be great and socialist&quot;.</p>
<p>Another rally, organised by trade unions, was taking place in another part of Moscow on a warm and sunny day.</p>
<p>Communist leader Gennady Zyuganov said earlier this week his party would start collecting signatures during the May Day rally, demanding Yeltsin's resignation. Such petitions have no legal force.</p>
<p>Yeltsin unexpectedly returned to Moscow from a holiday on the Black Sea on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>The Kremlin said it was due to bad weather and denied that the 66-year-old leader, who had heart bypass surgery last November and pneumonia in January, was ill again.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
