<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553379" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania asks Germany to invest more.</title>
<headline>Romania asks Germany to invest more.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's centrist coalition government told German businessmen their investment was needed to ensure the success of overdue market reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;Without serious foreign investment we will not overcome the economic and social crisis,&quot; Prime Minister Victor Ciorbea told 600 local and German businessmen in Bucharest on Wednesday during a visit by German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel.</p>
<p>&quot;Romania will continue to need help. The most precious support we can get now is the trust to invest in Romania.&quot;</p>
<p>Romania, Eastern Europe's second largest market after Poland, has attracted far less foreign investment than other ex-communist countries.</p>
<p>Total direct foreign investment since 1989 stood at $2.3 billion early in April, with 97 percent of it in small businesses.</p>
<p>The centrists, who defeated leftists in elections last year, have promised incentives and improved legislation aimed at benefiting companies which invest a minimum $10 million in Romania, instead of $50 million at present.</p>
<p>They include tax breaks, extension of customs duties holidays and free acquisition of land and production spaces.</p>
<p>&quot;We are determined to simplify administrative measures, cut bureaucracy, check corruption and propose new incentives for businessmen,&quot; Foreign Minister Adrian Severin said.</p>
<p>Germany was Romania's largest commercial partner in 1996, with two-way trade amounting to $5.6 billion. It is the second largest foreign investor with investments worth $220 million and 6,000 joint ventures.</p>
<p>Romania has already adopted a law allowing foreigners to own land and pledged amendments to legislation to simplify investment procedures.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
