<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553515" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Sony's strong growth seen continuing - analysts.</title>
<headline>Sony's strong growth seen continuing - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sony Corp will continue to enjoy robust earnings growth in the current business year to March 1998, helped by buoyant sales of consumer electronics and a weak yen, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The good market conditions that boosted Sony's profits last year remain unchanged,&quot; said Hitoshi Kuriyama, an analyst at Goldman Sachs (Japan) Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;I see very few risks in Sony's performance this year, except for the film-making business, where sales of some films may be disappointing,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>On May 8, Sony will announce its parent and group business results for the year that ended on March 31. It will also announce its forecasts for the current business year that started on April 1.</p>
<p>Sony in February surprised the market with a bullish earnings forecast for fiscal 1996/97, predicting 140 percent growth in its group net profit over 1995/96.</p>
<p>Sony at that time said almost all of its electronic products, such as videogame players, minidiscs and camcorders, were doing well following successive launches of new digital products.</p>
<p>Most analysts expect Sony's group operating profit for the 1997/98 year to climb to 410 to 420 billion yen from an estimated 340 to 353 billion yen in 1996/97.</p>
<p>Group net profit in 1997/98 is seen rising to around 158 to 165 billion yen, up from an estimated 134 to 137 billion yen.</p>
<p>Some analysts are watching to see how far Sony will boost sales of studio-use broadcasting equipment after launch schedules for digital broadcasting were moved forward in the United States and Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;Sony may post broadcasting equipment sales of some 300 billion yen this year (1997/98), up from 210 billion yen in 1995/96,&quot; said Kazuya Yamamoto, an analyst at Daiwa Institute of Research.</p>
<p>Sony plans to begin test-beaming of digital satellite broadcasts in Japan this year jointly with Australia's News Corp and Japan's Softbank Corp, but the impact of the digital satellite broadcasting business on Sony's profitability will be limited, analysts said.</p>
<p>Some analysts are also watching Sony's personal computer strategy as it prepares to launch its first desktop PCs in Japan this year.</p>
<p>&quot;It will give a hint about Sony's business in the next century,&quot; Goldman's Kuriyama said.</p>
<p>The following are analysts' forecasts of Sony's earnings (in billions of yen):</p>
<p>		     Morgan Stanley	UBS	  Daiwa</p>
<p>97/98 group</p>
<p>   Operating prft    409.1	     410	   420</p>
<p>   Net prft	    157.8	     157	   165</p>
<p>96/97 group</p>
<p>   Operating prft    353.5	     348	   n.a.</p>
<p>   Net prft	    137.5	     134	   n.a.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
