<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553543" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. separatists break silence in Texas standoff.</title>
<headline>U.S. separatists break silence in Texas standoff.</headline>
<byline>Kieran Murray</byline>
<dateline>FORT DAVIS, Texas 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Texas separatists holed up in a mountain hideout broke two days of silence on Thursday and responded to police phone calls, raising hopes that stalled negotiations to end a five-day standoff would resume.</p>
<p>Texas Department of Public Safety spokesman Mike Cox told reporters that Richard McLaren, leader of the separatist Republic of Texas group, answered a call from police shortly after his attorney, Terence O'Rourke, appeared on a local radio programme and asked him to resume communications.</p>
<p>&quot;So far, the conversations have, frankly, not amounted to much more than chit chat...we hope to move on to more substantive discussions later today,&quot; Cox said.</p>
<p>Dozens of heavily-armed police and 13 Republic members have been locked in a tense standoff in the Davis Mountains of west Texas since Sunday when the separatists, who advocate Texas' secession from the United States, took two hostages in a hail of gunfire. The hostages were later released, but felony charges were filed against the rebels.</p>
<p>Police were dismayed when McLaren suddenly stopped responding to their phone calls and faxes on Tuesday night. Cox said negotiators felt they had been on the verge of an agreement that would end the siege.</p>
<p>He said McLaren, a 43-year-old vintner originally from Missouri, did not explain why he had broken off talks nor why he had chosen to speak again. &quot;We're just pleased that he's back in touch with us. We think this is a productive and optimistic development,&quot; Cox said.</p>
<p>Cox said McLaren also responded to a &quot;diplomatic pouch&quot; of papers that police in an armoured personnel carrier dropped off in front of his ramshackle compound on Wednesday evening. He said McLaren had sent back confidential documents for O'Rourke.</p>
<p>Cox said an earlier threat to cut off electricity to the compound had been withdrawn because of the renewed talks.</p>
<p>Police say they have no idea how much longer the standoff -- or the uneasy peace surrounding it -- will last. They have feared from the beginning that the standoff could attract sympathetic anti-government militia groups.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Texas Rangers in Peco, Texas, 70 miles (112 km) to the north, arrested seven Republic of Texas supporters travelling in two cars loaded guns and ammunition.</p>
<p>DPS Trooper John Barton told Reuters police got a report late on Wednesday that a caravan of three recreational vehicles and other carss carrying Republic supporters from Arkansas was within 200 miles (321 kilometres) of Fort Davis.</p>
<p>&quot;We alerted all state troopers to be on the lookout,&quot; he said, but the group, which supposedly said it was on a fishing trip to New Mexico, had not been located.</p>
<p>He said there were reports of other groups planning to help the Republic of Texas, but nothing confirmed. &quot;We're asking them to stay back, stay back,&quot; Barton said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FORT DAVIS, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
