<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553519" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Iran says Asian trade ties to expand after EU row.</title>
<headline>Iran says Asian trade ties to expand after EU row.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran has told members of the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) that it would be boosting trade ties with Asia after a row with the European Union, the Iranian news agency IRNA said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;'Look east' policies will be brighter in the future and Iran's ties with Asian countries will be expanded with greater momentum,&quot; Iranian deputy foreign minister Alaeddin Boroujerdi told ASEAN envoys to Tehran in remarks reported by the agency.</p>
<p>&quot;Europe will be the main loser in this game,&quot; he said in reference to the row over a German court verdict that accused Tehran leaders of ordering the 1992 killings of four Kurdish dissidents in Berlin. Iran has denied involvement.</p>
<p>&quot;The recent developments proved this principle more than ever before that the Asian countries...should strengthen ties and expand links with each other even more,&quot; Boroujerdi told the ambassadors of Indonesia, Malaysia, Thailand, the Philippines and Brunei. ASEAN also groups Singapore and Vietnam.</p>
<p>The EU withdrew its ambassadors after the April 10 verdict. A meeting of EU foreign ministers this week agreed to send the envoys back but suspended ministerial contacts.</p>
<p>But Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei said the German ambassador was not welcome for now. Foreign Minister Ali Akbar Velayati was quoted by newspapers as saying the same also applied to the Danish envoy.</p>
<p>Iran's foreign ministry also said it was suspending all talks with the EU, including those affecting human rights, terrorism and chemical and nuclear weapons, Iranian media said.</p>
<p>The move came after the EU meeting upheld a suspension of the 15-member bloc's policy of &quot;critical dialogue&quot; with Iran, which aimed at keeping lines of communication open and move Tehran closer to the West.</p>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel on Thursday denounced as improper Iran's refusal to accept the return of its ambassador and said his country would not submit to &quot;blackmail&quot;.</p>
<p>State-run Tehran state radio on Thursday the EU of duplicity for deciding to allow the envoys to return.</p>
<p>&quot;Is it imaginable that the European Union could send its ambassadors to Tehran as if nothing had happened while at the same time insisting on its enmity against Islamic Iran by accusing Iran of committing acts against human rights?,&quot; it said in a commentary.</p>
<p>The hardline Tehran newspaper Kayhan demanded a break in trade ties with Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;It is now the duty of government officials to put a break in economic relations with Germany on the agenda and immediately close all ports and airports to German goods,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The total value of EU-Iran trade was $11.2 billion in 1995, the latest full year for which figures are available.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
