<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553520" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Thousands of Moroccan workers in May Day marches.</title>
<headline>Thousands of Moroccan workers in May Day marches.</headline>
<dateline>CASABLANCA 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tens of thousands of workers marched in Morocco's financial centre of Casablanca to mark May Day on Thursday and demanded an increase of wages and benefits, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Abderrazak Afilal, leader of the Moroccan General Workers Union (UGTM) told a meeting in Casablanca: &quot;The May Day this year reflects hope and confidence in the future...It coincides with our recent promising negiotiations with government officials and CGEM businessmen association.&quot;</p>
<p>UGTM, which is affiliated to the opposition Istiqlal party, said negotiations with the government were underway for a salary increase and a package of 1.4 billion dirhams ($150 million), to be deducted from the 1997/98 state budget, to build houses for workers and civil servants at reasonable prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The government should implement its promises and order the private sector to improve the condition of millions of workers in industry, fisheries and textile sectors,&quot; another UGTM leader said.</p>
<p>The Confederation Democratique du Travail group (CDT), which belongs to the opposition Socialist Union of Peoples Forces (USFP), also joined the UGTM to press demands for what is described &quot;the necessary improvement of working class material and moral conditions&quot;.</p>
<p>CDT is considered as an ally of UGTM but the two groups organised separate marches in the city of four million.</p>
<p>Other parades took place in the country's main cities with slogans underlining the same demands, the official MAP news agency said.</p>
<p>Morocco has a workforce of an estimated 10 million, of which around 50 percent is concentrated in urban areas. It has three main trade unions, including the independent Union Marocaine du Travail which controls half-a-million members.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CASABLANCA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
