<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553760" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Arbor hopes CFTC will approve CBOT corn/soy plan.</title>
<headline>Arbor hopes CFTC will approve CBOT corn/soy plan.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chicago Board of Trade Chairman Pat Arbor said on Thursday he hopes the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) will approve proposed changes in the CBOT corn and soybean delivery system despite opposition from some commercial firms, farm groups and politicians.</p>
<p>&quot;I certainly hope that the CFTC moves expeditiously and quickly to approve the plan and not tamper with it or adjust it,&quot; Arbor said in an interview with Reuters.  </p>
<p>The proposal, approved by the CBOT membership last month by a two-to-one margin, drops delivery in Toledo, Ohio, and changes delivery to elevators on the Illinois River from Pekin, Ill., to Chicago, and at Burns Harbor, Ind.</p>
<p>Pending CFTC approval, the changes go into effect with the March 1999 corn contract and January 1999 soybean contract.</p>
<p>But on April 18, the CFTC extended a public comment period on the proposal for another 60 days after the agency received hundreds of letters, mostly critical of the proposal.  </p>
<p>The plan has drawn fire largely from eastern Corn Belt merchants, producers and politicians who objected to dropping Toledo. Other opponents have said the change places unfair emphasis on grain export channels and does not offer adequate rail access to the grain.</p>
<p>Arbor acknowledged the plan &quot;disadvantaged&quot; eastern Corn Belt users but said the advantages to the central and western portions of the belt, where the bulk of the crops are grown, outweighed objections from the east.</p>
<p>&quot;We recognize the eastern interest,&quot; he said. &quot;While I'm sympathetic to it, I strongly support the proposal.&quot;  </p>
<p>Arbor said unit train access to the proposed new delivery area was developed, as were rail lines to Pacific ports that were shipping points for the Asian customers who have become growing sources of demand for U.S. grains.</p>
<p>Among opponents was Rep. Marcy Kaptur, an Ohio Democrat, who last week inserted language in an emergency bill on disaster relief that would delay implementing the CBOT plan until a General Accounting Office (GAO) review was completed.</p>
<p>Arbor said other lawmakers, including Senator Dick Durbin (D-IL) and other Illinois members of Congress, would likely oppose that language and succeed in getting it deleted.</p>
<p>&quot;I would suggest to her (Kaptur) to carefully consider what's in the best interest of the American producer,&quot; Arbor said. &quot;I do not think it is necessary to have a GAO review.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We think in the end it will not be acted upon,&quot; he added. &quot;Believe me, there will be opposition to it.&quot;</p>
<p>((Emily Kaiser 312-408-8749))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
