<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553924" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - May 1.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - May 1.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indian business and political stories in leading newspapers prepared for REUTERS by Business News and Information Services Pvt Ltd, New Delhi Tel:3324842, 3351006, 3761233 Fax:+91-11-3351006 Internet: biznis@giasbm01.vsnl.net.in</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>		   -------oo0oo-------</p>
<p>			TOP STORIES</p>
<p>The Hindustan Times</p>
<p>NO SHIELDING OF GUILTY, NO WITCH HUNTING: PRIME MINISTER</p>
<p>Prime minister I.K. Gujral assured parliament that the guilty would not be spared in the Bihar animal husbandry scandal. Reaffirming his earlier commitment, Gujral said his government would ensure transparency in its dealings, eschew witch hunting and see to it that the guilty were brought to book. The prime minister's intervention followed a demand by the opposition as well as the leftwing constituents of the ruling United Front that Bihar chief minister Laloo Prasad Yadav resign following the decision to prosecute him in the scandal.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Times Of India</p>
<p>FEAR OF SPLIT DEFLATES 'REMOVE LALOO' CAMPAIGN</p>
<p>Prime minister I.K. Gujral and his Janata Dal colleagues have decided to go slow in the &quot;remove Laloo Prasad Yadav&quot; campaign, for fear of precipitating a split in the party. United Front sources said party functionaries were monitoring the mood of members of its Bihar legislature party, which was clearly no longer united in its commitment to the chief minister.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Pioneer</p>
<p>LOYALISTS TURN HEAT ON LALOO</p>
<p>Bihar chief minister Laloo Prasad Yadav has spoken to prime minister I.K. Gujral and state governor A.R. Kidwai, triggering speculation that he might resign. Gujral was believed to have hinted that Yadav should take a reasonable stand to avoid a constitutional crisis if he was charged in the animal husbandry scandal. Several loyalists also appealed to the chief minister to resign to save himself from further embarrassment.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Economic Times</p>
<p>NO SMOOTH SAILING FOR BROADCAST BILL</p>
<p>The draft Broadcast Bill was not accepted by the cabinet in toto. A number of changes were made in the draft legislation since it was first placed before the cabinet. The Bill now adopted proposes to permit free to air news and current affairs, sports and educational channels from the requirement of licences. Entertainment channels, however, would have to obtain licences from the proposed broadcast authority to beam into the country. The broadcast authority, which would be set up through the passage of the Bill, would also ask licensees to declare all information required for transparency and to ascertain the true ownership of the applicant.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>BANKS STRIVE TO REVIVE MIBOR</p>
<p>Eight banks, including Standard Chartered, ANZ Grindlays, Citibank, Bank of America and Hongkong Bank, held a meeting to try and revive the still born Mumbai inter-bank offer rate (Mibor). The banks decided to start providing two-way quotes on a daily basis in an attempt to boost the term money market. The meeting was called to discuss the impediments being faced by banks in creating a term money market and ways to remove them. The banks decided to refer some of these problems to the apex bank committee on money markets.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>KICK OFF DERIVATIVES TRADE WITH INDEX FUTURES - SEBI</p>
<p>Trading in derivatives should be introduced only through index futures, the Securities and Exchange Board of India's (SEBI) panel on regulating derivatives trading said. It recommended derivatives trading along with stocks on bourses and there was no need for a separate exchange. It was felt there could be some synergy in the trading of derivatives and stocks if undertaken on the same exchange.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>PLANNING COMMISSION BLAMED FOR NOT PROVIDING FUNDS</p>
<p>The World Bank has accused the Planning Commission of not providing enough funds to the states to complete externally aided projects. The bank threatened to cancel some of the loans for irrigation and power projects if loan disbursement did not improve soon. The bank was also believed to have decided against funding power and irrigation projects. Despite India's assurance to restructure state power utilities, the World Bank said it would not provide any finance to the power sector till they earned a three percent rate of return.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Financial Express</p>
<p>PUBLIC ACCOUNTS COMMITTEE SEEKS DETAILS OF TAX CASES</p>
<p>The Public Accounts Committee (PAC) has sought details of provisional tax assessment cases against tobacco firm ITC Ltd and Hindustan Lever from the Finance Ministry. The PAC tabled its report in Parliament and pointed out that the finance ministry should go into the details of the cases involving ITC and HLL. The Committee also instructed the Finance Ministry to give reasons why the cases of provisional assessments in respect of these two assesses were still pending.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>U.S. PUTS INDIA ON PRIORITY WATCH LIST</p>
<p>The United States has placed India on its priority watch list under the U.S. Trade Law 301 for its alleged failure to provide protection to American intellectual property, particularly patents. The U.S. trade representative's (USTR) office said the U.S. would engage India in a dialogue aimed not only at resolving the problem that brought about its inclusion in the list but also at seeking an improvement in the overall level of its intellectual property protection.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business Standard</p>
<p>BILL TO PASS MUSTER: IBRAHIM</p>
<p>Information and Broadcasting Minister C.M. Ibrahim said the proposed Broadcasting Bill would be passed in the budget session despite the Left's critism. He said the bill would be referred to a select committee which would be asked to resolve differences on crossmedia holdings. The bill incorporates the views of all political parties, he said. Left leaders wanted the Prasar Bharati Bill to precede the Broadcasting Bill. They objected to proposals on direct-to-home (DTH) broadcasts, arguing that only Doordarshan should be allowed to provide DTH facilities. The Left also opposed to allowing satellite uplink from India.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>RESERVE NORMS MAY BE IMPOSED ON SHORT TERM DEPOSITS</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) was likely to slap reserve requirements on financial institutions planning to tap the short-term market for resources in order to place them at par with commercial banks. The institutions have decided to make an aggressive foray into short-term lending and would need to raise short term resources for this. Commercial banks were lobbying the RBI to impose cash reserve ratio and statutory liquidity ratio on at least part of the institutions' liabilities.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>ROYALTY RATES OF MINERALS REVISED</p>
<p>The Ministry of Steel and Mines has increased the royalty rates of major minerals by eight to 14 percent. The ministry said the royalty accruals to the state governments from major minerals would go up by more than one billion rupees annually. The government also revised the rates of dead rent which would be based on the area of the lease and would increase with the number of years of holding.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Observer</p>
<p>DAEWOO TO INVEST MORE THAN 35 BLN RUPEES IN PLANT</p>
<p>Daewoo Corporation plans to invest more than 35 billion rupees in its plant in Surajpur, near Delhi. The company has remained the single largest investor in the domestic automobile industry and has already invested over 20 billion rupees in the factory. Daewoo also planned to make light and heavy commercial vehicles. Sources said the company was set to introduce four more models, including a small car, in the next two years in the Indian market.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
