<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553954" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan's Habib Bank seen privatised by 1999.</title>
<headline>Pakistan's Habib Bank seen privatised by 1999.</headline>
<byline>Ovais Subhani</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The new chief of state-run Habib Bank Ltd (HBL) said he must tackle bad debts, poor management and bureaucratic meddling before offering Pakistan's largest commercial bank for sale by 1999.</p>
<p>Shaukat Tareen's task is to turn HBL around and get it ready for privatisation. &quot;It is difficult, but not that difficult as many people think,&quot; he said in an interview with newspaper reporters. Reuters obtained a copy of the interview, which is to be published on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;All I have to do is introduce discipline, stop interference from the bureaucracy and politicians, bring in some fresh talent and new ideas and then you will see that this will be a great bank,&quot; Tareen said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the ultimate challenge is to make it a viable entity and then privatise it.</p>
<p>&quot;It (HBL) will obviously start performing next year and I think by 1999 we should be able to take it to the market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On the request of Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif, Tareen has taken leave as head of the Thailand operations of U.S.-owned Citibank to become the first private sector banker to run a state-run bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Habib Bank in many ways is the microcosm of the economy. This means that whatever issues which the HBL is facing are the same being faced by the economy,&quot; Tareen said.</p>
<p>&quot;Incompetence, loot and plunder, absolutely no strategy, very poor customer service and no product innovation...net bad governance,&quot; he said adding that the same was the case with the overall economy.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say closing down of some of the unprofitable branches, and cleaning up the inefficient staff should do,&quot; he said, adding he would prune management to cut costs and improve customer service.</p>
<p>Moody's Investors Service in October last year assigned to HBL long and short- term bank deposit ratings of B2/Not Prime and a financial strength rating of E, saying the &quot;management may not be able to solve the bank's problems unilaterally and there is likely to be an eventual need for outside assistance&quot;.</p>
<p>Tareen said despite capturing 35 percent of 765 billion rupees ($19 billion) of total bank deposits, HBL has a non-performing loan portfolio of 35 billion to 40 billion rupees, a lot of excess staff and a network of 1,930 branches of which more than half are in the red.</p>
<p>Tareen said he planned to take tough action against defaulters but added he would be pragmatic when dealing with different types of bad debts.</p>
<p>He said some bad debts were wilful, backed by political or economic patronage, others were the result of bad management and some because of an economic down cycle.</p>
<p>HBL would adopt innovative techniques used elsewhere, such as debt-equity swaps, to manage bad debts, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not use the traditional stick only, but will use the carrot as well.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Pakistan had a high interest rate environment, saying loans in the range of 24 percent to 40 percent for house finance, auto finance and credit cards could not be expected to perform well.</p>
<p>Tareen opposed the establishment of a Resolution Trust, a body proposed for cleaning up the estimated 130 billion rupees of bad debts, mostly with the state-run financial sector. He said this would be an expensive answer to the problem.</p>
<p>He said strict foreclosure laws were needed to deal with the bad debts but added that the number one requisite for turning around the state financial sector was to bring in more chief executives from the private sector and eventually to privatise state firms. ($1 = 40.2 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
