<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="554021" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ford boosts sport/utility production.</title>
<headline>Ford boosts sport/utility production.</headline>
<dateline>WAYNE, Mich. 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ford Motor Co said Thursday its Michigan Truck Plant will make 100 percent full-size sport/utilities, coinciding with the start of production of its new Lincoln Navigator later this month.</p>
<p>The change will allow Ford to make 282,000 Expeditions and Navigators a year, up 28,000 units from the previous production mix of 45 Expeditions and five F-Series pickup trucks an hour.  </p>
<p>Michigan Truck, the only plant that makes the full-size sport/utilities, began production of the Expedition last July. Since then, it has made more than 150,000 of the popular vehicles, one of the most profitable at Ford.</p>
<p>Ford has not set a formal Job One production launch yet for the Navigator, a luxury version of the popular Expedition, but it will be later this month, said spokesman Mike Vaughn. The Navigator is due to go on sale July 1.  Ford has said it expects to sell 30,000 Navigators a year.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Expedition is now a clear leader in its segment, and we believe initial demand for the Lincoln Navigator indicates another winner,&quot; said Jacques Nasser, president or Ford Automotive Operations, in a statement.</p>
<p>All 1997 model year F-Series pickup production lost at Michigan Truck due to the change will be made up through overtime work on weekdays and Saturdays at other Ford truck plants now producing the F-Series.</p>
<p>Ford makes the F-Series trucks at plants in Norfolk, Va., Oakville, Ontario, and Kansas City.</p>
<p>Ford said it is studying how to make up lost production of F-Series on a long-term basis, once 1998 model production begins this summer.  If market conditions changed, Ford said it would be able to return F-Series production to Michigan Truck within 90 days.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WAYNE, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
