<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55406" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Leading Moslem, Serb candidates take early lead.</title>
<headline>Leading Moslem, Serb candidates take early lead.</headline>
<byline>Mark Heinrich</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leading Moslem and Serb candidates for a new collective Bosnian presidency were well ahead of their rivals according to early results in the country's first post-war elections, organisers said on Monday.</p>
<p>President Alija Izetbegovic was comfortably ahead of his main rival for the Moslem seat in Bosnia's new three-man presidency, former premier Haris Silajdzic, by 75 per cent to 25 per cent, scrutineers said.</p>
<p>In the Bosnian Serb republic, incomplete results from eastern Bosnia showed Momcilo Krajisnik, candidate of the ruling Serb Democratic Party (SDS), with 83.6 per cent of the vote.</p>
<p>His nearest rival, Milan Ivanic of the opposition Democratic Patriotic bloc, had 15 per cent.</p>
<p>The first results showed Kresimir Zubak, favoured to win the Bosnian Croat seat, trailing his rival.</p>
<p>International organisers cautioned that the samples, particularly for the Moslem contest, were too small to indicate reliably whether Izetbegovic would win a big enough majority to ensure he would head the presidency, which will also have Croat and Serb representatives.</p>
<p>Izetbegovic's SDA party feared that Silajdzic might take enough votes to let a Bosnian Serb candidate capture the presidency's senior seat.</p>
<p>Organisers also noted that while east Bosnia is an SDS stronghold, some 70 percent of Bosnian Serbs live in the north.</p>
<p>The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), which is organising the poll, said it had received 75 protests over the conduct of Bosnia's first post-war elections and a respected monitoring group said the balloting was not remotely free and fair.</p>
<p>Some of the complaints involved groups, apparently Moslem refugees bused under NATO security into separatist Serb territory to vote, who said they were disenfranchised because their names were missing from polling station lists.</p>
<p>One was a challenge by the SDA which denounced voting results on Serb territory as fraudulent, before they were even announced, and vowed not to recognised them.</p>
<p>Authorities must rule on complaints within 72 hours of receipt. Elections results cannot be certified before all protests are resolved.</p>
<p>An independent monitoring agency said many refugees in Bosnia were effectively disenfranchised because of technical errors in voter registration.</p>
<p>Some 200,000 refugees abroad may have been unable to vote for the same reason, the Soros Foundation-backed International Crisis Group (ICG) said in a statement.</p>
<p>A U.N. spokesman said only 14,700 of an eligible 150,000 displaced people dared to cross Bosnia's internal boundary lines to vote on terrain from which they were evicted by nationalist militias during the 1992-95 war.</p>
<p>International officials at an election post-mortem briefing blamed the poor turnout for buses hired to take refugees across ethnic lines on several factors, including a postponement of municipal voting and a general climate of fear.</p>
<p>ICG monitors said most refugees who wanted to vote in the Serb entity did not because polling stations were deliberately placed well away from their old neighbourhoods and because of confusion over security precautions.</p>
<p>&quot;Against this background of adverse conditions, electoral engineering and disenfranchisement, these elections cannot be described as free, fair or democratic,&quot; the ICG said.</p>
<p>International officials also conceded that the Bosnian Serbs placed some polling stations in &quot;unsavoury locations&quot; intended to intimidate refugees hoping to come home one day.</p>
<p>One station was set up in a school in an eastern village where U.N. war-crimes investigators believe a large number of unarmed Moslems from Srebrenica were executed by Serb forces, said U.N. police monitor spokesman Alex Ivanko.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
