<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="554267" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian Liberals unveil new spending plans.</title>
<headline>Canadian Liberals unveil new spending plans.</headline>
<byline>Randall Palmer</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's Liberals, forced on Wednesday into an early release of their election platform, unveiled spending plans for when Canada's deficit is finally licked but immediately drew their campaign rivals' scorn.</p>
<p>The populist Reform Party had on Tuesday scooped Prime Minister Jean Chretien by releasing key details from a leaked copy of the Liberal platform, throwing the Liberals into a tizzy and causing Chretien to release it a day ahead of time.</p>
<p>The new document, dubbed Red Book Two as a sequel to the 1993 Liberal platform, pledged C$6.5 billion (US $4.6 billion) of new spending over the next five years, and Chretien said the Liberal way was to think that government was good.</p>
<p>&quot;This notion that the government will be out of everything -- what kind of society will that be?&quot; Chretien asked a news conference in the prairie city of Saskatoon. &quot;A government has a role to play.&quot;</p>
<p>Reform leader Preston Manning said in Ottawa: &quot;Goodbye Red Book, hello checkbook. It's your checkboook that's going to suffer from this document.&quot;</p>
<p>Conservative leader Jean Charest, vying with Reform for the support of the right wing, symbolically made a declaration in front of an H&amp;R Block tax accounting office since April 30 is the deadline for Canadians to file income returns.</p>
<p>&quot;It's written over Jean Chretien's door in stark letters: You send it, we'll spend it,&quot; he declared.</p>
<p>On the left, New Democratic Party (NDP) leader Alexa McDonough called it the &quot;Retread Book&quot; and asked why Canadians should believe it in light of a litany of broken promises.</p>
<p>Canada has the highest personal income taxes among the leading industrial nations. Forty-eight percent of an average family's income goes to the ta xman, a study this week showed.</p>
<p>On Sunday Chretien called a June 2 federal election, 1-1/2 years before he was required to do so, in order to capitalize on a commanding lead in the polls.</p>
<p>He had used the Red Book to great effect in sweeping to a solid majority in 1993, and Red Book Two was supposed to give the Liberals new impetus as they near the end of a battle to eliminate fiscal deficits.</p>
<p>It pledged that once the budget is balanced, half of any new surplus would go to new spending. The other half would be divided between debt reduction and tax relief.</p>
<p>But even then, Chretien said Canadians' needs must come before broad tax cuts, ones that give all taxpayers relief.</p>
<p>&quot;We won't promise across-the-board tax cuts before addressing the needs of Canadians,&quot; he declared.</p>
<p>Pollsters say that among decided voters, the Liberals hold a lead ranging from 24 to 40 percentage points, though a large portion of the populace has not made up its mind.</p>
<p>A Compas poll published in Wednesday's Financial Post gave the Liberals 47 percent of decided voters against 18 percent to the Conservatives, 13 percent for Reform, 10 percent for the NDP and 11 percent for the separatist Bloc Quebecois.</p>
<p>The poll was taken from April 15 to 25, before Chretien's announcement of the election date. Some media pundits have commented that he had a shaky start as he stumbled to explain what issues required an election 1-1/2 years early.</p>
<p>The central province of Manitoba has been preoccupied more with its worst flood in 145 years, and Chretien said on Wednesday that it was possible that voting could be postponed in the affected areas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
