<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55433" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Greece's Intracom to modernise Bulgarian lottery.</title>
<headline>Greece's Intracom to modernise Bulgarian lottery.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's sports lottery operator and Greece's  Intracom group said on Monday they had sealed a deal to introduce modern technology into the Bulgarian game, ending a long-running battle between the two firms.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreement envisages the implementation of one of the most modern technologies, using On-Line Systems comparable to those used in Europe and the United States for organising games based on chance,&quot; said the joint statement.</p>
<p>It said the project, to be financed by Intracom, was the biggest investment in the field of information technology in Bulgaria in recent years, with investment totalling more than $40 million.</p>
<p>The statement said the project guaranteed a big growth in the revenues of the Bulgarian Sports Totalisator (lottery), which help fund Bulgarian sport.</p>
<p>It also said Intracom would not implement the decision of the International Arbitrage Court in Paris, which last year ruled that the Bulgarian lottery should pay the Greek grouping $10 million for cancellation of an earlier contract.</p>
<p>A Bulgarian court is due to rule on the Paris court's decision this Wednesday.</p>
<p>The lottery, which runs a number-forecasting game and also tries to forecast the results of Britain's premier division soccer games, is very popular in Bulgaria. It has thousands of betting shops across the country.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's prominent coach in artistic gymnastics Neshka Robeva has launched a campaign against the new agreement with Intracom, saying it threatens the funding of Bulgarian sport.</p>
<p>-- Liliana Semerdjieva, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
