<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="554343" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Iran emerges as a mystery big buyer in world wheat.</title>
<headline>Iran emerges as a mystery big buyer in world wheat.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran is emerging as the world's biggest importer of wheat in the current year, according to figures from the International Grains Council on Thursday</p>
<p>The London-based IGC, an authoritative monitor of supply/demand trends in world grain, saw Iran importing 6.6 million tonnes of wheat and flour in the 12 months to June 30, 1997 - ahead of Egypt on 6.2 and Japan at 6.0 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The forecast for Iran in the latest IGC monthly report was sharply up from an estimate of 5.0 million tonnes a month ago and from the estimated total for 1995-96 of 3.0 million.</p>
<p>The IGC offered no explanation. Grain traders say the surge is something of a mystery but believe that much of the wheat is for re-export elsewhere in central Asia after poor harvests there.</p>
<p>The rise in demand from Iran is offset by the lower Chinese imports after good crops in China.</p>
<p>The IGC retained an estimate of the total 1996 world wheat crop at a bumper 580 million tonnes, up from a drought-hit 1995 total of 540 million tonnes.</p>
<p>And it forecast 1997 as only just lower, at 578 million.</p>
<p>Its report was issued against a backdrop of renewed concern about high grain prices, at a time when world stocks are around the lowest in 20 years.</p>
<p>Wheat prices &quot;spiked&quot; to historic highs in Chicago grain pits at $7.50 per bushel early in 1996. After flood and freeze in North America and a prolonged dry spell in Europe, some analysts see a risk that importers will again be paying inflated food bills.</p>
<p>Chicago wheat traded at $4.50 in April, up from $3.80 at the end of 1996, and the European Union has reimposed a tax on exports to keep a lid on its internal prices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
