<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="554589" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: 3M sees $500 mln after tax gain from sale.</title>
<headline>3M sees $500 mln after tax gain from sale.</headline>
<byline>Jane Light</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing Co said Thursday it could see a gain of nearly $500 million from a proposed $1 billion sale of its outdoor advertising and mall advertising company.</p>
<p>&quot;We won't know the exact gain until the close of the sale but we are looking at close to $500 million after taxes and after severance liabilities,&quot; Mary Auvin, a spokeswoman for 3M, said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Earlier, 3M said it agreed to sell National Advertising Company to Outdoor Systems Inc for $1 billion.  </p>
<p>The sale is contingent on government approval which might take from 30 to 120 days, she said.</p>
<p>National Advertising employs about 180 people at its headquarters in Bedford Park, Ill. and about 530 people across the United States.</p>
<p>The company has about 22,000 billboards, 2,400 poster panels which appear on the sides of buildings, and another 6,700 displays in regional malls. Its annual revenues are estimated by industry sources at about $220 million.  </p>
<p>Auvin noted that consolidation in the outdoor advertising industry is accelerating and it &quot;was not until this year that 3M decided to take a more active role in bringing the business unit to market for sale. It made a lot of sense,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>3M's outdoor advertising business began about 50 years ago with acquisition of a company in 1947, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;The outdoor advertising industry has changed significantly in recent years, and we recognize that substantial investments would be required to maintain market leadership,&quot; said Ray Richelsen, 3M group vice president, in a statement.  </p>
<p>Outdoor Systems Inc, based in Phoenix, Ariz., is the largest outdoor advertising company in North America operating 58,000 display faces in 22 metropolitan markets in the United States and seven metropolitan markets in Canada. It has been growing through acquisition and acquired Gannett Co Inc's outdoor division in August 1996 for about $700 million.</p>
<p>Outdoor Systems went public in April 1996.</p>
<p>		  ((Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
