<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="554745" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - May 1.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - May 1.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>-- U.K. HOUSING MARKET CONTINUES STRONG RECOVERY</p>
<p>Figures from the Lord Chancellor's department reveal that home repossessions hit an eight-year low in the first three months of 1997. There were 14,869 home repossession orders in January-March, the lowest figure since late 1989. Separately, figures from Britain's second largest building society, Nationwide, show that sharp increases in house prices in southeast England have lifted the average cost of a home by 8.9 per cent in the past year.</p>
<p>-- SHARE SALE PLAN VALUES NTT ARM AT $20 BLN</p>
<p>Japanese telecoms carrier NTT DoCoMo is planning the largest ever offering of shares in a cellular telecoms operator. The sale, scheduled to take place in the second half of 1998, is expected to value the company at more than $20 billion. Such a figure would make it the world's most highly capitalised quoted mobile phone operator.</p>
<p>-- FAST-GROWING U.S. ECONOMY SHIFTS INTO A HIGHER GEAR</p>
<p>Figures from the U.S. Commerce Department reveal that the U.S. economy expanded at its fastest rate in almost 10 years in the first three months of 1997. GDP grew at a real annual rate of 5.6 per cent in the first quarter, providing further evidence that the long business expansion of the 1990s has shifted up a gear. Stocks and shares remained unmoved by the figures, buoyed by the knowledge that despite the growth there remains little obvious sign of inflation.</p>
<p>-- IRISH PUNT FALLS AGAINST POUND, MARK</p>
<p>With the currency markets betting on Ireland entering European economic and monetary union at its inception, and weakening the currency's traditional ties with the UK, the punt fell on Wednesday to its weakest level against sterling since July 1992. It dropped 6.5 pfennigs against the mark to close at 2.602. The movements follow comments from Prime Minister John Bruton that the Irish currency was now decoupled from Britain.</p>
<p>-- BURGER KING FACES CLAIM ON COST OF SUPPLIES</p>
<p>Fast food restaurant franchise Burger King is facing legal action from one of its largest independent franchisees. Solicitors for the franchisee, J&amp;H Kyrris partnership of Yorkshire and the east Midlands, have issued a writ at the High Court claiming Burger King forced it to buy materials from an approved supplier at unfairly high prices.</p>
<p>-- SUMMERS SHRUGS OFF EURO THREAT</p>
<p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Lawrence Summers has predicted that the euro is unlikely to replace the dollar any time soon as the world's leading reserve currency. Speaking to an international financial conference in New York, Summers said that predictions that investors and central banks would find the euro a more attractive currency had been overstated.</p>
<p>-- BT OFFERS DATA NETWORK PACKAGES</p>
<p>British Telecom has announced details of a managed data network service, the first step in a campaign to woo smaller businesses with a &quot;packaged&quot; approach to data networking. BT is offering 24-hours a day support at prices up to 40 per cent lower than it would cost companies to build and maintain their</p>
<p>own networks.</p>
<p>-- NATWEST SET TO SUPPORT SOLAR ENERGY SCHEME</p>
<p>National Westminster Group has said it intends to convert one of its buildings to solar energy as part of an international scheme to cut the costs of solar energy. Mike Kelly, environmental manager at the bank, announced that the installation of solar panels at one of the bank's buildings was &quot;subject to technical and financial aspects being resolved&quot;, but</p>
<p>that such an approach was &quot;the easiest way to learn about it&quot;.</p>
<p>-- ANDERSON VOTES AGAINST SPLIT</p>
<p>Partners in global accountancy and consultancy empire, Anderson Worldwide have voted against a split from the company's consultancy arm and in support of keeping the empire together.</p>
<p>-- UK GROUPS MAY HALT RUSSIAN INVESTMENT</p>
<p>Mercury Asset Management, M&amp;G and Robert Fleming of the UK have written a letter to Russian President Boris Yeltsin warning they could be ending their investment in the country's stock market. The three firms do not agree with the uncertainty created in April after the Russian court stated the privatisation of Lenzoloto gold company was invalid. Australian group Star Mining had made an agreement to receive 49 per cent of gold from Lenzoloto, but are now unable to, angering Mercury, M&amp;G and Robert Fleming, all of whom have a stake in Star Mining.</p>
<p>-- BICC SHARES FALL SHARPLY ON PROFITS WARNING</p>
<p>Cables and construction group BICC shares have fallen to their lowest point in a year, following announcements by the company that lower demand for power cables and price reductions in Italy and Germany would undermine first-half profits.</p>
<p>For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC</p>
<p>+44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
