<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="554723" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pentagon's number-two official to leave post.</title>
<headline>Pentagon's number-two official to leave post.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deputy U.S. Defense Secretary John White, the Pentagon's number-two official, will leave his post in June to return to private life after two years on the job, the Defense Department said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Pentagon spokesman Ken Bacon said Defense Secretary William Cohen will quickly begin looking for a replacement for White, a former business executive and defense analyst. But he also said Cohen was concentrating on a sweeping review of U.S. security policy and force structure.</p>
<p>&quot;They just discussed it earlier this week. It's a little early to be talking about (replacement) names,&quot; Bacon told Reuters. &quot;The secretary will probably review options both inside and outside of the department.&quot;</p>
<p>The Washington Post reported on Thursday that White, a former business executive and an assistant defense secretary under former President Jimmy Carter, informed Cohen he will leave this summer after remaining long enough to help out in the so-called Quadrennial Defense Review.</p>
<p>Cohen is the only Reublican on President Bill Clinton's Cabinet, but has stressed that he has been under no pressure to name Democrats to senior Pentagon posts. He gained a reputation as a bipartisan leader as a member of the Senate and U.S. House of Representatives from Maine.</p>
<p>White, 60, agreed when Cohen replaced William Perry as secretary in February that he would stay for at least several months to assist in a smooth transition and to work on the QDR, which will result in major decisions on arms modernization and force structure.</p>
<p>The QDR report is due to be sent to Congress on May 15.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now at the end of a very successful transition,&quot; White said in a letter to Cohen released by the Pentagon. &quot;The time has now come for me to move on to new challenges.&quot;</p>
<p>In a letter of reply dated Wednesday, Cohen praised White's leadership and guidance.</p>
<p>&quot;From the day I was nominated Dec. 5, you have been unfailingly helpful and professional in the transition between Dr. Perry and me,&quot; Cohen wrote.</p>
<p>The Post reported that White had no firm idea of what he wanted to do next.</p>
<p>White, a former vice president of Eastman Kodak Co., was named by Perry to become deputy secretary after heading a blue-ribbon panel of military and private experts on streamlining the armed forces. He is considered a skilled administrator.</p>
<p>White left Eastman Kodak in 1992 and served as director of the Center on Business and Government at Harvard's John F. Kennedy School of Government until he became deputy secretary under Perry.</p>
<p>The deputy secretary is a graduate of Cornell University and owns a home on Cape Cod, Massachusetts. He also holds master's and doctoral degrees from Syracuse University.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
