<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55473" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish depos soar as cash-shortage deepens.</title>
<headline>Polish depos soar as cash-shortage deepens.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish one-day deposit rates soared past discount rate levels on Monday and nearly hit the 25 percent lombard rate as practically all players searched for cash on the barren market in late trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Only the early bird got the worm this morning...since then the market was almost completely dry,&quot; said Wlodzimierz Kado of Bank Handlowy SA.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market's cash shortage, which has been keeping rates above the 14-day drainage rate of 19.15 percent for about a week, was likely caused by banks' overinvesting in high-yielding NBP-bills earlier in September.  </p>
<p>They said T-bill payments on Wednseday for today's auction and monthly tax payments around the 20th are likely to keep rates from returing to drainage levels for most of the week.</p>
<p>Overnight rates closed at 23.20/24.00 percent up from Friday's close at 20.80/21.90 percent. Tomorrow/next rates were at 23.30/24.00 percent, against last week's 19.90/21.90.</p>
<p>The treasury sold 566 million zlotys worth of T-bills at its primary auction after investors bid for 923 million.</p>
<p>The average yield of the 13- and 26-week paper held flat at 18.60 and 19.11 percent respectively, but it increased by 0.04 to 19.46 percent for the benchmark 52-week bills.  </p>
<p>Dealers said banks sold T-bills on the secondary market to gain liquidity, which caused yields to rise.</p>
<p>In secondary trade three-month paper was quoted around 18.80 percent and six-month T-bills around 19.15 percent.</p>
<p>The Central Statistical Office (GUS) said consumer prices rose 0.5 percent in August, against market expectations of 0.57 percent, increasing year-on-year inflation to 20.5 percent from 20.4 percent in July.</p>
<p>&quot;August inflation was well within the expectations of the market, whose focus will now switch to September price growth data,&quot; said Wojciech Kowalczyk, dealer at Bank Handlowy SA.  </p>
<p>Analysts and dealers said a modest rise in consumer prices in September would cause the year-on-year index to fall significantly because of the large three percent price jump in September of last year.</p>
<p>Analysts expected prices to grow by 1.4 percent this month, according to a Reuter poll of the country's 26 largest banks.</p>
<p>GUS said producer prices rose 0.9 percent in August taking year-on-year producer price index (PPI) down to 11.4 percent.</p>
<p>Polish PPI rose only 7.2 percent in the January-August period, against a 13.2 percent rise in the same period of 1995.  </p>
<p>The Polish zloty closed slightly stronger against the basket of currencies after drifing sideways in uneventful trade for most of Monday's session.</p>
<p>It was at 1.71/1.65 pct from the trading band centre, just up from Friday's close at 1.71/1.65 percent.</p>
<p>The zloty closed at 2.7858/63 to the dollar, down from last week's 2.7850/60 and at 1.8410/20 per mark, up from 1.8410/25.</p>
<p>-- Wojciech Moskwa +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
