<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="554822" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: US worker in Antarctic dies before planned rescue.</title>
<headline>US worker in Antarctic dies before planned rescue.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Brockett</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. civilian worker in the Antarctic has died just as plans were being readied for a dangerous winter flight to evacuate him, a rescue service source in New Zealand said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The U.S. Naval Antarctic Support Unit (NASU) in New Zealand, which had been getting ready for a landing at the U.S. McMurdo Base on the Ross Ice Shelf, was not initially able to comment.</p>
<p>Enquiries were being directed to the National Science Foundation headquarters in Washington, the man's employer. The worker, who has not been identified, was to have been evacuated to Christchurch, New Zealand, where NASU is based.</p>
<p>&quot;As I understand it the chap has died. They are in mourning down there and planning a memorial in the Chapel of Snows,&quot; the source told Reuters.</p>
<p>He added that the man was the 48th American to have died on the ice-clad continent since what the U.S military calls Operation Deepfreeze began.</p>
<p>The winter landing attempt would have been only the third ever made and have involved great risks.</p>
<p>&quot;Any landing in Antarctica is dangerous, but landing during the winter makes it extra dangerous,&quot; NASU spokesman Dave Lippman told Reuters earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;This is only the third time we've ever done a flight like this in our history. This is a hazardous undertaking.&quot;</p>
<p>With the southern winter setting in, Lippman said temperatures at McMurdo Base last week dropped to minus 34 degrees Fahrenheit (-37 Celsius), with a windchill factor as low as minus 97 degrees Fahrenheit (-72 Celsius).</p>
<p>He said the last sunset before winter occurred at McMurdo last week and the base would experience short and diminishing periods of twilight until the winter solstice in late June.</p>
<p>McMurdo Station's winter party of about 156 people is normally completely isolated until missions resume in August, bringing in personnel and supplies to prepare the Antarctic bases for the summer season.</p>
<p>McMurdo has a population of about 1,000 in the summer.</p>
<p>NASU is part of U.S. Naval Support Force Antarctica, which provides logistic support to the U.S. Antarctic Programme.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
