<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="554849" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia union takes legal action against govt.</title>
<headline>Australia union takes legal action against govt.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Community and Public Sector Union (CPSU) said on Thursday it had launched legal action against the federal government claiming it was acting in a way that discriminated against its members in the public service.</p>
<p>The union said the action was a response to the government's requirement that individual unionists confirm the deduction of union dues from their pay.</p>
<p>&quot;The union claims that the singling out of union deductions is discriminatory and breaches international conventions to which Australia is party,&quot; the CPSU said in a statement.</p>
<p>The union said that since the government's announcement of payroll deductions, thousands of union members had moved to direct payment methods to maintain their privacy.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been advised by our lawyers that we have a strong legal case,&quot; CPSU national secretary Wendy Caird told Reuters.</p>
<p>Caird said in a separate action to protest against the government's policy on public sector employment, members of the CSPU would begin a campaign of rolling stopages on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The action is taken against more central concerns that we have about government policy and will start with a two hour stoppage in Melbourne tomorrow,&quot; Caird said.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 61-2 9286-1435</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
