<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55513" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech ministers agree heat price deregulation.</title>
<headline>Czech ministers agree heat price deregulation.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech Council of Economic Ministers on Monday agreed to deregulate the price of district heating, Labour and Social Affairs Minister Jindrich Vodicka said.</p>
<p>Following a meeting of the council Vodicka told reporters the ministers agreed to switch &quot;from regulated prices to prices adopted according to inflation and other normal indicators.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the ministers also agreed that there should be some type of social compensation to soften the impact of the decision on those unable to pay.</p>
<p>District heating plants account for most of the heat provided to the large Communist-era housing estates where many Czechs live, and are heavily subsidised by the state.</p>
<p>The issue of deregualtion of utilities prices has been one of the most sensitive in the Czech post-Communist reforms.</p>
<p>Vodicka said this all must be first approved by the full cabinet before the final budget plan for 1997 is approved. That is expected within the next two weeks.</p>
<p>The full cabinet, which rarely rejects decisions of the economic ministers, has its next regular meeting on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
