<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="555188" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA-SONICS BEAT SUNS IN OVERTIME, MAGIC TAKES HEAT.</title>
<headline>NBA-SONICS BEAT SUNS IN OVERTIME, MAGIC TAKES HEAT.</headline>
<dateline>PHOENIX, Arizona 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gary Payton scored four of his 28 points in overtime as the Seattle SuperSonics forced a decisive fifth game in their Western Conference first-round series with a 122-115 victory over the Phoenix Suns on Thursday.</p>
<p>Seattle's other two All-Stars -- Detlef Schrempf and Shawn Kemp -- both had big games to help the Sonics avoid another first-round upset. Schrempf had 26 points, including five in the extra session, and Kemp had 24 and 20 rebounds. In the fourth quarter, Kemp was 6-for-6 from the foul line.</p>
<p>The Sonics led by as much as 12 points in the fourth quarter, but the Suns closed with a 19-7 burst to force overtime.</p>
<p>Kevin Johnson, playing what may have been the final home game of his career, had 23 points and 11 assists for Phoenix.</p>
<p>In Orlando, Penny Hardaway scored 41 points to again lead the undermanned Orlando Magic to a 99-91 victory over the Miami Heat that forced a decisive fifth game in their Eastern Conference first-round series.</p>
<p>Playing the entire game in the absence of injured starters Rony Seikaly and Horace Grant, Hardaway shot 12-of-23 from the field, 13-of-16 from the line and grabbed seven rebounds. He was just as spectacular as he was in Game Three, when he scored 42 points to lead a comeback from a 20-point deficit.</p>
<p>&quot;It says that we all know he's a star in this league, but he has demonstrated in the last two games that he's going to be one great superstar in this league,&quot; Orlando coach Richie Adubato said. &quot;I gave him a break the other day, he played 47 minutes. I couldn't give him one minute today.&quot;</p>
<p>Derek Strong scored 15 points and Darrell Armstrong again played well with 12 points and nine rebounds for the Magic, who were in control throughout and led by as many as 15 points in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Alonzo Mourning scored 23 points and P.J. Brown 20 for the Heat, looking for the first series win in team history.</p>
<p>Hardaway began hot and never really cooled off. He made 6-of-9 shots in the first quarter, including 3-of-4 three-pointers, and scored 18 points as Orlando grabbed a 27-25 lead.</p>
<p>The Magic took control for good in the second period with a 15-2 burst.  Dennis Scott scored five points and Hardaway added four as the lead ballooned to 42-27 on a layup by Danny Schayes with 6:19 remaining.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHOENIX, Arizona"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
