<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="555214" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER SHOWCASE-TRAPATTONI AIMS TO STICK TO OLD ADAGE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-TRAPATTONI AIMS TO STICK TO OLD ADAGE.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Gray</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bayern Munich coach Giovanni Trapattoni aims to stick as closely as possible to one of soccer's oldest adages for Sunday's German league derby with 1860 Munich -- never change a winning team.</p>
<p>The former Internazionale and Juventus boss does not want to tamper much with a side who last weekend notched Bayern's highest win of the season -- a 5-0 demolition of relegation candidates Fortuna Duesseldorf.</p>
<p>So while Christian Ziege may return after suspension, top-class internationals Thomas Strunz and Mehmet Scholl will probably have to be content with a place on the bench.</p>
<p>1860 coach Werner Lorant, on the other hand, is almost certain to make several changes from the side who beat Duisburg 3-2 on their last Bundesliga outing. Ghanian Abedi Pele is available aagain after international duty.</p>
<p>Pele is likely to slot into midfield despite a broken bone in his left hand for a game sixth-placed 1860 insist they want to win, although they have not beaten Bayern since 1977.</p>
<p>&quot;We're complete outsiders,&quot; admitted Lorant. &quot;But we have an obligation to our fans. We want to play in the UEFA Cup and we need three points against Bayern.&quot;</p>
<p>Lorant welcomes back Swiss defender Marco Walker after suspension but is still deprived of Berhard Winkler, 1860's top goalscorer this season who is suffering from a groin injury.</p>
<p>The coach had been hoping Winkler may have recovered enough to play against Bayern but the player made clear Lorant would have to think again.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm injured and he'll just have to get used to that,&quot; Winkler said. &quot;I can't play in my condition.&quot;</p>
<p>Winkler has been one of the season's biggest surprises. He has notched 17 league goals -- five more, for example, than Juergen Klinsmann at Bayern.</p>
<p>Lorant has several options when it comes to compensating for the loss of Winkler, who has been in the bad books for saying the club doctor should have spotted his injury sooner.</p>
<p>He could move Pele forward and use Bulgarian international Daniel Borimirov as a striker or he could opt for a direct replacement in the form of striker Olaf Bodden.</p>
<p>The only injury worry for Trapattoni involves Mario Basler. The midfielder suffered a thigh strain playing for Germany in Wednesday night's World Cup qualifier against Ukraine but is confident he'll be fit.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm feeling better,&quot; Basler said after taking part in light training on Friday. &quot;I'm getting injections and I think we'll manage to make it in time for Sunday.&quot;</p>
<p>Probable teams:</p>
<p>1860: 12-Rainer Berg; 6-Bernhard Trares; 15-Holger Greilich, 4-Marco Walker, 8-Manfred Schwabl, 20-Mirolsav Stevic; 10-Peter Nowak, 19-Pele, 33-Manfred Bender; 13-Harald Cerny,, 17-Daniel Borimirov.</p>
<p>Bayern: 1-Oliver Kahn; 10-Lothar Matthaeus; 2-Markus Babbel, 5-Thomas Helmer, 16-Dietmar Hamann, 17-Christian Ziege; 13-Mario Basler, 6-Christian Nerlinger, 21-Alexander Zickler; 18-Juergen Klinsmann, 20-Ruggiero Rizzitelli.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
