<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="555231" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-ITALIAN SERIE A FIXTURES AT THE WEEKEND.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ITALIAN SERIE A FIXTURES AT THE WEEKEND.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serie A fixtures scheduled for this weekend (league positions in parentheses, kick-off times GMT): Internazionale (3) v Vicenza (8), Saturday 18.30</p>
<p>Both sides may be distracted by impending cup final appearances -- Inter away to German side Shalke 04 in the UEFA Cup final first leg next Wednesday and Vicenza away to Napoli in the Italian Cup final first leg on Thursday. For Inter, Dutchman Aron Winter and defender Salvatore Fresi are suspended but Frenchmen Youri Djorkaeff and Jocelyn Angloma and Englishman Paul Ince, all suspended for the UEFA Cup final, are expected to play. Vicenza may rest strikers Roberto Murgita and Uruguayan Marcelo Otero, relying instead on Giovanni Coracchinni.</p>
<p>Atalanta (10) v Parma (2), Sunday 14.00</p>
<p>Second-placed Parma have not yet given up hope of a Juventus slip-up in the final run-in. Parma's Enrico Chiesa makes a welcome return from injury to partner Argentine Hernan Crespo in attack while Atalanta's Gigi Lentini also returns to partner Filippo Inzaghi, still leading goalscorer on 19.</p>
<p>Juventus (1) v Sampdoria (4), Sunday 14.00</p>
<p>If Juventus are going to falter in their final six games, it would logically have to happen in this tie as their next two opponents Verona and Piacenza cannot be expected to cause problems. The league leaders welcome back, at least for one half, injured striker Alessandro Del Piero while Christian Vieri, who missed out on Italy's midweek 3-0 World Cup win against Poland, is expected to start alongside Croat striker Alen Boksic. Sampdoria should be at full strength, led by captain Roberto Mancini and Vincenzo Montella in attack and with Frenchman Christian Karembeu and Argentine Juan Veron in midfield.</p>
<p>Perugia (16) v Fiorentina (9), Sunday 14.00</p>
<p>Relegation battlers Perugia badly need points if they are to stay up. Demotivated Fiorentina, out of the Cup Winners' Cup and long shots for a UEFA Cup place, may be the perfect victims. Fiorentina will be without injured Swedish midfielder Stefan Schwarz and suspended defender Giulio Falcone, while Perugia will be without midfielder Federico Giunti and defender Salvatore Matrecano, both suspended.</p>
<p>Piacenza (14) v Bologna (6), Sunday 14.00</p>
<p>Bologna are unlikely to give much away to relegation battlers Piacenza since they need all the points they can get to ensure a UEFA Cup place. Pasquale Luiso and Andrea Tentoni lead the Piacenza attack, while Bologna are without midfielder Massimo Brambilla and defenders Andrea Tarozzi and Stefano Torrisi, all suspended, as well as injured Russian striker Igor Kolyvanov. In their absence, Swede Kennet Andersson leads the Bologna attack.</p>
<p>Reggiana (18) v Cagliari (15), Sunday 14.00</p>
<p>Bottom club Reggiana are not yet mathematically relegated so this clash with fourth from bottom Cagliari is sure to be a fierce squabble. Russian Igor Simutenkov leads the Reggiana attack, while Sandro Tovalieri and Roberto Muzzi are up front for Cagliari who are missing three suspended players in defenders Giuseppe Pancaro and Matteo Villa and midfielder Marco Sanna.</p>
<p>Roma (12) v Lazio (5), Sunday 14.00</p>
<p>A UEFA Cup place could be at stake in this derby which comes at the end of a desperately disappointing season for both Rome clubs. Roma's coach, Swede Nils Liedholm, may opt for a bold three-man attack of Francesco Totti, Argentine Abel Balbo and Uruguyan Daniel Fonseca. Lazio welcome back Pierluigi Casiraghi alongside Giuseppe Signori in attack.</p>
<p>Udinese (7) v AC Milan (11), Sunday 14.00</p>
<p>Udinese are seeking a giant-killing hat-trick following wins against Juventus and Parma and, given their good league standing, must fancy their UEFA Cup chances. Roberto Baggio returns to the Milan side galvanised by his goal in Italy's 3-0 midweek World Cup win against Poland. Baggio plays alongside Liberian George Weah, while the Udinese front line is led by Paolo Poggi and German Oliver Bierhoff, also a midweek World Cup goalscorer in Germany's 2-0 win against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Verona (17) v Napoli (13), Sunday 14.00</p>
<p>In their first game under new coach Vincenzo Montefusco, Napoli are unlikely to concede much to second-from-bottom Verona. Filippo Maniero and Nicola Zanini lead the Verona attack, while Brazilian midfielder Andre Cruz, Argentine defender Roberto Ayala and Belgian defender Bertrand Crasson are all expected to play for Napoli.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
