<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="555445" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zairean rebels fly troops, artillery towards front.</title>
<headline>Zairean rebels fly troops, artillery towards front.</headline>
<byline>Buchizya Mseteka</byline>
<dateline>LUBUMBASHI, Zaire 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zairean rebels are flying troops, artillery and other supplies westwards to bolster forces advancing on the capital Kinshasa, regardless of face-to-face talks with President Mobutu Sese Seko.</p>
<p>A rebel commander in the southeastern city of Lubumbashi said on Friday an airlift to the towns of Kikwit and Kananga began on Thursday and rebel forces were about to enter Kenge, the biggest town before Kinshasa.</p>
<p>At the airport in the southeast city of Lubumbashi, hundreds of chanting rebel soldiers boarded Boeing 737s, 727s and Fokkers and officers said they were going to Kikwit for the final push on Kinshasa.</p>
<p>&quot;Our forces are advancing and are now about to enter Kenge. The Zaireans withdrew yesterday when they heard we were approaching the town,&quot; said the commander.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like they (rebels) are going in for a kill otherwise they would be no need for ferrying such equipment and troops,&quot; said a Western diplomat in Lubumbashi.</p>
<p>The commander, who asked not to be named, said rebels were using bridge-laying equipment to move troops across rivers because Mobutu's presidential guard in Kenge, commanded by his son Kongolo Mobutu, had destroyed bridges to block the advance.</p>
<p>He did not say how far they now were from Kenge, which lies 200 km (120 miles) east of Kinshasa. Kikwit and Kananga, both in rebel hands, are further to the east.</p>
<p>Kenge residents said on Thursday the Zairean government's ragged army had just pulled out of town, which was quiet and waiting for the rebels to arrive -- a familiar pattern in the seven-month war.</p>
<p>Asked whether the rebels would suspend fighting because rebel leader Laurent Kabila was on his way to talks with Mobutu, the commander said Kabila had left no such instructions.</p>
<p>Mobutu and Kabila, leader of the Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire (AFDL), were expected to meet aboard a South African navy ship off the coast of West Africa later on Friday under South African auspices.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no ceasefire. Our boss said the military campaign must continue while he attended the talks,&quot; the commander added.</p>
<p>Kabila told Reuters on Wednesday his advance on Kinshasa would stop only after Mobutu stepped down after more than three decades in power.</p>
<p>But Mobutu's camp hopes the talks, chaired by South African President Nelson Mandela, will lead to a ceasefire and a peaceful transition with elections open to all.</p>
<p>&quot;The talks will just be about Mobutu and what we do with him. Our uncompromising demand is that he leaves power and we shall look after him,&quot; Kabila said before leaving his Lubumbashi headquarters for talks in neighbouring countries.</p>
<p>&quot;There can be no ceasefire or indeed elections in this country until Mobutu and all he represents is removed and thrown away,&quot; Kabila added.</p>
<p>Kabila's rebels, who took up arms in October, say they expect to take the capital over the next 10 to 15 days. They now control about three quarters of the vast Central African nation -- including all its main cities outside the capital.</p>
<p>A regional military analyst who is closely monitoring the war said another rebel column with tanks, armoured vehicles and heavy artillery was moving towards the front from Tshikapa, a town close to the Angolan border.</p>
<p>On Friday the Washington Post said that Angolan armour had joined the Zairean rebel forces pushing toward Kinshasa.</p>
<p>Quoting unidentified U.S. officials and reports from the region, the newspaper said the rebel advance had led to a widely shared assessment that Mobutu's fall from power was imminent.</p>
<p>As a result, the focus of diplomatic efforts was now on minimising the bloodshed when the forces of Kabila entered Kinshasa, the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;At this stage, the objective would be to arrange a cessation of hostilities, Mobutu stepping down and some kind of arrangement that would lead to elections,&quot; White House National Security Adviser Samuel Berger said at a meeting of Washington Post editors and reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know if that's feasible or not,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>With troops in Zaire and a stake in the outcome, Angola had become a key player whose restraint would be required if bloodshed were to be minimised, U.S. officials told the Post.</p>
<p>Several thousand former Zairean paramilitary policemen and their sons from the province of Shaba, formerly Katanga, after living in Angola for many years, were advancing through south central Zaire toward the capital, the newspaper reported.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUBUMBASHI, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
