<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="555480" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: PRESS DIGEST - Zimbabwe - May 2.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Zimbabwe - May 2.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Zimbabwe press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>ZIMBABWE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>- The Zimbabwe government plans to purchase an additional fleet of over 50 Mercedes Benz cars and an unspecified number of Mazda 626s valued at over U.S.$3 million to boost its fleet for service during the Organisation of African Unity summit scheduled to take place in Harare in June.</p>
<p>- Zimbabwe's major cargo airline, Affretair, is threatened with closure at the end of June after the airline decided it was no longer viable to send its one remaining aircraft for a complete overhaul.</p>
<p>- Negotiations are underway for a reverse take-over of FMB Holdings Ltd by a black-owned Zimbabwean financial institution in what is seen as a move to bolster First Merchant Bank Zimbabwe Ltd 's faltering market share under stiff competition.</p>
<p>THE HERALD</p>
<p>- The price of petrol, diesel and other petroleum products went up as of midnight on Thursday by between 12 and 24 percent, three months after the last increases.</p>
<p>- The Vehicle Inspection Depot in Harare has stopped accepting new applications for driving tests until September when it hopes to have cleared a backlog of about 11,000 people.</p>
<p>- Zairean rebel leader Laurent Kabila flew into Zimbabwe on Thursday for talks with President Robert Mugabe on the situation in his country.</p>
<p>--Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 28/9--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
