<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="555510" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovakia - May 2.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovakia - May 2.</headline>
<text>
<p>NARODNA OBRODA - German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel, on a two-day visit to Bratislava, said Germany would support Slovakia's efforts for NATO and EU membership.</p>
<p>- The Slovak governemnt is still waiting for a formal apology from Czech President Vaclav Havel for his remarks that Slovak Premier Vladimir Meciar is paranoid.</p>
<p>- Czech tyre maker Barum Continental Otrokovice last year took about 30 percent of the Slovak tyre market.</p>
<p>- The Slovak capital Bratislava plans to issue an unspecified tranche of municipal bonds in 1998 to cover part of planned investment programmes worth 500 million crowns.</p>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Construction production is expected to increase month-on-month in April, according to a survey carried out by the Slovak Statistical Bureau.</p>
<p>- Slovakia's foreign trade turnover totalled 155 billion crowns in the first three months of this year, an increase of 11 percent over the same period last year.</p>
<p>- A planned Slovak-Russian joint venture managing gas supplies to Slovakia should not negatively affect revenues and the market position of the Slovak monopoly state-run gas distributor SPP.</p>
<p>PRAVDA - Slovak President Michal Kovac said a government attempt to postpone a referendum on direct presidential elections was an interference in his constitutional powers.</p>
<p>- Klaus Kinkel says German Chancellor Helmut Kohl has so far not visited Slovakia because of a busy schedule and not because he was not interested in the country as such.</p>
<p>- According to Andreas Krautscheid, a parliamentary deputy of the ruling German CDU, Germany will not support Slovakia's invitation to be included in the first wave of NATO enlargement, but Bonn supports Bratislava's attempts to integrate into Western structures. Krautscheid is now on a visit to Slovakia as a member of Kinkel's delegation.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 421-7-521-8402</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
