<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="555536" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: FOCUS-Czech CEZ Q1 profit dips,demand down.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Czech CEZ Q1 profit dips,demand down.</headline>
<byline>Jan Lopatka</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech electrical utility CEZ a.s. said on Friday its net profit dropped more than expected in the first quarter as demand for electricity fell.</p>
<p>Company officials said net profit for the first three months of the year, calculated according to international accounting standards, slipped to 2.84 billion crowns ($92 million) from 3.66 billion for the same period last year.</p>
<p>They added that according to Czech accounting standards, net profit fell to 2.46 bilion crowns from 3.51 billion.</p>
<p>CEZ's director of planning and analysis, Petr Voboril, told a news conference that demand for energy fell by 5.5 percent for the period, year-on-year, to 15.4 terawatthours, mainly due to sluggish industrial production.</p>
<p>Demand from the industrial sector fell by 8.4 percent in the first three months, while household demand decreased by 4.5 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;About 30 percent of the drop can be attributed to the warmer climatic conditions, so the remaining 70 percent is a result of other factors, mainly the decline of consumption by industry,&quot; Voboril said.</p>
<p>CEZ said the average temperature for the period was 3.4 degrees celsius higher than last year.</p>
<p>Czech industrial production showed a real year-on-year decline of 5.8 percent in February, after a fall of 3.9 percent in January.</p>
<p>CEZ shares fell on the news, closing down 14 crowns at 950, and analysts said they expected further losses as investors begin to lose interest in the market's largest blue chip.</p>
<p>&quot;These results are even worse than we expected,&quot; said John Vax, director of capital markets at ING Barings.</p>
<p>&quot;The fall is indicative of a decline of electricity consumption in the industrial sector, which means...the economy is coming to an industrial recession, which is negative for CEZ shares, as well as Komercni Banka, which is quite exposed in that sector,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Voboril said that according to Czech accounting, total revenues dropped by 740 million crowns to 16.26 billion, mainly due to lower sales, while costs rose by 717 billion to 12.01 billion as financial costs, write-offs and fees and taxes rose.</p>
<p>&quot;The profit is lower than we expected at the time when the decrease in demand was not so significant,&quot; Voboril said.</p>
<p>Write-offs rose to 1.64 billion from 1.32 billion and financial costs increased to 902 million from 559 million.</p>
<p>Voboril told reporters that CEZ had been expecting a two billion crown decrease in full year net profit to 6.1 billion under Czech standards but said he was not able to update the forecast as projections for consumption development varied.</p>
<p>&quot;The top projections are little over last year's demand, while the pesimistic ones range around 0.5 to one terawatthour below last year's reality,&quot; Vobiril said. Last year, consumption rose 3.75 percent to a record 54.11 terawatthours.</p>
<p>However, a CEZ statement said the &quot;budgeted profit would not be achieved&quot;.</p>
<p>Voboril said CEZ was limiting and postponing pre-contracted imports over its grid to match the decrease.</p>
<p>The director said CEZ was still planning to pay out a dividend for 1996 but it could be lower than the originally planned 30 to 35 crowns per 1,100 nominal value share due to the latest developments.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 420-2-2423-0003 ($ = 30.90 Czech Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
