<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="555505" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian-Chechen peace deal seen close.</title>
<headline>Russian-Chechen peace deal seen close.</headline>
<byline>Anatoly Verbin</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian President Boris Yeltsin and Chechen leader Aslan Maskhadov may sign a political accord next week in Moscow, Interfax news agency said on Friday, quoting Maskhadov's spokesman.</p>
<p>The spokesman, Kazbek Khadzhiyev, said one article in the accord, aimed at turning a ceasefire between Russia and Chechnya into lasting peace, had not been agreed yet, but he gave no further detail.</p>
<p>The two leaders were expected to try to iron out the differences during face-to-face talks due to take place between May 5 and 10, he said. They were also likely to sign a deal on economic issues.</p>
<p>A Russian presidential spokesman said he could not confirm the report but said such a meeting was &quot;quite possible&quot;.</p>
<p>Russia and Chechnya agreed a ceasefire last summer after 21 months of war in which tens of thousands were killed, but have struggled to reach a full political and economic settlement.</p>
<p>Maskhadov has been insisting on full independence. Moscow will not grant that and is offering what it calls broad sovereignity inside Russia. It is holding back funds to rebuild the Chechen economy until a final peace accord is signed.</p>
<p>The situation in the region deteriorated badly over the past week after a spate of violence in the districts neighbouring Chechnya, including fatal bomb attacks and the murder of an official in which some Russian officials saw a Chechen link.</p>
<p>It appeared that agreement for Maskhadov to visit Moscow came during talks between Russian security officials and Chechen bosses held hastily in the Chechen capital of Grozny on Wednesday in an attempt to ease tension in the North Caucasus.</p>
<p>Movladi Udugov, deputy prime minister of Chechnya, who has held most of the talks with Russian officials, told Interfax the two delegations had done all they could and the fate of the accord was now in the hands of Maskhadov and Yeltsin.</p>
<p>&quot;We are unable to make any steps further without the two presidents because neither side has corresponding powers,&quot; Udugov said.</p>
<p>Yeltsin consistently refused to meet Chechen leader Dzhokhar Dudayev, who spearheaded Chechnya's independence drive from 1991 until he was killed in a Russian rocket attack last April.</p>
<p>He met Dudayev's successor, Zelimkhan Yandarbiyev, last May in the Kremlin to sign an accord which was followed by the August truce hammered out by Maskhadov and former Russia's security tsar, Alexander Lebed.</p>
<p>Many Russian conservatives, including Interior Minister Anatoly Kulikov, have condemned the Lebed-Maskhadov accord as a surrender to the separatists.</p>
<p>But Yeltsin, who has said the decision to use military force to quell Chechnya's independence bid could have been his biggest political mistake, appears keen to press on with a search for a lasting peace.</p>
<p>A senior Russian official, closely involved in the talks with Chechnya, told reporters recently that the main sticking point in the draft accord was a reference to war and peace.</p>
<p>Chechnya wanted the deal to be named Peace Accord and to include international guarantees. Russia, which considers the conflict an internal affair, objected.</p>
<p>Maskhadov, who had led Chechen forces in fighting with Russian troops and was elected president in January, is in a difficult situation, the official said.</p>
<p>On one hand, he realises that outright independence is impossible -- the August deal postponed any decision on Chechnya's political status until the year 2000.</p>
<p>On the other hand, Maskhadov is under pressure from powerful and more radical field commanders and needs an accord which would be at least a step more far-reaching than the August agreement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
