<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="555953" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila says China ships leave disputed Spratlys.</title>
<headline>Manila says China ships leave disputed Spratlys.</headline>
<byline>Dolly Aglay</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>China has withdrawn armed naval ships from disputed islands in the South China Sea, defusing tension in an area claimed by six Asian nations, Philippine officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>In the first Chinese explanation of the ships' purpose, Beijing's ambassador in Manila said on Friday the ships were sent to perform scientific research.</p>
<p>Manila has protested against the presence of the vessels in an area it claims in the disputed Spratly Islands.</p>
<p>&quot;A Highlander plane reconnoitred the area this morning and there are no more Chinese naval vessels near Panata and Kota island. They are gone,&quot; Major-General Reynaldo Reyes, commander of the Western Command, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Beijing says the Spratlys, a cluster of reefs and islands in the South China Sea important for potentially vast reserves of oil and gas, historically belong to China.</p>
<p>However, Vietnam, Taiwan, Malaysia, Brunei and the Philippines also claim all or part of the area.</p>
<p>Vietnam, itself recently at odds with China over claims to some islands, earlier this week called for calm in this latest dispute.</p>
<p>Delia Menez Rosal, executive director at the Philippine Department of Foreign Affairs, told reporters Chinese ambassador Guan Ding-ming met her Friday and told her the ships &quot;were merely conducting regular scientific research in the area&quot;.</p>
<p>Defence Secretary Renato de Villa earlier told reporters he had been waiting for confirmation that the ships had left.</p>
<p>He said Chinese ships had visited the area before but it was unusual for them to anchor so close to islands which Manila claims. Panata is one of the islands.</p>
<p>Manila lodged a protest after spotting the Chinese ships, accompanied by fishing boats, near the islands a week ago.</p>
<p>Manila originally said its military sighted three armed ships in the area, but de Villa said there were actually four, including one with a helicopter landing area.</p>
<p>&quot;It (China's encroachment) is really surprising... In your relations there should be no surprises,&quot; Foreign Secretary Domingo Siazon told reporters.</p>
<p>China's presence near two islands occupied by Philippine troops caused an uproar in Manila. Senate foreign relations committee chairman Blas Ople urged the government to seek help from the United States to make China remove the ships.</p>
<p>After a similar incident two years ago, the two countries agreed not to make moves that would disturb peace in the area.</p>
<p>Tension flared in 1995, when Manila accused the Chinese of building what it said looked like naval support structures on Mischief Reef. Beijing said they were shelters for fishermen and refused to dismantle them.</p>
<p>De Villa said he was still concerned about anew building constructed by the Chinese. &quot;We are not drawing any conclusion... we are just saying that we are concerend that they might have some intentions in the area,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Some Foreign Ministry sources said they were not alarmed by the events, which they felt were being played up by the armed forces for domestic consumption in a bid to increase its budget to replace ageing military hardware.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
