<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="555962" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore editor defends Malaysia crime story.</title>
<headline>Singapore editor defends Malaysia crime story.</headline>
<byline>Nick Edwards</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The editor of the Singapore Straits Times newspaper said on Friday he was sorry a story about crime levels in Malaysia's Johor state offended Malaysians, but said his first duty was to report the facts.</p>
<p>&quot;We are sorry if our story offended anyone in Malaysia but our first duty as a newspaper is to report the facts accurately,&quot; editor Leslie Fong told Reuters in a written reply to questions.</p>
<p>Fong said he was puzzled by the angry reactions in Malaysia to the paper's coverage of a High Court hearing on Monday which deleted from court records comments criticising Johor made by Singapore elder statesman Lee Kuan Yew.</p>
<p>Lee, in an affidavit filed in pursuit of a libel case against opposition politician Tang Liang Hong, described Johor as &quot;notorious for shootings, muggings and car-jackings&quot;.</p>
<p>A leak of the affidavit, intended to pour scorn on Tang's flight to Johor saying he had received death threats at home following his general election defeat in January, sparked a furious reaction in Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>Lee offered unreserved apologies, then promised to have the comments deleted from the record when that failed to cool Malaysian wrath.</p>
<p>On Monday, Lee said his comments were based on newspaper reports about crime in Johor and submitted to the court a compilation of them from the past three years, Fong said.</p>
<p>&quot;We did what any newspaper would have done -- we took a look at the compilation, highlighted some of the more prominent cases and made the observation that anyone reading them might well come to the conclusion that crime was a problem there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Malaysian ministers slammed the coverage, with International Trade and Industry Minister Rafidah Aziz calling for a media war against Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;We thought the subject was dead...The government does not want to argue. Why not have a media war?&quot; she said to reporters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>On Thursday, leading Malay daily Utusan Malaysia took up the banner in a sharply critical front page editorial and the New Straits Times daily carried an item about a United Nations report showing crime in Singapore to be higher than in Malaysia.</p>
<p>The Straits Times carried both reports without editorial comment.</p>
<p>Analyst Bruce Gale of the Political Economic Risk Consultancy in Singapore told Reuters he was surprised by the Straits Times coverage of Lee's compilation of crime reports.</p>
<p>&quot;I was a little bit surprised the Straits Times wanted to keep at it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;What we see in the New Straits Times is a bit tit for tat,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
