<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="555948" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru stand cost government up to $15 million.</title>
<headline>Peru stand cost government up to $15 million.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>High-tech bugging, spy planes and round-the-clock police guards at the site of Peru's 126-day hostage standoff have meant an estimated cost of up to $15 million for the government, analysts said.</p>
<p>For four months following a rebel takeover on Dec. 17 of the Japanese ambassador's residence, Peru's spending on the police and military soared, prompting analysts polled by Reuters to estimate the crisis' cost between $12 million and $15 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The main thing to remember is that this (crisis management) has not been free and that somebody is going to have to pay the costs. There will be taxes and some spending will be adjusted,&quot; said Elmer Cuba of the local economic consulting firm Macroconsult.</p>
<p>The government's costs incurred during Latin America's longest-ever hostage taking break down into three basic areas.</p>
<p>Around the site, the government stationed police guards 24 hours a day to control thousands of reporters camped out around the diplomatic residence.</p>
<p>At the residence, Peruvian security forces used state-of-the-art technology to plant bugs, flew overhead a spy plane with infra-red cameras and dug tunnels under the compound from which to launch their explosive April 22 rescue.</p>
<p>But the largest expense was probably at a secret army base, where, according to President Alberto Fujimori, 140 elite troops trained for its raid around an exact replica of the home, blowing up the mock-up in rehearsals.</p>
<p>The military's bloody attack rescued alive 71 VIP captives held by Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement rebels but cost the lives of one hostage, two commandos and all 14 guerrillas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
