<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="556036" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S., North Korea to hold talks in New York.</title>
<headline>U.S., North Korea to hold talks in New York.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. and North Korean officials will meet on Sunday in New York to discuss continuing joint efforts to account for missing U.S. servicemen from the Korean War, the Pentagon said on Friday.</p>
<p>The talks, which will continue into next week, are separate from stalled negotiations which broke off in New York last month in which the United States and South Korea urged Pyongyang to begin four-way peace talks with China to formally end the 1950-53 war.</p>
<p>It will be the fourth set of talks between the Pentagon and North Korea on missing U.S. troops. The two sides last met in New York a year ago and reached agreement which led to joint recovery of the remains of a U.S. Army corporal north of Pyongyang.</p>
<p>The Pentagon declined to say where Sunday's meeting would be held in New York City, but said the talks were expected to last at least through Thursday.</p>
<p>A defense official, who asked not to be identified, said that the North Korean delegation had also agreed to meet privately with a small number of representatives of U.S. veterans and family groups.</p>
<p>There are still some 8,100 U.S. troops missing from the Korean War. The Pentagon has said that it has no evidence that any are still being held captive in North Korea.</p>
<p>Separate negotiations broke off in New York City last month on whether the Communist North, where famine has caused crisis conditions, would take part in four-way peace talks with the United States, South Korea and China. The North demanded more food aid, U.S. diplomatic recognition and other concessions in order to talk peace.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the United States said on Friday that it will not pressure Japan to donate more food aid to North Korea at a meeting next week in Tokyo despite the worsening food crisis that could produce starvation in 11 weeks.</p>
<p>John Dinger, a State Department spokesman, confirmed the food situation in North Korea would be on the agenda when senior U.S., South Korean and Japanese officials meet on Wednesday in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Friday's announcement at the Pentagon said the U.S. delegation on Sunday would be led by Deputy Assistant Defense Secretary James Wold, who is in charge of matters dealing with American troops missing in action or held prisoner.</p>
<p>Defense officials said the North Korean delegation would be led by Ambassador Kim Byong-Hong.</p>
<p>There have been reports of sightings of some Americans living in North Korea, and the Pentagon announcement said Wold intended to discuss those reports as well as access to North Korean military archives to recover data on Americans who were held prisoner during the war, which was halted by a truce but not a peace treaty.</p>
<p>The new round will also be aimed at &quot;establishing a schedule for resuming joint excavations to recover American remains buried in North Korean cemeteries and at specific loss sites,&quot; such as aircraft crash sites, the Pentagon said.</p>
<p>A joint U.S.-North Korean search team last summer found the remains of U.S. Army Cpl. Lawrence LeBoeuf of Gretna, Louisiana, buried north of Pyongyang. The remains were identified and returned to the United States for burial by his family.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
