<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="556113" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Nynex must respond to MCI bad faith claim.</title>
<headline>Nynex must respond to MCI bad faith claim.</headline>
<byline>Eric Auchard</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nynex Corp. has until Monday to respond to charges it acted in bad faith by not signing an agreement with MCI Communications Corp. that would have allowed the nation's No. 2 long-distance carrier to enter Nynex's local market in New York state.</p>
<p>MCI filed a motion against Nynex on Monday asking the state Public Service Commission (PSC) to impose sanctions on Nynex for failing to sign the so-called interconnection agreement, which would enable MCI to provide local phone access in the state.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, state Attorney General Dennis Vacco filed papers with the commission seeking to bar Nynex from offering long-distance service because it discriminates against local-service rivals.</p>
<p>Vacco has been an outspoken critic of the proposed Bell Atlantic Corp. takeover of Nynex, and its New York Telephone operating unit, on anticompetitive grounds.</p>
<p>Nynex operates 11.1 million local service lines while competitors have less than 100,000 local service lines, according to state regulators' estimates.</p>
<p>Nynex spokesman Mark Marchand said the New York-based company strongly disagreed with Vacco's assessment of their draft application for long-distance service in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;Fifty phone companies are licensed with the PSC to provide all forms of local phone service,&quot; Marchand said. &quot;What they do is up to them. The market is open. There is no other state in the country which has a more competitive market.&quot;</p>
<p>Nynex has signed full interconnection deals with competitive access providers, including MFS Communications, a unit of WorldCom Inc.; Teleport Communications Group Inc. and WinStar Communications Inc.</p>
<p>The deals would allow the companies to route traffic over their own network switching equipment.</p>
<p>In addition, Nynex has reached resale pacts with Frontier Corp., among others, to allow companies to offer local access over Nynex's network.</p>
<p>Most of the new entrants into the New York local service market are focused on profitable niches in the business services market, rather than residential service.</p>
<p>The dispute is part of a broad change across the United States due to the 1996 Telecommunications Act, under which local and long-distance providers are seeking to meet regulatory requirements that would allow them to compete on each other's historic turf.</p>
<p>Washington-based MCI, which has waged an agressive campaign to enter local service markets, so far has reached five interconnection deals -- two in California, where Pacific Telesis and GTE Corp. operate, and with the respective Baby Bells in Georgia, Minnesota and Iowa.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
