<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="556143" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S MUNICIPAL FOCUS - ends flat, $4.1 bln on tap.</title>
<headline>U.S MUNICIPAL FOCUS - ends flat, $4.1 bln on tap.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Municipal bond prices were flat to up one quarter of a point in late trade on Friday as the market debated what the Federal Reserve's next step would be in the wake of somewhat contradictory payrolls data.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, municipal bond supply picked up and now totals $4.1 billion for next week.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say we're unchanged towards the end of the day,&quot; a trader said. &quot;It would seem the government market could begin to give us a lift but everybody's pretty much bailed out,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>While another trader pegged prices up around one-quarter of a point, he cautioned that activity was light, and that not all sales were being made to long-term holders. &quot;I did not hear a lot of going away business at all.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said that arbitrageurs appeared to be buying up cash bonds as municipal futures seemed rich.</p>
<p>Discount bonds, which tend to perform best in rising markets remained in demand, which suggests some big players expect this week's strong rally to continue. But not all agree. &quot;That's what the perception is, but personally, I'm trying to buy six-percent (coupons),&quot; a more cautious trader said.</p>
<p>Wall Street mainly expects the Federal Reserve to raise short-term interest rates at its next monetary policy meeting on May 20, as 22 of 29 economists polled by Reuters predicted it would raise federal funds at least 25 basis points at that session. A slightly bigger proportion, 25 of 29, see the central bank tightening rates by its July meeting.</p>
<p>One of the main features that might drive the Federal Reserve to raise rates was the stunning low unemployment rate reported by the Labor Department, which said the level fell to 4.9 percent in April--the lowest since 1973. Still, employers added fewer jobs than expected--only 142,000, which was sharply below consensus forecasts for a 211,000 increase.</p>
<p>This somewhat contradictory data sparked speculation that the unemployment rate might be revised upward.</p>
<p>Still, bond prices might find more reason to climb next week, when the full impact of the budget accord agreed between the president and Congress can be assessed, as it was not announced until trading had started winding down on Friday afternoon.</p>
<p>Next week could be the second biggest week for selling new municipal securities this year, as the total was estimated at $4.06 billion.</p>
<p>Negotiated offerings totaled $3.3 billion in 42 sales, with a $486 million San Antonio, Texas, deal through PaineWebber Inc. topping the list.</p>
<p>On the competitive side, 60 sales added up to $749 million, with the largest a $173 million Tennessee deal on Wednesday is the largest.</p>
<p>Another 11 sales, which totaled $646 million, were on the possible calender, meaning underwriters have said they may price the bonds next week depending on market conditions.</p>
<p>In debt futures, June muncipal bonds rose eight ticks to 114-30/32, while June Treasury bonds climbed the same amount to 109-29/32. The MOB spread stood at plus 161 ticks.</p>
<p>In the secondary market, Texas State Turnpike Authority Dallas North Thruway Revenues of January 2025, which pay a five percent coupon, were bid at 5.72 percent, NET, down two basis points.</p>
<p>And Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, JFK International Air Terminal bonds of December 2022, which pay a 5.75 percent coupon, were bid at 5.94 percent, down three basis points.</p>
<p>((--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
