<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="556372" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Banks, Wall St. give closing lift to Danish shares.</title>
<headline>Banks, Wall St. give closing lift to Danish shares.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish share prices got a late afternoon boost after a lacklustre day on Friday, climbing on a Wall Street rally, U.S. April employment data and renewed interest in Danish banking shares.</p>
<p>&quot;The American numbers were good this time and foreign interest (in Danish shares) is strong, especially for Den Danske Bank&quot;, a dealer said.</p>
<p>The KFX top-20 index rose 0.69 point to close at 156.85, in overall bourse turnover of 730 million crowns.</p>
<p>The KFX June future rose 0.45 point to 156.70 with 70 contracts, each worth 100,000 crowns, traded.</p>
<p>Den Danske Bank rose 11 crowns to 585.5. Smaller rivals Unidanmark and BG Bank also rose, but less markedly. Unidanmark closed two crowns up, at 331.0 crowns and BG Bank ended up three crowns, at 293.0.</p>
<p>Coloplast also benefited from foreign buying interest, which helped lift it 16 crowns, to close at 480.0.</p>
<p>Another gainer was Copenhagen Airports which rose 15.0 crowns to 680.0. The company on Thursday said that it was considering taking stakes in foreign airports as a new area of growth. --Steve Weizman, Copenhagen newsroom +45 33 969650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
