<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55632" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Ergo sees NZ rates easing in first half of 1997.</title>
<headline>Ergo sees NZ rates easing in first half of 1997.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>An encouraging medium-term outlook for inflation suggests New Zealand interest rates will ease in the first half of next year, personal finance company Ergo said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Home buyers should not be scared off by election uncertainty and the Reserve Bank's latest prescription for the economy,&quot; Ergo, a subsidiary of AMP New Zealand, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>In its latest economic projections, the central bank took an easing of monetary policy &quot;off the agenda&quot; until it saw proof that underlying inflation would rapidly fall back within its 0-2 percent target band next year.</p>
<p>Ergo said rates would ease in the first half of 1997, providing that investors did not over play risks associated with the first MMP election on October 12.</p>
<p>&quot;We are four weeks out from the election and really it's anyone's guess as to what the outcome could be,&quot; Ergo said.  </p>
<p>&quot;This situation, combined with the Reserve Bank's forecast that interest rates are unlikely to fall in the short term, should not send home buyers into a panic.</p>
<p>&quot;It should indicate the need to look closely at their finances and prepare as best they can for the uncertain time ahead.&quot;</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
