<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="556340" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian shares end higher but activity low.</title>
<headline>Italian shares end higher but activity low.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Italian stock market inched up to close firm but with activity subdued and volumes reduced in holiday-thinned trade on Friday.</p>
<p>The market woke up slightly after U.S. jobs data released during the afternoon session and roused itself from lethargy with the blue-chip Mib30 index ending 0.6 percent up at 18399 and the all-share Mibtel index 0.63 percent stronger at 12354.</p>
<p>Many players took Friday off, extending Thursday's public holiday into a long weekend and dealers said the reduced volume had exaggerated moves.</p>
<p>They said the only real action was in ever popular telecoms stocks while otherwise &quot;sellers met no bids and vice versa.&quot;</p>
<p>State mobile phone service operator Telecom Italia Mobile (TIM) forged a new high at 5455 earlier in the session before ending up 0.32 percent on the day at 5388.</p>
<p>State telecom operator Telecom Italia climbed 2.1 percent to 4628 while state telecom holding Stet, with which it is set to merge in July, ended 1.03 percent up at 8210.</p>
<p>Blue chip carmaker Fiat closed 0.78 percent up at 5704 while state-controlled energy giant Eni ended 0.24 percent lower at 8695.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
