<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="556351" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy exiled king says Jewish laws &quot;not that bad&quot;.</title>
<headline>Italy exiled king says Jewish laws &quot;not that bad&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Tom Wright</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The son of Italy's last king, recently given hope of returning from a 50-year exile, faced a storm of protest on Friday after refusing to apologise for anti-semitic laws signed by his grandfather during Italy's Fascist era earlier this century.</p>
<p>In an interview given to state RAI television from his home in Switzerland on Thursday, Vittorio Emanuele said 1938 racial laws which removed Jews from schools and later from public jobs were &quot;not that bad&quot;.</p>
<p>When asked whether he would apologise for the laws, which were signed by his grandfather Vittorio Emanuele III as head of state under Benito Mussolini's fascist regime, the 59-year-old succesor to the Italian throne said:</p>
<p>&quot;No. No. I wasn't even born then.&quot;</p>
<p>The remarks came two days after the centre-left cabinet agreed to a proposal to allow the male line of the royal family to come home for the first time since war-weary Italians voted in 1946 to scrap the monarchy, blaming it for complicity with the fascist dictatorship.</p>
<p>Vittorio Emanuele moved quickly on Friday to clarify his remarks after a storm of protest and called the laws &quot;a grave error&quot;. But he repeated it was not his position to apologise for them.</p>
<p>&quot;My grandfather, who personally was against them, signed the laws as head of state but he tried to soften their effect,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>Others did not agree.</p>
<p>&quot;It is immoral that 60 years after this shameful page in this family's history that Vittorio Emanuele cannot find the force to admit the terrible guilt of Vittorio Emanuele III,&quot; Rome councillor Victor Magliar said in a statement.</p>
<p>The leader of Rome's Jewish community Rabbi Elio Toaff also vented his anger over the comments.</p>
<p>&quot;(The laws) are a disgrace that cannot be cancelled from the history of the House of Savoy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Paolo Cento, a member of parliament for the Green Party, which forms part of the centre-left coalition government, called on the cabinet to scrap the proposal to allow Vittorio Emanuele's return in light of the remarks.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope the Greens' (environment) minister (Edo) Ronchi immediately declares his opposition to this initiative by (Prime Minister) Romano Prodi because we can't give our unanimity to a scandal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Vittorio Emanuele was forced into exile with his father Umberto II when he was nine years old. Umberto died in exile in 1983, leaving his son as next in line to the Italian throne.</p>
<p>He may be allowed to return to Italy from his present home in Geneva if the draft, which will be drawn up at a future cabinet meeting, is passed by both houses of parliament, allowing it to become law.</p>
<p>The House of Savoy united Italy when Vittorio Emanuele I of Piedmont became the country's first king in 1861.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
