<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="556721" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Blair promises government to unite Britain.</title>
<headline>Blair promises government to unite Britain.</headline>
<byline>Giles Elgood</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's new prime minister Tony Blair, savouring a stunning landslide victory, promised on Friday his Labour government would unite the nation after 18 years of Conservative rule.</p>
<p>Blair's defeated rival John Major shocked colleagues by announcing that he would resign as leader of the Conservatives after his party lost its first election since 1974.</p>
<p>Greeting ecstatic, flag-waving party workers outside the prime minister's Downing Street office in central london, Blair promised &quot;a government of practical measures in pursuit of noble causes&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We have secured a mandate to bring this nation together, to unite as one Britain, one nation,&quot; said Blair, at 43 the youngest prime minister this century.</p>
<p>&quot;For 18 years, 18 long years, my party has been in opposition. It could only say, it could not do. Today we are charged with the deep responsibility of government.</p>
<p>&quot;Today, enough of talking. It is time now to do.&quot;</p>
<p>Major had earlier left Downing Street for the last time to hand in his resignation to Queen Elizabeth at Buckingham Palace after bidding an emotional farewell to his office staff.</p>
<p>&quot;When the curtain falls it is time to get off the stage,&quot; he told reporters. The Conservative Party had been in power since Margaret Thatcher won an election in 1979 -- the longest term of single-party government in Britain this century.</p>
<p>The timing of Major's resignation is uncertain -- he could stay until July -- but the news sparked an immediate battle for his succession. Kenneth Clarke, Major's finance minister, was the first to throw his hat into the ring. Former deputy prime minister Michael Heseltine and former Welsh Secretary William Hague were the bookmakers' favourites.</p>
<p>But Labour supporters spent Friday, a cloudless day, savouring the party's biggest-ever victory.</p>
<p>With all but 26 of the 659 seats counted, the party was on course for a majority of almost 180 seats, allowing Blair to govern without looking over his shoulder for the next five years.</p>
<p>Turnout among the 44 million voters was 71.3 percent -- a record post-war low. In the 1992 election, 77.7 percent of the electorate voted.</p>
<p>The defeat was on a scale unseen for 165 years with seven cabinet ministers, including Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind and Defence Secretary Michael Portillo, losing their seats.</p>
<p>&quot;Today on the eve of this new millennium the British people have ushered in this new era of politics,&quot; said Blair, who has force-marched Labour from the left to the centre of British politics in his three years as leader.</p>
<p>Major, who was re-elected in his safe Huntingdon constituency, looked shocked by the scale of the defeat as he arrived at Conservative headquarters in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Tonight we have been comprehensively defeated. Let us not pretend to ourselves it was anything other than what it was.&quot;</p>
<p>Former prime minister Margaret Thatcher congratulated Blair but warned him she would watch to ensure he did not fritter away the legacy of 18 years of Conservative rule.</p>
<p>Speaking to reporters outside her London home, Thatcher said Blair had skilfully concealed his detailed policies during the election campaign but had endorsed many of the principles that guided her and Major over the past two decades.</p>
<p>Asked whether her legacy would be safe with Blair, she said: &quot;I shall have something to say if it is not.&quot;</p>
<p>The Conservatives were projected to win 31 percent of the vote, down from 42.8 percent at the 1992 election, with Labour jumping to 45 percent from 35.2 percent.</p>
<p>In a sign of the speed with which Britain's ousted political leaders are stripped of the trappings of office, a removal van appeared behind Downing Street and began loading furniture. Blair has already been given Major's official limousine.</p>
<p>Major's appeal to voters, after 18 years of Conservative rule, was &quot;better the devil you know than the devil you don't&quot;.</p>
<p>But voters were hungry for change after the longest period of single-party rule this century.</p>
<p>They punished the Conservatives for years of internal party civil war over ties with Europe, broken promises over taxes, and a tide of sleaze scandals in the ruling party.</p>
<p>Farmers were alienated over government handling of the crisis over mad cow disease. Home owners lost small fortunes in a property market collapse, and the privatisation of monopoly industries made huge profits for a handful of &quot;fat cat&quot; business leaders.</p>
<p>The landslide was a ringing endorsement of Blair's agenda of change -- but not too much change.</p>
<p>The Conservatives were without any members of parliament in Scotland, Wales and vast swathes of south-west England, where the centre-left Liberal Democrats inflicted most damage.</p>
<p>The BBC projected the LibDems, Britain's third party, would more than double the 20 seats they won at the 1992 election, giving it its greatest breakthrough in 60 years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
