<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="556858" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Early UK rate rise vital for anti-inflation credibility.</title>
<headline>Early UK rate rise vital for anti-inflation credibility.</headline>
<byline>Cheryl Juckes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The newly-elected British Labour Party needs to raise official interest rates next week if it hopes to convince financial markets that its professed aim of beating inflation is more than just lip service, analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;If Brown really wants to be the iron Chancellor, it would be a help to start early,&quot; said Salomon Brothers economist Michael Saunders. &quot;If he delays, the markets are not going to be sure whether he's just waiting a month or if he's not going to be the iron Chancellor after all.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Gordon Brown, who is expected to be appointed Chancellor of the Exchequer later today, should increase Britain's 6.0 percent official interest rates by 50 basis points at the monetary meeting pencilled in for Wednesday.</p>
<p>Financial markets are so far discounting a rate increase of just 25 basis points and could be impressed by a larger move.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr. Brown's perspective is that he does want to establish him montetary credibility. The only issue is whether go for 50 basis points or compromise on 25,&quot; said Morgan Stanley econmist Kevin Gardiner.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't be at all surprised if he goes for 50 basis points,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Raising interest rates by a swift 50 basis points is also likely to allay Bank of England fears that inflation pressures are being allowed to build up.</p>
<p>Kenneth Clarke, Chancellor of the Exchequer for the outgoing Conservative administration, repeatedly rejected request from Bank of England Governor Eddie George for a 25 basis point increase. The minutes of the March meeting showed George warning delay might necessitate sharper rate rises later.  </p>
<p>The central bank is set to publish its quarterly inflation report on May 13, provided the date of the monetary meeting does not change, and if rates have increased, it is likely to be more confident about the chances of hitting the inflation target of 2.5 percent or lower and of sustaining it.</p>
<p>Such an endorsement from the central bank would go some way to quelling latent market fears that Labour might revert to its old high spending, high borrowing ways and allow inflation to soar once again, analysts said.</p>
<p>Other economists agreed a prompt move was necessary but considered they should just move rates by 25 basis points.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they ought to raise rates next week because that will establish some credibility for Gordon Brown but I don't think they put them up by more than 25 (basis points) because of how strong sterling is,&quot; said Kleinwort Benson gilt strategist Steve Scott.</p>
<p>&quot;But the market is certainly expecting some sort of rise.&quot;</p>
<p>The pound's recent strength has dampened demand for British exports and there are fears that the manufacturing sector could suffer further if interest rates go up again.  </p>
<p>An article in this morning's edition of The Times spooked sterling and gilts, with the suggestion Labour should tighten fiscal policy to take the strain off interest rates and allow the pound to devalue to help the manufacturing sector.</p>
<p>But, Morgan Stanley's Gardiner said that countries with better inflation records than Britain such as the U.S. and Germany rejected the textbook approach suggested by the newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;It's even more difficult to control the economy with fiscal tightening than with monetary tightening. If you look at places like the U.S. and Germany, they don't tinker with the tax system except for medium term supply side objectives. If they want to hit inflation, they let monetary policy take the strain.&quot;</p>
<p>BZW gilts analyst Kevin Adams also said that interest rates needed to rise but said there was a strong chance the new government would wait a couple of weeks before putting up interest rates rather than be seen to be bounced into a decision by financial markets or the Bank of England.</p>
<p>&quot;Clarke was clearly his own man while he was Chancellor and Brown is going to want to be the same. He'll want a decision to raise rates to be clearly his decision rather than the Governor's,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Adams added that after consideration of state of the economy Brown might well opt for a 50 basis point rise rather than just 25 basis points.</p>
<p>LIFFE June short sterling -- the best gauge of market sentiment to interest rates -- was unchanged at 93.37, discounting a rate of more than 25 basis points but not a full 50 basis points.</p>
<p>The reaction in gilts, sterling and equities to a Labour victory has also been muted, in contrast the jitters caused by even the threat of a Labour victory before Leader Tony Blair completed the party's modernisation.</p>
<p>But the markets are still keeping a wary eye on Labour.</p>
<p>&quot;We're definitely looking for a rise in interest rates next week,&quot; one trader on the LIFFE floor said. &quot;And we're waiting for some sort of statement from Brown,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The market is looking for confirmation that Labour will still hold the monetary meeting which the previous government set for next week.</p>
<p>&quot;If he puts off the meeting the market is not going to like it,&quot; the trader warned.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
