<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="556887" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Palestinians said to jail lawyer over criticism.</title>
<headline>Palestinians said to jail lawyer over criticism.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Palestinian Authority has jailed a Gazan lawyer on charges he slandered it by writing in an article that Palestinians should adopt Israeli standards of democracy, a human rights activist said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Palestinian Attorney General Khalid al-Qidreh signed an arrest order charging Naim Salameh of slandering the Palestinian Authority, and presenting him to the State Security Court which would use the article as legal evidence against him,&quot; Palestinian human rights activist Bassem Eid told Reuters.</p>
<p>Eid said lawyer Salameh wrote an article about an Israeli corruption scandal in which the prime minister and justice minister were interrogated by police over suspicions they appointed an attorney-general in a shady deal with a political ally.</p>
<p>Police recommended Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu be charged with fraud and breach of trust but the prosecution decided to close the case for lack of evidence.</p>
<p>Eid quoted Salameh as praising the system that allowed police to investigate senior officials and writing &quot;he wondered when we will see such examples applied in Palestinian Authority territory&quot;.</p>
<p>Salameh sent his article to the Gaza Lawyers Union for publication in a quarterly journal, Eid said. One lawyer took it to Attorney General al-Qidreh, who decided to jail him.</p>
<p>&quot;Salameh has been arrested and remains in jail,&quot; Eid said.</p>
<p>Al-Qidreh and the Gaza Lawyers Union were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Since the Palestinian Authority took control of parts of the West Bank and Gaza Strip under a PLO-Israel peace deal, many Palestinian and international human rights groups have accused it of restricting freedom of speech and of the press.</p>
<p>Eid blasted the Lawyers Union and the Palestinian public for remaining silent and failing to condemn Salameh's arrest.</p>
<p>&quot;I personally consider such acts as a symbol of how freedom of press is in the Palestinian Authority-ruled areas...I claim that Salameh criticised the Authority and didn't slander it,&quot; Eid said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
