<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="556817" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FORECAST - Margins key as Sainsbury profits dip.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Margins key as Sainsbury profits dip.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>British supermarket chain J. Sainsbury Plc has already warned its profits will fall this year so the focus when it reports on May 7 will be on progress on sales and margins, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The focus will be on the bottom line, the real issue is whether they have turned sales into profit,&quot; said Miriam Shea, analyst at Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>Sainsbury said in January that the cost of rebuilding sales had reduced profitability short-term and predicted year profits would fall to 640-650 million stg before exceptionals, from 764 million stg a year ago.</p>
<p>Analysts said the store group, striving to regain ground against arch-rival Tesco, was likely to keep its dividend flat at 12.1 pence.</p>
<p>Sainsbury was toppled off the market leader slot by Tesco over a year ago and has since taken steps, including launch of a loyalty card, to try to regain momentum.</p>
<p>Its latest sales report in January showed that same store sales were up four percent in the 16 weeks to January 11 with a 4.4 percent rise over the key Christmas period.</p>
<p>That compares with Tesco's six percent gain in the first four weeks of its financial year which started in March.</p>
<p>&quot;If Sainsbury's sales in supermarkets are up 3.0-3.5 percent, that will be seen as good news, under two percent and the market will take it as bearish,&quot; said one analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;If they can prove sales and margins are doing better, there could be a bit of performance in the shares,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Sainsbury shares were trading at 336-1/2 pence at 1100 GMT on Friday, up 3p.</p>
<p>Tesco, which in April reported year pretax profits of 750 million stg, up from 675 million stg, said then that its operating margins slipped 0.4 percent to 5.8 percent but added that gross margins might stabilise this year.</p>
<p>That boosted stocks in the sector, which has seen a highly competitive market with low food price inflation in recent months.</p>
<p>Sainsbury chairman David Sainsbury said at half-year results in October, 1996, that the year would be about &quot;getting the basics right, next year will be about getting profits moving,&quot; and most analysts are looking for an improvement in results next year.</p>
<p>The group has turned to loyalty cards and set up a bank with Bank of Scotland as part of efforts to woo back customers and move sales ahead.</p>
<p>Kwik Save, one of the second tier of British supermarkets, will follow Sainsbury's annual results with its own half year profits on May 8.</p>
<p>Analysts were expecting pretax profits to come in between 32 million and 43 million stg compared with 44.2 million stg a year ago, with an unchanged dividend payout of 5.95 pence.</p>
<p>The group announced a radical shake-up of its discount chain in November with the closure of 107 stores and investment of some 50 million stg on a New Generation programme.</p>
<p>Kwik Save may announce further results of its strategic review with half year profits.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
