<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557095" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Sweden praises British Labour victory.</title>
<headline>Sweden praises British Labour victory.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish Prime Minister Goran Persson on Friday hailed Tony Blair's British election victory and said it put a final end to conservative doctrines launched by former premier Margaret Thatcher between 1979 and 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt the Labour victory is a result of the devastating social consequences which the conservative Thatcher politics caused for large groups of British citizens.</p>
<p>Persson, who heads a minority social democratic government, said the victory was a boost for social democratic parties around Europe and would make jobs a key issue for the European Union.</p>
<p>&quot;The Labour victory is strong inspiration for Social Democrats in all of Europe,&quot; Persson said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;With a Labour government in Britain European Union cooperation in the struggle against unemployment will be affected in a positive and constructive direction,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Persson said the victory sounded the death knell for conservative politicies.</p>
<p>&quot;The victory shows that the British people would like to have a change and politics characterised by social responsibility for all people,&quot; Persson said.</p>
<p>Persson said he looked forward to meeting Blair at a meeting of European Socialist Parties (ESP) in the Swedish city of Malmo in June.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
