<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557147" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Blair win opens new era in Europe - Italy's D'Alema.</title>
<headline>Blair win opens new era in Europe - Italy's D'Alema.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Democratic Party of the Left (PDS), the biggest force in Italy's government, on Friday hailed Tony Blair's British election victory as a new era for Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;The extraordinary victory of New Labour led by you opens a new political phase for Europe,&quot; PDS leader Massimo D'Alema said in a letter congratulating Blair on the landslide victory of his Labour party that ended 18 years of Conservative rule.</p>
<p>&quot;The Conservative age has ended. The age of the left, which has had the courage to renew itself and become a credible alternative for government, has begun,&quot; D'Alema said.</p>
<p>D'Alema knows the feeling. His party entered government a year ago in an historic victory for the left after it dumped its communist past and relaunched itself as a social democratic force.</p>
<p>The PDS is the backbone of Prime Minister Romano Prodi's centre-left coalition.</p>
<p>D'Alema said Blair's victory in Thursday's general election would reinforce the role of the left in Europe. &quot;The right in Europe loses a stronghold, bringing it closer to its decline,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
