<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557253" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK wool prices to rise this year, says industry.</title>
<headline>UK wool prices to rise this year, says industry.</headline>
<byline>Paul Carrel</byline>
<dateline>BRADFORD, England 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>British wool prices are set to pick up later in 1997 on the back of increased demand even if sterling stays strong, industry specialists said at the start of the new wool season on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We think that may be longer-term, eight to nine months ahead, wool prices will increase,&quot; British Wool Marketing Board (BWMB) chief wool appraiser Malcolm Brook told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>UK Super 56S wool is quoted now around 345 pence sterling per kg.</p>
<p>But should the pound continue its rise, it could have a negative effect and actually depress demand for British wool. As about 60 percent of domestic wool output is exported, British wool producers are vulnerable to a high sterling exchange rate.</p>
<p>&quot;If sterling gets much stronger it could have a bounce-back effect and damage the British wool trade,&quot; Brook said.</p>
<p>With UK wool stocks relatively low compared to last season, demand would push prices higher, he added. But he said it was difficult to gauge by how much prices would rise.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point in time we are not fully aware as to how much stock our buyers are holding. What is more, we do not know how much of that stock is sold forward to cover orders.&quot;</p>
<p>Stocks in key wool producers Australia and New Zealand are also diminishing. Australian stocks are currently around two million bales compared with five million bales 12 months ago, BWMB's Brook said.</p>
<p>New Zealand now has no stockpiled wool, against two million bales a year ago.</p>
<p>But global demand for wool is on the increase, according to Brook.</p>
<p>&quot;Principal buyer China blows hot and cold. At the moment China's blowing hot for British wool,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>China, traditionally a volatile market, is blending U.K. wool with its own poorer quality output, he added.</p>
<p>Back in Britain uncertainty about possible interest rate rises after the general election on May 1 and whether sterling would maintain its strength made it harder still to forecast British wool prices, Brook said.</p>
<p>But industry experts were sure demand pressures would hot up as prices clawed their way back from the 1990 wool price crash.</p>
<p>&quot;With western Europe appearing to be out of recession we think supply and demand pressures are starting to come into equilibrium,&quot; said Ian Hilton, director of market intelligence at the International Wool Secretariat.</p>
<p>And UK wool production was set to increase, experts said, boosted by the British BSE scare. Consumers worried about &quot;mad cow disease&quot; were choosing to eat more lamb which would increase sheep stocks and have the knock-on effect of lifting wool production, Brook said.</p>
<p>He expected this year's U.K. fleece wool production to rise to at least 48 million kilos from 46-1/2 million in 1996.</p>
<p>John Lambert, director of the Confederation of British Wool Textiles said the uptrend in UK wool prices would be supported by steady increases in world wool prices on the back of growing demand and tightening supply.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices will be bolstered as British wool stockpiles are depleted,&quot; Lambert said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRADFORD, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
