<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557200" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. jobless rate falls to 4.9 percent in April.</title>
<headline>U.S. jobless rate falls to 4.9 percent in April.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The unemployment rate fell to 4.9 percent last month -- its lowest rate in more than 23 years -- from 5.2 percent in March, even though the economy created jobs at only a modest pace, the government said on Friday.</p>
<p>The Labor Department said 142,000 non-farm jobs were added to payrolls in April, little changed from a revised 139,000 that were created in March and far fewer than had been expected. Before its revision, the department had estimated that 175,000 jobs were created in March.  </p>
<p>(May be bylined Peter Szekely)</p>
<p>Economists surveyed by Reuters had forecast an unemployment rate of 5.2 percent and the creation of 211,000 non-farm jobs. They said financial markets would be focused on the jobless rate for April more so than the change in the number of jobs.</p>
<p>The 4.9 percent jobless rate matched a level last seen in December 1973, the department said.</p>
<p>Katharine Abraham, commissioner of the department's Bureau of Labour Statistics, did not explain the sharp rate drop, except to note that the data often vary from month to month.</p>
<p>&quot;Although a great deal of attention undoubtedly will be paid to the drop in the jobless rate, I would caution, as always, against reading too much into any one month's data,&quot; Abraham said in a prepared testimony to the congressional Joint Economic Committee.</p>
<p>Accompanying the lower rate was a sharp drop of 430,000 idle workers to 6.7 million and a jump of 209,000 jobholders to 129.4 million, the department said in its household survey. The total civilian labour force, which includes all job holders and job seekers, fell by 221,000 to 136.1 million, it said.</p>
<p>The jobs report, the government's first look at the health of the economy in April, follows a report earlier this week that the economy grew at a nine-year-high annual rate of 5.6 percent in the first quarter.</p>
<p>But the GDP report also showed a rise in prices that analysts said was troubling and could prod Federal Reserve policymakers to further tighten credit following the central bank's quarter-point boost in short-term interest rates on March 25.</p>
<p>When Fed policymakers meet again on May 20 to consider another rise in rates, economists expect Friday's job market report to weigh heavily in their thinking.</p>
<p>So far, however, the there has been little or no wage-driven inflation, despite growing tightness in the job market. Gains in total compensation, as measured by the department's Employment Cost Index (ECI) earlier this week, slowed to 0.6 percent in the first quarter from 0.8 percent in the fourth quarter as the cost of providing benefits such as health care was nearly unchanged.</p>
<p>In April average hourly wages, a less comprehensive measure than the quarterly ECI, fell by 1 cent to $12.14, after gaining 5 cents in March, the department said. Over the past 12 months, wages rose 3.6 percent, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the month-to-month movements in this data series remain quite volatile, the over-the-year gains for recent months clearly have been running higher than during the early part of 1996,&quot; Abraham said.</p>
<p>The April payrolls increase occurred entirely in a variety of service-type industries, while manufacturing and construction employment declined, the department said.</p>
<p>Job growth included 32,000 in retail trade, 32,000 in government employment, 34,000 in health services and 29,000 in engineering and management. While finance, insurance and real estate employment grew, the number of temporary help jobs fell.</p>
<p>The manufacturing sector lost 14,000 jobs in April after gaining 75,000 in the previous six months, the department said.</p>
<p>But factories were operating in high gear last month as factory overtime hours rose 6 mintues to a record-high 5 hours per week, while the factory work week rose by 6 minutes to 42.2 hours, matching a post-World War Two high.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
