<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557317" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Inexperience, expectation - Blair's great problems.</title>
<headline>Inexperience, expectation - Blair's great problems.</headline>
<byline>Robert Woodward</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The flush of victory is warm on Tony Blair's cheeks but the newness of &quot;New Labour&quot; and the inexperience of Blair and his cabinet may chill the party's confidence after its first election win since 1974.</p>
<p>For Labour this victory is like the birth of a child after many disappointments. Joy is unconfined but in a few hours those responsible for the happy event will be aware the hard work does not end with a successful delivery, it begins within hours.</p>
<p>Blair, 43, made few specific promises during the election campaign, beyond vowing not to raise income taxes for five years and to keep a tight grip on public spending. Many of his policies seemed to be carbon copies of the Conservatives'.</p>
<p>But millions of Britons voted Labour because they were fed up with Major's party. They may not be life-long Labour voters but they voted for change.</p>
<p>Britain's youngest prime minister this century will face popular pressure to change the government of the country as much as he has changed his party since becoming leader in 1994. Only four members of Blair's cabinet will have held a government post, all at junior ministerial level in the Labour government ousted in 1979 by the Conservatives. It will be the most inexperienced cabinet of the 20th century.</p>
<p>Blair, a member of parliament for 14 years, has never held a ministerial position. Unlike most of his Labour predecessors he has not held an executive post in union or local government politics, being a lawyer before entering politics.</p>
<p>Under Labour's internal regulations, Blair's first cabinet has to be drawn from the so-called &quot;shadow&quot; cabinet elected every year by the party's members of parliament.</p>
<p>He is not bound by these rules at any future reshuffle, and there has been speculation that Blair might not even respect them to the letter when he names his first cabinet.</p>
<p>The cabinet's ignorance of the levers and pulleys of government have been alleviated by backroom meetings with senior civil servants over recent months, but ministers are bound to run into problems with the basic mechanics of decision-making.</p>
<p>&quot;Civil servants will be able to advise Labour ministers on how to be efficient administrators. They will be completely unequipped to guide those ministers on how to be effective members of a successful administration,&quot; says former Labour minister Gerald Kaufman.</p>
<p>Blair's biggest problems over the early months may well come from the expectations of both party and people, some of whom want a seamless transition and others radical change.</p>
<p>John Major's Conservatives were ousted partly because of a feeling they were tired, out of touch and self-serving.</p>
<p>Many Britons desire a complete change after 18 years of the same government and could turn against Labour if they merely mimic the policies of the outgoing administration in an attempt not to frighten financial markets and overseas investors.</p>
<p>Others voted for New Labour because it resembled old-style &quot;one nation&quot; Conservatism. Blair offered the excitement of a new government without the danger, a changeless novelty that guaranteed no nasty shocks.</p>
<p>Blair has repeatedly said he would not attempt a &quot;First 100 Days&quot; of policy during which Britain's political script would be totally rewritten. Blair wants two terms of government to impose New Labour policies on the nation.</p>
<p>But a softly-softly approach will not endear him to members of the left wing of the party. They have largely kept quiet since July 1994 as Blair squeezed socialism out of Labour and repositioned the party in the centre ground.</p>
<p>The left will now expect a payback for their tameness during the election campaign, and they know their words and actions will have far more effect on public opinion and party leaders in government than in opposition.</p>
<p>&quot;Our problem will be to prevent a rootless Labour government moving further to the right to gain impetus... Stopping that will be the responsibility of old Labour,&quot; said member of parliament Austin Mitchell late last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
