<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557305" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK Labour's big win permits tough economic policy.</title>
<headline>UK Labour's big win permits tough economic policy.</headline>
<byline>Rosemary Bennett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The sweeping election victory secured by Britain's opposition Labour Party means the new government can take tough decisions on tax and interest rates with impunity in the first weeks of power, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;If anything, (this result) is slightly market positive because it allows (opposition leader Tony) Blair to do pretty much what he wants,&quot; said James Barty, UK economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>&quot;And since a lot of the Labour candidates in more marginal seats are probably Blairites, if anything it gives Blair more power over the hard left.&quot;</p>
<p>With most of the votes counted by early Friday, Labour was expected to have an overall majority of 179 seats, the biggest in its history.</p>
<p>During the election campaign, Labour pledged it would keep a tight grip on public spending and retain the ruling Conservatives' 2.5 percent inflation target.</p>
<p>But there were latent fears in financial markets that a landslide win would empower Labour and allow it to revert back to more traditional, high-spending policies.</p>
<p>However, the large number of new, young Labour MPs loyal to Blair mean this moderate faction dwarfs the old left wing and the government does not have to rely on the hardliners for support to push through economic decisions.</p>
<p>&quot;The size of the left wing faction within this new government is very small,&quot; said Andrew Cates, UK economist at UBS.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe Tony Blair should find it easier, not harder, to pursue policies which he has attempted over the past year or so to persuade markets are credible.&quot;</p>
<p>Ivor Crewe, political analyst and vice-chancellor at the University of Essex, said the new intake of MPs will be very loyal to Blair in the first two years of power.</p>
<p>&quot;Labour's majority will be manageable, certainly for the first year or two, because Tony Blair is a winner and they will be grateful to him.&quot;</p>
<p>This makes it likely the government will use the early months of power to push through the least popular policies.</p>
<p>And that could mean a monetary tightening as early as next week.</p>
<p>Chancellor of the Exchequer-in-waiting Gordon Brown said he was anxious to start work as soon as possible and the BBC said he intended to go ahead with the scheduled monthly monetary meeting on May 7.</p>
<p>Markets are focused on that meeting which could well result in a small rise in the 6.0 percent interest rate, although most analysts favour a mvoe coming at the next meeting in June.</p>
<p>Brown could also use his mini-budget, due within the next two months, to tighten fiscal policy. Although the party is committed to keeping the standard rates of income tax unchanged, it has been careful not to promise to leave all indirect taxes unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's pretty clear Labour will use its honeymoon period to get the bad news out of way quickly,&quot; said Mark Henry, financial analyst at GNI.</p>
<p>&quot;Comments from Brown overnight suggest he will get things up and running as soon as he can, and that could mean a monetary tightening next week, although June is more likely.&quot;</p>
<p>Financial markets took a sanguine view of the massive Labour majority.</p>
<p>The pound gained on the mark overnight but wobbled slightly in early trade. It stood at 2.7866/76 marks against 2.7970/80 marks before the result.</p>
<p>June gilt futures opened 2/32 higher at 110-27/32, up 2/32.</p>
<p>Traders said shares would probably react adversely with politically-sensitive utilities stocks likely to lead a deline.</p>
<p>The FTSE index of 100 leading shares was seen opening 50 points lower after setting a record close on Thursday of 4,445.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7715</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
