<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557399" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Fear creeps in as UK markets mull Labour landslide.</title>
<headline>Fear creeps in as UK markets mull Labour landslide.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Levene</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Initial market relief at an apparent landslide election victory for Britain's Labour Party rapidly gave way to fears of an over-powerful and under-experienced government.</p>
<p>&quot;A reasonable Labour majority was largely what was in the market -- a very strong majority gives them the upper hand to do whatever they want,&quot; said Peter Osler, head of research at GNI.</p>
<p>Sterling and gilts rallied after exit polls indicated Labour -- out of government since 1979 -- was on course for a resounding victory over the ruling Conservatives.</p>
<p>The market's immediate reaction was to cheer the prospect of a clear victor as it dispelled fears of a slim, unworkable majority or -- the worst-case scenario for markets -- a hung parliament, where no party has a majority.</p>
<p>But the currency and bonds backtracked as results filtered through and traders rethought the implications of Labour domination of Britain's 659-seat parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;A Labour victory has been discounted by the market but it may get a little bit concerned about the extent of the majority if it's well over 100 seats,&quot; said Corey Miller, UK equity strategist at Credit Lyonnais Laing.</p>
<p>&quot;The implication being that Labour may be over-confident and resort to old' Labour, pursuing much more radical spending policies.&quot; Labour finance spokesman Gordon Brown moved fast to soothe those concerns as poll results set him on course to become Britain's next Chancellor of the Exchequer.</p>
<p>&quot;We fully intend to keep all our promises and will move very quickly on a budget,&quot; Brown told ITN television news.</p>
<p>He said a Labour government would deliver the first budget within two months and stick to the commitments made during the election campaign.</p>
<p>Sterling spiked up to $1.6280 and 2.8010 marks after the first exit poll gave Labour 47 percent of the vote, with the Conservatives on just 29 percent. It stood at $1.6253/60 and 2.7970/80 marks just before the polls appeared.</p>
<p>But the pound had retreated to $1.6225/35 and 2.7965/75 by 2340 GMT.</p>
<p>Gilts gained ground initially, then fell. The benchmark 10-year 7.25 percent gilt was trading around 98-25, down from 98-27 before the exit polls and 99-07 after them.</p>
<p>&quot;Because it's such a large majority it means Labour can do what they like, But what does that mean? No-one really knows,&quot; one currency trader at a European bank in Singapore said.</p>
<p>Sterling should be underpinned, however, by the prospects of an early interest rate rise, he added.</p>
<p>Analysts said a Labour government, keen to establish credibility with the markets, would probably tighten the screws quickly on monetary policy.</p>
<p>Bank of England governor Eddie George has long been calling for an interest rate rise -- though his advice has fallen on deaf Conservative ears.</p>
<p>&quot;On the one hand this is a very strong government and a very decisive result -- but on the other hand it's something completely new,&quot; said GNI's Osler.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44-171-542-8968</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
