<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557477" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila stocks fall again, no relief in sight.</title>
<headline>Manila stocks fall again, no relief in sight.</headline>
<byline>Katherine Espina</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine shares plunged on Friday as foreign investors continued to flee a market battered by fears that many top companies are in for troubled times, and analysts warned that a reversal was nowhere in sight.</p>
<p>The latest tumble capped a week that saw the market suffer some of its sharpest falls in more than two years.</p>
<p>The market closed on Friday at 2605.65, down 1.61 percent for the day and some 25 percent below its record high just three months ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The follow-through selling continues. It's quick and savage,&quot; said Louie Bate, managing director for equities brokerage at ING Baring Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;Blue chips are being sold by foreign fund managers who are not so hot about the Philippines and the region, concerned about the property sector and the FOMC meeting on interest rates,&quot; said Monique Lecaros, trading supervisor at Sun Hung Kai Securities.</p>
<p>The United States Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meets next on May 20 to decide whether to change interest rates.</p>
<p>Sentiment was further weighed down by blue chip Philippine Long Distance Telephone Co's overnight fall in New York.</p>
<p>Week-on-week, the index lost 266.72 points, or just more than nine percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said fears about the property sector had in turn weighed on the banking sector and the gloom was exacerbated by poor first-quarter company earnings and a negative stance by fund managers towards the region created the bearish market.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, the market is selling. Investors feel it is not worth going to the office just to lose money,&quot; said Noel Reyes, research head of Ancor-Hagedorn.</p>
<p>Traders see no end in sight to the market's downtrend.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook is still negative. We see no light yet at the end of the tunnel,&quot; said Teresa Lee, vice-president at Asiamerit Securities.</p>
<p>But other analysts said the release of positive first-quarter gross national product growth figures by the first week of June may bring lustre back to the market.</p>
<p>The hammering of share prices has put heavy pressure on the peso, forcing the Central Bank to sell dollars again on Friday to protect the currency.</p>
<p>Dealers said the Bank was worried that as foreigners liquidated their shares into dollars pressure would come to bear on the peso.</p>
<p>Despite complaints from exporters, the Central Bank has kept the peso strong as part of efforts to keep a lid on inflation.</p>
<p>However, because of the share price collapse it had to raise interest rates this week and traders are warning they may be raised again next week to prop up the peso.</p>
<p>In the stock market, traders advised investors to be cautious.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not out of the woods and this very bearish market is just for long-term investors, not for those looking to buy and sell,&quot; said Nathan Lozada, assistant vice-president at Philippine Asia Equity.</p>
<p>But ING's Bate saw the possibility of a technical rebound.</p>
<p>&quot;Some stocks unjustly sold are beginning to be picked up. We could experience a dead cat bounce,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
