<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557552" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Nera says to get Singapore share listing.</title>
<headline>Nera says to get Singapore share listing.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian telecommunications company Nera ASA (NERA) said on Friday it had applied for a main board listing on the Stock Exchange of Singapore (SES) but would not issue any new shares to mark the event.</p>
<p>&quot;This listing is one of many pieces building our presence locally and in the region,&quot; Nera chairman Frode Botnevik told Reuters after a news conference announcing the move.</p>
<p>About 40 percent of Nera's 1996 2.62 billion kroner turnover was generated in Asia and that was expected to edge up towards 50 percent over the next two or three years, Botnevik said.  </p>
<p>While no shares were being offered in the introductory listing, Nera did not rule out an offering in future.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's just say we're talking in terms of quarters rather than months,&quot; Botnevik told reporters in response to questions on a possible timeframe, adding it was &quot;difficult to make promises&quot; that this would happen by the end of the year.</p>
<p>Any new offering &quot;would have to be meaningful -- at least a couple of million shares&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>Nera shares are already listed on the Oslo Stock Exchange and quoted on New York's NASDAQ.  </p>
<p>The company has a market capitalisation of more than US$400 million and had issued 13.15 million fully paid ordinary shares of 10 Norwegian kroner each as of December 31 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of you may be surprised that this listing comes with no offering, but we think this is best for all parties concerned,&quot; said Eric Ang, executive vice president of DBS Bank Ltd, the institution sponsoring the listing.</p>
<p>Botnevik said the reason no more shares were being offered &quot;really has more to do with the recent performance of our Oslo shares and our not wanting to dilute them&quot;, than any concern about recent weakness in the Singapore market.  </p>
<p>He said the shares had suffered recent weakness in Oslo after earnings dipped in the 1996 financial year and continued falling in the first quarter on 1997.</p>
<p>Ang said he expected SES would confirm the listing next week and dealing, which would be conducted in U.S. dollars in board lots of 100 shares, should begin soon after.</p>
<p>-- Nick Edwards, Singapore newsroom (65 8703011)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
