<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557596" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK stock market reflects China's growing influence.</title>
<headline>HK stock market reflects China's growing influence.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Genevieve</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's property-dominated stock market has become heavily focused on China plays in the run up to Chinese rule, offering the prospect of a wider variety of drivers as mainland influence grows, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;In itself Hong Kong does not really have that much to offer. All you do is that you end up owning financial assets,&quot; said Lehman Brothers senior strategist Abhijit Chakrabortti.</p>
<p>&quot;Buying into the China growth story is far more attractive than really buying into Hong Kong in itself,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Property stocks make up about 29 percent of the market capitalisation of the blue chip Hang Seng Index, and banking stocks -- which are also heavily influenced by the property market and mortgage lending -- represent about 30 percent.</p>
<p>But the market capitalisation of China plays has been bolstered by a furious rise in stock prices and a rash of new share issues in the red chip and H-share sectors ahead of Hong Kong's return to Chinese sovereignty at midnight on June 30.</p>
<p>Red chips are Hong Kong-incorporated companies with financial backing from China. H-shares are mainland incorporated companies listed in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>&quot;To the extent that we see more China listings, the composition of the market will change somewhat,&quot; said Jake van der Kamp, investment strategist at HG Asia.</p>
<p>The increased exposure to China should ensure a stronger earnings stream, he said. &quot;You cannot maintain a high earnings growth rate out of Hong Kong alone and at some point you will have to be looking more offshore,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund expects China's economy to grow by 9.5 percent in 1997. A drive to improve infrastructure should ensure continued focus on China-related power, transport, telecommunications and construction stocks, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Anything China exposed is going to look good during this year and next year because China's economic cycle is favourable,&quot; said South China Brokerage director Howard Gorges.</p>
<p>Analysts said the 33-company blue chip Hang Seng Index, which represents more than 70 percent of Hong Kong's market capitalisation, fails to reflect the market's changing nature.</p>
<p>&quot;A couple of...the red chips have grown and expanded to such a size that they now dwarf a lot of index stocks,&quot; said Andrew Fernow, director of research at Vickers Ballas.</p>
<p>He predicted a shuffle in the Hang Seng Index this year to include a red chip, possibly Shanghai Industrial Holdings Ltd, controlled by the Shanghai municipal government, or China Resources Enterprise Ltd, controlled by China's Ministry of Foreign Trade and Economic Cooperation.</p>
<p>Shares in Shanghai Industrial, a maker of cigarettes, pharmaceuticals, packaging and printing products, have soared 57 percent this year. China Resources, which operates cold storage, brewery and property businesses, is up 27 percent.</p>
<p>HSI Services Ltd, the keeper of the Hang Seng Index, declined to comment on whether it would reshuffle the index.</p>
<p>&quot;The HSI is reviewed on a quarterly basis. If any stock has a large market cap and high turnover it will have a better chance to become a constituent,&quot; spokesman Tony Chiu said.</p>
<p>CITIC Pacific Ltd, the Hong Kong branch of Beijing's official foreign trading arm China International Trust and Investment Corp, and Guangdong Investment Ltd, controlled by Guangdong province, are already blue chips.</p>
<p>But pure China plays are not the only sources of exposure to mainland growth, with many Hong Kong companies expanding their operations in China, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;A tremendous amount of stocks listed in Hong Kong either have direct or indirect China exposure,&quot; said Marshall Mays, chief strategist at Nikko Research Center (Hong Kong) Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;The percentage of Hong Kong's market capitalisation which reflects sales in China and production in China will only increase.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong News Room (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
