<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557517" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: More mergers seen among Thai finance companies.</title>
<headline>More mergers seen among Thai finance companies.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>More mergers are expect among Thai finance companies in the near future as competition intensifies, making it necessary for firms to have a larger capital base, a central bank official said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is certain that the number of finance companies will decrease through the mergers,&quot; the Bank of Thailand's deputy governor Jaroong Nookhwun told a seminar.</p>
<p>&quot;The mergers among them will help boost competitiveness in preparation for fiercer competiton following the liberalisation of the financial market,&quot; he added. Thailand currently has 91 operating finance and finance and securities companies.</p>
<p>The central bank last month launched a package of incentives including the granting of new bank licenses to promote mergers among weak finance and securities companies.</p>
<p>The move followed a massive revamp of the troubled and liquidity-hit finance sector in March by the Thai authorities.</p>
<p>Jaroong said finance companies will need to have a bigger capital base to compete with increasing foreign participation in the local financial market. &quot;The central bank wants finance companies to have large capital base. The best way now is to trigger more mergers which will automatically increase their capital,&quot; he said. -- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
