<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557673" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila financial markets take a fresh beating.</title>
<headline>Manila financial markets take a fresh beating.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Thatcher</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippines shares slumped on Friday at the end of a week which has seen the heaviest fall in prices for more than two years.</p>
<p>The plunge in the market that only three months ago was surging to new peaks, was triggered by fears of a property and banking collapse that turned into a tidal wave of selling as investors took fright that the country's outlook was not so bright after all.</p>
<p>In morning trading, the Philippines share index was down just over one percent at 2,619.73 though the volume of selling was beginning to calm down.</p>
<p>&quot;Follow-through selling is still driving the index lower,&quot; said Louie Bate, managing director of equities brokerage ING Barings.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, the market is selling. Investors feel it is not worth going to the office just to lose money,&quot; said Noel Reyes, research head of Ancor-Hagedorn.</p>
<p>Sentiment was further undermined by the drop in Philippine Long Distance Telephone Corp shares overnight on Wall Street. The company is one of the biggest in the Philippines.</p>
<p>The hammering in the share market has put heavy pressure on the peso and the Central Bank had to sell dollars again on Friday to protect the currency.</p>
<p>Dealers said the Bank is worried that as foreigners sell their shares and switch back into dollars this will push the peso down further.</p>
<p>Despite complaints from exporters, the Central Bank has kept the peso strong as part of efforts to keep a lid on inflation.</p>
<p>However, because of the share price collapse it also had to raise interest rates this week and traders are warning that they may have to go up again next week to prop up the peso.</p>
<p>In the shares market, some blue chips managed to post gains during the morning despite the general weaknes, said Irving Ackerman, president at I. Ackerman &amp; Co Inc.</p>
<p>He pointed to B shares in San Miguel Corp, Manila Electric Corp, and Ayala Corp, all of which firmed. B shares are open to foreign investors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
