<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557698" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai baht strengthens, interbank rises.</title>
<headline>Thai baht strengthens, interbank rises.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Thai baht firmed against the dollar on Friday and demand for funds ahead of a bank holiday weekend pushed the interbank rate higher, dealers said.</p>
<p>The baht was quoted at 26.105-26.110 per dollar early on Friday against 26.110-26.115 late on Wednesday. The market was closed on Thursday. The Bank of Thaiand mid-rate was 26.09. The one-month baht/dollar swap premium rose to 6.25/7.25 satang per dollar against 5.00/6.00 satang on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said the spot market was quiet but forward swaps were active as reported problems with a proposed merger Finance One and Thai Danu Bank had spurred dollar buying forward.  </p>
<p>&quot;The spot is quiet but the forward swaps are quite exciting because of rumours about the Thai Danu and FinOne deal,&quot; said a local dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems like they may be rumours but if this deal doesn't go through there could be some problems in the financial system, so that is seeing people buying forward,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thai Danu Bank Plc earlier this year announced it was to merge with Finance One, the country's largest non-bank financial institution. Local newspapers reported on Thursday that the deal was in danger of collapse.  </p>
<p>The baht/dollar swap was bolstered by the dollar's decline by 0.66 yen during morning trade in Tokyo.</p>
<p>The overnight interbank rate rose to 9.50-10.00 percent from 7.50-8.00 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Banks, reopening after Thursday holiday, sought funds ahead of a three-day holiday weekend, dealers said. Fortnight bank reserve requirements are due next Wednesday.</p>
<p>Some traders said the central bank may have moved to tighten liquidity through open market operations late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- James Mclean (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
