<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557735" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta stocks seen mixed, focus on MSCI news.</title>
<headline>Jakarta stocks seen mixed, focus on MSCI news.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta stocks are expected to continue being mixed on Friday with attention focused on the new composition of the Morgan Stanley Capital Index, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;That news will continue affecting market sentiment as not all brokers and investors are aware of the new MSCI composition announced yesterday,&quot; a broker with a London-based securities house said.</p>
<p>He predicted cigarette maker Gudang Garam and cement firm Indocement will come under selling pressure as MSCI had downgraded its weighting on Gudang Garam and deleted Indocement from the index.  </p>
<p>Brokers said blue chip counters such as Bank Negara Indonesia, Bimantara Citra and toll road operator Citra Marga Nusaphala would make gains following their inclusion in the MSCI.</p>
<p>But one broker with a local firm said the gains in those stocks would not lead to a rise in the composite index.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think buying interest on the companies included in the MSCI can help the index rebound. On Fridays many investors tend to take profit,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>She added that domestic political news ahead of the May 29 general election would prevent the market from active trading and limit any possible sharp rebound.</p>
<p>On Thursday, the Jakarta Composite Index fell 1.60 points to close at 650.46 points. -- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364  </p>
<p>The broker said players were seen taking profit in stocks which had made modest gains on Thursday after news that they had been included in the MSCI and hunting for bargains in stocks which had fallen.</p>
<p>The most active Bank BNI fell 25 rupiah to 1,475 rupiah, with some 16 million shares traded, brokers said.</p>
<p>BNI rose 150 rupiah on Thursday to close at 1,500 rupiah following the inclusion of the bank in the index.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, players hunted for bargains in heavyweight Gudang Garam as it was considered to have bottomed out following a sell-off on Thursday, brokers said.  </p>
<p>Reports that the cigarette firm's market capitalisation factor in the index would be lowered to 0.4 from 1.0 prompted the sell-off, brokers said.</p>
<p>Gudang Garam rose 175 rupiah to 9,625 rupiah but volumes were relatively small as there were only around 450,000 shares traded.</p>
<p>Brokers said the composite index was likely to remain in negative territory the rest of the day, with focus likely to shift to certain secondliners due to speculative reasons.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
