<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557811" id="root" date="1997-05-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: EU to hold extra summit to push for treaty reforms.</title>
<headline>EU to hold extra summit to push for treaty reforms.</headline>
<dateline>THE HAGUE 1997-05-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union leaders will meet at an informal summit in the Dutch coastal town of Noordwijk on May 23 in a bid to keep the 15-member bloc on track for landmark reforms at a mid-June Amsterdam summit.</p>
<p>Announcing the extra meeting, Dutch Foreign Minister Hans van Mierlo, whose country currently holds the EU presidency, said the &quot;very informal&quot; session, starting at midday and concluding in the evening, would cover the key issues in the inter-governmental conference (IGC).</p>
<p>This ongoing ministerial review of the EU's &quot;constitution&quot; aims to produce a more efficient and transparent Union, paving the way for an ambitious eastward expansion that could see up to a dozen ex-communist states joining in the next decade.</p>
<p>But, just six weeks before EU leaders are due to sign landmark treaty reforms at Amsterdam, negotiations are bogged down over the nuts and bolts of institutional change -- the size of a future European Commission and how to ensure the decision-making process fairly represents each country's population.</p>
<p>Van Mierlo also said the extra summit would give member states the chance to quiz Britain's new Prime Minister Tony Blair on his stance towards deeper EU integration as planned under the IGC.</p>
<p>Blair's Labour Party, which won a resounding victory in Thursday's general election, is widely seen as more cooperative towards Europe than the defeated Conservatives.</p>
<p>The Dutch said that a preparatory meeting of EU foreign ministers, expected to include Labour's Robin Cook for the first time, would be held at the foreign ministry in The Hague on May 20.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="THE HAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
