<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557996" id="root" date="1997-05-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RUGBY UNION-NATAL IN UPSET DEFEAT BY QUEENSLAND.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-NATAL IN UPSET DEFEAT BY QUEENSLAND.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1997-05-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Natal lost their way in the chase for home semifinal advantage in the Super 12 competition after sinking to an upset 40-3 defeat against lowly Queensland on Saturday.</p>
<p>The South Africans wasted the chance to lift themselves into second place in the standings behind Auckland with a disjointed, lacklustre display at Ballymore.</p>
<p>Winger Joos Joubert was sent off for a high tackle on reserve winger Willie Carne in the final minute to complete a miserable night for the visitors, who surrendered six tries to a resurgent Queensland without reply.</p>
<p>The dismissal was a double blow for Joubert, who gave away a penalty try just before halftime for deliberate obstruction against Queensland counterpart Damian Smith.</p>
<p>Referee Wayne Erickson ruled Joubert's professional foul prevented Smith gathering a kick through by Queensland full-back and captain Tim Horan.</p>
<p>The converted try, which gave Queensland the lead, changed the course of the match as Natal disintegrated as an attacking force.</p>
<p>Flanker David Wilson, winger Ben Tune, prop Glen Panoho, second rower John Eales and centre Jason Little added further tries for Queensland.</p>
<p>Eales, who gave a commanding defensive display and dominated the line-outs, converted five of the tries for a personal tally of 15 points.</p>
<p>Natal's only reply came from the boot of full-back Gavin Lawless, whose 30th minute penalty gave his side the lead after an error-ridden opening to the match by both teams.</p>
<p>The visitors suffered a further blow when centre Pieter Muller was forced off the field with a back injury after only 14 minutes.</p>
<p>Natal remain in fourth place on the Super 12 table behind Auckland, Wellington and Australian Capital Territory. The top four teams qualify for the semifinals, with the top two enjoying home advantage.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Queensland - Tim Horan (captain); Damian Smith, Daniel Herbert, Jason Little, Ben Tune (Willie Carne, 75th min); Elton Flatley, Brett Johnstone; Mark Connors, David Wilson, Toutai Kefu, John Eales, Matt Cockbain, Glen Panoho, Christiaan Knapp, Scott Webster.</p>
<p>Natal - Gavin Lawless; Dirkie Strydom, Pieter Muller (Geoff Appleford, 14th min), Jeremy Thomson, Joos Joubert; Henry Honiball, Kevin Putt; Gary Teichmann (captain), Wayne Fyvie, Walter Minaar, Ryan Strudwick, John Slade, Adrian Garvey, John Allan, Andre-Henri Le Roux.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
