<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557939" id="root" date="1997-05-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: TABLE TENNIS-SURPRISE PACKAGE STUNS OLYMPIC CHAMPION.</title>
<headline>TABLE TENNIS-SURPRISE PACKAGE STUNS OLYMPIC CHAMPION.</headline>
<byline>Morley Myers</byline>
<dateline>MANCHESTER, England 1997-05-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The great thing about table tennis is that a game that many view as so predictable can throw up some very surprising results.</p>
<p>And so it was at these 44th world championships where the awesome Chinese are defending the seven titles they achieved with their clean sweep on home territory two years ago.</p>
<p>China comfortably retained both team titles, perhaps the surest bet because of their composite strength.</p>
<p>But the individual events can throw up the occasional freak happening, a maverick shooting star which defies the accepted pattern.</p>
<p>On Friday night, the Yugoslav player Aleksandr Karakasevic came into the orbit of Olympic champion Liu Guoliang and confounded all the pundits by eliminating the world No.3.</p>
<p>Chinese men's team coach Cai Zenhua had chartered the course for his players with extreme care. China's lineup was formidable, spearheaded by defending champion Kong Lingui and Liu, runner-up in 1995 and Kong's heir apparent should anything go amiss with the world No.1.</p>
<p>In support was that doughty 29-year-old warrior Wang Tao, silver medallist at the Atlanta Games and the only Chinese player to remain undefeated in the team event.</p>
<p>The meticulous Cai drew up a list of 41 players divided into three categories as the chief dangers to the Chinese.</p>
<p>Swedish world No.2 Jan-Ove Waldner, champion in 1989 and a three-time losing finalist, headed the eight-strong top flight. There was a second group of 13 followed by the third string of 20 players.</p>
<p>Most of them were based on world rankings with some thrown in because of their playing styles.</p>
<p>But there was no place on Cai's list for Karakesevic, 109th in the world.</p>
<p>The 21-year-old Yugoslav left-hander was never given a chance in his second round match against third-seeded Liu, but he sprang the surprise of the tournament by beating the Olympic champion 17-21 21-16 21-10 18-21 21-13.</p>
<p>Yin Xiao, Liu's person coach for the last six years, was stunned by the result.</p>
<p>&quot;Liu was mistiming his shots, hitting the ball too slowly. He was unable to get his fast attack going. He was also very nervous in the final set when he was 9-1 down and didn't play to his full potential,&quot; Yin said.</p>
<p>One person who had full faith in Karakasevic, was the player's father Milivoy, Yugoslavia's team manager and a former top-class international.</p>
<p>Karakasevic senior had a distinctive penholder style unlike his son's western shakehand grip. Practice with his father was perfect prepararation for facing the penholder Liu and many other leading Asian players.</p>
<p>Even if Karakasevic fails to get any further, he will have left his imprint on these championships and, perhaps, earned an entry in Cai's danger list.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANCHESTER, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
