<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557929" id="root" date="1997-05-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER-BAYER LEVERKUSEN MISS OUT ON VITAL POINTS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BAYER LEVERKUSEN MISS OUT ON VITAL POINTS.</headline>
<byline>Emma Thomasson</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-05-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bayer Leverkusen missed a chance to catch Bundesliga leaders Bayern Munich on Saturday when they allowed hosts Borussia Moenchengladbach to snatch a 2-2 draw with a last-minute goal.</p>
<p>Leverkusen, who are now two points behind Bayern, stormed ahead in the first half with a goal after just 45 seconds by Niko Kovac and another headed in by German international Ulf Kirsten just before half-time.</p>
<p>But Leverkusen could not hold on to their lead, letting in Jorgen Pettersson in the 65th minute and fellow Swede Martin Dahlin just before full-time.</p>
<p>Bayern have a chance to build a five-point cushion between themselves and Leverkusen when they face local rivals 1860 Munich at the Olympic Stadium on Sunday.</p>
<p>1860 will struggle to do Leverkusen any favours in their title chase. They have not defeated Bayern since 1977.</p>
<p>&quot;The 2-2 draw could be decisive for the championship,&quot; Leverkusen coach Christoph Daum said. &quot;After the first goal we controlled the game and had enough chances for a 3-0 win but Moenchengladbach got going after the break.&quot;</p>
<p>Bayer have four more league matches this season.</p>
<p>At least Leverkusen striker Kirsten could console himself with his 18th goal of the season, making him joint top scorer with VfB Stuttgart striker Fredi Bobic.</p>
<p>Third-placed Stuttgart, meanwhile, narrowed the gap between themselves and Leverkusen to two points and booked themselves a place in the UEFA Cup with a 3-0 rout of relegation-bound St Pauli, who were reduced to nine men by the 68th minute.</p>
<p>Stuttgart, without Bobic who sustained a head injury in Germany's World Cup qualifier against Ukraine on Wednesday, were held goalless in the first half.</p>
<p>Andreas Buck ended Stuttgart's frustration in the 54th minute. Bulgarian Krasimir Balakov added the second, followed by Bayern-bound Brazilian Giovane Elber, who scored his 17th this season.</p>
<p>&quot;That was no easy game against a very defensive opponent. Before the change we missed out on going ahead. But by the end we had an easy game,&quot; said coach Joachim Loew.</p>
<p>Champions Borussia Dortmund stayed in fourth place with a 1-0 victory over Schalke, who meet Inter Milan in next week's UEFA Cup final first leg.</p>
<p>Bottom of the table Freiburg regained some dignity with a 2-0 victory over Duisburg and Hamburg pulled away from the relegation zone with a 3-2 win over mid-table Werder Bremen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
