<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="557995" id="root" date="1997-05-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RUGBY UNION-WAIKATO TORPEDO GAUTENG'S SEMIFINAL HOPES.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-WAIKATO TORPEDO GAUTENG'S SEMIFINAL HOPES.</headline>
<dateline>HAMILTON, New Zealand 1997-05-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Waikato Chiefs dealt the Gauteng Lions a disastrous blow in the Super 12 competition on Saturday with an emphatic 47-9 win at Hamilton.</p>
<p>Waikato's victory was well-deserved while the Lions' chances of making the semifinals were all but dashed.</p>
<p>Gauteng, formerly Transvaal, now have to beat Queensland and then Natal in their last two games to stand any chance of remaining in semifinal contention.</p>
<p>Waikato took the lead in the 11th minute after a  scrum close to the Gauteng Lions' line when No 8 Deon Muir dived over for a converted try.</p>
<p>Penalties were traded before Waikato eased further in front in the 28th minute with a penalty try after Gavin Johnson was penalised for failing to release the ball. Matthew Cooper converted to make it 20-6.</p>
<p>The Chiefs struck decisively two minutes from the break.</p>
<p>Blindside flanker Aaron Hopa and Muir, showing an uncanny understanding of each other's play, combined at mid-field in the Lions' half to spark a move which sent substitute left-wing Caleb Ralph in for Waikato's third converted try.</p>
<p>Waikato, playing exciting, crisp rugby, deservedly led 30-9 at halftime and Ralph and right-wing Scott McLeod added two more tries in the second half to stamp their authority on the match and also notch up a bonus point.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Waikato Chiefs - Matthew Cooper; Bruce Reihana, Frank Bunce, Eric Rush, Scott McLeod; Ian Foster, Mark Robinson; Deon Muir, Brett Sinkinson, Glenn Taylor, Ian Jones, Aaron Hopa, Richard Loe, Greg Smith, Michael Collins.</p>
<p>Gauteng Lions - Dawie du Toit; Gavin Johnson, Japie Mulder, Jannie van der Walt, Edrick Luber; Louis van Rensburg, J P du Plooy; Andre Vos, Ian McDonald, Hannes Strydom, Armand du Preez, Warren Brosnahan, Mornie van der Merwe, Robert Grau, Bailie Swart.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMILTON, New Zealand"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
