<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558063" id="root" date="1997-05-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: ONE KILLED, SIX HURT IN FIGHTING AT NAIROBI RALLY.</title>
<headline>ONE KILLED, SIX HURT IN FIGHTING AT NAIROBI RALLY.</headline>
<byline>Louise Tunbridge</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-05-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>One man was killed and at least six were injured in the Kenyan capital Nairobi on Saturday during running battles between riot police and thousands of opposition supporters intent on attending a rally on civil liberties.</p>
<p>In nearby streets a local office of the ruling party Kenya African National Union (KANU) was burned down, at least a dozen vehicles had their windows smashed, a supermarket was seriously damaged and a petrol station was looted.</p>
<p>Police used teargas, batons, bayonets and live ammunition to disperse thousands of people who tried to gather in a field in a slum area in the east of the capital.</p>
<p>The protesters pelted the police with stones and opposition members of parliament came to blows with policemen.</p>
<p>The man who died was driving along one street when a group of KANU youth wingers began to pelt the car with stones. The driver died after veering out of control, witnesses said.</p>
<p>One man had a bullet wound in the head and two had wounds from police bayonets. Three policemen had injuries from rocks and one, an officer, was seriously hurt, the witnesses said.</p>
<p>A coalition of opposition leaders and civil liberty advocates had called the rally to assert a constitutional right of free association.</p>
<p>They declined to apply for the licence stipulated by the Public Order Act because they dispute the act's validity.</p>
<p>Nairobi Provincial Commissioner Zachary Ogongo said on Friday he would not have given a permit anyway and the police would do their best to make sure the rally did not take place.</p>
<p>Before the fighting began, the opposition supporters had started a sit-in on the field and were chanting slogans hostile to President Daniel arap Moi. &quot;Moi must go&quot; and &quot;Moi must change the constitution&quot;, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;All these people here are just interested in fighting for the total liberation of this country. Our mere presence here dramatises some of our problems,&quot; leader of the opposition Kijana Wamalwa told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The curious explanation being given for preventing our meeting is the Public Order Act but that act is supposed to be subordinate to the constitution that protects freedom of association for all Kenyans,&quot; added Gibson Kamau Kuria, a veteran civil rights lawyer and activist.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
