<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558085" id="root" date="1997-05-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ERITREA: Eritrea expels UN refugee agency.</title>
<headline>Eritrea expels UN refugee agency.</headline>
<byline>Victoria Engstrand</byline>
<dateline>ASMARA 1997-05-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Red Sea state of Eritrea has given the United Nations refugee agency UNHCR four days to leave the country, apparently because of a row over the repatriation of Eritrean refugees in exile.</p>
<p>Eritrean state television said on Friday night that UNHCR had 48 hours to leave the country. The agency had circulated documents without authority, it added without elaboration.</p>
<p>Aid agency sources said later that Eritrea had extended the period to 96 hours, giving UNHCR a respite until Tuesday May 6.</p>
<p>The UNHCR chief of mission in Eritrea, Arnulv Torbjornsen, declined to comment on Friday evening. The agency said it would comment after talks over the weekend.</p>
<p>The UNHCR director of operations for central, east and west Africa, Albert-Alain Peters, visiting Eritrea at the end of April, said the Eritreans were dragging their feet on repatriation and so he had raised the possibility of UNHCR abandoning responsibility for the refugees.</p>
<p>UNHCR figures say 145,000 Eritreans remain in refugee camps in Sudan, five years after the country became independent. In addition, there is an Eritrean urban population in Sudan.</p>
<p>The U.N. agency wants to bring them all home but bad relations between Sudan and Eritrea have helped to hold up the repatriation programme.</p>
<p>&quot;Two years ago, when the repatriation operation was halted, we had 25,000 people who had come back in the pilot programme. The government says 127,000 people have come back spontaneously since then,&quot; Peters said.</p>
<p>In December 1996 Eritrea broke a pledge to hold a technical meeting with the Sudanese government on the repatriation.</p>
<p>Peters said: &quot;We are totally behind them (the Eritrean government), but we would be more behind them if they would take part in a repatriation programme. They achieved independence five years ago. But still most refugees are outside the borders. They have no more reason to be in exile.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We said (to the Eritreans) that we are a bit worried about the pace. It is time for the refugees to come back, so that the UNHCR can pull out,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Under the &quot;secession clause&quot; evoked by Peters in his talks, all Eritreans presently holding refugee status anywhere in the world will lose that status. They will no longer be able to approach any government as refugees.</p>
<p>&quot;The secession clause...can be used when there is no further reason for refugees to fear persecution etcetera, when the refugees cease to require need as refugees,&quot; Peters said.</p>
<p>&quot;They (the Eritrean government) said they don't want them to come back without the government being fully prepared. They said they want information on all the 145,000 refugees. This means to me that maybe the goodwill is not there,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ERTRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ASMARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ERITREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
