<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558107" id="root" date="1997-05-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURMA: Burma vows no change despite U.S. sanctions.</title>
<headline>Burma vows no change despite U.S. sanctions.</headline>
<dateline>RANGOON 1997-05-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burma's military vowed on Saturday that it would not change its current political and economic course despite recent U.S. economic sanctions which bar new American investment in the country.</p>
<p>Secretary One of the ruling State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC) Lieutenant General Khin Nyunt was quoted in the official media as saying Burma was confident it could overcome the latest hurdle imposed on it by Washington.</p>
<p>He also blamed unidentified groups opposed to the SLORC of being behind the latest diplomatic setback for Rangoon.</p>
<p>The United States imposed economic sanctions on Burma in April, banning new investment by American firms, as a condemnation of the military regime's alleged human rights abuses and its suppression of the pro-democracy movement led by opposition leader Aung San Suu Kyi.</p>
<p>&quot;Destructionist groups within the country are employing various way to destablise the nation, to jeopardise the nation's political and economic development and to cause difficulties in international relations,&quot; Khin Nyunt was quoted as saying at a meeting with local authorities in Hakha township, 375 km (600 miles) northwest of Rangoon on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;As the government can overcome all these obstacles, it has no big problem,&quot; he said. &quot;The (U.S.) economic sanctions will have no result for the U.S. as they expect nor will they affect Burma.&quot;</p>
<p>Burma would never change its current political and economic trend and would march onward to reach its objectives despite any obstacles and hindrances that were placed in its way, he added.</p>
<p>SLORC vice chairman General Maung Aye said at another function at Bahtoo township, about 312 km (500 miles) northeast of Rangoon, that there was no need for Burma to be shaken by the latest sanctions.</p>
<p>&quot;A western power has come to impose economic sanctions on Burma. But the SLORC government need not tremble at their sanctions and need pay no attention,&quot; he said. &quot;The nation has stood on its own self reliance for years since before the military government came into power.&quot;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a general meeting of the pro-government Union Solidary and Development Association (USDA) held on Saturday condemned the U.S. economic sanctions as shameless interference in Burmese affairs.</p>
<p>&quot;The action of the U.S. government to enforce such economic sanctions on Burma is merely an undignified interference, said Daw Kyi Kyi Htwe, senior committee member of the USDA.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RANGOON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
