<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558388" id="root" date="1997-05-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Rebels advance on Kinshasa, take Mobutu birthplace.</title>
<headline>Rebels advance on Kinshasa, take Mobutu birthplace.</headline>
<byline>William Wallis</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-05-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's rebels are drawing closer to Kinshasa on several fronts, capturing President Mobutu Sese Seko's birthplace and moving into a town 200 km (125 miles) from the capital, witnesses and security sources said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Western security sources said that on one front the rebels were moving towards Mobutu's huge jungle palace at Gbadolite, his ancestral village in the north near the border with the Central African Republic.</p>
<p>&quot;Lisala has fallen. The rebels are now heading towards Gemena and Gbadolite on foot, by boat and by road,&quot; one source told Reuters in the capital. Mobutu was born in Lisala on October 14 1930.</p>
<p>The rebels themselves say they are massing fighters and weapons much further south in Kikwit for a final push against Zaire's teeming capital of five million people.</p>
<p>The sources had no details of whether there had been heavy fighting for Lisala, in the Equateur region on the broad Zaire River, 300 km (190 miles) south of Gbadolite.</p>
<p>Residents of Kenge on the road to Kinshasa said that rebels had entered the town late Friday or early Saturday, without a fight. One said residents turned out to greet them.</p>
<p>Government soldiers left Kenge earlier in the week.</p>
<p>Mobutu's ramshackle army has been unable to halt the rebels who now hold three quarters of the vast state and all the main cities outside Kinshasa since launching their war in October.</p>
<p>Even the elite Presidential Guard, drawn from Mobutu's Ngbandi tribe and related ethnic groups from Equateur have withdrawn in the face of better armed and disciplined rebels.</p>
<p>Rebel leader Laurent Kabila has said Mobutu will be well treated if he agrees to give up power.</p>
<p>Political pundits in Kinshasa say that military pressure building around Kinshasa leaves Mobutu with little choice but to surrender power if talks go ahead as planned on board a South African ship in the Atlantic.</p>
<p>South Africa said on Saturday that all obstacles to the talks had been removed and the Mobutu-Kabila face-to-face meeting was expected later in the day.</p>
<p>Residents of Kikwit, 400 km (250 miles) east of Kinshasa, said rebels had flown in large numbers of reinforcements in recent days and a large column of rebel fighters was moving towards the capital.</p>
<p>Outside Kinshasa, Gbadolite is the only army outpost well-equipped with military hardware.</p>
<p>The road from Lisala to Gbadolite is good by Zaire's dilapidated standards after 32 years of Mobutu's rule.</p>
<p>Perceiving Kinshasa as a hotbed of opposition, Mobutu has spent much of his time in recent years at Gbadolite.</p>
<p>Reputed as fierce warriors by Belgian colonialists the tribes of Equateur were recruited into the army which Mobutu used as his springboard to power in a 1965 military coup.</p>
<p>Carved out of tropical forest where once there stood only a village, Mobutu has erected a palace inspired by France's Versailles, served by an international airport that is long enough for the supersonic Concorde jet to land.</p>
<p>Enfeebled by prostate cancer Mobutu returned to Zaire from a European clinic in March to face the deepening crisis.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
