<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558434" id="root" date="1997-05-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Key events in Zaire's civil war.</title>
<headline>Key events in Zaire's civil war.</headline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-05-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's President Mobutu Sese Seko and rebel leader Laurent Kabila failed to agree on terms for Mobutu stepping down from 32 years in power when they met aboard a South African naval vessel on Sunday.</p>
<p>It was their first face-to-face encounter since the start of a revolt last October that has swept Africa's third-largest country and taken Kabila's forces within striking distance of the capital Kinshasa.</p>
<p>Here is a chronology of major events in the conflict:</p>
<p>1996</p>
<p>Oct 7: Deputy governor of South Kivu province tells 300,000-strong Banyamulenge community -- ethnic Tutsis settled there for generations -- to leave Zaire. It sparks revolt.</p>
<p>Oct 24: Rebels seize their first major town, Uvira, on northern shore of Lake Tanganyika.</p>
<p>Nov 1: Rebels capture Goma, main town in east.</p>
<p>Nov 15: Exodus of Rwandan Hutu refugees; up to 700,000 return to Rwanda, remainder flee west with armed Hutu hardliners blamed for 1994 genocide of minority Tutsis there.</p>
<p>Nov 24: Zaire marks 31 years of Mobutu rule; Mobutu is in Europe where he had been since cancer surgery in August.</p>
<p>Nov 28: U.N.-backed military intervention plan fizzles out after exodus home of refugees.</p>
<p>Dec 17: Mobutu flies home, appoints new army chief and reshuffles government. He returns to France three weeks later.</p>
<p>1997</p>
<p>Jan 20: Government launches counter-offensive but rebels advance on several fronts.</p>
<p>Feb 5: Kabila gives Mobutu until Feb 21 to relinquish power or face all-out rebel offensive.</p>
<p>Feb 7: Mobutu returns to Zaire from Europe for two weeks.</p>
<p>Feb 18: U.N. Security Council adopts five-point peace plan.</p>
<p>Feb 19: South Africa tries to broker Zaire peace talks.</p>
<p>March 5: Zaire agrees U.N. plan.</p>
<p>March 8: Rebels say U.N. plan basis for talks.</p>
<p>March 15: Rebels capture Zaire's third city Kisangani.</p>
<p>March 22: Mobutu returns from cancer treatment in Europe.</p>
<p>April 2: Mobutu names rival Etienne Tshisekedi prime minister in place of Kengo wa Dondo; Tshisekedi names government from own loyalists, offers rebels posts. Offer rejected.</p>
<p>April 5: Rebels capture diamond mining centre of Mbuji-Mayi, capital of Kasai province.</p>
<p>April 8: Mobutu declares nationwide state of emergency.</p>
<p>April 9: Rebels capture Zaire's second city of Lubumbashi, capital of southern copper and cobalt province of Shaba.</p>
<p>April 14-15: Tshisekedi supporters close down capital Kinshasa for two days as part of campaign to oust Mobutu.</p>
<p>April 17: U.N. envoy Mohamed Sahnoun announces agreement in principle for meeting between Mobutu and Kabila.</p>
<p>April 30: U.S. envoy Bill Richardson announces Mobutu and Kabila will meet on South African ship. Airlift home of Rwandan Hutu refugees from eastern Zaire begins after charges that the rebels were delaying the process.</p>
<p>May 2: Citing security concerns, Kabila fails to show for talks with Mobutu on South African navy ship, hosted by President Nelson Mandela.</p>
<p>May 3: Mandela stays on board navy ship as contacts intensify to bring Kabila to the negotiating table. Rebel leader arrives at ship late at night. Rebels seize Mobutu's hometown and are said to be only 150 km (95 miles) from Kinshasa.</p>
<p>May 4: Mobutu meets Kabila on South African ship after agreeing in principle to stand down. But they fail to agree on the terms for his departure. Kabila rules out a ceasefire, saying his forces will fight on while Mobutu considers his demand to hand over power directly to the rebels. Mandela says he will convene a fresh round of talks in 8-10 days.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
