<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558558" id="root" date="1997-05-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian army quells Java poll protest.</title>
<headline>Indonesian army quells Java poll protest.</headline>
<byline>Lewa Pardomuan</byline>
<dateline>YOGYAKARTA, Indonesia 1997-05-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian soldiers broke up a small demonstration by Moslem youths in the central Java city of Yogyakarta early on Sunday as tensions between contestants in Indonesia's election continued to rise.</p>
<p>Attorney-General Singgih, the government's poll watchdog, said all of the three sanctioned parties had breached the rules since campaigning began a week ago but most had been violations of traffic laws or violence against rival contestants.</p>
<p>In Yogyakarta, armed soldiers charged a protest held by about 100 Moslem youths early on Sunday after they took to the street to protest against a recent attack on the local offices of the Moslem-oriented United Development Party (PPP).</p>
<p>The youths carried three mock coffins, a mock corpse, flaming torches and incense to symbolise the death of democracy. They chanted &quot;Allahu Akbar&quot; (God is Greater) as they marched or rode motorcycles through the streets.</p>
<p>The university town has a long tradition of student protest.</p>
<p>Soldiers dispersed the procession by pointing their rifles at the protesters when they stopped near the Sultan's palace in the city centre.</p>
<p>Witnesses said no shots were fired but at least two youths youths were injured after being beaten with rattan sticks. Soldiers then burned one of the coffins, they said.</p>
<p>In nearby areas, PPP supporters burned car tyres in the streets. These were later cleared by police without incident.</p>
<p>Residents say sentiment against Indonesia's ruling Golkar party continued in Yogyakarta on Sunday after an attack this week on a rival's office.</p>
<p>The PPP, one of only three parties allowed to contest the May 29 poll, halted campaigning in this ancient court city last week after a mob, whom party officials said were Golkar supporters, ransacked the party headquarters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The tourism centre of Yogyakarta is one of several cities in Central Java province which have seen political violence between the PPP and Golkar supporters ahead of the campaign.</p>
<p>In the capital Jakarta the PPP also stopped campaigning after police restricted its rallies when tens of thousands of supporters took to the streets in illegal parades.</p>
<p>Despite the ban on such activities, thousands defied police again on Friday and took to the streets, causing further traffic havoc in the capital.</p>
<p>The minority Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI) also called off campaigning in the second city of Surabaya on Monday after internal rivals to the current government-backed leader stoned a stage during a rally forcing its cancellation.</p>
<p>&quot;None of these violations can be categorised as subversion,&quot; Singgih was quoted as saying in Sunday's Jakarta Post newspaper.</p>
<p>Last week nine activists from the unrecognised People's Democratic Party (PRD) were sentenced to up to 13 years jail for subversion. The group advocates a boycott of the current poll.</p>
<p>Golkar's campaigning in Yogyakarta went ahead amid tight security with troops stationed in several parts of the low-rise city, especially in the districts considered as PPP strongholds.</p>
<p>Golkar banners and those from the Christian-Nationalist PDI could be seen throughout the city, capital of a special administrative region of more than three million people.</p>
<p>But party officials removed all PPP banners, flags and posters after the attack. In their place, anti-Golkar graffiti was scrawled on walls in black spray paint.</p>
<p>PPP officials will meet in Jakarta and Yogyakarta on Monday to decide whether it will continue with the campaign which will last through May 23.</p>
<p>Golkar, in power for the past 30 years under President Suharto, is seeking to push its share of the vote above 70 percent from the 68 percent it won in the last polls in 1992.</p>
<p>The PPP won 17 percent and the PDI 15.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="YOGYAKARTA, Indonesia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
