<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558638" id="root" date="1997-05-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egyptian share prices retreat in weak trade.</title>
<headline>Egyptian share prices retreat in weak trade.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-05-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egyptian shares retreated in weak trade on Sunday as the market emerged from a quiet holiday week, with relatively high turnover stocks barely showing a flicker of price movement.</p>
<p>The Capital Market Authority all-share index fell 1.27 points to a four-week low of 383.14 points. Turnover was a quiet 33.59 million pounds ($9.89 million).</p>
<p>It was highest in Eipico/Egyptian International Pharmaceutical Industries, with 3.88 million pounds changing hands.</p>
<p>&quot;It's one of the good stocks, a pioneer among the pharmaceutical stocks,&quot; said Mohammad Magdi, broker at EFG Hermes. Its share closed unchanged at 214 pounds.</p>
<p>He said the market was slow on Sunday and he did not see any immediate prospects for prices to recover, but one factor could be foreign brokers waiting to see whether the Cairo stock market would be linked to one of the known indexes.</p>
<p>&quot;Then that might increase interest in Egypt's market again and lead to a rise in prices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Helwan Portland Cement turnover was 2.8 million pounds but its price slipped 1.4 to close at 78.6 pounds. Amriyah Cement clung to third place with 2.46 million pounds turnover, ending down one pound at 89.</p>
<p>Brokers say Amriyah's expansion plans may be contributing to its attractiveness to investors.</p>
<p>Alexandria National Iron and Steel shares were also lower - by a fractional 0.1 to 275 - in trade worth 2.33 million pounds.</p>
<p>Brokers see promise in chemicals and pharmaceuticals shares.</p>
<p>Paints and Chemical Industries/PACHIN turnover just inched over 2 million pounds trade with its share price up 1.45 pounds to a 143 close.</p>
<p>The index for openly traded firms fell to 557.26 points from 561.49 points on Wednesday while the index for rarely traded &quot;closed&quot; firms fell to 274.58 from 274.84 points. Tuesday was the only other market day last week, which was dominated by holidays including Labour Day.</p>
<p>Out of the 81 shares traded, 22 advanced, 39 declined and the remaining 20 closed unchanged.</p>
<p>$1 = 3.395 pounds</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
