<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558700" id="root" date="1997-05-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Texas rebel leader's wife to surrender - police.</title>
<headline>Texas rebel leader's wife to surrender - police.</headline>
<dateline>FORT DAVIS, Texas 1997-05-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The wife of the leader of a group of armed Republic of Texas separatists planned to leave the compound in the Texas mountains on Saturday, a police spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Evelyn McLaren has been holed up with her husband, Richard McLaren, and other members of the group for six days, refusing pleas from police to surrender to face felony charges.</p>
<p>The Republic members claim Texas is an independent nation and that they form its provisional government.</p>
<p>&quot;She's indicated she would like to come out of the enclave,&quot; police spokeswoman, Laureen Churnow, said of Evelyn McLaren.</p>
<p>Mrs. McLaren decided to leave after repeated pleas from her daughter over the past three days to come out. The tearful pleas were broadcast by television and radio.</p>
<p>Her departure would leave six separatists holed up at the group's dilapidated compound in the Davis Mountains.</p>
<p>The group remains surrounded by police who overnight moved to within 440 yards of the compound.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FORT DAVIS, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
