<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558745" id="root" date="1997-05-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain's king gives blessing to daughter's marriage.</title>
<headline>Spain's king gives blessing to daughter's marriage.</headline>
<byline>Merissa Marr</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-05-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's King Juan Carlos and Queen Sofia gave their blessing on Saturday to the marriage of their younger daughter to a professional handball player, the palace said.</p>
<p>Inaki Urdangarin, dressed in a smart dark suit and tie, had gone to Zarzuela palace, the royal residence, to ask formally for Princess Cristina's hand.</p>
<p>The couple smiled and giggled as they wandered through the palace gardens holding hands for the first time in public under the spotlight of cameras and reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's great because if she's happy, I'm happy,&quot; King Juan Carlos said as the pair posed on the palace steps with their relatives.</p>
<p>Cristina, 31, wearing a cream-coloured trouser suit, happily held up her finger to show off a diamond ring that her fiance gave her as an engagement present.</p>
<p>Word of the engagement emerged on Wednesday when the palace said Cristina would marry Urdangarin, 29, whom she met at the Olympic Games in Atlanta last year.</p>
<p>The couple said they planned to marry later this year  in Barcelona, where they both live and work.</p>
<p>Urdangarin, born in the Basque town of Zumarraga, is the son of a banking family and plays handball for Barcelona and Spain.</p>
<p>At the Atlanta Games, his team won a bronze medal which he later physically split in half with an injured team mate who could not attend the Olympics, Spanish media reported.</p>
<p>Uradangarin, standing 6 feet 5 inches (1.96 metres), is rated as one of Spain's top five hand ball players of all time and has expressed a desire to go on playing professionally after the marriage.</p>
<p>Media reports have described him as the perfect gentleman who, among other things, likes to cook and listen to the British rock group Queen.</p>
<p>Cristina, third in line to the throne, also intends to continue working at the savings bank where she assists with cultural projects, the palace said.</p>
<p>The children of Spain's king and queen have captured the affection of the public with their down-to-earth style and the family has become a symbol of their country's young democracy.</p>
<p>After King Juan Carlos came to the throne after the death of dictator General Francisco Franco in 1975, he guided the country to democratic rule and he further cemented a place in the hearts of the public when he averted a military coup in 1981.</p>
<p>He has tried hard to allow his children to lead as normal a life as possible, encouraging to marry for love and not status, according to media reports.</p>
<p>It will be the second royal wedding in two years. Princess Elena, the elder daughter, married Spanish businessman Jaime de Marichalar in a lavish ceremony in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Already the second one has gone,&quot; the king told reporters with a broad smile on his face.</p>
<p>The youngest member of the family, Crown Prince Felipe, 29, is still single. Asked by reporters when he would marry, he lifted a hand to his ear and joked: &quot;I'm a little deaf at the moment.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
