<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55878" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Northeast should expect high winter heating bills.</title>
<headline>Northeast should expect high winter heating bills.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Paul</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Short supplies of heating oil are likely to drive up home heating bills in the Northeast this winter, a top U.S. energy official warned on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The limited amount of stocks would suggest that all things being equal there will be a lot of pressure on prices to go up,&quot; said Jay Hakes, head of the Energy Information Administration.</p>
<p>Low rates of production and a thin stock build in July, when inventories should have been filled, &quot;is giving rise to growing concerns over distillate stock levels for the upcoming winter,&quot; according to materials presented by Hakes at the annual meeting of the National Association of State Energy Officials in Biloxi, Miss.</p>
<p>Distillates, which include heating oil, diesel and jet fuel, are refined from crude oil. With the economy growing faster than expected, trucking demand for diesel had boosted the need for distillates, Hakes said.</p>
<p>To meet all the demand, the Northeast would be heavily reliant on imports. However, U.S. importers would have to compete heavily with European buyers for supplies, because stocks across the Atlantic were low, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Even with normal weather, there would be much a larger import level than we've seen in the last five years,&quot; Hakes said after his presentation.</p>
<p>To raise stocks significantly by the end of November, when inventories normally peak, distillate production would also have to increase.</p>
<p>&quot;Relying on strong production and imports makes us much more vulnerable to price runups if any supply difficulties occur,&quot; EIA warned.</p>
<p>With inventories drained and oil prices running about $6 a barrel higher than a year ago, consumers could not avoid bigger bills unless oil prices dropped.</p>
<p>On Monday crude oil futures, which have posted big gains recently amid tensions with Iraq, fell $1.32 a barrel to $23.19 on the New York Mercantile Exchange for the October contract. Heating oil dropped 2.65 cents a gallon to 65.29 cents.</p>
<p>At the end of August, U.S. distillate stocks were 21 million barrels or 16 percent lower than the five-year average for the month, and 20 million barrels of that deficit was on the East Coast, which makes up most of the U.S. winter heating fuel market.</p>
<p>&quot;It is unlikely that the shortfall will be made up at this late date,&quot; said the EIA, the statistical arm of the Energy Department.</p>
<p>U.S. propane and natural gas stocks were also lower than normal for this time of year, although natural gas storage was being built rapidly, according to EIA.</p>
<p>Propane inventories at the end of August were at a 25-year low and about 11 percent lower than last year.</p>
<p>While not commenting on prices, oil refiners saw little reason to be alarmed about stock levels.</p>
<p>&quot;While it is impossible to account for every contingency, the industry historically has met demand and fully expects to do so this winter,&quot; said the American Petroleum Institute, which represents oil companies.</p>
<p>An API spokesman said heating oil inventories were adequate to meet drawdowns of 300,000 barrels per day at the coldest point this winter -- double the average volume API and EIA expected would be needed from inventories in October through March.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, Northeast lawmakers were circulating a letter this week to ask the Energy Department to look at the supply situation.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a concern that the stage might be set for steep increase in home heating oil and diesel prices this winter,&quot; said a Congressional aide.</p>
<p>Administration officials last week said while they were monitoring the situation, there was no need to panic.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a yellow flag up,&quot; said Deputy Energy Secretary Charles Curtis. &quot;We're trusting that the market will make the requisite adjustment here.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
