<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558754" id="root" date="1997-05-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: European Song Contest goes on despite bomb call.</title>
<headline>European Song Contest goes on despite bomb call.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-05-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Eurovision Song Contest in Dublin was won by Britain on Saturday and went ahead despite a bomb warning from a telephone caller claiming to speaking for hardline pro-British &quot;Loyalists&quot;.</p>
<p>Ireland's broadcasting network, RTE, which produced the live television broadcast seen by an estimated 300 million viewers, reported that nothing was found in a search of the venue, the Point Depot complex, after the warning was relayed to a Belfast television station.</p>
<p>RTE said in a news report that a caller had claimed that two devices had been planted and gave a 30-minute warning just before the start of the contest.</p>
<p>The caller claimed to represent the Loyalist Volunteer Force, a recently formed group of extremists pledged to keep Northern Ireland under British rule.</p>
<p>&quot;An immediate but discreet search was made by Special Branch officers when the warning was received but nothing was found in the building,&quot; an RTE reporter said.</p>
<p>The competition, won for Britain by the band Katrina and the Waves, was held amid unprecedented securitry following police fears that Protestant guerrillas might stage an attack. The British entry coasted to victory scooping 227 points, with Ireland second on 157 and Turkey third with 121.</p>
<p>Some 400 police officers, some of them armed, were on duty around the venue. &quot;There is a lot of security at the building, just to make sure,&quot; a spokesman for the competition told Reuters before it got underway.</p>
<p>Police and security experts guarded the Point Theatre in the run-up to the event and the venue was closed for two hours in the afternoon as officers with sniffer dogs combed the complex.</p>
<p>Irish President Mary Robinson and Prime Minister John Bruton were among 3,000 spectators at the theatre in Dublin.</p>
<p>Entrants from 25 countries took part competing for the honour of winning the prize for the best song.</p>
<p>Irish newspapers had reported fears that Northern Ireland-based Protestant &quot;Loyalist&quot; guerrillas might try to disrupt the Eurovision competition in retaliation for recent IRA action in Britain.</p>
<p>The Irish Republican Army, fighting to end British rule of Northern Ireland, forced the postponement of the famous Grand National horse steeplechase in April with a hoax bomb warning.</p>
<p>It has also disrupted Britain's travel network several times in recent weeks with a series of bomb attacks and hoax calls.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
