<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558703" id="root" date="1997-05-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Australian plans swim from Cuba to Key West.</title>
<headline>Australian plans swim from Cuba to Key West.</headline>
<byline>Ben Iannotta</byline>
<dateline>KEY WEST, Fla. 1997-05-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian marathon swimmer Susie Maroney will try next week to succeed where others have failed -- swimming from Cuba to the United States across the treacherous Florida Straits.</p>
<p>Maroney, 22, plans to dive off Havana's famous Malecon seawall on Thursday on her second attempt to cross the straits. If all goes well she will walk ashore 40 hours later near Key West.</p>
<p>The straits are one of marathon swimming's last great challenges. The distance from Havana to Key West is 90 miles (144.8 km) but Maroney will probably end up swimming over 100 miles (160.9 km) because of the powerful currents.</p>
<p>&quot;This is probably considered one of the most difficult swims in the world because of the distance, the heat and the sun,&quot; said Bob Duenkel, curator of the International Swimming Hall of Fame in Fort Lauderdale.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that it's never really been done before makes it all the more noteworthy,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Unlike the famed English Channel swim, there is no official association or group that monitors the Florida Straits swim, Duenkel said. Maroney will have two camera crews on accompanying boats, one from the United States and one from Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;They would be scrutinising her the whole way. There's really nothing that she can do wrong except get out and get back in,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Last June Maroney vomited and hallucinated her way across the straits inside an anti-shark cage. Her team debated the best route and most became seasick themselves. She swam for 38 hours and 30 minutes but was plucked from the water 12 miles short of the Keys.</p>
<p>&quot;At first everyone was happy I got to U.S. waters. But a couple of marathon swimmers came out and said 'but she didn't make it to the shore',&quot; Maroney said in recent telephone interview from her home in Sydney.</p>
<p>This time she has put together a new team and is determined to reach the beach. The strong Gulf Stream currents will initially work to her advantage, pushing her in the general direction of the Keys as they whip eastward round the southern tip of Florida. Then she will have to cut across the current or be swept parallel with the island chain.</p>
<p>&quot;The last 20 miles (32.19 km) is an unbelievable swim. You are almost like a salmon trying to get into the Key West area,&quot; said swim coordinator Joe Pignatiello of Coral Springs, Fla., who will ride in the lead boat.</p>
<p>Maroney's new team includes Australian navigation expert Ean McDonald. The longtime seaman and Second World War veteran will consult the latest satellite photos of the currents before finalising the route. During the trip he will drop lighted buoys to test the currents.</p>
<p>Success will require a blend of determination and old fashioned luck. Last year Maroney endured night thunderstorms that spawned 12-15 foot (4-5 metre) seas, Pignatiello said.</p>
<p>&quot;If Susie doesn't have to go through a thunderstorm and gets to territorial waters, I think she's a shoo-in to finish.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KEY WEST, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
