<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558832" id="root" date="1997-05-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan says telecom sale still on the agenda.</title>
<headline>Pakistan says telecom sale still on the agenda.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-05-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani authorities on Sunday denied they had indefinitely put off the planned privatisation of the state-run Pakistan Telecommunication Company Ltd (PTCL) and said the sale was still on their &quot;active agenda&quot;.</p>
<p>The statement by the government's Privatisation Commission came two days after the official APP news agency quoted Communications Minister Azam Khan Hoti as saying that the privatisation of the telecommunications sector had been put off until it can be sold for a better price.</p>
<p>A commission spokesman, quoted by the APP, said on Sunday the impression that the PTCL privatisation had been postponed was &quot;totally incorrect and misleading&quot;.</p>
<p>He said the PTCL privatisation was still on &quot;the active agenda of the government and no decision has been taken for its indefinite postponement as yet&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Soon after the financial accounts of PTCL are finalised and published, the company will be processed for privatisation and shortly a definite programme for the privatisation of PTCL will be announced,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Hoti was quoted as saying on Friday in a speech to the workers of a state-run telephone factory in the North West Frontier province that the privatisation process had been postponed as &quot;there were lots of liabilities on the PTCL, TIP (Telephone Industries of Pakistan) and other government-owned telecommunication organisations&quot;.</p>
<p>Pakistan's plan to sell a 26 percent stake in PTCL and transfer management control to a strategic investor have suffered repeated delays since the original target date of December 1995.</p>
<p>Last year, the government of the then prime minister Benazir Bhutto said it was delaying the PTCL privatisation for some time because it feared it would not get a good price while sales of telecom firms were taking place in many other countries.</p>
<p>However, in December, the caretaker government then in office said it had put the PTCL on its privatisation agenda and expected the sale to take place in a few months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
