<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558994" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-MARTINEZ LEADS 19-HIT YANKEE ASSAULT WITH TWO HOMERS.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-MARTINEZ LEADS 19-HIT YANKEE ASSAULT WITH TWO HOMERS.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY 1997-05-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Red hot Tino Martinez belted two of the Yankees' five home runs on Sunday to lead a 19-hit attack that propelled New York to a 13-5 walloping of the Kansas City Royals.</p>
<p>Martinez, who leads the majors with 40 RBI, went 4-for-5. He smacked a solo homer in the third inning off Glendon Rusch (2-2) and added a two-run shot off Jeff Montgomery in the eighth.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm in one of those good grooves,&quot; Martinez said. &quot;I'm really seeing the ball good. I'm staying back and swinging at good pitches.&quot;</p>
<p>Bernie Williams, Cecil Fielder and Jorge Posada also homered for the Yankees.</p>
<p>Brian Boehringer (1-1) replaced a wild Kenny Rogers after 2 2/3 innings and threw three scoreless innings, striking out seven while allowing three hits for the win. Rusch gave up seven runs and 10 hits with a pair of walks in 3 2/3 innings.</p>
<p>In the third inning with Derek Jeter aboard, Williams and Martinez hit back-to-back homers to give the Yanks a 4-0 lead. Williams has four homers and Martinez has 12.</p>
<p>Fielder added a two-run shot in a four-run fourth and Posada's first homer was a solo shot in a four-run seventh.</p>
<p>In Baltimore, Roberto Alomar hit a grand slam and drove in five runs and Rocky Coppinger and Mike Johnson combined on a four-hitter as the Orioles embarrassed the Oakland Athletics 11-0 for their fifth win in six games.</p>
<p>Cal Ripken had three hits, drove in two runs and scored two more for the Orioles, who improved the American League's best record to 19-8, including 11-4 at home.</p>
<p>Ripken drove in runs in the first and fifth innings off Ariel Prieto (2-2), helping the Orioles to a 4-0 lead.  Alomar broke open the game with his second career grand slam in the sixth off Don Wengert.</p>
<p>In Cleveland,  Willie Blair threw 5 2/3 scoreless innings before a line drive fractured his jaw and Tony Clark and Jody Reed added RBI singles as the Detroit Tigers snapped a 13-game losing streak to the Indians, 2-0.</p>
<p>The shutout was the second this season for the Tigers after just four last year and only the second Detroit win at Jacobs Field in 21 games.</p>
<p>Blair was hit in side of the head by a line drive off the bat of Julio Franco in the sixth inning and was taken off the field on a stretcher and rushed to the hospital.</p>
<p>In Toronto, Pat Hentgen returned to Cy Young form with a four-hitter and Carlos Delgado's fourth-inning RBI single gave the Blue Jays a 1-0 win over the Minnesota Twins.</p>
<p>Hentgen (2-1) struck out 10 and walked one in his first complete game of the season. He retired 17 straight batters from the last out in the first inning until walking Matt Lawton with one out in the seventh.</p>
<p>Orlando Merced opened the Blue Jays fourth with a double to right- centre before Delgado's single to right drove him home for the game's lone run.</p>
<p>In Seattle, Jamie Moyer allowed five hits over seven innings and Dan Wilson drove in four runs to lead the Mariners to a 9-0 rout of the Milwaukee Brewers.</p>
<p>Moyer (1-0) and Scott Sanders combined on the first shutout of the season for the Mariners, who have alternated wins and losses in their last 11 games.</p>
<p>Joey Cora had three hits, two runs and an RBI for Seattle, which had 12 hits and scored in its last five at-bats.</p>
<p>Milwaukee starter Cal Eldred (3-3) lasted six innings, allowing six runs and eight hits for the loss.</p>
<p>In Chicago, Jaime Navarro allowed a pair of runs over seven innings and Harold Baines homered and added an RBI single as the White Sox won a series for the first time this season, defeating the Anaheim Angels 4-2.</p>
<p>Navarro (3-1) allowed eight hits and one earned run, walking two and striking out three for the win.</p>
<p>White Sox first baseman Frank Thomas went 2-for-3. In his last nine games, he is 15-for-30 with two homers, three doubles and seven RBI.</p>
<p>With one out in the sixth, Baines hit his 326th career homer, moving him past Willie Horton into 59th place all-time.</p>
<p>At Texas, Billy Ripken's RBI single in the bottom of the seventh inning scored Damon Buford with the go-ahead run as the Rangers erased a five-run deficit for a 7-6 victory over the Boston Red Sox.</p>
<p>Danny Patterson (3-3) notched the victory with two perfect innings in relief. Butch Henry (2-2), who surrendered the go-ahead run in the seventh, took the loss.</p>
<p>Will Clark added a three-run homer for Texas in the fifth as the Rangers rallied from 5-0 and 6-2 deficits.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
