<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="559016" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-PSG HOPEFUL OF SECOND PLACE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-PSG HOPEFUL OF SECOND PLACE.</headline>
<byline>Rex Gowar</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paris St Germain began the French league season as favourites to win the championship.</p>
<p>Their European Cup Winners' Cup run which has taken them to their second successive final against Barcelona in Rotterdam in nine days time suggests that, with better management, they could have done it.</p>
<p>But for the third season in a row since their 1994 title the Parisians have come off second best, Monaco clinching their sixth championship at the weekend after the triumphs of Nantes in 1995 and Auxerre last year.</p>
<p>&quot;I really thought Paris would be champions this season,&quot; said Jean-Pierre Papin, who helped Bordeaux hold PSG to a 2-2 draw at the Parc des Princes on Saturday.</p>
<p>Bordeaux coach Rolland Courbis was less surprised. &quot;Monaco are champions because they are the ones to have least weakened their squad in two years.&quot;</p>
<p>PSG and Bordeaux, with the likes of Youri Djorkaeff and Zinedine Zidane moving to Italian clubs, saw several key players pursue their careers abroad without signing adequate replacements.</p>
<p>The Parisians are, however, going for a prize that did not exist in previous seasons -- a place in the European Cup for the runners-up in the leading leagues in Europe.</p>
<p>Their only realistic rivals for the berth are Nantes, unbeaten in 29 matches, who might have given Monaco more of a fight for the title if they had not made a disastrous start to the season managing only five draws and five defeats in the opening 10 matches.</p>
<p>Bordeaux, who look set to lose Courbis to ambitious Marseille for next season, and surprise team Metz -- who have won their last four games -- are in with a small chance but should both qualify for the UEFA Cup.</p>
<p>Metz coach Joel Muller said: &quot;Some time ago I told my players that to end the season with such a series of wins was like Mission Impossible. But I also pointed out to them that in the (television) series the heroes always get there.&quot;</p>
<p>PSG defend a three-point lead over third-placed Nantes when they resume league action away to arch-rivals Marseille in two weeks time.</p>
<p>With six points left to play for, four will be enough for PSG who are at home to Strasbourg, already in the UEFA Cup as League Cup winners, on the final day.</p>
<p>Defending champions Auxerre retain high hopes of snatching a UEFA Cup berth after beating Rennes 4-1 at home, but Bastia have fallen out of contention with a shock run of three defeats in succession.</p>
<p>Fourth in the standings three weeks ago just two points behind PSG after a 1-1 draw at home to the Parisians, Bastia have crashed 4-2 at Lyon, 2-1 to lowly Le Havre at home and 1-0 away to Metz on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;This evening was the end of a catastrophic week,&quot; Bastia coach Frederic Antonetti said on Saturday. &quot;...I'm very sad for my players, I'm also sad for Corsica which deserved (a place in) Europe.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
