<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55909" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soybeans close lower on weather, technicals.</title>
<headline>CBOT soybeans close lower on weather, technicals.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A forecast for good crop weather over the near term in the U.S. Midwest and technical selling drove CBOT soybean futures to a lower close, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's follow-through technical selling from the breakdown late last week and the lack of any significant cold air for the next 10 days,&quot; said Mark Cermak of O'Connor and Co.</p>
<p>Friday's National Weather Service six- to 10-day outlook was for above normal temperatures and below normal rainfall in the Midwest September 19 through September 23.</p>
<p>&quot;There was talk of some frost damage,&quot; Cermak said.</p>
<p>&quot;But it was minimal and the market wasn't too concerned about it.&quot;</p>
<p>Agronomists said frost on Saturday damaged corn and beans in low-lying fields in northern Iowa and southern Minnesota.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is saying there was not a lot of damage,&quot; said Vic Lespinasse of Dean Witter Reynolds, of Monday's futures declines in the face of the frost news.</p>
<p>Sell stops were hit initially when November opened below support at $8.00 per bushel and again at $7.91, they said.</p>
<p>Soybeans closed five to 14 cents per bushel lower, with September down 14 at $8.14-1/2.</p>
<p>Fund selling, estimated at at least 15.0 million bushels, led the way down with LIT America selling 11.0  million bushels of November, Refco Inc sold six million and Rosenthal Collins sold five million November, traders said.</p>
<p>Traders pointed to Friday's Commodity Futures Trading Commission Commitments of Traders report as evidence funds continued to hold a large portfolio of long positions.</p>
<p>The CFTC data showed as of September 10, funds were long soybeans by roughly a 10 to one ratio.</p>
<p>Soybean futures volume was estimated at 50,000 contracts, below the 51,649 Friday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>In soybean options, Smith Barney bought 500 November $8.00 puts at 22 cents and Term Commodities sold 400 November $8.00 calls at 16 to 19 cents, sources said.</p>
<p>Soybean options volume was estimated by the CBOT at 30,000 contracts, up from 24,943 Friday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
