<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="559134" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - May 12.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - May 12.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the major events to have occurred on May 12 in history:</p>
<p>1809 - Sir Arthur Wellesley (later Duke of Wellington) defeated the French at Oporto, forcing them to retreat from Portugal.</p>
<p>1820 - Florence Nightingale, English nurse and founder of the modern nursing profession, born in Italy. Served as a nurse in Turkey and the Crimea during the Crimean War.</p>
<p>1870 - Manitoba was purchased from the Hudson's Bay Company by the Dominion of Canada and made a province.</p>
<p>1871 - Daniel-Francois-Esprit Auber, French opera composer, died. Famous for developing opera containing spoken as well as sung passages.</p>
<p>1884 - Czech composer Bedrich Smetana, composer of operas including &quot;The Bartered Bride&quot; and &quot;The Brandenburgers in Bohemia&quot;, died.</p>
<p>1888 - Britain established protectorates over North Borneo and Brunei.</p>
<p>1918 - Julius Rosenberg born. In 1953 he and his wife, Ethel, became the first U.S. civilians to be executed for espionage, despite a worldwide campaign for mercy.</p>
<p>1926 - Norwegian Roald Amundsen, Italian Umberto Nobile and American Lincoln Ellsworth crossed the North Pole in an airship.</p>
<p>1926 - Jozef Pilsudski led a successful military coup against the government in Poland.</p>
<p>1937 - King George VI of England was crowned at Westminster Abbey in London. The coronation procession was broadcast by the British Broadcasting Corporation in its first outside broadcast.</p>
<p>1938 - Andrei Amalrik, Soviet author, historian and political dissident, born. He achieved worldwide fame with the publication in 1970 of his provocative essay &quot;Will The Soviet Union Survive Until 1984?&quot;.</p>
<p>1943 - In World War Two, all organised Axis resistance in Tunisia ended and the German commander in North Africa, General von Arnim, surrendered.</p>
<p>1949 - The Russian blockade of Berlin officially ended after 11 months with a food convoy driving into the city .</p>
<p>1957 - Erich Von Stroheim, film actor and one of the silent screen's greatest directors, died. Films include &quot;Greed&quot;, &quot;The Merry Widow&quot; and &quot;The Wedding March&quot;.</p>
<p>1962 - France and independent French-speaking West African states initialled an agreement setting up a West African Monetary Union.</p>
<p>1967 - John Masefield, English poet and, from 1930, poet laureate, died.</p>
<p>1975 - President Ford ordered the U.S. aircraft carrier Coral Sea into the Gulf of Thailand after the Cambodian navy seized the American merchant ship Mayaguez.</p>
<p>1981 - President Benjamin Sheares of Singapore died in office.</p>
<p>1989 - Retired British pilot Jack Mann was kidnapped by Islamic fundamentalists in Beirut. He was the oldest of the Westerners held hostage in Beirut during the Lebanese civil war.</p>
<p>1993 - Franco Nobili, the head of Italy's biggest state firm and Europe's second largest company, IRI, was arrested in Rome after a 15-month corruption investigation.</p>
<p>1994 - British Labour leader John Smith, a canny Scots lawyer with a burning ambition to lead his party back to power after 15 years in opposition, died of a heart attack.</p>
<p>1994 - A token force of Palestinian police crossed the Jordan River in preparation for the end of 27 years of Israeli military rule in a West Bank enclave around Jericho.</p>
<p>1994 - The Senate voted to order President Clinton to seek international agreement on ending the U.N.-mandated arms embargo against the Bosnian Moslems.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
