<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="559294" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian shares rise on healthy volumes, seen up.</title>
<headline>Russian shares rise on healthy volumes, seen up.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading Russian shares rose on domestic and Western demand on Monday in active trading and traders saw the market growing further in the short term after a possible slowing or slight fall on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Russian Trading System index of 22 shares rose to 334.59 from 321.19 on Wednesday, the last day the market traded before four days of national holidays.</p>
<p>Total market turnover on Monday was a vigorous $43.1 million, a level considered healthy by the standards of Russia's emerging market but which has not been touched for several weeks.</p>
<p>Traders said Friday's rise on Wall Street spurred foreign investor confidence and combined with domestic speculation to push prices higher in both first- and second-tier shares.</p>
<p>Market benchmark UES  rose to $0.2720 after closing on Wednesday at $0.2600 while Russia's biggest oil company LUKoil  rose to $14.53 from $14.20 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Regional energy company Irkutskenergo  rose to $0.275 from $0.246.</p>
<p>But steel producer Nizhnetagilsk Metal (NTMK) was unmoved by news it had approved plans to issue new shares, doubling capital to 2.07 trillion roubles ($359.7 million). NTMK did not trade on Monday but traded at $0.080 last Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;People have been expecting growth for a long time, but the growth of the American market is also not unimportant -- many major investors orient themselves around it,&quot; said Rinaco-Plus trader Alexander Lobanov.</p>
<p>One trader said he saw new money from foreign funds starting to trickle into the Russian market on the back of their good 1996 results, while domestic banks were also becoming more active.</p>
<p>&quot;A whole range of funds are sending new money into Russia and many Russian banks have started to participate. GKO yields are falling and they are putting money into blue chips,&quot; said Aton trader Boris Shvedsky.</p>
<p>Traders said profit taking would cut into growth on Tuesday but said they saw an uptrend for the rest of the week, although the mood from Western investors would help determine which way the market went.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm seeing selective buying from the client base supported by domestic speculators. For every $100,000 there's at least that much or more put in by local boys hoping they'll be selling higher tomorrow,&quot; said a trader at a Western bank.</p>
<p>&quot;It depends on how the London client reacts to the new level of prices...but I see all the reasons why this should be more than a blip,&quot; he said, adding he thought it could be several weeks before the market went into a major correction.</p>
<p>--Christina Ling, Moscow Newsroom, 941 85 20</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
