<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="559360" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Bucharest bourse share prices mixed after May Day.</title>
<headline>Bucharest bourse share prices mixed after May Day.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share prices on the Bucharest stock exchange were mixed and volumes drifted slightly lower on Monday when the bourse started the first week of trading extended to five sessions.</p>
<p>&quot;There were thinner volumes as orders accumulated after Labour Day were fewer,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>Two independent indices touched year highs on the back of hefty rises, of up to 30 percent, in the average quotes of several stocks, most of them on the second tier.</p>
<p>Two first-tier stocks and one on the second tier took most of turnover, which slipped 1.48 billion lei to 6.89 billion.</p>
<p>High-cap Azomures fertiliser maker had 2.81 billion lei in turnover but closed 400 lei weaker at 3,400.</p>
<p>&quot;Azomures fell and it will inch further down on Tuesday as the share packages on sale are very large,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Another heavyweight, Oltchim chemical plant, had 1.97 billion lei in turnover and closed flat at 2,550 lei.</p>
<p>Oltchim trading was halted for a couple of hours on Monday to allow distribution of a company statement to brokers. The statement said Oltchim had a net profit of 22.81 billion lei last year and would pay a gross dividend per share of 28 lei.</p>
<p>First-tier pharmaceuticals company Terapia traded modestly in thin supply but closed 1,000 lei stronger at 5,600. The other first-tier pharmaceuticals company Antibiotice was suspended pending an announcement.</p>
<p>On the second tier, dye maker Policolor put on a strong show, trading more than 480,000 shares and having 1.76 billion lei in turnover. It closed 400 lei stronger at 3,400.</p>
<p>&quot;Its turnover is comparable with levels on the first tier,&quot; another trader said. &quot;It's time it joined the higher category.&quot;</p>
<p>Policolor is expected to move on to the first tier in the immediate future.</p>
<p>Interest in the other second-tier listings was thin, with eight stocks having no trade. Another seven companies were suspended pending release of their 1996 results.</p>
<p>The VAB and the BIG unofficial indices rose by 9.4 and 5.67 percent respectively from the previous session. The BIG first-tier index rose by 4.63 percent to 3,276.64 points.</p>
<p>		MAY 5   APR 30  Week's change  1997 high   1997 low</p>
<p> VAB-Index  947.1   865.7   not applicable   947.1	262.0</p>
<p> BIG-Index  926.63  876.89  not applicable   926.63     266.43</p>
<p>($=7,094 lei)</p>
<p>-- Luli Popescu, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
