<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55940" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FCOJ futures end close to lows, Nov nears support.</title>
<headline>FCOJ futures end close to lows, Nov nears support.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Frozen concentrated orange juice futures closed weaker on late-session speculative and local selling, market sources said.</p>
<p>The selling gained momentum once stops were elected around 106.00 basis November, but trade buying buoyed the contract to close above 105.00. Support basis November was maintained at 103.00, and resistance was seen between 110.00 and 112.00.</p>
<p>November ended off 1.75 cent a lb at 104.80, having ranged from 107.45 to 104.50. The remaining months lost 1.45 to 0.65.</p>
<p>The market dismissed a report on tree-bearing acreage released after the close Friday. The Florida Agricultural Statistics Service (FASS) said bearing acreage for all oranges rose 16 percent in 1995 from 1994. There are 594,775 bearing acres currently, compared with 510,819 acres in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;The report was a wash,&quot; said Kevin Marshburn, an analyst with Fimat Futures. He said the 500,000 to 1.0 million additional trees bearing fruit this year, a number he extrapolated from the data, has already been filtered into the market.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Agriculture will release its next estimate for the Florida crop next month. Expectations are around 215 million 90-lb boxes.</p>
<p>--Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
