<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="559514" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: INTERVIEW-Mexico considers range of debt proposals.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Mexico considers range of debt proposals.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kozak</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico is considering proposals for new debt issues but has no firm plans at the moment to hit the markets, said Carlos Mendoza, director general of public credit at the Ministry of Finance.</p>
<p>&quot;We have various proposals, but there is nothing concrete yet,&quot; he said in an interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>Proposals to place debt issues flow into the finance ministry, which has been extremely active in debt markets this year, on an almost daily basis.  </p>
<p>Some recent proposals suggested Mexico might want to place a 100-year bond. However, they came before recent interest rate hikes in the U.S. clouded the picture.</p>
<p>&quot;It was something we were looking at, but we are still not convinced that it would be convenient,&quot; Mendoza said in the interview conducted last Friday.</p>
<p>When asked about placing a bond in French francs, he said, &quot;It is something that has been proposed, francs as well as (British) pounds, Portuguese escudos.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said they would want to see what the costs would be comparable to those in U.S. dollar in any market where Mexico does not now have a presence.</p>
<p>In the case of French francs, they would also have to examine what effect of Europe moving to a single currency will have.</p>
<p>&quot;There are advantages to entering a market with new investors. It is a market where the placements could be smaller,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not saying that it is advantageous for us, but it could be,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Mexico has also placed several issues in German marks since returning to international debt markets after the peso crisis.</p>
<p>But its longest term Deutschemark denominated bond has a 12 year maturity.</p>
<p>&quot;There we could extend it,&quot; he said, speaking about the government's maturities in marks.</p>
<p>He noted that part of the government's strategy is to place debt in various currencies, since among other things that reduces concerns about volatility in its debt servicing.  </p>
<p>&quot;This is an advantage, as well as having a wider base of investors. The wider the base of investors, the more probable it is that we will continue to have sources of funds. Those are two fundamental advantages,&quot; Mendoza said.</p>
<p>The government has also been very active in both Italian lira and Japanese yen recently.</p>
<p>The yen issues are also aimed at the retail side and are cost effective, he noted.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a very attractive market for us,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Both the German mark and the U.S. dollar market offer advantages of being very deep and being able to handle substantial amounts of funds, he said.</p>
<p>As far as Portuguese escudos, he said, &quot;We would have to see that there is a cost advantage.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that in general the government does not like to go to markets where there is uncertainty, as investors in this case tend to &quot;punish&quot; borrowers. &quot;It is not that one can't place there but they demand higher rates,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((--Mexico City newsroom +525 728 9559))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
