<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="559695" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Shenzhen B index ends up on Shanghai bull-run.</title>
<headline>Shenzhen B index ends up on Shanghai bull-run.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shenzhen's hard currency B share index closed Monday sharply higher on active buying triggered by surges in Shanghai's B share market, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Shenzhen B index gained 4.87 points or 2.76 percent to end at 181.14 on turnover of HK$253.9 million, compared with HK$149.9 million on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Shenzhen and Shanghai stock exchanges were closed for two days on Thursday and Friday due to the Labour Day holiday.</p>
<p>The Shanghai B share index soared 5.598 points or 6.14 percent to finish at 96.817 with investors pouring funds into blue chips and Pudong real estate shares, brokers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Shenzhen's advance was propelled by strong rises in Shanghai,&quot; an analyst with a major Chinese brokerage said.</p>
<p>With the ending of the annual reporting season, investors have begun to build positions in shares with a good 1997 outlook, analysts said.  </p>
<p>All listed firms have released their 1996 annual reports, with results being generally within expectations, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The macro-economic background looks better in 1997, from which listed firms are likely to benefit,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>Analysts said Shenzhen's B share market was likely to maintain upward momentum to top the 200 point level this month.</p>
<p>Steep gains on Shenzhen and Shanghai's domestic A share markets despite Beijing's announcement of a market expansion plan also fueled B share advances, brokers said.</p>
<p>Shenzhen's A share index climbed 18.66 points or 3.81 percent to close at 507.88 on turnover of 16.90 billion yuan.  </p>
<p>Shanghai's A share index soared 56.800 points or 3.90 percent to 1,513.303 on turnover of 12.628 billion yuan.</p>
<p>The China Securities Regulatory Commission, the country's top securities watchdog, on Monday announced an addition of five billion yuan to the existing 10 billion yuan quota of new share issues for 1997 or later.</p>
<p>Analysts said the move was clearly aimed at reining in the bull run on China's stock markets by diverting funds out of existing shares into new issues.  </p>
<p>&quot;A shares firmed today because investors have digested the news,&quot; an analyst at Shenzhen J&amp;A Securities said.</p>
<p>Analysts also warned of the risks in the markets, with the continued rises increasing the chance that the government could take measures to cool them down.</p>
<p>Television tube maker Shenzhen SEG was the top gainer in Shenzhen's B share market, surging HK$0.78 or 8.67 percent to HK$9.78 due to optimism over the company's 1997 earnings, brokers said.</p>
<p>Shenzhen Tellus Machinery rose HK$0.19 or 5.94 percent to HK$3.39 on volume of 787,240 shares.  </p>
<p>Brokers said Tellus's surge was linked to speculation that Tellus's new shareholder would drag Tellus into the black in 1997 after Tellus posted a net loss of 187.55 million yuan for 1996.</p>
<p>Tellus announced last Wednesday that the state-owned Shenzhen Special Economic Zone Development (Group) Co had bought 159.59 million state shares, accounting for 72.4 percent of Tellus's outstanding shares, from the city government-backed Shenzhen Investment &amp; Management Co.</p>
<p>Shenzhen Development Bank was the most actively traded A share, up 10 percent to 40.43 yuan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
