<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="559847" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: N.Y.S. gov says about $2 bln apart in budget revs.</title>
<headline>N.Y.S. gov says about $2 bln apart in budget revs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York State Gov George Pataki on Monday said negotiators were still about $2 billion apart in revenue estimates after budget talks resumed with the first meeting in two weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;We're about $2 billion apart, but that's not on spending, because our analysis of the Assembly's spending plan is that they're $2 billion above what they are,&quot; the Republican governor told reporters after he met with top lawmakers from the Senate and Assembly after the end of the legislature's spring break.  </p>
<p>The governor said that, on an overall basis, the new federal budget accord that was reached should help all New Yorkers and U.S. citizens because it is balanced, but he noted that different parts of the pact could aid and hurt New York State, depending on how the balancing mechanism.</p>
<p>&quot;There are some things we're pleased about, like the restoration of aid to legal immigrants, that's a plus. There are certain things we are very concerned about, like the Medicaid proposal with respect to disproportionate share hopsitals. That could have a very negative impact on New York State, so we're pleased they're moving toward a balanced budget, we just don't think it would be fair for them to do that on the backs of New Yorkers and we have to analyze the specific provisions to see the impact it will have on New Yorkers.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman for the state Health Department said so-called disproportionate share hospitals served Medicaid patients and people he defined as &quot;medically indigent.&quot; No further details about the impact the new agreement Washington reached might have on the state were immediately available.</p>
<p>((--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
