<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="559821" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AOL reports Q3 profit, marketing costs drop.</title>
<headline>AOL reports Q3 profit, marketing costs drop.</headline>
<dateline>DULLES, Va. 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>America Online Inc said it reported a profit in its third quarter of $2.6 million, or $0.02 a share, primarily due to lower marketing expenses in its first full quarter since it started flat rate pricing.</p>
<p>Wall Street had been expecting AOL to report a loss, with the First Call consensus estimate of a loss of $0.07 a share.</p>
<p>AOL said that as it had planned, it held its membership relatively flat at about 8 million subscribers, while it worked to improve access for existing members. When it launched its flat-rate pricing in December, a surge in demand for its service led to network access problems for its members.  </p>
<p>AOL's revenues climbed to a record $456.2 million, up 46 percent from total revenues of a year-ago of $312.3 million.</p>
<p>AOL also said that its other, non-subscription revenues grew to $74.7 million. Within other revenues, advertising and electronic commerce revenues were $60.7 million in the third quarter, up 37 percent from the December quarter.</p>
<p>The company also said that as expected, member cancellation increased in January, due to the change to flat-rate pricing and because of access issues. But the world's largest online service also said that its member retention improved steadily as the quarter progressed.  </p>
<p>AOL said that both trial member conversions and retention rates for April hit their highest levels in the past year.</p>
<p>AOL said that it recently resumed marketing on a limited basis and plans to continue carefully balancing demand for the service with its ability to keep improving access.</p>
<p>When its members started experiencing major problems in January in accessing the system, AOL announced a $350 million system expansion program.</p>
<p>&quot;As promised, we have worked around the clock to serve our existing members first and our top priority was, and still is, improving access,&quot; said AOL Chairman and CEO Steve Case.  </p>
<p>&quot;At the same time, we have achieved profitability a bit ahead of schedule,&quot; Case continued in a statement.</p>
<p>AOL also said that its cash position improved to $197.8 million, from $130.2 million in the December quarter.</p>
<p>As of March 31, AOL had $211.2 million in deferred revenues, up from $95.4 million in the December quarter, primarily reflecting advance subscription payments and its marketing agreement with Tel-Save Holdings Inc. A year ago, AOL reported $33.5 million in deferred revenue.</p>
<p>AOL said that as part of its system expansion program, it has installed more than 75,000 new modems in its AOLNet network.  </p>
<p>AOL said that during the quarter, it signed up 27 new advertisers, despite it being a seasonally slow period for advertising. AOL said it now has over 180 advertising clients, including companies such as Barnes &amp; Noble Inc, American Greetings and TRW Inc.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DULLES, Va."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
