<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="559974" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: G10 ask derivative clearers to tackle weaknesses.</title>
<headline>G10 ask derivative clearers to tackle weaknesses.</headline>
<byline>Peter Nielsen</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Volatile markets typically trigger a surge in trading of financial derivatives, but weak clearing arrangements at organised exchanges can trigger systemic disturbances to the global financial system, the Group of 10 (G10) leading industrial nations said on Monday.</p>
<p>Although risk management at clearing houses of derivatives exchanges has proved effective, the collapse of Barings Plc and the stock market crash in 1987 revealed sources of vulnerability and shook confidence in the financial integrity of the houses, G10's Committee on Payment and Settlement Systems (CPSS) said.</p>
<p>In a report titled Clearing Arrangements for Exchange-Traded Derivatives, CPSS recommends that clearing houses should examine stress testing, enhanced intra-day risk management and money settlement arrangements as steps to reduce credit and liquidity risks vis-a-vis clearing members and settlement banks.</p>
<p>Central bankers, always nervous about systemic risks, are concerned about the health of exchanges' clearing houses because the trading of derivatives is now a crucial component of the financial infrastructure of G10 countries.</p>
<p>Financial derivatives, such as futures and options on interest rates, exchange rates and stock indices, allow banks and companies to manage risks more effectively.</p>
<p>Derivatives are traded either as standardised contracts on exchanges, for example the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME) or London International Financial Futures and Options Exchange (LIFFE), or over-the-counter (OTC) between two parties.</p>
<p>The volume on the unregulated OTC market exceeds that of exchange-traded derivatives, but is normally quite illiquid.</p>
<p>Average daily money settlements of exchange-traded derivatives is normally modest, but once financial markets are in turmoil, settlement amounts rocket.</p>
<p>In 1995 average daily settlements at the Clearing House Division of CME was $280 million. But during the stock market crash in October 1987, settlements peaked at $2.5 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;During such periods market participants tend to be experiencing significant liquidity demands in cash markets as well as derivatives markets,&quot; the CPSS report said.</p>
<p>Clearing houses are at the core of exchanges. They normally serve as the central counterpart to deals struck between exchange members. The clearing house becomes the buyer to every seller of a contract and vice versa.</p>
<p>Banks and securities firms assume organised derivatives exchanges will provide them with enough liquidity to offset exposure to collapsing market prices and depend on the timely completion of payments to manage their liquidity risks.</p>
<p>But just when banks need money, it is hard to come by.</p>
<p>&quot;Consequently, when markets are already under stress, the loss of an exchange's liquidity or a delay in the completion of exchange-related payments or deliveries could well lead to systemic disturbances -- the liquidity of other financial markets could be seriously impaired, and payment systems and other settlement systems could be disrupted,&quot; CPSS said.</p>
<p>By becoming the counterparty to all trades on the exchange, the clearing house assumes a variety of risks, including default by its members, failure at the settlement bank and the risk to its own funds as well as operational and legal risks.</p>
<p>In addition, the internationalisation of markets and links between clearing houses in different countries could make risk management more complex and difficult, CPSS cautioned.</p>
<p>Clearing houses in the G10 countries employ a common set of safeguards to limit the likelihood of defaults by members and these have generally proved quite effective, CPSS said.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, there have been several cases where sharp movements in market prices have raised doubts about the health of clearing houses.</p>
<p>This include the collapse of stock prices in October 1987 and the sharp decline in Japanese equity prices in early 1995 which triggered defaults by units of Barings that were members of clearing houses in Japan and Singapore.</p>
<p>CPSS concluded that clearing houses &quot;simply cannot be made fail-safe,&quot; but there are still several steps clearing houses could take to reduce their vulnerability to potential problems.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GTEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
