<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="560043" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norway shares up with Wall Street, but trade thin.</title>
<headline>Norway shares up with Wall Street, but trade thin.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian shares were given a boost on Monday by Wall Street's gains last Friday, but volume was thin partly because of a public holiday in London, dealers said.</p>
<p>Oslo's Total share index rose 1.13 percent to 1,101.86 points in lacklustre turnover of 700 million crowns.</p>
<p>Industrial giant Norsk Hydro, which has a 20 percent weighting on the Total index, was up 1.03 percent at 344 crowns.</p>
<p>Bergesen, Norway's biggest shipping company, also shone, its A share rising 4.38 percent to 155 crowns.  </p>
<p>Branded-goods conglomerate Orkla saw its A share up 1.99 percent at 615 crowns following news that the European Commission would examine a planned Nordic alliance between its competitors Carlsberg of Denmark and Coca Cola.</p>
<p>A-class shares in industrial holding company Aker RGI were down 0.6 percent at 169 crowns the day before the release of the group's first-quarter results.</p>
<p>Pharmaceutical company Nycomed was up 1.36 percent at 112 crowns the day before its first-quarter presentation.</p>
<p>--Rolf Soderlind, Oslo newsroom +47 22 42 50 41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
