<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="560032" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish industry attacks govt environment tax plan.</title>
<headline>Danish industry attacks govt environment tax plan.</headline>
<byline>Steve Weizman</byline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Confederation of Danish Industries (DI) reacted swiftly and angrily to Monday's government announcement of a new package of environmental taxes, saying that they would swell unemployment.</p>
<p>&quot;New tax and duty increases, under cover of a user-related initiative will increase industry's costs and harm employment,&quot; a DI statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is incomprehensible that the government does not display greater understanding of industry's situation regarding competitiveness,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The statement added that consumers were being used as a scapegoat when the real economic threat came from excessive government spending.</p>
<p>A government statement presented the package -- including new vehicle, road and fuel taxes, a passenger tax on domestic air travel and lower public transport fares -- as a green initiative.</p>
<p>Financial markets were unmoved by the news. The measures are expected to add two billion crowns annually to state revenues, compared to a 706 billion crown state debt, which the government has pledged to eradicate by the year 2005.</p>
<p>Scandinavian Airlines System (SAS) said that the package's introduction of taxes on domestic flight tickets was intended to protect state-owned Danish railways competitiveness and could make reduced-price air fares unviable.</p>
<p>&quot;The proposed passenger tax would entirely erode earnings from the sale of low price air tickets and might possibly force SAS to do away with cheap air travel offers,&quot; SAS spokesman Troels Rasmussen told Reuters.</p>
<p>Car importers argued that the new vehicle taxes could actually harm the environment by encouraging motorists to keep older cars on the road longer.</p>
<p>&quot;The proposals are in direct contradiction to earlier government statements that it would penalise the polluters but make it easier to acquire a modern, environmentally-sound vehicle,&quot; Danish Car Importers head Bent Mikkelsen said.</p>
<p>The package is subject to ratification in parliament but should be assured a safe passage.</p>
<p>It is supported by two leftist parties, the Socialist People's Party and the Unity List, giving the centre-left minority government and its allies a majority in this case.</p>
<p>The agreement cuts bus and train fares by 10 percent and raises the upper limit for child fares to 15 years from 12. It raises the rate of road tax for commercial vehicles also used for private journeys and alters duty on new cars to encourage the purchase of smaller models.</p>
<p>Vehicles meeting latest EU environmental criteria will pay a reduced rate of road tax and petrol would be taxed according to the amount of benzene it contained.</p>
<p>Benzene is a constituent of petrol which, the statement said, can cause leukaemia.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Mogens Lykketoft told reporters that the deal did not oblige the Socialist People's Party and the Unity List to support his 1998 budget, due to be unveiled in draft form in August for passage by the end of the year. --Copenhagen newsroom +45-33969650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
