<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="560026" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FRENCH ELECTION - PARTIES POSITIONS ON EMU.</title>
<headline>FRENCH ELECTION - PARTIES POSITIONS ON EMU.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>France will hold an early two-stage parliamentary election on May 25 and June 1. The following is a summary of the main parties' positions on European economic and monetary union (EMU) and the creation of a single currency on January 1, 1999:</p>
<p>RALLY FOR THE REPUBLIC (GAULLIST)</p>
<p>The senior partner in the ruling conservative coalition, founded by President Jacques Chirac and led by Prime Minister Alain Juppe, it is committed to launching the euro on time.</p>
<p>-- Meeting Maastricht</p>
<p>Government ministers have pledged to do whatever is needed to cut the state deficit to three percent of gross domestic product this year to meet Maastricht treaty criteria. They have promised to continue reducing the budget gap in future years.</p>
<p>They refuse to be drawn on how they believe the European Union should interpret a Maastricht treaty provision allowing countries to join EMU even if their deficits overshoot, provided they are going in the right direction.</p>
<p>-- Italian, Spanish membership</p>
<p>Government ministers have taken no clear position on whether they think founder member Italy, as well as Spain and Portugal, can or will join EMU in 1999, saying this, and a judgement on how to interpret the Maastricht treaty, must await the scheduled decision time in late April/early May 1998.</p>
<p>-- Role of the ECB</p>
<p>The government has said it wants a political counterweight alongside the European Central Bank, but has diluted its original proposals after running into heavy flak abroad. It has since settled with France's partners on an informal stability council to co-ordinate economic policies inside the euro zone.</p>
<p>-- Currency policies on the euro</p>
<p>The government says it wants a stable, credible euro, paving the way for low interest rates. Its calls last year for a rise in the dollar raised fears France might be lukewarm in its support for a strong euro, though ministers now says the dollar's recent rise has corrected its previous undervaluation</p>
<p>-- EU &quot;stability pact&quot; limiting deficits after 1999</p>
<p>Juppe and others railed against the pact as first proposed by Germany last year, but agreed to it after securing a compromise that leaves some room for political judgement on when countries whose deficits overshoot should be fined</p>
<p>UNION FOR FRENCH DEMOCRACY (CENTRIST)</p>
<p>The UDF, junior partner in the ruling coalition, has traditionally been more pro-European than the RPR.</p>
<p>Its manifesto says achieving the single currency on time is &quot;a fundamental, non-negotiable objective&quot;.</p>
<p>It says the euro will require tight co-ordination of national fiscal decisions, and says the EU's council of ministers should develop into a proper &quot;economic government&quot;.</p>
<p>Europe must adopt a more federal approach, develop a genuine common foreign and defence policy, press ahead with reform of EU institutions to give them more say. It favours deeper European integration where possible among a hard-core of countries, led by France and Germany.</p>
<p>SOCIALIST PARTY</p>
<p>The Socialist party negotiated the Maastricht treaty under late president Francois Mitterrand, who along with German Chancellor Helmut Kohl laid the foundations for monetary union.</p>
<p>Though still committed to launching the euro in 1999, it has set conditions on this:</p>
<p>-- Meeting Maastricht</p>
<p>The party opposes a dogmatic interpretation of Maastricht criteria, says the treaty itself leaves leeway to take account of trends shown by a country towards meeting EMU entry targets</p>
<p>Party leader Lionel Jospin has said the Socialists would not impose a new round of austerity to meet Maastricht targets, but would instead negotiate a political agreement with Germany</p>
<p>-- Italian, Spanish membership</p>
<p>Italy and Spain must be in EMU from the start, and Britain too if it wants</p>
<p>-- Role of European Central Bank</p>
<p>The Socialist party wants a European economic government alongside the ECB</p>
<p>-- Strength of the euro</p>
<p>Party manifesto says the euro must not be overvalued against the dollar and the yen, though party officials say the recent rise in the dollar has calmed such worries. One official has said one-for-one currency parity between the euro and the dollar would be a good thing economically.</p>
<p>-- EU stability pact</p>
<p>The Socialist party manifesto calls for a &quot;solidarity and growth pact&quot; rather than an &quot;austerity pact&quot;. Party officials have said the Socialists want to review the stability pact and question its assumption that deficits must continue to be reduced below three percent of GDP after the launch of the euro.</p>
<p>COMMUNIST PARTY</p>
<p>The Communists want a fresh referendum on the single currency, calling the creation of the euro an &quot;ultra-liberal political project&quot;.</p>
<p>NATIONAL FRONT</p>
<p>The extreme-right party is militantly opposed to the single currency and would halt progress toward further European integration of most kinds.</p>
<p>It wants a fresh referendum on the euro.</p>
<p>GREENS</p>
<p>The Greens favour a single currency but with conditions. They oppose European liberalism and deregulation, want to scrap the EU's &quot;stability pact&quot;, and are seeking policies to promote job creation, social progress and environmental protection. The Greens broadly support further European integration.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 42 21 53 81 Monday, May 5 1997</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
