<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="560098" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan to decide sugar tender on Wednesday.</title>
<headline>Pakistan to decide sugar tender on Wednesday.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The state-run Trading Corporation of Pakistan (TCP) will decide the outcome of a tender for 50,000 tonnes of crystal white refined sugar on Wednesday, a senior TCP official said on Monday .</p>
<p>&quot;We will arrive at a decision on Wednesday,&quot; said the TCP official. &quot;The tender was opened on Saturday as scheduled but we are still negotiating with the bidders on...specifications given in the tender.&quot;</p>
<p>The TCP invited tenders from international suppliers last month for 50,000 tonnes of crystal white refined sugar in two equal shipments to reach Karachi by June 20 and July 10.</p>
<p>The official said sugar imports for June and July were intended to check rising domestic prices and offset an expected shortage in July-September ahead of the new cane crushing season.</p>
<p>However, the Pakistan Sugar Mills Association (PSMA) said stocks would last until the new season starts in October.</p>
<p>&quot;Sugar mills have enough sugar now,&quot; said a PSMA official questioned about fears voiced by opposition leader Benazir Bhutto that Pakistan might soon face shortages of sugar and cooking oil following recent unrest over wheat supply.</p>
<p>&quot;The opposition always cries that a lion is coming out of the woods, but at the end we see a dog,&quot; one mill owner said.</p>
<p>A government spokesman, quoted by state television, said on Sunday that the government had decided to abolish a 10 percent import duty on sugar to forestall any shortages.</p>
<p>He said a formal announcement would be made after the cabinet's Economic Coordination Committee meets on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The PSMA official said sugar production had reached 2.32 million tonnes by April 15 compared to 2.43 million at the same time a year ago.</p>
<p>He said mills aimed to produce 2.4 million tonnes in 1996/97, compared to 2.47 million in 1995/96 and 3.0 million in 1994/95. Dealers had bought 1.13 million tonnes, or 49 percent, of the production, and 1.18 million remained at the mills.</p>
<p>He said that despite the comfortable stock position, some importers had opened at least 10 letters of credit to import 125,000 tonnes of sugar. He could not say when it would arrive.</p>
<p>Cooking oil dealers said there were ample stocks of vegetable oils and domestic cottonseed oil would reach the market from July onwards as the cotton harvest arrived.</p>
<p>-- Karachi newsroom 9221-5685192</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
