<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="560351" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Global TeleMedia says signs $240 mln contract.</title>
<headline>Global TeleMedia says signs $240 mln contract.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Global TeleMedia International Inc said Monday it signed a service agreement with a provider of prepaid calling cards worth at least $240 million.</p>
<p>The company added that the provider bought a five percent equity position in the company. It declined to identify the provider, but said it was one of the &quot;country's largest.&quot;</p>
<p>The initial term of this agreement, which began May 1, is for 24 months following an initial four month start-up period.</p>
<p>The company expects that, during the start-up period, the provider will buy about $3 million a month of prepaid calling card services, with a minimum guarantee to buy $10 million in services a month after that for the balance of the agreement.</p>
<p>The agreement calls for prepayment of at least one month's projected revenues for the duration of contract. For the year ended December 31, 1996, Global Telemedia reported revenues of $1.4 million.</p>
<p>The company said the deal also guarantees minimum gross profit margins of at least six percent during the start-up stage, which is to raise to a minimum of 10 percent for the balance of the term of the agreement. It plans to invest at least $10 million to expand its switch capacity for the contract.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
