<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="560564" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GM invests $300 mln in Mich. stamping plant.</title>
<headline>GM invests $300 mln in Mich. stamping plant.</headline>
<dateline>FLINT, Mich. 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Motors Corp said it will invest about $300 million at the Flint Metal Center for new manufacturing equipment and tooling to prepare the plant for future product programs.</p>
<p>GM also said it will update existing presses at the metal stamping plant, which is a part of its Metal Fabricating Division. The Flint facility produces engine cradles and major and minor sheet metal panels for GM cars, trucks, and mid-size vans.  </p>
<p>The automaker in 1994 initiated an aggressive program to simplify its stamping operations and use common manufacturing equipment and processes throughout its 13 North American stamping plants.</p>
<p>GM said its investments in the Flint Metal Center will help accelerate its plan to identify common processes or best practices that can be shared with other facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;This commitment to update the Flint Metal Center supports our continuing efforts to commonize GM's stamping operations,&quot; plant manager Donald Mayton said in a statement.</p>
<p>Mayton said the new equipment will enhance the facility's ability to respond quickly to changes in product mix or customer preference demands.</p>
<p>The plant employs 3,996 people, or nearly 12 percent of the Metal Fabricating Division's 34,000-member workforce.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FLINT, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
