<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="560726" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel Treasury questions central bank policy.</title>
<headline>Israel Treasury questions central bank policy.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior Treasury official on Monday questioned the Bank of Israel's policy of absorbing excess liquidity in the market, saying it was costly to the economy.</p>
<p>The central bank has been forced to buy large amounts of dollars to prevent the Israeli currency from appreciating beyond its fixed trading band. The central bank has absorbed the excess liquidity by such methods as issuing short-term paper, on which it pays interest.</p>
<p>In 1996 this so-called sterilisation policy cost two billion shekels, said David Milgram, the Treasury's budget director. He said he feared this cost would rise in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;This cost does not find expression in the government's national priorities,&quot; Milgram told reporters in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The Treasury has been urging the central bank to lower interest rates, which has helped buoy the shekel in the past year.</p>
<p>In response the central bank said it was a mistake to link the cost of liquidity absorption to its monetary policy.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bank of Israel acts to achieve the inflation target set by the government while being obligated to maintain the exchange rate within the trading bands,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the present exchange rate system the absorption costs would rise together with the costs tied to an acceleration in inflation and the damage to economic stability.&quot;</p>
<p>The central bank has called for a widening of the trading bands, to allow the shekel to rise further before intervention.</p>
<p>Milgram said other non-budgeted expenditures were forced upon the government, including spending passed by parliament after the budget is finalised, public sector wage agreements, pension accords and the deficits of health care funds.</p>
<p>Milgram said the Treasury was analysing April budget data, which showed a smaller-than-expected deficit of 928 million shekels in the first four months. The Treasury still expects a larger-than-forecast deficit for all of 1997 but the size of the deviation may be smaller than was thought earlier.</p>
<p>Milgram said the Treasury would announce in a few days the size of the deviation and then propose a budget cut to guarantee the government meet its 1997 deficit target of 2.8 percent of gross domestic product. Government sources say the proposed cut will likely be less than one billion shekels.</p>
<p>Milgram also said the Treasury and Health Ministry were studying reform of the national health care system. Under the present system Israelis receive health care from funds called Kupoth Holim and in return pay a health tax, the receipts of which the government divides among the funds.</p>
<p>The government is obligated to cover the deficits of the Kupoth Holim, placing a growing burden on the budget.</p>
<p>&quot;This situation cannot continue and we'll have to decide whether to nationalise health services completely or give the health funds more flexibility, more responsibility,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>($1 = 3.41 shekels)</p>
<p>-Jerusalem newsroom, 972-2-537-0502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
