<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="560706" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Euro products outlook - fuel, gas oil eye Asia.</title>
<headline>Euro products outlook - fuel, gas oil eye Asia.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>European oil products traders are closely watching thirsty Asian markets which could soak up European gas oil and fuel oil if relative prices swing by a few dollars.</p>
<p>But public holidays on Monday in Britain and on Thursday in several European countries will hamper smooth trading.</p>
<p>The main Singaporean buyer of gas oil is now quieter and the chances of speculative arbitrage business to Asia have dimmed - although further sharp falls on the IPE could turn that around.</p>
<p>Naphtha is expected to remain flat with the possible exception of naphthenic and aromatic (n+a) material - a feedstock for reformers to make gasoline - which will be supported if gasoline recovers from Friday's sell-off.</p>
<p>Traders may try to keep prices at these lower levels until the first four cargoes out of Skikda this month, all likely to head for the Far East, are out of the way. Prices may then bounce later.</p>
<p>The prompt naphtha to front-month Brent crude crack spread should also hold at around $40-$42 a tonne, a source said.</p>
<p>Traders were divided over gasoline's move after Friday's drop in NYMEX unleaded futures. Rich NWE margins may prompt refiners into boosting output, but traders said much hinged on the arbitrage and recent talk of a barge market squeeze.</p>
<p>At least 200,000 to 300,000 tonnes was sold to the U.S. in the second half of April, including several cargoes of cat gas out of the Med. That is down from 800,000 tonnes in April 1996.</p>
<p>Gas oil lost some of its recent strength at the tail end of last week and a significant recovery is not anticipated.</p>
<p>Diesel, which has been tight, saw a spate of four cargoes getting sold which helped pull premiums off highs to May IPE +$11-13 cif NWE while DIN and FOD heating oil lost about $1 apiece on premiums.</p>
<p>India may provide some comfort, although the 315,000 tonne June buy tender was lower than expected.</p>
<p>Speculation abounds as to how the summer flow of Russian fuel oil, expected to appear mid-month, will hit prices. Some expect it to trigger big falls in bunker values later in the month.</p>
<p>Barge business will again be dented by holidays this week but traders expect high sulphur fob prices to stay in the narrow $80-$83 range where they have been since early April.</p>
<p>But eyes will still be on Singapore, where bunker prices are still $20 above Europe's, with fears any fall in Asia will push the western market onto the rocks.</p>
<p>A dip in low sulphur prices early last week sparked a flurry of cargo trades which cleared out most prompt material. High sulphur will continue tight in the immediate period in the Mediterranean, but the overall demand picture continues to worsen as summer nears, leaving prices steady for now.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
