<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="560829" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Police close in on escaped Texas separatists.</title>
<headline>Police close in on escaped Texas separatists.</headline>
<byline>Kieran Murray</byline>
<dateline>FORT DAVIS, Texas 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police dogs on Monday closed in on two escaped members of the Republic of Texas separatist group who fled into a canyon hours before the group ended its week-long standoff over the weekend, a Texas police spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Five shots were fired and one police bloodhound was injured about an hour after the dogs were set loose and began tracking the men through rugged terrain surrounding the group's compound in the west Texas mountains, spokeswoman Sherri Deatherage Green said.</p>
<p>&quot;The dogs were released about 8 a.m. this morning, and within 10 minutes they were on the trail,&quot; Green said. No shots had been fired by law enforcement officers, she said.</p>
<p>A pack of about 20 bloodhounds were leading troopers on horseback and in helicopters searching a canyon in the Davis Mountains where separatists identified as Richard Keyes and Mike Matson were believed to be hiding.</p>
<p>Five other Republic of Texas members, including their leader Richard McLaren, surrendered to police Saturday, ending a seven-day standoff with police sparked by the arrest of one of the group's members on state firearms charges.</p>
<p>McLaren and his followers, who claim Texas is an independent nation, had vowed to defend their &quot;embassy&quot; compound to the death but surrendered when scores of police surrounded them and prepared to move in.</p>
<p>Keyes and Matson were seen escaping into the mountains at around midday on Saturday, four hours before the others surrendered. But police waited for the others to lay down their arms before beginning the search for the two men.</p>
<p>The start of the search also was slowed while ordnance teams cleared 40 to 60 pipe bombs stored in a series of makeshift bunkers around the compound. Police also had to defuse a dozen makeshift fire bombs surrounding the compound.</p>
<p>Bloodhounds were set loose after dawn on Monday after police cleared the boobytraps surrounding a dilapidated trailer in a remote residential enclave used by the Republic of Texas to wage its battle for Texas independence.</p>
<p>The escaped separatists were dressed in camouflage and armed with an assault rifle, a deer-hunting rifle and a 9mm pistol. Keyes is wanted on state kidnapping charges, but no charges have been filed against Matson, police said.</p>
<p>The Republic of Texas, which claims to have thousands of members and ties to anti-government militia groups, says that Texas' 1845 annexation by the United States was illegal. Texas was an independent nation for nine years after it broke from Mexico in an 1836 rebellion McLaren likened to his own.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FORT DAVIS, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
