<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="560832" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Universal Studios to extend Florida theme park.</title>
<headline>Universal Studios to extend Florida theme park.</headline>
<dateline>ORLANDO, Fl. 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Universal Studios plans to announce a major new expansion to its Florida vacation theme park Tuesday, company officials said.</p>
<p>Film director Steven Spielberg, a creative consultant on the new $2.6 billion development, will take part in the announcement, Universal spokeswoman Yvonne Goforth said.</p>
<p>Universal was releasing no more details, but some accounts of the expansion have appeared in newspapers and trade publications in recent weeks.</p>
<p>Plans include a second Orlando theme park -- Islands of Adventure -- hotels and nightclubs. Together with the Universal Studios theme park, the resort will become known as Universal City Florida, according to the reports.</p>
<p>Islands of Adventure will feature five islands built around popular stories and characters such as Spiderman, Jurassic Park and the children's characters of Dr. Seuss, the reports said.</p>
<p>The company is expected to announce that Islands of Adventure will open in the summer of 1999.</p>
<p>Universal is 80 percent owned by Seagram Co Ltd. --Miami bureau (305) 374-5013</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97412">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ORLANDO, Fl."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
