<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="561003" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares continue to rally at record levels.</title>
<headline>German shares continue to rally at record levels.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's IBIS DAX index continued its record-breaking rally in afternoon electronic trade on Monday, with market players revising their outlooks for the DAX index upwards to 3,600/3,700 points for the year.</p>
<p>The IBIS DAX was up 54.83 points, or 1.57 percent, at 3,545.91 points in afternoon trade, just shy of an all-time high of 3,550.62 points.</p>
<p>Earlier the DAX index ended bourse trade at a record closing high of 3,528.78 points.</p>
<p>&quot;What we have here is problem-free growth and the index keeps rising,&quot; said one Frankfurt trader.  </p>
<p>Another trader said that after the massive jump in the first quarter, the markets were a bit nervous and the month of April signalled a bit of a consolidation phase.</p>
<p>&quot;But now we may be getting an external impulse so people might just take up where they left off in April. If we don't get any massive dirt from the U.S. this may be sustainable,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>He also said that he thought there may be a need for short term consolidation back toward 3,480 if any significant gains were to be achieved.  </p>
<p>Among financial stocks, Dresdner Bank was up 2.36 marks at 58.38 marks, a rise of over four percent. Dealers said it was in a strong technical position and that sentiment was lifted by long-running speculation about changes in the shapr of the banking sector.</p>
<p>Other big gainers in the afternoon were Deutsche Lufthansa AG, up 3.71 percent at 25.72 marks, and RWE AG, up 3.05 percent at 73.70 marks, which illustrates how the gains were really across the board in afternoon IBIS trade.</p>
<p>Market attention now turned to the U.S., with many market players hoping for an upbeat start on the Dow Jones Industrial.  </p>
<p>marks after Frankfurt prosecutors said they were probing a potentially serious insider trading case involving the company.</p>
<p>Dealers downplayed the move, noting that SAP is notoriously volatile. By afternoon trade the share was down 1.50 marks at 326.50 marks.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar is stable, the debt market is strong and the U.S. helped us last Friday,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
