<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="561107" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - May 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - May 5.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>-- BLAIR PRESSED TO RAISE TAXES</p>
<p>Tony Blair, Britain's new prime minister, is under increasing pressure to raise taxes. Support for the tax rises comes in an article written in The Financial Times by Mr Adair Turner, the director general of the Confederation of British Industry, the industry lobby group. Turner says some action is needed to be taken soon to slow down the economy.</p>
<p>-- WINDFALL COMPLAINTS BEYOND WATCHDOG'S JURISDICTION</p>
<p>Thousands of people will be disappointed to hear that their complaints about the 22 billion stg demutualisation bonanza handed out by building societies will not be redressed. The Building Societies' ombudsman says that most cases fall outside his jurisdiction. And where he has adjudicated, he has found in favour of the societies every time.</p>
<p>-- TORY LEADERSHIP RACE OFFERS UP FEW FAVOURITES</p>
<p>The Tory leadership race heated up over the weekend with two of the main contenders throwing their hats into the ring. Peter Lilley, former social security secretary, joined ex-chancellor Kenneth Clarke in declaring his hand. They are almost certain to be joined by Michael Howard and John Redwood. Two candidates who would be seen as consensus figures, Stephen Dorrell and William Hague, told colleagues they too would almost certainly stand.</p>
<p>-- BSKYB AND BT IN 700 MILLION STG VENTURE TO LAUNCH DIGITAL TV</p>
<p>British Sky Broadcasting will announce on Wednesday that it is to launch 200 channels of digital television in the UK. BSkyB has finalised details of a 700 million stg joint venture with British Telecommunications, Midland Bank and Matsushita, the Japanese electronics company, to form British Interactive Broadcasting. BSkyB and BT will each have 30 percent of the venture and the other partners will have 20 percent each.</p>
<p>-- ONLINE TRAVEL BOOKINGS SET TO REACH ONE BILLLION STG IN FIVE YEARS</p>
<p>The value of travel booked through online computer services in the UK will increase from less than 1 million stg to more than 1 billion stg per year within five years, according to a report from Datamonitor. New distribution channels such as the Internet will account for a growing proportion of travel sales, posing a challenge to travel agents. The technology is being seized upon by airlines as a way of cutting distribution costs.</p>
<p>-- BUILDING ON A POLICY OF GOOD HOUSEKEEPING</p>
<p>Construction industry executives at one time expected much joy from the prospect of a Labour government planning to step up investment in social housing, hospitals, schools and other infrastructure. However, this time Labour has pledged its spending policies will be just as tough as those under the Tories. It has little fiscal room to do otherwise.</p>
<p>For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
