<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="561159" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: W. Australia exploration spending plateaued - report.</title>
<headline>W. Australia exploration spending plateaued - report.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spending on mineral exploration in Western Australia appears to have plateaued and may not be sufficient to sustain the minerals industry over the long term, the state Chamber of Minerals and Energy said on Monday.</p>
<p>In a report entitled &quot;Minerals in Western Australia: Bedrock of the Economy,&quot; the chamber said spending is at historically high levels but says exploration is also becoming more expensive and the cost per unit of discovered resource is increasing.</p>
<p>&quot;A high level of successful exploration is particularly needed when known reserves of the mineral or energy source have very short term lives,&quot; the report says.  </p>
<p>&quot;In Western Australia this is especially important for oil and gold,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;... The key question which is not answered by the raw data (on exploration spending) is whether even these historically high levels of expenditure are delivering the resources needed to sustain the minerals industry over the long term.</p>
<p>&quot;That expenditure growth appears to be levelling out at a time of strong growth in output is a worrying indication.&quot;</p>
<p>The report was written by Don Stammer, director and chief economist of Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, and the chamber's economist, Steven Gerhardy.  </p>
<p>It said the state is experiencing a quiet boom marked by sustained high levels of investment and greater interest in mineral processing than in previous periods.</p>
<p>However, the industry is facing several major challenges &quot;which if not met will severely check its further expansion and the capacity to generate jobs, exports and incomes&quot;.</p>
<p>As well as the need to increase exploration spending, the report listed the challenges as:</p>
<p>- Countering increased global competition as new countries establish mining industries;  </p>
<p>- Ensuring improved access to land and &quot;a workable and efficient Native Title process which yields real benefits for all parties&quot;;</p>
<p>- The provision of adequate infrastructure;</p>
<p>- Reform of the tax system;</p>
<p>- Further effective reform of the state's electricity and gas markets; and</p>
<p>- Maintaining adequate levels of profitability so as to attract the capital sums needed to develop new projects and provide a competitive return to shareholders.  </p>
<p>&quot;While average mining company profitability increased modestly in 1995/96 the rate of return on capital (8.8 percent) remained below the average rates of return earned by other industries,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;It also remained below the long-term average of the mining industry.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
