<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="561141" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks fade by close as BHP loses.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks fade by close as BHP loses.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>------------------(Snapshot 4.20 p.m./0620 GMT)-----------------</p>
<p>AORD		 2492.7    +1.1   DJIA cl	7071.20   +94.72</p>
<p>SPI Sycom	    2498   -10.0   US 30yr cl	6.88    -0.03</p>
<p>10yrbond futs    92.240  +0.120   Gold NY 339.65 Lon fix 339.80</p>
<p>AUD     $0.7828 (Fri   $0.7843)   CRB Index cl  246.62    -1.28</p>
<p>NIKKEI closed, market holiday     FTSE cl	 4455.6    +10.6</p>
<p>S&amp;P500(Globex)   818.30   +1.75   NZSE40 cl    2276.61    -0.92</p>
<p>--------------------------(May 5)-------------------------------</p>
<p>*Stocks faded by the close on a fall in bellwhether BHP after the market neared fresh highs early. Vol 289.40 million, value A$835.02 million, 1,027 stocks traded, 325 steady, 345 up, 357 down.</p>
<p>Early enthusiasm for Australian shares faded by the close on Monday as market bellbether BHP lost all of its early gains in afternoon trade after unions voted for a nationwide strike against BHP on May 15.</p>
<p>By 4.20 p.m. (0620 GMT), the All Ordinaries index ended 1.1 points higher at 2,492.7 after hitting an intra-day high of 2,509.9, but never built enough momentum to topple the record high of 2515.1 reached last Wednesday.</p>
<p>June share price index futures closed 10 points lower at 2,501, after hitting a high of 2,525. The contract is at an 8.3 point premium to the underlying index.  </p>
<p>BHP ended one cent lower at A$18.03, after reaching a high of A$18.22, on more than A$123 million worth of trade after unions announced mid-afternoon that they had voted to strike in protest at BHP's plan unveiled last week to close its steelworks in Newcastle.</p>
<p>&quot;It (BHP) is going to have some negatives in the short term,&quot; said Richard Nelson, fund manager at BNP Investment.</p>
<p>Brokers said there was also little support for the market above 2,500, which was another reason for the pullback.</p>
<p>&quot;Things don't look cheap here. I think we are seeing more on the sell side then the buy side at the moment,&quot; Nelson said.  </p>
<p>Nelson said the market is also steadying itself ahead of the Australia Federal budget on May 13.</p>
<p>Kerry Packer's media group Publishing and Broadcasting (PBL) posted the biggest fall amongst blue chips after PBL announced on Saturday it would not take an option to buy management control of Sydney Harbour Casino.</p>
<p>PBL fell more than three percent to close at A$6.45 as the market anticipated Packer's long awaited tilt at newspaper group John Fairfax.</p>
<p>Fairfax ended slightly up, while Sydney Harbour Casino closed steady.  </p>
<p>&quot;Maybe people think a casino is a better option for Packer than a newspaper,&quot; Nelson said.</p>
<p>There was a mild negative effect on the Australian gold sector after Bre-X released a consultant's report showing the Busang gold discovery in Indonesia had been massively falsified.</p>
<p>Shares in Golden Valley, which has a disputed claim on part of the Busang project, fell more than 26 percent to 38 cents after the Bre-X announcement.</p>
<p>Shares in Bougainville Copper surged on reports that secessionists rebels on Bougainville Island would consider re-opening the dormant Panguna copper mine on the island.  </p>
<p>The gold sector recorded the biggest fall amongst the major indices with more indices posting gains than falls.</p>
<p>FUTURES/OPTIONS - Futures saw reasonable activity as the SPI fell after opening strongly. Options trade was also stronger.</p>
<p>Total options traded 34,749 (26,581)</p>
<p>In other market news, Australian bond yields closed sharply lower as long end yields started to price in a market-friendly budget on May 13. By 5.05 p.m. (0705 GMT), 10 year T-bonds closed on a yield of 7.75 percent, down 11 basis points.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar spent the session building a base around US$0.7820 support ahead of an expected busy week.  </p>
<p>At 5.15 p.m. (0715 GMT), the dollar was trading at US$0.7824/29.</p>
<p>*BHP A$18.03 (-.01) 18.00/18.22 Vol: 6,853,610</p>
<p>BHP's shares lose earlier gains after unions vote to strike against BHP following its plans to close Newcastle steelworks.  </p>
<p>*Fairfax A$3.25 (+.02) 3.24/3.30 Vol: 1,063,871</p>
<p>Newspaper group up on speculation that media mogul Kerry Packer will make bid for Fairfax after he withdrew Sydney Casino deal.</p>
<p>*Sydney Casino A$2.16 (steady) 2.12/2.16 Vol: 2,668,864</p>
<p>*PBL A$6.45 (-.25) 6.45/6.72 Vol: 624,031.</p>
<p>PBL decides not to take option on buying a stake and management control of the Sydney Casino.</p>
<p>*Bougainville A$0.55 (+.11) 0.45/0.58 Vol: 280,111</p>
<p>Owner of the dormant Panguna copper mine up on reports that secessionist rebels would consider re-opening of the mine.</p>
<p>*Golden Valley A$0.38 (-.14) 0.38/0.52 Vol: 473,534</p>
<p>Shares tumble in gold hopeful, which has a disputed claim on part of the Busang project.</p>
<p>*Westpac A$7.15 (+.10) 7.09/7.16 Vol: 8,722,784.</p>
<p>Bank shares continue rise after Friday's buy-back announcement.</p>
<p>-- Kevin Morrison 61-2 9373-1813</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
