<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="561234" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia rubber closes down on poor sentiment.</title>
<headline>Malaysia rubber closes down on poor sentiment.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian rubber prices ended down after the market closed the day with virtually no trades reported, said dealers.</p>
<p>There were no sales or inquiries, the dealers said, adding that the closure of the Bangkok and Tokyo markets led to further uncertainties in pricing.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing happened today,&quot; said an official trade source. &quot;Maybe, we'll see something tomorrow.&quot;</p>
<p>The Malaysian Rubber Exchange and Licensing Board quoted June RSS One buyer at 275.50 cents ($1.10) a kg, down half cent from Friday. June SMR20 buyer was also half cent lower at 259.  </p>
<p>Trading houses offered the SMR CV at 332 cents, SMR L at 310 cents, SMR 5 at 269, SMR 10 at 255 and drum latex at 228 cents.</p>
<p>Dealers said prices were expected to fall further with the steady supply of latex after recent improvements in the weather.</p>
<p>The INRO five-day moving indicator was quoted at 208.05 Malaysian/Singaporean cents per kg on May 2, compared to the 208.10 on April 30. The daily indicator was, however, higher at 208.57 from 207.43 previously.</p>
<p>-- K. Baranee (603-230-7510) ($1=2.5080 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
