<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="561269" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Politician's lawyers sit out Singapore libel case.</title>
<headline>Politician's lawyers sit out Singapore libel case.</headline>
<byline>Raj Rajendran</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Singapore opposition politician instructed his lawyers on Monday not to participate in hearings to assess damages in 13 libel suits against him after they failed to get the case postponed.</p>
<p>Tang Liang Hong, a defeated candidate in Singapore's January 2 elections, was found to have libelled Prime Minister Goh Chok Tong and 10 other leaders of the ruling People's Action Party (PAP) in remarks he made during the election campaign and in subsequent interviews with the local media.</p>
<p>Goh's PAP won 81 of 83 parliament seats in the elections in which Tang was a major target of the ruling party's campaign, accusing him of being a &quot;Chinese chauvinist&quot; who threatened multi-racial harmony.</p>
<p>Tang called them liars and was swiftly sued by Goh and the others who said their integrity had been attacked. Shortly after the elections, Tang fled Singapore saying he had received death threats, and gave interviews from across the border in Malaysia.</p>
<p>He did not return to defend himself against the libel actions and the court awarded the cases to Goh and his PAP colleagues, setting May 5 as the date it would start hearing arguments on the amount of damages to be awarded.</p>
<p>Tang's lawyers, Peter Low and Loo Ngan Chor, said Tang faced financial ruin and needed time to bring in top London lawyer Charles Gray, who was not immediately available.</p>
<p>When that plea was rejected, Low and Loo said they were not the best lawyers to deal with the case and asked to be excused.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been instructed by our client not to participate in the proceedings,&quot; Low said.</p>
<p>The court accepted they would not argue for Tang but told them to stay as observers.</p>
<p>Davinder Singh, counsel for former prime minister Lee Kuan Yew who was among the PAP leaders who sued Tang, told the court they were seeking substantial damages because Tang had aggravated the libel.</p>
<p>He did not say how much they were asking, but early in the cases a court ordered Tang to set aside Singapore $11.2 million (US$7.8 million) in the event the suits went against him.</p>
<p>Singh charged that Tang had lied and committed criminal defamation and criminal conspiracy against the PAP leaders.</p>
<p>In one of the 13 suits, Tang was sued for saying he feared arrest under Singapore's Internal Security Act (ISA), which allows detention without trial for up to two years, when Goh said there was no reason for him to fear arrest.</p>
<p>In an interview with the Straits Times newspaper, Tang asked whether he could believe Goh's assurances.</p>
<p>In that judgement against Tang, Judge Lai Kew Chia said it suggested that Goh would use his power corruptly and illegally to arrest Tang under the ISA.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
