<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="561557" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Foundation Health, Physicians in acquisition talks.</title>
<headline>Foundation Health, Physicians in acquisition talks.</headline>
<byline>Andrea Orr</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foundation Health Systems Inc., the country's fourth-biggest managed care company, said Tuesday it is in talks to acquire Physicians Health Services Inc., which serves about 425,000 members in the Northeast.</p>
<p>Foundation, based in Rancho Cordova, Calif., said if a definitive deal is reached, the purchase price would be no more than $30 per share, which would work out to a total of about $279 million.</p>
<p>Wall Street analysts said $30 a share would be a &quot;full&quot; price for Trumbull, Conn.-based Physicians Health, which has struggled to implement a profitable operating strategy and last year lost close to $13 million. Despite the money-losing pattern, analysts said the company could bring Foundation a fairly simple means of advancing its strategy of penetrating the Northeastern market.</p>
<p>Foundation, whose operations spread across 19 states in the West, South and Northeast, has considered further penetration in the Northeast as central to its expansion strategy.</p>
<p>The managed care style of health care has been particularly slow to catch on in the Northeast, a region where health maintenance organizations still account for less than 25 percent of all health plans, compared with more than 40 percent in Foundation's home state of California.</p>
<p>&quot;Foundation's strategy is to be a fairly aggressive acquiror in the Northeast,&quot; said Volpe Welty analyst Ed Keaney. &quot;Despite Physician Health's recent losses, it could be a very profitable source of growth for Foundation.</p>
<p>&quot;The main attraction is that it's a relatively underpenetrated market. It's not that it's easier to complete an acquisition there, but the growth prospects are larger.&quot;</p>
<p>Keaney said Physicians Health's recent problems stemmed mainly from its failure to raise prices and to control medical utilization among members. He said Foundation has demonstrated an ability to control costs, which could help it reverse Physicians' money-losing pattern.</p>
<p>Moreover, said Josephthal Lyon &amp; Ross analyst Mary O'Connell, industry-wide trends are beginning to improve.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year, Physicians saw its margins squeezed in what was a fairly low-margin business to begin with. This year, there is a growing recognition that the underwriting cycle has started to turn.&quot;</p>
<p>Physicians Health's stock rose $3.75 to $26.625 on Nasdaq in afternoon trading. Foundation Health fell 75 cents to $27 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
