<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="561536" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Caledonia boosts South African mine output.</title>
<headline>Caledonia boosts South African mine output.</headline>
<dateline>OAKVILLE, Ontario 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Caledonia Mining Corp said on Tuesday that it boosted output and recoveries at its Barbrook Mine in South Africa, and increased its measured and indicated gold reserves.</p>
<p>Since it started up, Barbrook has increased recoveries to the 65-70 percent range which will rise as the milling process is improved.</p>
<p>Also, the measured and indicated gold reserves jumped in tonnage and grade from 1996. &quot;Measured reserves now stand at 913,000 tonnes at an undiluted grade of 6.52 g/t (grams per tonne) versus 478,000 tonnes at 5.09 g/t last year,&quot; it said. &quot;The indicated reserves have increased to 954,000 tonnes at 6.12 g/t this year from 219,000 tonnes at 6.5 g/t last year.&quot;</p>
<p>Barbrook's mineral resource stands at about 11 million tonnes at a grade of 6.48 g/t containing 2.3 million ounces of gold, it said.</p>
<p>In March and April the plant produced about 17,000 tonnes per month which surpassed expected targets. Ore grades to the million averaged 4.33 g/t. &quot;With the anticipated improvements, Barbrook should be profitable in the near future at present gold prices.&quot;</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OAKVILLE, Ontario"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
