<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="561942" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Conference Board sees fast US growth, higher rates.</title>
<headline>Conference Board sees fast US growth, higher rates.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. economy looks set to slow down in the second quarter but will re-accelerate in the latter half of this year, Conference Board chief economist Gail Fosler said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Echoing the results of a survey by the National Association of Purchasing Management, Fosler predicted a strong economy in 1997, with growth of 3.25 to 3.5 percent.</p>
<p>She told the purchasing managers she did not expect higher interest rates to be a threat to the economy, at least this year.  </p>
<p>The Federal Reserve raised interest rates in March for the first time in two years to keep the economy from growing too fast for its own good.</p>
<p>&quot;..therefore I think it's almost a foregone conclusion that the Fed will raise interest rates in May and then frankly I don't think they'll do very much until the second half of the year when the stubborness and durability of this economic environment really makes itself felt once again as it has early in the year,&quot; said Fosler.</p>
<p>With economic growth strong, Fosler sees a double-digit increase in corporate profits this year. That profit growth will be generated by both higher prices and bigger sales, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a decided effort to look for opportunities to raise prices,&quot; Fosler said, noting that companies' labor and energy costs are on the rise.</p>
<p>The strong dollar is likely to continue to cause difficulties for U.S. exporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar is going to continue to be a serious problem,&quot; Fosler said.</p>
<p>While it has probably peaked against the Japanese yen, the dollar will continue to rise versus the European currencies, she said. She projected the dollar would rise to 1.85 to 2.0 marks over the next year. The dollar is now trading just above 1.72 marks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
