<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="562237" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Historic British Commons chamber sees sea-change.</title>
<headline>Historic British Commons chamber sees sea-change.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's new members of parliament who arrive on Wednesday to take their seats after Labour's landslide election win will find a building designed for another era and a different political reality.</p>
<p>From the provision of toilets to the shape of the debating chamber, the facilities at the Palace of Westminster are ill-suited to the needs of the 659 MPs elected on Thursday.</p>
<p>It is not merely the scale of the Labour victory which will cause problems. There is also the fact that an unprecedented number of MPs are women -- almost double the 62 in the last parliament.</p>
<p>Unlike most modern parliamentary debating chambers, the Commons, designed in the mid-1800s, is not hemispherical in shape, but consists of two tiers of benches facing each other.</p>
<p>The front benches of each tier are exactly two swords' length apart, a reminder that two sides of roughly equal strength are expected to do verbal, if not physical, battle.</p>
<p>So a House containing a ruling party of 418 members, a Conservative opposition with just 165 and a substantial third force in the Liberal Democrats with 46 does not fit easily.</p>
<p>Already plans are being laid for some Labour members to sit on what would normally be opposition benches to alleviate the squash on the government side.</p>
<p>Already the Liberal Democrats have queried whether, following the Conservatives' failure to win a single seat in Scotland, they should occupy the opposition front bench when Scottish issues are being discussed.</p>
<p>Architecture seemingly designed to promote confrontation rather than cooperation is also unlikely to suit a House with almost a fifth of its members women.</p>
<p>&quot;Women are more co-operative in the way they work. They're not so into scoring points, and more interested in hearing different points of view...I think it's time to modernise Westminster,&quot; said new Labour MP Julia Drown.</p>
<p>New Prime Minister Tony Blair has already canvassed ideas for making debate more constructive, including reform of Prime Minister's question time, twice-weekly confrontations notorious in Britain for their bluster and lack of content.</p>
<p>The new intake of women is also sure to criticise the facilities in parliament, where there is a shooting range but no creche for children.</p>
<p>Other members who may find the &quot;mother of parliaments&quot; conceived in a Christian age a difficult place to operate include Labour's Mohammad Sarwar, elected Britain's first Muslim MP.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
