<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="562230" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Eurotunnel loses big claim.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Eurotunnel loses big claim.</headline>
<byline>Greg Mahlich</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Debt-laden Eurotunnel SA/Plc saw its hopes fade on Tuesday of getting the firms which built the Anglo-French subsea railway to help to dig it out of its deep financial hole.</p>
<p>The Transmanche Link (TML) consortium of tunnel contractors said that a &quot;Panel of Experts&quot; appointed to arbitrate on disputes with Eurotunnel had rejected the bulk of a 1.0 billion pound ($1.6 billion) claim made by Eurotunnel against TML.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel's claim was submitted to the Panel in December 1995. It alleged delays in deliveries and inadequacies in rolling stock supplied by TML for its Le Shuttle train service between Folkestone and Calais.</p>
<p>&quot;The Panel's decision does not recognise any merit in the majority of Eurotunnel's claims and they were rejected on both legal and factual grounds,&quot; TML said in a statement commenting on the Panel's 146-page judgement.</p>
<p>&quot;TML takes the view, therefore, that Eurotunnel's one billion pounds claim is nullified by the Panel's ruling.&quot;</p>
<p>The statement was released on behalf of TML by consortium member Tarmac Plc.</p>
<p>In its own response to the judgement Eurotunnel said that the Panel had decided the company was entitled to damages for deficiencies in some rolling stock supplied, but rejected claims for loss of revenue.</p>
<p>&quot;While recognising the merits of the majority of Eurotunnel's claims, the Panel declared a large number inadmissible on the basis of contractual principles which it judged applicable,&quot; Eurotunnel said in a statement.</p>
<p>Regarding damages for the rolling stock, the panel encouraged the parties to negotiate between themselves on the appropriate level of compensation, the company said.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel declined to specify how much of the billion-pound claim had been upheld by the Panel. TML said the figure was minor.</p>
<p>&quot;The Panel recommended that...Eurotunnel and TML should discuss the potential effect of problems arising from the performance of a particular sub-contractor and agreed that relatively minor sums might, at some future point, be due to Eurotunnel if certain conditions were met,&quot; TML said.</p>
<p>Under the project's disputes procedure the tunnel operator has 90 days to decide whether to appeal against the ruling to the Paris-based International Chamber of Commerce (ICC).</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the company told Reuters in Paris that it was dissatisfied with the Panel's decision and an appeal was likely.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel needs any compensation it can get to help to persuade its shareholders and creditor banks to agree to a restructuring of nearly nine billion pounds of debt.</p>
<p>&quot;Eurotunnel was expecting to get about a billion pounds in compensation from TML,&quot; said Richard Hannah, London-based transport analyst and Eurotunnel expert at investment bank UBS.</p>
<p>&quot;Reading the reaction from the two sides (to the Panel judgement) it now looks likely that any damages they receive will be substantially below that level,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel shares were unchanged at 70-1/2 pence in an overall firm London market, and were down five centimes at 6.65 francs in Paris.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 1717 542 7717($ = 0.618 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020039">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
