<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56220" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Colombo tea auction boom cuts exports to Britain.</title>
<headline>Colombo tea auction boom cuts exports to Britain.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lankan tea exports to Britain fell sharply this year as producers cut back their offerings at the London auction because of soaring prices in Colombo, brokers said on Monday.</p>
<p>Exports to London fell by 63 percent to 5.4 million kg in the first seven months of this year from a year earlier, brokers Forbes and Walkers said in a report.</p>
<p>&quot;This has resulted to a great extent from producers curtailing their offerings at the London auction consequent to the stronger performance of Colombo,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>The drop came just as Sri Lanka had begun recovering market share in Britain after losing primarily to Kenya, brokers said.</p>
<p>British buyers may also have been priced out of the Colombo auction, where prices have soared to record levels in recent months, propelled by heavy buying by the Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS), they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The CIS continues as the prime destination for Ceylon tea,&quot; said the Forbes report. Sri Lanka shipped three million kg to the CIS in July alone bringing total exports to the former Soviet Union to 24.3 million kg in the first seven months of the year from 21.4 in the same 1995 period, it said.  </p>
<p>Tea imports by Turkey rose sharply to 19.1 million kg in the seven months from 4.7 million kg a year ago, the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;Turkey has developed into a major gateway into neighbouring countries in the CIS,&quot; said a Forbes official. &quot;Turkey grows a large volume of tea but it is of low quality and consumed locally.&quot;</p>
<p>The report said tea exports to Iran almost doubled during the period to 7.1 million kg from 4.9 million kg a year ealrier.</p>
<p>Brokers said Iran and the United Arab Emirates, which bought almost nine million kg of tea in the seven months, also appeared to re-export much of the tea to its neighbours, brokers said.  </p>
<p>Sri Lankan tea export earnings shot up 38 percent to 18.4 billion rupees in January-July this year from 13.3 billion rupees in the same period last year, Forbes and Walker said.</p>
<p>Export earnings rose despite a slight fall in the export volume to 138.8 million kg in the first seven months of this year from 139.2 million kg shipped a year earlier, it said.</p>
<p>Officials attributed the drop in export volume to the uncertainty caused by the presidential poll in Russia which prompted buyers to hold back.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
