<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="562228" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-London and Frankfurt close at new peaks.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-London and Frankfurt close at new peaks.</headline>
<byline>Leonard Santorelli</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>London and Frankfurt stocks surged to close at record peaks on Tuesday despite faltering as Wall Street made an unsettled opening on profit-taking.</p>
<p>On currency markets the dollar ended the session weaker but sterling grabbed the limelight jumping to a 4-1/2 year high after Britain's new Labour government raised interest rates by a quarter of a percentage point and made sweeping monetary reforms.</p>
<p>London, lifted initially by a  blistering overnight rally in New York, soared to new trading peaks amid euphoria over the government's decision to grant the Bank of England freedom to set interest rates without political interference.</p>
<p>New finance minister Gordon Brown's decision to give the bank a level of independence was well received by investors, still uncertain about how tough a party last in power 18 years ago, would be on inflation and monetary policy.</p>
<p>The blue-chip FTSE 100 Index ended 63.7 points higher at a closing peak of 4,519.3 though it wobbled slightly as Wall Street fell at the opening -- only to claw its way back into profit within the first hour of trading.</p>
<p>Frankfurt floor trade ended at a record close of  3,568.28 points, eclipsing the previous best set only yesterday. But after-hours computerised transactions were rattled by Wall Street's weak start and finished down 0.5 percent.</p>
<p>In strong contrast, Paris, buffeted by political uncertainties, had a bad day, showing losses of 0.8 percent at the close.</p>
<p>The push for the initial advances in Europe came from New York's performance on Monday where stocks were lifted by hopes that a balanced budget agreement would keep the U.S. central bank from raising interest rates later this month.</p>
<p>But the London market was given an extra shove by Brown who ended uncertainty by making the small interest rate increase and giving the central bank independence to set interest rate policy.</p>
<p>&quot;It went far beyond what the market was hoping for,&quot; David Coleman, chief economist at Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce. &quot;Although this reform was expected in due course, it was not expected to take place so soon.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The rate rise had already been discounted but Brown is obviously trying to end the market's perception that Labour is a tax and spend party,&quot; the head of trading at a large brokerage said.</p>
<p>&quot;If he keeps spending under control in his first budget, the market might actually start to believe it. Today certainly has been a good start.&quot;</p>
<p>In Frankfurt, though floor trade ended at a new peak, computerised transactions had a rough time, hit by a see-sawing dollar and an uncertain Wall Street, before settling into calmer territory in the afternoon.</p>
<p>Prices had held steady or higher through the day until an initial weak opening on Wall Street and plunge by the dollar sent prices falling in low volume to show losses of 0.5 percent at the close.</p>
<p>&quot;It might be time to consolidate,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;It was alarming to see the market take such a beating today of all days.&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Paris stood out because of its poor performance, ending down 0.8 percent. French investors were clearly anxious over the outcome of the May 25-June 1 parliamentary election which polls suggest will be a tight race.</p>
<p>On currency markets, most  of the action was in sterling which made big gains after announcements about interest rate rise and policy independence for the Bank of England. The tightening was expected; the central bank news was not.</p>
<p>Sterling climbed almost two pfennigs and more than one cent after the interest rate rise announcement before falling back.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is looking more at the BOE independence measures than the rate rise and the forex market at least is taking the view that this will mean a tighter overall monetary policy than previously seen,&quot; said Peter Wood, trader at Bank of Boston. The stronger pound dragged up the dollar but comments from Ernst Welteke of the German central bank later unsettled the U.S. currency.</p>
<p>Welteke said the Bundesbank was well advised to maintain its steady interest rate policy, and said the bank would not welcome a further rise in the dollar.</p>
<p>The dollar also fell against the yen. Fears about an interest rate rise in Japan are growing and the yen gained against both the dollar and mark overnight while Japanese government bond yields pushed higher.</p>
<p>STOCKS PRICES</p>
<p>London's FTSE 100 ended up 63.7 points at 4,519.3.</p>
<p>The Paris CAC-40 index finished down 20.91 points at 2,651.93.</p>
<p>Frankfurt's DAX index closed up 39.50 points at 3,568.28.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES</p>
<p>The dollar stood at  1.7220 marks in late European trading compared with 1.7286 marks on Monday. It was at 125.45 yen, compared to 126.62 on Monday.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold ended at  $342.95 an ounce, compared to Friday's close in London of $340.05. Silver was $4.75, up two cents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
