<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56235" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Barney's Inc. seeks to protect potential investor.</title>
<headline>Barney's Inc. seeks to protect potential investor.</headline>
<byline>Robin Sidel</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bankrupt Barney's Inc. will go to court Thursday to protect the identity of an outside investor who has expressed interest in the luxury retailer.</p>
<p>Barney's is asking U.S. Bankruptcy Court Judge James Garrity to seal documents relating to the potential investor, who is demanding to remain anonymous and also is asking the bankrupt retailer to pay for its financial review of the company, according to court papers filed last week.</p>
<p>Barney's, parent of Barneys New York, has been in bankruptcy since January.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential investor has participated in numerous sessions with (Barney's) regarding its proposed investment and has prepared a written preliminary proposal letter outlining the terms of its proposed investment ...&quot; Barney's said in the court papers.</p>
<p>Barney's creditors also have received the letter.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential investor has expressly required that it remain anonymous and has made clear that if its identity, or the terms of the preliminary proposal letter, are disclosed publicly, it will nor proceed with the offer,&quot; according to the papers.</p>
<p>The motion faces opposition from Barney's business partner Isetan Co. Ltd., which has joined with Saks Holdings Inc. to consider a plan to take control of Barney's.</p>
<p>&quot;Isetan disagrees with the notion that a secret bidder can keep its identity anonymous,&quot; said Isetan attorney David LeMay of law firm Hughes Hubbard &amp; Reed, noting that the Japanese company does not know the identity of the potential investor.</p>
<p>Although Isetan and Barney's are business partners, their relationship has turned acrimonious and they are locked in a legal dispute.</p>
<p>Barney's said in the papers that the potential investor is seeking to be reimbursed for the due diligence because it believes Saks has an unfair advantage due to the relationship between Isetan and Barney's.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Saks could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>A Barney's spokeswoman declined to comment on the anticipated cost for the due diligence process.</p>
<p>According to the papers, the investor has held numerous discussions with Barney's about the proposed investment since February, when it was contacted by Barney's financial adviser, The Blackstone Group.</p>
<p>A top executive for Saks told Reuters in July that he expected other bidders to express interest in Barney's. Also in July, Hong Kong retailer Dickson Concepts Holdings Ltd. disclosed that it was considering a bid.</p>
<p>Barney's also has acknowledged other bidding interest.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
