<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="562478" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech PM Klaus says sees Q1 GDP at about 0.0 pct.</title>
<headline>Czech PM Klaus says sees Q1 GDP at about 0.0 pct.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus on Tuesday said he expected real GDP growth for the first quarter to be &quot;about zero percent&quot;, year-on-year, after growth of 4.6 percent in the first three months of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't be surprised if we will be somewhere around zero percent (GDP),&quot; Klaus said at a lecture at the Prague School of Economics. &quot;I suppose the acceleration of growth (GDP) in 1998 will be somewhere between 3-4 percent,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Industrial output in the Czech Republic contracted in the first two months of 1997.</p>
<p>The trade deficit hit a record 160.3 billion crowns in 1996, and is expected to surge to some 200 billion this year.</p>
<p>The Czech economy recorded real growth of 4.4 percent in 1996, but a downturn in industry has sent economists scrambling to revise their forecasts downward.</p>
<p>On April 16, the government announced a series of economic measures aimed at reviving the economy while easing pressures from a burgeoning trade deficit and rising wages.</p>
<p>During the announcement, Klaus said he would consider it a success if Czech real GDP growth was 2.7 percent, one-half of the government's original estimate for 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
