<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="562499" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks mixed, no changes forseen.</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks mixed, no changes forseen.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks traded mixed in livelier business on Tuesday, and market participants said prices were likely to hover around current levels in the next few weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't expect any major leaps on the market. We are more likely to see trading on higher volumes than any important price changes,&quot; said Igor Kos of Taurus brokerage.</p>
<p>He said there were not many foreign investors who could boost the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Buyers will have to make their decision at these levels. They can't wait for sellers to lower the offers,&quot; Marijana Reskovac of Karlovacka Banka said.</p>
<p>Seven of 18 active stocks rose, eight fell and three were flat. Volume more than tripled to 11,386 shares, turnover also rose to 5.4 million kuna from Friday's 1.2 million.</p>
<p>Top gainer Adriatic oil pipeline operator Janaf climbed 800 kuna to 6,400, selling 43 shares.</p>
<p>Biggest decliner hotelier Istraturist lost 12 kuna to 193, with 180 shares changing hands.</p>
<p>Most active food processor Podravka inched up one kuna to 305 on volume of 3,879 units.</p>
<p>All fully-listed stocks were decliners. Drugs firm Pliva inched down one kuna to 484, selling 2,216 shares. Zagrebacka Banka ordinary shares edged down 30 kuna to 2,170, selling 41 units.</p>
<p>Varazdinska Banka first issue lost 1,500 kuna to 44,500 but on a poor volume of two shares. Its second issue dipped 50 kuna to 1,200, with 50 units sold.</p>
<p>Traders singled out textile firm Varteks as a possible gainer, following the company's announcement last week that the U.S. giant Levi Strauss would extend its licence for producing jeans for another five years.</p>
<p>Varteks added seven kuna to 92 on Tuesday, selling 364 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Varteks is a proof that our market has started reacting to announcements made by companies,&quot; Reskovac said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
