<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="562530" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia to issue franc-denominated Eurobond.</title>
<headline>Russia to issue franc-denominated Eurobond.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia hopes to issue a French franc-denominated Eurobond, First Deputy Prime Minister Anatoly Chubais said in a magazine interview published on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are counting on the fact that after having solved the issue of debt to France we shall enter the franc market,&quot; Chubais said in an interview in Kommersant magazine. &quot;The volume of our potential on the international finance markets is immense.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman for Chubais was unable to comment on the text of the interview, but said it was based on conversations with Chubais on his flights to and from Washington to last week's International Monetary Fund and World Bank meetings.  </p>
<p>Last year Russia signed an agreement with France to repay around $400 million to some 400,000 French holders of Tsarist bonds, which were issued before the 1917 Bolshevik revolution, ending a long-standing dispute with French investors.</p>
<p>Chubais said Russia was shifting the focus of its debt policy to international from domestic borrowing.</p>
<p>Russia issued its debut $1 billion Eurobond in November. It was priced to yield 345 basis points over U.S. Treasuries. The second issue, denominated in marks, was priced at 370 bp over Bunds.</p>
<p>Russia plans to issue one more dollar-denominated Eurobond in May to be followed by at least one other issue in autumn.</p>
<p>Chubais said the cost of borrowing on the international markets was 10 to 15 percent for Russia.</p>
<p>On the domestic government securities market yields at the latest auctions were around 30 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We are set to conquer European markets, and ... foreign capital will come to us, but not through GKO (discount Treasury bills) but through Eurobonds,&quot; Chubais said.</p>
<p>--Julie Tolkacheva, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
