<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="562612" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia Alfa Capital says Omsk telecom longterm buy.</title>
<headline>Russia Alfa Capital says Omsk telecom longterm buy.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian regional telecom Omskelektrosvyaz is a good long-term buy though currently overvalued against its peers, Alfa Capital investment bank said in an April 25 report by analyst Kristen Burton Steiner.</p>
<p>Liquidity is limited, with only about nine percent free float for the unlisted Siberian telecom, and large spreads erode short-term investment profit potential, but shares trading at around $0.60 could be valued at $26.79, Alfa calculated.</p>
<p>The telecom's price earnings ratio, at 28.97 by Alfa's estimate, is high compared to peer Volgogradelektrosvyaz's 13.50 and 27.19 for heavyweight Moscow City Telephone(MGTS).</p>
<p>But price to sales ratio, which Alfa says does not show the effect on earnings of the company's efforts to increase depreciation in order to lower taxes, is 1.45 compared to Volgograd's 2.12 and 3.67 for MGTS.</p>
<p>Omskelektrosvyaz's revenue per access line compares well with regional and major telecoms, while revenues per employee are above regional peers but less than half those of MGTS.</p>
<p>Alfa said profits would shrink in 1997 but begin to grow in 1998 based on a growing economy, the introduction of local charge metering due to begin phasing in this year and revenues from cellular and other value-added ventures.</p>
<p>Management is open, aggressive and working to replace obsolete equipment, Alfa said.</p>
<p>--Peter Henderson, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
