<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="562605" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - May 6.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - May 6.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the reports carried by Estonia's newspapers on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- Parliament is debating a law on special pensions and other social guarantees for high government officials and deputies.</p>
<p>- The Coalition Party, the leading ruling party, recommended Ivi Eenmaa, director of the national library, as candidate for mayor of Tallinn and she has accepted the proposal.</p>
<p>SONUMILEHT</p>
<p>- Priit Saksing, former director of the Silmet metal processing plant, accused the Coalition Party of persecuting him in connection with an accusation of embezzlement.</p>
<p>EESTI PAEVALEHT</p>
<p>- The European Union commission is dissatisfied with the internal security in Estonia and would place Estonia in a third group of candidates for admission to the EU, diplomats warn.</p>
<p>POSTIMEES</p>
<p>- Police director Ain Seppik called for reinforced security measures for government officials.</p>
<p>- New Interior Minister Robert Lepikson is expected to make major changes in the ministry and the police department.</p>
<p>ARIPAEV</p>
<p>- Former tax department director Ardo Ojasalu is currently offering companies tax factoring services.</p>
<p>- The management of the Hotel Viru is ready to finance a 15-storey expansion worth 150 million kroons. Building may begin next year.</p>
<p>- Uhispank and an investment firm have founded a company for business in the Russian securities market.</p>
<p>-- Riga newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
