<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="562628" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil wins court boost in CVRD sale battle.</title>
<headline>Brazil wins court boost in CVRD sale battle.</headline>
<byline>Fatima Cristina</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Brazilian government won a crucial boost on Monday in its battle to privatise mining giant Companhia Vale do Rio Doce (CVRD) when a high court threw out a series of legal challenges.</p>
<p>Officials said two or three injunctions remained blocking Latin America's largest state sell-off to date from taking place but government lawyers would rush to contest them on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Tomorrow perhaps we will have good news,&quot; said Jose Pio Borges, privatisation director of the National Development Bank, which runs Brazil's privatisation programme.</p>
<p>The sale of 45 percent of CVRD's voting stock was due to have begun on April 29 but has been delayed repeatedly by court action.</p>
<p>The government appealed to the Superior Court of Justice in Brasilia, the country's highest court for non-constitutional matters, arguing that all lawsuits should be considered by a single tribunal because of a &quot;conflict of interpretation&quot;.</p>
<p>An official at the court said Justice Democrito Reinaldo agreed with the government's view, quashing all the injunctions included in the government's petition and naming a federal court in Rio de Janeiro as the tribunal responsible for all new cases.</p>
<p>Borges, however, said two or three injunctions remained.</p>
<p>&quot;Tomorrow we will examine how best to overturn these injunctions,&quot; Borges told reporters, adding the government could either appeal to a federal court in Rio de Janeiro or ask the Superior Court of Justice to extend its ruling to the new cases.</p>
<p>Brazil hopes to raise at least $5 billion from the sale of the world's largest iron ore exporter, making it the biggest Latin American privatisation to date.</p>
<p>But the sell-off of the jewel in the Brazilian public sector's crown has been controversial.</p>
<p>Demonstrators clashed with police in downtown Rio last week and a chorus of criticism has risen from past presidents, Catholic bishops and the judiciary.</p>
<p>Monday's O Globo newspaper said the delay was beginning to irritate the leader of one of the two consortia bidding.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very unpleasant situation,&quot; Globo quoted Antonio Ermirio de Moraes, chief executive of Brazil's largest private conglomerate Votorantim, as saying. Votorantim heads the Valecom consortium together with South Africa's Anglo American Corp.</p>
<p>Moraes said Brazil was putting on a &quot;Third World show&quot; and complained that the delay was costing his partners money.</p>
<p>According to Globo, the government also was losing out, having had to spend $280,000 on the documents for its high court case alone.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
