<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="562715" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil Ag Min has not heard about soybean/meal tax.</title>
<headline>Brazil Ag Min has not heard about soybean/meal tax.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's Agriculture Ministry has heard nothing about talk of a new tax on soybeans and soymeal which hit soybeans and soymeal prices earlier today in Chicago, a spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have heard absolutely nothing about a tax,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>She added however that the matter would not be handled by the Agriculture Ministry but by the Finance or Industry and Commerce Ministries.</p>
<p>Officials from both ministries were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Traders also expressed surprise at the rumors which they attributed to the expectation Brazil may have to import more soybeans later in the year than originally forecast because of high exports at the start of the season.</p>
<p>But they could see no reason for the government to impose any taxes to slow down the flow of soybeans as it has been basing its expectations on an improving trade balance in 1997 on record revenue from the country's soycomplex exports.</p>
<p>&quot;First I heard from Chicago about a tax on soybeans. When I asked around, people burst out laughing. Then I heard it was also soymeal - the laugh was louder,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>Brazilian consultant Safras e Mercado has estimated that Brazilian soybean exports could reach up to seven million tonnes out of a total crop of 26.2 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Given world supply is expected to be greater - and therefore prices lower - when Brazil needs to import later in the year, traders are taking advantage of the current higher international levels to sell overseas.</p>
<p>&quot;People are making the most of international prices. There will be plenty of stocks when they need to buy later on,&quot; one dealer said.  </p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, no-one is talking about a lack of stocks. But even if the government is worried about a supply problem, all it has to do is commit traders to buy back for future shipment at the same time as they sell,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>This is not the first time there has been talk about a tax but the suggestion has previously been rejected by the Agriculture Ministry.</p>
<p>((-Caroline Bulloch, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 5074151))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
