<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="562813" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia state says Century zinc mine to go ahead.</title>
<headline>Australia state says Century zinc mine to go ahead.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Premier of the Australian state of Queensland Rob Borbidge had accepted the 12 signatures of Aboriginal claimants as final agreement for the A$1 billion Century zinc mine in the state's northwest to proceed, a premier's office spokesman said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The premier has accepted the 12 claimants' signatures and the signature of the Century Zinc Ltd and has called a special Cabinet meeting for tomorrow afternoon,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Century Zinc is owned by Anglo-Australian mining giant RTZ Corp Plc-CRA Ltd.  </p>
<p>&quot;The premier said he will be recommending to state Cabinet that the government's A$30 million aid package for Aborigines be put back on the table,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The 12 Aboriginal groups who had been in dispute over development of the Century Zinc mine signed up for the deal late last week.</p>
<p>Talks on the mine's development collapsed in February following failure by the parties to obtain the signatures of all the Aboriginal groups who were claiming land rights on areas surrounding the mine and Queensland withdrew its aid package offer.  </p>
<p>The Century zinc mine project would subsequently be a commercial agreement between the company and the Aboriginal claimants, the premier's spokesman said.</p>
<p>RTZ-CRA spokesman Greg Walker said the company was now looking forward to completing the necessary transactions and proceeding with the mine's development.</p>
<p>RTZ-CRA said on Friday it would be prepared to make available a separate A$60 million aid package for Aboriginal land holders.</p>
<p>&quot;We are obviously delighted and very pleased at the agreement being foreshadowed by the government,&quot; Walker said.  </p>
<p>An official announcement from the state government was expected on Wednesday, the premier's spokesman said.</p>
<p>In January, Pasminco Ltd said it would buy the Century mine and nearby Dugald River zinc projects from RTZ-CRA for A$345 million, conditional on Queensland issuing mine leases which depended on Aboriginal groups resolving the impasse over land tenure.</p>
<p>Pasminco had previously planned to buy half of the mine's annual output of 780,000 tonnes of low iron-bearing concentrates to feed its Budel zinc smelter in the Netherlands.  </p>
<p>It later agreed to purchase the project, pending claim-free title to the site and access to land covering a slurry pipeline leading to a port on the Gulf of Carpentaria.</p>
<p>Century's development is crucial to the continued operation of the Budel smelter, whose current operating licence from the Netherlands authorities requires it to cease generating hazardous jarosite zinc residue.</p>
<p>If development work was to start on the mine in the next few months, production could commence in the latter part of the year 2000, Century Zinc has said.  </p>
<p>Pasminco has said the collapse of talks in February were potentially damaging, but it could still meet its deadline if things progressed within the six months from that month.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
