<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="562856" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: U.K. rejecting most late HK requests for passports.</title>
<headline>U.K. rejecting most late HK requests for passports.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain said on Tuesday it was rejecting most late applications from Hong Kong people seeking British National Overseas (BNO) passports but would consider objections raised by local legislators to the move.</p>
<p>&quot;We are accepting late applications from the...quite a small number of people who are able to establish that there were special circumstances why they could not apply for that BNO passport within that deadline,&quot; Francis Cornish, Senior Trade Commissioner at the British Trade Commission, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;But the vast majority of late applicants made absolutely no pretence that they have a special case,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>About three million of Hong Kong's 6.4 million people hold some type of limited British passport such as the BNO, which grants no residency rights in Britain but offers some consular protection and travel convenience.</p>
<p>The rest of the territory's people hold only a local travel document that confers no nationality. A number of residents -- estimated at 750,000 -- hold full passports from countries such as Canada, Australia and the United States. The BNO issue is critical for Hong Kong people who do not hold passports. The British colony reverts to Chinese rule at midnight on June 30, after which Hong Kong will issue a passport which is not yet recognised by many countries.</p>
<p>The commission, which took over the job of processing BNO applications from Hong Kong's Immigration Department on April 1, was considering about 85 submissions a day from people claiming special circumstances, Cornish said.</p>
<p>He said the commission was accepting late applications from about 500 people who had already begun the process with the Immigration Department as well as parents of children born in 1996 whose deadline was March 31.</p>
<p>In a meeting with Cornish, Hong Kong legislators urged Britain to grant the passports to late applicants.</p>
<p>Legislator James To said more than 1,000 late applications had been submitted since April 1.</p>
<p>He said legislators would consider writing to British Prime Minister Tony Blair and Foreign Secretary Robin Cook if they received no reply from Cornish by Friday.</p>
<p>Cornish said he &quot;would reflect very carefully on the views&quot; the legislators expressed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
