<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="562946" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: FOCUS-Kuwait investors undeterred by crash talk.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Kuwait investors undeterred by crash talk.</headline>
<byline>Ashraf Fouad</byline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investors in the Arab world's liveliest bourse appreared undeterred despite repeated warnings of a crash with the Kuwait Stock Exchange index edging back up on Tuesday towards recent record levels.</p>
<p>&quot;Things are back to usual and people are buying after increased talk of a crash,&quot; said a Western-educated analyst of Tuesday's $270 million trading value during the 2-1/2 session.</p>
<p>The KSE index closed on Tuesday 21.3 points up at 2,330.4, just 24.3 points below the April 27 record. It lost 3.3 percent on Saturday and Sunday before climbing back up on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is concern with the market running away like this and we are wondering what is supporting this market?&quot; added the leading analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Fears of a correction emerged late last year as trading value soared above $160 million a day but talk of a crash, including by MPs, gained steam when the daily value hit $414 million and the index set the new record of 2,354.7.</p>
<p>&quot;Do we see a crash? We do not, but a correction yes.&quot; said the analyst. &quot;We don't see the market continuing at this rate.</p>
<p>&quot;If I had the money I won't play this market,&quot; added the analyst. Only Gulf Arabs can trade on the KSE while Kuwait's foreign residents can participate through Kuwaiti funds.</p>
<p>Several analysts and MPs claim that in some cases trade is not driven by fundamentals but by heavy speculation and a group of key investors manipulating the market to raise prices.</p>
<p>&quot;There are people behind this not real trading,&quot; said leading Kuwaiti economist Jassem al-Saadoun.</p>
<p>Another analyst said &quot;there are some people collaborating, it is a pool mentality. Where is the real growth? Is this (rise) backed by fundamentals? I think not. Kuwaitis are speculators by nature...This market has its own psychology and its own engine.&quot;</p>
<p>Saadoun, who also predicts a correction, said caution was needed as the recent KSE records came at a time &quot;when there are no surprises with annual results for 1996 already out and (Kuwait's) revenues are lower with weaker (world) oil prices.&quot;</p>
<p>Kuwait's 1996 gross domestic product is estimated by some economists at around $27 billion while the KSE, which has 66 listed firms, has market capitalisation of about $24 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;As a percentage, this is very high and also take into consideration a very important factor: None of these (listed) companies have a claim on the country's oil resources,&quot; said the analyst of the state's firm grip on the strategic industry which generates most of Kuwait's revenue.</p>
<p>The word crash revives memories of the 1982 collapse of Kuwait's unregulated Manakh bourse, resulting in a debt of over $20 billion which the government is still trying to resolve.</p>
<p>The state at the time stepped in to buy shares in many concerns which it is now selling in the first phase of a privatisation programme that would eventually include the more controversial, heavily-susidised public utilities.</p>
<p>Saadoun told Reuters that both MPs and the government were wrong to recently issue conflicting remarks on the market. Kuwait's central bank governor and finance minister were both quoted on Tuesday as saying they saw no danger of a crash, stressing that the situation was &quot;reassuring&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The bourse's situation does not call for any fear&quot; Governor Sheikh Salem Abdul-Aziz al-Sabah told al-Qabas daily but it could &quot;require the development of regulatory and dealing systems and rules governing the listing of new firms on the KSE.&quot;</p>
<p>As the market set new records, KSE Director-General Hisham al-Oteibi told Reuters last Tuesday: &quot;Normally after a rise there are correction moves...They are always a possibility and are expected but not a crash...No way, impossible.&quot;</p>
<p>Jassem Saadoun said comforting official statements could attract more investors &quot;to rush into the market. What is needed is caution not exagerrations (of a crash) nor down playing.&quot;</p>
<p>He says although the market was not expected to go through a Manakh-like crisis it could face a stiuation with negative social and political impacts, harming many small investors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
