<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56312" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Over-regulation, price hamper Europe's IT business.</title>
<headline>Over-regulation, price hamper Europe's IT business.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Neil Winton, Science and Technology Correspoondent</p>
<p>Demand for information technology in Europe will stagnate unless the roadblocks of over-regulation and high prices are removed, the world's biggest personal computer maker said Monday.</p>
<p>Eckhard Pfeiffer, chairman and chief executive officer of Compaq Computer Corp of the U.S., said the convergence of computing and telecommunications was being hampered in Europe by regulation.</p>
<p>&quot;Convergence has brought together the largely unregulated computer companies with the historically hyper-regulated telecoms industry, and this is slowing growth for the first time,&quot; Pfeiffer said in a speech to IDG's &quot;European IT Forum&quot;.</p>
<p>Pfeiffer told the conference the fragmented nature of European markets was also a drag on business.</p>
<p>&quot;In our new notebook computer, we've had to incorporate 19 individual cable modems for Europe,&quot; Pfeiffer said.</p>
<p>Prices in Europe are also significantly higher in Europe, Pfeiffer said.</p>
<p>IDG, the U.S. information technology consultancy and publisher, has said that European personal computer buyers pay an average 23 percent more for the same machine than in the U.S., before taxes, After taxes the figure soars to 34 percent.</p>
<p>Pfeiffer said that the Internet, the world-wide network of computers linked by telephone lines, also faces gridlock unless telephone line capacity is improved.</p>
<p>Pfeiffer didn't hold out much hope that these problems would be solved soon.</p>
<p>&quot;The dawning era of the wired consumer will only happen if progress is made on the cost of ownership and ease of use. The problem must be solved,&quot; Pfeiffer said in his speech.</p>
<p>&quot;These issues are complex. We are trying to get progress, but these things are not done overnight,&quot; Pfeiffer told Reuters after his speech.</p>
<p>Pfeiffer, in his speech, said that the mass market for computers will never materialise unless basic problems are addressed. Personal computers were too expensive and too difficult to use, admitted Pfeiffer.</p>
<p>Pfieffer was sharing the platform with Scott McNealy, President and Chief Executive Officer of U.S. software powerhouse Sun Microsystems Inc.</p>
<p>McNealy has been a powerful advocate of the so-called Network Computer, a stripped down personal computer which dials up computing power from a telephone line, rather than having an expensive, built-in processor.</p>
<p>The computer industry has been riven by arguments about the most sensible direction it should take. Software giant Microsoft Corp has advocated ever more powerful computers.  McNealy, and Oracle Corp chairman Larry Ellison have criticised the PC as an over elaborate, opaque device.</p>
<p>Pfeiffer said that although he felt the Network Computer was not the panacea its advocates suggested, Compaq would enter this market if demand was there.</p>
<p>The Network Computer would be useful for unsophisticated tasks like transaction data processing, or for consumers with simple needs, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Network Computer strikes a chord because of the shortcomings of the PC. Compaq fully embraces the network computer, but in no sense is this a replacement for the PC,&quot; Pfeiffer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Progress will come, not by scaling back the PC, but by incorporating uses like the telephone, tape recorder and cell phones all in one place. This Personal Information Appliance should be as easy to use as the phone and as intuitive as a TV,&quot; Pfeiffer said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
