<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="563185" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs and pork bellies end up sharply.</title>
<headline>CME hogs and pork bellies end up sharply.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Short covering and new demand prompted by ideas cash product prices may be ready to turn higher lifted CME hog and pork belly futures for sharp gains, traders said.</p>
<p>Hogs closed 1.025 cent per lb higher to unchanged with June up most at 84.525 cents. Frozen bellies posted gains of 2.300 to 1.200 cents with July up 2.250 at 89.950 cents.</p>
<p>Short covering and demand from cash connected houses increased as indications on cash hog markets turned bullish in light of continued light hog marketings and talk that some pork products may be firming, traders said.</p>
<p>Cash calls for Wednesday firmed from steady early in the day Tuesday to $0.50 to $1.00 per cwt higher by late in the trading session based on the light runs. The Iowa-Southern Minnesota hog run totaled an estimated 88,000 head Monday versus 95,000 projected and Wednesday's run will likely be under the 90,000 estimated, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;These (farmers) are all out in the fields and they're saying we are not going to see very many hogs (marketed) tomorrow,&quot; said Chuck Levitt, senior livestock analyst for Alaron Trading Corp.  </p>
<p>&quot;There is also some talk that the (cash) loin market is beginning to stabilize,&quot; Levitt added.</p>
<p>Rand Financials notably bought June and July during the day with locals actively covering short positions early in the session. Buy stops added to the advance. In hog options, Saul Stone bought August 88 calls and locals bought the 82 June straddle and sold the 85 straddle, pit sources said.</p>
<p>Pork bellies also ran up on local short covering with pit talk that the out-of-town will likely show another large out-movement last week added to strength and touching off buy stops, traders said.</p>
<p>Analysts estimated an unchanged to out 200,000 lb out-movemnt in the CME weekly out-of-town storage report. But traders reported talk of up to 1.0 million lbs out.</p>
<p>After the close, the CME reported an net out-movement of 952,000 lbs.</p>
<p>Expectations the cash market may have also reached a bottom added to support. Cash bellies ranged down to $72 per cwt at noon, lowest level since April 8, but this encouraged increased interest for cash, especially with futures providing a hedge for storage interests, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The fresh market may have had it on the downside. The spread between the cash and futures now in the bellies is enough for the warehousemen to come in and clean up the fresh offerings,&quot; Levitt said.</p>
<p>Delivery concerns weighed on May early, but the storage concerns and potential for higher prices later on a seasonal basis provide support and it also ended higher.</p>
<p>&quot;You need to take the physical bellies in May, then when you get that cash inversion in June you can start merchandising the frozen bellies for more than what the board is at,&quot; said Rich Tokheim from Investment Research Company.</p>
<p>Hog kills decline at the end of June and beginning of July and if slicers wait to take the bellies at the end of July, through deliveries, it will be too late to merchandise them before hog slaughter starts to rise seasonally in August.  May will gain on July and August later when early month delivery concerns abate, Tokheim added.</p>
<p>E.D.&amp;F. Man and RBH bought July late while LFG sold. Rand Financials and R.J. O'Brien bought July early, pit sources said.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
