<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="563264" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sister of accused bomber told of &quot;something big&quot;.</title>
<headline>Sister of accused bomber told of &quot;something big&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Judith Crosson</byline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The sister of accused Oklahoma City bomber Timothy McVeigh testified on Tuesday her brother wrote her before the bombing that &quot;something big is going to happen&quot; and that she burned the letter on his instructions.</p>
<p>Jennifer McVeigh, 23, completing 2 1/2 hours of testimony over two days, broke down in tears when describing how the FBI threatened to charge her with treason unless she cooperated. She testified under a grant of immunity from prosecution.</p>
<p>She told the court she received a letter from her brother in early 1995 telling her &quot;something big is going to happen in the month of the bull&quot; -- an astrological reference that she said meant March or April. But she later corrected herself to say the time period began April 20.</p>
<p>In matter-of-fact tones, she said her brother told her to burn the letter and she added that she did so the day she received it. But she said she did not know what her brother was referring to in the letter and that she never asked him.</p>
<p>She lost her business-like manner during cross- examination, weeping at times and insisting throughout that she had no knowledge of her brother being involved in the bombing or that it was going to happen.</p>
<p>But she added that before going on vacation to Florida a week before the bombing, she packed up her brother's military records, political literature and personal items and took them to a friend's house because &quot;from what had been indicated, I thought something might happen while I was on vacation.&quot;</p>
<p>When she heard her brother had been arrested in the bombing, she &quot;smoked a lot of cigarettes&quot; and destroyed some clippings he had sent her from the right-wing, anti-semitic novel &quot;The Turner Diaries&quot; because she was frightened.</p>
<p>She said she received a second letter on March 25, 1995, three weeks before the April 19, 1995, bombing of the Alfred P. Murrah federal building in Oklahoma City that killed 168 people. That letter asked if she had burned the first letter.</p>
<p>Under cross-examination by defence attorney Rob Nigh, she described an ordeal at the hands of FBI agents who questioned her for up to nine hours a day for eight days straight after her brother had been charged.</p>
<p>She broke down crying as she described the FBI offices in Buffalo, New York, where she was interrogated, saying she saw big photographs of herself and her brother on the walls with the crimes they both could be charged with listed next to their picture.</p>
<p>She was told she could be charged with treason, but not told she could only be charged with treason during a war.</p>
<p>&quot;They told me he was guilty and (they said) he was going to fry,&quot; Jennifer McVeigh testified. McVeigh has pleaded not guilty to planning and carrying out the bombing and, if convicted, faces the death penalty.</p>
<p>A conservatively dressed student who attends Buffalo State College in Buffalo, she flashed her brother a big smile when she walked into the courtroom.</p>
<p>She also testified about a computer file her brother created on her computer, called &quot;ATF-READ,&quot; referring to the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms. In it McVeigh called the federal agents &quot;tyrannical mother f-----&quot; who would someday &quot;swing in the wind.&quot;</p>
<p>The government contends McVeigh bombed the building in revenge for a government raid on the Branch Davidian compound in Waco, Texas. In the 1993 assault, cult leader David Koresh and about 80 followers perished in a fire and prosecutors say McVeigh blamed the government for their deaths.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
