<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56321" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Markka ERM peg at present levels seen drawing near.</title>
<headline>Markka ERM peg at present levels seen drawing near.</headline>
<byline>Peter Starck</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen on Monday indicated a decision to link the Finnish markka to the European Exchange Mechanism (ERM) was drawing near and the central parity exchange rate would be on the firm side, analysts said.</p>
<p>Lipponen was quoted as telling a regional newspaper that the time was ripe to decide in the near future about a link to the European currency grid within which some European currencies float.</p>
<p>He also suggested there would be no official attempt to influence the central parity rate at which the markka was fixed in the ERM.</p>
<p>&quot;The level of the markka cannot be manipulated. It would be noticed immediately and it would weaken the confidence in Finland,&quot; the paper quoted Lipponen as saying. &quot;He indicated that a fix could happen at stronger levels than earlier thought,&quot; said Interbank economist Sampsa Laine.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be below 3.05 (markka per German mark). What he said could even be interpreted as making possible a peg below 3.03.&quot;</p>
<p>The reaction on the foreign exchange market on Monday morning supported this conclusion, analysts said.</p>
<p>The markka strengthened as Finnish exporters began to convert foreign currency earnings into markka having taken the prime minister at his word and stopped hoping for a weaker ERM peg, the analysts said.</p>
<p>At 0930 GMT, the markka was at 3.018 against the German mark having traded well above 3.02 before news broke of Lipponen's comments. It closed at 3.0225 last Friday.</p>
<p>But Pertti Thornberg, analyst at Enskilda, said nothing specific about the markka's central parity exchange rates in ERM should be read into the prime minister's comments.</p>
<p>&quot;The level could be 3.02 (markka per mark), or it could be 3.06 or 3.07,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Of eight analysts polled by Reuters, six now expect the link to take place soon. But they noted that Lipponen had not given any clear clue about the timing.</p>
<p>Handelsbanken Finland chief economist Carlo Erakallio said he still expected the linking of the markka to the ERM to take place later this autumn with November the likeliest month.</p>
<p>But the government may opt to make a quick formal decision in favour of a peg and so reaffirm its commitment to European economic and monetary union (EMU), he said.</p>
<p>Some of the analysts said the right time to link the markka could be in connection with the coming weekend's meeting of EU finance and economy ministers in Dublin.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
