<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="563377" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: NATO-Russia talks fail, but make progress.</title>
<headline>NATO-Russia talks fail, but make progress.</headline>
<byline>Janet McEvoy</byline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>NATO and Russia failed on Tuesday to reach a new deal on an all-embracing post-Cold War partnership, but said &quot;some progress&quot; had been made.</p>
<p>A joint communique said the two sides, represented by alliance Secretary-General Javier Solana and Russian Foreign Secretary Yevgeny Primakov, had also agreed to &quot;intensify negotiations in order to reach agreement at the earliest possible date&quot;.</p>
<p>After the talks Primakov said the next round would be held in Moscow, but declined to give a date.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously the talks are not easy, but you understand that the subject is not easy,&quot; Primakov told newsmen.</p>
<p>NATO sources said the talks took place in an atmosphere of goodwill and said follow-up talks were still aimed at reaching an agreement which could be signed at a NATO-Russia summit in Paris on May 27 -- a date originally proposed by Moscow.</p>
<p>The statement did not give details of areas where progress had been made.</p>
<p>The Western allies are keen that a NATO-Russia &quot;charter&quot; should be the centrepiece of a new European security order for the 21st century that would alleviate Russian fears over NATO's planned eastwards enlargement.</p>
<p>Russia has been demanding strict curbs on any military activities in any new member states likely to be admitted to the alliance from former communist Europe. Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic are the favourites to be admitted at an enlargement summit in Madrid next July.</p>
<p>NATO says such demands are out of the question because such issues are a matter of national sovereignty.</p>
<p>Before starting the talks Primakov said he hoped the meeting would be successful in removing the remaining obstacles to a historic pact.</p>
<p>Shortly before the meeting ended, Yeltsin appeared to be preparing Russian public opinion for a climbdown on the enlargement issue which Moscow has strongly opposed.</p>
<p>&quot;We will do everything to minimise the consequences of possible NATO enlargement for Russia's security,&quot; Itar-Tass news agency quoted Yeltsin as saying in an interview to be published on Wednesday by the defence ministry newspaper Krasnaya Zvevda.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, tacitly accepting that Moscow could not stop enlargement, said he would press on with efforts to deepen integration between Russia and other former Soviet republics and to develop ties with China.</p>
<p>Russia has demanded that new members should not be permitted to overhaul existing military establishments such as airfields to bring them in line with NATO standards.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
