<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="563472" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch shares close at another high, correction seen.</title>
<headline>Dutch shares close at another high, correction seen.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares closed at an all time high on Tuesday, but dealers said the time was ripe for a correction after the recent strong rise with signs emerging that investors were poised to take profits in some stocks.</p>
<p>The 25-share AEX share index closed 2.19 points higher at an all-time high of 781.76 points, after hitting an intra-day high of 786.82.</p>
<p>&quot;A correction of a few percent would only be healthy,&quot; said one dealer, adding he expected the index to fall to somewhere between 750-760 points in the near future.</p>
<p>Philips was one of the first hit by profit taking.</p>
<p>The electronics group fell 1.80 guilders to 105.20, after already losing 1.10 guilders on Monday.</p>
<p>AEX shares were evenly split between gainers and losers, despite the higher close of the index and dealers said this could also be a signal that a correction is near.</p>
<p>ABN AMRO, Heineken and Oce were among AEX components that were hit by profit taking.</p>
<p>&quot;Unilever could be among the stocks hurt next, especially since we have not seen much growth in this stock since it published first quarter results last Friday,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Unilever gained 3.00 guilders today at 382.00 after hitting a high of 384.00 guilders earlier.</p>
<p>Dealers still saw some scope for builders, since the construction market is currently booming.</p>
<p>But Volker Stevin lost 1.50 guilders today at 228.50. NBM-Amstelland was unchanged at 47.30 guilders and Kondor Wessels was down 0.30 guilders at 98.70.</p>
<p>Shares in semiconductor equipment maker ASM International were among the biggest losers today after the company released disappointing first quarter results last night and added that it saw no big improvement in second quarter results.</p>
<p>ASM International closed almost 15 percent or 3.80 guilders lower at 22.10 guilders.</p>
<p>&quot;This should be the bottom,&quot; said one dealer. He added that ASM International was only expected to drop further if some big brokers downgrade the stock. Engineering group IHC Caland gained 3.60 guilders to 103.60.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
