<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="563423" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French polls show many are disappointed with Chirac.</title>
<headline>French polls show many are disappointed with Chirac.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two thirds of French voters are disappointed with conservative Jacques Chirac's record as president and up to 41 percent say he should quit if the left wins a May 25-June 1 election, opinion polls said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A Sofres poll published in the daily Le Monde said 65 percent of 1,000 people questioned were disappointed by Chirac's policies since he was elected two years ago, compared with 22 percent who were satisfied and 13 percent who had no opinion.</p>
<p>A CSA survey saw the ruling centre-right retaining power in the snap election with a sharply reduced majority, winning 296 seats against 258 for the combined left in the National Assembly.</p>
<p>The Sofres poll said Chirac, who dissolved parliament and called the snap election nine months ahead of schedule, was most harshly judged on his record in the fight against unemployment and social inequalities -- issues seen in earlier polls as the voters' two top concerns.</p>
<p>Eighty-seven percent were dissatisfied with Chirac's fight against unemployment. Seventy-four percent condemned his social policies, 73 percent his action against social inequalities, and 66 percent his policies on immigration.</p>
<p>Of the seven issues surveyed, European policy was the only one on which Chirac scored positive marks: 45 percent of voters were satisfied against 34 percent who were dissatisfied.</p>
<p>Highlighting Chirac's gamble in calling the snap election, a BVA poll for the weekly Paris Match said 50 percent of voters wanted Chirac to stay on if the left won but a significant 41 percent believed he should quit.</p>
<p>A CSA poll for the weekly L'Evenement du Jeudi said 55 percent wanted him to stay on and work with a left-wing prime minister, but 33 percent said he should resign.</p>
<p>The CSA poll also said that only 36 percent would vote for Chirac, compared with 49 percent who would not if a presidential election were held now.</p>
<p>Chirac is to mark the second anniversary of his election for a seven-year term on Wednesday with an article in provincial newspapers seeking to reinvigorate the conservatives' campaign.</p>
<p>The BVA survey, which also looked at voters' preferences for the premiership following the parliamentary election, highlighted the unpopularity of Prime Minister Alain Juppe.</p>
<p>Only nine percent wanted Juppe to retain his job if the centre-right retained power.</p>
<p>Twenty-two percent wanted ex-premier Edouard Balladur, Chirac's fellow Gaullist and defeated presidential rival, to return as prime minister.</p>
<p>Eighteen percent preferred former National Assembly speaker and anti-Maastricht campaigner Philippe Seguin, and 13 percent ultra liberal ex-finance minister Alain Madelin.</p>
<p>Should the left win, 43 percent of voters favoured former European Commission president Jacques Delors, who opted out of the presidential election two years ago, for prime minister.</p>
<p>Lionel Jospin, who is leading the Socialist election campaign, gathered only 18 percent with Delors' daughter, ex-labour minister Martine Aubry, close behind at 16 percent.</p>
<p>Looking at a main campaign issue, surveys found an overwhelming majority of voters backing a sharp cut in working hours as part of a strategy to curb record unemployment.</p>
<p>BVA said those polled backed a Socialist plan to cut the working week to 35 hours from 39 by 61 percent to 34, and an even bigger majority said wages should not be cut.</p>
<p>CSA found 68 percent backing a four-day week, and 67 percent saying they were prepared to take a five percent salary cut to compensate for the shorter working time.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
