<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="563488" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Madrid stocks end lower on profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Madrid stocks end lower on profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Madrid stocks erased early gains to end mildly lower on Tuesday in a bout of profit-taking inspired by Monday's strong rally, dealers said.</p>
<p>* General index closes down 1.64 points, 0.31 percent, at 524.21</p>
<p>* Ibex-35 blue chip index down 16.78 points, 0.28 percent, to 6043.15</p>
<p>* Dealers see further gains near term from heavy domestic fund flows and positive tone on world markets but caution of pullback once euphoria fades  </p>
<p>Dealers were expecting a pullback to around the 6,000 level on the Ibex and to 520 on the general index near-term but saw further gains fuelled by domestic fund flows and world markets.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is very clear the market is overbought and as soon as the euphoria calms down we will be looking for it to come back down,&quot; said Banco Santander dealer Nick Henderson.</p>
<p>Volume was heavy with 124 billion pesetas changing hands.</p>
<p>Banesto was one of the top performers with a gain of 4.24 percent. Argentaria was up 1.2 percent. Telefonica fell 10 pesetas to 3,815, Endesa was down 1.77 percent and Iberdrola rose 1.9 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
