<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56349" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Filter buys Wheelabrator units for $385 mln.</title>
<headline>U.S. Filter buys Wheelabrator units for $385 mln.</headline>
<dateline>PALM DESERT, Calif.</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Filter Corp. said Monday it agreed to buy the industrial water process and manufacturing units of Wheelabrator Technologies Inc. for $385 million in cash.</p>
<p>The two companies also said they will create a joint venture firm that will be a giant in water and wastewater treatment services.</p>
<p>It was the second acquisition in as many weeks by U.S. Filter. Last Wednesday, it announced the buyout of WaterPro Supplies Corp., the nation's largest maker of water and wastewater products for municipal water authorities, for $95 million in stock.</p>
<p>Under an agreement signed over the weekend, U.S. Filter said it will buy Wheelabrator's industrial water process business, which includes Wheelabrator's HPD, CPC Engineering, Johnson Screens, Wiesemann, Memtek, Westates Carbon, Wheelabrator Corp. and Custom Engineered Systems.</p>
<p>It will also acquire the unit's businesses in the Netherlands, Singapore, Taiwan, Britain, Ireland, France, Spain, Japan and Australia.</p>
<p>The companies that are being acquired were expected to post sales of $465 million this year.</p>
<p>The U.S. Filter and Wheelabrator venture initially will have $100 million in annual revenue and will operate more than 200 municipal and industrial water and wastewater treatment projects, making it North America's largest such firm, the companies said.</p>
<p>&quot;These transactions continue to expand U.S. Filter as the leading one-stop shop for water services and technology,&quot; said Richard Heckmann, chairman and chief executive officer of U.S. Filter.</p>
<p>&quot;The joint venture with Wheelabrator will create an enterprise of unmatched capability and technical resources -- one singularly positioned to pursue the huge opportunity available in the privatisation of municipal waterworks and the outsourcing of industrial process water and wastewater treatment facilities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wheelabrator, which is based in Oakbrook, Ill., is a unit of WMX Technologies Inc., though it trades under its own stock.</p>
<p>U.S. Filter's stock jumped $1.125 to $27.75 while Wheelabrator was up 37.5 cents at $14.75 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32840">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I92110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALM DESERT, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
