<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="563580" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan opens capital markets to foreigners.</title>
<headline>Pakistan opens capital markets to foreigners.</headline>
<byline>Tahir Ikram</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani Finance Minister Sartaj Aziz, delighting stocks analysts, unveiled a package of tax exemptions on Tuesday aimed at boosting foreign and local investment and developing capital markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Our government is keen to launch a comprehensive programme for sustained and balanced development of the capital market,&quot; Aziz told a news conference.</p>
<p>He said the government would extend capital gains tax exemption, due to expire on June 30, 1998, for three more years, exempt bonus shares from tax and remove a 0.5 percent turnover tax on the sale or purchase of shares.</p>
<p>The aim was to stimulate investment in the equity market, Aziz said. Some measures would be enacted in the next few days and some in the June budget for fiscal 1997/98 (July-June).</p>
<p>Ammar Ali Qureshi, analyst at brokerage house James Capel Asia, said the package was an excellent way to boost investment.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to develop a secondary market and provide a variety of instruments and at the same time remove restrictions on various bodies like provident funds and non-banking insurance companies to invest in the stock market,&quot; Aziz said.</p>
<p>He said foreign investment in government securities and corporate fixed-income securities would be made tax-free.</p>
<p>&quot;The corporate debt market is at a nascent stage in Pakistan and policy measures are required for its promotion,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Aziz said the State (central) Bank of Pakistan (SBP) had agreed to allow investment by non-bank financial institutions in listed debt securities for the purpose of statutory liquidity requirements as was the case with investment in shares.</p>
<p>The SBP has ruled that foreign banks operating in Pakistan may invest in corporate fixed-income securities provided that such securities carry no conversion option, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;This would also encourage more investment from the foreign banks in the fixed-income securities,&quot; Aziz said.</p>
<p>He said rules were being amended to allow employee provident funds to invest up to 20 percent of their money funds in listed securities, instead of a maximum 10 percent at present.</p>
<p>&quot;This limit is being raised to 20 and also the cap of one percent of a provident fund to be invested in one company is also being raised to five percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Aziz said Pakistan needed to develop mutual funds so that ordinary people, not conversant with the complexities of the market, could be encouraged to invest. The government planned to remove some fiscal anomalies hindering this process.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been decided that tax on dividend pay-outs by all mutual funds and collective investment schemes approved by the Corporate Law Authority should be removed and there should be uniformity in tax treatment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have taken these measures with the objective of removing anomalies in the policies towards capital markets and I hope the market will positively respond to our bold initiatives.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
