<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="563592" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistani rupee seen weak amid rising inflation.</title>
<headline>Pakistani rupee seen weak amid rising inflation.</headline>
<byline>Ovais Subhani</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's central bank announced a slight rupee depreciation against the dollar on Tuesday and analysts said further adjustments were likely to close an inflation differential with major trading partners.</p>
<p>The State Bank of Pakistan (SBP) moved the rupee down to 40.3300/40.5317 to the dollar from 40.2400/40.4412 fixed on April 23, when it depreciated the rupee by 0.29 percent.</p>
<p>The April adjustment followed a six-month period when the rate remained unchanged. The rupee was devalued by 7.86 percent against the dollar on October 22.</p>
<p>The central bank gave no reason for the latest change, but bankers said it was designed to keep exports competitive.</p>
<p>They said the dollar had strengthened against other major currencies in the past six months, while inflation in Pakistan was running at close to 12 percent a year.</p>
<p>They said with a stubborn trade deficit and a strong dollar in international markets, the central bank had to reassess the value of the rupee to keep Pakistani exports competitive.</p>
<p>The rupee has now lost 14.65 percent of its dollar value since the beginning of fiscal 1996/97 (July-June) compared with a depreciation of 13.2 percent in the year- ago period.</p>
<p>&quot;The rupee had appreciated by five percent since October and there was a need to bring it down to the real effective exchange rate to offset the inflation differential with our trading partners,&quot; Raza Mirza, head of research at KASB &amp; Co, said.</p>
<p>He said the depreciation would have little immediate impact on the trade deficit but would help keep the gap from widening.</p>
<p>The consumer price index rose 11.8 percent in March year-on-year from 10.27 percent in March 1996, while the wholesale price index jumped 13.4 percent.</p>
<p>The trade deficit for the first nine months of fiscal 1996/97 had exceeded $2.6 billion.</p>
<p>Sameer Ahmed, head of sales at ING Baring Securities, said the rupee may depreciate by about five percent in the next two to three months.</p>
<p>He said the central bank seemed to be following a crawling peg devaluation policy to avoid any panic in the kerb market and any major impact on the import bill and foreign loan repayments.</p>
<p>The rupee opened 0.05 lower at 41.20 to the dollar in the kerb market following Tuesday's adjustment.</p>
<p>Dealer Ovais Kalia said the central bank was likely to devalue the rupee by another three percent before the June 14 announcement of the 1997/98 budget.</p>
<p>A foreign banker said the rupee's real effective exchange rate had appreciated 9.3 percent between October and March while the nominal effective exchange rate was up 3.9 percent.</p>
<p>He said the central bank was unlikely to go for a one-step devaluation but might slash another two percent off the rupee's value by end-June. He said it would continue the depreciation to keep the rupee close to its real exchange rate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
