<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="563754" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: EUROPEAN INVESTMENT IN ZAIRE FALLS, US RISES - UNCTAD.</title>
<headline>EUROPEAN INVESTMENT IN ZAIRE FALLS, US RISES - UNCTAD.</headline>
<byline>Elif Kaban</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. firms are slowly increasing their direct investment in Zaire's chaotic economy, while flows from once-dominant European companies are slowing to a trickle, figures in a new report showed on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Although former colonial ruler Belgium accounts for the bulk of Zaire's foreign direct investment stock, its net flows have diminished in recent years, the report by UNCTAD, the United Nations Conference on Trade and Development, said.</p>
<p>Belgium accounted for more than 90 percent of Zaire's stock of foreign direct investment with $511 million in 1993, the last year such statistics were available, UNCTAD said.</p>
<p>But Belgian firms began shifting funds out of Zaire after 1991, when they recorded their last annual net inflow of $17 million, it added.</p>
<p>By comparison, U.S. direct investment flows to Zaire grew to $21 million in 1995 from $8 million in 1994, according to International Monetary Fund data quoted by UNCTAD.</p>
<p>U.S. companies have also gradually built up their foreign direct investment stock in Zaire to $80 million in 1995 from $39 million in 1991, the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;Many European companies are simply losing interest in Zaire,&quot; said UNCTAD economist Masataka Fujita. &quot;Once the chaos is over in Zaire, U.S. companies could emerge as winners.&quot;</p>
<p>In another major shift after years of European domination in Africa's largest French-speaking country, U.S. companies have begun making inroads in rebel-held areas of Zaire to exploit its mineral riches.</p>
<p>A U.S. company, America Mineral Fields Inc, has signed a $1 billion deal with the Tutsi-dominated rebels to exploit southern Zaire's copper and cobalt deposits and build a zinc plant.</p>
<p>Zaire currently exports 5,000 tonnes of cobalt per year, or about one fifth of world output.</p>
<p>Another U.S. group has entered a joint venture with the rebels to open a bank in the eastern town of Goma, the de facto capital of the rebels who have taken more than half of Zaire since October and are marching on the capital Kinshasa.</p>
<p>In neighbouring Rwanda, Washington has developed close military and political ties with the new Tutsi-dominated government, which took power after the Hutu-led genocide of Tutsis in 1994 and whose key ministers are Anglophone.</p>
<p>Washington has shown renewed interest in the continent as a whole, and U.S. President Bill Clinton plans to make Africa a priority at a G7 summit meeting in Denver in June.</p>
<p>France is in disarray over how to keep its exclusive control over Francophone Africa, Britain is showing little interest in its former colonies, and analysts say Washington appears well placed to fill the resulting power vacuum.</p>
<p>Zaire appears to have slipped out of the area of influence of French businesses, although they remain the biggest group of direct investors in Africa with 20 percent of the total and more than a third of all foreign affiliates, according to UNCTAD.</p>
<p>UNCTAD figures showed French direct capital flows to Zaire were &quot;negligible&quot; in recent years after totalling just $1 million in 1990.</p>
<p>Overall in Africa, despite continuing French and British domination of the foreign investment scene, UNCTAD noted a jump in U.S. investments to $1.2 billion in 1996 from $970 million in 1995 and only $173 million in 1994. More than 30 percent of the U.S. flows went to South Africa, followed by Nigeria and Egypt.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
