<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="563703" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austria fights EU on anonymous accounts.</title>
<headline>Austria fights EU on anonymous accounts.</headline>
<byline>Janet McBride</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austria was set on a collision course with its EU partners on Tuesday when the Vienna government said it had thrown out a European Commission demand to abolish controversial anonymous savings accounts.</p>
<p>A foreign ministry spokesman confirmed that Austria had written to the Commission rejecting its call for banking reform contained in a so-called &quot;reasoned opinion&quot; dispatched from Brussels in February.</p>
<p>The Commission, which could take Austria to the European Court of Justice over the issue, based its case on an EU law aimed at stamping out money laundering. Brussels is expected to decide on its next move by the end of June.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an inappropriate misrepresentation to cast suspicion of criminal behaviour on a large section of the Austrian population - namely anonymous savers,&quot; the government wrote.</p>
<p>It defended Austria's secretive banking system against charges of harbouring illegal funds. The nation of eight million has an estimated 26 million anonymous savings books.</p>
<p>But the government insisted the accounts were unsuitable for criminal activity, saying: &quot;The savings accounts generally contain very modest sums and therefore do not present an appropriate means for laundering money.&quot;</p>
<p>Critics of Austrian banking have been less charitable. In 1995, the United States ranked Austria high in an international league of countries that tolerate money laundering.</p>
<p>In its letter to the European Commission, Austria pointed out that it had adopted EU legislation requiring customers to identify themselves when making transactions of over 200,000 schillings ($16,000) and taken on board other recommendations.</p>
<p>Anonymous securities accounts are being phased out after the government passed a law last August making it impossible to open new accounts and forbidding investors from adding to existing ones.</p>
<p>&quot;Banning anonymous savings books and securities accounts would be over-regulation,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The letter warned of serious economic consequences if the EU forced Austria's hand. A flight by savers from the nation's banks may force up interest rates and ulitimately endanger Austrian qualification for a single European currency by &quot;undermining the country's budget consolidation measures&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Minor advantages in combatting money laudering would be bought at the expense of enormous damage to Austria's capital market,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Austrians, who voted overwhelmingly to join the EU in a 1994 referendum, were baffled by the Commission's opposition to their cherished accounts and may ultimately turn against the bloc if forced to change their savings habits.</p>
<p>&quot;The population would not understand the banning of their anonymous savings accounts and acceptance of the EU in Austria would doubtless deteriorate as a result,&quot; the government said.</p>
<p>Austrian politicians, bankers and savers have leapt to defend their 200-year tradition of anonymous accounts.</p>
<p>Many older Austrians, who have seen their savings wiped out twice this century, harbour a deep mistrust of &quot;open banking&quot; and cling to anonymous accounts that can only be unlocked with a password.</p>
<p>Families can pass down the accounts, which are taxed 25 percent on interest at source, from generation to generation thereby avoiding costly inheritance taxes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
