<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="563944" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Full text of April UK CIPS services survey.</title>
<headline>Full text of April UK CIPS services survey.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following is the full text of the April Report on Services of the Chartered Institute of Purchasing and Supply (CIPS):</p>
<p>Continued strong growth in service sector activity leads to further tightening of the labour market.</p>
<p>The UK service economy continued to show strong growth in April. The Business Activity Index, based on information provided by a panel of 500 business executives in private sector service industries, remained well above the 50.0 level (above which growth is indicated), reflecting sharply rising demand for services. Almost a third of all companies surveyed reported a rise in business activity while less than 10% reported a decline.</p>
<p>Since last July, when this survey began, the service economy has shown consistently strong growth (and considerably faster growth than the manufacturing economy over this period).</p>
<p>Employment showed a further significant increase as companies raised capacity to meet further strong growth of incoming new business. However, the amount of business outstanding rose again, suggesting that firms have yet to raise capacity sufficiently to fully meet the growth of demand for services.</p>
<p>A factor reportedly limiting the scope for companies to boost capacity was a shortage of suitably skilled personnel. This was most notable for, but by no means restricted to, IT and computing staff.</p>
<p>The shortage of suitable labour was reflected in a rise in wages and salaries. Average input prices, of which salaries tend to form the lion's share in the service sector, showed the largest monthly rise since the survey began.</p>
<p>Charges levied by panel member companies rose for the sixth consecutive month in April. However, the increase was only modest as, on the whole, strong competition was generally reported to have discouraged firms from increasing charges. Thus, although higher input prices were reported by over a fifth of all panel members, only half of that figure were able to pass higher costs onto their customers.</p>
<p>Business optimism remained buoyant, with nearly three quarters of all firms expecting to see business activity rise over the next twelve months. The overall measure of optimism fell slightly for the third month running, however, largely reflecting uncertainty arising from the General Election. The Election was also commonly blamed for the slight deceleration in the rate of growth of both business activity and incoming new business.</p>
<p>INCOMING NEW BUSINESS</p>
<p>Demand for services continued to show strong growth in April. The seasonally adjusted Incoming New Business Index registered a rise of almost the same magnitude to that seen in the previous month, despite reports that uncertainty due to the proximity of the General Election had caused a temporary slowdown in some sectors, especially financial services. Over a third of all companies surveyed reported an increase in the level of new business placed during April compared with a month ago. Only 11% reported a decline.</p>
<p>OUTSTANDING BUSINESS</p>
<p>The Outstanding Business Index remained well above the 50.0 no change level in April, signalling a further increase in work in hand (although of smaller magnitude than that seen in March). The amount of business outstanding has risen throughout the history of this survey in line with strong growth of new business. In recent months, an increasing (but still relatively small) number of companies have reported that their ability to keep up with the growth of business has been hampered by a lack of resources  notably skilled labour.</p>
<p>EMPLOYMENT</p>
<p>The seasonally adjusted Employment Index registered a further increase in recruitment during April, although the rise was smaller than that recorded in March. Nevertheless, over a fifth of all firms took on additional staff in April to meet rising levels of business activity  more than double the number of firms that cut staff during the month. The strongest growth in recruitment was reported by computing and IT firms, the weakest by financial services providers.</p>
<p>PRICES CHARGED</p>
<p>Prices charged rose for the sixth consecutive month in April, and at a slightly faster rate of growth than previously recorded. However, the total number of companies able to raise their charges continued to be subdued by strong competitive pressures. Thus, despite almost a fifth of all companies reporting a rise in their costs in April, only 11% of all companies surveyed raised their charges. Higher charges were most commonly reported for consumer-based services such as hotels, restaurants and personal services.</p>
<p>INPUT PRICES</p>
<p>Prices charged rose for the sixth consecutive month in April, and at a slightly faster rate of growth than previously recorded. However, the total number of companies able to raise their charges continued to be subdued by strong competitive pressures. Thus, despite almost a fifth of all companies reporting a rise in their costs in April, only 11% of all companies surveyed raised their charges. Higher charges were most commonly reported for consumer-based services such as hotels, restaurants and personal services.</p>
<p>BUSINESS EXPECTATIONS</p>
<p>The Business Expectations Index dropped modestly for the third month running in April but nonetheless remains very strong. Just under three quarters of all companies surveyed expect business activity to be higher than now in a years time. Only 6% expect a decline. Optimism regarding the health of the economy and overseas prospects continue to be met with greater sales and marketing activities and further investment in capacity. The slight decline in the index is almost wholly explained by uncertainty due to the General Election.</p>
<p>NOTE: The survey covers transport and communication, financial intermediation, business services, personal services and hotels and restaurants. Respondents are asked whether business has reported an improvement, deterioration or no change on the previous month, From their percentage replies, an index is derived, with a level of 50 indicating no change, a higher number signals an increase or improvement and a lower number signalling a decrease or deterioration.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
