<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="563976" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraq ratifies oil contract with Russia - INA.</title>
<headline>Iraq ratifies oil contract with Russia - INA.</headline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraqi has ratified an oil contract with Russia under which Moscow is to develop seven to eight billion barrels of reserves in southern Iraq's West Qurna oilfield, the official Iraqi News Agency (INA) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Iraqi National Assembly unanimously ratified last month the deal, which was signed between the two countries on March 21.</p>
<p>INA quoted an Iraqi oil source as saying the contract would &quot;strengthen Iraq's stand in the world oil market...and would activiate Iraq's dealings with world banks.&quot;</p>
<p>Under strict U.N. sanctions imposed on Baghdad for its 1990 invasion of Kuwait, Iraq is banned from exporting its oil. Moscow has reaffirmed it would not violate the current international trade curbs on Iraq.</p>
<p>The 23-year contract includes a plan under which Russia is expected to pump about 600,000 barrels per day (bpd). This, the experts say, will consume almost half of Qurna's proven reseves in 23 years at the end of which the Russians are obliged to hand it back to Iraq.</p>
<p>Russia is also expected to treat the associated gas and deliver the surplus quantities to the Iraqi side free of charge.</p>
<p>Moscow is required to give Iraq a grant of $10 million in the form of materials and equipment needed for Qurna's development. The Russian side is also obliged to spend about $500 million in the first three years of signing the contract.</p>
<p>Iraq hopes to reap about $70 billion in 23 years from Qurna oilfield, 500 km (300 miles) south of Baghdad.</p>
<p>Iraqi officials have freguently said that similar deals would be signed with China and France, both -- along with Russia -- favour the immediate lifing of U.N. curbs on Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
