<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="564098" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Drought-breaking rains in Europe, more on way - WSC.</title>
<headline>Drought-breaking rains in Europe, more on way - WSC.</headline>
<dateline>LEXINGTON, MASS 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Drought-breaking rains have developed in western Europe including northern Spain, France, the Benelux countries and Britain, independent forecaster Weather Services Corp said.</p>
<p>It forecast more rain in western Europe for Tuesday and a few light showers in the more eastern areas with this pattern continuing on Wednesday. Rainfall will be significant this week in the west, breaking the drought, while the weather in more favourably mild and drier in the east, especially the Southeast, WSC said.</p>
<p>In its three-to-five day forecast, WSC said Western Europe will have periods of rain and fog on Thursday to Friday and lingering showers on Saturday, mostly in the north. It will be cool.</p>
<p>Germany and Central Europe will also be showery and cool while Mediterranean Europe will have showers in western and central areas on Thursday, and in eastern areas on Saturday, with temperatures cooling west to east. From Saturday it will be drier as temperatures return to near normal.</p>
<p>In eastern Europe showers and thunderstorms will develop from west to east during Thursday with temperatures still above normal. There will be a chance of rain during Friday with temperatures turning cooler. Temperatures will be near to below normal on Saturday with showers likely.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LEXINGTON, MASS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
