<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="564070" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYC mayor wants MTA to give city more toll income.</title>
<headline>NYC mayor wants MTA to give city more toll income.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York City Mayor Rudolph Giuliani plans to push the Metropolitan Transportation Authority (MTA) of the State of New York to give the city a bigger share of surplus bridge-and-tunnel toll income.</p>
<p>The Republican mayor said on Monday that his presentation on the executive budget for fiscal year 1998, due Thursday, will hold independent authorities, like the state MTA and the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, partly responsible for the city's deficits.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not an agenda for this year. It's an agenda for the future,&quot; Giuliani told reporters at City Hall. &quot;Next year is a statewide election. It might be a time in which this becomes an interesting issue.&quot;</p>
<p>Giuliani released a chart showing that the New York City Transit Authority's share of the surplus toll revenue has decreased steadily since 1972, while the portion spent on suburban commuter rail operations increased. The Authority is a unit of the MTA.</p>
<p>The Triborough Bridge and Tunnel Authority, another MTA subsidiary, distributed 66 percent of the surplus to the city transit system in 1972 but only 51.9 percent last year.</p>
<p>The mayor traced the drop to a 1972 agreement that granted city transit the first $24 million in surplus toll money, then split the remainder equally.</p>
<p>That worked well for the city in 1972, when the surplus was $74 million, the mayor said. But the city's proportionate share fell as the total Triborough Bridge and Tunnel Authority surplus rose to $610 million last year.</p>
<p>Giuliani said that if the city still got the share it received in 1972, its transit system would have received $86 million more than it did in 1996.</p>
<p>Tom Kelly, a spokesman for the MTA, in a statement said that under the Pataki Administration, the state spends about twice as much subsidizing the MTA and the city. He added that under Gov George Pataki, the city's subway and bus system has been improved and modernized, and noted that on July 4, the Authority will start allowing riders to transfer freely between subways and buses.</p>
<p>The MTA board consists of a chairman and 18 other members appointed by the governor, including four on the New York City mayor's recommendation.</p>
<p>In 1994, Giuliani crossed party lines to endorse Gov Mario Cuomo, a Democrat, for re-election. Since then, he has avoided criticizing the winner of that gubernatorial election, Pataki, who is a Republican.</p>
<p>((--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
