<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="564220" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France says deeply concerned by Zaire rebel threat.</title>
<headline>France says deeply concerned by Zaire rebel threat.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>France, a longtime ally of embattled Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko, expressed deep concern on Tuesday over Zairean rebel threats to take the capital Kinshasa by force and renewed its appeals for a peaceful transition.</p>
<p>United Nations and Organisation of African Unity special envoy Mohamed Sahnoun was in Paris for talks with officials at President Jacques Chirac's office and the foreign ministry, ministry spokesman Jacques Rummelhardt said.</p>
<p>Rummelhardt said France would renew support for Sahnoun's peace plan during the talks and discuss a summit held between Mobutu and rebel leader Laurent Kabila at the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;We strongly wish for an immediate halt to hostilities, as foreseen in the peace plan,&quot; he said. &quot;In this regard, we view with deep concern the latest declarations by Mr Kabila indicating that he has not renounced the military option.&quot;</p>
<p>Kabila has vowed to chase Mobutu out of Kinshasa  if he has not handed over power by the time the approaching rebels, reported to be less than 85 km (50 miles) away, arrive in the capital.</p>
<p>The rebels on Tuesday urged government troops to surrender to avert a bloody takeover of the city which has a population of five million.</p>
<p>In their surrender appeal, the rebel Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire (AFDL) said they had set up centres to receive government troops and would not harm those willing to turn themselves in.</p>
<p>&quot;Zaire will not be able to find a lasting solution to the crisis except by implementing an orderly transition aimed at preparing for elections,&quot; Rummelhardt said.</p>
<p>Rummelhardt also said Paris was very concerned by the humanitarian situation in Zaire.</p>
<p>He said Paris fully backed appeals by the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, Sadako Ogata, to the AFDL to let aid reach the needy and to allow unrestricted repatriation of Rwandan refugees.</p>
<p>Rummelhardt also said Paris had renewed calls for French citizens to leave Zaire if they could.</p>
<p>Defence ministry sources said many French nationals had already left and no decision had been taken yet on evacuating the foreigners remaining in the Zairean capital.</p>
<p>Some 300 French soldiers were among western troops standing by in Brazzaville, across the river from Kinshasa in neighbouring Congo, to evacuate foreigners. They could quickly be reinforced if necessary by French contingents in Gabon, the Central African Republic and Chad.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OAU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
