<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="564406" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - June BTPs to brake at 128.76 resistance.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - June BTPs to brake at 128.76 resistance.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>June BTPs on LIFFE look positive after powering higher in Tuesday's early session, but are likely to come to a halt close to current session highs, technical analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Resistance is to be found at the daily downtrend 128.76, which is expected to hold for the next few days,&quot; wrote Brenda Sullivan and Elizabeth Miller of Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in a note to clients.</p>
<p>The June contract was trading 59 basis points above Friday's close at 0802 GMT, at 128.42. The contract earlier reached a high of 128.65.  </p>
<p>The contract broke through resistance at Thursday and Friday's highs of 128.40 after Italian March EU-harmonised consumer price inflation rose 2.2 percent year-on-year, fanning expectations of a cut in interest rates. Monday was a market holiday in London.</p>
<p>Support for the contract lies at 127.75 and more substantial support at 127.50, said Elli Gifford, independent technical analyst near Cambridge.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be some easing later on today, but support may not be tested,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>June Eurolira futures were two basis points higher at 93.25 at 0840 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;There is potential for an extension higher toward retracement at 93.38, but unlikely through the downtrend at 93.47,&quot; said Sullivan and Miller.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
