<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="564490" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia Opposition demands pension tax revamp.</title>
<headline>Australia Opposition demands pension tax revamp.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's Labor opposition on Tuesday demanded the government revamp its proposed tax surcharge on pension saving funds.</p>
<p>&quot;Labor will not support the Liberals' 15 percent tax on superannuation unless low and middle income earners and retrenched workers are exempted,&quot; opposition assistant treasury spokesman Nick Sherry told reporters.</p>
<p>The government said in March it expected the superannuation legislation -- which will bring in an extra A$500 million a year -- to pass the upper house of parliament this month because it believed it had the support of the opposition.</p>
<p>The government needs the support of at least two non-government senators to pass legislation through the Senate.</p>
<p>The goverment plans to levy a tax surcharge of up to 15 percent on superannuation savings for people who earn more than A$70,000 a year or more -- through the surcharge.</p>
<p>The surcharge would be on top of the existing 15 percent tax on contributions.</p>
<p>But Sherry said the reforms would catch up to one million lower income earners who could be pushed above the A$70,000 level by retrenchment payments, insurance payouts or other one-off payments.</p>
<p>The government's position in the Senate has become more precarious with key independent senator Mal Colston pledging on Tuesday to vote against government measures.</p>
<p>A Senate motion needs majority support to pass. If Colston, Labor and other minority parties combine, even if a second independent continues to support Howard's administration, government measures would still be blocked with a 38-38 tied vote.</p>
<p>Sherry said minority parties had not yet declared their position on his planned changes.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
