<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="564403" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Hardliner Redwood joins race to replace Major.</title>
<headline>Hardliner Redwood joins race to replace Major.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hardline Eurosceptic John Redwood joined the battle for the leadership of Britain's dispirited Conservatives on Tuesday, warning his party that it faced an &quot;awesome&quot; task to make itself electable again.</p>
<p>Redwood, the third member of parliament to declare he would bid to replace John Major, said the fact he had been outside Major's cabinet for two years before Thursday's election defeat by Tony Blair's Labour Party would be to his advantage.</p>
<p>Major announced he would step down in the aftermath of last Thursday's debacle for the party when it won just 156 of the 659 seats in the House of Commons, its worst showing for 150 years. Kenneth Clarke, the pro-European former finance minister, and right-winger Peter Lilley have already put themselves forward as the men to lead the party out of the political wilderness to which the voters consigned it last week.</p>
<p>Former interior minister Michael Howard has called a news conference later on Tuesday at which he is expected to throw his hat into the ring.</p>
<p>Announcing his candidature in an article in the Times newspaper, Redwood said: &quot;I want to offer the Conservative Party hope for the future...Our task is awesome in scale.&quot;</p>
<p>He said as leader he would not have to defend the policies which caused the Conservative vote to plummet on Thursday, adding: &quot;I can't defend the past. I can unite the party.&quot;</p>
<p>Redwood resigned as Major's Welsh Secretary in 1995 to challenge him for the party leadership.</p>
<p>He attracted support from Eurosceptics who wanted the government to rule out British membership of a single European currency but was soundly beaten by Major, leader of the party since taking over from Margaret Thatcher in 1990.</p>
<p>In a BBC radio interview, Redwood said it should now be possible for him and Clarke, on the opposite wings of the party on the European issue, to unite.</p>
<p>&quot;Ken and I are...entirely united in saying that a fudged single currrency will not work and would be bad for Britain. I don't think there will be anything other than a fudged one on offer,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>With former Deputy Prime Minister Michael Heseltine having ruled himself out of the race because of ill health, the bookmakers make William Hague, who replaced Redwood as Welsh Secretary, the favourite to replace Major.</p>
<p>Hague, a right-winger who is just 36, has yet to say he will stand but is still quoted at 5-4, with Clarke and Howard at 4-1, Dorrell at 7-1 and Redwood and Howard at 8-1.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
