<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="564579" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Shenzhen B index ends higher on economic forecast.</title>
<headline>Shenzhen B index ends higher on economic forecast.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shenzhen's B shares ended higher on Tuesday with investor confidence bolstered by Beijing's positive economic forecast for the first half of 1997, brokers said.</p>
<p>The hard currency B share index rose 3.06 points or 1.69 percent to close at 184.20 on turnover of HK$263.7 million, compared with Monday's HK$253.9 million.</p>
<p>China's gross domestic product is expected to grow 9.6 percent year-on-year in the first half, with retail price inflation seen at two percent, the Beijing-based Financial News reported on Tuesday, quoting a forecast by the State Economic and Trade Commission.  </p>
<p>&quot;The new economic data fuelled optimism over China's stock markets,&quot; an analyst with a major Chinese brokerage said.</p>
<p>Responding to the forecasts, the Shenzhen's domestic A share index surged 17.33 points or 3.41 percent to end at a historic high of 525.21, brokers said. Turnover was a massive 19.83 billion yuan against Monday's 16.90 billion yuan.</p>
<p>&quot;Concerns over listed firms' 1996 annual results have disappeared with the end of the yearly reporting season on April 30,&quot; an analyst at China Guotai Securities said.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are eyeing 1997 interim earnings, expecting high returns due to China's dynamic economy,&quot; the analyst said.  </p>
<p>New listings in Shenzhen scheduled for later this month are expected to further boost sentiment and push the B index above the 200-point level, analysts said.</p>
<p>Pesticide maker Hubei Sanonda Co Ltd, Shandong Chenming Paper Holdings Ltd and Nanjing Posts &amp; Telecommunications Equipment Co Ltd have announced they will each offer 100 million B shares for listing later this month.</p>
<p>&quot;The three firms are expected to post strong debuts on listing because of their solid earnings and the market's recent bullishness,&quot; an analyst at Shenzhen J&amp;A Securities said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Expected strong debuts will in turn boost the B share index,&quot; the J&amp;A analyst said.</p>
<p>Shenzhen Gintian was the best performer on the B share market, after the conglomerate announced a plan to buy a domestic power plant for 80.94 million yuan.</p>
<p>The counter soared HK$0.33 or 8.68 percent to HK$4.13 on volume of 983,588 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors bought Gintian anticipating the acquisition will boost its operations in the long term,&quot; the Guotai analyst said.  </p>
<p>&quot;But I think investors seems to be too enthusiastic about the plan,&quot; the analyst said, citing Gintian's 1996 net loss of 62.10 million yuan under international accounting standards.</p>
<p>Gintian's A shares hit their 10 percent limit up at 11.70 yuan soon after afternoon trading started and stayed at that level for the rest of the session.</p>
<p>The A share market leader was Shenzhen Development Bank, which surged 10 percent to 44.47 yuan on volume of 29.60 million shares. Shenzhen Development Bank was also the most actively traded counter.  </p>
<p>The bank's sharp gains followed a report in the Shenzhen-based Securities Times on Monday which quoted bank president He Yun as forecasting a strong rise in the firm's 1997 earnings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
