<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="564689" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan stocks close up despite profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Taiwan stocks close up despite profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan share prices closed slightly higher on Tuesday despite late profit-taking, but brokers expected a consolidation to continue.</p>
<p>The weighted index closed 24.84 points or 0.30 percent higher at 8,294.27. Turnover was T$77.6 billion, well below recent levels that were in excess of T$100 billion.</p>
<p>Brokers said Wall Street's overnight rise helped sentiment but was not a big incentive to fuel buying.</p>
<p>&quot;It is encouraging to see Wall Street's gains, but the market is still largely dominated by domestic factors,&quot; said Albert Lin, research head of Golden Securities.  </p>
<p>Some brokers described the market as in a &quot;vacuum period&quot; as investors were still looking for new investment targets after dumping shares they believed were over-valued.</p>
<p>Fears over worsening social disorder and political instability also deterred buying interest, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;People are not willing to take the risk and increase their stock portfolio amid the uncertainties,&quot; Lin said.</p>
<p>Shocked by the murder of a famous actress's teenage daughter, more than 50,000 people demonstrated on Sunday to demand the resignation of Premier Lien Chan and a cabinet reshuffle to take responsibility for rising crime.  </p>
<p>Electronics shares suffered early selling after a 20-minute power outage in Taiwan's Hsinchu Science-based Industrial Park on Monday shut down operations at many electronic firms.</p>
<p>United Microelectronics fell 50 cents to T$66. But the island's leading chipmaker Taiwan Semiconductor recovered from early setbacks to gain T$1.50 or 1.56 percent to T$97.50.</p>
<p>Taiwan's First International Computer Inc was up T$1 or 1.28 percent to T$79 after Lehman Brothers, the global investment bank, said it had initiated coverage on the firm with a &quot;1-buy&quot; rating.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
