<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="564700" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Shenzhen B index firms at noon on economic data.</title>
<headline>Shenzhen B index firms at noon on economic data.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shenzhen's hard currency B share index firmed at midday on Tuesday, with positive economic forecasts for the first half of 1997 from Beijing boosting sentiment, brokers said.</p>
<p>The index rose 2.37 points or 1.31 percent to 183.50 on turnover of HK$115 million.  </p>
<p>China's gross domestic product is expected to grow 9.6 percent year-on-year in the first half, with retail price inflation seen at two percent, the Beijing-based Financial News said on Tuesday, quoting a forecast by the Information Department of the State Economic and Trade Commission.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are betting on good 1997 interim earnings from listed firms given China's booming economy,&quot; an analyst at China Guotai Securities Co said.  </p>
<p>Three B share listings in Shenzhen scheduled for later this month are expected to further boost sentiment and push the B index up through the 200-point level, analysts said.</p>
<p>Pesticide maker Hubei Sanonda Co Ltd, Shandong Chenming Paper Holdings Ltd and Nanjing Posts &amp; Telecommunications Equipment Co Ltd have announced they will each offer 100 million B shares for listing later this month.</p>
<p>&quot;The three firms are expected to post strong debuts on listing because of their solid earnings and the market's recent bullishness,&quot; an analyst at Shenzhen J&amp;A Securities said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Their expected strong debuts will in turn boost the index,&quot; the J&amp;A analyst added.</p>
<p>On the B share market, Shenzhen SEG maintained its strong upward momentum on institutional demand due to optimism over the colour television tube maker's 1997 interim earnings, brokers said.</p>
<p>The share, the session's sharpest gainer, rose HK$0.57 or 5.83 percent to HK$10.35 on volume of 1.38 million shares.  </p>
<p>The domestic A share index climbed 12.78 points or 2.52 percent to 520.66 as the market's recent rises sparked inflows of fresh capital, brokers said. Turnover in the morning was 9.57 billion yuan.</p>
<p>The A share market leader, Shenzhen Development Bank, soared 10 percent to 44.47 yuan on heavy volume of 20.46 million shares.</p>
<p>Shenzhen Development Bank's sharp gains follow an item in the Shenzhen-based Securities Times on Monday which quoted the bank's president He Yun as forecasting a strong rise in the firm's 1997 earnings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
