<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="564701" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai B shares up at noon on strong sentiment.</title>
<headline>Shanghai B shares up at noon on strong sentiment.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai B shares were sharply up at noon on Tuesday with bullish investors continuing to chase blue chips and shares with a heavy weighting on the index, brokers said.</p>
<p>The B index surged 2.345 points or 2.42 percent to 99.162 points on volume of 25.515 million shares worth $16.524 million.</p>
<p>The news that the Shanghai Stock Exchange has no plans to introduce measures to cool down the market will have little impact on the market because the major policy maker is the China Securities Regulatory Commission, brokers said.  </p>
<p>The exchange president Yang Xianghai said in an interview with Reuters this morning that the exchange had no plans to take measures to depress shares prices, which have risen sharply since the begninning of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The final decision maker is the central securities authorities, so the information from the Shanghai bourse will have little impact on the local market,&quot; said one broker</p>
<p>Brokers said the recent good performance of the stock markets had attracted fresh capital, which was the key factor pushing the index up.  </p>
<p>&quot;Investors are scrambling into the market, lured by its cheaper prices compared with A shares,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;Institutions are seen buying heavily in blue chips and heavily-weighted shares, which boosted market sentiment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;A correction is quite possible if the index breaches the key resistance level of 100 points,&quot; another broker said.</p>
<p>Of 43 B shares, 42 traded, with 26 up, seven flat and nine down.  </p>
<p>Shanghai Worldbest was the star on institutional buying, surging $0.064 or 9.35 percent to $0.784 on volume of 1.5 million shares.</p>
<p>The market giant Shanghai Chlor Alkali Chemical was the most actively traded on overseas institutional buying on optimism over its prospects, up $0.020 or 5.34 percent to $0.394 on volume of 4.4 million shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai's A share index moved up this morning on bullish sentiment, but the market is in need of a correction in the short term after continued solid gains over the past few days, brokers said.  </p>
<p>The index rose 21.575 points or 1.43 percent to 1,534.878 points on volume of 513.3 million shares worth 7.9 billion yuan.</p>
<p>The SSE30 blue chip index jumped 110.542 points or 2.64 percent to 4,300.407 points.</p>
<p>Fujian Cement was the star on institutional buying, soaring 1.31 yuan or 10.02 percent to 14.38 yuan on volume of 2.2 million shares.</p>
<p>--Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
