<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="564753" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks seen down on economy, results worries.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks seen down on economy, results worries.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks are seen falling on Tuesday as concerns surrounding the economy and corporate results continue to depress the market, analysts said.</p>
<p>The market closed last Friday at 660.10 after losing 1.19 points in lacklustre trade. The SET 50 closed at 48.72. The market was closed on Monday for a public holiday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market should move in a narrow range today, moving down perhaps in single digits ... people should stay with defensive stocks,&quot; said Thanawat Patchimkul, an analyst at Seamico Securities.  </p>
<p>The prospect of more depressing first quarter corporate earnings results and a number of macro-economic concerns continue to undermine sentiment, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Government tax revenue figures suggest that company results will be poor and I can't see the bottom for the economy yet,&quot; Thanawat said.</p>
<p>Last week's 25 basis point cut in the lending rate of leading commercial banks was not seen as sufficient enough to stimulate the economy which most private forecasters believe will grow by around five percent this year, its lowest level for a decade, analysts said.  </p>
<p>Continuing concerns surround the stability of the financial sector despite government pledges to alleviate troublesome property loans, analysts said.</p>
<p>The baht, which came under speculative attack in February, may again become a subject of renewed worry among investors, and would leave little room for rate cuts of a magnitude which would help the economy, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The overall outlook is not good...if the central bank asks the commercial banks for another rate cut the interest rate differential between the U.S. rate and Thai rate will narrow and that would be a worry,&quot; Thanawat said. --J. Mclean 662-652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
