<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="564728" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Hong Leong Properties in Putrajaya deal.</title>
<headline>Hong Leong Properties in Putrajaya deal.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Leong Properties Bhd said it is involved in the development and construction of certain parcels of land within Putrajaya, the site for a proposed new federal capital.</p>
<p>In a statement sent on Monday to the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange, Hong Leong Properties said it has entered into a joint venture agreement with Putrajaya Holdings Sdn Bhd and its unit Putrajaya Properties Sdn Bhd for the project.</p>
<p>Putrajaya, located just outside Kuala Lumpur, is a multi-billion dollar government administrative centre.</p>
<p>The project will involve residential and commercial development covering an area of about 663.7 acres.</p>
<p>Under the joint venture, Hong Leong Properties said it proposes to dispose of its wholly-owned indirect unit, Sabna Development Sdn Bhd to Putrajaya Properties for 187.21 million ringgit. Sabna is principally involved in property development.</p>
<p>Putrajaya Properties has authorised capital of 100,000 ringgit, which will be increased to 200 million ringgit with the transaction.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603 206 2323)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
