<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="564840" id="root" date="1997-05-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O.Licht - Daily coffee report.</title>
<headline>F.O.Licht - Daily coffee report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from commodity statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>COFFEE - World market for May 5, 1997</p>
<p>Arabica futures in New York ended higher with pared gains and well off intraday highs. May ended 3.35 cents/lb higher at 250.90 cents/lb, while July added 2.35 cents/lb to close at 218.50. London was closed. Open interest in the May remains stubbornly high and there were no notices issued. Traders said although there are about 12,000 bags pending grading, some of the coffee graded most recently has failed. Certified coffee stocks are still not sufficient to offset the open interest.</p>
<p>News of a warehouse fire in Costa Rica re-ignited supply worries although the damage was apparently much less than the 50,000 bags originally reported. While the losses in Costa Rica may come in well below 50,000 bags, traders said any supply problems at a time when inventories were already at low levels are perceived as bullish. Low consumer stocks have seen the nearby spreads become sharply backwardated, with the May/July spread widening to 31.40 cents/lb today from 30.40 cents/lb at the close on Friday.</p>
<p>Most analysts expect prices to continue to rise although setbacks are not excluded, as the market right now seems to be heavily overbought. However, any setback may be only temporary.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>GUATEMALA - Guatemala exported just under 575,000 60-kg bags of coffee in April, the head of the Guatemalan National Coffee Association (Anacafe) said. The country has now exported 3.3 million bags of coffee this harvest, up more than 33 percent from last year, it was added. Hence, there will be only little coffee for export during the remainder of this year's harvest. Overall Anacafe predicted that Guatemala will produce 3.6 to 3.7 million 60-kg bags of coffee during the 1996/97 (October/September) harvest, significantly up on earlier forecasts. At the beginning of February 1997 Anacafe predicted production in 1996/97 to reach 3.3 million bags, down from 3.6 million bags the previous year.</p>
<p>COLOMBIA - The Colombian FNC will not sell any coffee in May 1997 to European roasters, trade sources said. This is because of complications resulting from the high spreads between May and July futures and the current formulas used to determine internal prices. The Colombian ICO price has been unquoted and therefore based on their own internal rules the Colombians must use spot quotations to determine internal prices. Private exporters have already moved into July quotes. If the FNC were to roll to July quotes, the ten-day average would drop forcing the internal price down at a time when there is little fresh coffee to sell. Apparently the FNC has not shipped total coffees that were available for March and April and are not selling the balance either.</p>
<p>COSTA RICA - A fire destroyed an unquantified amount of coffee and damaged the warehouse where it was stored. A spokesman for the Costa Rican Federacion de Cooperativas de Caficultores said less than 50,000 bags were believed to be affected. Costa Rica ended its 1996/97 harvest in March with a crop of 2.7 million 60-kg bags, similar to the previous cycle.</p>
<p>INDIA - According to trade sources rising international prices and prospects of lower output pushed up India's domestic coffee prices to new highs. India's state-run coffee board has scaled down its 1996/97 (October/September) production estimate to 3.4 million 60-kg bags from the previous 3.6 million but industry sources and traders expect output not to exceed 3.0 million bags comparedto last year's 3.7 million. This means exports will fall significantly below last year's 2.8 million bags.</p>
<p>NORWAY - Norway imported 65,780 bags of coffee in February 1997, 16 percent less than was imported the same month the previous year. That brought total imports since the beginning of 1997 up to 129,500 bags, 8 percent less than was imported the same period in 1996. Total imports in calendar year 1996 rose by 9 percent to 719,900 bags. Main suppliers of green coffee in January/February 1997 were Brazil (43,900 vs 42,400 bags) and Colombia (26,100 vs 33,300 bags).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
