<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="565148" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee settles seesaw session mixed.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee settles seesaw session mixed.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures ended mixed in choppy dealings on Wednesday, with local and light speculative liquidation pressuring the nearby contracts, trading sources said.</p>
<p>Benchmark July fell 1.45 cents per lb on the day, to 211.40 cents, after ranging between 218.00 and 209.00. Spot May, which set a new life-of-contract high of 256.00 early in the day, ended 3.95 cents lower, at 245.65. The back months closed 1.20 to 2.00 higher.</p>
<p>The market gapped some 5.00 cents higher at the opening, as expected, after a drawdown in exchange inventories rekindled concerns about tight spot supplies.</p>
<p>U.S. certified coffee stocks fell by 13,999 bags, to 27,699 bags as of May 5, the CSCE reported late Tuesday.</p>
<p>But traders said steady selling by producers toward the highs limited gains and prevented a breach of key chart resistance at 218.00 cents per lb basis July.</p>
<p>&quot;We expected a strong open -- and had one -- because of the drawdown,&quot; one trader said. &quot;But there's a sense that the market is still a bit overdone. There was no follow-through and good origin selling.&quot;</p>
<p>Additionally, traders viewed as bearish the narrowing of the nearby spreads. May/July came in to 34.25 cents today from 36.75 at the close on Tuesday, while July/September shrunk to 20.05 cents from 22.70 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;The switches came in, which is not a good sign,&quot; said a trader. &quot;I think the market is still overpriced. We had some bullish news today and the market gave back quite a bit.&quot;</p>
<p>However, traders said low consumer coffee stockpiles, combined with the onset of winter in top-producer Brazil, should keep prices well underpinned.</p>
<p>After Wednesday's close, the CSCE reported certified coffee stocks dropped by 3,000 bags, to 24,699 bags as of May 6. There were 11,250 bags of coffee pending grading, the exchange said.</p>
<p>Technically, traders said July's low of 209.00 was seen as near-term support, with a break below that level could lead to a test of 200.00.</p>
<p>On the upside, a breach of 218.00-220.00 could lead to a test of July's life-of-contract high of 225.00, they said.</p>
<p>Volume reached an estimated 9,189 lots on the day.</p>
<p>((--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodity Desk 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
