<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="565335" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL ICE HOCKEY - DETROIT TAKES 3-0 LEAD, RANGERS ARE UP 2-1.</title>
<headline>NHL ICE HOCKEY - DETROIT TAKES 3-0 LEAD, RANGERS ARE UP 2-1.</headline>
<dateline>ANAHEIM, California 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sergei Fedorov and Vyacheslav Kozlov scored within 24 seconds of each other as the Detroit Red Wings scored four unanswered goals for a 5-3 victory over the Mighty Ducks of Anaheim and 3-0 lead in their Western Conference semifinal series on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Detroit can advance to the conference finals with a win in Game Four Thursday.</p>
<p>Only two teams -- the 1942 Toronto Maple Leafs and 1975 New York Islanders -- have ever lost the first three games of a best-of-seven series and come back to win.</p>
<p>Mike Vernon made 20 saves for the Red Wings, who outshot the Ducks, 49-23, including 34-12 over the final two periods.</p>
<p>Igor Larionov and Doug Brown scored 3:25 apart late in the third period to lift the Red Wings into a 3-3 tie and Fedorov's second goal of the post-season put Detroit ahead for good. He took a pass from Larry Murphy at the Anaheim blue line, skated to the top of the left faceoff circle and blasted a low slap shot inside the left post.</p>
<p>Kozlov's second goal of the game and fifth of the series just 24 seconds later made it 5-3.  Kozlov skated down the left side and faked a pass into the slot before cutting across the top of the crease and beating Ducks goaltender Mikhail Shtalenkov with a backhander.</p>
<p>Shtalenkov, making his first post-season start in place of the injured Guy Hebert, stopped 44 shots.</p>
<p>The Red Wings went 2-for-5 on the power play, improving to 3-for-14 in the series.  The Ducks were 2-for-3 with the extra man and are 3-for-8 in the series.</p>
<p>Detroit's Joe Kocur left the game in the first period with back spasms after falling awkwardly into the boards.</p>
<p>In New York, the Rangers grabbed a 2-1 lead in their Eastern Conference semifinal with the New Jersey Devils on Tuesday, thanks to a pair of former Oilers and a video replay.</p>
<p>Esa Tikkanen scored two goals and Wayne Gretzky had a goal and an assist to lead New York, who were lucky to escape with a 3-2 victory in Game Three of the best-of-seven series.</p>
<p>Gretzky should have had another assist after making an amazing no-look pass early the first period that sprung Russ Courtnall on breakaway. But Courtnall was thwarted by Devils goaltender Martin Brodeur.</p>
<p>Gretzky, Tikkanen and Rangers captain Mark Messier, who had an assist, all played for the great Edmonton Oilers teams that won five Stanley Cups in the 1980s.</p>
<p>Randy McKay and Steve Thomas scored for New Jersey, each time quickly cutting the deficit to one goal.</p>
<p>Doug Gilmour appeared to score the tying goal for New Jersey on a powerplay with 7:42 left in the third period. But review of a video replay of the goal clearly showed Bill Guerin was in the crease and the goal was disallowed.</p>
<p>&quot;We were all over them in their end in the third period and the only goal we got they took away,&quot; complained New Jersey coach Jacques Lemaire. &quot;I didnt think the officials were going to review it until the crowd started yelling and the Rangers started yelling.&quot;</p>
<p>Even Rangers coach Colin Campbell was somewhat sympathetic regarding the controversial &quot;in the crease&quot; rule.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't like the rule, I don't agree with it. I never liked it,&quot; Campbell said with a shrug.</p>
<p>After the first two games produced a split of 2-0 shutouts with one goal in each coming from empty netters in the final minute, Game Three featured three goals in the first 6:04.</p>
<p>The Rangers broke through when Gretzky scored at 3:57 of the first period, picking up a puck that deflected off the stick of Devils defenceman Scott Niedermayer and firing it into the net for his 117th career playoff goal.</p>
<p>Tikkanen made it 2-0 at 5:24. Messier attracted two defenders before threading a pass across to Tikkanen, who fired a shot past Brodeur.</p>
<p>McKay put the Devils on the scoreboard just 40 seconds later. He was fighting off a check right in front to the Rangers net when a rebound landed at his feet and he poked it past Mike Richter to make it 2-1.</p>
<p>In the second period, Tikkanen and Thomas traded goals 45 second apart -- at 6:41 and 7:26.</p>
<p>The Devils dominated play the rest of the way, keeping up almost constant pressure in the New York zone as the Rangers defence appeared to leave Richter to fend for himself. But the brilliant New York goalie kept his team in the game.</p>
<p>&quot;For some reason we caved in when we scored,&quot; Campbell said. &quot;We stopped hitting and they got vicious and mean and they took the game over.&quot;</p>
<p>Richter finished with 33 saves, while Brodeur, who made some remarkable saves early in the game, stopped 23 shots.</p>
<p>&quot;We were a little bit fortunate tonight,&quot; admitted Gretzky. &quot;Obviously you'd like to be in their end a little more than we were. They had us back on our heels.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANAHEIM, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
