<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="565407" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-SERIE A POOR RELATIONS FIGHT FOR ITALIAN CUP.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SERIE A POOR RELATIONS FIGHT FOR ITALIAN CUP.</headline>
<dateline>NAPLES, Italy 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Napoli and Vicenza, two of the most cash-strapped clubs in serie A, meet on Thursday in the first leg of the Italian cup final with each knowing that a European competition jackpot awaits the winners.</p>
<p>Neither club have hugely expensive stars on their books but one of them will end up in Europe next season envied by the likes of wealthy AC Milan whose poor league form seems certain to lead to a season without foreign travel.</p>
<p>Former champions Napoli, who have twice come close to financial collapse in the past three seasons, have the pedigree and past glories in their favour but little else.</p>
<p>They won the UEFA Cup in 1989, were league champions in 1987 and 1990 and have taken the Italian Cup three times.</p>
<p>They sacked coach Luigi Simone, who is moving to Inter next season, last month in a move that smacked of spite and have been heading ever further down the league table since.</p>
<p>They are 13th, after losing 2-0 to second-from-bottom Verona on Sunday, and still in danger of relegation.</p>
<p>&quot;If the most recent results are the ones that count then it should be pretty smooth for Vicenza,&quot; admitted Napoli striker Alfredo Aglietti. &quot;But don't be fooled by appearances.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody says we are in a crisis, the results show that Napoli is at a standstill. But the Cup could end all these problems. It's up to us and how we play.&quot;</p>
<p>Napoli can also count on a packed San Paolo stadium roaring them on to what would constitute their greatest achievement since the days of Diego Maradona in the late 1980s.</p>
<p>But they will be without Brazilian striker Beto, who returned from Brazil two days ago after leaving Italy without the club's approval to have further tests at home on an injured knee, and compatriot Andre Cruz in defence.</p>
<p>Vicenza, a provincial team who cannot even claim the &quot;once-great&quot; tag that accompanies Napoli, are currently run by an official receiver after their chairman was arrested on charges of suspected bankruptcy fraud.</p>
<p>The club have never won anything in their 95-year history and their only previous foray into Europe ended in the first round of the 1978-79 UEFA Cup against Dukla Prague.</p>
<p>Vicenza do have form on their side however, having led the league briefly this season for the first time ever before fading away in the New Year. But they beat third-placed Inter in Milan last weekend and are again challenging for a UEFA Cup spot.</p>
<p>Coach Francesco Guidolin has lectured his players about history, reminding them that they are on the verge of achieving something that even the great Italian striker Paolo Rossi failed to do in his time at the club in the 1970s.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a date with destiny. We know that and we are devoting all our energies to it,&quot; said the coach, who will be without defenders Luigi Sartor and Giovanni Lopez.</p>
<p>Uruguayans Marcelo Otero and Gustavo Mendez will be back in the line-up after missing the Inter match to give them a rest after international duty in South America.</p>
<p>The second leg of the final is scheduled for May 29 in Vicenza.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAPLES, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
