<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="565439" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: FOCUS-BULK OF POLISH BUY-BACK IN DISCOUNT BRADYS.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-BULK OF POLISH BUY-BACK IN DISCOUNT BRADYS.</headline>
<byline>Jan Strupczewski</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's finance ministry said the bulk of the $1.69 billion of its Brady bonds it bought back on the secondary market was discount bonds, but declined to say if it would repeat the buy-back operation in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;They were various papers, most of them were discount bonds,&quot; Wieslaw Szczuka, head of the ministry's foreign department told Reuters. Asked if in the future the ministry would buy more of Poland's debt on the secondary market, Szczuka said: &quot;No comment&quot;.</p>
<p>Prices of Poland's par and discount bonds rose 0.375 point and of the PDI bond 0.5 point on the buy-back news while RSTA bond held stable. But dealers said the operation must have been spread over many months.</p>
<p>&quot;$1.7 billion worth of Brady bonds is a huge amount for such a shallow market, so the purchases must have been done over many months so as not to move prices too much,&quot; said Jacek Lech, deputy chief dealer at Bank Handlowy SA.</p>
<p>Analysts said the operation would therefore have no visible effect on the country's official foreign reserves, whcih have been growing by a moderate $100-200 million a month in recent months.</p>
<p>The ministry said it financed the purchase, which cut Poland's foreign debt by more than four percent and reduced the outstanding amount of Bradys maturing up to October 27, 2024, to $6.05 billion, with a bond issue sold to the central bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The ministry must have used currencies from the country's reserves to buy back the Brady's, but has done it so gently, that it did not show,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>The bonds sold to the National Bank of Poland are denominated in dollars but would be serviced and redeemed in zlotys, the ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>Some analysts speculated the ministry may have decided to disclose the buy-back to the markets to improve Poland's credit rating before a planned new issue of Eurobonds later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The buy-back could mean large annual savings on debt servicing, so it is understandable why the ministry did it,&quot; a senior analyst, who declined to be named said.</p>
<p>&quot;On the other hand the reason behind the fact that they decided to tell about it and not continue buying, is that maybe they want to boost Poland's rating before a new Eurobond issue,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Poland now has a Baa3 investment grade from Moody's Investor service, BBB minus from Standard&amp;Poor's and BBB from IBCA. Under the 1997 budget it may issue up to $500 million worth of international bonds this year.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
