<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="565621" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GABON: Zaire's Mobutu arrives in Gabon for summit.</title>
<headline>Zaire's Mobutu arrives in Gabon for summit.</headline>
<dateline>LIBREVILLE 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's President Mobutu Sese Seko, battling cancer and rebel advances, arrived in Gabon's capital Libreville on Wednesday on a visit that raised speculation at home that he had left for good.</p>
<p>Witnesses said that Mobutu, who was with his wife Bobi Ladawa, looked tired and went straight to a waiting vehicle.</p>
<p>Mobutu aides in Kinshasa, which rebels say they are poised to capture, said he would attend a regional mini-summit in Libreville on efforts to broker peace in his troubled country.</p>
<p>&quot;The president will go to Libreville on Wednesday and will return on Friday,&quot; spokesman Kabuya Lumuna said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Gabon's president, Omar Bongo, host of the latest Zaire summit, welcomed the man who has dominated Africa's third largest country for over three decades.</p>
<p>Gabon's government newspaper, L'Union, reported that the summit would take place on Thursday and would bring together Mobutu, Bongo and the presidents of Congo, Central African Republic and Equatorial Guinea.</p>
<p>A Zairean government statement on Tuesday said the presidents of Cameroon and Chad would attend.</p>
<p>The talks were a follow-up to a weekend peace summit between Mobutu, rebel leader Laurent Kabila and South Africa's Nelson Mandela on a South African ship in the Congolese port of Pointe Noire, it added. That meeting proved inconclusive.</p>
<p>Mandela said he would convene fresh talks within 10 days.</p>
<p>Mobutu, 66, has seen his hold over Zaire, broken by a whirlwind rebel offensive. Kabila and his commanders, who took up arms in October, say they are building up for a final push against the capital.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GABON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIBREVILLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GABON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
