<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="565731" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish security head fired over egg-throw scandal.</title>
<headline>Polish security head fired over egg-throw scandal.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's interior minister on Wednesday fired the chief of the government agency protecting state officials after it failed to stop four Poles from flinging eggs at President Aleksander Kwasniewski in Paris.</p>
<p>Three of the Poles appeared in court in Paris, where two of them were given suspended prison terms and the third was aquitted.</p>
<p>Minister Leszek Miller said he had sacked General Miroslaw Gawor because he could not excuse mistakes by the agency, called the Government Protection Office (BOR), especially before a visit of Pope John Paul II starting on May 31.</p>
<p>&quot;BOR's mistakes, especially before the Pope's visit, cannot be tolerated,&quot; Miller told reporters. He said he appointed BOR's deputy head Colonel Henryk Sobczyk as its new chief.</p>
<p>The rightists targeted Kwasniewski, a former communist turned social democrat, and his wife Jolanta with eggs last Sunday as they entered a Champs Elysees theatre in Paris.</p>
<p>The projectiles missed Kwasniewski, who had come to Paris to see President Jacques Chirac.</p>
<p>But Polish media reported that his wife and one of his aides were hit and were planning law suits against their attackers, who were detained by police.</p>
<p>Lukasz Kazmierczak, and Woytek Wybranowski, both 23, were sentenced to three months suspended prison terms each in Paris.</p>
<p>They were also ordered to pay yet-to-be-determined damages to the aide who was hit while a third accused, Piotr Grzmeski, 25, was found not guilty. No mention was made of a fourth man.</p>
<p>The public prosecutor had asked for six-month suspended sentences against the trio, who were accused of premeditated assault. They said their action was &quot;a political joke&quot;.</p>
<p>The Polish Foreign Ministry on Tuesday sent a note to France, which was officially responsible for Kwasniewski's security in Paris, urging it to step up protection measures for visiting officials to avoid similar events in the future.</p>
<p>Kwasniewski's attackers, who travelled to Paris precisely to hurl eggs at the president, come from two small, virtually unknown rightist groups.</p>
<p>They and other bigger organisations, rooted in the former opposition to the communist system, say Kwasniewski and his political allies from the co-ruling ex-communist Democratic Left Alliance should be disqualified from politics because of their involvement in the old regime before 1989.</p>
<p>Kwasniewski was elected in 1995. His party emerged victorious from parliamentary elections two years earlier.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
