<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="565733" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia adopts new vision for national security.</title>
<headline>Russia adopts new vision for national security.</headline>
<byline>Alastair Macdonald</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian leaders, squaring up to the impending expansion of Moscow's old Cold War foe NATO, adopted a programme on Wednesday laying out a new vision of national security to see the country into the 21st century.</p>
<p>The Security Council, chaired by President Boris Yeltsin, approved the document at a meeting in the Kremlin, the presidential press service said.</p>
<p>Among key concepts and recommendations, the 30-page text states that social upheaval and economic crisis pose greater risks than any military threat, an official told Itar-Tass news agency. No details of the document were announced.</p>
<p>Tass said the priorities would be &quot;strengthening social stability&quot; and completing and developing notions of statehood and federalism, as well as ensuring a return to economic growth.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, who again pledged to forge ahead with slimming down and modernising Russia's vast but impoverished armed forces, also warned, however, that Moscow had to take steps to limit any threat to its security from NATO's eastward enlargement.</p>
<p>The alliance, at a summit in Madrid in July, is expected to invite three ex-communist nations, Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic, to join its ranks.</p>
<p>Yeltsin told the Council, including the prime minister and his first deputies, the defence, interior and justice ministers and others, that the government had a responsibility to take account of NATO's planned expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;What should we do? Either leave ourselves open or somehow give ourselves good cover in the East? We have to think seriously about this,&quot; Tass quoted Yeltsin as saying.</p>
<p>Yeltsin appeared to referring to attempts to forge better ties with China and other Asian countries.</p>
<p>Yeltsin told Krasnaya Zvezda, the Defence Ministry newspaper, in an interview that he would do everything possible to minimise the consequences of NATO expansion, including deepening integration with other former Soviet states, such as Belarus, and with China and other neighbours.</p>
<p>Kremlin spokesman Sergei Yastrzhembsky told a news briefing that Moscow was still not satisfied with NATO's proposals for a charter designed to assuage Russia's worries over expansion. He said &quot;much more effort&quot; was needed if a deal were to be struck, as planned, for signing on May 27.</p>
<p>He said Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov and NATO Secretary General Javier Solana, who have held intensive talks in Luxembourg, had made some progress. They will meet again, in Moscow, on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Yeltsin pledged to improve the economic lot of service personnel while promoting a transition to a smaller, better-trained professional army without conscription. He also criticised the slow pace of reform in the armed forces.</p>
<p>The defence ministry has complained that government defence cuts of about 30 percent in the 1997 budget, forced this month by a 40 percent shortfall in tax revenues, risk undermining the nation's security.</p>
<p>But Yastrzhembsky said Yeltsin would not make any changes in the budget plans which were submitted to parliament this week.</p>
<p>The armed forces are preparing for Friday's celebrations of the 52nd anniversary of the 1945 victory over Nazi Germany.</p>
<p>Yeltsin will review troops at the first Victory Day military parade on Red Square for five years. But unlike in Soviet days, tanks and missiles will not roll by.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
