<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="565705" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - May 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - May 7.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are significant stories in the Nigerian press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>- Cameroon launches fresh attack on Nigerian troops in disputed Bakassi peninsula in the southeast but no casualties reported on either side.</p>
<p>- State-owned National Insurance Corporation of Nigeria acquires federal government's 60 percent stake in Nigeria-Arab Bank and approves injection of 850 million naira into the bank to shore up its capital base by 650 percent.</p>
<p>- Some of the banks sealed up last month after failing to raise their capital base as ordered by the authorities are to be reopened to enable their debtors who have chosen to pay up rather than face trial at failed bank tribunals do so.</p>
<p>- Military ruler General Sani Abacha approves that 1.4 billion naira should be spent to combat erosion along Lagos Marina lagoon front.</p>
<p>THISDAY</p>
<p>- Warri refinery in the midewest, which was shut last week because of ethnic clashes in the area, has reopened. Top army and navy commanders shift their operational bases to Warri to ensure rival tribes there maintain peace.</p>
<p>- Human rights activist and lawyer Gani Fawehinmi files a suit in court seeking the release of 67 bank executives detained since 1995 for alleged fraud that bankrupted their banks.</p>
<p>MIDWEEK CONCORD</p>
<p>- State-owned Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation moves its European office to Paris from London.</p>
<p>- Inter-bank lending rates have risen to 15 percent, their highest level this year, following the withdrawal of a big tranche of funds from banks by the Petroleum Trust Fund, which disburses money accruing from a 1994 increase in pump prices.</p>
<p>($1=85 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
