<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="565875" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: FOCUS - MOL int'l price no surprise - analysts.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - MOL int'l price no surprise - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Michael Roddy</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The pricing of an initial public offering in Hungarian oil and gas company MOL Rt at $16.25 per share internationally was no surprise while the domestic price should spark local interest, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;That is generally what we expected it to come, at a discount to the closing price in the market,&quot; Stephen O'Sullivan, head of research at MC Securities in London, said after privatisation agency APV Rt announced the price on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A discount of more than seven percent on the domestic offer, which is priced at 2,970 forints, below the Tuesday closing price of 3,220, should spur domestic interest in the placement that starts on May 12, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;That's slightly on the aggressive side,&quot; said Roger Monson, chief equity strategist for Daiwa Europe in London.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a fairly wide discount especially when you're given the relatively limited size of the offering domestically, so that should move it well,&quot; Monson said.</p>
<p>APV Rt, Hungary's privatisation agency, announced in a statement that its international offering in MOL for a 12.5 percent stake, with a 2.5 percent over-allotment option, had been priced at $16.25 per share.</p>
<p>Gabor Hegy, an official of a public relations firm retained by APV, said the private placement was six times oversubscribed.</p>
<p>In addition, APV is offering a one percent stake domestically, with a three percent over-allotment, at 2,970 Hungarian forints, with placement to start on May 12.</p>
<p>MOL shares closed on Tuesday at 3,220 HUF, up 20 but below the year high of 3,790.</p>
<p>Another London analyst, who asked to remain anonymous, said he was surprised by the international pricing.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought $16.50 would be the lowest, and it's $16.25, a good discount to where the market has been,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Stephenson said strong domestic Hungarian interest in the issue might have justified higher prices.</p>
<p>&quot;There seems to be very strong domestic demand and people have been suggesting that the price would have been higher as a result of that -- finding domestic buyers willing to pay higher prices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But they obviously are concerned about the aftermarket as well,&quot; Stephenson said.</p>
<p>Monson said the domestic pricing should give Hungarians a good opportunity.</p>
<p>&quot;It should give people a chance to see a little bit of black on their account on top of the obvious attractions of the company over the next two or three years as we have price deregulation...that's the key attraction, of course.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
