<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56591" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Sears edgy as market expects the worst.</title>
<headline>Sears edgy as market expects the worst.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in retailer Sears Plc were trading nervously in heavy volume on Monday as the market braced itself for the worst from first-half results due on Tuesday.</p>
<p>One analyst said the firm's results may come in even lower than the already bearish consensus forecasts for a 14 percent decline from a year ago, and warned that downgrades may come swiftly after the figures.</p>
<p>&quot;It's one of the walking wounded at the moment,&quot; said Rowan Morgan, a retail analyst at Nikko Europe in London.</p>
<p>Morgan forecasting a 25.0 million stg first-half pretax profit, less than the consensus view of 25.6 million stg.  </p>
<p>&quot;They are going to be lucky to make even that (25.0 million stg),&quot; Morgan said. &quot;We will probably see some downgrading on the figures.</p>
<p>The retailer made first-half profits before tax of 29.9 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Sears shares were 1-1/2 pence lower at 96-1/2 at 1040 GMT with volume topping the 3.5 million mark.</p>
<p>Some analysts said most of the expected bad news was already priced in. They said talk that Sears may be considering selling off its property division in Scotland would do little to improve the market's gloomy view of the stock.  </p>
<p>&quot;The property transaction being talked about would not make any difference whatsoever,&quot; said Morgan. &quot;If they do do it, they will make money out of it, but it is not going to make people enthusiastic about trading the stock.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Kate Kelland, London Newsroom +44 171 542 4026</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
