<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="565923" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: CVRD shrs seen stable till new owner sets strategy.</title>
<headline>CVRD shrs seen stable till new owner sets strategy.</headline>
<byline>James Craig</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Both series of Cia Vale do Rio Doce (CVRD) stock should steady and remain on an even keel until its new owners spell out plans for the mining giant, analysts said.</p>
<p>CVRD's preferred share, a blue chip on the Sao Paulo bolsa, and its less liquid common shares have traced different paths since the announcement of the CVRD auction up to today's trade.  </p>
<p>But analysts said they expect both series to stay close to home, or even stagnate, for the near term while the bourse as a whole rises.</p>
<p>&quot;The trend will be stable,&quot; said Marcelo Mesquita, an analyst at Banco de Investimentos Garantia SA.</p>
<p>After a sharp run-up prior to the auction, CVRD preferred took a hard 8.09 percent skid today as investors repriced the stock in disappointment that the premium at Tuesday's auction was not higher and that the rival bidding group did not clinch the auction.  </p>
<p>For the moment, traders see both series stable near the 26.67 real base price asked by the government, in spite of the fact that the winning CSN consortium paid 32 reais per share with its 3.34 billion real ($3.15 billion) bid for a 41.73 percent stake of voting, or common shares.</p>
<p>CVRD common stock has traded around 28.90 reais since April 28, the eve of the original auction date. The stock closed at that level today, the day after the sale actually took place.</p>
<p>The preferred share closed today at 25.55 reais.  </p>
<p>Near-term, the market maybe hashing out whether it thinks the base price or the auction price represents the fair value of the company.</p>
<p>&quot;The market thinks the minimum price was the real price of CVRD,&quot; said Adriana Lacombe, an analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is waiting for the consortium that bought CVRD to say what their plans are, why they saw a return at that price,&quot; Mesquita said.  </p>
<p>The winning CSN bid was 20 percent above the government-set price, but analysts said many investors had forecast a 30 percent premium. They also expected the auction to go to CSN group's competitor -- a consortium led by Brazil's Votorantim group that was perceived as stronger.</p>
<p>CSN chief Benjamin Steinbruch, who has been dubbed Brazil's new &quot;Steel Baron,&quot; told reporters his group planned no major changes in CVRD in the next six months, almost year-end, and denied reports it may spin off assets.</p>
<p>But the comments did not directly address what the group plans to do with the firm, analysts said.  </p>
<p>Mesquita noted that the earliest point at which CVRD may rack up significant gains may be some time in the fall, when the government is expected to offer a 28 percent voting stake on world markets.</p>
<p>&quot;People will now wait for the global offering&quot; before venturing into CVRD stock, he said.</p>
<p>Despite the uncertainty, analysts said the sell-off has had a positive overall impact on the market because it shows the government's determination to push ahead with privatization.</p>
<p>&quot;For the market, the news was very positive,&quot; Caspian Securities analysts said in a report.</p>
<p>&quot;The selling of CVRD should boost investors' confidence in the privatization process...and should make future privatization plans more accessible,&quot; they added.</p>
<p>((-- James Craig, Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 2485413))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
