<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="566057" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil CVRD sale takes mining analysts by surprise.</title>
<headline>Brazil CVRD sale takes mining analysts by surprise.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Bulloch</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>A consortium led by local steelmaker CSN was the surprise buyer of the controlling stake of Brazilian state mining giant Companhia Vale do Rio Doce (CVRD), mining analysts said.</p>
<p>Many had anticipated a second consortium, led by the family-run Votorantim group and South African mining group Anglo-American Corp, would easily snap up the maximum 45 percent voting stake put up for sale today.</p>
<p>But it was not to be.</p>
<p>&quot;I really am amazed,&quot; said independent consultant Peter Rich. &quot;For Anglo-American, this must have been something they really wanted,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The CSN consortium paid 3.338 billion reais ($3.15 billion) for a 41.73 percent voting stake in CVRD. At 32 reais a share, the government received a 19.98 percent premium on the 26.67 reais per share minimum price.</p>
<p>&quot;The CSN consortium was very aggressive. This was at the high end of our expectations as we expected the final share price to be 15 to 20 percent above the minimum price,&quot; said Alberto Arias, Latin American mining analyst at SBC Warburg.</p>
<p>After being postponed several times because of a flood of court injunctions, the auction finally got under way this morning but was stopped in midflow by court officials carrying yet another court order, suspending the sale.</p>
<p>The auction was eventually resumed later in the day but the week of delays probably took its toll on the Votorantim consortium which also included a group of 11 Japanese steelmakers and trading comnpanies led by Nippon Steel Corp, Rich said.</p>
<p>&quot;I reckon the Japanese got annoyed with the whole thing. They had already started complaining to Votorantim and I wouldn't mind betting they got cold feet,&quot; Rich said.</p>
<p>The jewel in the company's crown is iron ore. Thanks to the mine at Carajas in the northern state in Para, the company is the world's largest iron ore producer and exporter.</p>
<p>The company posted a 1996 profit of $632 million, has total assets of $10.4 billion and annual sales of $5 billion.</p>
<p>But apart from iron ore, the Carajas region is also rich in other minerals. The Salobo mine located in the area is expected to produce an annual 300,000 tonnes of copper, 14 tonnes of silver and three tonnes of gold by 2001.</p>
<p>CVRD is already Latin Americas's largest gold producer, with output totaling 18 tonnes of gold in 1996 and plans to produce 31 tonnes of gold by 2001.</p>
<p>In February last year President Fernando Henrique Cardoso announced the discovery of a deposit in Serra Leste, Para state, which is expected to hold at least 150 tonnes.</p>
<p>The company is only expected to have more concrete indications of the extent of the deposit by the end of this year and there had been criticism the government was selling off untold mineral wealth for a pittance.</p>
<p>But in April this year it signed a risk contract with the government's National Development Bank (BNDES) which gives each the right to 50 percent of the mineral wealth found after CVRD's privatisation.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the government has hedged itself against any potential risk,&quot; Arias said.</p>
<p>CVRD is also involved in many of Brazil's aluminium production units through its aluminium holding Aluvale as well as having a key role in bauxite and alumina production.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically a large part of Brazil's bauxite and a large part of its alumina production are inside the CVRD system,&quot; one industry source said.</p>
<p>Prior to the auction, many mining analysts speculated that should the CSN consortium emerge as the winner, it might spin off various activities such as the company's gold, aluminium, pulp and paper businesses.</p>
<p>But at a press conference after the auction CSN chairman Benjamin Steinbruch said there were no plans to split up CVRD.</p>
<p>For the time being there are no mining companies directly involved in the consortium although South African mining company Gencor Ltd did sign a letter of intent to join, should the consortium win.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not clear what is the agreement between Gencor and the CSN consortium at this time,&quot; Arias said.</p>
<p>Gencor already has a direct presence in Brazil through its offshore arm Billiton which is involved in aluminium production here, including a venture with Aluvale, called Valesul.</p>
<p>With South African gold production falling at around five to six percent a year, Gencor may well be attracted to join the group for the same reasons as Anglo-American, Rich said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is certainly a trend in all the major mining companies to go after elephant-sized projects. And Carajas is elephant country,&quot; Rich said.</p>
<p>((-Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 5074151))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
