<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="566136" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: ITT sees Hilton bid as helpful.</title>
<headline>ITT sees Hilton bid as helpful.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK, Thailand</dateline>
<text>
<p>A $6.5 billion hostile takeover bid by Hilton Hotels Corp. for ITT Corp. has strengthened ITT, which hopes to get leaner and raise shareholder value to avoid a takeover, an ITT official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;In a sense it had a very positive impact,&quot; said Daniel Weadock, senior vice-president of ITT and chief executive of the company's wholly-owned hotel group, ITT Sheraton Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a long-term plan to be implemented over a 3-1/2- to four-year period. Long term became nine months, once Hilton announced the takeover plan,&quot; Weadock said in an interview during a visit to Thailand.</p>
<p>ITT has been selling properties and assets it has deemed to be &quot;non-core&quot; to focus on the hotels and gambling businesses in an effort to thwart the hostile bid launched by Hilton in January.</p>
<p>Among the higher-profile assets sold by ITT were its 50 percent stake in New York's Madison Square Garden and a portion of its stake in French telecommunications company Alcatel Alsthom.</p>
<p>Weadock said the company's goal is to increase ITT's share price and convince shareholders against a takeover by Hilton.</p>
<p>He said a realistic goal for the share price this year could be about $80.</p>
<p>ITT stock was at $59.875 on Wednesday, down 62.5 cents, and has risen from about $42 before Hilton launched the offer. The stock has consistently traded above Hilton's bid on views that Hilton could raise its bid.</p>
<p>Hilton launched a $55-per-share cash and stock bid for ITT in late January. ITT rejected the bid, calling it inadequate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK, Thailand"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
