<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="566108" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong to be more democratic in 10 years - Tung.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong to be more democratic in 10 years - Tung.</headline>
<byline>Dominic Lau</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's future leader Tung Chee-hwa, mired in controversy over a plan to curb political liberties, said the territory would become more democratic but only gradually.</p>
<p>Tung flew to Beijing early on Wednesday to discuss a raft of outstanding problems facing him in Hong Kong's final 55 days as a British colony with Chinese Foreign Minister Qian Qichen and China's Hong Kong policy chief Lu Ping.</p>
<p>&quot;Actually over the next 10 years, we have a very progressive but orderly development of a political structure which will become increasingly democratic,&quot; Tung, anointed by China to run Hong Kong after Beijing resumes sovereignty on July 1, said in an interview with CNBC Asia Television aired on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He was referring to the gradual democratisation envisaged in the Basic Law, Hong Kong's post-handover constitution promulgated by China in 1990.</p>
<p>Tung said Hong Kong was following a path of development set by other Asian nations.</p>
<p>&quot;In Asia...economic success and freedom has preceded political development,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;And in Hong Kong, of course, we have tremendous economic success and economic freedom, and political freedom...is something as a colony we really never had until about six years ago... we are now developing it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tung's burdens in running Hong Kong include hefty public opposition to his China-inspired plan to whittle down civil liberties, restricting protest rights and foreign funding of local political parties.</p>
<p>On Wednesday a key member of Tung's cabinet signalled that the government-in-waiting might soften the controversial proposals as the public had demanded for a more liberal approach during a three-week pulsetaking of views on the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;There are many proposals that have been put forward to us,&quot; Henry Tang, a member of Tung's future Executive Council, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;In the consultation exercise, there are more liberal (proposals) than what is in the consultation document,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm saying that yes, I think, some of them are worthy of our consideration and they will be considered and finalised.&quot;</p>
<p>The pro-democracy camp and lawyers in Hong Kong have strongly protested the proposed curbs.</p>
<p>Signs also emerged on Wednesday that the vast array of grand celebrations planned by various groups in Hong Kong to mark the historic handover were posing further headaches for Tung.</p>
<p>Most groups staging events were awaiting final approval from Tung's short-staffed government-in-waiting, a pro-China association organising handover events said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It said it hoped to meet Tung within the next two weeks to finalise the celebration programme straddling the sovereignty change, which takes place at midnight on June 30.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Tung told Reuters none of the events mentioned required Tung's approval, however. &quot;None of them requires approval from Mr Tung's office. There is no question of any delay arising from a lack of confirmation from this office.&quot;</p>
<p>The main events are already organised -- a sunset military parade by the British on the evening of June 30 and a joint Sino-British ceremony with 4,000 dignitaries at midnight.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
