<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="566107" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Deputy PM Anwar to run Malaysia while Mahathir away.</title>
<headline>Deputy PM Anwar to run Malaysia while Mahathir away.</headline>
<byline>K. Baranee Krishnaan</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian deputy premier Anwar Ibrahim will run the country when Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad goes away on a work-and-vacation mission which could last two months, government officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The 49-year-old Anwar will be acting prime minister in the absence of his boss, who will be visiting a number of countries to promote Malaysia's new technology zone, the Multimedia Super Corridor, the officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no secret here. The PM will be going on leave for two months and Anwar will be the acting PM,&quot; Nazri Aziz, deputy minister in the prime minister's department, told reporters.</p>
<p>Officials said Anwar, also Malaysia's finance minister, will handle Mahathir's powerful home ministry post as well.</p>
<p>Mahathir, currently winding up a visit to African countries, was scheduled to return home on Thursday and make an announcement about his mission, which could start late May.</p>
<p>News of his impending leave -- reportedly the longest he has ever planned since becoming prime minister in 1981 -- stirred up much speculation in financial markets on Wednesday. Dealers said the speculation helped weaken the local ringgit currency.</p>
<p>Most of the talk centred on whether Mahathir would be testing the governing abilities of Anwar, widely regarded as his most natural successor.</p>
<p>Another concern was that Mahathir's health was failing, although officials firmly denied that the 71-year-old premier, who had a heart operation eight years ago, was ill in any way.</p>
<p>&quot;This has nothing to do with his health,&quot; a government source told Reuters.</p>
<p>Transport Minister Ling Liong Sik told reporters Mahathir was scheduled to visit London and a number of eastern European countries such as Poland and Russia to discuss bilateral issues and promote the Multimedia Super Corridor -- a planned high-tech zone which will extend south from the capital Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>The opposition saw the move as a ploy by Mahathir to re-assess his own political strength and that of the government.</p>
<p>&quot;You take a step back, watch the weaknesses and strengths in your government while you're gone, and then ponder on ways to improve things. He's right to do it,&quot; said Lim Guan Eng, deputy secretary-general of the Democratic Action Party, Malaysia's largest opposition party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
