<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="566151" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: FOCUS - Malaysian Hock Hua's Sabah unit acquired.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Malaysian Hock Hua's Sabah unit acquired.</headline>
<byline>Madhav Reddy</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Associates of Malaysian government economic adviser Daim Zainuddin said on Wednesday they were taking over small bank Hock Hua (Sabah) Bhd for 190 million ringgit ($75.7 million).</p>
<p>The move is seen by financial analysts as a precursor of bigger things for the tiny bank situated in Sabah state on Borneo island, including a possible merger with another bank.</p>
<p>Previously unknown private firm Langkah Bahagia Sdn Bhd announced it was buying a 51.8 percent stake in the bank and plans to raise the bank's shareholders' funds to one billion ringgit.</p>
<p>Langkah Bahagia will make a mandatory general takeover offer for the remaining shares of Hock Hua Sabah it does not already own. Malaysia British Assurance Bhd holds a roughly 12 percent stake in the bank.</p>
<p>The 12-branch bank was a subsidiary of listed Hock Hua Bank Bhd.</p>
<p>&quot;We have received the approval of the minister of finance and (central) Bank Negara Malaysia to acquire 51.8 percent in Hock Hua Bank Sabah Bhd,&quot; Mohd Nasir Ali, director of Langkah Bahagia, said in a speech at a news conference.</p>
<p>He said Langkah aimed to increase the shareholders' funds of Hock Hua Sabah to one billion ringgit in order to attain &quot;Tier-1&quot; status under Malaysia's two tier banking system. Tier-1 banks operate in a more liberal regulatory environment.</p>
<p>Nasir said to boost the shareholders' funds, Langkah Bahagia may opt for cash or asset injections. &quot;It could also go public,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The bank reported net profit of 8.597 million ringgit in 1996, against 6.136 million the year before.</p>
<p>Nasir said Daim, an influential politician who is a trusted aide of Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad, is an interested party but has no management say.</p>
<p>&quot;Tun (Daim) is an interested party in the deal. I am a nominee for a certain percentage of his shares,&quot; Nasir said. &quot;Tun is just an investor,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Analysts said 190 million ringgit was a fair price to pay for a banking licence, a rare commodity as the central bank has not issued any new licences in more than two decades.</p>
<p>&quot;The deal's price is about right. It's a pretty good price to pay for a banking licence,&quot; said Chan Wee Lee, banking analyst at Jupiter Securities.</p>
<p>Analysts said the move to increase the bank's capital means that bigger things are afoot for Hock Hua Sabah, especially with Daim seen playing an important background role.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think that this is the end of the exercise. I think it will be merged with another bank,&quot; said Tan Pye Sen, analyst at Pesaka Jardine Fleming.</p>
<p>Questioned about the possible injection of Hock Hua Sabah into UCM Industrial Corp Bhd, of which Nasir is a director, he said that UCM, which has a stockbroking arm, was undergoing a restructuring exercise of its own. &quot;For the time being, we are not going to (bring it) under UCM&quot;, Nasir said.</p>
<p>($1=2.51 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
