<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="566225" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Chinese grain stores reach record - paper.</title>
<headline>Chinese grain stores reach record - paper.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A 42 percent hike in the price the Chinese government pays farmers for their grain has helped push official purchases to a record so far in 1997, the China Securities newspaper said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>By the end of March 1997, grain purchases for addition to state reserves totalled 11.85 million tonnes, 2.41 million tonnes more than at the end of March 1996, it said.</p>
<p>Of this figure, 4.9 million tonnes was purchased by the central authorities, up 560,000 tonnes on 1996.</p>
<p>A further 4.87 million tonnes were purchased by city authorities, up 500,000 tonnes on 1996.</p>
<p>Central reserve authorities purchased 2.08 million tonnes, up 158,000 tonnes on the period to the end of March 1996.</p>
<p>There had been no recurrence of past problems, such as unwillingness of peasants to sell their grain, nor of having to issue &quot;white strips&quot; or IOU's, the paper said.</p>
<p>It did not say how much the farmers had been paid.</p>
<p>By the end of March, grain bureaux had sold 7.05 million tonnes of grain from the 1996 harvest into the market, a fall of 2.2 million tonnes on the same period of a year ago. Of that 2.62 million tonnes was sold at a state-set price, 247,000 tonnes less than in the same period of 1996.</p>
<p>City grain bureaux sold 2.72 million tonnes, 52,500 less than they had by the end of March 1996, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>Other sales accounted for 1.71 million tonnes, 440,000 less than at the same time last year, it said.</p>
<p>China's total 1996 grain harvest was an official record of 490 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Between September 1996 and April 20, 1997, a total of 6.25 million tonnes of grain had been transported from the northeast and Inner Mongolia to large and medium-sized cities and areas where grain shortages were available, it said.</p>
<p>By the end of March, 5.16 million tonnes of grain from the 1996 harvest had been added to grain bureau stocks, it said.</p>
<p>Stockpile figures are treated as a state secret in China.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-8544</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
