<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="566584" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Drugmakers settle with AIDS-infected hemophiliacs.</title>
<headline>Drugmakers settle with AIDS-infected hemophiliacs.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Drawbaugh</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four drug manufacturers whose blood products allegedly infected thousands of U.S. haemophiliacs with the AIDS virus in the early 1980s will pay about $670 million in a settlement approved by a federal judge.</p>
<p>Under the settlement approved Tuesday, 6,000 haemophiliacs will each receive $100,000. An earlier settlement in Japan paid AIDS-infected haemophiliacs $450,000 each.</p>
<p>The settlement is &quot;one of the most horrible scenarios that can be imagined,&quot; said Ron Niederman, spokesman for the Committee of Ten Thousand, which represents the haemophiliacs.</p>
<p>&quot;In light of the damage they caused, the companies are getting off cheap,&quot; Niederman said in an interview.</p>
<p>While admitting no wrongdoing, the companies agreeing to settle were Germany's Bayer AG, Japan's Green Cross Corp., Franco-American Rhone-Poulenc Rorer Inc. and Deerfield, Ill.-based Baxter International Inc.</p>
<p>Combined, the companies will pay a total of up to about $670 million, said Rhone-Poulenc spokesman Guy Esnouf.</p>
<p>Of that sum, about $600 million will go to individual haemophiliacs, he said.</p>
<p>To resolve insurance complications and ensure that the haemophiliacs will be able to keep their money, the companies will pay $12 million to the federal government and $18 million to 25 state governments and private insurers, he said.</p>
<p>In addition, the companies face up to $40 million in legal fees, Esnouf said.</p>
<p>Bayer will shoulder 45 percent of the total cost; Baxter and Rhone-Poulenc 20 percent each; and Green Cross 15 percent.</p>
<p>The office of U.S. District Court Judge John Grady confirmed that he granted oral formal approval to the settlement on Tuesday. The settlement had won preliminary court approval in April 1996.</p>
<p>The settlement does not entirely end the decade-old controversy stemming from the infection of 6,000 to 8,000 U.S. haemophiliacs by contaminated Factor VIII and Factor IX blood clotting agents.</p>
<p>Another 550 haemophiliacs opted out of the class-action settlement and may pursue litigation against the companies on their own, said Niederman, who is among those opting out and plans to press his case &quot;to the bitter end.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody wins these class action things but the lawyers,&quot; he said. &quot;The litigants get pennies and the lawyers walk away with pots of money.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition, the companies are still in discussions with 25 other states and Prudential Insurance Co. of America over settling remaining insurance matters, Esnouf said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
