<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="566674" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fight against inflation seen critical -- Atlanta Fed.</title>
<headline>Fight against inflation seen critical -- Atlanta Fed.</headline>
<dateline>BOCA RATON, Fla. 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Reserve, watchful of tight U.S. labor markets and aware that productivity may be understated, views it as critical to prevent inflation from edging back up, Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta President Jack Guynn said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Confidence we are going to keep inflation low has made a major contribution to economic growth,&quot; Guynn told reporters at a conference of the Bankers Association for Foreign Trade.</p>
<p>&quot;It is absolutely critical that we keep inflation from creeping back up again,&quot; Guynn added.  </p>
<p>Guynn said one important factor in assessing the implications for inflation of tight labor markets and robust growth is the measurement of productivity.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of things that look different about the economy this time around that we are trying to understand,&quot; Guynn said, adding that businessmen in the Atlanta Fed district he met on Tuesday reported continued investments in high-tech equipment boosting productivity.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not something that happens once, it's a continuing process. Only time will tell if the kind of productivity we hear about will continue,&quot; Guynn stated.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOCA RATON, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
