<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="566700" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy threatens pull-out if Albania deal collapses.</title>
<headline>Italy threatens pull-out if Albania deal collapses.</headline>
<byline>Jude Webber</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy said on Wednesday the multinational security force it is leading in Albania should pull out if a deal among political parties that provides for early elections comes to grief.</p>
<p>Defence Minister Beniamino Andreatta told parliament the mission went ahead because of an accord by the parties in Tirana two months ago which installed an interim unity government and agreed to hold early elections by the end of June.</p>
<p>&quot;The mission is linked to the compromise which should lead to elections in June,&quot; Andreatta said.</p>
<p>&quot;If this agreement fails, both the United Nations and the governments involved...should look again at the reasons for the mission and proceed with its withdrawal,&quot; he said during question time in the Chamber of Deputies (lower house).</p>
<p>His comments, the first indication that the force could be pulled out early, came as European mediator Franz Vranitzky flew to Tirana for talks with Prime Minister Bashkim Fino and President Sali Berisha, who are at odds over election rules.</p>
<p>Vranitzky's latest mission will seek to unblock an impasse over electoral procedure that threatens to scupper the vote.</p>
<p>Albanians hope the election will restore stability to Europe's poorest state after a wave of violence swept the country in March after the collapse of dubious savings schemes.</p>
<p>Vranitzky, an envoy of the Organisation for Security and Co-operation in Europe, said during his last visit in April that Albanian parties wanted to hold the general election on June 29.</p>
<p>But a fifth round of talks between political parties failed to agree on a voting system on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Diplomatic sources in Rome said Italy was not so much concerned about the election date as by the failure so far of Albania's squabbling parties to find common ground on the rules.</p>
<p>&quot;The date of the vote could slip if the parties agree,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>Albania's parliament, where Berisha's rightist Democratic Party holds the majority, only has until May 15 to agree on an electoral procedure if the vote is to take place on June 29.</p>
<p>Parliament must be dissolved for 45 days before an election.</p>
<p>If, as expected, Fino's government approves a draft law this week on the electoral system, it is likely to be sent to parliament with a confidence vote attached, Jorgji Kote, a spokesman for Fino, said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The government would therefore fall if the bill is defeated. &quot;This will mean a return to chaos and anarchy,&quot; Kote said.</p>
<p>The parties are deadlocked on three points -- which voting system to use, how to deal with so-called citizens' committees set up during the unrest and how to interpret an anti-genocide law which bans ex-communists from standing for office.</p>
<p>Fino's Socialist Party are the former communists.</p>
<p>Rome has previously said it expected the eight-nation force, the first such mission to be led by Italy, to remain in Albania until one month after the vote. Its mandate may be extended by the United Nations.</p>
<p>The force began deploying last month to secure aid deliveries but is not authorised to act as a police force or to collect the thousands of weapons looted from state arsenals when law and order disintegrated.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
