<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="566860" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India call ends easy, gilt prices up in light trade.</title>
<headline>India call ends easy, gilt prices up in light trade.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian call money ended Wednesday at 7.5-8.5 percent against the Tuesday's close of 8.75-9.25 as the impact of central bank dollar purchases was felt by the domestic money market, dealers said.</p>
<p>Call money opened Wednesdayt at 8.0-9.0 percent.</p>
<p>Dealers said Reserve Bank of India (RBI) dollar purchases injected liquidity into the banking system and helped push call money rates down.</p>
<p>Dealers estimate RBI's combined dollar purchases on Monday and Tuesday at $300-400 million. The RBI bought dollars again on Wednesday, pushing the rupee down against the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;They (RBI) were buying spot dollars,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;So rupees came in today from Monday's (dollar) purchases.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said call money could be easy next week on inflows from RBI's continuing forex market intervention and interest payments on government securities despite a 30 billion rupee bond issue on Friday.</p>
<p>The RBI auctions 30 billion rupees of five-year central government bonds on May 9.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected a cut-off rate of around 12.60 percent at the auction despite secondary market yields of around 12.75 percent for securities of similar maturity.</p>
<p>Dealers said there were indications from the RBI it wanted banks to bid at lower yields at the auction than current secondary market yields.</p>
<p>&quot;Current high call money rates are an aberration and have pushed yields up,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;Rates should come down to around 6.0 percent next week. So 12.60 percent may be reasonable for five-year paper.&quot;</p>
<p>Interbank term money rates rose to 9.0-9.5 percent for 30 days maturity, dealers said.</p>
<p>Last week 90-day money had been quoted in the same range.</p>
<p>Prices of government securities rose in thin trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>The 13.05 percent 2007 government stock was in demand and buying by an insurance company moved its price up 100.55 rupees from 100.10, dealers said.</p>
<p>The 13.85 percent 2000 stock rose to 105.25 rupees from 104.25, 13.50 percent 1997 to 101.64 from 101.50 and 13.50 percent 1998 to 102.70 from 102.45, dealers said.</p>
<p>Yields on treasury bills maturing in April 1998 fell to 9.30 percent from 9.35 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>The money market is largely inactive on Thursday as banks in India's commercial capital of Bombay are closed for a local holiday. They reopen on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Suresh Gonsalves , Bombay newsroom +91 22 265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
