<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567232" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Hunting bids to fly DHL Airbus freighters.</title>
<headline>Hunting bids to fly DHL Airbus freighters.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hunting Cargo Airlines said it is bidding to operate up to five converted Airbus A300B4 freighters on behalf of DHL Worldwide Express.</p>
<p>The UK carrier's commercial manager Steve Guynan told Reuters the proposal was for Hunting to fly the aircraft after they had been &quot;sourced&quot; -- leased or purchased -- by the express giant.</p>
<p>He said he expected a decision to be taken by DHL on its Airbus operating plans &quot;in six to seven weeks&quot;.</p>
<p>Guynan added that &quot;in due course Hunting Cargo might be interested&quot; in acquiring its own A300B4 freighters.</p>
<p>&quot;We will see how things go with DHL,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On April 16, Gordon Olafson, managing director of DHL's sister company European Air Transport (EAT), told Reuters that DHL hoped to be operating two leased, converted A300B4 freighters on routes linking Scandinavia, the UK, Iberia and possibly Istanbul and Greece with Brussels in the last quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>Among the leasing options, he said, were two former Egyptair A300s now being converted into 45-tonne capacity freighters at Dresden for U.S. leasing company Pinnacle, and up to 13 conversion orders for the aircraft type negotiated by U.S. lessor C-S Aviation Services with British Aerospace Plc.</p>
<p>Hunting Cargo currently operates its own Boeing 727Fs and Lockheed Electras on behalf of DHL on various European routes, said Guynan.</p>
<p>Its current owned all-cargo fleet comprises six 727Fs and six Electras. Additionally, it flies four 727 freighters for their owner, TNT Express Worldwide, and leases one Lockheed Hercules.</p>
<p>-Bob Murphy, Reuters Air Cargo Service Tel+ 44 171 542 7706; fax +5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
