<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567326" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: TURKISH SHARES SOAR 3.14 PCT AS VOLUME JUMPS.</title>
<headline>TURKISH SHARES SOAR 3.14 PCT AS VOLUME JUMPS.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Istanbul shares surged an average 3.14 percent amid selective purchases on Wednesday with the help of liquidity inflow which boosted volume, brokers said.</p>
<p>The IMKB National-100  .ISEC closed 45 points, or 3.14 percent higher at 1,478, bringing two-day gains to 6.2 percent in the strong correction that followed recent sharp losses.</p>
<p>Daily trade volume rose sharply to 19.20 trillion lira from Tuesday's 11.05 trillion.  </p>
<p>&quot;Today's sharp rise was a continuation of the correction that began yesterday. The index has reached 1,480 resistance. I expect sales to emerge at between 1,480 and 1,500 levels on Thursday,&quot; said Ersen Alkay from Marbas securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is still indexed to politics, so if there is a cabinet meeting tomorrow, that may raise caution. So it is difficult for the index to pass the 1,500 mark,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Brokers said fresh cash entry was expected for Wednesday after the Treasury sold only 34.6 trillion lira of two-year inflation-indexed bonds in Tuesday's auction with Wednesday value.</p>
<p>Banks paid 34.3 trillion lira for the auction today while the Treasury injected 130 trillion lira for maturing bonds.</p>
<p>The average overnight money and repo rates edged lower on Wednesday after the money market opened 10.1 trillion lira long.</p>
<p>The market index had plunged 9.1 percent in eight days amid political worries over the fate of the Islamist-led coalition government after the market opened on April 24 following a 6-1/2 day holiday. It recovered 2.95 percent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Of the 248 shares traded, rises outdid falls by 145 to 53 and 50 ended stable. The IMKB Industrial gained 2.16 percent to 1,465, the IMKB Services jumped 2.17 percent to 1,319 and the IMKB Financial soared 3.92 percent to 1,619.</p>
<p>Top actives were largely state owned flat steel maker Eregli, up 1,250 lira at 15,500 and Yapi Kredi Bank, steady at 6,100 lira. They made up 15.2 percent of the total turnover.</p>
<p>Brokers said the rise in bluechip Eregli's price influenced the market index due to the firm's high market capitalisation.</p>
<p>Ismail Karakaya, chairman of Turkey's privatisation administration (OIB) said in a television interview that two bids received in the January tender for the partial block sale of a 51.66 percent state stake in Eregli were still being reviewed.</p>
<p>-- Aydan Eksin, Istanbul newsroom +90-212-2750875</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
