<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567503" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Britain, France agree to work for landmine ban.</title>
<headline>Britain, France agree to work for landmine ban.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain and France on Wednesday agreed a joint effort to ban anti-personnel landmines and said they hoped Germany would join the campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope we will be able today to make a tripartite statement comitting our three countries to work together to achieve a ban on the landmines that have caused so much suffering around the world,&quot; British Foreign Secretary Robin Cook told reporters after meeting French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette.  </p>
<p>Cook, on his first foreign trip since taking office last week after his Labour Party ended 18 years of conservative rule, said he and de Charette had agreed a text on landmines and he would seek to have it endorsed later in the day by German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel.</p>
<p>Cook said he hoped that his trip to Paris and Bonn would mark the start of a new era in Britain's relations with Europe after what he called a sterile and fruitless period of confrontation.</p>
<p>He said that France and Beritain would try to work out a joint approach to a review of the workings of European Union institutions at the EU Intergovernmental Conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Britain will of course insist on the protection of its vital national interests such as our anxiety to ensure we preserve our external border control against third countries,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
