<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567583" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austria politicians to maintain pressure over Iran.</title>
<headline>Austria politicians to maintain pressure over Iran.</headline>
<byline>Elizabeth Fullerton</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian opposition parties vowed on Wednesday to keep up pressure for an urgent inquiry into allegations that former ministers turned a blind eye to the escape of suspected Iranian assassins from Vienna in 1989.</p>
<p>Chancellor Viktor Klima's government has rejected calls for an independent probe into the release of three Iranians believed to be behind the murder of Kurdish dissident leader Abdorrahman Qasemlu and two other activists in Vienna eight years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no cooperation with state terrorism,&quot; Foreign Minister Wolfgang Schussel said in his statement to parliament during a five-hour debate on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Deputies of the ruling coalition parties, the Social Democrats and the conservative People's Party, backed the government's position in a vote in parliament late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Opposition liberals, Greens and the far right accuse former ministers from the same two ruling parties of bowing to Iranian demands to let the assassins leave without any diplomatic fuss.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not giving up. We're not going to stop the pressure,&quot; a spokesman for the opposition Liberal Forum said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an issue that needs clearing up urgently. I think the public knows that all is not right.&quot;</p>
<p>The Liberal Forum has demanded information from Schuessel on the extent of contacts between Austria and Iran in the months after the murders and the release of the minutes of cabinet meetings at the time.</p>
<p>Pressure has been growing since April when a German court linked the 1992 slaying of a group of Kurdish dissidents in Berlin with the Vienna murders. In a verdict that sparked a diplomatic row, it accused Tehran of ordering the Berlin killings.</p>
<p>Austrian media and some diplomats allege the government allowed one of the suspects to seek refuge in the Iranian embassy and even escorted a second suspect to Vienna airport in an official motorcade. The third man disappeared without trace.</p>
<p>Warrants for the Iranians' arrest were only issued once they were outside Austria.</p>
<p>Civil servants at the foreign, interior and justice ministries are compiling reports on the case, which the government has promised to make public.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the reports from the justice and interior ministry on Monday. We'll go through them and if they are unsatisfactory we ask again for an inquiry,&quot; Green MP Rudi Anschober told Reuters. &quot;We are not going to let this lie.&quot;</p>
<p>Anschober said there were signs that some deputies in Klima's Social Democrats were also concerned over the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;There are more and more people in the Social Democrats who feel uneasy about this,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Greens say they have documents proving that an interior ministry official intervened to prevent arrest warrants being issued immediately.</p>
<p>&quot;No one in the government intentionally protected murderers, covered up facts or abused human rights,&quot; said conservative party whip Andreas Kohl.</p>
<p>Former Austrian foreign minister Alois Mock, interior minister Franz Loeschnak and justice minister Egmont Foregger have been in the direct line of fire from the opposition.</p>
<p>Kohl defended the three politicians, saying &quot;they wanted to do the best for Austria within the framework of the law&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
