<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567593" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: AGF confirms interest in GAN insurance.</title>
<headline>AGF confirms interest in GAN insurance.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>French insurer AGF said on Wednesday it was interested in buying state-owned GAN's insurance business.</p>
<p>&quot;AGF is definitely interested in buying GAN's insurance operations,&quot; said a spokesman for the insurer which has been looking at ways to strengthen its number two market position in France following the mega-merger announced last year between French insurers Axa and UAP.</p>
<p>Official minutes of a Senate hearing last month of AGF chairman Antoine Jeancourt-Galignani quoted him as saying AGF would be an &quot;active candidate&quot; to buy GAN's insurance operations.  </p>
<p>AGF has stressed it would only be interested in GAN's insurance activities, not its real estate or banking operations.</p>
<p>The centre-right government has said it plans to pump 20 billion francs into GAN, which has been forced to take repeated provisions to cover property losses, to ready it for sale this year.</p>
<p>Moves to privatise GAN have been put on hold by the two-round parliamentary election to be held May 25 and June 1. The ruling centre-right coalition has pledged to continue its privatisation programme.</p>
<p>The opposition Socialists, which polls indicate are gaining on the centre-right, have vowed to keep all public service companies under government control.</p>
<p>But they have pledged to take a &quot;pragmatic&quot; approach to state-controlled companies which operate &quot;in the competitive sector which do not have a public service role and where state participation is no longer necessary.&quot;</p>
<p>Shares of GAN were up 2.49 percent at 140 francs while shares of AGF were down 0.42 percent at 0947 GMT.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
