<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567506" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Cannes festival turns 50, leaps into 23rd century.</title>
<headline>Cannes festival turns 50, leaps into 23rd century.</headline>
<byline>John Follain</byline>
<dateline>CANNES, France 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Cannes film festival launched its 50th birthday celebrations on Wednesday with a 90-million-dollar leap into the 23rd century courtesy of France's Luc Besson and his taste for the spectacular.</p>
<p>As the May 7-18 competition opened, organisers announced that leading Iranian director Abbas Kiarostami would after all bid for the Golden Palm award although the director had previously quoted Tehran authorities as refusing him permission.</p>
<p>Good (New York cab driver Bruce Willis and his partner Milla Jovovich reborn from a beetle-like creature) takes on Evil (agent Gary Oldman and a planet sent to explode the Earth) in &quot;The Fifth Element&quot;, a fable which Besson kept under wraps until its premiere in the French Riviera resort.</p>
<p>After earth, wind, fire and water, the fifth element is life itself which alone can ensure the defeat of Evil, which enters the Earth's dimension through a gateway between dimensions which opens only once every 5,000 years.</p>
<p>&quot;Luc (Besson) came to my house five years ago and tried to explain his idea to me. I thought it had not quite coagulated. A year and a half ago he came to me again and just after reading it I said 'OK',&quot; Willis, wearing his trademark woollen cap and dark glasses, told a news conference.</p>
<p>A Hollywood blockbuster made by a French director in a British studio, the film cost a reported $90 million according to industry sources. Despite the price tag, it failed to convince many Cannes critics.</p>
<p>Besson started on the story when he was 16. &quot;I was writing solely for the pleasure of it. I just put down on paper everything that I love and see. I just like to go for it, and I consider the serious questions later,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We spent a whole year creating. We locked ourselves in to create the decor, the costumes, even the spoons,&quot; said Besson who held the camera and oversaw all technical details.</p>
<p>But despite that progress made in 1992, producers began to panic at the spiralling cost of the project, and Besson had to shelve it to make &quot;Leon&quot; (The Professional) instead, which earned more than $20 million in the United States alone.</p>
<p>Maverick French stylist Jean-Paul Gaultier designed outlandish outfits for a cast including dainty space hostesses to police officers with bizarre plastic cones on their heads.</p>
<p>In the latest eleventh-hour change to the Cannes bill, festival supremo Gilles Jacob said in a terse statement that Kiarostami's &quot;The Delicious Taste of Cherries&quot; would run in the competition. No more details were available.</p>
<p>Kiarostami had last month quoted a Culture Ministry official as telling him that Tehran would not allow him to take the film to Cannes because it should first be shown at the Fajr (Dawn) festival in Tehran which marks the Islamic revolution every February.</p>
<p>Organisers had already hastily amended the Golden Palm running list after China, according to industry sources, banned Zhang Yimou's &quot;Keep Cool&quot; which had been picked by Jacob.</p>
<p>There was no official explanation, but Chinese authorities have criticised previous films by Zhang, whose &quot;To Live&quot; won awards at Cannes in 1994 although he had been banned from attending, for portraying China as backward in films for Western audiences.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANNES, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
