<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567630" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Chidambaram stands by trail-blazing budget.</title>
<headline>India's Chidambaram stands by trail-blazing budget.</headline>
<byline>Sabyasachi Mitra</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Finance Minister P. Chidambaram on Wednesday brushed aside demands by left-wing allies and political rivals that his landmark 1997/98 (April-March) budget be amended.</p>
<p>&quot;No major changes have been made in taxation and on customs duties,&quot; Chidambaram told parliament as he moved the budget plan that would slash corporate and personal income taxes.</p>
<p>Leaders of left-wing parties in the ruling coalition, along with those of the Congress party and the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), met Chidambaram earlier this week to press for changes in the tax and tariff components of the budget, which he first presented to parliament on February 28.</p>
<p>The four left-wing parties in Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral's 15-party United Front coalition had objected to tax cuts as well as a proposal to open up insurance to private competition.</p>
<p>The four parties have 52 deputies in the 545-seat lower house of parliament. The United Front controls 178 seats and has the support of the Congress party, which has another 140.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said he had accepted some of the changes which the three political groups had agreed to, but left the thrust of the Finance Bill intact. The lower house of parliament is expected on Friday to approve the bill, which contains the tax and tariff proposals.</p>
<p>&quot;I wish I could have done more, but I have to keep in mind the important interest of the revenue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The changes in customs and excise duties which he did incorporate would shave 1.1 billion rupees ($30 million) off government revenues.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said the tax proposals in the budget aimed to keep India competitive with the vibrant economies of Asia.</p>
<p>The left-wing parties had already indicated they did not intend to risk toppling Gujral's 10-day-old government by pressing for amendments on the floor of the house. Their reaction to Chidambaram's speech was muted.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's wait and see. Until it is adopted, I won't make any comments,&quot; Harkishen Singh Surjeet, secretary general of Communist Party of India (Marxist), told Reuters.</p>
<p>The left-wing parties had opposed plans to open up health insurance to private firms. Chidambaram said a bill to establish an insurance regulator would provide a chance to debate the issue.</p>
<p>The main opposition BJP had opposed a proposal to levy a 10 percent tax on dividends distributed by companies.</p>
<p>In parliament, Chidambaram tabled an additional proposal to cut the import duty on ferro-nickel to 10 percent from 20 percent in a bid to help the steel industry.</p>
<p>He also proposed excluding profits earned from software exports from a minimum alternate tax (MAT) on corporations.</p>
<p>The controversial MAT -- a 12.9 percent minimum tax on company profits -- was introduced in last year's budget to bring some of India's top companies into the tax net.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
