<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567769" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian PM falls on hard time, but not for long.</title>
<headline>Australian PM falls on hard time, but not for long.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Timms</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's conservative government appears under siege midway through its first term, with populist politician Pauline Hanson wooing away its voters and a rogue senator endangering key reforms.</p>
<p>But with the next election still 18 months away, a lacklustre opposition and an economy apparently on the upturn, political analysts say Prime Minister John Howard's woes are not as bad as they might seem.</p>
<p>&quot;In the case of Pauline Hanson, the vote is clearly not sustainable,&quot; Malcolm Mackerras, electoral analyst at the Australian Defence Force Academy, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The election will be in December next year, that's 18 months away, which is plenty of time for all the other parties to knock Hanson,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll be completely bored with her before too long.&quot;</p>
<p>A string of opinion polls have shown Hanson and her month-old One Nation Party rapidly enticing voters away from Howard's Liberal-National coalition.</p>
<p>Hanson sparked a divisive national race row last year, warning that Asians threatened to overrun Australia and complaining that Aborigines received favoured treatment at the expense of whites.</p>
<p>Her comments prompted criticism from Asia, but struck a chord with many white Australians.</p>
<p>Hanson's support -- about 10 percent -- is strong enough to give One Nation an influential bloc in parliament in the right circumstances and is also eroding the government's once commanding lead over the Labor opposition.</p>
<p>Howard has seen his government's lead -- which hovered around 12 percent over most of the past 14 months -- plunge to about six percent in recent weeks.</p>
<p>But the polls also show Howard's personal popularity remains about double that of Labor rival Kim Beazley -- giving the government hope it can reverse the slide if Hanson fades as quickly as analysts expect.</p>
<p>Australian National University political scientist Jim Jupp said Hanson was hot property now, but would not last.</p>
<p>&quot;She's a rather damaging flash in the pan,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>However, Howard faces another problem in the hostile Senate, where he needs the support of at least two non-government senators to pass his reforms.</p>
<p>Independent Mal Colston, under fire over allegations of travel expense fraud and shunned by the administration that once courted his support, resigned as Senate deputy president on Tuesdayt and threatened to start voting against the government.</p>
<p>If Colston carried out his threat to line up with Labor and other minor parties, government legislation would be blocked by a tied 38-38 vote, even if the Senate's second independent continued to support the government.</p>
<p>The threat comes as Howard prepares to unveil his budget for the next financial year and ahead of likely controversial legislation over Aboriginal land rights and media ownership.</p>
<p>But Canberra University political lecturer Gwyn Singleton said that while Colston's decision was an obstacle to government reforms, it was not insurmountable.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't see him as too great a risk,&quot; she told Reuters, adding the government could win support for its measures by striking deals with minority parties.</p>
<p>If the Senate does reject legislation twice, the government can call a double dissolution early election, followed by a joint sitting of both houses of parliament to deal with the contentious measures.</p>
<p>But Mackerras said Howard, desperate to avoid One Nation winning Senate seats, was unlikely to go to the polls early.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody has an interest against a double dissolution except Pauline Hanson, and therefore Pauline Hanson will want a double dissolution but there won't be one,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Under the Senate's complicated proportional voting system, fewer votes are needed to win a seat in a double dissolution, when all senators face re-election instead of just half as in normal full-term elections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
