<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567755" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ debt ends weaker on lower TWI, Brash comments.</title>
<headline>NZ debt ends weaker on lower TWI, Brash comments.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>-----------------------(Snapshot at close)----------------------</p>
<p>Figures in brackets compare against previous day's close</p>
<p>FUTURES					  PHYSICAL YIELD (PCT)</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS (JUN) 92.86 (PREV 92.96)  90-DAYS  6.89 (PREV 6.78)</p>
<p>3-YR BONDS   (JUN) 92.45 (PREV 92.58)  02/00    7.42 (PREV 7.34)</p>
<p>10-YR BONDS  (JUN) 92.29 (PREV 92.30)  11/06    7.67 (PREV 7.66)</p>
<p>OVERNIGHT CASH 6.00 PCT   (PREV 6.10)  US 5-YR  6.55 (PREV 6.53)</p>
<p>NZD/USD    0.6834/41 (PREV 0.6863/70)  US 10-YR 6.67 (PREV 6.66)</p>
<p>TWI		    67.94 (PREV 68.19)  US 30-YR 6.90 (PREV 6.88)</p>
<p>----------------------------(May 7)-----------------------------</p>
<p>* NZ yields finish higher as currency slips  </p>
<p>* RBNZ's Brash dampens sentiment through cautious remarks</p>
<p>* High volumes trade</p>
<p>New Zealand debt ended weaker across the curve on Wednesday after a bad start on the back of a lower currency.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market's tone never really recovered, and the market's recent easing was arrested by comments made by Reserve Bank governor Don Brash.  </p>
<p>The currency ended down at 67.94 on its Trade-Weighted Index, from 68.19 at Tuesday's close and 67.92 at today's open. Dealers said more than NZ$300 million of kiwi was dumped onto the market overnight, prompting an initial round of selling as the forex market opened.</p>
<p>In response to the lower TWI the 90-day bill rates climbed to 6.87 percent in early trade, and notched up another couple of basis points during the session to end at 6.89 percent.</p>
<p>The June futures contract finished 10 points weaker at 92.86 on solid volume of 4,658 contracts.  </p>
<p>The RBNZ's Brash, appearing before parliament's Finance and Expenditure Committee, failed to give the market reassurance that its recent easing in monetary conditions was appropriate.</p>
<p>The market read comments by Brash last week as indicating the central bank would take an easier stance on conditions in its June monetary policy statement.</p>
<p>In March it signalled it preferred 90-days at 7.5 percent and the TWI at 68.0, or an equivalent mix.</p>
<p>&quot;At this stage we have to say that we haven't changed our desired monetary conditions from those announced in the middle of March,&quot; Brash said.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the Brash's taciturn stance had compounded the negative tone shrouding the market.</p>
<p>&quot;He's not promising anything, which is very him,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>The dealer said short rates had recently pushed down to levels where downside was limited, and people started seeing scope for profit-taking after Brash's comments and on the weak TWI.</p>
<p>Trade was whippy in the futures market while the physicals were more calm, although a move lower in cash to six percent prompted some buying in the 30-day bank bills.</p>
<p>-- Catherine McCaw, Wellington newsroom (64 4) 471 4275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
