<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567707" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - Notionnel to struggle at 129.66 high.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Notionnel to struggle at 129.66 high.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>June notionnel futures on MATIF managed to push ahead on Wednesday in the face of a weak Bund market but will find it difficult to get beyond the previous session's high at 129.66, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;France is okay on the technical front but 129.66 is going to be a tough level to take out,&quot; said Simon Mattholie, proprietary trader at Deutsche Bank in London.</p>
<p>The 129.66 level was the highest the contract has been since March 12.</p>
<p>June notionnel was quoted at 129.60 at 0745 GMT, up 12 basis points from Tuesday. It has hit a high of 129.62 in the session.  </p>
<p>&quot;If we do take out 129.66 it looks like it's going to have the 130.32 target in sights again,&quot; Mattholie said.</p>
<p>That was the high on March 11 before the contract descended lower. In between, projections would give a more immediate target of 129.84 Mattholie said.</p>
<p>Richard Adcock, manager of technical research at HSBC Futures in London, also had 130.32 as his main upside objective, noting the contract had aborted the potential head and shoulders pattern on weekly charts.</p>
<p>To the downside, it was crucial for the contract to hold the 129.32 zone, the bottom of the recent range, Mattholie said.  </p>
<p>&quot;If we take out that then straight away we're looking for 129.16 and probably a return to 129-3/4,&quot; Mattholie said.</p>
<p>Adcock also said in a research note that short term corrections were well supported at 129.16, the April 30 high.</p>
<p>June Pibor futures were quoted at 96.36, up two basis points from Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
