<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567881" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: North Korea membership not an issue at meeting-ADB.</title>
<headline>North Korea membership not an issue at meeting-ADB.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Korea's application to join the Asian Development Bank (ADB) will not be discussed officially at the bank's forthcoming annual meeting, an ADB official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He also said there will be no participation by North Korean officials at the meeting, to be held in Fukuoka, Japan from May 11 to 13.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not an issue at the annual meeting. They're not even coming as observers,&quot; an ADB official in Fukuoka told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the Stalinist nation had simply expressed an interest in joining the multinational bank and that the issue had to go through various procedures first.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to establish some kind of a consensus,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>There has been speculation that, with its economy in tatters after two years of record floods, North Korea might turn to the ADB for help.</p>
<p>The official declined to comment on media reports that Japan opposed North Korea's membership and that it had blocked Pyongyang's participation at the annual meeting.</p>
<p>An official at Japan's Foreign Ministry said the ministry had been informed by the ADB that North Korea was interested in joining the bank but said it had not made any official statements opposing North Korea's membership.</p>
<p>&quot;We will discuss the issue with other nations, but due to various matters, we must consider it very cautiously,&quot; he said, referring to Japan's allegations that North Korean agents had abducted Japanese citizens in the past.</p>
<p>Separately, an official at Japan's Ministry of Finance said it was still premature to make a judgment on North Korea's entry into the ADB.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still not at a stage where we should voice our support or our opposition,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>ADB President Mitsuo Sato said in late April that North Korea had expressed an interest in joining the ADB and said the bank's member nations would be formally told of the request shortly.</p>
<p>-- George Nishiyama, Tokyo Policy Desk +81-3-5473-3710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
