<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567894" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Time to bottom fish for Singapore stocks - Vickers.</title>
<headline>Time to bottom fish for Singapore stocks - Vickers.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>April's sell down of blue chips in Singapore has opened an opportunity for investors to bottom fish, Vickers Ballas Investment Research said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Singapore stock market was now undervalued after weak investor sentiment pushed stock prices down over the past three months, the research house said in its monthly research report.</p>
<p>Singapore is trading at a price earning (PE) ratio of 15 times, representing the low-end of its historic PE range of 14 to 24 times. Fair valuation of the market was pegged around PE 19-20 times.  </p>
<p>Vickers said it expected the market to bottom out over the next two months given the low valuation and improving fundamentals.</p>
<p>It said recent portfolio adjustments ahead of the revised Morgan Stanley Capital International (MSCI) Singapore Free Index weightings on June 1, 1997, would have been completed.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the foreign tranches of bank stocks to respond positively.&quot;</p>
<p>Singapore's budget announcement expected in late June was also expected to reveal a few goodies, including a good dose of pro-business measures, Vickers said.  </p>
<p>The stocks recommended were Cycle &amp; Carriage, Keppel Corporation, Foreign tranches of banks like OCBC and OUB.</p>
<p>Others included stocks with potential growth like Elec &amp; Eltek, MMI Holdings, Sin Soon Huat, Lindeteves-Jacoberg as well as stocks with recovery plays like Haw Par, ST Aerospace and Straits Trading.  </p>
<p>Vickers said its recommendation was for investors with a time horizon of about 12 months. The stocks were expected to have an upside of at least 20 percent within that period, it said.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
