<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="568029" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China tightens border controls with Macau - papers.</title>
<headline>China tightens border controls with Macau - papers.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>China has tightened security on the border with Macau in an effort to help the Portuguese-run territory crack down on a gang-related crime wave, Macau's Chinese-language newspapers reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The stricter controls were meant to &quot;fight illegal immigration and stop the entry and exit of suspected criminals,&quot; the Va Kio daily quoted Chinese border inspection office spokesman Huang Yan-quan as saying.</p>
<p>Huang said the office would also step up vetting of illegal immigrants deported from neighbouring Macau in an effort to identify criminals but gave no further details.</p>
<p>So-called &quot;snakeheads&quot; charge about 5,000 yuan ($600) a head to spirit Chinese nationals into Macau, a Portuguese outpost for more than 400 years.</p>
<p>A wave of shootings, bombings and arson attacks blamed on a turf war between members of rival Chinese criminal organisations known as &quot;triad societies&quot; has rocked once-sleepy Macau in recent months.</p>
<p>Police suspect many of the shootings were carried out by imported mainland hitmen.</p>
<p>Macau, which reverts to China in 1999, deported 6,875 illegal immigrants to China last year, an increase of 4.3 percent on 1995 levels, government statistics show.</p>
<p>The Macau peninsula is located on the southern delta of the Pearl River and shares a narrow 240 metre (yard) land border with China</p>
<p>But the surrounding bays separating Macau from the southern Chinese region of Zhuhai are shallow and easy to navigate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MACAO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
