<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="568022" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai Danu says merger deal still on.</title>
<headline>Thai Danu says merger deal still on.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The planned merger between Thai Danu Bank Plc and Thailand's largest finance company, Finance One Plc is still on and the boards are due to approve the merger on May 15, a Thai Danu official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The boards of Finance One and Thai Danu are scheduled to hold meetings on May 15 to approve the merger after the due diligence is completed,&quot; Chaiwat Utaiwan, executive vice president of Thai Danu, told a news conference.  </p>
<p>Chaiwat made the comments amid rumours and local media reports that the merger was in danger of collapsing.</p>
<p>The biggest merger of Thai financial institutions was said to be in danger of collapse because Thai Danu was planning to walk away from the deal due to various problems.</p>
<p>But Thai Danu officials have said those reports and subsequent market rumours were caused by a misunderstanding over the reason behind a request to extend the due diligence period by two weeks.</p>
<p>Chaiwat said the two-week delay of due diligence was made because of difficulties in the process due to the fact that both companies have a large asset size.</p>
<p>&quot;The delay was...because both institutions have a very large asset size of more than 100 billion baht ($3.85 billion) each,&quot; Chaiwat said.</p>
<p>He refused to directly comment on any talk that the merger might collapse, saying only the boards of directors and shareholders had final say in the merger and it was their decision to approve or reject it.</p>
<p>When asked if Thai Danu would suffer if the merger were not approved, Chaiwat said there would be no &quot;significant damage&quot; and said Thai Danu would continue with its normal business.  </p>
<p>Chaiwat said the two companies hope trading will resume on May 16.</p>
<p>&quot;We will submit the resolutions of the board (made on May 15) to the Stock Exchange. We hope both shares will resume trading the following day,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Trading in shares of both companies have been halted since March 3 when they first began talking publicly of the merger.</p>
<p>Analysts have said Finance One sought the merger because it faced liquidity problems that emerged amid a major shakeup of Thailand's troubled finance sector.</p>
<p>Thai Danu said last month it would absorb about six billion baht worth of Finance One's outstanding 21 billion baht in property loans when the companies merge.</p>
<p>Finance One has a total of 66 billion baht in outstanding loans.</p>
<p>The firms' merger plans set in motion a spate of proposed mergers between many of Thailand's troubled finance and securities firms. Analysts say the process is just the start of a major shake-up among Thailand's 91 finance and securities companies.  </p>
<p>The industry is suffering from declining loan portfolio quality, high financing costs and portfolio losses on investments in a depressed local stock market.</p>
<p>($1 = 26 baht)</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
