<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="568045" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea drafts laws to set up bad loans fund.</title>
<headline>S.Korea drafts laws to set up bad loans fund.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's Finance and Economy Ministry said on Wednesday it had drafted legislation establishing a fund to address the problem of corporate bankruptcies.</p>
<p>The legislation would designate state-funded Korea Asset Management Corp to run the fund, which would be capitalised at 1.5 trillion won, a ministry statement said.</p>
<p>The ministry will submit the draft to parliament in June for approval.</p>
<p>The Management Corp, whose paid-in capital is 200 billion won, would be expanded and reshaped.</p>
<p>The statement said the fund would be operational for five years and would be financed mainly with contributions from banks, bond issues and borrowings.</p>
<p>The goal of the fund would be to &quot;speed up and rationalise&quot; the handling of bad loans, reduce losses of companies, banks and creditors and minimise disorder in the banking system, it said.</p>
<p>The ministry estimated bad debts held by the nation's commercial banks at about 2.4 trillion won at the end of 1996, the statement said.</p>
<p>It described bad debt as debt on which payment is doubtful.</p>
<p>The organisation would buy mortgaged bad debts from financial institutions, repackage and later sell them.</p>
<p>The finance ministry is negotiating with the Home Affairs Ministry to grant tax benefits for the Management Corp to buy or sell the mortgages.</p>
<p>A ministry official said the government was also considering extending tax benefits to buyers but that nothing had been finalised.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
