<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="568178" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FOCUS - Merita first quarter profit surges.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Merita first quarter profit surges.</headline>
<byline>Roland Moller</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finland's largest banking group Merita Oy on Wednesday reported a much higher-than-expected increase in first quarter operating earnings and said full-year net earnings would improve on last year.</p>
<p>Merita's operating profit after credit losses surged to 934 million markka ($179.7 million) from 233 million in the year-ago period, boosted by a 584 million markka gain from the systematic reduction of the group equity portfolio by 2.6 billion markka to 4.3 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The full-year result of the Merita group is expected to be distinctly better than in 1996,&quot; Merita said in a statement.</p>
<p>Analysts said the size of Merita's divestments were a positive surprise, and said this had been possible since most of the shares sold were blue-chips and the stock market had set records in terms of levels and volumes early this year.</p>
<p>Merita shares rose 0.50 markka or almost three percent to 18.50 markka after the announcement, but eased to 18.30 markka by noon, and analysts said the report was not altogether positive for the long-term outlook.</p>
<p>Evli analyst Christian Kock said the report was neutral news all in all, with the equity disposal gain and a strong performance in credit losses which pointed to an annual rate of 0.5 percent on one hand, but squeezed margins in core banking operations on the other.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking at core banking, it does not look very beautiful, there is tough competition for clients,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But analysts said they would raise their full-year forecasts since the first quarter beat forecasts so clearly due to the equity portfolio downsizing.</p>
<p>The median forecast had been for a 431 million markka operating profit after credit losses.</p>
<p>Merita said it had cut its stake in Nokia by 1.7 percentage points to 1.7 percent, in insurers Sampo and Pohjola by 3.2 percent and 1.1 percent respectively to 15.3 and 14.8 percent in the first quarter.</p>
<p>Its stake in engineering group Metra fell to 3.1 percent from 4.9 percent, its Huhtamaki holding fell to 1.3 percent from 3.5 percent, and its stake in forestry major UPM-Kymmene fell to 3.1 percent from 4.9 percent.</p>
<p>Merita had earlier said it expected full-year 1997 operating profit to improve on last year, so the outlook now for better net earnings was in fact a more positive statement than its previous forecast, it said.</p>
<p>In 1996, Merita posted a 1.2 billion markka operating profit and its net profit was 1.72 billion markka.</p>
<p>Merita repeated that credit losses and costs would continue to fall, and most of the synergy benefits from the merger of Unitas and Kansallis-Osake-Pankki, which created the group in 1995, would be felt this year.</p>
<p>($ = 5.196 Finnish Markka)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
