<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="568124" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGB futures fall sharply on panicky selling.</title>
<headline>JGB futures fall sharply on panicky selling.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Key June Japanese government bond (JGB) futures fell sharply in early Tokyo trade on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Aggressive selling was seen in the benchmark cash 182nd JGB and JGB futures after Tuesday's sharp fall, traders said.</p>
<p>The June contract was down 0.47 at 123.95 as of 9.40 a.m. (0040 GMT), after falling as low as 123.68.</p>
<p>&quot;Panicky selling is continuing despite the weakness of Tokyo stocks this morning. People are choosing to sell benchmark cash and futures because of their high liquidity,&quot; said a trader at a trust bank's securities unit.  </p>
<p>The yield of the 182nd JGB stood at 2.480 percent, after rising as high as 2.520 percent. It had ended at 2.420 percent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>JGBs fell sharply on Tuesday as the Nikkei 225 stock average surged.</p>
<p>The Nikkei's fall earlier on Wednesday morning, however, failed to improve sentiment in the bond market, traders said.</p>
<p>The key stock index was down 2.70 points at 20,178.22 as of 9.50 a.m. (0050 GMT) after falling to 20,074.31 earlier.</p>
<p>If the Nikkei rises into positive territory, that is likely to weigh on JGBs, traders said.  </p>
<p>Traders see the key support point for June JGB futures as 123.60, which is this year's low set on January 6.</p>
<p>&quot;If 123.60 does not hold, it would be difficult to predict the next support point,&quot; said a trader at another trust bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-9780  </p>
<p>Matsushita also said in a parliamentary committee meeting that monetary policy should not be relied on heavily to correct current account imbalances.</p>
<p>However the BOJ governor's comments did not have a lasting impact, traders said.</p>
<p>They said the direction of JGBs was likely to continue to depend on the Nikkei.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Nikkei remains comfortably above 20,000, the market's perception of the economy could change. We might see more money flowing into stocks,&quot; said a trader at a trust bank's securities unit.  </p>
<p>&quot;Last year, money was flowing into bonds due to a lack of alternative investment vehicles. That situation may be changing,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>At midday, the yield of the benchmark 182nd JGB stood at 2.440 percent, after earlier rising as high as 2.520 percent. It closed at 2.420 percent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Kanta Watanabe, Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-9780</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
