<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56879" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek shares rally in heavy volume, seen bullish.</title>
<headline>Greek shares rally in heavy volume, seen bullish.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek equities rallied on Monday, continuing their advance for the fifth consecutive day in heavy trading volume of 11.9 billion drachmas. Brokers said a bullish outlook and positioning was behind the broad-based advance.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a very strong market today and it looks that it wants to continue this way with investors discounting several positive developments ahead. Briefly, a strong government and measures that will boost the economy,&quot; said Lambros Papaconstadinou, managing Director of P &amp; K Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The heavy trading volumes are clear evidence of positioning and we expect to have a good market until year end, led to a great extent by the banking sector. We may see some nervousness towards the end of this week as we head for election day,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The two lead candidates for prime minister, socialist Costas Simitis and conservative Miltiadis Evert, faced off in a TV debate Friday evening hoping to lure the undecided voters in what the press has dubbed the &quot;couch elections&quot;.</p>
<p>Many analysts called it a draw with no winning punches and no major gaffes by either candidate.</p>
<p>Greece will hold early elections September 22.</p>
<p>The Athens general share index closed 1.67 percent, or 16.01 points higher at 974.20 from Friday's 958.19 close after opening at 961.75 points. Turnover rose to 11.9 billion drachmas from 9.5 billion on Friday on volume of 4.85 million shares.</p>
<p>Advancers led decliners 157 to 66 with 22 issues unchanged on 245 traded. Banks climbed 1.90 percent, industrials jumped 2.18 percent and construction advanced 1.06 percent. Small-caps gained 1.08 percent.</p>
<p>On Friday, market watchers sensed the beginning of a bull trend saying further gains could unfold with the market discounting a strong government after the elections.</p>
<p>The Merrill Lynch call spread warrant on OTE with a strike price of 3,800 drachmas was quoted at 561-579 at the close. Shares of OTE telecom, the underlying, ended up 20 drachmas at 4,070.</p>
<p>The recently launched Merrill Lynch stock index call warrant based on a basket of 23 shares was quoted higher at 223.80-235.60 drachmas. It expires on January 9 1998 with a strike price of 1000. It was in the money at 1065.6.</p>
<p>The Morgan Stanley Hellenic Blue Chip Warrant, which has a strike price of 100 marks, was quoted higher at 4,625-4,925 drachmas at the close. --George Georgiopoulos, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
