<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56891" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Markka ERM peg at present levels seen drawing near.</title>
<headline>Markka ERM peg at present levels seen drawing near.</headline>
<byline>Peter Starck</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen on Monday signalled that a decision to link the Finnish markka to ERM is drawing near and that the central parity exchange rate will be on the firm rather than on the weak side, analysts said.</p>
<p>Lipponen was quoted as saying in a regional newspaper that the time had now become ripe to decide in the near future about a link to Europe's exchange rate mechanism.</p>
<p>He also suggested there would be no official attempt to influence the central parity rate at which the markka was fixed in the ERM.</p>
<p>&quot;The level of the markka can not be manipulated. It would be noticed immediately and it would weaken the confidence in Finland,&quot; the paper quoted Lipponen as saying.</p>
<p>The paper also said: &quot;According to Lipponen, the value of the markka is what it is. Efforts to start changing it will not be made.&quot;</p>
<p>For many analysts, the comments meant there would be no effort to fix marka at lower levels. &quot;He indicated that a fix could happen at stronger levels than earlier thought,&quot; said Interbank economist Sampsa Laine.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be below 3.05 (markka per German mark), what he said could even be interpreted as making possible a peg below 3.03,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chief analyst Jukka Lepomaki at Merita Bank said the prime minister's comments supported &quot;stronger fixing levels.&quot;</p>
<p>He seemed to make it clear that central parity exchange rates above 3.05 would not be appropriate, Lepomaki said.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like it will be fixed at current levels, not at weaker ones,&quot; said Postipankki chief economist Ari Aaltonen.</p>
<p>The forex market reaction on Monday morning supported this conclusion, he and other analysts said.</p>
<p>The markka strengthened as Finnish exporters began to convert foreign currency earnings into markka having taken the prime minister on his word and stopped hoping for a weaker ERM peg, the analysts said.</p>
<p>At 1230 (0930 GMT), the markka was at 3.018 against the German mark having traded well above 3.02 before news broke of Lipponen's comments. It closed at 3.0225 last Friday.</p>
<p>But Pertti Thornberg, analyst at Enskilda, said nothing specific about the markka's central parity exchange rates in ERM should be read into the prime minister's comments.</p>
<p>&quot;The level could be 3.02 (markka per mark), or it could be 3.06 or 3.07,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Speaking on condition of anonymity, the head of a big corporate treasury said the only interpretation he could draw was that the fixing would take place &quot;near the going exchange rate at the time of the link.&quot;</p>
<p>And OKOBANK chief economist Matti Huomo told a news conference: &quot;I agree with Lipponen that the markka will be linked close to the rate it has been trading at in the days prior to a fixing.&quot;</p>
<p>Of eight analysts polled by Reuters on Monday, six now expect the link to take place soon. But they noted that Lipponen had not given any clear clue about the timing.</p>
<p>&quot;It is now rather a question of weeks than of months,&quot; said Aaltonen at Postipankki.</p>
<p>But OKOBANK's Huomo repeated his opinion that the markka would enter ERM only after Finland's October 20 local government and European Parliament elections.</p>
<p>And Handelsbanken Finland chief economist Carlo Erakallio said he still expected the linking of the markka to ERM to take place later this autumn with November the likeliest month.</p>
<p>But the government may opt to make a quick formal decision in favour of a peg and so reaffirm its commitment to Economic and Monetary Union EMU, he said.</p>
<p>Some of the analysts said the right time to link the markka could be in connection with the coming weekend's ECOFIN meeting in Dublin.</p>
<p>&quot;Then the budgets will be known,&quot; Laine at Interbank said, referring mainly to the French 1997 budget.</p>
<p>The Bank of Finland has expressed concerns that budget austerity designed to help key European countries like France and Germany meet the budget deficit criterion for EMU could lead to political unrest and so to volatility in the ERM.</p>
<p>The Bank of Finland must propose to the government that the markka be linked.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the central bank will hold a news conference at 1300 (1000 GMT) about the new issue of its key monetary policy publication, Markka &amp; Talous.</p>
<p>On Wednesday morning, the economic council -- a discussion forum grouping top-level leaders in government, central bank, industry, banking and labour market and other special interest organisations -- is scheduled to meet.</p>
<p>Some observers have said the government might consult or inform the economic council when an ERM link is imminent.</p>
<p>The Bank of Finland's board of parliamentary supervisors, an important link in the decision-making chain, is due to meet on Thursday morning.</p>
<p>--Helsinki Newsroom  +358 - 0 - 680 50 245 ($=4.5604 markka)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
