<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56914" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: U.S., French, UK defence ministers to meet on Iraq.</title>
<headline>U.S., French, UK defence ministers to meet on Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry will brief his French and British counterparts on latest developments in the crisis between the United States and Iraq at talks in London on Monday, French officials said.</p>
<p>Perry, who visited the Gulf at the weekend to secure support for a possible U.S. military showdown with Iraqi President Saddam Hussein, flew to Turkey on Monday after talks in Saudi Arabia, Kuwait and Bahrain.</p>
<p>France has distanced itself from U.S. cruise missile strikes on Iraq earlier this month aimed at punishing Saddam for sending troops into Kurdish areas of northern Iraq to back a Kurdish guerrilla movement which has since gained control over the area.</p>
<p>Britain strongly backed President Bill Clinton's action.</p>
<p>The latest flare-up was triggered by Iraq firing missiles last week at U.S. aircraft patrolling no-fly zones over northern and southern Iraq enforced since the 1991 Gulf War with Western allies Britain and France.</p>
<p>The French Foreign Ministry urged Iraq to refrain from any attack on allied aircraft, saying that would be unacceptable, but it has lent no public support to the idea of retaliation.</p>
<p>French officials said Paris would not depart from its long-term policy of drawing Baghdad back into the international community.</p>
<p>They said Perry would find little enthusiasm in Europe or among Arab friends for further military action against Iraq.</p>
<p>Diplomats in the Gulf said Saudi Arabia, Washington's most powerful Gulf ally and one of the three countries Perry visited, was unlikely to back more strikes on Iraq or give open approval for a further American military buildup in the oil-rich region.</p>
<p>Kuwait and Bahrain, Perry's two other stops at the weekend, were in no rush to approve U.S. requests for a greater military buildup on their soil.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
