<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56951" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Rosenthal denies in talks with Wedgwood.</title>
<headline>Rosenthal denies in talks with Wedgwood.</headline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>German porcelain group Rosenthal AG on Monday denied a weekend magazine report claiming Waterford Wedgwood was in talks with the company with a view to taking it over.</p>
<p>&quot;The report is not true,&quot; a spokesman said in answer to Reuters enquiries following a report in Focus magazine.</p>
<p>He added that Rosenthal was also not in takeover talks with any other companies.</p>
<p>The spokesman was unable to rule out that Wedgwood could be buying up Rosenthal stock in the open market, but he noted that Rosenthal has a restriction which caps the voting share of any single shareholder at five percent.</p>
<p>Focus had reported that Wedgwood hoped to increase its European presence by buying up Rosenthal and said talks had been taking place for several months. The five percent voting clause was seen as the major barrier, it said.</p>
<p>Rosenthal reported a loss of 10.7 million marks for the first half of 1996, hurt by weak domestic demand and high German production costs. But the loss was smaller than a year earlier, when it reported a shortfall of 13.1 million marks.</p>
<p>Sales in the first half dropped to 151.5 million marks from 165.1 million in the 1995 first half.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
