<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57001" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Europe crude outlook - Firmer as backlog clears.</title>
<headline>Europe crude outlook - Firmer as backlog clears.</headline>
<byline>Tom Ashby</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea Brent Blend crude is expected to recover from its currently depressed price over the next week because the U.S. arbitrage is opening and the bearish pressure has come mainly from distressed September sales, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is some very short-term oversupply, mainly in Brent and mainly in the next 10 days,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;That is because a refiner can't book Brent far ahead like the other grades. Brent normally goes transatlantic, but the arbitrage has been closed.&quot;  </p>
<p>Prompt Brent cargoes were offered into a vacuum on Friday as the U.S. arbitrage remained stubbornly shut for most traders.</p>
<p>Offers plummeted to October -35 cents without finding any interest. Except, that is, for a U.S. bank which kept all five Brent cargoes nominated from the paper chains last Thursday and Friday, bringing their total long position to eight cargoes. Dealers say this trader must have locked in an arbitrage to the U.S. earlier in the month and were likely to sail to the Gulf coast with a VLCC and two cargoes of a million barrels.</p>
<p>&quot;We will see the distressed Brent moving out of the way and then a jump in value for October loadings,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>Last week's escalating military tension between Iraq and the United States -- which showed signs of easing over the weekend -- artificially inflated Brent paper prices, closing the Brent/WTI spread, decoupling paper prices from wet demand and giving traders a disincentive to carry any crude on their books.</p>
<p>&quot;What we are seeing is no-one really wanting to buy crude at any price,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been no fundamental justification for the last $2.50 rise in prices, so where is the attraction of keeping a $24 cargo on your books for any longer than you have to, when there is a risk that the market will drop $3 overnight?&quot;.  </p>
<p>A price bounce was also expected on the other North Sea differentials to Brent, he added.</p>
<p>There was little doubt that the distressed Norwegian crudes would trade at a discount to normal premiums, but October values were likely to jump.</p>
<p>From the low trades of last week, such as Oseberg at Dated Brent -3 cents and Forties at Dated +16, one trader said both values would jump to +25/+30 in October.</p>
<p>He said: &quot;At the end of the month you normally have two or three Oseberg and Ekofisk left. I would not say there is a lot of oversupply on the grades.&quot;  </p>
<p>Fewer loadings from the main North Sea fields would help the market to rise, too. Schedules so far released showed a net drop of 4.5 million barrels of crude in October -- a longer month than September. Against slightly higher loadings of Brent and Forties, Gullfaks output would be halved by maintenance.</p>
<p>Mediterranean sour crude was expected to strengthen further over the next week as loading delays in Russia combined with strong fuel oil prices, traders said. Delays in Novorossiisk grew to 9-10 days last week as bad weather exacerbated the effect of maintenance on the pipeline feeding the port.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8145</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
