<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57129" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila aims for 4-5 pct inflation in 1998.</title>
<headline>Manila aims for 4-5 pct inflation in 1998.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippine government is aiming for an average inflation rate of 4 to 5 percent by 1998, similar to the levels posted in Malaysia, Taiwan and Singapore, the presidential palace said in a statement on Monday.</p>
<p>Manila expects inflation to reach 7.5 to 8.5 percent this year and to fall to 6.0 to 7.0 percent in 1997. Inflation was 8.1 percent in 1995.  </p>
<p>To achieve this goal, the statement laid out plans presented by Central Bank Governor Gabriel Singson, quoting him as saying:</p>
<p>&quot;The Central Bank will keep increases in money supply consistent with the demand for real money balances. This helps reduce interest rates by damping inflationary expectations.&quot;</p>
<p>The Central Bank said it has identified several measures to bring down banks' intermediation costs and encourage more savings in order to reduce interest rates.</p>
<p>Foremost among these is the further reduction in banks' reserve requirements to approximate the levels in other Southeast Asian countries.</p>
<p>Currently, the reserve requirement is now at 15 percent which adds to banks' intermediation costs by reducing the portion of funds they can lend out.</p>
<p>The Central Bank will also seek to ease the mandatory credit allocation schemes required on banks since these translate to foregone revenues by reducing a bank's flexibility in portfolio management.</p>
<p>Banks are required to set aside 15 percent of their funds to agriculture, 10 percent to agrarian reform activities and another 10 percent for small-and medium-scale enterprises.</p>
<p>The Central Bank will also support the legislative measure that will abolish the gross receipts tax on the volume of banks' transactions. This has also increased banks' intermediation costs.  </p>
<p>On the mobilisation of savings, the Central Bank said it will support measures to further liberalise the setting up of bank branches to increase the supply of loanable funds and ease the pressure on interest rates.</p>
<p>It will also push for the creation of a National Provident Fund which will require individuals to save part of their income with the government providing counterpart funds.</p>
<p>&quot;Such schemes like the Employee's Provident Fund in Malaysia and the Central Provident Fund in Singapore have helped increase the level of savings,&quot; Singson was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom (632) 841-8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
