<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="571339" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL ICE HOCKEY-COLLEGE COACH SNUBS BRUINS JOB.</title>
<headline>NHL ICE HOCKEY-COLLEGE COACH SNUBS BRUINS JOB.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boston University coach Jack Parker has turned down the job of head coach of the Boston Bruins, leaving the tradition-rich National Hockey League club still looking for a leader.</p>
<p>The Bruins, who fired coach Steve Kasper last month after they missed the playoffs for the first time in 30 years, also announced that Mike Keenan was removed from consideration for the job.</p>
<p>The NHL team released a statement Friday that said the coach of Boston University's successful hockey programme had decided to stay where he is.</p>
<p>&quot;Jack Parker informed me today that he has decided to remain at Boston University and is therefore declining our offer to become the next Bruins head coach,&quot; said Bruins president and general manager Harry Sinden.</p>
<p>&quot;While I regret his decision as a loss to the Bruins, I have tremendous respect for Jack as both a person and as a coach and I understand completely his reasons for declining our offer. We wish him nothing but continued success with Boston University and their hockey programme.&quot;</p>
<p>Parker has compiled an impressive 549-257-46 record in 24 years with the Terriers. The team advanced to college hockey's Final Four three times in the past four years and won the NCAA Championship in 1995 to add to his 1988 college title.</p>
<p>Keenan, fired early in the regular season by St. Louis, interviewed for the position last week. Keenan guided the New York Rangers to the 1994 Stanley Cup, ending the franchise's 54-year title drought.</p>
<p>&quot;(Assistant GM) Mike O'Connell and I will continue to evaluate and interview coaching candidates to determine the best fit for the Bruins,&quot; said Sinden.</p>
<p>Other candidates include current New Jersey Devils assistant Robbie Ftorek and Mighty Ducks of Anaheim head coach Ron Wilson.</p>
<p>Before missing this season's playoffs, the Bruins had the longest running streak of consecutive playoff appearances. They finished the season with the NHL's worst record (26-47-9) despite the presence of star defenceman Ray Bourque.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
