<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="571554" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>zaire: Zaire's Mobutu delays return home from Gabon.</title>
<headline>Zaire's Mobutu delays return home from Gabon.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bunce</byline>
<dateline>LIBREVILLE 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's embattled President Mobutu Sese Seko delayed his return to Kinshasa on Friday for talks in Gabon with South Africa's Vice-President Thabo Mbeki, a Zairean Foreign Ministry official said.</p>
<p>Mbeki, shuttling round Africa as part of efforts to head off a bloody battle for Zaire's capital, was in Zaire's second city Lubumbashi earlier for talks with rebel leader Laurent Kabila.</p>
<p>As two more international airlines cancelled flights to Kinshasa, the rebels restated their demand that Mobutu stand down and hand power to Kabila.</p>
<p>&quot;We insist as we have always insisted that Mr Mobutu must resign and hand over power directly to 'President' Kabila,&quot; rebel &quot;foreign minister&quot; Bizima Karaha said in Lubumbashi.</p>
<p>There was little fresh news from the war front. Last reports of the rebel advance spoke of a bloody battle at the start of the week at Kenge, around 250 km (155 miles) from Kinshasa.</p>
<p>Karaha accused Central African presidents who held a mini-summit in Libreville with Mobutu on Thursday of &quot;playing games and trying to protect Mobutu&quot;.</p>
<p>The summit foresaw a key role for Zaire's parliament and urged early replacement of its speaker -- the constitutional successor in the event of Mobutu's death or incapacity.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot be fooled,&quot; Karaha said. &quot;The proposal is absolute nonsense to us.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. television network CNN reported from Kinshasa that Mbeki was carrying a new peace plan that envisaged parliament electing a speaker to whom Mobutu could hand power and who in return could hand over to another leader.</p>
<p>Mbeki's trip is part of a South African attempt to mediate a peaceful transition of power. Kabila's rebels control three quarters of the country and Mobutu has agreed in principle to step down after 32 years in power.</p>
<p>Officials in Kinshasa had said that Mobutu, who also has cancer, would return home on Friday.</p>
<p>The Zairean Foreign Ministry official told Reuters in Libreville that Mobutu would return to Kinshasa on Saturday -- one day later than planned. &quot;We are waiting for the vice-president of South Africa to arrive,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>Mbeki is trying to build on talks between Mobutu and Kabila hosted by South Africa's president, Nelson Mandela, on a South African ship on Sunday.</p>
<p>Karaha and senior U.N. sources in Geneva said the two civil war rivals had agreed to meet on the ship again on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Mobutu's fellow French-speaking Central African presidents welcomed his decision not to seek re-election, saying it opened a way for a peaceful end to the war.</p>
<p>France, a longtime Mobutu ally, expressed similar hopes. Foreign Ministry spokesman Jacques Rummelhardt said in Paris the mini-summit &quot;opened new prospects for an orderly and peaceful transition, based on the regular functioning of institutions&quot;.</p>
<p>The United Nations accused Zairean rebels on Friday of blocking an investigation into alleged massacres of Rwandan Hutu refugees in eastern Zaire by denying U.N. investigators and forensic experts access to rebel-controlled areas to dig up mass graves.</p>
<p>Belgian airline Sabena has cancelled all stops at Kinshasa and is diverting its flights to Congo's capital Brazzaville. Ethiopian Airlines also cancelled its flights and diverted them to Togo's capital Lome. Swissair has switched to Brazzaville.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GABON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIBREVILLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
