<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="571610" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Deadline looms for South Africa political amnesty.</title>
<headline>Deadline looms for South Africa political amnesty.</headline>
<byline>Anton Ferreira</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa passes a key milestone in efforts to bury the hate and bitterness of three decades of race war on Saturday, the deadline for combatants from all sides to claim amnesty.</p>
<p>The Truth and Reconciliation Commission, mandated to grant amnesty to those who make full confessions, warned apartheid-era defence minister Magnus Malan on Friday that he should not miss the deadline at midnight on Saturday.</p>
<p>Malan, defence minister from 1980 to 1991, has declared along with former white presidents P.W. Botha and F.W. de Klerk -- the three most senior surviving apartheid leaders -- that he would not seek indemnity from prosecution or civil claims.</p>
<p>Most of the leadership of the African National Congress, with the likely exception of President Nelson Mandela, are expected to file amnesty applications on Friday or Saturday.</p>
<p>Malan testified voluntarily to the commission on Wednesday, saying he accepted moral responsibility for the actions of the defence force, including raids on ANC targets in neighbouring countries.</p>
<p>&quot;However, I do not intend to seek amnesty for those operations,&quot; he said. &quot;If with the wisdom of hindsight...my authority should be regarded by some as culpable, I am prepared to face the consequences.&quot;</p>
<p>Truth commission deputy chairman Alex Boraine urged Malan to change his mind.</p>
<p>&quot;He would be well advised not only in terms of reconciliation but in terms of his own self-interest to apply for amnesty even at this 11th hour,&quot; Boraine said.</p>
<p>The deadline for amnesty applications was originally December last year, but Mandela extended it by five months at the request of commission chairman Archbishop Desmond Tutu because relatively few people had lodged applications.</p>
<p>Tutu has urged anyone who might be liable for criminal prosecution or civil damage claims to &quot;take this golden opportunity to apply for amnesty on the most generous terms possible&quot;.</p>
<p>His commission, set up in 1995 to uncover as much as possible about political crimes and human rights abuses during the apartheid era, hopes the lure of amnesty will persuade perpetrators to reveal their secrets.</p>
<p>Dozens of former security police officers have applied, including those responsible for the death of black activist Steve Biko in 1977.</p>
<p>But few of their political masters have followed suit. De Klerk has said he regrets that some maverick officers stepped out of line but that he never personally ordered an extra- judicial killing.</p>
<p>ANC deputy secretary-general Cheryl Carolus said this week de Klerk was making a mistake because he could be prosecuted some day for what happened during his rule.</p>
<p>Political analyst Laurie Nathan said it was significant that General Malan had accepted moral responsibility, but added that only if he applied for amnesty would the full story of his activities be told.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that he may be experiencing pressure from other soldiers,&quot; Nathan said.</p>
<p>&quot;Senior members of the old defence force feel betrayed that their political and military leadership have denied responsibility or claimed ignorance. And these soldiers were operating under orders.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
