<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="571657" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romanian leader pledges to help abandoned children.</title>
<headline>Romanian leader pledges to help abandoned children.</headline>
<byline>Karin Popescu</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romanian President Emil Constantinescu on Friday told a group representing nearly 100,000 abandoned children he would employ a former orphan to help tackle the problems of children in care.</p>
<p>&quot;I will organise a competition to take on an orphan at the presidency to monitor what happens in orphanages with children like you,&quot; Constantinescu told 25 youngsters who ate sandwiches and drank juice at the presidential Cotroceni palace.</p>
<p>Constantinescu, a father of two, met the children at the end of a United Nations' Children's Fund (UNICEF) conference in Bucharest focusing on the rights of institutionalised children.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first instance of recognition at this level of the problem of institutionalised children,&quot; Maie Ayoub von Kohl, UNICEF representative in Romania, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Constantinescu, whose election victory last November ended seven years of leftist rule which followed the 1989 fall of communism, set child protection as a major goal for his four-year mandate.</p>
<p>&quot;Initially, not a word was spoken about orphans and abandoned children. Then, the media reports started,&quot; Constantinescu told journalists after a one-hour chat with the children. &quot;The time has come to do something.&quot;</p>
<p>Of one million children in care in 18 countries in eastern Europe, Romania alone has 90,000. Their number has grown by 20 percent in seven years of post-communist decline.</p>
<p>At least another 2,000 live in the streets of Bucharest or other major towns. Romanian children also account for 54 percent of Europe's juvenile AIDS victims and HIV carriers.</p>
<p>Romania is trying hard to shed its image of the early post-communist years, when television pictures of malnourished children in filthy orphanages were broadcast around the world.</p>
<p>Most children land in institutions after family breakdown or because their parents have criminal records or are long-term unemployed. Forty percent remain there until adulthood.</p>
<p>Despite budget cuts imposed by market reforms, authorities have attacked the problem by quadrupling monthly child benefit to the equivalent of $7 and extending paid maternity leave. Monthly salaries stand at about $80.</p>
<p>&quot;I will become involved and hope ministers, mayors and members of parliament will follow,&quot; Constantinescu said after being photographed seated with children on the residence's red-carpeted staircase.</p>
<p>&quot;The truth is that most of society is passive. We cannot sit and watch how society degrades itself.&quot;</p>
<p>Long-term institutionalisation, a legacy of communism, is both harmful and costly. Statistics show that each child kept in an institution cost the Romanian public purse an average of $1,700 per year over the past five years.</p>
<p>&quot;Now that we have broken the ice with this visit, we will keep in contact,&quot; Constantinescu told the children. &quot;Consider me your father and call me whenever you have problems.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
