<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="571608" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Investors, mining firms visit Zairean rebel leader.</title>
<headline>Investors, mining firms visit Zairean rebel leader.</headline>
<byline>Buchizya Mseteka</byline>
<dateline>LUBUMBASHI, Zaire 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some 25 fund managers, investors and mining experts arrived in rebel-held Zaire on Friday for talks with rebel leader Laurent Kabila.</p>
<p>Earl Young, spokesman for U.S.-based America Mineral Fields Inc, organisers of the visit, said the team included representatives of S.G. Warburg, C.M. Oliver of Canada, Value Investors and leading banks from Europe and the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;Our interest is to see an end of hostilities and the creation of a good economic and commerce environment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kabila's alliance last month awarded the Kolwezi copper/cobalt tailings project to America Mineral Fields in a $1 billion deal which also included building a 200,000 tonne a year zinc smelter at Kipushi near the Zambian border.</p>
<p>Young told Reuters that the deal also includes rehabilitation and repair of the $4 billion Kipushi mine, rehabilitation of the concentrator and processing of tailings at Kipushi.</p>
<p>&quot;We consider the agreement to be a major coup, given that Kipushi mine, during the period of its full-scale operation, was considered the world's largest zinc mine while at the same time being in the lowest cost quartile,&quot; Young said.</p>
<p>Young said once fully rehabilitated, Kipushi could process 200,000 tonnes of zinc and 30,000 tonnes of copper a year and generate 400,000 tonnes of by-product acid a year, as well as precious metals.</p>
<p>As Kabila's rebels close in on the capital Kinshasa, the country's vast mineral riches are beckoning foreign firms, igniting a scramble that recalls the grab for wealth over 100 years ago in Africa's third largest country.</p>
<p>On Thursday, the rebel-appointed head of the Zairean mining giant Gecamines said he was seeking foreign fund managers to provide badly needed hard currency to help revamp what was once the world's fifth leading copper producing firm.</p>
<p>Mbaka Kawaya Swana, managing director of Gecamines (Generale des Carrieres et des Mines), told Reuters that his firm needs $1 billion to restore mining operations to 1960 levels but a few hundred million would be enough for a start.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUBUMBASHI, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
