<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="571863" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BARBADOS: Caribbean, U.S. disagree on how to handle Cuba.</title>
<headline>Caribbean, U.S. disagree on how to handle Cuba.</headline>
<byline>Michael Becker</byline>
<dateline>BRIDGETOWN, Barbados 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>As leaders of the Caribbean prepare for their first-ever summit May 10 with U.S. President Bill Clinton, communist-ruled Cuba is the ghost at the feast.</p>
<p>Washington and the Caribbean's leaders are poles apart on how to deal with absent Cuba, the sole communist regime in the hemisphere, and neither side is happy with the other's approach.</p>
<p>Caribbean leaders prefer a form of &quot;constructive engagement&quot; similar to U.S. diplomacy toward the apartheid regime in South Africa to coax and encourage change in Cuba.</p>
<p>The United States, on the other hand, recently tightened its 35-year-old embargo against Cuba, passing a controversial law seeking to extend its effects to companies in third countries that trade with and invest in Cuba.</p>
<p>To regional leaders, the law, known as Helms-Burton, is another example of unilateral U.S. action that rankles.</p>
<p>Leaders of the 14-member Caribbean Community (Caricom), Haiti and the Dominican Republic plan to raise several such issues with Clinton on Saturday.</p>
<p>These include the Federal Communications Commission's decision to lower the accounting rates for international phone calls, which is likely to cost the Caribbean hundreds of millions of dollars in annual revenue if implemented.</p>
<p>There is also the Federal Aviation Administration's new categorization of civil aviation departments, which has cost the two main regional air carriers some $150 million in losses over the past two years as they attempt to compete with U.S.-based American Airlines.</p>
<p>The Caribbean fears the U.S. embargo will only lead to political instability in Cuba, which in turn would have a chilling ripple effect on potential investment for the entire region. Foreign investment is vitally needed to replace aid flows that have dried up in the past decade.</p>
<p>Former Commonwealth secretary-general and current Caricom chief trade negotiator Sir Shridath Ramphal said the United States needs to move &quot;out of their Cold War posture (of) being a strong-arm power&quot; and begin &quot;giving more enlightened leadership&quot; on issues like Cuba.</p>
<p>Ramphal headed the West Indian Commission, set up by Caricom six years ago to chart a course for the region's future, which recommended the region strengthen its ties with Cuba and invite Havana to join the 35-member Association of Caribbean States.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, a Jamaican firm become the first foreign company to set up shop in Cuba's first free zone. Air Jamaica will begin direct flights to Havana on June 1, and the European Union-funded Caribbean Export Development Agency has opened an office in Cuba.</p>
<p>Perhaps the most telling gesture occurred last month, when Grenada's Prime Minister Keith Mitchell was in Cuba on an official visit, 14 years after U.S. troops ousted a Cuban- backed Marxist regime in Grenada.</p>
<p>Mitchell invited Cuban President Fidel Castro to attend next year's Caricom summit -- which will likely be held in Grenada.</p>
<p>Caricom will meet in Jamaica this July to consider whether to begin negotiating a free trade accord with Cuba. However, the region is proceeding more cautiously than most officials care to admit publicly, out of concern for Washington's reaction, regional sources say.</p>
<p>&quot;The reality is the politicians don't want to jeopardise their relations with the U.S.,&quot; admitted one regional trade official. &quot;Save Trinidad, Barbados, and the Dominican Republic, none of these countries has the capacity to export to Cuba at levels that would justify the political risk.&quot;</p>
<p>When asked if the May 10 summit would broach the issue of Cuba, the response of Jamaican Prime Minister and summit chairman P.J. Patterson was a terse &quot;no.&quot;</p>
<p>But officials say the matter of raising it with Clinton was discussed in Thursday's preparatory talks among the region's heads of governments. The final decision was not to bring it up, for fear it would bog down the rest of the meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we'll make our position (on relations with Cuba) clear,&quot; noted Caricom Secretary-General Edwin Carrington, &quot;but we're not going to fight that battle at this summit.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BARB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CARCOM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CARIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRIDGETOWN, Barbados"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BARBADOS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
