<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="571876" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico soybean demand high, record imports seen.</title>
<headline>Mexico soybean demand high, record imports seen.</headline>
<byline>Chris Aspin</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Demand for soybeans in Mexico remains very strong, and despite record high prices for beans, traders believe imports will surpass last cycle's 2.7 million tonne record.</p>
<p>&quot;Even with the record high price of beans, the demand in Mexico is very strong according to United States and Mexico-based traders,&quot; the United Soybean Board and American Soybean Association (ASA) said in a update obtained Friday.  </p>
<p>&quot;Importers have ordered a record volume to date and if they execute current orders there will be a larger volume of imports than earlier expected for the marketing year,&quot; they said.</p>
<p>In the marketing year Sept 1 - Aug 31, a total of 1,875,000 tonnes has been imported up to April 9 from the United States, Mexico's traditional sole supplier of beans, although the amount of beans commited to be imported is put at 2,492,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Traders said they did not expect high prices to trend down in the near future, that is until the start of the U.S. harvest. &quot;Not even the beginning of the Argentine harvest is expected to push prices down,&quot; the USB-ASA said.  </p>
<p>In a new and interesting trend, high prices have forced some importers to look to other sources of beans.</p>
<p>&quot;One major oil crusher has confirmed the purchase of two boatloads of beans from South America that were quoted at $7 per tonne less than U.S. sources,&quot; the USB-ASA said.</p>
<p>The umbrella organisation said it had not been confirmed but the two shiploads are expected to be sourced from Brazil.</p>
<p>&quot;If one crusher has already purchased beans from Brazil we can be assured that other crushers are looking for quotes from the south as well,&quot; the USB-ASA said.</p>
<p>One trader pointed out that although there might be more orders from South America, as of Aug 1, a tariff of 15 percent on beans from non-North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) countries comes into effect.</p>
<p>&quot;This does not give a lot of time for importers to get vesels to Mexican ports before the tariff goes into effect,&quot; the USB-ASA said.</p>
<p>Meal prices in  Mexico remain around 2,900 to 2,950 pesos per tonne (around $370/tonnes), but are likely to be raised soon because of pressure from higher bean prices, traders said.</p>
<p>((--Chris Aspin, Mexico City newsroom +525 7289530))</p>
<p>E-mail at chris.aspin@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
