<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="571914" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>COSTA RICA: Central American rights activists say abuses continue.</title>
<headline>Central American rights activists say abuses continue.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Worsnip</byline>
<dateline>SAN JOSE, Costa Rica 1997-05-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>As U.S. President Bill Clinton hailed a new era of democracy in Central America on Thursday, human rights advocates were telling his wife that free elections had not ended abuses in the region.</p>
<p>A group of 10 rights champions, most of them women, gave a warm welcome to first lady Hillary Rodham Clinton and Secretary of State Madeleine Albright -- perhaps the two most powerful women in Washington -- at a meeting in San Jose.</p>
<p>But while Mrs. Clinton and Albright praised their hosts' efforts to promote women's rights in the region, they were thrown on the defensive by criticism of U.S. treatment of illegal immigrants from Central America.</p>
<p>Victoria Marina de Aviles, Human Rights Procurator in El Salvador, called on the United States to &quot;make laws more flexible&quot; to deal with the immigrants, thousands of whom fear deportation as a result of a recent toughening of the law.</p>
<p>The Czech-born Albright, following a line she has taken throughout her tour this week of Guatemala, Mexico and Costa Rica, pointed out that she herself was an immigrant and well understood the lure of the United States.</p>
<p>The new U.S. legislation, she said &quot;is trying very hard to make it possible for there to be more legal immigrants so that the problems that are created by many illegal immigrants are dealt with.&quot;</p>
<p>President Clinton, who was confronted with similar appeals during a meeting earlier on Thursday with Central American leaders, had pledged to try to &quot;mitigate some of the harsher aspects&quot; of the law and to avoid mass deportations, she said.</p>
<p>Juan Mendez, director of the Inter-American Institute of Human Rights which hosted Mrs. Clinton and Albright, said that despite the fall of right-wing dictatorships in Central America, most countries still suffered from &quot;insufficient democracy.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Authoritarian attitudes often co-exist with elected and representative government,&quot; Mendez said. Freedom of the press was not encouraged and large sections of the population felt marginalized and deprived of legal recourse, he added.</p>
<p>Several participants spoke of continuing oppression and abuses against women as a result of what one called the &quot;macho and patriarchal culture&quot; in Latin America.</p>
<p>El Salvador sociologist Sonia Cansino made clear that bitter divisions over abortion were not confined to the United States, saying the practice had been &quot;criminalized completely&quot; in her country. &quot;We are considered good citizens only as long as we are mothers,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Mrs. Clinton said that while massive human rights abuses were a thing of the past, &quot;that doesn't mean we can let up on our vigilance about the importance of human rights or the need to make insufficient democracies sufficient democracies.&quot;</p>
<p>With a more positive spin, Albright said that &quot;the greatest pleasure at the moment is that we are at this moment facing a new challenge&quot; in Central America.</p>
<p>&quot;It has changed from protecting citizens against the violations of human rights perpetrated by government agencies to now working with elected governments to protect against violations committed by individuals. That is a big difference.&quot;</p>
<p>Human rights would continue to be a central plank of U.S. foreign policy, she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN JOSE, Costa Rica"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COSTA RICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
