<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572006" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bill to prohibit Internet taxation moving forward.</title>
<headline>Bill to prohibit Internet taxation moving forward.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Legislation is moving ahead to prevent state and local governments from imposing new taxes on Internet transactions, with hearings expected in the next few weeks, Congressional staff said on Friday.</p>
<p>Rep Chris Cox, California Republican, and Sen Ron Wyden, Democrat of Oregon, introduced identical bills back in March to impose an indefinite moratorium on state and local taxation of electronic commerce.</p>
<p>Congress can &quot;help ensure that state, local and foreign tax policies don't interfere with the potential for economic growth over the Internet,&quot; Peter Uhlmann, a Cox staffer said.  </p>
<p>Senate Commerce Committee's Communications subcommitee will hold a hearing on the measure in the next few weeks, Uhlmann said speaking at a meeting sponsored by the Internet Caucus here.</p>
<p>Commerce Committee chairman John McCain of Arizona and subcommittee chairman Conrad Burns of Montana are co-sponsors of the Wyden bill, Uhlmann noted.</p>
<p>In the House, both the Commerce and Judiciary Committees will consider the bill.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to be able to move forward with some hearings and, if all goes well, we're hopeful this will be moved through on a fast-track,&quot; Uhlmann said.  </p>
<p>In March, Rep. Cox said he wanted to prevent the World Wide Web from becoming the &quot;World Wide Wallet&quot; for governments looking for additional tax revenues.</p>
<p>Industry officials at the meeting urged Congress to prevent excessive or inconsistent taxation of Internet commerce.</p>
<p>Electronic commerce &quot;is not an issue that state taxation can be left out of,&quot; AT&amp;T Corp's Jim Eads said at the meeting. &quot;It should be addressed and, I think, will be addressed ultimately by Congress.&quot;  </p>
<p>Sales of goods and commerce online are projected to grow to over $7 billion in the year 2000 from under $1 billion last year, according to market researchers at Jupiter Communications.</p>
<p>But that still pales by comparison to tradtional sales and mail order transactions, International Business Machines Corp's 's Roger Cochetti noted.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the value of tax revenues that are at risk today is relatiavely small...these are areas where governments ought to restrain themselves from leaping to some tax conclusion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A complete audio recording of the Internet caucus event will be posted in the next few weeks at http://www.democracy.net.</p>
<p>--Aaron Pressman((202-898-8312))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
