<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572057" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE cocoa ends thinly traded session higher.</title>
<headline>CSCE cocoa ends thinly traded session higher.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE cocoa futures ended broadly higher in sluggish dealings Friday, with a late bout of local buying nudging the market toward session peaks, traders said.</p>
<p>Benchmark July futures rose $18 a tonne on the day, to $1,440, having ranged from $1,441 and $1,420. Spot May, which goes off the board next week, also gained $18, to $1,430, while the remaining months ended between $14 and $16 higher.</p>
<p>After a slow start, cocoa prices climbed in the morning after a burst of speculative buying sent the July contract through near-term resistance at $1,432.</p>
<p>But scale-up trade buying halted the rally and prices spent the bulk of the day drifting in positive territory.</p>
<p>Trading volume remained light, reaching an estimated 4,309 lots at the close.</p>
<p>Technically, traders said July would need to punch through resistance at $1,450 to encourage enthusiastic buying, while support was eyed toward today's low of $1,420.</p>
<p>On the fundamental front, traders said all eyes were focused on West African weather to gauge early development of the 1997/98 cocoa crop.</p>
<p>They said there are concerns dry conditions in Ivory Coast earlier this year may have kept soil moisture below optimum levels.</p>
<p>&quot;We did see significant rains in mid-April, still it may not have been enough to replenish moisture,&quot; a trader said. Traders await the latest CFTC Commitment of Traders report due late Friday. They expect the report to show little change in speculative (non-commercial and nonreportable) positions from two weeks ago, when speculators were net long more than 12,000 lots.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the spec position will be little changed,&quot; one trader said. &quot;There's been little change in price, volume has been light, open interest is steady, so there's little reason to expect it to change.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodity Desk +1 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
