<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57227" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - Sept 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - Sept 16.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Thai press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>TOP STORIES</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa has rejected another request by senior Chart Thai members for him to voluntarily step down before the censure debate which will begine in parliament on Wednesday. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>- Flash floods have hit the northern province of Phrae after two days of heavy rain. Most roads are closed as the water level is 50 centimetres above the road surface. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>- A large number of military personnel are dissatisfied with the delay in the announcement of this year's annual military reshuffle. Many officers thought Prime Minister Banharn delayed the announcement so he could use it as a bargaining chip to gain the support of key  coalition allies during the censure debate. (NATION)</p>
<p>- A court in the northeastern province of Buri Ram is set to hand down a verdict today on case of a couple who were arrested last year just before the general election and charged with vote buying. Police found a large amount of money at their home in small denominations three days before the election. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>	 + + + +</p>
<p>BUSINESS</p>
<p>- The Bangkok Bank of Commerce is heading for a two billion baht loss this year, its third loss in three years. A bank committee source said the bank plans to lodge charges against three officials of the bank who were allegedly involved in misappropriation of the bank's funds during the former management. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>- Some nine construction companies are to propose that the Stock Exchange of Thailand establish a new constuction sector this week in an attempt to distance themselves from the embattled property sector. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Bodi Chunnananda has asked finance ministry and central bank officials to prepare documents relating to economy problems to help the Prime Minister during an upcoming censure debate in the parliament. (KRUNGTHEP THURAKIJ)</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
