<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572311" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Solidere stars in trade in Beirut.</title>
<headline>Solidere stars in trade in Beirut.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Solidere shares continued to rise on the Beirut Stock Exchange in the week ended on Friday and brokers said the company's shares shone in a stable market which encouraged Arab investors to buy 30 percent of traded shares.</p>
<p>Solidere A shares rose 4.5 percent to $11.5 from last week's $11 and B shares rose 11.4 percent to $12.25 from $11.</p>
<p>&quot;Solidere shares played star this week in a stable market after last week's rise of the company's Global Depositary Receeipts  in London and due to dividend declaration expected before the end of May,&quot; Samar Assaf, a broker for Fidus told Reuters.</p>
<p>The GDRs, issued last November at $11.5 on the London Stock Exchange, rose last week to $17.625 from $12 a week earlier. It closed at $15.875.</p>
<p>This week prices were the highest since January 1996 when Solidere, Lebanon's biggest company, still traded its shares on the private Beirut Seondary Market.</p>
<p>It switched to the BSE last September and the private market no longer operates.</p>
<p>Assaf said Arab investors, encouraged by last week's rise of Solidere shares, bought nearly 30 percent of the 590,270 traded shares this week.</p>
<p>The Solidere rise helped the LISPI and BLOM general indices rise 1.56 percent and 5.66 percent to 88.37 and 1,008 respectively. The LIBX bank index rose 1.23 percent to 139.75.</p>
<p>Among the three listed banks only shares of Banque Libanaise pour le Commerce rose 3.8 percent to $17.25 from $16.625 on last Friday while Bank of Beirut and Banque Audi held steady on $3.5625 and $20.125 respectively.</p>
<p>Total BSE turnover for the week shortened to three days by public holidays was 970,240 shares for a value of $9,687,292 against 938,421 shares for a value of $8,133,821 for during also three working days last week.</p>
<p>Of the four listed industrial companies Eternit rose to $1.875 from $1.8125, Ciments Libanaise fell slightly to $1.2812 from $1.28125 and Ciments Blancs fell to $4.75 from $5. There was no trade in tilemaker Uniceramic.</p>
<p>-Sultan Sleiman, Beirut editorial (9611) 602057 745307</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
