<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572321" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. accuses landlord of $5 million kickback scheme.</title>
<headline>U.S. accuses landlord of $5 million kickback scheme.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Croft</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. officials said Friday they had filed a civil lawsuit against a well-known landlord, accusing him of taking part in a $5 million kickback scheme involving government-subsidized low-income housing projects.</p>
<p>U.S. Housing and Urban Development (HUD) Secretary Andrew Cuomo and Michael Yamaguchi, U.S. attorney for northern California, announced the 12-count civil complaint against landlord Bruce Rozet, his business partner Deane Ross and several companies they jointly own.</p>
<p>Yamaguchi said the complaint -- filed in federal court in San Francisco on Thursday -- arose from a kickback scheme involving management contracts for 17 HUD-insured multi-family housing projects in California and Nevada.</p>
<p>&quot;We have zero tolerance for waste, fraud and abuse. If you violate the public trust, if you defraud this department or abuse the properties, we will be relentless in our pursuit of justice,&quot; Cuomo said, speaking at a San Francisco news conference by video satellite link from Washington.</p>
<p>The government said the case was part of a &quot;get tough&quot; campaign it launched recently against landlords engaged in waste, fraud or abuse of taxpayer dollars.</p>
<p>Rozet is estimated to be involved with more than 230 housing projects across the nation that receive more than $71 million in federal assistance, the government said. It said the investigation would continue to look at the other Rozet properties nationwide.</p>
<p>Prosecutors said they had evidence that Rozet entered into a $5 million kickback scheme, allegedly defrauding the federal government and siphoning off funds intended for the maintenance of the 17 properties.</p>
<p>The complaint alleged that Rozet and the other defendants entered into a fee-splitting agreement which gave a property manager the exclusive right to oversee certain HUD properties in exchange for paying Rozet and the others one third of all management fees earned under the contract.</p>
<p>The management fees were paid mainly from HUD subsidies but HUD did not know about the scheme, which allegedly began in October 1990 and continued until now, Yamaguchi said.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result, assets were misappropriated, resulting in substandard upkeep and management, and rents increased at an inflated rate,&quot; a government statement said.</p>
<p>Cuomo said &quot;matters such as today's are in my opinion double crimes. They steal taxpayer dollars and they condemn tenants to live in deplorable living conditions.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he had visited one of the properties named in the complaint and had seen a broken pipe &quot;literally spewing human waste on a children's playground.&quot;</p>
<p>Rozet is chief executive officer of Los Angeles-based property company Associated Financial Corp. (AFC) and Ross is president of the company, which is also a defendant. Also named as a defendant was Lawrence Penn, an executive of a company that allegedly acted for Rozet and Ross.</p>
<p>The government accused them of violating the Anti-Kickback Act and the False Claims Act and alleged breach of contract and negligence.</p>
<p>Robert Bonner, an attorney representing Rozet and AFC, said: &quot;We believe that the government's civil suit is unfounded (and) that the practice of management companies paying owners in conjunction with managing properties is a common practice that has been known to HUD for many years.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We're confident that our clients did nothing wrong and that they will prevail in this lawsuit,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Rozet was quoted in the Los Angeles Times Friday as denying the allegations. &quot;It's a scurrilous attack on someone totally innocent of wrongdoing. This is nothing more than a publicity stunt,&quot; he was quoted as saying.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8500011">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
