<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572466" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS - Gasoline demand seen growing, but slowly.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Gasoline demand seen growing, but slowly.</headline>
<byline>Matt Daily</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Very high &quot;implied demand&quot; for gasoline overstates real underlying demand and prices are expected to remain fairly tame, even with rising seasonal demand and near record-low inventories, analysts said.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, the American Petroleum Institute showed continued high &quot;implied demand&quot; for gasoline (the sum of stocks drawdown, imports and output) and the Department of Energy also reported a sharp decline in gasoline stocks.</p>
<p>Gasoline futures began a small rally after Wednesday's DOE report which has taken them up about 5.5 percent, to stand at around 63 cents a gallon Friday afternoon.</p>
<p>However, the DOE, which has a much more comprehensive survey of demand, has been running contrary to API &quot;implied demand&quot;, showing anemic demand through to the first week in May - about 1.1 percent higher year-on-year.</p>
<p>&quot;We will probably see tight short-term supplies,&quot; said Dave Costello, analyst with the Department of Energy's Energy Information Administration (EIA). &quot;But it would take a much greater demand growth rate this summer than we thought to cause problems,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>According to figures released by the American Petroleum Institute, implied demand totaled 8.76 million barrels per day last week -- much higher than levels usually seen during the peak demand summer months.</p>
<p>However, the DOE demand four-week average for &quot;gasoline supply&quot; - basically, from the refinery sector to the distribution level - at 7.963 million bpd, up about 90,000 bpd, or 1.1 percent, from the same period last year.</p>
<p>&quot;On a week-to-week basis, the data is a little tricky to use,&quot; said Kevin Lindemer of Cambridge Energy Research Associates. &quot;Demand is growing. It's slow growth, but it's there,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Gasoline stocks fell to a meager 193.6 million barrels in the latest reporting week, down 2.4 million barrels from a week ago and about 9.4 million barrels below last year's mark, according to the EIA.</p>
<p>That drop came despite the U.S. refinery output of 7.69 million barrels a day (bpd) and imports averaging 544,000 bpd over the past four weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not assuming stocks will get back to what people call 'normal levels'... It would take some pretty high refinery runs and imports to make that happen,&quot; Costello said.</p>
<p>Costello said the DOE forecast for U.S. gasoline demand in the second and third quarter is between 8.1 and 8.2 million barrels a day, an increase of about 1.9 percent from 1996 levels.</p>
<p>To meet expected demand, the U.S. will need to produce about 7.75 to 7.8 million bpd of gasoline, an increase of about 100,000 bpd from year-ago levels, coupled with imports of about 300,000 bpd.</p>
<p>Other factors outside of the immediate supply-demand fundamentals should keep a lid on prices, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Crude oil stocks are pretty high,&quot; at around 15 million barrels above last year's levels, said Paulo Nery, senior consultant with Pace Consultants Inc in Houston. &quot;That's why people are not concerned with gasoline stocks.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition, traders said U.S. refineries could easily boost their gasoline output if needed, just as the low heating oil inventory level before winter 1996 was met by record production.</p>
<p>&quot;We've seen capacity a lot higher than it is now,&quot; said Gerald Samuels, managing director of Arb Oil.</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk +1 212 859-1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
