<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572425" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Political, environmental groups target Texaco.</title>
<headline>Political, environmental groups target Texaco.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Environmental groups, Burmese political activists and the Reverend Jesse Jackson's Rainbow-Push Coalition plan to descend on Texaco Inc's annual shareholder meeting in Rye Brook, N.Y., on May 13.</p>
<p>The Westchester People's Action Coalition, New York Student Environmental Coalition and Wetlands Environmental and Social Justice Centre said that they will organize a protest outside the meeting.</p>
<p>The Interfaith Center for Corporate Responsibility, a church shareholder activist organisation, will address the shareholder meeting.  </p>
<p>The environmental activists said they are targeting Texaco's environmental record in Ecuador.</p>
<p>A legal case against the company was rejected by a New York State Federal Court in White Plains and a motion for reconsideration is under appeal following a submission to the courts by the Ecuadorean government.</p>
<p>Texaco has until May 12 to make a response in the case which seeks $800 million to $1.0 billion from the oil major for allegedly polluting rivers and land and displacing Amazon Indians.  </p>
<p>The Free Burma Coalition, a student organization, will also be represented at the annual meeting to protest Texaco's participation in Yetagun gas field in the Andaman Sea, some 125 miles off the Burmese coast, in which it holds a 42.9 percent stake.</p>
<p>Activists charge that U.S. companies which invest in Burma are prolonging the life of the country's military government.</p>
<p>Father Joe LaMar of the Interfaith Center for Corporate Responsibilty said that Texaco could avoid the opprobrium which has attached to another U.S. oil company involved in Burma, Unocal Corp, by pulling out now.  </p>
<p>&quot;They indicated to us that they were not necessarily committed to Burma.  They can get out with a profit now,&quot; LaMar said.</p>
<p>Last year, Texaco shareholders rejected calls to pull out of Burma at the annual meeting by a large majority.</p>
<p>Since then, the U.S. has imposed economic sanctions on new investment in Burma and New York City and some public sector and state pension funds have indicated they are considering divesting stakes in companies which invest there.</p>
<p>Texaco has always said it will abide by U.S. law in its dealings in Burma.</p>
<p>Jesse Jackson is also expected to attend the annual meeting to protest against Texaco's treatment of black employees, other groups said.</p>
<p>His office could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Texaco has been a target for Rainbow-Push since the company lost a racial discrimination lawsuit last year.</p>
<p>Texaco settled a suit brought by black employees last year for $176.1 million but faces a new race suit in a Manhattan federal court. ((-- David Chance New York Newsroom 212 859 1902))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
