<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572458" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: San Onofre Calif. power plant owners to build reef.</title>
<headline>San Onofre Calif. power plant owners to build reef.</headline>
<dateline>ROSEMEAD, Calif. 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Owners of the San Onofre nuclear power plant, near Los Angeles, agreed on Friday to build an artificial reef ordered by the state to compensate for the power plant's impact on marine life.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not going to litigate the commission's decision,&quot; said Steve Hansen, a spokesman for Edison International, whose subsidiary Southern California Edison Co holds a 75 percent stake in the plant.</p>
<p>San Onofre's other owners are Enova Corp's subsidiary San Diego Gas &amp; Electric Co (20 percent) and the cities of Anaheim and Riverside (5 percent).  </p>
<p>Edison said that they do not yet have a cost estimate for the project.</p>
<p>But Hansen noted that the owners have not chosen to establish a $118 million trust to fund the mitigation measures, as suggested by the Coastal Commission staff. They plan instead to carry out the requirements themselves.</p>
<p>Edison had sought to revise a 1991 agreement to construct a 300-acre artificial kelp reef off the coast of the San Clemente nuclear plant.  </p>
<p>But the state's Coastal Commission turned down the proposal and is requiring the plant's owners to restore 150 acres of wetland at San Dieguito Lagoon at Del Mar and to construct a 150-acre artificial kelp reef at a site to be chosen near the power plant.</p>
<p>The plant's owners will also provide $3.6 million to enhance marine fish hatchery programs in California and provide funding to the Coastal Commission staff to monitor and oversee the projects as soon as the commission decides how the funds are to be paid, a decision expected on May 14.</p>
<p>The nuclear plant's two operating units produce about 2,200 megawatts of electric power.</p>
<p>((--Los Angeles bureau + 1 213 955 6761))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROSEMEAD, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
