<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572489" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Grace, restructuring done, eyes acquisitions.</title>
<headline>Grace, restructuring done, eyes acquisitions.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Zengerle</byline>
<dateline>BOCA RATON, Fla. 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>In just over two years, W.R. Grace &amp; Co has seen a chief executive depart abruptly, undertaken a major restructuring, and turned down a merger offer under its new chief Albert Costello.</p>
<p>But Costello, who became Grace's chief executive on May 1, 1995, said Friday the company had completed its restructuring to focus on its core packaging, specialty chemical products and construction products businesses. He said Grace intended to remain independent and was set for steady growth, including some acquisitions.  </p>
<p>&quot;Everything we have now is core (business),&quot; Costello told reporters after Grace's annual shareholder meeting, during which he said he expected sales to be up 6 to 7 pct in 1997 and spelled out growth plans for the company's three core businesses by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Costello, said Grace is interested in acquisitions including $20-40 million deals in its construction businesses and some up to $100 - $150 million in its packaging business.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking at some bigger ones, but you never know if you're going to get them,&quot; said Costello, who joined Grace after a long career at the drug firm American Cyanamid.  </p>
<p>Grace packaging, which makes shrink films used for food and non-food products, accounts for about 65 percent of its business. Grace Davison, a supplier of catalysts and silica products, accounts for about about 25 percent and construction comprises about 15 percent, Costello said.</p>
<p>The executive, who is also Grace's chairman and president, did not forecast 1997 profits. He said he expected the company's EBIT (Earnings Before Income Taxes) margin to be at 14 percent for 1997, versus 12 percent in 1996.  </p>
<p>The company had targeted a 13 percent EBIT margin last year, but came in at 12 percent, for reasons including dampening of its packaging sales in Europe as beef sales were slowed by concerns over Mad Cow disease.</p>
<p>This year, Costello said, &quot;We will come in at 14 percent... We've taken out a lot of costs, we have good engineering.&quot;</p>
<p>Costello said he expected some lingering effects of Mad Cow disease as hog and beef herds are replenished. &quot;In Europe we have recovered to within 5 to 10 percent of pre-mad cow,&quot; he said, discussing the company's packaging business.  </p>
<p>He said the unit had a slow start in 1997, but added, &quot;We see it getting up to 6 or 7 percent (sales growth).&quot;</p>
<p>Costello also said Grace has felt the effects of the strong dollar in 1997, saying it had cost 2-1/2 percent of sales and 4- 1/2 percent of profits in the first quarter.</p>
<p>During the annual meeting, Costello said pricing pressure that had dampened a catalyst business were beginning to lessen.  </p>
<p>Costello also said Grace has basically completed a restructuring, except for a few previously announced sales. Through the restructuring, Grace garnered more than $3.5 billion in aftertax proceeds by spinning off businesses.</p>
<p>On April 25, Grace reported first quarter 1997 basic earnings per share of $0.62, up 41 percent from $0.44 from continuing operations a year earlier. Sales for the 1997 quarter were $785 million, up three percent from the year earlier, excluding sales from divested units.</p>
<p>As Grace's chief executive, Costello succeeded J.P. Bolduc who resigned abruptly in March 1995. After Bolduc's departure, reports surfaced that his resignation resulted from a clash with long-time chairman J. Peter Grace over perquisites granted Grace and his son and allegations from the company that Bolduc left following claims of sexual harassment, which Bolduc denied.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOCA RATON, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
