<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572499" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. military reviewing fraternization policy.</title>
<headline>U.S. military reviewing fraternization policy.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Pentagon said on Friday it had begun a review of rules against fraternisation between military officers and enlisted troops at the same time that the Army is investigating a major sexual harassment scandal.</p>
<p>The Defence Department confirmed a report in the Washington Times that the review was &quot;in response to recent concerns over fraternisation policies.&quot;</p>
<p>Those concerns have been sparked in part by charges that some male Army drill instructors and training officers have raped or had consentual sex with young female recruits at several bases.</p>
<p>A senior defence official, who asked not to be identified, said the department was trying to determine whether all of the services should operate under one common and strict fraternisation rule.</p>
<p>The official noted that the Army now allowed dating between officers and enlisted personnel if they were assigned to different units. But the other military services, each under separate rules, prohibit virtually any close relationship between officers and enlisted troops.</p>
<p>The brief Pentagon announcement did not give details, but said the fraternisation review team included representatives from the department and each of the military services. It was formed April 23.</p>
<p>&quot;The team has begun reviewing each service's regulations and instructions on fraternisation,&quot; the announcement said. Once the review was complete, it added, recommendations would be made to Assistant Defence Secretary for Force Management Policy Frederick Pang.</p>
<p>While fraternisation specifically prohibits dating and other close social contact between officers and enlisted personnel, it is generally defined as close contact with anyone of a junior rank.</p>
<p>Conviction on charges of fraternisation under the Uniform Code of Military Justice can bring career-ending punishment or even criminal charges that result in imprisonment.</p>
<p>Friday's announcement came two days after the Army filed charges of adultery and assault against its top enlisted man, Army Sgt. Maj. Gene McKinney. He is accused by four female servicemen of sexual harassment.</p>
<p>The McKinney case was the latest development in an Army harassment scandal that included charges of rape of women recruits by a number of drill sergeants and trainers at several training bases.</p>
<p>Army Staff Sgt. Delmar Simpson, a key figure in one of the worst U.S. military sex scandals, was sentenced on Tuesday to 25 years in prison for raping six women and other sexual offences at Aberdeen Proving Ground in Maryland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
