<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572473" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S., N. Korea hold talks on U.S. MIAs.</title>
<headline>U.S., N. Korea hold talks on U.S. MIAs.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. and North Korean officials tried again on Friday to agree on how to get &quot;the fullest possible accounting&quot; of U.S. servicemen missing in action from the Korean War, a U.S. defence official said.</p>
<p>The talks began on Sunday and have continued almost every day since then with some breaks for the North Korean negotiators to confer with officials in Pyongyang, said Larry Greer, spokesman for the Defence Department's POW/Missing Personnel Office.</p>
<p>The discussions are the fourth round of talks between the Pentagon and North Korea on missing U.S. troops. A statement on the results will be released later on Friday, Greer said. The North Korean representatives will also meet here privately with several American families of missing U.S. servicemen, he added.</p>
<p>U.S. and North Korean officials last met in New York a year ago, reaching an agreement that led to the recovery of the remains of a U.S. Army corporal north of Pyongyang.</p>
<p>But a second excavation scheduled for the fall of 1996 fell through after a North Korean submarine loaded with commandos ran aground last September off South Korea.</p>
<p>There are still some 8,100 U.S. troops missing from the Korean War. The Pentagon has said it has no evidence that any are being held captive in North Korea.</p>
<p>The current U.S.-North Korean talks have had three purposes, Greer said. First, the United States wants to learn more about live sightings of alleged Americans still living in North Korea. Second, the United States wants access to North Korean military archives. Third, the United States wants to establish a schedule for continued joint excavations to recover the remains of Americans buried in North Korea.</p>
<p>Washington has chosen 10 sites it considers the most fruitful, Greer said. These were either the sites of U.S. plane crashes or known burial locations of Americans who died in battle or in North Korean prison camps.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a certainty&quot; that there are mass graves in North Korea containing the remains of U.S. servicemen, Greer said.</p>
<p>&quot;We know precisely where many of them are located because of all of our thousands of interviews with returned (prisoners of war). In many cases, there are many, many Americans buried in one spot.&quot;</p>
<p>The reports from returned American POWs told of men who died from battle wounds and in prison camps and men who were on forced death marches and executed, said Greer.</p>
<p>Greer said despite dozens of reports coming out of North Korea over the last several years referring to Caucasians living in North Korea, the United States has not been able to corroborate those sightings as being Americans who were held against their will.</p>
<p>The United States does know of four Americans still alive in North Korea who are deserters from the U.S. Army, Greer said.</p>
<p>Greer said the United States has asked the North Koreans to grant it access to these men &quot;in order to learn what we could about the other sightings ... We know that some of the sightings are associated with these deserters,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Washington wants access to North Korea's military archives to learn more about Americans who died in North Korean prisoner of war camps, Greer said.</p>
<p>Greer said that although the United States covers the costs associated with excavations, recoveries have to be done jointly to aid identification of the remains.</p>
<p>&quot;When the North Koreans unilaterally turned over some remains in 1991, we had a very, very poor rate of identification,&quot; said Greer. &quot;There was no forensic chain of custody which could help lead us to identification ... so we asked (North Korea) to stop unilateral excavations.&quot;</p>
<p>While the United States and North Korea are also involved in talks on other issues, the identification of missing Americans is being addressed in separate talks, Greer said.</p>
<p>Talks in New York between the United States and South Korea to urge Pyongyang to begin four-way peace talks with China to negotiate a formal end to the 1950-53 Korean War broke off in April.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
