<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572553" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS - Rain rescues French grain crop outlook.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Rain rescues French grain crop outlook.</headline>
<byline>Paule Bonjean</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>France is resurrecting forecasts of a good grain crop this year, perhaps approaching the 1996 record, after rain this week dampened fears of drought, government sources said on Friday.</p>
<p>But even as grain crops started to look fresher, new water restrictions emerged in parts of France and strawberry growers complained the rainfall was doing them little good.</p>
<p>&quot;If it keeps raining we should have a grain crop that doesn't reach last year's yield record, but which should be close to last year's volume since the area is up three percent,&quot; an agricultural aide to Prime Minister Alain Juppe said.</p>
<p>He did not give a precise forecast but said those who had built &quot;catastrophe scenarios&quot; on nearly four months of drought between January and late April would now have to think again.</p>
<p>Last year's French grain harvest was a record 62.46 million tonnes, including 34.69 million tonnes of wheat, a major export.</p>
<p>&quot;Except for durum wheat in the south, we are still looking at a good cereals harvest,&quot; the aide said.</p>
<p>Grain prices, fired up by drought warnings in April, dropped this week after heavy rain broke up the soil and revived crops.</p>
<p>State weather service Meteo France said an average of 60 mm of rain had descended on France since the last week of April.</p>
<p>That is about an entire month's average rainfall for May.</p>
<p>Weather experts even hinted on Friday at the risk of local flooding, but stressed it was too early to be certain.</p>
<p>The medieval fortress town of Besancon in eastern France, surrounded by a river, has had a record downpour this month.</p>
<p>Water shortages persist, however, and the environment ministry on Friday reported irrigation restrictions in seven new French provinces, bringing the total to 25 out of around 100.</p>
<p>Farm groups say that even though rain is helping crops to develop, a chronic lack of water in underground reservoirs means the weather will keep farmers on edge until at least mid-summer.</p>
<p>Maize growers said this week that water rationing would do most damage the nearer any new restrictions came to August, when irrigation peaks. About 45 percent of the maize grown for commercial use in France depends on artificial water sprays.</p>
<p>Juppe's office has set up day-to-day monitoring of the weather's effect on crops and until this week had been watching out for the risk of forest fires, government officials said.</p>
<p>Farmers, who have a crucial vote in parliamentary elections later this month, had previously been lobbying for cash payments to compensate them for drought.</p>
<p>Most farm groups say it is still too early to say how well arable crops, some of which are still being planted, will cope with the rapid swings in the weather.</p>
<p>But government crop forecasters noted that a similar turn in the weather had washed away a similar drought in early 1996.</p>
<p>Even so, fruit lobby Interfel complained that rain and low temperatures had hit strawberry consumption while supplies of the fruit had soared due to competition from Spain and Italy.</p>
<p>Strawberry growers demonstrated against cheap prices on Thursday by selling fruit at $2 a tray beneath the Eiffel Tower. On Friday, they took their campaign to Bordeaux, where Juppe is mayor, dumping 10 tonnes of strawberries on the town hall steps.</p>
<p>The farmers, who enter the peak of their annual growing season next week, say they are being driven out of business by imports and cheap prices forced on them by supermarkets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
