<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572577" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Brussels bourse seen dancing to NY tune next week.</title>
<headline>Brussels bourse seen dancing to NY tune next week.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian shares are seen taking their cue from Wall Street next week, in the absence of domestic news to drive prices.</p>
<p>The Brussels bourse ended lower on Friday, but the index more than recovered from coupon-clipping of several blue-chip shares. The Bel-20 index  .BFX ended down 8.77 points or 0.39 percent at 2225.98. Mathematically, the index should have lost 13.54 points as shares of BBL, CBR, CMB, Cobepa, Cofinnimmo, Generale Bank and Gevaert went ex-dividend.</p>
<p>Volume was a strong 2.5 billion francs despite fact that banks were absent from market due to a holiday today.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as Wall Street holds up, Brussels will,&quot; one dealer said. But he and many others said they were increasingly worried about the divergence between the price of stocks and bonds in the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;A crash scenario is in the making,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Oil group Petrofina was the main riser, up 1.6 percent at 12,775. Traders think the share is being supported ahead of the expiry of a warrant on its shares.</p>
<p>Between May 20 and June 3, the warrants can be exercised at a ratio of one share for one warrant at a price of 12,500 francs.</p>
<p>Brokerage Cels Guigon Securities said in a recent study that the exercise of the 1.3 million warrants could raise 16.36 billion francs of new capital for the group, allowing it to finance the full takeover of its American unit Fina and reduce its debt.</p>
<p>Shares in steel group Arbed rose 5.7 percent in a late rally which took them to 3,730 francs, following cautiously optimistic comments about the second half earlier this week.</p>
<p>-- Geert De Clercq, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6813, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
