<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572682" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka plantations to see another boom year.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka plantations to see another boom year.</headline>
<byline>Prithi Kodagoda</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lanka's tea plantations are seen experiencing a second successive boom year, led by demand for tea from the Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS) and the Middle East, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Growth will continue to be primarily driven by the strong CIS and Middle Eastern liking for Sri Lanka's unique 'orthodox' tea, which other suppliers are unable to duplicate,&quot; said Anil Cooke, a director of commodity brokers Forbes &amp; Walker.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka saw a boom year in 1996, with production reaching an all time high of 258.4 million kg, of which 244.1 kg were exported.</p>
<p>&quot;If the weather holds, we should see production of around 262 million kilos in 1997,&quot; Cooke said.</p>
<p>The Middle East, which has long been a market for Sri Lankan tea, was overtaken by the CIS after the collapse of the former Soviet Union. The two regions now account for 65 percent to 70 percent of Sri Lanka's tea exports.</p>
<p>The Central Bank said Sri Lanka earned 34 billion rupees (US$573 million) from tea exports in 1996, up from 24.6 billion in 1995.  </p>
<p>&quot;Earnings should rise in 1997 because we expect not only production, but also the national sales average to rise to about 108 rupees a kilo from 103.88 rupees in 1996,&quot; Cooke said.</p>
<p>Stock market analysts said plantation sector shares listed on the Colombo Stock Exchange would also rise in line with good growth expectations.</p>
<p>The plantation sector comprises six firms, which were privatised in 1995. They are Agalawatte Plantations, Kelani Valley Plantations, Horana Plantations, Bogawantalawa Plantations, Kotagala Plantations and Kegalle Plantations.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the sector to see EPS (earnings per share) growth of 20 to 30 percent in 1997,&quot; said Channa Kurukulasooriya, head of research at brokerage Lanka Securities.</p>
<p>The sector has already gained 43 percent in the recent rally, second only to the food, beverage and tobacco sector, which has gained 47 percent, he added.  </p>
<p>Colombo stocks, which closed at 733.11 on Thursday, have climbed 127.11 points or 21 percent this year. The rise has been due to good growth expectations, low interest rates and the government and opposition agreeing to work together to end the ethnic conflict, in which Tamil rebels are fighting for a separate state in the north and east.</p>
<p>Analysts say the six listed firms, which are now trading at an average price of 36.50 rupees a 10-rupee share, should at worst maintain current price levels.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no way they can fall below the current average, because earnings forecasts for 1997 are good,&quot; said Suresh Nadarajah, plantation sector analyst at brokerage John Keells.</p>
<p>The government plans to privatise the remaining 17 estate firms by June, which analysts say will further boost investor interest in the sector.</p>
<p>The government began by privatising management of 23 debt-ridden regional plantation firms, which own some 600,000 hectares of tea, rubber and coconut, in 1992.</p>
<p>Privatisation spread to ownership in 1995 with the sale of 51 percent to a strategic investor, 20 percent to the public and 10 percent gifted to employees. (US$1 = 59.3 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
