<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572638" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian budget clears hurdle in parliament.</title>
<headline>Indian budget clears hurdle in parliament.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's lower house of parliament on Friday approved the 1997/98 (April-March) Finance Bill, the cornerstone of the centre-left government's landmark budget proposal that would slash taxes and tariffs.</p>
<p>The lower house, the Lok Sabha, approved the bill by voice vote after three days of debate. The upper house, the Rajya Sabha, was expected to adopt the bill next week and send it to President Shankar Dayal Sharma for his signature.</p>
<p>Finance Minister P. Chidambaram presented the Finance Bill as part of a broader budget package on February 28. The bill, which would cut personal and corporate income tax rates as well as many import duties, triggered a rally in share prices.</p>
<p>Chidambaram fended off demands by left-wing allies in Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral's coalition and the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) to make radical changes in the Finance Bill.</p>
<p>However, on Wednesday he announced he had agreed to accept minor changes which would cost the exchequer 1.1 billion rupees ($30.7 million) in the current fiscal year.</p>
<p>&quot;The bill as amended is passed,&quot; Lok Sabha speaker P.A. Sangma said after the voice vote.</p>
<p>The Lok Sabha approved the government's spending proposals for 1997/98, outside the scope of the Finance Bill, on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Gujral's United Front coalition has said the budget package will carry forward economic reforms which were launched in 1991 and have gradually opened up India to foreign investment and trade, and cut red tape.</p>
<p>The budget was warmly welcomed in investment circles but criticised by the BJP and left-wing parties for exposing some sectors to greater competition. ($1 = 35.8 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
