<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572765" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Echostar says files against News Corp.</title>
<headline>Echostar says files against News Corp.</headline>
<dateline>ENGLEWOOD, Colo. 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>EchoStar Communications Corp said Friday it has filed for a declaratory judgment in the United States District Court for the District of Colorado.</p>
<p>Echostar said in a statement the action seeks a judgment confirming the obligation of News Corp to loan EchoStar $200 million.</p>
<p>EchoStar said it is confident that the court will confirm its position.  </p>
<p>News Corp officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>In February, EchoStar and News Corp announced a direct-TV satellite deal intended to offer as many as 500 channels of digital television, Internet services and local-broadcast TV signals to markets nationwide.</p>
<p>But last week the deal between the two companies seemed to have snagged on a dispute over which conditional-access system would be used. That is the system that allows subscribers to view only those channels they have paid to watch.</p>
<p>EchoStar delayed regulatory filings in regard to the deal, saying News Corp wanted it to abandon its current system in favor of one owned by News Corp.</p>
<p>Then on May 2 came the resignation of Preston Padden, head of News Corp's ASkyB satellite TV service, which created more doubt about the venture among industry analysts.</p>
<p>At the time, News Corp Chairman Rupert Murdoch was quoted in the Wall Street Journal as saying he would go ahead with launching a satellite TV service, with or without EchoStar.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ENGLEWOOD, Colo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
