<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572781" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. debt futures higher on Greenspan's comments.</title>
<headline>U.S. debt futures higher on Greenspan's comments.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. debt futures were higher as retail and funds continued their buying spree from Thursday due to Federal Reserve chairman Alan Greenspan's comments, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Greenspan's comments have been interpreted in fashion not in line with the highest probability of a Fed tightening,&quot; Rick Santelli, vice president of futures trading at Rand Financial Services, said.</p>
<p>June T-bonds rallied to 110-09/32, near the overnight high and last Friday's pit high of 110-10/32, on active buying from retail firms as well as hedge funds, they said.  </p>
<p>Selling by one Swiss bank at the opening vanished on the positive interpretation of Greenspan's string of comments in a speech to the New York University's Stern School of Business.</p>
<p>While Greenspan said the Federal Reserve would need to act if growth fails to slow as expected, he also said he saw scant signs now of an imminent resurgence of inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;The perception is that a rate hike is still a possibility, but if it happens it will be the last one,&quot; one Eurodollar futures trader said.</p>
<p>He said December Eurodollars were still pricing in one more tightening.  </p>
<p>The contract will price out another rate hike if it climbs through the 94.00 level. Medium-term resistance is at the two-month high of 93.84.</p>
<p>Several traders noted that Greenspan also sounded defensive during his speech in which he discussed the March 25 rate hike.</p>
<p>&quot;Greenspan sounded almost apologetic for raising rates,&quot; one Eurodollar futures floor source said.</p>
<p>Greenspan defended the March 25 rate hike against what he called &quot;more than the usual share of...criticism,&quot; and said the Fed raised rates as &quot;a form of insurance.&quot;  </p>
<p>Traders said a new wave of buying would develop in T-bonds once June cracked the 110-10/32 level.</p>
<p>Most noted the bullish implications of the surge in open interest for bond futures during Thursday's slow grind higher.</p>
<p>According to preliminary estimates, total open interest rose more than 26,000 to 590,306. If preliminary estimates are correct, Thursday's open interest will be at a record high.</p>
<p>&quot;Open interest alone is telling you that this market will go higher,&quot; one bond futures trader said.</p>
<p>He is looking for June to rise to 111-00 to 111-16/32 in the intermediate term.  </p>
<p>As long as June bonds close above 109-24/32 on Friday, the June T-bonds will continue to rise, Santelli said. He pegged long-term resistance at 112-06/32, which is currently equivalent to a long bond yield of 6.75 percent.</p>
<p>At 0851 CDT/1351 GMT, June T-bonds were up 13/32 at 110-07/32, 10-year notes were 13/32 higher at 107-15/32, September T-bills were up 0.075 at 94.51, September Eurodollars were 0.08 higher at 93.925 and December Eurodollars were up 0.1 at 93.725. ((DerivativesDesk(312)408-8750)) E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
