<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572994" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Eurobonds see British TV firm reach wider audience.</title>
<headline>Eurobonds see British TV firm reach wider audience.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The primary market remained subdued on Friday morning with many European players still absent from their desks after yesterday's holiday.</p>
<p>The main exception was a 200 million stg 10-year deal from British television company Carlton Communications, its debut in the Euromarket.</p>
<p>Final pricing was due later at a spread of 65 basis points over the key 2006 gilt via lead manager BZW.</p>
<p>Sources close to the issue said while it was an opportunistic financing it was, nevertheless, &quot;a boringly routine transaction&quot;.  </p>
<p>The Carlton deal was a bit slow, a new issues trader at one of the five co-lead managers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's definitely not a blow-out deal. The high market means it's not the best moment to launch a sterling deal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>British government bonds have surged this week in the wake of the elction and after major reforms at the Bank of England.</p>
<p>The yield spread between 10-year gilts and German Bunds has narrowed to just over 130 b.p. from around 175 b.p. at the start of the week.  </p>
<p>Carlton, which bought the film distribution subsidiary of Rank Group for 65 million stg in early April, is involved with BSkyB and Granada Group in a joint venture called British Digital Broadcasting, which is seeking to win Britain's first licences for digital terrestrial television.</p>
<p>The consortium has pledged to put up to 300 million stg into the venture.</p>
<p>Carlton last December reported pre-tax profits of just under 300 million stg for its financial year ending the previous September.  </p>
<p>Also in sterling, Denmark set a 100 million stg three-year deal via Nomura International, which, with its 6.25 percent semi-annual coupon, will be aimed at Japanese investors.</p>
<p>Three-year gilts were yielding around 6.8 percent.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Deutsche Hypo Hannover raised a 1.0 billion mark Pfandbrief issue due November 2000 via five joint lead managers at a seven basis points spread over German government bonds.</p>
<p>Turkey's long-awaited Eurobond -- a $250 million five-year -- will be launched on Monday, bankers close to the deal said.</p>
<p>Spread talk was 340-350 b.p. over U.S. Treasuries.</p>
<p>Turkey held roadshows in key financial centres in Europe, Asia and the U.S. in April.</p>
<p>International credit rating agencies recently cut Turkey's debt rating. It is rated B by Standard and Poor's and B1 by Moody's.</p>
<p>-- Dan Lalor, London newsroom +44 171 542 8863</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
