<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572902" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FORECAST - Safeway sales eyed for reassurance.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Safeway sales eyed for reassurance.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>British supermarket group Safeway Plc is expected report slightly higher annual profits on May 14 but the figures which will catch market attention will be sales, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The biggest issue is what is happening to current trading and sales performance,&quot; said one analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Safeway is forecast to turn in pre-tax profits of 425-435 million stg, up from 401 million stg a year ago and pay out a dividend of 14.0-14.45 pence per share, compared with 12.75 pence previously.</p>
<p>But there are concerns that the group, seen as the most technologically innovative of the leading supermarkets, could be losing out to its major rivals -- market leader Tesco, J. Sainsbury and ASDA.</p>
<p>Safeway said in February that sales growth had slipped back to 4.5 percent in the first 16 weeks of the second half after hitting 5.2 percent over the Christmas period.</p>
<p>It said then that if the slowdown continued, profits for the rest of the second half could be hit.</p>
<p>As a result, analysts made downgrades to forecasts of around 10-15 million stg to current levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The presumption is that Safeway may not be doing so well simply because the others are,&quot; said another analyst who requested anonymity.</p>
<p>Sainsbury said earlier this week that sales from existing stores in the first seven weeks of the current year were up 4.2 percent, better than the four percent gain seen in the 16 weeks to January 11.</p>
<p>Tesco reported a strong six percent rise in current sales a month ago, although that was down from 8.1 percent in the 21 weeks to January 5, while ASDA is thought to be sustaining around 6-7 percent growth.</p>
<p>&quot;People are thinking that Safeway must be deteriorating. We will be looking for a rise of better than 3.6 percent in the second half, otherwise the impact on the share price could be quite dramatic,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>He added that current sales growth could be as low as two percent for the group.</p>
<p>Discounter Kwik Save, among the second tier of supermarkets, saw its shares tumble on Thursday after it said current sales were down six percent.</p>
<p>Safeway has tried to differentiate itself in the highly-competitive food retail sector by targeting family shoppers and stressing technology to ease the load for consumers with initiatives such as self-scanning and automated checkouts.</p>
<p>Its trademark advertising campaign featuring two children, Harry and Molly, who are wise beyond their years, has won awards and is one of the best known among consumers.</p>
<p>But analysts remain concerned that Safeway's appeal is not broad enough and that it may be failing to convert consumers who drop in for top-up shops to visit stores regularly.</p>
<p>Safeway may also give an update on the success of its ABC loyalty card and its foray into financial services in conjunction with Abbey National, analysts said.</p>
<p>-- Jo Winterbottom, London Newsroom +44171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
