<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573190" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - May 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - May 9.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following stories were reported in Friday's electronic version of The Wall Street Journal:</p>
<p>* Bre-X Minerals Ltd has filed for bankruptcy-court protection from creditors and its top geologist and vice chairman, John Felderhof, has resigned.</p>
<p>* Pentagon officials may seek changes in Raytheon Co's planned acquisition of Hughes Electronics Corp's defense segments.</p>
<p>* Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan indicated the central bank is ready to act and to raise interest rates to keep inflation in check.</p>
<p>* A Food and Drug Administration panel voted to recommend rejection of a new injection treatment for Lou Gehrig's disease that was developed by Chiron Corp and Cephalon Inc .</p>
<p>* US Airways Group Inc said it plans to drop unprofitable routes, ground 22 aircraft and close some facilities.</p>
<p>* Many large U.S. retailers showed anemic sales gains in April.</p>
<p>* U.S. accounting rule makers said that new rules for derivatives accounting will not be ready until at least October, instead of June 30.</p>
<p>* The Dow Jones Industrials rose 50.97 points to 7136.62, finishing nearly 75 points off the day's high, while bond prices rose and the dollar fell.</p>
<p>* Restaurant sales at McDonald's Corp have been down by as much as six percent since it began selling Big Mac sandwiches at 55 cents, a company survey shows.</p>
<p>* The board of directors at Giddings &amp; Lewis Inc rejected a $631 million hostile bid from Harnischfeger Industries Inc.</p>
<p>* Seagram Co Ltd Universal Studios is prepared to buy Viacom Inc's half of USA Networks, according to people familiar with the deal.</p>
<p>* AT&amp;T Corp named Daniel Hesse president of AT&amp;T Wireless, succeeding Steven Hooper who, along with two other executives, have left the unit to form a local-phone services firm.</p>
<p>* Living Centers of America Inc said it will be recapitalized by Apollo Management LP, an investment firm controlled by investor Leon Black, creating a new firm and then buying nursing home operator GranCare Inc.</p>
<p>* Texas Instruments Inc is pulling out of two semiconductor ventures in Thailand, saying its local partner was unable to obtain financing.</p>
<p>* Heard on the Street: With real estate investment trusts now attracting a broader group of investors than in the past, is it possible to take such a company public in the face of harsh criticism from veteran investors and analysts? Australian mall maven Frank Lowy is about to find out.</p>
<p>* Credit markets: Clearly stung by widespread criticism that the Federal Reserve had been too quick to raise interest rates six weeks ago, Chairman Alan Greenspan aggressively defended the action Thursday night, saying that failure to act would have constituted &quot;a threat to the job security and standards of living of too many Americans.&quot;</p>
<p>((New York newsdesk, 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
