<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573298" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Telefonica Q1 profit seen as brisk as 1996.</title>
<headline>Telefonica Q1 profit seen as brisk as 1996.</headline>
<byline>Robert Hetz</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spanish telecommunications giant Telefonica should be able to maintain a brisk 20 percent growth rate in both first quarter and 1997 full-year earnings, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>Profit for the January to March period is expected to come in at around 28.9 billion pesetas versus 24.08 billion in the first quarter last year.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect net profit to be boosted by around 20 percent, after showing the same rate one year earlier,&quot; an Madrid based analysts said.</p>
<p>But analysts warned that Telefonica's depreciation and provisions policy will make a difference, and may be more cautious than usual.</p>
<p>Analysts said new Spanish rules allowing companies to update the value of their fixed assets, effective since the end of 1996, gives companies huge scope to lift depreciation levels.</p>
<p>Telefonica may also decide to bolster provisions aiming to provide incentives for early retirements.</p>
<p>At the end of April Telefonica said it had offered a new package for early retirement, reducing the minimum age to 55 years from 57.</p>
<p>The firm, one of Spain's biggest employers, has around 70,000 staff and expects to cut that level by 11,000 by 2001.</p>
<p>But analysts were confident about its ability to produce earnings, and even a lower rate of growth in the first quarter would not change their expectations of 20 percent growth for the whole year.</p>
<p>&quot;Telefonica is a money machine. (Chairman) Juan Villalonga said clearly the firm's main target is to produce profits and to increase value for shareholders,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>During the first four months of this year alone Telefonica shares have gained 30 percent to a new all-time high on Friday of 3,940 pesetas.</p>
<p>Recently Villalonga told a group of investors he expects group profit to rise 60 percent in the next three years.</p>
<p>Analysts are expecting revenues in the first quarter of 1997 to swell 15.5 percent to 515.4 billion pesetas, while ordinary margin is seen climbing 14.8 percent to 133.4 billion pesetas.</p>
<p>More business in both basic and mobile phone services was seen compensating for cuts in international tariffs since the end of 1996, experts said.</p>
<p>But the downtrend in rates for international and domestic phone calls is one of the few question marks hanging over the Telefonica's future.</p>
<p>&quot;The first quarter this year is going to be the best in terms of operating results. Later in the year further tariff cuts will have more obvious weight,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>In mid-March Telefonica cut international tariffs by 8.8 percent. Domestic long distance phone calls fell five percent in April, and are expected to be fall another five percent in July.</p>
<p>The other uncertainty is how the market will evaluate the recently-announced deal with British Telecom and MCI Corp, and analysts believe it is still too early to say.</p>
<p>-- Madrid Newsroom, + 341 585 8340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
