<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573389" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Carriers still struggling with Valujet crash.</title>
<headline>Carriers still struggling with Valujet crash.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Zengerle</byline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's been a year since a ValuJet jetliner crashed in the Florida Everglades, but the low-cost airline industry is just beginning to overcome safety concerns from the tragedy that killed 110 people.</p>
<p>&quot;Frontier (Airlines) was the only low-cost airline that wasn't hit dramatically by the ValuJet fallout and this was because the public thought, incorrectly, that they had been around for years,&quot; said Russell Winter, an industry analyst at Hambrecht &amp; Quist, referring to the Denver-based carrier.</p>
<p>Known for rapid growth, older aircraft and a string of incidents including a hard landing in Nashville and overrunning a Washington runway early last year, Atlanta-based ValuJet flew into a nightmare on a sunny Saturday afternoon on May 11, 1996.</p>
<p>That day, a fire erupted on Atlanta-bound Flight 592 shortly after takeoff from Miami International Airport, a disaster linked to old oxygen canisters that had been incorrectly loaded into the jet's cargo hold.</p>
<p>The pilot radioed for help and tried to turn back, but the plane plunged into the Everglades, killing everyone aboard.</p>
<p>Afterward, reports of the devastation at the crash site, plus investigator's questions about ValuJet's safety procedures -- regulators grounded the airline for three months until late September -- cast a pall on discount airlines.</p>
<p>Potential customers feared that newer, lesser-known carriers were cutting costs by scrimping on safety.</p>
<p>For example, AirTran Airways, which has about 4 percent of the important Orlando, Fla., market and serves 21 cities with 10 Boeing 737s, said reservations dropped 23 percent the week following the ValuJet crash.</p>
<p>ValuJet lost $41.5 million in 1996, including a $68 million charge related to its grounding. Closely held Kiwi International Air Lines Inc. filed for bankruptcy protection from creditors last fall.</p>
<p>Another privately owned carrier, Carnival Air Lines, which agreed to be acquired by smaller rival Pan American World Airways in March, said it had been consistently profitable until the ValuJet crash, but had been in the red ever since.</p>
<p>Analysts said the deal gave Carnival the chance to link itself to a well-known airline brand name.</p>
<p>&quot;The no frills airlines face a real issue which is that they can't be seen as no frills in terms of safety. If you're new, the public seems to be very wary about the few dollars you are saving,&quot; said Peter Harleman, a managing director at Landor Associates, a brand-name consultant.</p>
<p>But analysts said the stronger startup carriers would survive if their finances were sound and they found niche markets where they were not overly vulnerable to big price cuts by more established carriers.</p>
<p>&quot;Just as the majors recovered impressively from safety fears due to terrorism in 1991, the startups, as they are still described, are now similarly recovering from safety fears due to ValuJet in 1996,&quot; Winter said.</p>
<p>Michael Boyd, president of Aviation Systems Research in Golden, Colo., a consulting firm, said many of the small carriers that have had financial problems since the ValuJet crash had problems long before May 11, 1996, mainly from failing to attract a large core of customers.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of them didn't start with a huge customer base to begin with. It (ValuJet) may have enhanced a situation that was already in place,&quot; Boyd said.</p>
<p>But those with solid strategies would survive for the long term, with ValuJet-linked problems only a blip, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now, there are only two or three that are really out of the woods and are really strong -- AirTran in Orlando and Frontier in Denver,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The thing to watch out for is airlines that have hallucinations of grandeur. A startup who comes along and says 'We are going to be a substantial player in this city or that city,' -- the chances of that happening are nil.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
