<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573302" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Sarajevo orphan odyssey shown at Cannes festival.</title>
<headline>Sarajevo orphan odyssey shown at Cannes festival.</headline>
<byline>John Follain</byline>
<dateline>CANNES, France 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>British director Michael Winterbottom paints a harrowing picture of Sarajevo under siege in a story of a frustrated television reporter shown in competition at the Cannes film festival on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Welcome to Sarajevo&quot; is based on the clandestine adoption of a local girl by ITN correspondent Michael Nicholson, as told in his book &quot;Natasha's Story&quot;.</p>
<p>The film draws on painful video footage of massacres of the time and detail the journalist's (Stephen Dillane) crusade against the background of the siege of the Bosnian capital and the local residents' determination to keep up their social routines despite the inhumanity around them.</p>
<p>&quot;I used shots which we all saw on television at the time. I wanted pictures which people would recognise, I wanted to insist on the fact that we had seen this war on television, often zapping from one channel to another,&quot; Winterbottom said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of these pictures are horrible, but when we saw them on the news, we didn't react. I think we're so used to news that no picture can have much impact any more,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The film, which also stars Woody Harrelson as a guarrulous American hack, recreates the eerie atmosphere of the Holiday Inn hotel in the Bosnian capital, with journalists crouching in the battered corridors to find a light bulb by which to file a story.</p>
<p>After covering a massacre of people queuing outside a baker's shop, the journalist played by Dillane returns to the hotel only to be told he has failed to make the lead in the news broadcast at home. &quot;The lead is the divorce of the Duke and Duchess of York,&quot; his producer tells him.</p>
<p>Later, a series of reports on a frontline orphanage fails to move the international community. Video footage ridicules the platitudes mouthed by visitings heads of state, peace emissaries and United Nations envoys.</p>
<p>Frustrated by his failure, the journalist throws objectivity to the winds and clandestinely takes a child to England, where he eventually adopts her.</p>
<p>&quot;Press reporters played a special role in this conflict. More than witnesses of brutality and barbarity, they became militants to make politicians react,&quot; Winterbottom said.</p>
<p>&quot;After the mortar attacks, it wasn't rare for press vehicles to transform themselves into ambulances,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Winterbottom's crew won permission to film in Sarajevo last year. They had to recruit a mines expert to clear locations and fit their schedules around curfew restrictions.</p>
<p>The team had originally planned not to film the most violent scenes on location out of respect for locals. But residents and local authorities insisted the events be recreated on site, as faithfully as possible.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope the audience will feel the same thing that I felt when I read the script,&quot; Winterbottom explained.</p>
<p>&quot;How is it possible that we sat there during this war, calmly watching it on television in our sitting-rooms, without ever doing anything? How is that possible today in Europe when everybody knew what was happening?&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANNES, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
