<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573373" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French shares turn higher in quiet market.</title>
<headline>French shares turn higher in quiet market.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>French shares turned higher in a quiet market on Friday after a lower opening on the back of an easier dollar and an opinion poll giving the centre-right just a thin majority ahead of the May 25/June 1 election.</p>
<p>&quot;It's starting to hot up. At the start everybody thought that the right would win, now there are some doubts,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>Wall Street closed higher on Thursday but below its highs.</p>
<p>The CAC-40 was up 0.17 percent at 2647.80 at 0840 GMT with the Masy future up five points at 2.635.  </p>
<p>While Wall Street posted a gain on Thursday the rise did not compensate the Wednesday fall made after the Paris Bourse closed on the even of an Ascension day holiday on Thursday.</p>
<p>Lagardere, up 2.73 percent at 180.80, rises after it made a bid for the state's 58-percent stake in Thomson-CSF with British Aerospapce Plc and Germany's DASA.</p>
<p>Rival bidder Alcatel-Alsthom was down 0.77 percent at 642 francs.  </p>
<p>* AGF, down 1.21 percent at 187.7 francs, suffers from its announcement it was interested in acquiring GAN's insurance activities.</p>
<p>* Renault, up 0.36 percent at 139.2, in rebound after Wednesday slide on the back of Appeal Court ruling it has to call special meeting before proceeding with Vilvoorde closure.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
