<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573477" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: New Zealand long bonds close strongly.</title>
<headline>New Zealand long bonds close strongly.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>---------------(Snapshot at close)-----------------</p>
<p>Figures in brackets compare against previous day's close</p>
<p>FUTURES					  PHYSICAL YIELD (PCT)</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS (JUN) 92.88 (PREV 92.87)  90-DAYS  6.84 (PREV 6.85) 3-YR BONDS   (JUN) 92.39 (PREV 92.45)  02/00    7.35 (PREV 7.43)</p>
<p>10-YR BONDS  (JUN) 92.25 (PREV 92.28)  11/06    7.58 (PREV 7.71)</p>
<p>OVERNIGHT CASH 6.00 PCT   (PREV 6.05)  US 5-YR  6.60 (PREV 6.64)</p>
<p>NZD/USD    0.6872/79 (PREV 0.6845/55)  US 10-YR 6.74 (PREV 6.76)</p>
<p>TWI		    67.83 (PREV 67.87)  US 30-YR 6.94 (PREV 6.96)</p>
<p>----------------------------(May 9)-----------------------------</p>
<p>* NZ long bonds rally hard into close  </p>
<p>* Short end, static with currency concerns</p>
<p>* Slew of data next week picked to confirm economic weakness</p>
<p>New Zealand long bonds rallied hard into Friday's close, taking heart from global trends which firmed on comments by Fed Chairman Alan Greenspan.</p>
<p>&quot;Greenspan's comments have helped and we've seen the U.S. market jump and Aussie is performing pretty well as well,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Greenspan indicated in a speech he was not alarmed about current economic fundamentals.  </p>
<p>&quot;It feels like there are a few shorts out there and the domestic market generally is little underinvested,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>The long bond ended at 7.58 percent, nearly 10 basis points lower from its morning level.</p>
<p>A slew of data next week, including retail sales, the food price index, building consents and registered unemployed is expected to confirm a weak economy and give bond yields another nudge down.  </p>
<p>&quot;You'd have to expect that all those indicators will continue to suggest that the economy is relatively weak and that can only help the bond market so the trend continues and yields will grind lower,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Bill dealers said the tone of the market was a little negative with concerns about the Trade-Weighted Index especially given dollar weakness.</p>
<p>&quot;Do we see the kiwi appreciate to offset dollar weakness or do we see an appreciation of kiwi appreciation and higher short-term interert rates,&quot; said one.  </p>
<p>&quot;I belive the market is long physical bills, and we haven't seen a retracement for two to three weeks now. I'm looking for the market to retrace.</p>
<p>&quot;The one thing that may help to hold the market in is the steepness of the curve at the moment, the cash and carry is quite a attractive.&quot;</p>
<p>The market needed new buyers. Traders had done their buying and were sitting waiting for the market to keep rallying, he added.</p>
<p>Weakness could come through in the future and the FRAs.</p>
<p>-- Simon Louisson, Wellington newsroom, 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
