<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573567" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Rate rise concerns seen pushing JGB yields higher.</title>
<headline>Rate rise concerns seen pushing JGB yields higher.</headline>
<byline>Masayuki Kitano</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The yield of the benchmark 182nd Japanese government bond (JGB), which only a month ago had fallen to below 2.1 percent, may rise to nearly three percent in the next few months due to mounting fears of higher interest rates, bond market sources said on Friday.</p>
<p>The key 182nd JGB yield will likely rise to nearly 2.75 percent in the near term and may rise as high as 3.3 percent in the next few months, said Masuhisa Kobayashi, a fixed income analyst for Merrill Lynch Japan Inc's research department.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors have been spooked by speculation about a possible credit-tightening (by the BOJ). They had not seriously contemplated such a possibility before, and are now caught in a panic and are selling,&quot; Kobayashi said.</p>
<p>Recent rises in Tokyo share prices have triggered renewed fears of a rise in short-term interest rates, and further rises in JGB yields are likely as expected price rises in the coming months fuel that anxiety, said Tetsufumi Yamakawa, director of Japan economic research at Goldman Sachs in Tokyo.</p>
<p>&quot;Firms in the basic material industry are said to be considering raising prices, so the domestic WPI could show a year-on-year rise of over two percent from May,&quot; Yamakawa said.</p>
<p>&quot;In that case, expectations of a credit-tightening are likely to become more realistic,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Japan's domestic WPI rose 1.9 percent year-on-year in April, the Bank of Japan said on Friday.</p>
<p>The sudden rise in the key JGB yield is reminiscent of the 1987 market, when the benchmark JGB yield rebounded sharply after dropping to within 0.050 percentage point of the official discount rate, which stood at 2.5 percent at that time, said Soichi Okuda, senior economist at Nippon Credit Bank Ltd.</p>
<p>In 1987, as is the case now, a tight supply/demand balance was considered the trigger for the fall in JGB yields, which took place just before they began rising sharply, Okuda said.</p>
<p>Barely a month ago, on April 8, the benchmark 182nd JGB yield fell to a record low for any benchmark cash JGB, of 2.075 percent.</p>
<p>Bond traders said factors such as a large-scale redemption of about six trillion yen worth of JGBs in June, expectations of renewed investor buying at the start of a new business year, as well as a widespread view that the Bank of Japan would not be able to raise interest rates at least until around September, had been behind the recent surge in JGBs.</p>
<p>The key 182nd JGB yield rose as high as 2.680 percent in Friday trade as mounting fears of higher interest rates led to long liquidation by investors.</p>
<p>A fluctuation of 0.605 percentage point in one month is extraordinarily high in proportion to current JGB yields, said Akio Kimura, a director at Japan Bond Trading Co Ltd, the largest inter-dealer broker in Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been moves of 0.6 percentage point before, for example when the key JGB yield stood at eight percent. But the fluctuation is definitely a large one in proportion to the current level of the key yield,&quot; Kimura said.</p>
<p>Although the medium-term outlook for JGBs is bleak, the key JGB yield is likely to stabilise near current levels in the short term, said Goldman's Yamakawa.</p>
<p>&quot;At this stage, we cannot say that economic data that is indicative of a clear economic recovery is at hand. So a runaway rise in long-term interest rates is unlikely.&quot;</p>
<p>The sharp rise in JGB yields will enable investors such as public funds and life insurers to buy JGBs without worrying about the possibility of negative interest rate margins, and such buying should provide short-term support to JGBs, Merrill Lynch's Kobayashi said.</p>
<p>Kobayashi said the deposit rate the Finance Ministry pays to other ministries for their long-term deposits is now at 2.6 percent while life insurers' expected rate of interest is at 2.5 percent. &quot;Investors (such as public funds and life insurers) are likely to buy JGBs based on their liabilities.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-5473-3748</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
