<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573514" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Stowaway twins appear in court on return to NZ.</title>
<headline>Stowaway twins appear in court on return to NZ.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Twin sisters found in remote tropical Northern Australia after swimming through shark-infested waters were remanded in custody on their return home to New Zealand on Friday.</p>
<p>The 18-year-old sisters Sarah and Joanne Ingham had been deported and were immediately taken by police to an Auckland court on charges relating to events before they left New Zealand.</p>
<p>They had a tearful reunion with their mother, Jeanette Ingham.</p>
<p>The twins made a 30-second court appearance and were remanded to appear in Nelson District Court on Monday. They were refused bail because they had absconded previously.</p>
<p>The twins had been missing since April 20, when they leapt overboard with a 27-year-old Malaysian seaman from the Malaysian container ship Bunga Terasek in Princess Charlotte Bay, north of Cairns. The trio were apparently locked in a love triangle.</p>
<p>The pair stowed away on the ship in early February after failing to appear in a New Zealand court on drink-driving and assault charges. The twins and the seaman were found on Wednesday by members of a remote Aboriginal community around 50 km (30 miles) inland at Coen, on the Cape York Peninsula.</p>
<p>They had reportedly paddled 20 km (12 miles) through shark and crocodile-infested waters after leaping from the ship.</p>
<p>Local Aborigines who found them gave them food and, after driving them to an area near Coen, called the police. The trio were eventually found by Aboriginal trackers.</p>
<p>An Aboriginal police tracker, Barry John Port, said on Thursday he believed the trio had survived once they reached the shore by scavenging for seafood.</p>
<p>&quot;They lived on the fish that they caught, oysters and crabs,&quot; Port said. &quot;I think it is amazing that they survived.&quot;</p>
<p>Some people doubt the twins' story.</p>
<p>Barb Shepherd, a Coen nurse who examined them after their ordeal described their survival as a &quot;cock and bull&quot; story.</p>
<p>&quot;I find the story pretty incredible. Their lips weren't chapped as you'd expect if they'd been in salt water for 18 hours and out in the sun for two weeks,&quot; she told The New Zealand Herald newspaper.</p>
<p>She suspects the trio had been picked up and dropped ashore by a prawn trawler, a view shared by North Queensland police.</p>
<p>The lack of insect bites or signs of dehydration and hunger lead Coen Regional Aboriginal Corporation project manager Annelies Vorhuis to doubt the story.</p>
<p>She questioned why they ran away from police and trackers if they had been living off the land for so long.</p>
<p>&quot;If you'd been out in the bush for two weeks, you'd be pretty keen to get into a warm bed and have a hot shower,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
