<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573591" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Newmont unit happy Batu Hijau resolved.</title>
<headline>Newmont unit happy Batu Hijau resolved.</headline>
<byline>K.T. Arasu</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia has cleared the way for a subsidiary of Newmont Gold Corp of the United States to begin construction at a major copper and gold mine, and the company said on Friday that it was happy with the result.</p>
<p>The Batu Hijau mining project on the eastern Indonesian island of Sumbawa swung into the spotlight last week after the government demanded a 10 percent stake in the project on the basis of national interests.</p>
<p>The news came as the mines and energy ministry said it was tightening mining regulations in the wake of the Busang goldfield fiasco.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very pleased. Logic prevailed and we got the permit to construct...we are under way,&quot; Eric Hamer, president-director of PT Newmont Nusa Tenggara, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Production, if we stay on schedule and have not not missed too much time, should begin in early 1999,&quot; Hamer said.</p>
<p>He said the government had accepted the company's decision to reject an attempt by the mines and energy ministry to secure a 10-percent stake in the gold and copper mining project.</p>
<p>&quot;We sorted it out. We just told them there was no room for the further carrying (of a local partner),&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Hamer said the government had also approved the sale of a 35-percent stake in the project to Sumitomo Corp.</p>
<p>Newmont Nusa had said the government had held up permission to begin construction at the project for six months and delayed approving the sale of a 35-percent stake to Sumitomo.</p>
<p>Industry analysts had said the government's attitude toward the Newmont project would reflect its policy on mines in the wake of Busang, the once-fabled gold deposit in Indonesia's East Kalimantan province which was recently found to be worthless.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be better for us to forget about Busang,&quot; former mines minister Mohammed Sadli said in an interview in the Jakarta Post on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;What concerns me much more is the Newmont case. (Asking for a 10 percent stake) will have a very bad influence on Indonesia. It will lead others to think that those are the rules of the game in Indonesia.&quot;</p>
<p>Newmont Nusa owns 45 percent of the Batu Hijau project, Sumitomo has 35 percent and Indonesian company PT Pukuafu Indah, controlled by miner Jusuf Merukh, the rest.  </p>
<p>Newmont Gold Corp said in Denver on Thursday the approval by the government would allow the company to begin construction immediately, with initial work on the port, electricity generation facilities, roads and telecommunication facilities.</p>
<p>Construction of the $1.9 billion project is expected to take three years. Newmont said Batu Hijau contains reserves of 12.1 million ounces of gold and 10.6 billion pounds of copper.</p>
<p>The mine is expected to produce an average of 550,000 ounces of gold a year and 270,000 tons of copper over a 20-year mine life. Newmont Gold is 94 percent owned by Newmont Mining Corp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
