<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573704" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks fall by lunch on bank, finance sales.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks fall by lunch on bank, finance sales.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks took a further drubbing on Friday morning as currency concerns resurfaced and economic worries prompted foreign investors to unwind positions in bank and finance stocks, trader said.</p>
<p>The SET Index lost 12.57 points, or 2.05 percent, to 601.49 by the break after briefly dipping below the 600 level in the morning. The SET 50 lost 0.93 points, or 2.07 percent, to 44.09 1.53 billion baht turnover.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreigners are continuing to sell banks and finance stocks and it is making people sell in other sectors of the market,&quot; said one local trader.  </p>
<p>Reports of central bank intervention in Singapore to defend the baht unnerved investors already concerned by fundamental economic indicators, corporate liquidity, weak corporate earnings prospects, and slow progress of mergers among finance companies, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The currency issue is back on the agenda and it is obviously a major worry for a lot of investors,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hopes of an export led recovery in the second half of 1997 faded after sluggish first quarter export data released by the customs department, analysts said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
