<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573719" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan to unveil Big Bang timing before June summit.</title>
<headline>Japan to unveil Big Bang timing before June summit.</headline>
<byline>Toru Suzuki</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan is expected to unveil the time schedule for implementing its &quot;Big Bang&quot; financial market reforms in mid-June, before the Group of Seven (G7) nations meets in Denver on June 20, financial industry sources said.</p>
<p>They said Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto is keen on presenting the plans to G7 leaders at their next meeting.</p>
<p>Last November, Hashimoto announced plans to liberalise the nation's financial markets by 2001 and catch up with reforms carried out more than a decade ago in Europe and North America.</p>
<p>The major points of the &quot;Big Bang&quot; reforms have been outlined, but details of when deregulation will be implemented and how have yet to be decided.</p>
<p>The reforms will end fixed brokerage commissions, allow banks to sell investment trust funds and tear down barriers between the banking, broking and insurance sectors.</p>
<p>A Ministry of Finance (MOF) official said a MOF advisory panel, the Financial System Council, is due to end discussions about the reforms' time schedule at a meeting on May 29.</p>
<p>The panel is expected to finalise its proposal, which the MOF will follow, during the second week of June, financial industry sources said.</p>
<p>Another advisory panel, the Securities and Exchange Council, is also expected to finalise details on deregulating the securities industry and markets by the time the Financial System Council finalises its proposal, they said.</p>
<p>Finance ministry sources said the Securities and Exchange Council was expected to propose abolishing rules which exclude brokers from such areas as asset management, investment trusts, insurance and commodity futures.</p>
<p>In order to provide time for smaller brokerages to prepare for competition and to protect them from immediately plunging into difficulties, the deregulation of stock brokering fees will be one of the last of the reforms to be implemented, a senior MOF official recently told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said that other liberalisation measures, such as allowing brokers to use a wrap accounts system, should be pursued first.</p>
<p>The wrap account system, widely used in the United States, is currently banned under Japan's Securities and Exchange Law.</p>
<p>The system allows a securities house to manage investors' assets based on discretionary management contracts. Investors pay commissions for a package including investment advice, stock transactions and account management services.</p>
<p>Japan's securities industry has been urging an end to the ban on wrap accounts, as part of a broad range of securities deregulation measures.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
