<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573759" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Shenzhen B index up at noon but mood jittery.</title>
<headline>Shenzhen B index up at noon but mood jittery.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shenzhen's B share index was up slightly at midday on Friday after a rumoured market clampdown failed to materialise, but trading was thin and volatile, analysts said.</p>
<p>The foreign currency B share index gained 1.06 points or 0.60 percent to 177.66 on turnover of HK$47.4 million.  </p>
<p>&quot;The index rose because the expected bad news did not materialise,&quot; an analyst at J&amp;A Securities said.</p>
<p>A Hong Kong newspaper said on Thursday that China's Ministry of Finance was considering increasing stamp tax on stock trading to 0.4 or 0.5 percent from the current 0.3 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The small trading volume shows investors are cautious after yesterday's sharp losses,&quot; an analyst at China Guotai Securities said. Shenzhen B shares fell 3.35 percent on Thursday due to fears of a government crackdown.</p>
<p>&quot;Monday's performance will depend on whether Beijing comes out with any measures over the weekend,&quot; the Guotai analyst said.  </p>
<p>On Thursday, the B index fell 3.35 percent to 176.61 following the A share index which tumbled 5.97 percent to close at 501.92.</p>
<p>Analysts said they expect narrow-range trading for the B index in the afternoon, with the wait-and-see mood persisting.</p>
<p>By midday, the domestic currency A share index had gained 7.39 points or 1.47 percent to 509.30 on turnover of 7.89 billion yuan.</p>
<p>Jiangling Motors Corp was among the sharpest gainers in both the A and B share markets.</p>
<p>Its B shares surged HK$0.29 or 7.88 percent to HK$3.97 while its A shares rose to its 10 percent limit-up at 8.66 yuan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
