<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573876" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - May 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - May 9.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Jordanian press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-DUSTOUR</p>
<p>- A government plan to reform the civil service and deal with the bloated bureacracy by setting up committees to evaluate performance of civil servants and retrain and rehabilitate underperformers.</p>
<p>- Jordan ranked fourth in league of contributors to the U.N. peacekeeping forces in April; the kingdom's troops play a major role in police monitoring and peacekeeping duties in eight different troublespots around the globe.</p>
<p>AL-RAI</p>
<p>- Deputy Prime Minister Ensour says King Hussein is determined to tackle nations concerns; says a &quot;social safety net&quot; plan to alleviate poverty is a ten-year strategy requiring $1 billion and which still needs to be presented to donors to get support.</p>
<p>- Finance and planning ministers head to Abu Dhabi to attend annual meetings of Arab finanancial institutions; finance minister says meetings an opportunity for bilateral and joint consultation to help boost Arab economies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
