<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573977" id="root" date="1997-05-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: TENNIS-SLOW PIERCE, SPEEDY MARTINEZ IN ROME FINAL.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SLOW PIERCE, SPEEDY MARTINEZ IN ROME FINAL.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-05-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mary Pierce of France took the slow route to her first Italian Open tennis tournament final on Saturday while Spain's Conchita Martinez made it five in succession without dropping a set.</p>
<p>The tall 10th-seeded Pierce, who dumped American Monica Seles out at the Foro Italico on Thursday, beat 11th seed Barbara Paulus of Austria 4-6 6-3 6-1.</p>
<p>Martinez, winner of the last four Italian Open titles, hurried to a 6-2 6-2 win against unseeded Swiss teenager Patty Schneider in 71 minutes.</p>
<p>Schnyder broke Martinez in the first game of each set but each time it proved to be a false dawn.</p>
<p>The Spaniard promised to be in less of a hurry against Pierce in a repeat of their 1995 semifinal clash, which the Frenchwoman lost after taking the Australian Open title.</p>
<p>&quot;On clay, you need a lot of patience,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The win meant Martinez had reached the final with the loss of just 16 games in her four matches played so far.</p>
<p>Pierce, losing finalist at this year's Australian Open and the comeback queen against Seles, had not lost a set either until Paulus took the first on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;I started out just really slow today, I felt tired,&quot; the Canadian-born player said after the match.</p>
<p>Paulus also said she felt Pierce had been slow, but was referring to the length of time it took the Frenchwoman to serve rather than her movements around the court.</p>
<p>&quot;She's very difficult to play against because you can't find your rhythm easily,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;She takes her time and she hits very hard.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not unfair because she is allowed to take 20 seconds, she has the time. As long as it's only 20. But it's very difficult. You think she wants to serve and you are standing there waiting for it and nothing happens.&quot;</p>
<p>Pierce, who in February teamed up with Martina Navratilova's old coach Craig Kardon, said of her slowness: &quot;It's just something I've always done.</p>
<p>&quot;I did it in juniors. I'm not the kind of person who can play as fast as Monica or Steffi (Graf). I always find I need to take my time on a serve, not to rush.&quot;</p>
<p>For the first time since Monday, the stands were almost full as spectators turned out on a bright afternoon.</p>
<p>Their expectations of a resounding Pierce victory were dampened by an opening set more punctuated by gasps of disbelief as the Frenchwoman mistimed shots, double-faulted and, on one occasion, smashed into her own half of the court.</p>
<p>Pierce double-faulted at break point in the third game to give Paulus a 2-1 lead. She was broken again to 5-2 in the seventh game after saving two earlier break points.</p>
<p>Pierce broke back to 5-3, held serve but then lost the set with a return forehand hit way too long.</p>
<p>&quot;It took me a little while to get going,&quot; said Pierce. &quot;As the match went on, I got better and better.&quot;</p>
<p>Certainly, the second and third sets saw a changed player with the Frenchwoman pulling off some fine passing shots and re-setting the timing of her long strokes to perfection.</p>
<p>In the fourth game of the third set the chair umpire overruled a decision against Pierce, to the bemusement of Paulus and the crowd who had been misled by the scoreboard that suggested there was another point to be played.</p>
<p>&quot;I lost my game somewhere. Maybe my concentration was not there. I didn't even know it was game at 3-1,&quot; said Paulus.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
