<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574023" id="root" date="1997-05-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL ICE HOCKEY-SABRES ALIVE AGAINST FLYERS, COLORADO PUTS OILERS ON BRINK.</title>
<headline>NHL ICE HOCKEY-SABRES ALIVE AGAINST FLYERS, COLORADO PUTS OILERS ON BRINK.</headline>
<dateline>PHILADELPHIA 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ed Ronan swept a rebound past Garth Snow at 6:24 of overtime to help the Buffalo Sabres avoid a four-game sweep in their Eastern Conference semifinal series Friday by defeating the Philadelphia Flyers 5-4.</p>
<p>The night's other NHL playoff game went into overtime as well when the defending champion Colorado Avalanche beat the Oilers 3-2 to bring Edmonton to the brink of elimination, three games to one in their best-of-seven series.</p>
<p>The Sabres' game-winner came after ex-Flyer Garry Galley intercepted a clearing attempt at the left point and put a shot on goal that was stopped by Snow.</p>
<p>The rebound caromed to Ronan, who was all alone to the goaltender's left and wristed the puck into the open side of the net. It was the fourth career playoff goal and first since Game 4 of the 1994 Eastern Conference quarterfinals for Ronan, who was scratched for six of Buffalo's first 10 postseason contests.</p>
<p>&quot;Philly tried to clear the puck after we got it in deep,&quot; Ronan said. &quot;It took a bounce and Galley was able to take a shot. Snow made the save and I was right there for the rebound. It was nice to be able to contribute offensively.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The puck was bouncing and I couldn't quite do what I wanted to do with it, so I left the rebound, went over to stack the pads, and he shot it in,&quot; Snow said.</p>
<p>The Sabres, whose five goals equalled their total for the first three games of the series, will host Game 5 on Sunday afternoon.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm confident that we'll walk in there and put together a good effort. We'll come out with the win, that's the bottom line,&quot; Flyers captain Eric Lindros said. &quot;We could sit around and cry about spilt milk all we want, but the bottom line is we have to win a hockey game, and our next chance is in two days.&quot;</p>
<p>Buffalo had been hoping for an emotional boost from the return of goaltender Dominik Hasek. But Hasek, who served a three-game suspension, felt continued pain in his ailing right knee during the morning skate. He joined the team in pre-game warmups, but was scratched, giving rookie Steve Shields his eighth straight start.</p>
<p>Shileds responded with 39 saves, including a series of key stops early in overtime, when he stopped Lindros and John LeClair from close range.</p>
<p>&quot;I was prepared to play even though I didn't think I would be playing,&quot; Shields said.</p>
<p>The Sabres grabbed a 4-3 lead on Dixon Ward's shorthanded tally with 8:07 to go in the third period.</p>
<p>&quot;We didn't want to go out in four because that's not what we deserve,&quot; Ward said.</p>
<p>The Flyers got the controversial tying goal just 93 seconds later. Shields appeared to have control of the puck under his left pad, but Mikael Renberg took a couple of whacks at it before poking it into the net for his third goal of the series and fourth of the postseason.</p>
<p>Dainius Zubrus, Dale Hawerchuk and Trent Klatt scored the earlier goals for Philadelphia, one in each period.</p>
<p>Donald Audette, Derek Plante and Michal Grosek scored the other Buffalo goals. Plante had a goal and three assists after managing just one assist in the first three games.</p>
<p>An apparent Flyers goal by LeClair with 5:01 to go in the second period was disallowed by the video replay official, who ruled LeClair had a skate in the crease.</p>
<p>&quot;My understanding was that they said I kicked it. But I never kicked it, that's not true,&quot; LeClair said.</p>
<p>In Edmonton, Claude Lemieux's league-leading ninth playoff goal 8:35 into overtime lifted the Avalanche to within one win of the Western Conference finals.</p>
<p>Lemieux and Valeri Kamensky came into the Edmonton zone on a 2-on-1 break, but Curtis Joseph made a stellar left-pad save on Kamensky's wrist shot from the bottom of right faceoff circle. Kamensky tracked down the rebound in the right corner and fed a pass to Lemieux behind the net.</p>
<p>Lemieux moved a stride to his left and slid the puck under Joseph's pads.  With the goalie out of position, the puck barely trickled though his pads and over the goal line.</p>
<p>Lemieux has goals in six straight games.</p>
<p>The Avalanche can wrap up the the series with a victory at home in Game 5 Sunday.</p>
<p>Colorado played without star centre Peter Forsberg for the first time in the playoffs. Forsberg suffered a mild concussion Wednesday in Game 4.</p>
<p>Avalanche goalie Patrick Roy finished with 27 saves and turned away several excellent scoring opportunties late in the game. He stuffed Andrei Kovalenko's wraparound attempt with 10 seconds left in regulation and made a right pad stop on Todd Marchant's partial breakaway 80 seconds into overtime.</p>
<p>Roy improved to 29-9 all-time in playoff overtimes.</p>
<p>Joseph, who made 38 saves, stopped Adam Deadmarsh's point-blank shot with 2:10 to play in the third period, keeping the game tied at two.</p>
<p>Kamensky scored his eighth goal of the playoffs 3:06 into the game to give Colorado a 1-0 lead. But Marchant scored short-handed and Ryan Smyth on the power play in the second period to put Edmonton up 2-1 before Sandis Ozolinsh tallied with 1:20 to play in the second period to tie it 2-2.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHILADELPHIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
