<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574071" id="root" date="1997-05-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>LITHUANIA: LITHUANIAN TELECOM ATTRACTS BIG NAMES.</title>
<headline>LITHUANIAN TELECOM ATTRACTS BIG NAMES.</headline>
<dateline>VILNIUS 1997-05-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Lithuanian Ministry for European Affairs announced on Saturday 23 major law firms, consultancies and investment banks who have applied to prepare the upcoming privatisation programme for Lithuanian Telecom.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch, Union Bank of Switzerland, Deloitte and Touche and Daiwa Institute of Research Ltd. are among the 23 candidates. Deutsche Morgan Grenfell and Nomura International are also participating together in the tender as a consortium.</p>
<p>&quot;I am really very happy that we received 23 applications... this makes me optimistic,&quot; European Affairs Minister Laima Andrikiene told reporters. &quot;Lithuanian Telecom is a really attractive object.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Only 34 percent will be left state-owned,&quot; Andrikiene said.</p>
<p>Andrikiene added that it had not yet been decided in what blocks the shares would be sold.</p>
<p>&quot;There are two basic options,&quot; said Vytenis Junevichius, director of the privatisation department at the European Affairs Ministry.</p>
<p>&quot;(The first is) to sell a substantial interest to a strategic partner, say 20 to 30 percent, or 50 to 70 percent, of the shares,&quot; Junevichius said. &quot;And, with the increased value of the company, put shares on the market.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The second option, an extreme option, is to start with a public offering,&quot; Junevichius said, adding that there was room in between both variants and that it would be the job of the adviser to help choose.</p>
<p>Andrikiene said a contract with the lead adviser will be signed in July.</p>
<p>&quot;At the end of this year, we will announce the second tender, which will be the real tender of privatisation, during which a strategic investor will be selected,&quot; Andrikiene said.</p>
<p>&quot;At the beginning of next year, in February, there will be the signing of agreements and contracts,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Lithuanian Telecom is one of 13 key state enterprises which Lithuania's right-of-centre government has committed itself to delivering into private hands through international tender.</p>
<p>-- Burton Frierson, Vilnius newsroom +370 2 22 35 18</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VILNIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LITHUANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
