<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574055" id="root" date="1997-05-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>MONACO: MOTOR RACING-FRENTZEN AND SCHUMACHER ON FRONT ROW IN MONACO.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-FRENTZEN AND SCHUMACHER ON FRONT ROW IN MONACO.</headline>
<byline>Timothy Collings</byline>
<dateline>MONTE CARLO 1997-05-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Heinz-Harald Frentzen ended his Williams team mate Jacques Villeneuve's run of five pole positions on Saturday when he claimed the front spot on the grid for Sunday's Monaco Grand Prix.</p>
<p>Frentzen, winner of the San Marino Grand Prix two weeks ago, clocked one minute 18.216 seconds to edge out compatriot Michael Schumacher in a Ferrari by 0.019 seconds and secure the first all-German front row in the 47-year history of the Formula One world championship.</p>
<p>The double world champion, who had been fastest for most of the session, made a tremendous bid to regain pole in the final minutes but had to settle for second place for the 55th running of the classic street race round the Mediterranean principality.</p>
<p>Frentzen's time eclipsed the record lap established in qualifying by Schumacher in 1994 when, in a Benetton, he clocked 1:18.560.</p>
<p>Since then, however, the track has seen alterations to the chicane after the tunnel and the entry to the swimming pool complex.</p>
<p>These have made the circuit slightly faster and safer and the changes, in addition to the rapidly-improving performances of the tyres this year, enabled Frentzen to beat Schumacher's qualifying record by three-tenths of a second. Last year's pole time, also set by Schumacher, was 1:20.536.</p>
<p>World championship leading Canadian Villeneuve was third fastest in his Williams and will share the second row of the grid with Italian Giancarlo Fisichella in a Jordan, ahead of Briton David Coulthard, who was fifth for McLaren, and German Ralf Schumacher, younger brother of Michael, in the second Jordan.</p>
<p>Frentzen's pole was the first of his career and came in his 53rd Grand Prix. He said he felt a great sense of relief and euphoria after opting for a risky set-up to overhaul Schumacher's team in the final part of the session.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything came good today for me,&quot; he said, referring to his accident on Thursday when he lost control of his Williams in opening practice. The car was repaired on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It was brilliant. Really exciting. I really didn't expect it to be easy to catch Michael and that is why I opted for a risky set-up. It worked, thankfully. When they told me the time was an 18.2, I didn't believe them.</p>
<p>&quot;It is wonderful to claim my first pole position. Now it is important for me to sleep well, not to drink any champagne and to be very relaxed and confident for the race.&quot;</p>
<p>Frentzen's pole confirmed his place as a major contender in this year's championship following his victory at Imola.</p>
<p>Schumacher, who has long overshadowed his compatriot, said: &quot;I always expected this. When Heinz-Harald went to Williams, I knew he would be fast.&quot;</p>
<p>Schumacher was fastest through most of the session after clocking his best time after 20 minutes. Both Frentzen and Villeneuve tried to eclipse him and the Canadian touched the guardrails at Sainte Devote corner, damaging his car slightly and then stopping on the side of the track near the entrance to the tunnel.</p>
<p>&quot;Something broke at the back of the car and I didn't want to end up getting in the way,&quot; he said. &quot;It is going to be a long race and I know that you can start anywhere and still end up on the podium so I am confident.&quot;</p>
<p>Schumacher, too, was full of confidence for the race and predicted that he could finish at least second. &quot;We shall have to see what the strategies are -- it will be interesting,&quot; he said, referring to the different teams' plans for refuelling pitstops in the 78-lap race.</p>
<p>If Schumacher can win, he will give Ferrari their first Monaco win since Jacques Villeneuve's father Gilles won for the Italian team in 1981. But if one of the Williams drivers wins, it will also end a long run without a win in Monaco dating back to Keke Rosberg's victory in 1983.</p>
<p>While the two most famous teams were satisfied with their positions on the front row of the grid, there were inquests elsewhere.</p>
<p>Eddie Irvine, in the second Ferrari, qualified down in 15th place watched by Ferrari's president Luca di Montezemolo. The two Benettons, driven by Frenchman Jean Alesi and Austrian Gerhard Berger, were in ninth and 17th positions.</p>
<p>Defending world champion Damon Hill of Britain was 13th in his Arrows, three places ahead of Brazilian team mate Pedro Diniz while another Briton, Johnny Herbert, who was fastest in Thursday's opening practice in his Sauber, qualified seventh.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MONAC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SMARNO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTE CARLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MONACO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
