<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574176" id="root" date="1997-05-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian ruling party stresses unity in E.Timor.</title>
<headline>Indonesian ruling party stresses unity in E.Timor.</headline>
<byline>Jim Della-Giacoma</byline>
<dateline>BAUCAU, East Timor 1997-05-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's ruling Golkar party chief Harmoko hit the campaign trail in East Timor on Saturday, telling a rally that the people of the troubled territory were an integral part of the nation.</p>
<p>Speaking during the second week of the campaign for the May 29 general elections, Harmoko said East Timorese should vote for Golkar as it had brought development to the former Portuguese colony, invaded by Indonesia in December 1975 and annexed the following year.</p>
<p>&quot;Golkar regards East Timor as being one with Indonesia,&quot; Harmoko told a pubic meeting of around 1,000 people, mostly dressed in the party's yellow colour, at an indoor basketball stadium in the town of Baucau.</p>
<p>However, in the capital Dili, and across the countryside between the two towns, there was almost no evidence of the election campaign, compared with the more hectic electioneering and colourful party banners strung across the country's most populous Java island and the capital Jakarta.</p>
<p>Only the Baucau army barracks had two Golkar flags at the front.</p>
<p>Despite considerable tension in East Timor, the Golkar rally passed off peacefully. A small number of uniformed police directed traffic while a number of armed troops stood in the shade a few hundred metres away watching the orderly event.</p>
<p>Many people in the territory do not accept Indonesian rule and a small band of guerrillas is still waging an armed struggle for self-determination.</p>
<p>Harmoko said the mostly Catholic East Timorese were citizens of Indonesia and were free to live anywhere in the predominantly Moslem nation.</p>
<p>Indonesia goes to the polls on May 29 to elect 425 seats in the 500-member parliament. The rest of the seats are filled by the military, which does not vote.</p>
<p>East Timor's 456,000 registered voters, a fraction of Indonesia's 125 million strong electorate, will choose four representatives to the parliament from candidates put up by the three authorised parties.</p>
<p>At the last poll in 1992, East Timor elected three Golkar legislators and one from the Christian-Nationalist Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI). The Moslem-oriented United Development Party (PPP) received only a fraction of the vote.</p>
<p>Dressed in his trademark yellow short-sleeved jacket, black T-shirt and black cap, Harmoko noted that East Timor, which Jakarta reagrds as its youngest of 27 provinces, has taken part in four Indonesian general elections since 1977.</p>
<p>&quot;East Timorese possess the same political rights as others in the Indonesian nation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The people of East Timor are Indonesian,&quot; Harmoko added. One youth at the side of the hall then said in a raised voice &quot;Empty talk.&quot;</p>
<p>However most of those in attendance sat silently unless they were urged by campaigners to shout party slogans.</p>
<p>Manuel Carrascalao, an outspoken Golkar legislator in the East Timor regional parliament, told Reuters in Dili that recent low attendances at rallies in East Timor were a reflection of the lack of enthusiasm for the current campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;Golkar has made many promises which have not been kept,&quot; he said. &quot;The first is about the political situation, the second about job opportunities and the third is about corruption. They said everything would be better but it is not.&quot;</p>
<p>Carrascalao said mysterious disappearances and torture still occurred in heavily-militarised East Timor, adding that the power of the army and police was unchecked and corruption in government was rife.</p>
<p>Harmoko said Golkar had brought good roads, electricity and infrastructure to all parts of East Timor.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAUCAU, East Timor"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
