<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574106" id="root" date="1997-05-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zairean rebels say Angola's UNITA joins fighting.</title>
<headline>Zairean rebels say Angola's UNITA joins fighting.</headline>
<byline>Buchizya Mseteka</byline>
<dateline>LUBUMBASHI, Zaire 1997-05-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zairean rebels said on Saturday Angola's UNITA movement had sent thousands of fighters to reinforce Zaire's ragged army in the defence of the Zairean capital Kinshasa.</p>
<p>Rebel &quot;Foreign Minister&quot; Bizima Karaha told Reuters Laurent Kabila's rebels had captured some UNITA troops after heavy fighting outside Kenge, 200 km (125 miles) east of Kinshasa, and rebel forces had advanced 50 km (30 miles) beyond the town.</p>
<p>&quot;We now have definite evidence that UNITA has come in to reinforce the government army. We captured a lot of UNITA troops after heavy fighting outside Kenge,&quot; said Karaha, adding the prisoners would be flown to rebel headquarters in Lubumbashi.</p>
<p>The Angolan government has been accused by Mobutu of sending its own troops to back the rebels advancing on the capital. Luanda has repeatedly denied any involvement in the Zaire war.</p>
<p>Independent military analysts have said Angolan government armour was involved in the rebel push towards Kinshasa, 200 km (125 miles) west of Kenge.</p>
<p>Karaha said the fighting at Kenge was heavy and thousands of UNITA fighters and the former Rwandan Hutu troops put up heavy resistance before being driven 50 km (30 miles) beyond the town.</p>
<p>Rebel Voice of the People radio said Chinese troops were fighting alongside the UNITA and former Rwandan Hutu troops.</p>
<p>South Africa says it has assurances from Kabila he will not move militarily on Kinshasa until after he has a second face-to-face meeting with Mobutu aboard a South African navy ship next Wednesday.</p>
<p>Jonas Savimbi's UNITA (National Union for the Total Independence of Angola) was a close ally of Mobutu's and received supplies through Zaire during the 20-year Angolan civil war.</p>
<p>Bill Richardson, U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, said on Friday that the Angolans needed to &quot;step aside ... They've got, unfortunately, some negative intentions in terms of moving their troops into Zaire to pay back Mobutu.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The Angolan government, which is in power now, wants to pay him back and they don't want to help Mobutu. They want him out militarily,&quot; Richardson said in a U.S. television interview shortly after he returned from a shuttle diplomacy trip throughout Central Africa.</p>
<p>U.N. officials in Angola said on Friday they had found no evidence of a reported military buildup of Angolan troops during a visit to the Angolan northern town of Noqui on the border with Zaire.</p>
<p>Noqui, just south of Zaire's port of Matadi, is controlled by UNITA.</p>
<p>Diplomats in the Angolan capital have said there has been an increase in the presence of Angolan government troops in the northern enclave of Cabinda but the reason for the buildup was not clear.</p>
<p>Cabinda, separated from the rest of Angola by a thin strip of Zairean territory and the Zaire river, is 400 km (250 miles) west of Kinshasa.</p>
<p>Cabinda separatist guerrillas FLEC are fighting a war for independence from Angola's government and have bases in Zaire.</p>
<p>During the Angolan civil war, which ended in 1994, Zaire harboured UNITA guerrillas opposed to the government and Angola took in Zairean Katangese gendarme forces after a revolt against Mobutu failed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUBUMBASHI, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
