<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574271" id="root" date="1997-05-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Lebanese Christians gather to welcome pope.</title>
<headline>Lebanese Christians gather to welcome pope.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-05-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Flag-waving crowds gathered in Christian districts of Beirut on Saturday to welcome Pope John Paul on his first visit to Lebanon and the Middle East but Moslem districts were quieter with few people on the streets.</p>
<p>Hundreds of civil and religious dignitaries headed by Maronite Christian President Elias Hrawi gathered at Beirut airport to greet the pope who was due to land at 1215 p.m. (0915 GMT) for a 32-hour visit.</p>
<p>Troops and police imposed tight security measures at the airport and along the pope's 10 km (six miles) route through Moslem and Christian districts to the presidential palace at Baabda, above Beirut.</p>
<p>Soldiers in battle fatigues with automatic weapons lined the route in bright sunshine, backed by armoured vehicles at intersections and helicopters flying overhead.</p>
<p>Large triumphal arches along the road were decorated with palm branches and Lebanese and papal flags and thousands of flags were strung across the road.</p>
<p>An hour before the pope's arrival scattered groups of schoolchildren and scouts with brass bands lined the route in a Shi'ite Moslem district near the airport that is a stronghold of the radical Hizbollah (Party of God) movement which is fighting Israeli troops in south Lebanon.</p>
<p>Streets were largely deserted in West Beirut, which is mainly inhabited by Moslems, although shops were open. Beach clubs were open and a fair number of people took advantage of the early summer heat to sunbathe.</p>
<p>But in Christian-inhabited districts further eastwards shops were closed and excited crowds gathered to line the route in a holiday atmosphere, many of them bussed in from Christian towns across the country.</p>
<p>Teenagers wore t-shirts with the pope's photograph on the front and cars paraded with yellow-and-white papal flags sticking from their windows.</p>
<p>The Christian district of Furn el-Shebak on the road to the palace was a forest of Lebanese and papal flags. At one intersection a special new lifesize shrine to the Virgin Mary had been erected to welcome the pope.</p>
<p>After meetings with state dignitaries and leaders of Moslem communities at the presidential palace the pope will fly north by helicopter to Lebanon's Christian heartland.</p>
<p>He will meet thousands of young people on Saturday evening for a ceremony at Harissa, Lebanon's principal shrine to the Virgin Mary.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
