<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574369" id="root" date="1997-05-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: TURK JOURNALISTS INVESTIGATED OVER COUP COMMENTS.</title>
<headline>TURK JOURNALISTS INVESTIGATED OVER COUP COMMENTS.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-05-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's Islamist Justice Ministry has ordered inquiries into eight journalists and two union officials for articles or speeches alleged to have been intended to provoke a military coup, the Turkish media said.</p>
<p>The private NTV news channel said various courts, including state security courts, were launching preliminary inquiries into three of the accused and full investigations into five of them.</p>
<p>&quot;Comical inquiry into the press,&quot; was how the daily Hurriyet interpreted the move by the ministry, which is attached to the Islamist wing of the coalition government.</p>
<p>&quot;Judicial pressure on journalists,&quot; said Sabah daily, which has three journalists, including a cartoonist, under investigation.</p>
<p>The Islamists of Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan's Welfare Party have had an unhappy relationship with the strongly secularist mainstream media ever since they came to power in an alliance with the conservatives last June.</p>
<p>Newspapers have often speculated over the possibility of the powerful, secularist army staging their fourth coup since 1960 during Welfare's time in office.</p>
<p>The speculation mounted earlier this year as the army confronted Welfare over increasing Islamist zeal in meetings of the military-dominated National Security Council.</p>
<p>Among those charged is the general secretary of the workers' federation Turk-Is, Semsi Denizer, for saying: &quot;If a coup is necessary we will support it&quot;, and Sabah columnist Fatih Cekirge, for an article headlined: &quot;The latest situation in Ankara -- something could happen any moment.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
