<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574374" id="root" date="1997-05-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-BETIS DEFEAT BOOSTS BARCELONA'S EUROPEAN CUP CHANCES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BETIS DEFEAT BOOSTS BARCELONA'S EUROPEAN CUP CHANCES.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-05-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Barcelona's hopes of taking Spain's second European Cup place were boosted on Sunday when rivals Real Betis unexpectedly went down 2-1 at bottom-placed Logrones.</p>
<p>With five games left to play, Betis are six points adrift of Barcelona, who beat Real Madrid 1-0 in a bad-tempered game on Saturday but who are still five points behind the league leaders.</p>
<p>Barcelona's biggest challenger for the coveted second spot now appears to come from Deportivo Coruna, who are level on points with Betis ahead of Monday's game at Valencia.</p>
<p>However Betis' international striker Alfonso Perez refused to be defeatist after the game, in which Logrones' veteran striker Ruben Sosa had scored a superb set-piece goal.</p>
<p>&quot;Until we are mathematically out of the running for the second place we won't throw in the towel,&quot; said Alfonso.</p>
<p>Fifth-placed Atletico Madrid virtually guaranteed a UEFA Cup place for next season by beating Athletic Bilbao 2-1.</p>
<p>Curiously the goalkeepers of both sides were booked -- at different stages of the game -- for wasting time.</p>
<p>The Athletic keeper saw the yellow card before Kiko Narvaez knocked in the winner with a superb backheader from a Milinko Pantic corner.</p>
<p>Zaragoza pulled out of trouble with a 1-0 win over Espanyol, while Sevilla surprised fellow strugglers Hercules with a crushing 5-0 victory.</p>
<p>Eleven teams are still in serious relegation trouble, amongst them Sporting Gijon, 2-1 winners over Celta Vigo.</p>
<p>After the second Sporting goal Celta's troubled Russian midfielder Alexander Mostovoi left the field of his own accord in an apparent protest at the poor play of his teammates.</p>
<p>Mostovoi later returned to the pitch, but is likely to face disciplinary action.</p>
<p>&quot;The club will probably take action ... The players criticised him for it afterwards,&quot; said Celta coach Fernando Santos.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
