<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57451" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chairman of large minority-owned bond firm resigns.</title>
<headline>Chairman of large minority-owned bond firm resigns.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chairman of one of the nation's largest minority-owned investment banking firms resigned on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Calvin B. Grigsby resigned as chairman of San Francisco-based Grigsby Brandford &amp; Co., according to a news release by the firm. The move comes a week after it was disclosed that he paid a fine for making campaign gifts in California without full disclosure.</p>
<p>Grigsby, the long-time chairman of the minority-owned firm he founded in 1981, could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>In Tuesday's news release, he said that he was &quot;looking forward to this as a major intersection in my life after a career devoted primarily to Grigsby Brandford &amp; Co.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I'm proud of Grigsby Brandford, the contribution it has made, and I'm eager to pursue new opportunities at this stage in my life,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The investment banking and financial advisory firm underwrites, sells and trades municipal bonds, preferred stock, Treasury notes and other government securities. It is the only Black-owned investment bank to rank in the top 15 senior managers of tax-exempt financial deals.</p>
<p>Napoleon Brandford was named board chairman by the private firm's shareholders. Suzanne Shank, a managing director for Grigsby Brandford based in the Midwest, was named president and chief executive officer, according to the release.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, California state officials disclosed that Grigsby had paid a $5,000 fine for making campaign contributions without full and complete disclosure.</p>
<p>In an interview last week, Grigsby said the press was exaggerating the campaign contribution violations.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't consider this a major item. To me, it's not a big deal because it's just a reporting violation,&quot; he said. &quot;Somehow, the press has made it look a lot more than that.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Why that happens, I think, has a lot to do with their interest in the fact that I'm an African American,&quot; Grigsby said. &quot;I think there's some character assassination there,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>--Adam Entous, 415-677 2511</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
