<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574536" id="root" date="1997-05-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: WALL ST WEEK AHEAD/Stocks ride rollercoaster.</title>
<headline>WALL ST WEEK AHEAD/Stocks ride rollercoaster.</headline>
<byline>Richard Jacobsen</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street's rollercoaster ride is showing no signs of stopping soon.</p>
<p>Market players said they expect further volatility in U.S. stocks this week as investors as react to a batch economic data that will give further clues as to whether the Federal Reserve will tighten interest rates again on May 20.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to have big swings in the market for the foreseeable future,&quot; Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter Ltd.</p>
<p>Big swings have become almost commonplace on Wall Street.  </p>
<p>After rising a record 332 points the week before last, the Dow industrials last Monday rose another 143 points and closed at record high. A fresh record high was set Tuesday, then the Dow fell 140 points on Wednesday.</p>
<p>For the week, the Dow ended up 98 points. It closed Friday with a gain of 33 points to 7170.</p>
<p>With most first quarter corporate earnings reports out of the way, investors will focus on the final dose of economic news ahead of the May 20 meeting of the Fed's Federal Open Market Committee.  </p>
<p>The market is hit on Tuesday by a report on April retail sales. Wednesday brings April wholesale inflation data and Thursday April retail inflation numbers.</p>
<p>The week &quot;is going to depend on the (economic) statistics,&quot; said Peggy Farley, chief executive at Amas Securities. &quot;One statistic that points at all to inflation and you're going to see a rapidly dropping market.&quot;</p>
<p>But, she added, &quot;I certainly don't see a huge sell-off ahead for this market. I think we've already gotten past that.&quot;  </p>
<p>After falling nearly 10 percent off its early year peak to close at 6392 on April 11, the Dow has risen 12 percent.</p>
<p>A speech by Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan on Thursday fueled speculation among market players as to whether the Fed would indeed hike short term rates for the second time after its quarter percentage point tightening March 25.</p>
<p>Greenspan said he expects economic growth to slow later this year and into next, but added that the central bank would need to act if that does not prove to be the case.  </p>
<p>Despite Wall Street's fixation on the Fed, stocks are benefiting from a number of long-term favorable factors, said Charles Pradilla, market analyst at Cowen and Co.</p>
<p>He cited recent weakness in the U.S. dollar, which would help foreign sales by U.S. multinational corporations, low inflation, and prospects of a balanced budget deal.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's somewhat immaterial whether Greenspan tightens on the 20th or not,&quot; Pradilla said.  </p>
<p>Some market players said they would be looking for the Nasdaq composite index to join the Dow industrial and transportation averages and the S&amp;P 500 index in setting record highs.</p>
<p>A Nasdaq record high would confirm that the recent rally in stocks had gained the full support of the key group of technology stocks, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;That would be the trigger for a significant rally,&quot; said William LeFevre, senior market analyst, at Ehrenkrantz, King, Nussbaum.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq composite ended the week at 1335, below its January 22 high of 1388.</p>
<p>((-- Wall St Desk, 212 859-1721))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
