<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57456" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dignity Partners retains Jefferies.</title>
<headline>Dignity Partners retains Jefferies.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dignity Partners Inc Tuesday said the company retained Jefferies &amp; Co. Inc. as financial advisor in connection with the development and implementation of strategic business options.</p>
<p>Dignity Partners is a nationwide specialty finance services company that provides viatical settlements for the terminally ill persons.  A viatical settlement is the payment of cash in return for an ownership interest in, and the right to receive the death benefit from, a life insurance policy.</p>
<p>On July 16, the company said it was temporarily ceasing to process new applications of policies insuring the lives of individuals diagnosed with HIV and AIDS while it further analyzed the research results reported at the International AIDS conference in Vancouver, British Columbia. The company continues to analyze the effects of such research results on its business.</p>
<p>As partial compensation for its services, Jefferies has received a five year warrant to purchase 300,000 shares of the company's common stock at an exercise price of $6.00 per share.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
