<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574671" id="root" date="1997-05-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China dons velvet glove as Hong Kong handover nears.</title>
<headline>China dons velvet glove as Hong Kong handover nears.</headline>
<byline>Diane Stormont</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>He was stiff and formal. A script rested on the table in front of him, taking the spontaneity out of the event.</p>
<p>But China's President Jiang Zemin nevertheless took a step that previous leaders would have found unthinkable: He faced the unblinking eye of a western television camera for an interview beamed around the world.</p>
<p>Jiang's appearance on Cable News Network (CNN) on Friday, and his soothing comments on Hong Kong, highlighted a softening in China's approach toward the territory it will soon reclaim.</p>
<p>As the clock ticks down on more than 150 years of British colonial rule, China is stepping up the battle for the hearts and minds of the 6.4 million Hong Kong residents who will once again become Chinese subjects on July 1.</p>
<p>Jiang told CNN that even he, the most powerful man in China, would not be above Hong Kong law if he set foot in the place.</p>
<p>Fears over the rule of law in Hong Kong have been stoked by the establishment of a China-backed provisional legislature to replace the present elected body and plans to water down civil rights and curb demonstrations in the territory.</p>
<p>Demonstrations are generally peaceful in Hong Kong. Arrests were made when protesters denouncing visiting senior Chinese official Lu Ping last year blocked traffic.</p>
<p>One that got out of hand was not a pro-democracy event. Angered by the landing of Japanese rightists on an island chain claimed by Japan, China and Taiwan, a group of local protesters invaded the Japanese consultate last year in a froth of pro-China patriotism causing some damage and minor injuries.</p>
<p>The group marched on Sunday to press China's claim on the the islands, called Diaoyu in Chinese and Senkaku in Japanese, but the 100-strong turnout was peaceful.</p>
<p>While Hong Kong's pro-democracy lobby remains vociferous, China has stopped its vilification of Chris Patten, the 28th and last British governor of Hong Kong who introduced democratic reforms vehemently opposed by China and which triggered China's moves to replace the current legislature.</p>
<p>Once denounced as a &quot;political prostitute&quot; and a &quot;criminal for 10,000 years&quot;, the verdict on Patten was revised last week by China's hardline envoy to Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Zhou Nan, sent to Hong Kong in 1989 after his predecessor defected to the United States following the bloody suppression of student-led demonstrators in Beijing, told Hong Kong journalists last week that Patten was not to blame for the Sino-British row over democratic reforms.</p>
<p>It was London's misguided policy that was at fault, said Zhou -- the director of the Xinhua News Agency which serves as China's de facto diplomatic mission in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Another Chinese olive branch was extended when the leaders of colonial trading giant Jardine Matheson, once labelled the &quot;black sheep of business&quot;, were welcomed in Beijing last week.</p>
<p>Jardine has long been China's whipping boy. Its 19th century roots as an opium trader were bound up in the British seizure of Hong Kong from a weak China in 1841.</p>
<p>With the ink on the 1984 Sino-British handover treaty barely dry, Jardine became the first company to shift its domicile out of Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Virtually every other major Hong Kong-listed company, including major Chinese-run firms, has followed suit and relocated their legal domiciles to Bermuda, the Cayman islands and other tax havens.</p>
<p>But Jardine's expression of unease over the future rankled with Beijing and its subsequent delisting from the Hong Kong stock market was seen as another insult.</p>
<p>So were comments by a senior company executive expressing support for Patten's democracy reforms.</p>
<p>Beijing retaliated by blocking a lucrative container terminal contract awarded by the government to Jardine, triggering concerns about politicisation and cronyism creeping into Hong Kong's relatively level business playing field.</p>
<p>But the gloom and doom which enveloped Hong Kong between 1993 and 1995 when Britain and China locked horns over Patten's reforms has largely dissipated, opinion polls show.</p>
<p>The stock market is booming, while the &quot;brain drain&quot; or exodus of Hong Kong professionals has fallen to the lowest level since 1989. Emigrants are even returning -- albeit with the insurance of a foreign passport in their back pocket.</p>
<p>But concerns still linger.</p>
<p>The Jardine impasse was resolved last September but fears about Chinese-style graft remain Hong Kong's number one concern, said Michael DeGolyer, director of a long-term study into the 1997 transition at the Baptist University.</p>
<p>&quot;We asked people which post-1997 aspects worried them most in July 1996, December 1996 and February 1997. It (corruption) was number one out of a total of seven various aspects...three times in a row. It's been number one there for over a year.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
