<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574758" id="root" date="1997-05-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel marks Memorial Day stuck in peace crisis.</title>
<headline>Israel marks Memorial Day stuck in peace crisis.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Heller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-05-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mired in a peace crisis and hearing the echoes of war, Israel on Sunday honoured its 18,538 soldiers killed in nearly half a century of independence.</p>
<p>Air raid sirens brought the Jewish state to a standstill for its national memorial day amid little sign of progress in U.S. efforts to renew Israel-PLO talks and warnings from Israeli generals that a peace deadlock would bring war nearer.</p>
<p>&quot;Today it is clear that despite the difficulties ahead, we are moving surely, step by step, towards an era of acceptance by our neighbours of Israel's existence,&quot; Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said at a memorial ceremony.</p>
<p>&quot;This acceptance stems from their understanding that they cannot destroy us and erase the fact of our existence,&quot; he said, calling a strong army &quot;the true basis for the hope of peace.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. envoy Dennis Ross, on his second mission in a month, searched for a formula to revive peace negotiations frozen since Netanyahu's right-wing government broke ground in March for a Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>&quot;The general assessment by military intelligence remains the same: a rise in the likelihood that tensions in the area will slide to confrontation,&quot; Israeli army chief of staff Amnon Shahak told the Yedioth Ahronoth newspaper.</p>
<p>Shahak and other generals were asked in Israeli media interviews if arch-foe Syria might opt for war to break a freeze in its peace talks with Israel, deadlocked over the future of the Golan Heights.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen both words and actions by Syrian leaders...pointing to the possibility of Syria using force to achieve political aims if the path of peace does not succeed,&quot; Shahak told Army Radio.</p>
<p>Deputy chief of staff Matan Vilnai said in the Jerusalem Post: &quot;Since last August, the Syrians have begun to wave the war option. They didn't say they are going to war. They said this is an option and we took this seriously.&quot;</p>
<p>Netanyahu later told Israel Radio that Washington had to be &quot;instrumental&quot; in reviving Israel's talks with Syria, halted by Israel more than a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;They say recently, in recent weeks, that they are interested in resuming the peace negotiations. But time and I suppose not a great deal of time will tell if the Syrians are sincere in their desire to renew the negotiations. If they are, they will find in us a ready partner,&quot; Netanyahu said.</p>
<p>In recent weeks, Israeli newspapers have rekindled memories of Iraqi Scud missiles attacks during the 1991 Gulf War by reporting Syria has acquired a new nerve gas.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands of Israelis poured into military cemeteries to attend ceremonies honouring the 18,538 soldiers who the Defence Ministry said had been killed since independence in May 1948.</p>
<p>Israeli radio stations played sombre music during Remembrance Day on Sunday until sunset when the mood would turn festive for Independence Day celebrations.</p>
<p>Netanyahu went to the Jerusalem grave of his brother Jonathan who was killed in Israel's 1976 commando rescue of hostages held by the Palestinian and German hijackers of an Air France plane in Entebbe, Uganda.</p>
<p>Some Israelis marked the occasion differently. Anti-Zionist ultra-Orthodox Jews ignored a memorial siren on Saturday night and hurled rocks and rubbish at cars along a Jerusalem road they have demanded be closed on the Jewish Sabbath.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
