<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574746" id="root" date="1997-05-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Financial status of S.Korean groups worsens.</title>
<headline>Financial status of S.Korean groups worsens.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-05-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The financial status of South Korea's top 30 conglomerates, or chaebol, deteriorated in 1996 due to their poor business performances, a statement from the Fair Trade Commission said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Combined net profits by the 30 groups dived to 354 billion won last year from 8.46 trillion won a year earlier, the statement said.</p>
<p>Liabilites of the conglomerates rose to 347.82 trillion won last year, up from 272.95 trillion in 1995, while the equity-to-asset ratio fell to 18.2 percent in 1996 from 20.5 percent a year earlier.</p>
<p>The commission statement did not elaborate on the profit figures and government officials were not available to comment.</p>
<p>Analysts have said a sharp fall in the nation's major export items and rising financing costs hit South Korean companies' business performance last year. Export prices for semiconductors, steel products and petrochemical goods declined sharply last year.</p>
<p>Chosun Ilbo said combined net profits of 30 chaebol were 609 billion won on turnover of 356.16 trillion. The figures excluded earnings from non-insurance financial institutions.</p>
<p>The newspaper did not give comparative figures for 1995.  </p>
<p>LG Group topped the net profit list with 360 billion won last year, followed by Daewoo Group with 328 billion.</p>
<p>South Korea's largest chaebol Hyundai Group posted the largest sales of 67.99 trillion won, followed by Samsung Group of 60.11 trillion won.</p>
<p>The newspaper said a total of 13 groups recorded losses last year. Financially-troubled Jinro Group's loss totalled 155 billion won, while Ssangyong Group's loss was 98 billion won.</p>
<p>Jinro's debt-to-equity ratio was the largest at 3,081 percent last year against 2,531 percent a year ago, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>-- Seoul Newsroom (822) 727 5647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
