<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574811" id="root" date="1997-05-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Tens of thousands ready Beirut welcome for pope.</title>
<headline>Tens of thousands ready Beirut welcome for pope.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-05-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tens of thousands of worshippers gathered at a seafront esplanade near Beirut's former Green Line battlefront on Sunday for a mass celebrated by Pope John Paul on the final day of his visit to Lebanon.</p>
<p>Television stations estimated the crowd at 200,000 people more than an hour before the pope was to arrive at the site beside the battle-scarred centre of the capital.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands more lined the road to cheer the 76-year-old pontiff as he drove towards Beirut in his bulletproof Popemobile through Lebanon's Christian heartland after spending the night at the residence of Cardinal Nasrallah Sfeir, the Maronite patriarch.</p>
<p>The mass is the main event of the pope's 32-hour visit, which ends on Sunday evening.</p>
<p>The pope, who received a tumultuous welcome on the first day of the visit, his first to the Middle East, was expected to emphasise his message of Moslem-Christian reconciliation at the mass.</p>
<p>Moslem and Christian militias fought each other throughout the 1975-90 civil war along the Green Line -- a trail of devastated buildings through the centre of Beirut that begins close to the site of the mass.</p>
<p>At a meeting with thousands of young people on Saturday the pope answered the concerns of Lebanon's Christian minority -- many of whom feel marginalised by the pro-Syrian government since the civil war -- by telling them they must change their hearts if they wanted to change their country.</p>
<p>He urged them to build bridges to other communities, not set up new walls to divide Lebanon.</p>
<p>The pope was due at Sunday's mass to unveil a document on &quot;A New Future for Lebanon&quot; summing up the conclusions of a 1995 Vatican synod of Lebanese bishops.</p>
<p>The bishops shocked Moslems by calling after the synod for the withdrawal of 35,000 Syrian troops as well as Israeli forces from Lebanon, and urging an end to political discrimination, torture and other abuses.</p>
<p>The pope's document, intended as the final word on the synod, will be watched closely to see if his views echo those of the bishops.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
