<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574802" id="root" date="1997-05-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Pope praises religious tolerance in Lebanon.</title>
<headline>Pope praises religious tolerance in Lebanon.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Tarnowski</byline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-05-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pope John Paul took his message of Moslem-Christian reconciliation into the battle-scarred heart of Beirut on Sunday, telling a huge crowd that Lebanon was an example to the world of religious co-existence.</p>
<p>Speaking on his first visit to the Middle East, he called for &quot;a just and lasting peace&quot; in the region that would respect the rights and aspirations of all.</p>
<p>The crowd estimated at more than 300,000 people -- more than 10 percent of Lebanon's population -- gave the Pope a massive welcome as he celebrated mass on a seafront esplanade on the second day of his 32-hour visit.</p>
<p>Thousands more overflowed into the streets and tens of thousands lined the Pope's 30 km (20 miles) route to the capital through the Christian heartland north of Beirut in a welcome that surpassed even Saturday's enthusiastic turnouts.</p>
<p>The bulletproof Popemobile was covered in rose petals and rice flung by flag-waving crowds by the time it reached the capital and got stuck for half an hour in the seafront throng.</p>
<p>&quot;Your presence is a motivation for us to continue with the reconstruction process and a sign that Lebanon will become independent, sovereign and enjoy the power of free decision,&quot; Cardinal Nasrallah Sfeir, the Maronite patriarch, told the Pope as the mass began.</p>
<p>Speaking within sight of the former Green Line battlefront where Moslem and Christian militias fought during the 1975-90 civil war, John Paul said Lebanon had an historical mission down the centuries as a country of many religious faiths.</p>
<p>&quot;Lebanon has shown that these different faiths can live together in peace, brotherhood and cooperation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It has shown that people can respect the rights of every individual to religious freedom, that all are united in love for this homeland which has matured over the centuries,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Several Moslem politicians attended the mass, including Sunni Moslem Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri and Shi'ite Moslem leader Nabih Berri, who is speaker of parliament.</p>
<p>Veiled Moslem women could also be seen in the crowd.</p>
<p>John Paul sought to encourage the Christian minority, many of whom complain bitterly of isolation by pro-Syrian governments since the war, but he did not address their specific grievances.</p>
<p>&quot;I am certain that the sufferings of the past years will not be in vain; they will strengthen your freedom and unity,&quot; he told them.</p>
<p>He urged the Lebanese to go forward &quot;along the path of peace and friendliness, with mutual respect for people's dignity and freedom.&quot;</p>
<p>On Saturday, the Pope told a cheering crowd of young people not to erect new walls dividing Lebanon but to build bridges to other communities and get involved in political life.</p>
<p>In what appeared a bow to Moslems who want the Pope to demand the withdrawal of Israeli troops from a south Lebanon occupation zone, the Pope expressed his sorrow for the sufferings of the people of Sidon and Tyre, the main cities of south Lebanon.</p>
<p>&quot;I ask Jesus today to put an end to these sufferings. And I also implore the grace of a just and permanent peace in the Middle East in respect for the rights and aspirations of all,&quot; he said at Sunday's mass.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
