<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574822" id="root" date="1997-05-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: San Francisco suffers hangover from wild party.</title>
<headline>San Francisco suffers hangover from wild party.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Croft</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-05-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>It was a party with a hangover that just won't go away.</p>
<p>A private birthday party last weekend for a San Francisco political consultant featuring live sex acts, strippers and sadomasochism stunned one of the world's most tolerant cities and sent shockwaves through its political elite.</p>
<p>Controversy over the party, attended by many of the city's power brokers, has snowballed, leading some to believe it could jeopardize a drive by the San Francisco 49ers football team to win voter approval for a $100 million city-backed bond measure to help build a proposed new stadium.</p>
<p>Friends threw the party to celebrate the 50th birthday of Jack Davis, one of San Francisco's most powerful political consultants who is managing the campaign for the 49ers stadium plan, which will be put before city voters on June 3.</p>
<p>The invitation list was a who's who of San Francisco's political and sports worlds. Guests included 49ers President Carmen Policy, San Francisco District Attorney Terence Hallinan, California Assemblywoman Carole Migden and several members of the city's governing Board of Supervisors, although a number of them said they left before the controversial acts began.</p>
<p>The invitation, titled &quot;Celebrate a half century of hedonism&quot; promised &quot;Food! Live music! Debauchery!&quot; and it lived up to its word.</p>
<p>The entertainment, according to the San Francisco Examiner, included male and female strippers, a sadomasochist performing oral sex on a female partner and a leather-clad dominatrix who carved a satanic star into a man's back, urinated on him and sodomized him with a bottle of Jack Daniels.</p>
<p>During one act, Board of Supervisors President Barbara Kaufman headed for the exit, moaning &quot;gross ... gross,&quot; the San Francisco Chronicle reported.</p>
<p>After details of the party were splashed across the city's newspapers, San Francisco politicians and the 49ers have been struggling to contain the political fallout.</p>
<p>Mayor Willie Brown, who made a brief visit to the party early but left before the entertainment began, said it &quot;seems ludicrous to even watch such a thing. I can't even visualize how something like that could occur.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, that's not the kind of entertainment that we find entertaining,&quot; the 49ers' Policy said this week.</p>
<p>Supervisor Kaufman received about 20 calls from people appalled that public officials would attend such a party, news reports said. An editorial in the San Francisco Chronicle said the party's  &quot;Caligulaean excesses ... were degrading and disgusting.&quot;</p>
<p>Political analysts said the negative publicity over the party could be another blow to the campaign to win voter approval for the stadium bond measure, which was already facing a difficult struggle.</p>
<p>Amid mounting criticism, Davis apologized in a statement on Thursday. He said the party, thrown for him by some of his friends, &quot;got out of hand, and there were some activities on stage that many people found shocking.&quot;</p>
<p>But he urged people not to let the party affect the stadium plan, which he said would create 10,000 jobs that would bring &quot;hope and economic opportunity&quot; to the depressed Bayview-Hunters Point area of the city where it would be built.</p>
<p>The 49ers propose to build a state-of-the-art, 75,000-seat stadium at a cost of about $325 million, of which the city would contribute up to $100 million, paid for by revenue bonds. The 49ers' owners also plan to finance a $200 million retail and entertainment complex next to the stadium.</p>
<p>Stadium supporters say sales tax revenues from the shopping mall would enable the city to pay off the bonds without putting the city's budget at risk.</p>
<p>The new stadium would also ensure that the 49ers, one of the leading NFL teams, remain in San Francisco for the next 40 years.</p>
<p>Tim Eaton, a spokesman for the 49ers' stadium drive, said the party had had no impact on the campaign and there was no connection between the two. &quot;I'm confident we will pull out a victory,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
