<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="574808" id="root" date="1997-05-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: U.N. official to assess Iran quake damage.</title>
<headline>U.N. official to assess Iran quake damage.</headline>
<dateline>MASHHAD, Iran 1997-05-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A United Nations official flew to Iran's stricken quake zone on Sunday to assess the extent of death and destruction -- the first step for international aid -- a U.N. spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;The United Nations has sent one officer to the affected area to assess the damage and report to the Department of Humanitarian Affairs in New York,&quot; a U.N. spokesman in Tehran told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>The U.N. Development Programme official, Hamid Reza Ghaffarzadeh, was expected to report back on Monday, the spokesman added.</p>
<p>Iran has appealed for international humanitarian assistance to relieve suffering in its eastern provinces struck by Saturday's force 7.1 earthquake in which up to 2,000 people were killed and thousands others injured. Many thousands have been left homeless.</p>
<p>In Washington, a White House spokesman said on Saturday the United States had provided assistance in similar circumstances through international relief organisations but the first step was for the Red Cross, Red Crescent and other organisations to carry out damage assessments.</p>
<p>Asked whether the United States would again offer help through international bodies once damage was assessed, the spokesman said &quot;I certainly wouldn't foreclose it&quot;.</p>
<p>Iran has despatched six C-130 Hercules transports and four helicopters to the quake zone, the head of the Interior Ministry's natural disasters headquarters, Rasul Zargar, said on Sunday.</p>
<p>He said two aircrafts would airlift 80 tonnes of relief supplies shortly.</p>
<p>Zargar forecast inhabitants of 135 villages in the stricken Qaen region would be temporarily re-settled within 48 hours.</p>
<p>Some 2,000 relief workers were assisting victims and 300 units of light and heavy machinery were being used.</p>
<p>Iran Red Cross official Alireza Bokaie said 9,000 tents, 18,400 blankets, 130,539 cans of food, 34,300 kg of rice, 21,452 kg of dates, 220 heaters and 45 tonnes of foodstuffs had been sent to the region.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MASHHAD, Iran"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
