<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575014" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US pipeline expansions spur Rockies gas production.</title>
<headline>US pipeline expansions spur Rockies gas production.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Projects to expand natural gas pipeline capacity out of the Rocky Mountains have spurred exploration and production in the key U.S. basin, producers and pipeline company executives said on Monday.</p>
<p>Five major pipeline projects have opened the gates for a sharp increase in Rocky Mountain production bound for East Coast, West Coast and Midwest markets in the coming years, executives at the Ziff Energy Group conference here said.</p>
<p>&quot;(Drilling) activity levels have really picked up and people are looking for rigs,&quot; said Rob Lindsey, general manager of Western gas sales and transportation for Union Pacific Resources Group Inc's UPFuels unit.</p>
<p>Rocky Mountain production is expected to rise to 5.2 billion cubic feet per day (bcfd) in 2000 and 5.5 bcfd in 2005, up from 4.18 bcfd last year, he said.</p>
<p>That increased production will largely be heading eastward into the Midwest and East Coast markets, much of it on expanded pipeline capacity, including 105 million cubic feet per day (mmcfd) being added to the Trailblazer pipeline and 255 mmcfd on the Pony Express line, he said.</p>
<p>The additional Rocky Mountain production will be competing with increased Canadian exports and surging production from the Gulf of Mexico, where associated gas from deepwater oil exploration is expected to play a large part in rising production levels.</p>
<p>Added capacity for Canadian exports into the United States should boost Canadian producers' share of the U.S. market to 15 percent in the year 2000 from 13 percent last year, Ziff Energy Group President Paul Ziff said.</p>
<p>As a result, by 2000 the differential between Chicago and Henry Hub, the New York Mercantile Exchange delivery point in Erath, Louisiana, will fall to nil and the East Coast differential to the Hub will fall to $0.35 per thousand cubic feet (mcf) from $0.56 mcf last year, Williams Pipe Line Co President Steve Cropper said.</p>
<p>-- James Pierpoint, Houston Bureau ((713 210-8508))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
