<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575256" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER-GERMAN MEDIA SYMPATHISE WITH KLINSMANN OUTBURST.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-GERMAN MEDIA SYMPATHISE WITH KLINSMANN OUTBURST.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>German media sympathised on Monday with a rare outburst from Bayern Munich striker Juergen Klinsmann after he was substituted by coach Giovanni Trapattoni at the weekend.</p>
<p>Klinsmann yelled at Trapattoni and kicked a hole in an advertising sign on Saturday after being substituted for Carsten Lakies in the 0-0 draw with Freiburg.</p>
<p>Afterwards he apologised to Trapattoni and told journalists he had been concerned that Bayern might once again fritter away its chances of clinching the championship.</p>
<p>Bayern stayed at the top of the league table after the embarrassing draw with last-placed Freiburg, but the gap between them and second-placed Bayer Leverkusen, who beat Hamburg 5-0, narrowed to one point.</p>
<p>German commentators said Klinsmann's outburst had been understandable in the context of his poor relationship with Trapattoni. They blamed the Italian for losing his nerve and making a bad decision.</p>
<p>&quot;That such an experienced player as Klinsmann should blow his top in this way can only be partly explained by the humiliating way Trapattoni took him him off,&quot; the soccer bi-weekly Kicker commented.</p>
<p>&quot;Trapattoni's 20 years experience as coach do not mean he is immune to losing his nerves in the decisive phase of the championship.&quot;</p>
<p>The mass-circulation daily Bild said footballers were entitled to outbursts and added it was a sign of Klinsmann's unhappy relations with the coach and the team which he is leaving at the end of the season.</p>
<p>&quot;Not only his frustration about Bayern's chances against Freiburg was behind that kick into the ad sign. He was letting out the fury of an opera diva who runs from the stage offended after a long-standing row with her Italian maestro,&quot; Bild said.</p>
<p>Commentators said the battle for the championship between Bayern with 64 points and Leverkusen with 63 would now on be purely a battle of nerves with three games to go.</p>
<p>The chances for Bayern, riven with internal quarrels, did not look good compared to Leverkusen, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am beginning to think...that Bayern may miss its chance to win the championship in the key phase. If they continue to play the way they did on Saturday this could easily happen,&quot; the Kicker commentary said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
