<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575271" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: ZIMBABWE MONEY RATES CONTINUE FIRM ON MONDAY.</title>
<headline>ZIMBABWE MONEY RATES CONTINUE FIRM ON MONDAY.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Short-term trading rates on Zimbabwe's money market continued firm on the whole on Monday.</p>
<p>Dealers predicted they would hold largely steady the rest of the week, saying the central Reserve Bank seemed keen to maintain a 23 percent ceiling on the rates, which soared in the last couple of weeks on the back of inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>&quot;Rates were shooting up last week but they seem to be stabilising now,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>He added that at a treasury bill auction earlier in the day, the Reserve Bank rejected all bids that came in at above 23 percent. The bank sold Z$460 million worth of the bills out of Z$500 million it had offered the market.</p>
<p>Meanwhile treasury bills were being re-sold on the secondary market at 20 percent while call money eased one percentage point to 19 percent. NCD bills redeemable after 30, 60 and 90 days were quoted at 25 and 20 percent (buying and selling respectively) and bankers acceptance bills were at 24 percent (buying) and 20 percent on the sell-side.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank said the market closed on Saturday in a square position.</p>
<p>--Stella Mapenzauswa, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 7/8/9--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
