<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575227" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA BASKETBALL-LARRY BIRD INTRODUCED AS PACERS COACH.</title>
<headline>NBA BASKETBALL-LARRY BIRD INTRODUCED AS PACERS COACH.</headline>
<dateline>INDIANAPOLIS 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>It was his competitive spirit that brought Larry Bird back from the city where he achieved glory as one of basketball's all-time greatest players to his home state as coach of the Indiana Pacers, &quot;Larry Legend&quot; told a news conference Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody asks me why do I want to do this,&quot; said Bird, who reached a multi-year agreement with the Pacers last Thursday. &quot;I've always been competitive and I've been laying around for five years. I found that 35 was too young to retire. And this is my home state.&quot;</p>
<p>Bird, 40, ends a long, glorious relationship with the Boston Celtics and replaces Larry Brown, who resigned last week and later was named coach of the Philadelphia 76ers. The Celtics named Rick Pitino as their head coach last week.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't want to be behind Rick and the people he brought in,&quot; said Bird, who was a special assistant with the Celtics since his retirement in 1992. &quot;I wanted to be more involved.&quot;</p>
<p>Terms were not disclosed, but various reports put Bird's salary at $4 million per year, with options ranging from entering the front office to partial ownership.</p>
<p>Bird was one of the smartest players in NBA history during his 13 seasons with the Boston Celtics, but he has never held any sort of coaching job.</p>
<p>One of Bird's last duties working for the Celtics was opening conversation with Pitino regarding Boston's coaching vacancy. Pitino accepted the job last Tuesday, leaving Kentucky, and said he hoped Bird would stay with the Celtics as general manager.</p>
<p>Instead, the &quot;hick from French Lick&quot; returned to his roots.</p>
<p>Bird was born in West Baden, Indiana, and was raised in French Lick. He attended Indiana University, briefly, and then Indiana State. He led the Sycamores to the 1979 NCAA title game, where they lost to Magic Johnson and Michigan State.</p>
<p>That game forever linked Bird and Johnson, whose rivalry continued in the NBA and is credited for saving the league from fan disaffection.</p>
<p>Bird won a Rookie of the Year award, three Most Valuable Player Awards and three NBA titles in 13 years with the Celtics before chronic back pain forced him to retire in 1992. He joined the Boston front office as a special assistant shortly thereafter.</p>
<p>Brown left Bird a pretty good starting team even though the Pacers, hit hard by injuries, finished just 39-43 and missed the playoffs for the first time since 1989.</p>
<p>The team features scorers in guard Reggie Miller and centre Rik Smits and has hardworking, productive forwards in Dale and Antonio Davis. Point guard Mark Jackson, re-acquired in February, led the NBA in assists.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="INDIANAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
