<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575202" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL ICE HOCKEY-RANGERS, FLYERS REACH EASTERN CONFERENCE FINALS.</title>
<headline>NHL ICE HOCKEY-RANGERS, FLYERS REACH EASTERN CONFERENCE FINALS.</headline>
<dateline>EAST RUTHERFORD, New Jersey 1997-05-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Rangers and Philadelphia Flyers earned berths in the National Hockey League Eastern Conference finals with victories Sunday.</p>
<p>The Rangers eliminated the New Jersey Devils from the playoffs with a 2-1 road victory on Adam Graves's goal 14:08 into overtime.</p>
<p>In Buffalo, Eric Lindros scored twice in a 41-second span of the second period, including the first successful penalty shot in team playoff history, as the Flyers rolled to a 6-3 victory over the Sabres.</p>
<p>Both best-of-seven series were settled four games to one.</p>
<p>The defending Stanley Cup champion Colorado Avalanche were hosting the Edmonton Oilers in the day's final playoff game. Colorado was up 3-1 in the series to determine the Detroit Red Wings' opponent in the Western Conference finals.</p>
<p>New York eliminated New Jersey for the third time in six years, this time on a goal stunningly similar to the 1994 series-winner by Stephane Matteau over the Devils.</p>
<p>Mark Messier got the puck in his own zone and sent it ahead to Russ Courtnall. He got it down low to Graves, who shook off defenceman Scott Stevens, skated behind the net and beat Martin Brodeur on a wraparound between the pads.</p>
<p>&quot;Mess made an outlet pass for us and I had momentum,&quot; Graves said. &quot;I split the gap, just tried to get the puck and wrap it around. The puck had eyes, so to speak.&quot;</p>
<p>Like the double-overtime goal scored by Matteau in Game 7 of the 1994 Eastern finals, Brodeur unsuccessfully tried a pokecheck, leaving his pads wide open and enabling Graves to deposit it into the net.</p>
<p>&quot;It was pretty similar, a wraparound attempt to the same side. A pretty simple goal when you look at it,&quot; Messier said.</p>
<p>Esa Tikkanen scored his fourth goal of the series and seventh of the playoffs 7:53 into the game to give the Rangers first blood for the fourth straight contest. Wayne Gretzky found Tikkanen in the middle of the ice for a breakaway and Tikkanen snapped a shot from between the circles over Brodeur's left shoulder.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the time of year you want to play, and it feels great to be playing well,&quot; said Tikkanen. &quot;Everybody is doing their job. The forwards, the defencemen and especially the goaltender.&quot;</p>
<p>New Jersey got its only goal on the power play at 12:20 of the second period. Brian Rolston picked off a clearing attempt at the right point and ripped a slap shot over Mike Richter's left shoulder.</p>
<p>Rolston's goal, his fourth of the playoffs, was New Jersey's first in 124 minutes, 36 seconds. The Devils were frustrated all series by Richter, who allowed just four goals.</p>
<p>He finished with 46 saves, including five in overtime, and had a spectacular .978 save percentage in the series.</p>
<p>&quot;It is so important to do the little things,&quot; Brodeur said. &quot;I think we felt we had to be real sharp to beat them. A goaltender can obviously make the difference. I think Mike Richter had our number.&quot;</p>
<p>In Philadelphia's victory, rookie Dainius Zubrus also had two goals for the Flyers, who advanced to the conference finals for the second time in three years.</p>
<p>The Flyers beat the Sabres for the fourth time in as many playoff meetings, preventing Buffalo from advancing to the third round for the first time since losing to Philadelphia in the 1975 Stanley Cup Finals.</p>
<p>Ron Hextall survived a shaky outing in his first appearance of the playoffs for the Flyers, who outshot Buffalo 40-24.</p>
<p>Goaltender Steve Shields, making his ninth straight start for the injured Dominik Hasek, stopped the first 22 shots before John LeClair got his first goal of the series at 5:27 of the second period.</p>
<p>Lindros, held to one goal over the first four games, erupted for two on Philadelphia's next four shots to make it 3-0. He beat Shields on a breakaway at 8:32 and would have had another one if he was not taken down from behind by defenceman Darryl Shannon.</p>
<p>Referee Bill McCreary awarded Lindros a penalty shot and he slipped a backhander past Shields at 9:13 for his sixth goal of the postseason.</p>
<p>Buffalo got the next two goals to climb back in the contest. Michal Grosek scored off a bad-angle rebound at 10:07 and the Sabres went on the power play at 13:24 when Rod Brind'Amour was penalised for interference. </p>
<p>It became a 5-on-3 advantage after a Buffalo request confirmed that Flyers defenceman Janne Niinimaa was using an illegal stick. The strategy paid off when Randy Burridge deflected Garry Galley's point shot past Hextall for his fourth playoff goal at 14:19.</p>
<p>But Zubrus restored Philadelphia's two-goal lead 32 seconds later.</p>
<p>Burridge got his second of the period during another Sabres' power play with six tenths of a second remaining.</p>
<p>The Flyers limited Buffalo to six shots in the final period and went ahead, 5-3 at the six-minute mark on a Lindros shot that deflected off Shjon Podein.</p>
<p>Zubrus found an empty net with 12 seconds to go to seal the victory.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EAST RUTHERFORD, New Jersey"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
