<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575314" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARY'S HORN FLOATS IDEA PF GRAND COALITION.</title>
<headline>HUNGARY'S HORN FLOATS IDEA PF GRAND COALITION.</headline>
<byline>Duncan Shiels</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian Prime Minister Gyula Horn, whose Socialist Party has slipped badly in the opinion polls, called for an anti-extremist &quot;grand coalition&quot; in the run-up to NATO and EU membership after elections next year.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be four or five parties represented in the next parliament and inter-party squabbling should be subordinated to the interests of the country,&quot; Horn told reporters on Monday.</p>
<p>Hungary is currently governed by a strong two-party coalition made up of the Socialists, who have 52 percent of all parliamentary seats, and the liberal Free Democrats, who have 20 percent.</p>
<p>However, following two years of austerity policies which have seen real wages fall by more than 10 percent, both parties lost much of their support and are now trailing two opposition parties, the conservative Smallholders and the Association of Young Democrats, Fidesz, in the opinion polls.</p>
<p>&quot;The coming four or five years will be very inportant because there will be decisions on joining NATO and the European Union,&quot; he said. &quot;We should be open to each other and we should be aware of Hungary's image abroad.&quot;</p>
<p>Horn said he could envisage working with any party which declared itself against extremism but predicted the current centre-left coalition would lead the &quot;national front&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;A future coaliton depends on the parties' platform and their election results, but three years of successful centre-left government show that it should be the determining force in directing this process,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Horn, whose personal popularity is at an all-time low, is also coming under some pressure from inside the Socialist Party, whose social democratic wing last week called for personnel changes in order to deal with a lack of public confidence.</p>
<p>Despite not being named, Horn reacted angrily to the proposal, declaring that he would not allow a change of direction.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as I head the government, I shall not alter its policy,&quot; he said last week.</p>
<p>Asked on Monday whether he would adopt British former prime minister John Major's &quot;put up or shut up&quot; tactic of calling a snap leadership election to deal with criticism from within his party, Horn replied, &quot;That's a good idea. I'll think about it.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1995, Major won comfortably a challenge to his leadership of the then governing Conservative party after calling the poll following repeated criticism of his performance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
