<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57537" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar hurting U.S. car sales - industry spokesman.</title>
<headline>Dollar hurting U.S. car sales - industry spokesman.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. car manufacturing spokesman disagreed Tuesday with an assessment by Commerce Secretary Mickey Kantor on Tuesday that the strong dollar has not affected U.S. car sales to Japan.</p>
<p>American Automobile Manufacturers Association president Andrew Card said a 30 percent decline in the value of the yen over the past year has put pressure on U.S. manufacturers' ability to price their products competitively with Japanese manufacturers.  </p>
<p>Card said at a news conference that if Kantor does not believe U.S. car sales have been hurt by the yen-dollar relationship, &quot;I think that he has missed reality for the last several months.&quot;</p>
<p>Kantor had told an earlier news conference that the strong dollar did not appear to be hurting U.S. car sales to Japan.  </p>
<p>Card complained that the Bank of Japan bought dollars in August and said that central banks should intervene in currency markets only during a crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;Exchange rates that find fluxuations of 30 percent in a year put tremendous pressures on various manufacturers to price their product competitively and produce their product to be priced competitively,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Card said the 1995 car trade agreement with Japan was a good agreement, but complained that U.S. manufacturers were having a hard time signing up dealers associated with the big Japanese manufacturers. The United States set a goal of 200 new dealerships in Japan by the end of the year, but so far only 107, mostly indepedent dealers, have signed up.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreement is a good agreement, but we want the results to reflect the fact that Japan's market is opening up,&quot; Card said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
