<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575452" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Grand Met H1 underlying profits rise.</title>
<headline>Grand Met H1 underlying profits rise.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>British food and drinks group Grand Metropolitan Plc, set to merge with Guinness Plc, said on Monday its first-half, pre-tax profits rose 3.5 percent to 471 million pounds ($765.6 million) before charges.</p>
<p>Grand Metropolitan said the pound's strength reduced its first-half operating profit by about 30 million pounds, while its pre-tax, pre-exceptionals profit was cut by some 28 million pounds.</p>
<p>However, this impact was mitigated by a 12 million pound gain on hedging activities related to its U.S. earnings, the company said.  </p>
<p>The company raised its interim dividend by 6.8 percent to 6.25 pence per share.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength of our food and drinks brands and the clear focus of our management on investing where we can earn good returns, give us confidence that we will continue to make progress,&quot; said chairman George Bull in a statement.</p>
<p>Grand Met said its Burger King fast food restaurants had a first-half operating profit of 69 million pounds, up 4.0 percent in local currency terms.</p>
<p>The company said Burger King's U.S. market share rose in the first half, with same-store sales rising 2.5 percent, although that trend slowed in the second quarter.</p>
<p>Burger King's European businesses posted a first-half operating loss, mainly due to closure costs of 20 stores in Britain and five in Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;The underlying trading performance therefore improved significantly on the second half of last year,&quot; the company said, adding that the outlook for Burger King worldwide was good.</p>
<p>Among its other operations, Grand Met said Pillsbury's reported operating profit rose five percent to 248 million pounds -- representing 10 percent local currency growth -- boosted by improved sales mix and margins in the U.S.</p>
<p>Operating profits for Grand Met's IDV drinks arm rose 5.0 percent in local currency, but its reported profit slipped 1.0 percent to 208 million pounds due to sterling's strength.</p>
<p>Grand Met's shares were marked up 61 pence at 576 by 0715 GMT. ($ = 0.615 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
