<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575480" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada oil and gas stocks stage another rally.</title>
<headline>Canada oil and gas stocks stage another rally.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian energy stocks were pumped again on Monday as strong oil and natural gas prices continued to entice investors into the sector, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Toronto Stock Exchange's oil and gas subindex was up 92.74 points to 6,747 in early afternoon trade after climbing nearly 89 points on Friday.</p>
<p>As was the case last week, Canada's large capitalization oils led the pack with such firms as Renaissance Energy Ltd, Talisman Energy Inc and Suncor Energy Inc enjoying big gains.</p>
<p>&quot;We're seeing the demand come on for summer driving season, which is driving oil prices up,&quot; Matt Janisch, analyst with brokerage Nesbitt Burns, said.</p>
<p>&quot;With (natural) gas prices remaining strong through the second quarter and oil prices bouncing back, I think that's in the near term what's driving it.&quot;</p>
<p>NYMEX crude oil on Monday was trading up 86 cents to US$21.29 a barrel after drifting below US$20 in April. Natural gas futures remained seasonally strong at US$2.235 per million British thermal units.</p>
<p>Janisch said he believed that big cap oils were oversold when Canada's energy sector suffered a correction earlier this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The large caps had all gotten really whacked as the large momentum players sold off in late January. The large caps, I think, disproportionately got hit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>It was still too early to predict whether Canadian oils would test the 7,000 point plateau in the next few months, he said. The oil and gas subindex climbed as high as 6,928 before the correction began in January.</p>
<p>Talisman on Monday was up 1.45 to 44.45, Renaissance climbed 1.70 to 41.25 and Suncor jumped 0.95 to 36.65.</p>
<p>Suncor, the smallest of Canada's four big integrated firms, was trading at 29.28 as late as April 11 (accounting for a two-for-one stock split).</p>
<p>((Reuters Calgary Bureau (403) 531-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
