<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575552" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - May 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - May 12.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Monday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- The National Party's Gauteng executive has been called to meet Roelf Meyer tonight - four days earlier than scheduled - to discuss &quot;options&quot; which apparently include probing whether the Gauteng branch can break away from the national party.</p>
<p>- Pharmaceutical manufactureres are, as a last resort, considering legal action to fight Health Minister Nkosazana Zuma's new medicines legislation, which gives her wide control over drug pricing.</p>
<p>- Laurent Kabila's rebels said on Sunday they were resuming their march to Zaire's capital, Kinshasa, abandoning a pledge to President Nelson Mandela to halt their advance to give diplomacy a chance.</p>
<p>-Independent Broadcasting Authority CEO Harris Gxaweni said on Sunday he was &quot;ridiculed&quot; by councillors when he began enforcing control systems 15 months ago.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- Metro Cash &amp; Carry (Metro) has established a multimillion-rand joint venture with Outspan, the citrus fruit export agent, for the marketing and distribution of citrus fruit to Hong Kong, the Philippines, Thailand and China, Metro sources said last week.</p>
<p>- South African conglomerates Anglo American and De Beers will not enjoy any special privileges in Zaire, Laurent Kabila, the leader of the rebel alliance controlling the bulk of the central African country, said at the weekend.</p>
<p>- Cosatu is to launch a Constitutional Court challengw over the Labour Court's interpretation of the right to strike, the labour federation said on Sunday.</p>
<p>- An objection to Tsogo Sun's rezoning application, submitted by failed casino-licence finalist African Sun International (Afrisun) an hour before the cutt off time on Friday, is expected to delay the opening of the Tsogo Sun's Witbank casino by up to three monoths.</p>
<p>- Bokomo and Sasko, two of the country's oldest &quot;agri businesses&quot;, based in the Western Cape, announced plans on Friday to merge in October this year, but executives played down speculation of a possible JSE listing.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SAKE BEELD</p>
<p>- The gold price began to show life at the weekend as the dollar weakened.</p>
<p>- The ministers of labour from 11 of the 12 Southern African Development Community (SADC) countries meeting at the weekend in Pretoria accepted a code of conduct for the workers with the HIV virus.</p>
<p>- ICS Holdings raised its earnings per share by 21 percent to 190.7 cents in the six months to the end of March despite lackluster consumer spending.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- The growing threat of violent death on Greater Johannesburg's streets has prompted The Star to turn its graffiti wall into a &quot;wall of remembrance&quot; to honour those who have been murdered during hijackings, robberies and other brutal crimes.</p>
<p>- A major security company has launched an extraordinary legal bid to reclaim about 815,000 rand from Josiah &quot;Fingers&quot; Rabotapi, believed to be Gauteng's most notorious bank robber.</p>
<p>- A total of 66 senor public servants who left because of early retirement, dismissal or retirement on medical grounds since May 1995 have been re-employed, some at higher salaries.</p>
<p>- A war of words has broken out between Gauteng Safety and Security MEC Jessie Duarte and the chief of Bramley's police station, the area which has the highest rate of hijackings anywhere in South Africa.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
