<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575747" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - May 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - May 12.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on May 12. Prepared for Reuters by the Co-operation Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- The council of Latvias National Conservative party, LNNK, expelled from the party minister without portfolio in EU affairs and chairman of parliamentary faction Alexandrs Kirsteins, former mayor of Riga Maris Purgailis and three other members.</p>
<p>- About 1,000 hockey fans gathered at Riga International airport to meet Latvia's national hockey team which finished seventh in the world hockey championship.</p>
<p>DIENA</p>
<p>- President Guntis Ulmanis opened the children's social rehabilitation centre in Kraslava, 250 kilometres from Riga.</p>
<p>- The ministry of defence have cancelled the contract with firm Man-Tess to buy 2,900 tons of fuel for military needs and State Secretary of Defence Minister Einars Vaivods has left his post at the request of Prime Minister Andris Shkele.</p>
<p>BIZNES &amp; BALTIYA</p>
<p>- Today the cabinet will discuss the amendments to the state budget to increase expenditures by about 30 million lats.</p>
<p>NEATKARIGA RITA AVIZE</p>
<p>- The number of crimes on railways rose by 19 percent compared to the previous year said the chief of transport police Nikolay Suvorov.</p>
<p>DIENAS BIZNESS</p>
<p>- A delegation of 40-50 Turkish businessmen representing wood processing, construction, fisheries and other areas will accompany Turkish president Suleiman Demirel on his visit to Latvia on June 4-5.</p>
<p>--Riga newsroom +371 721 52 40</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
