<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575842" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia April coffee output 824,000 60-kg bags.</title>
<headline>Colombia April coffee output 824,000 60-kg bags.</headline>
<text>
<p>BOGOTA, May 12 Reuter - Colombia's coffee output in April reached 824,000 60-kg bags, according to National Coffee Growers' Federation figures, a private exporter said Monday.</p>
<p>The figure was higher than the 670,000 60-kg bags production in the same month a year ago, which was abnormally low due to a late harvest, the exporter said.  </p>
<p>The federation forecast total output for the April to June quarter would reach three million 60-kg bags.</p>
<p>But the private exporter, who did not wish to be named, told Reuters he estimated the real harvest for that period would come in as much as 500,000 60-kg bags lower -- at around 2.5 million bags -- given the April result.</p>
<p>The latest federation estimate for production during the 1996/97 coffee year stands at about 10.1 million bags, down from an earlier estimate of 10.4 million bags, compared to a 12.9 million bag harvest the year before.</p>
<p>Production for the first quarter of the coffee year, October to December, was 3.7 million bags. Output in January was 778,000 bags, with 670,000 bags and 500,000 bags in February and March respectively, according to federation figures provided by the exporter.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on the figures so far I don't think the harvest this year will reach 9.5 million bags. I think it will be between 9.3 million and 9.5 million bags,&quot; the exporter told Reuters.  </p>
<p>The federation has said it will draw heavily on stocks and cut inventories from an estimated 5 million bags to 3.5 million bags by September to meet export schedules.</p>
<p>The private exporter, however, doubted the federation currently had 5 million bags in stocks and estimated only 800,000 bags were fresh crop.</p>
<p>He said the remainder was not export quality with 1.5 million bags affected by the berry borer or &quot;broca&quot; and another 1.7 million bags of beans harvested between 1991 and 1995.</p>
<p>(--Karl Penhaul, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
