<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575990" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Western companies reminded: in Asia family comes first.</title>
<headline>Western companies reminded: in Asia family comes first.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian workers are loyal above all to their families, not their companies, and Western managers would do well to remember that, a report made available on Monday said.</p>
<p>The Hong Kong-based Political and Economic Risk Consultancy (PERC) said in a report on managing Asian labour that the issue was not one most Western companies had to contend with at home.</p>
<p>&quot;There is almost no country in Asia where the 'corporate family' is ever going to be as strong a force as the employee's natural family. The latter is the core unit of Asia,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>It said many companies seemed to forget this and developed inappropriate strategies for motivating their employees.</p>
<p>&quot;Companies should not be trying to convince Asian nationals they are recruiting or endeavoring to retain that they are lucky to be part of a great corporate family, but that working for a particular company is the best thing the employee could do to support the interests of his own personal family,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>PERC said it also conducted a survey of 287 expatriate managers in 12 Asian nations during the first quarter of last year. On a scale of one to 10, the 12 countries were rated with zero representing the best and 10 the worst.</p>
<p>It showed that Japan was rated the best in terms of workers' loyalty to the company and the rate of turnover of skilled labour. It scored 2.51 in company loyalty and 2.77 when it came to turnover of skilled workers.</p>
<p>Running second to Japan in both categories was the Philippines, which scored 4.17 and 3.0, respectively.</p>
<p>Hong Kong was rated the most favourable for business in terms of the level of labour activism at a low 1.80 followed closely by Singapore with 1.81 and China with 2.03.</p>
<p>South Korea earned the lowest marks in the region as far as labour militancy was concerned with a score of 7.83 followed by India and the Philippines.</p>
<p>Manila also earned the highest marks in the turnover of unskilled labour, a grade attributed by PERC to the fact good jobs are hard to come by in the country.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
