<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57591" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW-Manpower backs '96 $1.80 EPS view.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Manpower backs '96 $1.80 EPS view.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Manpower Inc chief executive Mitchell Fromstein said he was comfortable with Wall Street analysts' 1996 earnings estimates of about $1.80 per share.</p>
<p>He said the company advised analysts to lower their estimates by $0.05 to roughly that level in a conference call on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We suggested they bring it down to $1.80 for 1996,&quot; Fromstein told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>The reason for the earnings estimate cut was weakness in the French economy. Manpower operations in France generate about a third of the staffing services company's revenues.  </p>
<p>The French economy is weak, Fromstein said. &quot;It looked like it was going to improve in June, July and August, our big months there, and the improvement came. But it just didn't come as strongly as we anticipated,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're still doing very well there. We're gaining market share, but the market itself is pretty flat,&quot; he said. &quot;Because France is a large part of our revenue stream and our profit stream, we thought that the estimates were too high.&quot;</p>
<p>The consensus of analysts' 1996 earnings estimates prior to the conference call had been $1.85 per share, he said.  </p>
<p>Operations elsewhere in the Manpower system around the world are doing well, especially in Japan and the United States, he said.</p>
<p>Shares in the Milwaukee-based firm were off 3-1/4 to 31.</p>
<p>--Kevin Drawbaugh 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
