<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575913" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: FOCUS - Firm NZ policy line underpins dollar, rates.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Firm NZ policy line underpins dollar, rates.</headline>
<byline>Simon Louisson</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand dollar bounced off recent lows on Monday after a rally in interest rates and a surprise statement from the central bank that it felt monetary conditions had eased beyond its target level.</p>
<p>But the Reserve Bank of New Zealand's (RBNZ) firm line depressed the share market. Investors had been clinging to hopes of lower rates to restore flagging corporate earnings.</p>
<p>The key 90-day bill rate climbed back over 7.00 percent to close the day up 26 basis points at 7.10 percent. The dollar's Trade-Weighted Index recovered to 67.91 from 67.65 at the start.</p>
<p>On Monday, the kiwi closed at 0.6940 U.S. cents, compared with the opening of 0.6880.</p>
<p>&quot;I think (the NZ dollar) will head higher. The bank has put a floor under the kiwi,&quot; said a Wellington bank chief dealer.</p>
<p>In the statement, the RBNZ said conditions had eased too much which economists interpreted as meaning any formal easing in the bank's June Monetary Policy Statement will now be cautious.</p>
<p>&quot;We were looking at an easing of 50-100 basis points and the comments from the Reserve Bank suggest they are slightly uncomfortable with 100 basis points,&quot; said Bankers Trust economist Nick Bennenbroek.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like they will be more cautious in the way they ease, so we would be looking for a 50 basis point easing on what they assumed in March,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;(That) is essentially where the market is right now.&quot;</p>
<p>The currency's TWI has backtracked sharply from 69 in the past fortnight since RBNZ governor Don Brash said in an interview the bank was reviewing the appropriateness of its monetary assumptions ahead of June's monetary policy statement.</p>
<p>Debt market players interpreted this comment as a signal of planned easing, and market rates fell below 7.00 percent.</p>
<p>Acting chief manager of the Reserve Bank's Financial Markets Department, Michael Reddell, said in the release that overall monetary conditions appeared to be settling at levels rather too low to be in line with the intended stance of monetary policy.</p>
<p>He said the bank had outlined in March that it preferred 90-day bank bills at 7.5 percent and the currency Trade-Weighted Index at 68, or an equivalent mix. Those assumptions were reaffirmed by Brash on May 7 at a parliamentary committee hearing.</p>
<p>Reddell said that to be consistent with that stance, the bank &quot;would prefer to see conditions firm somewhat, to levels rather closer to the announced desired conditions&quot;.</p>
<p>The result of the policy signal took its toll on New Zealand share prices, undermining sentiment because it implied the bank wants rates to remain relatively high rather than falling further.</p>
<p>The statement depressed a market already troubled over the earnings prospects of many top industrials, partly due to a period of prolonged firmness in the dollar through much of last year, but also due to overall low economic activity.</p>
<p>John Rattray, director of equities at Ord Minnett, said the market would possibly have weakened on the day without the RBNZ's help, but the statement sealed its fate.</p>
<p>He predicted the policy intervention would probably continue to act as a dampener over the next few days.</p>
<p>Bank of New Zealand treasury economist Peter Jolly, looking at the outlook for lower rates, said the statement cast some doubt on an easing in June.</p>
<p>&quot;They might well still lower those desired conditions...but it does beg the question: if they're going to lower them in June, why don't they lower them now?</p>
<p>&quot;It adds to the annals of confusing Reserve Bank statements,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
