<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="575941" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Dlr seen stable in Asia, eyes on official remarks.</title>
<headline>Dlr seen stable in Asia, eyes on official remarks.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar is likely to take a breather against the yen in Asia on Tuesday after recent wild swings, although dealers said they would stay watchful for any fresh remarks from government officials.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/yen is likely to take a rest after such wild movements,&quot; said a trust bank dealer. &quot;The market is likely to spend the rest of this week consolidating the dollar's floor.&quot;</p>
<p>A city bank dealer said selling pressure on rallies may be strong, making it difficult for the dollar to breach 120 yen.</p>
<p>&quot;Operators such as trust banks, securities houses and expporters will take a sell-on-rallies stance,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>The trust bank dealer said that the dollar may have a chance of advancing near 120 yen on stop-loss dollar buying expected above 119.50 yen. Interbank traders have held onto short dollar positions, dealers said.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka, Trade Minister Shinji Sato and EPA Minister Aso Taro are scheduled to hold news briefings in the morning after the cabinet meeting.</p>
<p>The dollar recovered from Monday's low of 117.50 yen partly on remarks by finance ministry officials that the dollar was likely to stabilise soon. Overnight, the mark's weakness in crosses pushed the dollar up against the mark.  </p>
<p>&quot;The mark is likely to carry over a weak tone against the yen and the dollar,&quot; said the trust bank dealer.</p>
<p>A rise in the dollar above 1.7050 marks may signal a move to 1.7100 marks, while support is seen at 1.7000 marks.</p>
<p>The city bank dealer said operators may be comfortable taking short mark positions amid a lack of clear direction in dollar/yen trading.</p>
<p>Sterling gained overnight after remarks from Britain's new Chancellor of the Exchequer Gordon Brown. He said on Monday he had no plans to take the pound back into Europe's exchange rate mechanism. Trading in the pound could be directionless in Asia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
