<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="576012" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China stocks ignore stamp duty hike, rise solidly.</title>
<headline>China stocks ignore stamp duty hike, rise solidly.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's shares leapt up again on Monday, ignoring a hike in the stock trading stamp tax, and brokers said the government was unlikely to introduce serious market cooling measures ahead of the Hong Kong handover.</p>
<p>The Shanghai B index rose 1.663 points or 1.77 percent to 95.794 points, but was off an intraday high of 97.865 points on profit-taking due to market uncertainties, brokers said.</p>
<p>Volume was 32.437 million shares worth $22.180 million.</p>
<p>The strong A share performance was the main factor behind the B share gains, but the continuing surge in the A share markets is increasing concerns about a possible government clampdown, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Recent A share movements are abnormal,&quot; said one broker. &quot;Beijing will not tolerate the over-speculative market.&quot;</p>
<p>The Shanghai A index rose 34.884 points or 2.27 percent to 1,568.999 points.</p>
<p>&quot;The B index will move between 93 to 98 points in the next few days if there is no major negative news in sight,&quot; another broker said.</p>
<p>Inner Mongolia Erdos Cashmere Products was the star on institutional buying to support its new 100 million share issue, surging $0.102 or 9.98 percent to $1.124 on volume of 706,200 shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai Refrigerator Compressor was the most actively traded and become the second-biggest winner on heavy institutional buying, soaring $0.082 or 9.95 percent to $0.906 on volume of 2.5 million shares.</p>
<p>The Shenzhen B share index put on 3.88 points or 2.16 percent to 183.50 on turnover of HK$184.3 million with the A index hitting an historic high of 546.02, up 20.88 points or 3.98 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;People believe Beijing is unlikely to announce market crackdown measures in the short term to avoid a stock market crash around the Hong Kong handover on July 1,&quot; an analyst at China Southern Securities said.</p>
<p>Beijing on Friday announced a rise in the stock trading stamp tax to 0.5 percent from 0.3 percent, but the markets did not even blink at the news on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The A share market rose because the stamp tax hike has been the government's only measure recently to cool the market,&quot; an analyst at Shenzhen J&amp;A Securities said. &quot;People really do not care about it given the bullishness of the market.&quot;</p>
<p>The B shares are likely to extend gains into Tuesday if the A share market continues to surge, analysts said. But they cautioned about the possibility of heavy profit-taking.</p>
<p>On the B share market, Jiangling Motors Corp was the best performer, up HK$0.39 or 9.95 percent to HK$4.31.</p>
<p>On the Shenzhen A share market, hot money was diverted into cheap and medium-priced shares which have performed less strongly than the blue chips, brokers said.</p>
<p>($1=8.3 yuan, $1=HK$7.8)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
