<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="576095" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wal-Mart, Nordstrom profits rise.</title>
<headline>Wal-Mart, Nordstrom profits rise.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wal-Mart Stores Inc. Monday reported sharply higher first quarter earnings, and upscale retailer Nordstrom Inc. reported better-than-expected profits.</p>
<p>May Department Stores Co. and Mercantile Stores Co. Inc. reported lackluster results.</p>
<p>Wal-Mart, the nation's largest retailer, said its profits rose to $652 million, or 29 cents per share in its fiscal first quarter ended April 30, from $571 million, or 25 cents per share a year ago.</p>
<p>Sales rose 12 percent to $25.4 billion.</p>
<p>The Bentonville, Ark.-based retailer said operating profits at its Wal-Mart division, including Supercenters, rose 12 percent to $1.26 billion. Operating profits at its Sam's division rose 5 percent to $189 million.</p>
<p>Its international division posted an operating profit of $6 million vs. a year-ago loss of $16 million.</p>
<p>Nordstrom, an upscale apparel retailer based in Seattle, earned a profit of $32.3 million, or 41 cents a share, in the three months ended April 30, a 25 percent rise from $25.9 million, or 32 cents, a year ago. Net sales grew 5.3 percent to $953.7 million from $906 million.</p>
<p>According to First Call, which tracks Wall Street earnings predictions, analysts had expected the company to report a profit of 34 cents a share for the fiscal first quarter.</p>
<p>Nordstrom Chairman John Whitacre attributed the results to improved cost controls.</p>
<p>&quot;While we have seen a modest rise in sales trends, we are encouraged by improvement in expense control and gross margins that contributed to increased earnings,&quot; he said. &quot;We are beginning to see better results in several of our women's apparel departments.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said Nordstrom sales were in line with expectations, but the company's expenses were below estimates. Per-share earnings also benefited from an aggressive stock buyback programme, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was an excellent quarter,&quot; said Tom Tashjian of Montgomery Securities.</p>
<p>Nordstrom has had a string of weak quarters attributed in part to a change in its merchandising strategy and economic weakness in the West, where it generates most of its sales.</p>
<p>But the regional economy has rebounded, and analysts said the company is taming its merchandise problems.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a nice improvement in the quarter defintely ... but I think there's still some room for them to go in terms of turning things around,&quot; said Dean Ramos of Dain Bosworth.</p>
<p>Nordstrom operates 84 stores in 17 states.</p>
<p>St. Louis-based May Department Stores Co. said earnings declined in its first quarter to $94 million, or 37 cents a share, from $109 million, or 41 cents a share a year earlier.</p>
<p>Revenues rose to $2.59 billion from $2.40 billion.</p>
<p>May also said it plans to open nine Lord &amp; Taylor stores, one Strawbridge's store, two Foley's units, and three Filene's stores in the rest of the fiscal year. May operates 366 department stores in 30 states and the District of Columbia.</p>
<p>Fairfield, Ohio-based Mercantile Stores Co. Inc. said earnings rose in the quarter but called them &quot;less than satisfactory&quot; because of weak results at new stores.</p>
<p>The company earned $19.3 million, or 52 cents a share, in its first quarter ended on May 3, compared with $13.3 million, or 36 cents per share, a year earlier.</p>
<p>Overall revenues rose to $683.3 million from $655.4 million a year earlier. However, sales in stores open at least one year, known as same-store sales, rose only 1.3 percent in the quarter, compared with a 6 percent rise the year earlier.</p>
<p>Disappointing same-store sales were a &quot;negative contributor to this earnings report, which we consider less than satisfactory,&quot; Chairman David Nichols said.</p>
<p>The retailer opened five new stores in the fourth quarter of 1996. Since most newly opened department stores operate in the red for the first year, the five outlets were a drag on first-quarter results, Mercantile said.</p>
<p>Mercantile operates 102 department stores under the names McAlpins, Gayfers, Castner Knott and others.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
