<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="576029" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Asian Metals - China zinc maker frets over high price.</title>
<headline>Asian Metals - China zinc maker frets over high price.</headline>
<byline>Mishi Saran</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A major Chinese zinc producer is worried about higher world prices, with a senior smelter official saying on Monday the jump would ultimately harm China's exports, particularly as Asian demand had weakened.</p>
<p>&quot;For fundamentals, zinc should go up much higher than last year, but we think it's going up too quickly,&quot; said the official from Zhuzhou smelter who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;If the price is too high, later it can be very harmful for zinc,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Attractive world prices already meant big and small Chinese smelters were churning out zinc for export, he said, adding that bigger smelters with LME-registered metal brands were suffering at the hands of smaller smelters who could offer cheaper zinc.</p>
<p>&quot;More and more smelters (will produce) and mines will produce more concentrate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>With supplies abundant, Chinese national warehouses no longer felt the need to hold onto stocks and were aggressively selling zinc in the domestic market to smelters for re-processing and export, the official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We bought over 10,000 tonnes of zinc (from national warehouses), zinc that has been there for 20 years, and we are still negotiating to buy more for processing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The smelter official said prices would average between $1,200 and $1,250 per tonne this year, with prices in August softening in the off season.</p>
<p>Already, it was difficult to sell physical zinc, he noted.</p>
<p>Traders have said demand in Taiwan, South Korea and Japan was weak, with South Korea and Japan already having bought much of the zinc they needed. Domestic zinc concentrate prices were around 30-40 percent lower than imported concentrate, and even though Zhuzhou was not planning to import zinc concentrate, the smelter would consider it if prices came down, he said.</p>
<p>The domestic price of concentrate was between 4,100 and 4,400 yuan ($494 to $530) per tonne.</p>
<p>But some traders reported quite active exports of Chinese zinc, including to India.</p>
<p>One source said his firm had concluded over 1,000 tonnes of Chinese physical zinc exports to destinations all over Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;With this level of London Metal Exchange (LME) prices, they are happy to (export),&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>LME zinc closed on Friday at $1,332 per tonne.</p>
<p>Traders said Chinese zinc ingots could not be found in Hong Kong, but that material cost about US$1,240-1,250 per tonne, FOB China, compared to last week's $1,210-1,220 FOB China.</p>
<p>&quot;There is nothing coming into Hong Kong,&quot; said one trader of zinc ingots.</p>
<p>&quot;China is still exporting, if the price is good. The problem is there are no buyers,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>In aluminium, second quarter demand had improved for China, with many factories buying to process into products for export, traders said.</p>
<p>Copper buying continued, but not in spectacular amounts and traders said if LME prices dropped below $2,290 per tonne China buying could pick up.</p>
<p>Some copper traders said their Chinese customers had sold long positions back to the LME.</p>
<p>The latest Hong Kong indications of premium or discount US$/tonne over LME cash prices on a CIF basis:</p>
<p>			    May 12			May 5</p>
<p>COPPER</p>
<p>    Cathode	     30-90			 20-30</p>
<p>ALUMINIUM</p>
<p>    99.7 pct ingot    100			   95-100</p>
<p>LEAD</p>
<p>    Chinese	     unquoted		    unquoted</p>
<p>ZINC</p>
<p>    99.995 pct ingot  unquoted		    40</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22471">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
