<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="576078" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Energy firms lift Morocco's bourse slightly.</title>
<headline>Energy firms lift Morocco's bourse slightly.</headline>
<dateline>CASABLANCA 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Casablanca stock exchange closed a slight 0.14 percent higher on Monday, with gains in blue chips stocks such as ONA Group, Societe Cherifienne des Petroles (SCP) and oil refinery Samir leading the way, traders said.</p>
<p>The all-share index closed at 670.80 points from 669.83 points on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The energy sector is behind the rise of bourse index... Otherwise many stocks are decreasing, which is a logical consequence of more than three months bullish trend,&quot; a broker at Wafa bourse said.</p>
<p>ONA, the country's largest private conglomerate was up five dirhams at 810 dirhams.</p>
<p>Societe Nationale d'Investissement, the second largest private conglomerate, closed unchanged at 760 dirhams.</p>
<p>Samir refinery, Morocco's main oil refinery, which was privatised last week, rose 9.50 dirhams to 336 dirhams.</p>
<p>SCP was the day's best performer, gaining 88 dirhams to 688 dirhams. The state sold 73.9 stake of SCP and 67.7 percent of Samir to the Swedish-based Saudi Corral Petroleum Holding AB at 473 million dirhams ($50.3 million) and 3.5 billion dirhams, respectively.</p>
<p>In the banking sector, Wafabank closed unchanged at 860 dirhams. Banque Marocaine du Commerce Exterieur dropped seven dirhams to 633 dirhams.</p>
<p>Banque Marocaine du Commerce et de l'Industrie rose 14 dirhams on talk of a possible capital increase.</p>
<p>Most agro-industry firms fell. Edible oil maker Lesieur was down 60 dirhams at 2,490 dirhams, sugar refiner Cosumar down 40 at 967 dirhams and brewer Branoma lost 35 dirhams to 1,275 dirhams.</p>
<p>Total volume traded on the official market stood at 35.7 million from 77.4 million dirhams on Friday. Volume on the over-the-counter market was 31.2 million from 43.6 million dirhams on Friday, a bourse spokesman said.</p>
<p>($1= 9.4 dirhams)</p>
<p>- Rabat newsroom +212-7 72 65 18</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CASABLANCA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
