<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="576016" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Tenaga turnover higher on tariff boost.</title>
<headline>Tenaga turnover higher on tariff boost.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian state-controlled power utility Tenaga Nasional Bhd posted a 26 percent rise in six-month turnover to 4.68 billion ringgit following a boost in average tariffs in 1996 of eight percent.</p>
<p>In a statement released on Monday, the company said it also saw demand growth of 13.5 percent in the six months ended February 28, 1997.</p>
<p>Tenaga said net profit rose to 511 million ringgit for the six months from 370 million a year ago.</p>
<p>It had an operating profit of 626 million ringgit in the six months ended in February 1997 versus 481 million a year ago.</p>
<p>The improvement in its operating profit was mainly due to higher electricity sales, a foreign exchange gain and the tariff adjustment, effective from March 1, 1996, it said.</p>
<p>For the 1997 six months, it reported a four million ringgit foreign exchange transaction gain versus a three million ringgit loss a year ago.</p>
<p>It also posted a 114 million ringgit foreign exchange translation gain for the 1997 six months compared with a 17 million ringgit loss in the prior year period.</p>
<p>It said operating costs rose during the six months mainly due to an increase in average fuel prices of 14 percent and an increase in Independent Power Producer (IPP) purchases of 59 percent compared with a year ago.</p>
<p>Over the half year, its capital expenditure was 3.147 billion ringgit, it said.</p>
<p>Discussing its current year prospects, Tenaga said that &quot;barring any unforeseen circumstances&quot;, it expected its operating profit in the second half of the year to improve.</p>
<p>It said its turnover should improve from electricity sales &quot;given the country's continued economic growth&quot; and the tariff increase effective from May 1, 1997.</p>
<p>Tenaga was granted an average 8.3 percent tariff hike from the beginning of May. -- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603 206 2323)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
