<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="576194" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Washington Rep. Linda Smith bids for Senate seat.</title>
<headline>Washington Rep. Linda Smith bids for Senate seat.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Representative Linda Smith, a Christian conservative swept into office in the 1994 Republican landslide, said Monday she would seek the Senate seat held by Washington Democrat Patty Murray.</p>
<p>Smith, who survived a tough Democratic challenge last year to narrowly win re-election to a second term, said she was driven by her belief in the need for campaign finance reform, lower taxes and less government interference.</p>
<p>&quot;We live at a time when government is trying to control more and more of our lives, and special interests are controlling more and more of government,&quot; she said. &quot;I want to change that.&quot;</p>
<p>In announcing her bid 18 months before the general election, Smith said she would forgo traditional campaign finance methods and refuse to hold fund-raising events in Washington, D.C., or accept contributions from political action committees.</p>
<p>She also said she would not rely on &quot;soft money&quot; donated to the Republican Party and targeted for her race.</p>
<p>Smith, 46, of the southwestern Washington town of Hazel Dell, served in the state legislature for a decade before being elected in a write-in campaign.</p>
<p>Murray, 46, was a self-described &quot;mom in tennis shoes&quot; and one-term state senator from the Seattle area when she rode into office on President Clinton's coattails in 1992.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
