<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="576198" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TWA says mulls more job cuts at Kennedy.</title>
<headline>TWA says mulls more job cuts at Kennedy.</headline>
<dateline>ST. LOUIS 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trans World Airlines Inc may consider cutting jobs at its maintenance center at Kennedy International Airport, a spokesman said Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;It wouldn't surprise me if we ended up in a position where we had to re-examine the manpower staffings up in Kennedy... in terms of maintenance,&quot; John McDonald, a TWA spokesman, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't have anything firm at this point and I wouldn't be able to discuss anything further until notices go out... if they go out,&quot; McDonald said. He declined to give any more details.</p>
<p>McDonald also confirmed the company will send out layoff notices Tuesday to 268 mechanics and workers at the airline's overhaul base in Kansas City.</p>
<p>McDonald explained that during the winter the airline had overhauled more aircraft at the Kansas City base than it normally does, and that the same number of staff were not needed during the summer months.</p>
<p>&quot;We brought in... a far greater number (of airplanes) than we normally would over the winter schedule season to get maintenance done, and now those planes are getting ready to go back out on the line,&quot; McDonald said. &quot;When that work's done, obviously you don't need the extra staff.&quot;</p>
<p>He also said the airline was in the process of modernizing its fleet with planes like the Boeing 757, which he said do not require as much maintenance as older ones.</p>
<p>((--Greg Frost, 816 561-8671))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
