<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57632" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-MANCHESTER CITY ROCKED BY FOUR-GOAL LINCOLN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MANCHESTER CITY ROCKED BY FOUR-GOAL LINCOLN.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Third division Lincoln added to Manchester City's misery with a shock 4-1 English League Cup second round win over the managerless first division club on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Luton beat premier league Derby 1-0 in their first leg clash and Tottenham were held 1-1 at Preston, another second division side.</p>
<p>Manchester City, relegated from the top flight last season and without a major trophy since 1976, looked set for a comfortable outing when German striker Uwe Rosler put them ahead after only four minutes.</p>
<p>But Terry Fleming, Steve Holmes, Dutchman Gilbert Bos and Jon Whitney all replied.</p>
<p>Julian James was Luton's hero with a 26th minute winner.</p>
<p>Michael Holt, a close-season free transfer from Blackburn, netted the first goal of his professional career in the last minute as Preston cancelled out Darren Anderton's second minute opener for Tottenham.</p>
<p>Blackburn scraped their first victory of the season with a 2-1 triumph over second division leaders Brentford.</p>
<p>Garry Flitcroft and Chris Sutton, with his third goal in as many games, netted for the struggling premier league club before Nicky Forster pulled one back for Brentford.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
