<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="576309" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Maine GOs sound investments says - AG Edwards.</title>
<headline>Maine GOs sound investments says - AG Edwards.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Maine general obligation bonds and the state's moral obligation-backed debt remain sound investments for conservative accounts, A.G. Edwards &amp; Sons analyst Patrick Early said in a recent report.</p>
<p>While Moody's Investors Service Inc is reviewing its current Aa rating on the state, Standard &amp; Poor's Corp continues its AA-plus rating with a stable outlook as does Fitch Investors Service Inc which rates Maine at AA.</p>
<p>Maine will face challenges in its next biennium budget cycle to cut expenses, Early said. Tax cuts already enacted is expected to impact state revenues by about $325 million or 18 percent of general fund revenues budgeted for the fiscal year ending June 30.</p>
<p>&quot;This will be a significant reduction which will require additional spending restraint, work force reductions and productivity initiatives,&quot; Early said, adding that while Maine has shown job growth and recovered almost all of the jobs lost since the 1989 recession, the new jobs are in lower-paying sectors.</p>
<p>While manufacturing employment has declined, it remains a vital component of the state's economy, Early said. Gov. Angus King has also made efforts to expand the state's share of jobs in the financial, high-tech and bio-tech sectors.</p>
<p>Noting Maine had been prone to annual cash deficits over recent years that has lead to short term borrowing, the state nonetheless posted a positive cash balance in fiscal 1996, the first since 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;Maine has a low and manageable debt burden with no major capital projects planned,&quot; Early said. &quot;Debt reduction has been imbedded in the state's plans for future issuance&quot; at a level equal to no more than 90 percent of the principal retired in a given year.</p>
<p>He described the state's payment schedule on its debt as &quot;aggressive.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Boston bureau, 617-367-4106))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
