<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57670" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: ZIMBABWE LENDING HOUSE MULLS INTEREST RATE CUT.</title>
<headline>ZIMBABWE LENDING HOUSE MULLS INTEREST RATE CUT.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe's Agricultural Finance Corporation (AFC), the country's main money lender to farmers, said on Tuesday it was considering cutting its interest rates following a similar move by commercial banks in August.</p>
<p>&quot;The corporation is currently carrying out an exercise to review its interest rates to determine if there is any scope for further reduction of these rates in view of the general reduction...by other commercial banks,&quot; AFC chief executive Taka Mutunhu told reporters.</p>
<p>However, he did not say when and by how much the rates, currently at 30 percent for short-term loans and 31 percent for long-term loans, would come down.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe's commercial banks last month cut their minimum lending rates by two percentage points to 30 percent following a fall in annual inflation, pegged at 17.7 percent in August from 22 percent in July.</p>
<p>Commercial farmers in the agriculture-led southern African country have complained that high borrowing rates were frustrating expansion plans while driving several debt-burdened growers off their farms.</p>
<p>Stella Mapenzauswa, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 28/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
