<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="576944" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bearish outlook for range bound palm oil in Europe.</title>
<headline>Bearish outlook for range bound palm oil in Europe.</headline>
<byline>Jim Ballantyne</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palm oil prices look set to remain stuck within a tight downward range during the coming week on the European vegetable oil market, traders said.</p>
<p>Output in Malaysia continues to outstrip demand resulting in declining prices in Europe, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen nothing in recent cargo surveyor data to make us think the market is going to do anything other than go down,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>During the past week nearby crude palm oil has fallen $10 a tonne from $572.50 down to $562.50 a tonne.</p>
<p>Traders said the market is likely to be fairly quiet during the early part of the week ahead of the Malaysia Palm Oil Registration and Licensing Authority's (PORTAL) data for April which is due for release on May 15 and most attention will be focused on the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;July palm oil futures have traded below 1261 ringgit, which is bearish, but on the other hand June olein has fetched $592.50 and $590 a tonne this morning which is steady and can only be due to the weaker dollar,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>Any fall in Chicago soy oil futures is also likely to affect palm oil.</p>
<p>Soy oil futures on the U.S. market have been taking a fair amount of punishment in recent days owing to ideas that soymeal demand would continue to outpace soyoil purchases, leaving a surplus.</p>
<p>&quot;It is really the same old story, palm oil is still too expensive against soft oils,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The tone of the soft oil sector for the coming week will be set by the USDA crop report due at 1230 GMT and by the U.S. weekly shipment figures expected around 1600 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;People will be looking at the carryover figure and waiting to see if hey just juggled around with the data and still came up with a carryover of 125 million bushels,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>Over the past week the general trend in soft oils has been weaker with soy oil down around two guilders, but as in the palm oil market, currency has been a major factor.</p>
<p>Lauric oils prices will continue to be governed by the palm oil sector. During the past week prices for coconut oil drifted $10 lower while in a neglected palmkernel oil market values lost $10 to $15 a tonne cif.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been no change in the supply of coconut oil and prices remain closely link to palm oil,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom, +44 171 542 8062</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
