<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="576968" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey says killed 30 rebel Kurds in clashes.</title>
<headline>Turkey says killed 30 rebel Kurds in clashes.</headline>
<dateline>DIYARBAKIR, Turkey 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey said it had killed 28 Kurdish rebels in clashes in the southeast of Turkey, a statement by the emergency governor's office said on Monday.</p>
<p>The statement said 19 rebels of the Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK) were killed in Bingol province, five in Sirnak and another four in the province of Tunceli. No details of when the clashes took place were given.</p>
<p>Turkish security officials said earlier on Monday their forces had killed a further two rebel Kurds in the main southeastern city of Diyarbakir.</p>
<p>Security forces chased the rebels' car around the city and clashed with them for about an hour on Sunday afternoon in a safe house in Diyarbakir's Bagcilar district, police said.</p>
<p>Three people were detained after the killings in Diyarbakir, police said.</p>
<p>More than 22,000 people have been killed in more than 12 years of fighting between the army and the PKK, which is seeking autonomy or independence in mainly-Kurdish southeast Turkey.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DIYARBAKIR, Turkey"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
