<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="576976" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Quake-prone Iran to &quot;reprimand&quot; jerry-builders.</title>
<headline>Quake-prone Iran to &quot;reprimand&quot; jerry-builders.</headline>
<dateline>QAEN, Iran 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran will reprimand any contractor of government buildings which collapsed in Saturday's severe earthquake and who is found neglecting building codes and standards, an interior ministry official said on Monday.</p>
<p>Rasul Zargar, head of the ministry's natural disasters headquarters, made the remark while inspecting devastation in the nearby city of Birjand caused by the quake, in which 2,400 were killed and 200 villages destroyed.</p>
<p>He told the official Iranian news agency IRNA that one of the reasons behind the collapse of government premises in quake-struck Khorasan province was that contractors did not build them quake-resistant.</p>
<p>Rural health centres, schools and administrative offices were flattened in the quake along with thousands of homes.</p>
<p>Iranian newspapers said earlier Iran was quake-prone and needed to take preventive measures to reduce losses and minimise casualties.</p>
<p>It was not the first time such a disaster had happened in Iran, the daily Iran News said.</p>
<p>&quot;The people, officials and specialists have definite individual responsibilities in this regard,&quot; it said. &quot;We should strive to take preventive measures to reduce the losses and minimise the casualties.&quot;</p>
<p>These should be taken into account in the design of cities, villages, bridges and other structures.</p>
<p>Both Iran News and Kayhan International said Japan's technological experience in building quake-resistant structures should be used.</p>
<p>&quot;Iran is believed to possess the required know-how on seismology and earthquake prevention. But mere know-how is not sufficient, as action is urgently needed,&quot; Iran News said.</p>
<p>Kayhan International, noting scores of tremors including a few major earthquakes were registered each year, said: &quot;It is painful to note that the safety norms are not practiced by builders in the capital, too.&quot;</p>
<p>A second but less severe jolt shook Iran's northwest on Monday in an area where about 1,000 people were killed by a quake in February. There was no immediate word of loss of life or damage in the latest tremor.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="QAEN, Iran"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
