<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="577081" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Merrill Lynch sees record highs for coffee.</title>
<headline>Merrill Lynch sees record highs for coffee.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coffee prices could reach record highs ahead of new crop shipments this autumn due to continued supply tightness, Merrill Lynch said in a bi-weekly report.</p>
<p>&quot;There seems to be nothing to stand in the way of record high prices being attained until the new crop mild coffee becomes available next season,&quot; Merrill Lynch analyst Judith Ganes wrote in the report. &quot;Since both producer and consumer stocks are at low levels and current price levels are not sufficent to curb demand.&quot;</p>
<p>Although Ganes did not specify a price, the highest price on CSCE was 340.70 cents a lb set April 14, 1977.</p>
<p>The report noted that despite record shipments by producers in the first six months of the season, consumer coffee inventories remained low.</p>
<p>&quot;Rather than European and U.S. stocks brimming with beans, inventories have risen only marginally, particularly in the U.S.,&quot; the report said. &quot;In fact, there could be 2.5 million fewer bags of coffee exported from Central America the remainder of the season. This should cause stocks to become depleted.&quot;</p>
<p>Ganes said the supply situation was compounded by production problems in second-largest producer Colombia.</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to think that the Colombian crop will come in short of the Federation's expectations based on production data to date,&quot; the report said. &quot;Lower output is the result of heavy rains and because many trees were not pruned properly in the past several years, reducing the yields.&quot;</p>
<p>The report said sources in Colombia continue to insist there is no fresh coffee available and it is &quot;likely that the Federation will not be making any direct sales to European roasters this month.&quot;</p>
<p>The bi-weekly report contained no production data for Colombia.</p>
<p>Additionally, the report said that while prospects for the upcoming 1997/98 Brazil harvest remain uncertain, most sources continue to expect a smaller yield than this past season.</p>
<p>&quot;While (Brazilian) supply would ordinarily weigh on the market into July, this year the market might deviate from this seasonal pattern because availability of all other coffee will be so sparse,&quot; the report stated. ((--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodity Desk, 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
