<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="577121" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Alaska legislature passes $2.35 billion budget.</title>
<headline>Alaska legislature passes $2.35 billion budget.</headline>
<byline>Yereth Rosen</byline>
<dateline>JUNEAU, Alaska 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Alaska legislature adjourned its 1997 session late Sunday after passing a $2.35 general operating budget for fiscal 1998.</p>
<p>The spending total was $62.8 million less than that in the current fiscal year, leaders of the legislature's Republican majority said just early Monday.</p>
<p>The total comprised roughly $55 million in state agency cuts, a $20 million reduction in state debt obligations and a $15 million increase in required formula spending such as Medicaid, said Rep. Mark Hanley, an Anchorage Republican and co-chairman of the House Finance Committee.</p>
<p>It also included a $164 million appropriation from the state's constitutional budget reserve, a savings account that requires a three-fourths legislative vote to tap.</p>
<p>The reduction met the Republican majority's $60 million goal and is within the coalition's five-year plan to eliminate the anticipated gap between state spending and receipts from dwindling North Slope oil revenues, lawmakers said.</p>
<p>State Sen. Drue Pearce, an Anchorage Republican and co-chairwoman of the Senate Finance Committee, acknowledged that luck helped state budget writers.</p>
<p>Alaska benefited from higher-than-expected oil prices and handsome stock market investments, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not going to turn down windfalls,&quot; Pearce said in an early morning news conference.</p>
<p>The budget included expected receipts from a steep increase in tobacco taxes.  Lawmakers passed a bill hiking taxes by $0.71 a pack on cigarettes and a similar amount on other tobacco products.</p>
<p>The new tax, to go into effect in October, will add to the current $0.29-a-pack rate and give Alaska the nation's highest tobacco tax.</p>
<p>Lawmakers also passed a bill granting a tax exemption to in-state manufacturers of aviation fuel to encourage sales to airlines flying international routes through Alaska.  That bill deleted an existing tax exemption for ethanol-blended gasoline.</p>
<p>The state's Democratic governor, Tony Knowles, gave mixed reviews to the budget.</p>
<p>The spending plan had some last-minute additions that he and other Democrats considered important, he said.</p>
<p>But there were some key items missing, the governor told reporters Sunday night.  He cited such programs as fish and wildlife management and child care for welfare recipients seeking to enter the job market.</p>
<p>Knowles had characterized the legislature's $60 million goal as arbitrary.</p>
<p>He said he was disappointed that lawmakers ignored bills he introduced that would have granted tax credits to companies that employ former welfare recipients, small businesses that make significant capital investments and fishing companies that develop new products and markets for Alaska's abundant salmon.</p>
<p>However, Knowles said he was pleased with the tobacco tax increase, although he had introduced a bill calling for a $1-a-pack hike.</p>
<p>&quot;Kids clearly won on the two-year effort on the tobacco tax, and I applaud the legislature for passing that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He and health advocates have sought for the past two years to sharply increase tobacco taxes to discourage teenagers from smoking.</p>
<p>The tax effort was part of a national campaign to erect barriers to youth tobacco use.  In that, &quot;Alaska does lead the nation,&quot; Knowles said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JUNEAU, Alaska"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
