<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57718" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECH C.BANK GUARANTEES CREDITORS OF AGROBANKA.</title>
<headline>CZECH C.BANK GUARANTEES CREDITORS OF AGROBANKA.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech National Bank (CNB) said on Tuesday that it would guarantee creditors of Agrobanka, following its move earlier in the day to place the bank under temporary forced administration.</p>
<p>&quot;All obligations, including interest payments, which are on the books of Agrobanka's accounting as of September 17, 1996, are guaranteed until their deadline. Those with no deadline ... are guaranteed for 12 months after forced administration ends,&quot; a CNB statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;Obligations which come after the 17th of September which are on Agrobanka's books, are guaranteed until their deadline, but for no longer than 12 months after the forced administration ends,&quot; the statement added.</p>
<p>&quot;This guarantee is given to any value of Agrobanka's obligations.&quot;</p>
<p>Early Tuesday morning, the CNB said it had placed the bank under temporary forced administration after it experienced liquidity problems arising from the failure of Kreditni Banka Plzen a.s. and the investigation of people in the Kreditni case who are also connected to Agrobanka.</p>
<p>In placing Agrobanka under forced administration, the CNB added: &quot;The business of Agrobanka, in all trading outlets, continues as normal. Agrobanka has sufficient capital and reserves.&quot;</p>
<p>Agrobanka is the largest private Czech bank with basic capital of some four billion crowns at the end of last year. -- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
