<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57716" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECH MOTOINVEST HEAD EXITS COUNTRY AMID BANK PROBE.</title>
<headline>CZECH MOTOINVEST HEAD EXITS COUNTRY AMID BANK PROBE.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of the Motoinvest investment group, implicated in the fall of the Czech bank Kreditni Banka a.s., has left the country amid reports another bank connected to the group was in trouble, Czech Television reported.</p>
<p>It quoted officials at Motoinvest headquarters in Prague as confirming that Motoinvest chairman Pavel Tykac, whose colleague was under criminal indictment in the Kreditni case, left the country on Monday evening.  </p>
<p>One official from Motoinvest, an agressive group of investors who jumped onto Czech headlines last year in a series of big takeovers battles with large institutions, was indicted last weeekend on criminal fraud charges for a debt swap scheme which police said led, in-part, to the failure of Kreditni Banka.</p>
<p>In a news conference on Monday, Tykac said the central bank had given its approval to the scheme, and said he knew who was truly responsible for the fall of Kreditni Banka which caused losses estimated at 12 billion crowns.</p>
<p>The Czech news agency CTK said it had received a fax from Tykac abroad saying that he had received indications that he was in danger after the news conference, but the agency said it could not verify the authenticity of the fax.</p>
<p>The Czech National Bank on Tuesday put another bank, Agrobanka a.s. under temporary forced administration due to liquidity problems connected to the fall of Kreditni.</p>
<p>Tykac serves on the board of directors of Agrobanka, in which Motoinvest has a significant stake.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
