<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="577376" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: FOCUS - HUNGARY'S RABA GLOBALISES AS PROFITS GROW.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - HUNGARY'S RABA GLOBALISES AS PROFITS GROW.</headline>
<byline>Ryan Tutak</byline>
<dateline>GYOR, Hungary 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Raba Rt, a Hungarian maker of major bus and truck parts, is continuing a dramatic globalisation drive as it prepares for privatisation and its sixth straight year of profits in 1997.</p>
<p>The company, whose full name is Raba Magyar Vagon -es Gepgyar, is the only large manufacturer in the commercial vehicle industry from the old East bloc to rebound from the collapse of communism.</p>
<p>While behemoths like Russian truckmakers AO KamAZ and AMO ZiL languish with outdated products and overcapacity, Raba has boldly modernised, enabling it to earn 70 percent of its sales from mature markets in Asia, Europe and North America, compared with 20 percent in 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;We went through a crisis in 1991 that required some tough decisions, but we now can achieve our output levels of 1989 with 40 percent fewer people,&quot; Mihaly Horvath, Raba's planning director, said in an interview.</p>
<p>Horvath spoke to Reuters from Raba's headquarters in Gyor, roughly 120 kilometers west of Budapest.</p>
<p>&quot;We also have reoriented our marketing strategies, and we are accelerating investments into new products -- advances in technology are critical to our long-term survival,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Raba hopes its successful transformation will attract foreign investors to help ensure its viability, Horvath said.</p>
<p>And Hungary's privatisation agency APV Rt, which owns roughly 80 percent of Raba, took a long-awaited step toward finding suitors for Raba by signing a contract on Monday for Rabobank International Utrecht of the Netherlands to manage Raba's privatisation, he said.</p>
<p>APV plans to divest of Raba in three stages before 1998, starting with an offering of 26-to-30 percent of Raba's shares to strategic investors in the auto industry, Horvath said.</p>
<p>Subsequently, the privatisation agency will offer 10-to-15 percent of Raba's shares to company employees and the remaining 35-to-44 percent to institutional investors or investors on the Budapest Stock Exchange, Horvath said.</p>
<p>The first stage also will coincide with Raba issuing new shares to raise around $20 million in share capital, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the first stage, no strategic investor will be allowed to buy more than 10 percent of Raba's shares,&quot; he said. &quot;This is to preserve Raba's independence and national character.&quot;</p>
<p>Horvath said he expects strong investor interest, as Raba's financial performance has improved each of the past six years.</p>
<p>At its annual general meeting on Thursday, the company plans to announce pre-tax earnings of 1.0 billion forints on revenue of 27.7 billion forints in 1996, compared with pre-tax earnings of 826 million forints on revenue of 23.7 billion forints in 1995, Horvath said.</p>
<p>In 1991, Raba's first year of profitability after a protracted crisis, the company earned 75 million forints on revenue of 17.2 billion forints.</p>
<p>But Raba's future looks even brighter, he said, adding the company forecast its net profit to reach 1.2 billion forints on revenue of 33.3 billion forints in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect definite improvements in our profits over the next five years,&quot; Horvath said. &quot;We are committed to success.&quot;</p>
<p>Raba's main source of income will continue to be the United States, where the company is Hungary's top exporter, generating sales of over $100 million in 1996 and 1995, he said.</p>
<p>The company now earns over 50 percent of its income from America, up from 20 percent in 1989, by supplying axles and axle parts to several multinational companies, including Case Corp and the world's three biggest axle manufacturers -- Dana Corp , Eaton and Rockwell International .</p>
<p>Raba also is expanding to the Far East, where it is selling parts for the first time this year to Japan and Korea, he said.</p>
<p>Customers include Isuzu Motors Ltd and Nissan Motor Co Ltd of Japan as well as Daewoo Group, Hyundai Motor Co Ltd  and Ssangyong Group of Korea.</p>
<p>Raba also is winning new business close to home. Most notably, it is starting to supply Mercedes-Benz AG for the first time this year with front and rear axles for low-floor buses, Horvath said.</p>
<p>&quot;We now supply around 70 countries,&quot; Horvath said. &quot;In the next five years, we want to focus our efforts to generate around the same amount of income from four core business areas -- Asia, the United States, eastern Europe and western Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GYOR, Hungary"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
