<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="577414" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek shares gain 1.6pct on upbeat construction	   Greek sh.</title>
<headline>Greek shares gain 1.6pct on upbeat construction	   Greek sh.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Momentum carried over from Friday in construction propelled Greek shares closer to the 1,600 level on Monday.</p>
<p>The Athens bourse's benchmark index settled 1.65 percent or 25.95 points higher at 1,595.54, from Friday's close of 1,569.59.</p>
<p>It opened at 1,576.19, recording an intra-day high of 1,597.60, which is also a new year high, at the early stages of trading.</p>
<p>Construction were up 2.62 percent, followed by industrials and banks which firmed 1.90 percent and 1.55 percent respectively.</p>
<p>Friday's press reports of a new EU financial aid package for Greece in the 2000-2005 period continued to pull construction stocks higher, leading the broader market, analysts said.</p>
<p>The market was becoming stronger as funds were finding their way across the board, narrowing price imbalances between large cap banks and industrials on the one side and small and medium caps on the other, the analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is on a clear upward channel. Shifting buying interest into all sectors besides banks and industrial blue chips provide greater support and expand the market's upside potential,&quot; said Iakovos Diamantopoulos, analyst at Hermes Brokerage.</p>
<p>A correction in prices will inevitably be realised, but the market's momentum suggests that this will have to wait for a while, he added.</p>
<p>Diamantopoulos said the 1,600 level was a mere way-point to the real psychological barrier of 1,684 points, recorded seven years ago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
