<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="577484" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Grand Metropolitan, Guinness in mega-merger.</title>
<headline>UK's Grand Metropolitan, Guinness in mega-merger.</headline>
<byline>Tim Farrand</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grand Metropolitan Plc and Guinness Plc on Monday announced a merger worth more than 20 billion pounds ($32.5 billion) to create the world's seventh largest food and drinks company, GMG Brands.</p>
<p>The merger will also form the world's leading branded spirits and wine company with combined spirits sales of over 100 million cases a year, bringing together brands such as GrandMet's Smirnoff vodka and Cinzano with Guinness-owned Johnnie Walker whisky and Gordon's gin.</p>
<p>It also unites GrandMet's strong U.S. food interests through Burger King and Pillsbury with Guinness' brewing operations which include its famous stout ale.</p>
<p>Shares in the two companies surged after the surprise news as investors and analysts looked to cost savings from the deal as well as a planned one-off cash handout to shareholders of 60 pence per share worth some 2.4 billion pounds.</p>
<p>GrandMet shareholders will own 52.7 percent of GMG under the deal, which is structured so that Guinness shareholders retain their shares in the renamed company, while GrandMet shareholders will receive one GMG share for every GrandMet share they hold.</p>
<p>On Friday's share prices, the combined value of the group was 20.61 billion pounds, making it the seventh largest food and drinks company worldwide and Britain's eight largest quoted company.</p>
<p>But the value of the deal was boosted to around 23 billion pounds in early Monday trading as GrandMet shares rose 57 pence to 572 after touching 585 and Guinness shares jumped 67 pence to 583-1/2 after also hitting a high of 585.</p>
<p>&quot;We have brought together two highly successful British-based companies which own some of the world's leading consumer brands, creating a powerful group comprising four world class branded businesses,&quot; said George Bull, GrandMet chairman.</p>
<p>He will initially chair the new group jointly with Tony Greener of Guinness, but will retire as planned in July 1998, leaving Greener as sole chairman.</p>
<p>GrandMet's John McGrath will be chief executive, with the rest of the board made up of a balance of directors from both firms.</p>
<p>Bull told reporters the move would, &quot;create a combined spirits and wine company which will truly be a world leader so it will be able to grow faster at that stage than either would be able to do on its own.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If you put the whole lot together then you achieve a much faster growth rate together than either could achieve on their own,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>GMG Brands' four divisions will be United Distillers and Vintners, the combined spirits and wines business, Pillsbury, Burger King and Guinness Brewing Worldwide.</p>
<p>The merger gives Guinness an increased interest in North America through GrandMet's Pillsbury and Burger King food divisions, while GrandMet shareholders will benefit from the Guinness spirits business in emerging markets.</p>
<p>Pilsbury brands include Green Giant vegetables and Haagen-Dazs ice cream.</p>
<p>Guinness stout is one of the world's most widely distributed beers, brewed in 50 countries and sold in about 150.</p>
<p>The companies said the merger, which needs approval from regulatory authorities as well shareholders, would generate cost savings of about 175 million pounds a year in the third year of trading by integrating the sales force around the world, pruning back at head offices and savings in production.</p>
<p>The companies did not detail possible job losses, but Guinness chairman Tony Greeener told BBC radio it was possible there would be around 2,000 job losses out of a combined workforce of 85,000.</p>
<p>The losses wold be distributed around the world and take place gradually over three years, he said.</p>
<p>Total costs of achieving these savings are expected to be some 375 million pounds, of which 300 million would be cash and the balance accounting writedowns.</p>
<p>GrandMet brought forward its first-half results to coincide with the merger news. Pre-tax profit rise by 3.5 percent to 471 million pounds before charges.</p>
<p>($ = 0.615 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
