<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="577489" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Euro oil products outlook - Post-holiday pickup.</title>
<headline>Euro oil products outlook - Post-holiday pickup.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil product trading in Europe will return to more normal patterns after last week's public holidays disrupted business.</p>
<p>Traders complained last week of jerky price movements and a lack of clarity and said they were looking forward to a pick-up in activity this week. Much will depend on whether crude holds the strength it picked up late last week, they added.</p>
<p>Gasoline prices will stay broadly steady unless U.S. demand picks up. &quot;The arb is not quite open,&quot; said a trader at a major oil company who regularly sells to the United States.</p>
<p>He saw the price difference between Rotterdam May barges and June NYMEX at slightly too narrow to allow widespread movement of gasoline to the U.S.</p>
<p>&quot;It's about $22 (a tonne) at the moment but most refiners in Rotterdam and the U.K. east coast need $23,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>European demand remains sluggish with only modest interest in Germany and no big movement of gasoline down to West Africa.</p>
<p>Gas oil supplies in Europe are expected to improve with fair refinery margins and the completion of Med refinery turnarounds leading to increased output.</p>
<p>In the Mediterranean the arb to Asia is shut making more gas oil available and pressuring premiums. Rising supplies will be countered by the Syrian tender awarded last week for four 25,000 tonne cargoes delivered end-May to end-June and Turkey's purchase of two 25,000 tonne cargoes for end-May.</p>
<p>Premiums for less-sought after 0.2 pct Russian cargoes are down to fob high +$1-1.50 and should hold steady, traders said.</p>
<p>EN590 appears well supplied. Premiums have been knocked to fob high EN590 quotes +$2 and could drop further.</p>
<p>Agricultural demand has limited Russian gas oil exports and this should limit the pressure exerted on premiums.</p>
<p>Naphtha has been bolstered by recent crude gains, but its immediate outlook is less rosy with slack local demand.</p>
<p>Fuel oil has pepped up after weeks of trading sickly in a narrow range, with stronger Singapore physical markets and U.S. buying of European swaps pushing it up.</p>
<p>But the enthusiasm was thinly founded, traders said, and barge prices will likely sink back towards $80 once all the players have returned to their desks.</p>
<p>Traders will continue to look for ways to move oil out of the region as local demand for both low and high sulphur is weak and Asia appears to be a profitable sink for bunker fuel.</p>
<p>Much of the Mediterranean high sulphur supply was soaked up last week with a spate of deals, some connected to Far East arb projects. But Russian resid material continues to appear there, though buying interest is limited.</p>
<p>After a flurry of low sulphur deals two weeks ago supply will be tight for cargoes in Europe into the last third of May.</p>
<p>The big imponderable for fuel oil markets, traders said, was the effect of the expected flood of summer Russian material due to pour out by the end of this month.</p>
<p>Predicted export figures are high, with bunker markets expected to be saturated. Some traders were predicting a sharp price fall once the extent of the flow becomes clear, unless there is an appetite in other regions for the product.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
