<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="577605" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Dlr takes breather at Tokyo noon after sharp fall.</title>
<headline>Dlr takes breather at Tokyo noon after sharp fall.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar took a breather against the yen at the Tokyo midday after it extended heavy losses and hit a nearly four-month low of 117.50 yen in early trade.</p>
<p>Japanese finance ministry officials' apparent efforts to put a brake on the dollar's dive by over six yen since Friday also prompted short-covering by traders and active purchases by Japanese importers on the downside, dealers said.  </p>
<p>Japan's Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka told reporters on Monday that the dollar is likely to settle down soon as the Group of Seven (G7) industrialised nations' statement on foreign exchange rates is digested by foreign exchange markets.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the message of the G7 nations' agreement on foreign exchange rates is gradually getting through to the market,&quot; Mitsuzuka said.</p>
<p>A senior Japanese bank trader said: &quot;In the face of the dollar's rapid fall in the past few days and the weakness of Tokyo stocks in early trade, the ministry apparently eased its stance on talking the dollar down.&quot;  </p>
<p>Asked over the weekend if a nearly six-yen rise against the dollar over the previous week was excessive, Finance Ministry official Eisuke Sakakibara, known as &quot;Mr Yen&quot; for his influence over currency markets, said: &quot;No, it is not overly excessive.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar dived in early trade on Monday on the remark, amid an absence of buyers in thin conditions. But Sakakibara said on Monday the dollar is likely to stabilise soon.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the dollar's fall by 10 yen from its recent high, their campaign to push the dollar down was successful,&quot; said a dealer at a European bank. &quot;They may be happy if the dollar stays in a 115 to 120 yen range,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>&quot;The dollar might have found its short-term bottom at around 117.50 yen, but its recovery was slow,&quot; said a senior dealer at a Japanese bank.</p>
<p>A dealer a German bank said it was unclear if the dollar had hit its near-term bottom and the dollar's direction could still be subject to remarks be monetary officials.</p>
<p>Active buying by Japanese importers and purchases by U.S. funds and some Japanese life insurers on falls gave support to the dollar. Japanese trust banks and Japanese securities houses, meanwhile, remained keen to sell dollars, preventing the greenback from recovering to 119 yen.  </p>
<p>Dealers said Japanese securities houses who have sold investors high-risk dual currency bonds with options may need to sell dollars for yen on behalf of those investors because of the dollar's fall.</p>
<p>Stop-loss dollar sales related to such bond investments had been triggered at several points, including 119 yen, with a relatively large amount of stops seen at 115 yen, dealers added.</p>
<p>--Tatsuo Ito 81-3-3432-1396</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
