<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57777" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Cuba says U.S. law not biting too hard.</title>
<headline>Cuba says U.S. law not biting too hard.</headline>
<byline>Frances Kerry</byline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The controversial Helms-Burton law aimed at curbing foreign investment in Cuba has not sent overseas companies packing and the Canadian government has introduced a bill to counter it, Havana officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Cuba's Foreign Investment Minister Ibrahim Ferradaz told a Havana conference on the law that so far &quot;the general reaction of investors who are present in Cuba has been positive, none have withdrawn.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that despite the law, in the first eight months of this year some 40 new associations with foreign firms had been signed, more than for the same period in 1985. He did not give details of the projects or of the money involved.</p>
<p>&quot;What better sign that foreign investors are independent and do not fear threats from the empire (the United States) than these figures?&quot; Ferradaz asked.</p>
<p>He said some 100 new investment projects were currently being evaluated, in addition to the island's total of 240 economic associations and joint ventures already in place.</p>
<p>The Helms-Burton law, passed by President Bill Clinton in March, added to the longstanding U.S. embargo and included measures to punish third country companies deemed to be &quot;trafficking&quot; in property confiscated after Cuba's 1959 revolution.</p>
<p>Ferradaz admitted that the six-month-old law could hurt by raising fears among potential investors and causing them to delay business with Cuba. But he said Cuba understood such fears and would help firms defend themselves.</p>
<p>By targeting foreign investors, he said even the United States had recognised there was international interest in doing business on the island.</p>
<p>Ferradaz was speaking at a meeting organised by a Cuban investment consultancy aimed at outlining Helms-Burton and its impact on current and potential investors. Speakers also included lawyers from the United States, Spain and Belgium.</p>
<p>The law has been widely criticised by countries such as Mexico, Canada and the European Union members, which were at varying stages of preparing measures to counter the law.</p>
<p>The Canadian government on Monday introduced a bill that would allow Canadians to countersue in Canada's courts to recover damages awarded by U.S. courts under Helms-Burton. It would also allow Canada to issue &quot;blocking&quot; orders so that judgments handed down under any objectionable foreign law would not be enforced or recognised in Canada.</p>
<p>The move is similar to measures being considered by the European Union's foreign ministers to limit the effects both of Helms-Burton and a second U.S. law, the D'Amato legislation, which targets Iran and Libya.</p>
<p>Under one of Helms-Burton's provisions, U.S. citizens and companies are allowed to sue foreign firms using property confiscated after the revolution. Another provision allows for the barring from the United States of senior executives and shareholders of such companies.</p>
<p>Clinton has waived the measure for six months allowing suits against foreign firms. But the provision to bar senior officials of selected companies from the United States is already in effect and has started to be applied.</p>
<p>In his address, Ferradaz reiterated current official sentiment that Cuba has overcome the worst of economic crisis caused by the collapse of the former Soviet Union, while admitting that the communist-ruled island remains squeezed for foreign currency.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
