<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="577843" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - May 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - May 12.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Thai press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>TOP STORIES</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh will oversee economic affairs to shore up confidence in the government's handling of the economy and to ease criticisms against the Finance Ministry. The Chart Pattana Party - the second largest in the coalition - is said to be unhappy with the way the economy is being run, as is the opposition. (BANGKOK POST) (THE NATION)</p>
<p>- Most senators say more than 120 days are needed to draw up and pass three laws associated with the constitution. The senators, who have been attending a seminar in Kanchanaburi province to discuss the charter, say they cannot agree with the timeframe set in Article 329 of the draft constitution. Three new laws, concerning the election, election commission and political parties, must be completed within 120 days of the introduction of the new constitution. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>- Business interests are to appeal to the prime minister to oppose land expropriation for the third-stage expressway project of the Expressway and Rapid Transit Authority (ETA), which they say will derive them of their property. Leader of the private parties says ETA has adjusted the expressway's route three times to avoid the property of a few &quot;senior figures&quot;, and the latest route change happens to affect the property of 2,000 villagers, a college and other businesses. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>	 + + + +</p>
<p>BUSINESS</p>
<p>- The Industrial Estate Authority of Thailand's (IEAT) Small Power Producer (SPP) program is likely to collapse because the Electricity Generating Authority of Thailand (EGAT) is unable to cooperate. IEAT introduces the plan with the aim of making its industrial estates more attractive to potential investors by providing on-site electricity. (BUSINESS DAY)</p>
<p>- More companies are issuing short-term bonds to fund expansion, having found that long-term bonds no longer appeal to investors, says executive vice-president of Thai Farmers Bank. The trend is in line with the economic slowdown with companies concerned that long-term bonds might not sell out because the market does not want to take higher risks in the future. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
