<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="577809" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Indian rupee currently at right level - Chidambaram.</title>
<headline>Indian rupee currently at right level - Chidambaram.</headline>
<dateline>FUKUOKA, Japan 1997-05-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Finance Minister Palaniappan Chidambaram said on Sunday the rupee was currently at the right level and he saw no need for intervention.</p>
<p>Asked to comment on the view of some analysts that the rupee was overvalued and should be weakened, Chidambaram told Reuters Financial Television &quot;No, I do not think we should induce a depreciation just to boost someone's confidence. Once you say the rupee will find its level in the market, then you must leave it to the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Chidambaram is in the southern Japanese city of Fukuoka to attend the annual meeting of the Asian Development Bank.</p>
<p>Asked about the Reserve Bank of India's (RBI) stance on the rupee, Chidambaram said: &quot;The RBI is not intervening indiscriminately. Within a band it allows the rupee to fluctuate and it's only when it goes beyond the band does the RBI intervene.&quot;</p>
<p>Foreign exchange inflows were strong and India had to find ways to use it.</p>
<p>&quot;One way is to liberalise imports and if industry picks up as I expect it to, then there will be larger capital goods imports which will absorb much of that foreign exchange,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Only if it becomes volatile, then the bank should intervene. &quot;Today I think the rupee has found its level and moves within a band.&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FUKUOKA, Japan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
