<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="577994" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: PRESS DIGEST - GERMANY - MAY 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GERMANY - MAY 12.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Monday morning's German newspapers:</p>
<p>FRANKFURTER ALLGEMEINE ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- Labour Minister Norbert Bluem and leaders of the liberal Free Democrats want compromise in reform of the pension system. But opposition SPD leader Oskar Lafontaine says this would only be a media stunt, while some members of his party considers meeting members of Chancellor Helmut Kohl's coalition for talks</p>
<p>- All the signs point to another strike in the construction industry. Unions will decide on industrial action today. Labour Minister Norbert Bluem warns there could be heavy job losses</p>
<p>- Only a few unanswered questions about the sale of Bewag. Kohl's CDU and opposition SPD which rule Berlin in a grand coalition can still not decide on how to sell the facility</p>
<p>- Bank workers' pay talks will go onto a second round</p>
<p>HANDELSBLATT</p>
<p>- Export boom will secure jobs. Companies drag their heels over expanding their capacities. The auto and electronics industries will profit from a good export economy. The firms employ personnel but do not invest in building up capacities.</p>
<p>- Construction sector is on point of going on strike</p>
<p>- In new row over space industry, it is not clear who will be Chancellor Helmut Kohl's oordinator for this field</p>
<p>- Speculation about a new budget shortfall after announcement that unemployment will be about 120,000 more than expected this year</p>
<p>- Energy consensus. Environmental Minister Angela Merkel sees chances for a compromise with opposition Social Democrats(SPD)</p>
<p>- The liberal Free Democrats (FDP) are prepared for talks on pension reform, after FDP Hermann Otto Solms parliamentary leader said such talks could produce results, but SPD leader Oskar Lafontaine rejected talks with the coalition</p>
<p>- HBV white collar workers union wants a 35-hour week and no cuts in sick pay in pay talks</p>
<p>SUEDDEUTSCHE ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- Fines for indebted regional states. Bavaria and Hesse demand state agreement for the introduction of the euro. The two states' finance ministers want to force big-spending states to accept financial strictures ahead of euro launch in 1999</p>
<p>- German construction sector is on point of going on strike for first time since 1950</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel wants to make it more attractive for Bosnian refugees to return home. He presents new concept of how repatriation should be carried out</p>
<p>- Bundesbank says Germany as a financial centre has a good competitive position before the start of Europe's single currency, the euro</p>
<p>- If Transrapid fails for political reasons the German government will have to cover the costs of damage</p>
<p>- Cable networks attack Deutsche Telekom saying that if it doesn't build up its networks more quickly it will lose millions of cable clients</p>
<p>- SAP wants to ban its employees from trading in company shares after prosecutors opened investigation into suspected insider trading there</p>
<p>- DIE WELT</p>
<p>- Opposition Social Democrats (SPD) leadership split over tax reform. Lower Saxony premier Gerhard Schroeder and Rhineland-Palatinate premier Kurt Beck both of the SPD want to meet Chancellor Helmut Kohl's coalition for talks. But SPD leader Oskar Lafontaine questions government's plans to reform pension system</p>
<p>- It looks like construction workers will go on strike. Crisis in the construction sector. Battle for jobs in construction sectors draws closer. Industry appeals to unions</p>
<p>- Government expected 120,000 more unemployed in 1997 than it forecast at the beginning of the year</p>
<p>- Lower Saxony premier Gerhard Schroeder unleashes new row about energy consensus talks -- Bonn Newsroom +49 228 26097160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
