<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="577929" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian Telenet to start in 1998, CEO says.</title>
<headline>Belgian Telenet to start in 1998, CEO says.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian telecommunications group Telenet, which aims to convert Flanders' cable television network to provide multimedia and voice telephone services, will become operational in 1998, its chief executive officer said.</p>
<p>&quot;We prefer to keep a low profile, because Telenet has nothing to offer at the moment. It is not until 1998 that we will offer our first services,&quot; Telenet CEO Paul Van der Spiegel told Belgian daily Le Soir in an interview.</p>
<p>He added, however, that a limited number of clients in the Flemish towns of Antwerp and Mechelen could be offered trial Internet services in autumn 1997.</p>
<p>He also said that it would take another four and a half years before all Flemish homes would be connected to its fibre-optics network.</p>
<p>Once the Flemish network is operational, Telenet will also start marketing its services in Brussels and in Wallonia.</p>
<p>Telenet has no ambition to become the operator of a third mobile telephone network, Van der Spiegel said. Belgium is expected to offer a third mobile phone licence next year.</p>
<p>Telenet Operaties NV is a unit of Telenet Holding NV, which is 25 percent-owned by U.S. West International and 20 percent by Flander's publicly-owned investment company GIMV.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6813, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
