<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="578105" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Retailers report earnings that exceed expectations.</title>
<headline>Retailers report earnings that exceed expectations.</headline>
<byline>Melissa George</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four large clothing retailers -- J.C. Penney Co. Inc., Dillard Department Stores Inc., TJX Cos. Inc. and Lands' End Inc. -- posted first quarter results Tuesday that exceeded Wall Street's expectations, aided by fewer merchandise markdowns and strong sales.</p>
<p>J.C. Penney's earnings fell about 2 percent to $139 million, or 53 cents a share, from $142 million, or 57 cents a share, in the first quarter of last year.</p>
<p>Still, the results exceeded Wall Street analysts' forecast of 50 cents a share, according to First Call, which tracks earnings estimates. Penney's sales for the three months rose 44 percent to $6.7 billion from $4.6 billion a year ago.</p>
<p>Plano, Texas,-based Penney's earnings were hurt by weak performance at its core department stores and costs of swallowing drug store giant Eckerd Corp., which Penney acquired for $3.3 billion during the quarter.</p>
<p>The company said operating profits at its Eckerd division rose 30 percent in the first quarter. The integration of Eckerd has met expectations so far, it added.</p>
<p>&quot;The earnings were a little better than consensus estimates,&quot; said Patrick McCormack of Alex. Brown &amp; Sons Inc.</p>
<p>Little Rock, Ark.-based Dillard said earnings rose 3 percent to $58.3 million, or 52 cents a share, from $56.4 million, or 50 cents a share, in the first quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>Sales increased to $1.52 billion from $1.45 billion a year earlier. Analysts had forecast Dillard's earnings per share would be flat in the first quarter, according to First Call.</p>
<p>Framingham, Mass.,-based TJX Cos. Inc. said net income rose 61 percent to $48.5 million, or 54 cents a share, from $30.1 million, or 33 cents a share, in last year's first quarter. Sales rose to $1.56 billion from $1.47 billion.</p>
<p>The earnings were above Wall Street's consensus estimate of 51 cents a share.</p>
<p>The discount retailer said combined profits at its off-price apparel chains T.J. Maxx and Marshalls stores climbed by 62 percent during the first quarter. TJX acquired Marshalls from Melville Corp. for $606 million in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;The combined buying power of these two divisions, as well as expense savings resulting from the consolidation of Marshalls, were the two major drivers of the substantial year-over-year gains in this first quarter,&quot; said TJX President Bernard Cammarata.</p>
<p>Dodgeville, Wis.-based catalog retailer Lands' End Inc. said net income rose to $11.3 million, or 35 cents a share, in the first quarter, including a $4.7 million gain from the sale of The Territory Ahead, a catalog company.</p>
<p>Minus the gain, earnings rose by 50 percent to $6.6 million, or 20 cents per share, from $4.4 million, or 13 cents a share, in the first quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>Sales rose 15 percent to $245 million.</p>
<p>Analysts had forecast Lands' End earnings would rise to 17 cents a share.</p>
<p>Strong sales of higher-priced merchandise and good terms with suppliers added to Lands' End's earnings, analysts said.</p>
<p>Like other retailers, Lands' End did not load up on too much inventory this year and was able to avoid the wrath of clearance sales that ate up profits at many chains last year.</p>
<p>&quot;A year ago, (retailers) probably came into Christmas with too much inventory and had to take markdowns in the first quarter,&quot; said Kevin Silverman of Everen Securities.</p>
<p>But this year, Lands' End as well as major chains kept a tighter lid on the amount of inventory they ordered.</p>
<p>&quot;They're trying to be careful on inventory,&quot; Silverman said of Lands' End. &quot;They've cut back on the things that didn't sell well.&quot;</p>
<p>J.C. Penney ended the quarter with a backlog of merchandise, and analysts worry that clearance sales could hurt profits in the second quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;It implies that if sales don't really pick up in the May, earnings could be at risk as a result of markdowns in June and July,&quot; said McCormack of Alex. Brown.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
