<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="578205" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE world sugar ends firmer after late rebound.</title>
<headline>CSCE world sugar ends firmer after late rebound.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE world sugar ended near the day's highs after a late burst of speculative and industry-linked buying, but the run-up faltered near key resistance levels, trading sources said.</p>
<p>After hovering near unchanged for much of the session, the New York market regained its footing late in the day, fueled by steady trade buying. Speculators joined the fray ahead of the close, but the rally was unable to muster enough steam to challenge resistance in the 11.15-11.17 area.</p>
<p>Benchmark July futures ended 0.07 cent per lb higher, at 11.11 cents, the highest level in more than two weeks. Trades were posted from 11.01 to 11.14. Second-position October rose 0.03, to 10.90, while the remaining months closed 0.06 cent higher.</p>
<p>While there were few new developments on the day, traders said talk that U.S. trade house Cargill would find buyers for more than 300,000 tonnes Brazilian and Central American raws may have underpinned sentiment. But traders remained split on what proportion of the sugar represented this year's crop.</p>
<p>Based on today's strong finish, traders said July was well positioned to test the 11.20 mark. But with speculators already net long some 58,000 lots, they may be reluctant to add to their position.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to be concerned to see if the speculators have enough ammunition to push it higher,&quot; a broker said. &quot;They're capable of adding more longs on, but there will be some good producer selling up there.&quot;</p>
<p>Beyond the 11.20 level, traders noted a long-term objective at 11.37 basis July. To the downside, July would need to hold above 10.85 cents to continue to appear constructive.</p>
<p>An estimated 18,996 lots changed hands on the day.</p>
<p>((-- W Pollack, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
