<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="578229" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Duramed says to cut losses later in 1997.</title>
<headline>Duramed says to cut losses later in 1997.</headline>
<dateline>CINCINNATI 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Duramed Pharmaceuticals Inc said on Tuesday that money funneled into its product development plan would be recorded as losses in the company's statement of operations, but that the losses should decrease during the second half of 1997.</p>
<p>Further, the company said its product development program would require about $3 to $5 million per quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;These investments will be expensed as incurred and will be reflected as losses in Duramed's statements of operations,&quot; the company said in a statement. &quot;As products are approved during the second half of 1997, the losses should decrease and Duramed expects to achieve overall profitability by mid-1998.&quot; it added.</p>
<p>In addition, Duramed said it had reached an agreement in principal for additional financing to follow through with the company's business plan to focus on specialty products with limited competition.</p>
<p>Duramed expects to finalize the agreement within a week.</p>
<p>Duramed also said it is working with a regulatory and legal team to review a recent FDA decision that places the burden of proof for identifying active ingredients on the generics industry.</p>
<p>Duramed Pharmaceuticals manufactures and markets a line of prescription generic drug products.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CINCINNATI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
