<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="578201" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. debt futures settle lower on Fed story.</title>
<headline>U.S. debt futures settle lower on Fed story.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. debt futures settled near daily lows after unnamed sources close to the Federal Reserve told Reuters that the U.S. central bank is likely to raise the Federal funds rate 25 basis points next week, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has been leaning toward the idea that the Fed would not tighten,&quot; one bond futures trader said.</p>
<p>The sources also said that U.S. financial markets are not yet helping the Fed restrain growth, indicating the need for another insurance move.</p>
<p>June T-bonds immediately pushed below 109-30/32, which had held a firm support level all morning.  </p>
<p>Earlier, locals had gradually pressured June through the 200-day moving average of 110-03/32 after prices failed on the upside. June quickly turned lower after rising to 110-22/32 in a knee-jerk rally to U.S. April retail sales data.</p>
<p>June T-bonds fell to 109-24/32, below Monday's overall low of 109-28/32 and closer to last Friday's low of 109-16/32.</p>
<p>Traders also said dealer selling turned aggressive after Richmond Federal Reserve president Alfred Broaddus' comments. Broaddus said the U.S. economy was expanding rapidly and that the job markets are expected to remain tight, with unemployment at a rate of 5.0 percent by late 1997.  </p>
<p>Broaddus said the current scenario suggests the risks remain tilted to the upside for the U.S. economy, but also said the GDP growth rate could slow to a little under 3.0 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>Expectations on the pace of U.S. economic growth in the second quarter may be revised, however, later this week, due to several key U.S. economic reports. On Wednesday at 0830 EDT/1230 GMT, the U.S. April Producer Price Index (PPI) is seen unchanged from March's 0.1-percent decline.</p>
<p>On Thursday the U.S. April Consumer Price Index (CPI) will be released.  </p>
<p>At the end of pit trade, June T-bonds were down 18/32 at 109-26/32, 10-year notes were off 12/32 at 107-05/32, muni bonds were 11/32 lower at 115-19/32, September T-bills were down 0.04 at 94.495, September Eurodollars were 0.06 lower at 93.88 and December Eurodollars were down 0.065 at 93.67. ((Derivatives desk 312-408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
