<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="578276" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dodgers says News Corp interested in team.</title>
<headline>Dodgers says News Corp interested in team.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Los Angeles Dodgers baseball team said Tuesday that it was seeking permission to negotiate the sale of the team to News Corp's Fox Sports unit.</p>
<p>&quot;Peter O'Malley, president of the Los Angeles Dodgers, announced that the Dodgers, pursuant to the rules of Major League Baseball, have (Monday) requested permission to enter into serious discussions with the Fox Group, an affiliate of News Corp,&quot; the team said in a brief statement.</p>
<p>The Dodgers said Fox was &quot;one of the entities expressing an interest in acquiring the team.&quot;  </p>
<p>In the statement, the team said, &quot;O'Malley reiterated his commitment to a dignified sales process...&quot;</p>
<p>In the statement, O'Malley said: &quot;We're in the fifth month of what we expected to to be a six-month process, and I am pleased that it has not been a distraction to date. For that I am grateful.&quot;</p>
<p>A source close to News Corp confirmed that the two sides were in talks, adding, &quot;Something should happen in the middle or end of next week.&quot;  </p>
<p>A spokesman for the baseball commissioner said the Major League Baseball Executive Council will consider the request. The commissioner's office had no comment on the talks.</p>
<p>A News Corp spokesman declined to comment.</p>
<p>The Los Angeles Times and Newsday reported on Monday that Fox was interested in buying the Dodgers professional baseball team.</p>
<p>The Los Angeles Times reported Monday that the team would be sold within two months, and it quoted National Football League sources as saying News Corp's Fox was interested. Fox broadcasts weekly NFL games.</p>
<p>The Times quoted Peter O'Malley, whose family owns the team, as saying it would be sold within two months. He did not name any potential buyers.</p>
<p>O'Malley announced in January that the club was for sale. The O'Malley family has owned the team since 1950.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
