<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="578293" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORECAST--U.S. April CPI a one-way bet for markets.</title>
<headline>FORECAST--U.S. April CPI a one-way bet for markets.</headline>
<byline>Roanne Daniels</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Consumer Price Index (CPI) report on Thursday could help convince the Federal Reserve to hike rates next week but will do little to strengthen the case for steady policy, economists said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Labor Department will release CPI data at 0830 EDT/1230 GMT on Thursday, May 15. Fed Chairman Alan Greenspan has made it crystal clear that he does not need to see a rise in price indices before boosting interest rates again.  </p>
<p>&quot;Those who wish for us, in the current environment, to await clearly visible signs of emerging inflation before acting are recommending we return to a failed regime of monetary policy that cost jobs and living standards,&quot; Greenspan said in a speech last week.</p>
<p>John Ryding, a senior economist at Bear Stearns, said if consumer prices meet expectations, they &quot;will have no bearing&quot; on next week's Federal Open Market Committee meeting.  </p>
<p>However, if the CPI beats Wall Street expectations for a 0.1 percent rise in the overall index and a 0.2 percent rise excluding food and energy, it could arm the Fed with the weapon it needs to tighten monetary policy.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a number that the Fed looks at and I suspect if it's any kind of trouble, it could sway the Fed,&quot; said Marilyn Schaja, money market economist at Donaldson, Lufkin and Jenrette Securities Corp.</p>
<p>Ryding said the report was a &quot;one way risk&quot; for the markets.  </p>
<p>While the U.S. economy moves further into its seventh year of expansion, consumer prices are nearing record lows.</p>
<p>The CPI index rose an annual 1.8 percent in the first quarter of 1997, well below the 4.0 percent rise seen in the first quarter of last year.</p>
<p>The core CPI increased 2.4 percent this year, markedly below the 3.0 percent annualized gain during the first quarter of 1996, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers so far this year have been terrific and they are following a very good 1996. There's no inflation filtering through to the consumer whatsoever,&quot; Schaja said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Whenever anybody tries to raise prices, they can't stick,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>A fall in energy costs, lead by weaker gasoline prices, probably dampened the overall CPI in April. Regarding other components, the report should hold few surprises, economists said.</p>
<p>Food, housing and hotel prices were expected to have risen modestly while auto, airline, and tobacco costs likely declined.</p>
<p>Apparel prices probably held flat to marginally higher for the month, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices in total remain constrained,&quot; said Carol Stone, senior economist at Nomura Securities International Inc.</p>
<p>((--N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1677))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
