<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57835" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE fuel oil - cracked steady, dealers cautious.</title>
<headline>NWE fuel oil - cracked steady, dealers cautious.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>High sulphur barges were slightly firmer on Tuesday with good buying interest and continued talk of tightness supporting prices.</p>
<p>Other fuel oil sectors were quieter, with dealers still cautious amid changeable crude futures.</p>
<p>Several barge deals were concluded around $112 fob ARA, after a morning trade at $108.50 fob ARA.</p>
<p>High sulphur cargo levels were seen broadly steady around $107-108 fob. An end-user was understood to have bid $114 cif for product, but may be forced to pay a bit more following crude's steady gains.  </p>
<p>On the bullish side supplies were viewed as tight, but talk of another Portuguese tender in the short-term appeared unsubstantiated. &quot;Not within the next couple of weeks, there's still a cargo to be delivery in early Oct,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>High sulphur swaps gained on Tuesday, but the increasing likelihood that Russian straight-run will filter into the cracked barge market could strip away the bullish tone. &quot;I think bearish factors will start to build up,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Low sulphur cargoes were also steady, and the firm tone was seen to have better underpinning than the high sulphur sector. Dealers said interest from the Med would have to be shown soon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
