<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="578562" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dollar calmer in Europe but on alert for US data.</title>
<headline>Dollar calmer in Europe but on alert for US data.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The market ended European trade a touch softer than where it began, but the market was clearly calmer after the nervous, volatile dealings of recent days.</p>
<p>The dollar wobbled slightly after soft U.S. retail sales data further deflated expectations of a near-term Federal Reserve interest rate rise, but earlier comments from Japanese finance and central bank officials had made for a steadier mood.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems the Japanese have started to put the brakes on. Though they'e quite happy with current levels, they don't want to see (the dollar) steaming to 110 yen and below,&quot; said Pat Magill, head of the corporate desk at Daiwa Europe in London.  </p>
<p>Japan's finance minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka said he expects FX markets to settle down soon at an appropriate level. Bank of Japan director Yutaka Yamaguchi said it was important for exchange rates to stabilise at levels reflecting fundamentals.</p>
<p>&quot;It's quite clear Japanese officials seem to be relatively content with current levels. They were probably somewhat surprised by the pace of the decline in the last few days,&quot; said Nick Stamenkovic, economist at DKB International here.</p>
<p>Japanese comments last week sparked fears of intervention to help the yen, and combined with talk of a possible Japanese rate hike to trigger dollar/yen's steepest one-week drop since 1989.  </p>
<p>The dollar stood at 118.93/03 yen at 1524 GMT versus its European opening of 119.30/40 and Monday's close of 118.67/77.</p>
<p>Dollar/mark slipped to 1.6968/73 from late yesterday's European level of 1.7010/20 and today's open of 1.7025/30.</p>
<p>Traders said mark crosses -- principally mark/yen and sterling/mark -- had again had a big influence on the dollar. The mark recovered above 70.00 yen today after slumping to an almost 12-month low of 69.64 in Europe on Monday.</p>
<p>U.S. overall April retail sales matched expectations, falling 0.3 percent on the month. The figure for the previous month was revised to unchanged from a 0.1 percent rise.  </p>
<p>Excluding cars, where analysts had predicted a 0.1 percent increase, retail sales fell 0.1 percent.</p>
<p>The market is now awaiting U.S. April producer prices out on Wednesday for the next data clue to whether the Federal Reserve will raise rates at its next policy-making meeting on May 20.</p>
<p>Reduced expectations of U.S. tightening were partly responsible for the dollar's downward lurch last week.</p>
<p>Business inventories are also due tomorrow, with CPI, industrial production, capacity utilization and real earnings out on Thursday and housing starts Friday. The May Philadephia Fed survey and Michigan sentiment survey also appear this week.  </p>
<p>Some analysts warned that the market now risked being caught out if the Fed did tighten. While soft data would continue to favour steady policy, the U.S. central bank had made clear its fondness for pre-emptive strikes against inflation, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the CPI and PPI data will clearly confirm inflation remains low...but the Fed is being pre-emptive,&quot; said DKB's Stamenkovic. &quot;It acknowledges inflation's low now and what it's concerned about is whether that can be sustained.&quot;</p>
<p>Though a Fed rate hike should boost dollar/yen by increasing the U.S. yield advantage over Japan, Daiwa's Magill said the Japanese authorities might choose to copy any U.S. tightening.  </p>
<p>&quot;If the U.S. do move, perhaps the Japanese would choose that moment to nudge their own rates so there's not any movement in the differentials,&quot; Magill said.</p>
<p>Sterling was boosted during the European session by the Bank of England's quarterly inflation report. It said the pound's strength would see underlying UK inflation well below the government's 2.5 percent this year but further rate rises were needed to maintain that two years out.</p>
<p>The report is seen as key for the UK interest rate outlook, since the bank gained operational independence last week.</p>
<p>-- Abigail Levene, London Newsroom +44-171-542-8968</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
