<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="578596" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Placer seeks more profits, bigger deposits.</title>
<headline>Placer seeks more profits, bigger deposits.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian gold miner Placer Dome Inc said on Tuesday it was drafting a new long-range strategic plan targeting improved profitability and the development of bigger deposits.</p>
<p>&quot;It basically switches the focus onto getting higher quality reserves, larger and longer-life mines, and improved financial performance,&quot; Placer spokesman Hugh Leggatt said.</p>
<p>The plan will be presented to the company's board of directors in late July and implemented immediately.</p>
<p>The company devised a similar long-range plan in 1993 when Chief Executive John Willson joined the company. The goals of that plan, which included increasing annual gold production to 2.5 million ounces by 2000, have either been achieved or are within sight.</p>
<p>Placer has already taken steps toward reaching its new objectives, including divesting marginal assets and establishing an exploration team dedicated to discovering big deposits. Willson also vowed at Placer's recent annual meeting to improve the company's profitability.</p>
<p>The plan would seek to strengthen Placer's profitability and set an exploration goal of discovering deposits containing at least five million ounces of gold, Leggatt said.</p>
<p>No specific profit figures had been established, he said.</p>
<p>As part of the effort, Placer announced late on Monday the consolidation of its Canadian and U.S. divisions into a single North American unit. &quot;It made sense from a cost point of view to combine the two,&quot; Leggatt said.</p>
<p>Several top executives are also taking new roles. Chief Financial Officer Ian Austin becomes executive vice president in charge of acquisitions, planning and business development, while Treasurer Rex McLennan becomes chief financial officer.</p>
<p>Jay Taylor, chief of Placer Dome U.S. will head the new North American unit.</p>
<p>Placer is also creating the position of vice president for sustainable development, which it believes is unique among mining companies. Doug Fraser, currently head of Placer Dome Canada, will fill the job, reporting to Austin.</p>
<p>((Cynthia Osterman, Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
