<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="578940" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico's sterling bond aims at currency diversity.</title>
<headline>Mexico's sterling bond aims at currency diversity.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kozak</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's plan to tap the sterling bond market will mark its first placement in that currency since well before the peso crash and help to diversify the base of its debt, analysts said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Lead managers BZW and SBC Warburg will lead a sterling bond for Mexico, likely a 300 million sterling five-year issue, bankers said.</p>
<p>Since its return to debt markets after the peso crash in 1994, Mexico has steadily built yield curves in Italian lira, Japanese yen, Deutsche marks, as well as U.S. dollars.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are seeing other Latin American countries, like Argentina, doing this. They are increasingly issuing debt in non-dollar currencies,&quot; said Bankers Trust Research economist Carl W. Ross.</p>
<p>He said sovereign borrowers are trying to lower debt costs and lessen the impact of any possible crises by widening the base of investors they have to draw from.</p>
<p>There is as yet no date for the sterling issue.  </p>
<p>Mexico last went to the sterling market in November 1991, placing a 100 million sterling bond, coming due in December 1998. In 1981, it had placed a 50 million sterling issue due in September 2008.</p>
<p>Bankers in London told Reuters there is still some lingering post-British election euphoria, which could boost prospects for the latest bond. Spread talk was between 185 to 200 basis points over gilts.  </p>
<p>The Mexican government has been able to cover its maturing market debt issues for 1997, which were only about $1.4 billion, by going to capital markets early at the start of the year.</p>
<p>But it has also been paying back what it owes to the International Monetary Fund. It most recently made a $590 million payment in February.</p>
<p>&quot;Outside of paying the IMF, they really have no need to place other bonds, but if conditions are favourable in capital markets, why not?&quot; said Santander Investment economist Enrique Ramirez.  </p>
<p>He said there is still good liquidity in capital markets that is helping countries like Mexico sell debt.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Guillermo Ortiz said in early May the country owes the IMF about $10.0 billion and expects to pay $500 million more this year.</p>
<p>He also said the country might prepay its IMF obligations if conditions permit.</p>
<p>So far this year, Mexico has placed a wide variety of debt, including a 10-year $1.0 billion global bond, a 12-year 1.5 billion mark bond, two yen issues, and two Italian lira issues, one with a 10-year term and the other a 20-year issue.</p>
<p>(( -- Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9559))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
