<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="578911" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico Cetes rate ends unchanged on U.S. long bond.</title>
<headline>Mexico Cetes rate ends unchanged on U.S. long bond.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican overnight Cetes rates closed unchanged at 19.25 percent on Tuesday after a session in which stability on the U.S. bond market offset liquidity pressures and surplus paper in the market.</p>
<p>&quot;We are close to the cutoff date for checking accounts and that always squeezes liquidity,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Banks have to settle balances outstanding on checking accounts they hold with the central bank by Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank has placed too much paper, that also pushed secondary rates upwards,&quot; another trader said, referring to daily central bank intervention.  </p>
<p>The central bank drained 4.294 billion pesos from the system by placing three direct sales of Cetes and five repos.</p>
<p>Dealers said upside pressure on rates was nonetheless cushioned by a favorable reaction on the U.S. bond market to mild U.S. retail sales data released in early trade.</p>
<p>U.S. 30-year Treasury bonds in late trade were down 15/32 to yield 6.93 percent.</p>
<p>Traders are waiting for the outcome of U.S. inflation data on Wednesday and Thursday to determine if this confirmed market expectations the Federal Open Market Committee would raise U.S. interest rates 25 basis points on May 20.  </p>
<p>Money market traders forecast that liquidity pressures and uncertainty about U.S. interest rates would force local interest rates up at the central bank's primary auction of govwernment securities later in the day.</p>
<p>A Reuters survey nN13531118 of nine dealers showed they believed on average that Banco de Mexico would assign bellwether 28-day Cetes rates at 19.37 percent. This would be an increase of 76 basis points since last week's auction.</p>
<p>Banco de Mexico was expected to announce the results of its auction at 1830 local time/2330 GMT.</p>
<p>June contracts for Cetes futures traded on the Chicago mercantile Exchange, meanwhile, ended up 23 centavos at 78.50 pesos.</p>
<p>Overnight rates on bank paper mirrored government rates by ending unchanged at 20.65 percent.</p>
<p>Liquidity of 1.866 billion pesos was due to return to the system on Wednesday from prior central bank intervention.</p>
<p>((--Elena Vega, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9554))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
