<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="578963" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine province in Northern Orion deal.</title>
<headline>Argentine province in Northern Orion deal.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's Catamarca province has agreed details of a contract to be signed in days with Canada's Northern Orion to explore its Antofalla Este gold prospect, a provincial official said Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The provincial decree authorizing the contract was issued two months ago and we are just waiting for the final bureaucratic formalities to be completed before signing,&quot; the northwestern province's Mining Secretary Raul Galarza told Reuters in an interview.  </p>
<p>&quot;Northern Orion, through Grupo Minero Aconcagua, could start drilling this month,&quot; Galarza said.</p>
<p>The 8,200-hectare site in the area of Antofagasta de la Sierra is at over 4,000 meters above sea-level but its dry climate should mean that snow should not impede work there in the coming southern hemisphere winter.</p>
<p>The prospect has vein formations including lead, silver and zinc, together with mineralization associated with disseminated gold. The gold provides the main economic interest, Galarza said.  </p>
<p>Catamarca is also negotiating exploration contracts with Northern Orion for its La Hoyada and Diablillos prospects, and with Australia's BHP Ltd for the Filo Colorado area.</p>
<p>&quot;The talks are going slower than we would like,&quot; Galarza said, &quot;But we want to have handed over all our prospects to the private sector by the end of 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>Catamarca is the site of the $1-billion Bajo de la Alumbrera copper and gold project being developed by MIM Holdings and North Ltd together with Canada's Rio Algom  </p>
<p>BHP is developing the nearby Agua Rica copper project, which is already being spoken about in the industry as being a potential rival to Bajo de la Alumbrera in size. BHP has 70 percent of Agua Rica and Northern Orion has 30 percent.</p>
<p>((--Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0655))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
