<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579011" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: TIMELINES-Today in History - May 14.</title>
<headline>TIMELINES-Today in History - May 14.</headline>
<text>
<p>** BIRTHDAYS **</p>
<p>German physicist GABRIEL FAHRENHEIT, who invented the temperature scale in 1714, was born in 1686.</p>
<p>English landscape and portrait artist THOMAS GAINSBOROUGH was born in 1727.  </p>
<p>Australian Judge SIR JAMES MARTIN was born in 1820. Martin Place in Sydney's central business district was named after him, and Lady Martin's Beach at Sydney's Point Piper was named after his wife.</p>
<p>German conductor OTTO KLEMPERER, known for his interpretations of BEETHOVEN symphonies, was born in 1885.  </p>
<p>British comedian ERIC MORECAMBE (ERIC BARTHOLOMEW), who teamed up with ERIC WISE in 1941 and enjoyed a television audience of 20 million in the 1970s, was born in 1926. He died of a heart attack on the 29th of May 1984, collapsing off stage after six curtain calls that followed a charity show at his friend STAN STENNETT's Tewkesbury Theatre.</p>
<p>American pop singer BOBBY DARIN, who reached the charts with &quot;Splish Splash&quot; and &quot;Mack The Knife&quot;, was born in 1936.  </p>
<p>American film director and producer GEORGE LUCAS, whose films included &quot;The Star Wars Trilogy&quot; (1977-83), &quot;American Graffiti&quot; (1973), &quot;Raiders Of The Lost Ark&quot; (1981), Indianna Jones And The Temple Of Doom&quot; (1984), &quot;Willow&quot; (1988) and &quot;Indianna Jones And The Last Crusade&quot; (1989), was born in 1944.</p>
<p>American singer FAB MORVAN was born in 1966. In 1985 he and ROB PLATUS formed &quot;Milli Vanilli&quot; who were hailed as the Newcomers of the Year in the United States. Their hits included &quot;Girl You Know It's True&quot; (1988), &quot;Blame It On The Rain&quot; (1989) and &quot;Girl I'm Gonna Miss You&quot; (1989). They were uncovered as a  </p>
<p>sham as they didn't sing their own songs and were 'lipsynching&quot;.</p>
<p>			  ** EVENTS **</p>
<p>    1643 :    LOUIS XIV acceded to the throne of France at the</p>
<p>age of four years eight months on the death of his father LOUIS XIII. His mother, ANNE of Austria, became regent. He reigned until his death in 1715.  </p>
<p>    1796 :    British physician EDWARD JENNER carried out the</p>
<p>first successful vaccination against smallpox in Britain. JENNER used a vaccine made from the blood of cattle that were infected with the cowpox.</p>
<p>    1811 :    Paraguay proclaimed its independence from Spain.</p>
<p>    1847 :    HMS Driver completed the first around the world</p>
<p>voyage by a steamship.  </p>
<p>    1853 :    GAIL BORDEN applied for a US patent for a process</p>
<p>of making condensed milk. There were doubts about the value of such a product, but the process was eventually marketed by a firm known as the Borden Company.</p>
<p>    1900 :    The second Modern Olympic Games opened in Paris,</p>
<p>with women allowed to compete for the first time.  </p>
<p>    1923 :    One of the most notorious cases in New Zealand</p>
<p>criminal history got underway in Wellington. The trial of husband and wife, DANIEL RICHARD COOPER and MARTHA ELIZABETH COOPER, were charged with murder after the discovery of three children's bodies in their yard. They pleaded not guilty. DANIEL COOPER was found guilty of the murder of a child while his wife was acquitted.</p>
<p>    1925 :    Sir HENRY RIDER HAGGARD, the author of &quot;King</p>
<p>Solomon's Mines&quot; and other rattling good yarns, died.  </p>
<p>    1931 :    The Bank of England's interest loan rates were cut</p>
<p>to 2.5 percent, the lowest for 22 years.</p>
<p>    1939 :    Hollywood film producer SAM GOLDWYN took control</p>
<p>of the United Artists company, buying out CHARLIE CHAPLIN, MARY PICKFORD and DOUGLAS FAIRBANKS, who founded the movie corporation in 1919.  </p>
<p>    1940 :    Two thirds of the Dutch city of Rotterdam was</p>
<p>destroyed by German bombing, killing almost 1,000 people and making at least 80,000 homeless.</p>
<p>    1948 :    The British mandate in Palestine ran out, bringing</p>
<p>the proclamation of the State of Israel and allowing the entry of Jewish immigrants who'd been banned since 1944.</p>
<p>    1948 :    Atlantic Records was founded in the United States</p>
<p>by AHMET ERTEGUN, the son of the Turkish Ambassador to the USA.  </p>
<p>    1955 :    The Eastern Bloc signed the Warsaw Pact. The USSR</p>
<p>and Eastern European Communist States signed the military alliance, in response to the admission of West Germany into NATO. Its military structures and agreements were dismantled early in 1991, and the politicial structure was officially dissolved in July 1991.</p>
<p>    1959 :    American jazz saxophonist SYDNEY BECHET died on</p>
<p>his 65th birthday.  </p>
<p>    1964 :    Egyptian President GAMAL ABDEL NASSER and Soviet</p>
<p>Premier NIKITA KRUSHCHEV took part in the detonation of a huge sand barrier, changing the course of the Nile River. The river had to be diverted to build the next stage of the ASWAN HIGH DAM, aimed at irrigating vast areas of Egyptian desert.</p>
<p>    1970:     Painter Sir WILLIAM DOBELL died.</p>
<p>    1973 :    Space exploration entered a new era, as the</p>
<p>American space-station SKYLAB 1 was blasted into orbit aboard a Saturn-5 rocket.</p>
<p>    1984 :    The one dollar coin, designed by STUART DEVLIN,</p>
<p>went into circulation in Australia.</p>
<p>    1987 :    Armed troops led by Colonel SITIVENI RABUKA staged</p>
<p>the first coup in Fiji, kidnapping Prime Minister Dr TIMOCI BAVADRA. The coup was aimed at curbing the influence of Indian migrants in government.  </p>
<p>    1989 :    In Argentina's general election, Peronist leader</p>
<p>CARLOS MENEM swept to power beating ruling Radical Party candidate EDUARDO ANGELOZ.</p>
<p>    1990 :    Anti-Semitism resurfaced in France, with the</p>
<p>desecration of Jewish graves at Carpentras Cemetery in the country's South.  </p>
<p>    1991 :     JIANG QING, widow of Chinese Communist Party</p>
<p>chairman MAO ZEDONG and leader of the 'Gang of Four', committed suicide.</p>
<p>    1991 :    WINNIE MANDELA, (wife of new South African</p>
<p>President NELSON MANDELA), was sentenced to six years jail, after being convicted of kidnapping and assault in the STOMPIE SEIPEI case. She and her husband separated in April 1992, and until March 1995 (when she was sacked) she held a place in the new South African Government (Deputy Minister for Arts, Culture, Science and Technology).  </p>
<p>    1993 :     American newspaper magnate WILLIAM RANDOLPH</p>
<p>HEARST Jr. died after a heart attack. He was 85 and editor-in-chief of Hearst Newspapers and chairman of the executive committee of the Hearst Corporation.</p>
<p>    1994 :     Noisy parades and celebrations enveloped the</p>
<p>700-strong Palestinian police force as it patrolled Jericho on the first full day of Palestinian self-rule after nearly three decades of Israeli occupation.  </p>
<p>    1995 :     The DALAI LAMA proclaimed six-year-old GEDHUN</p>
<p>CHOEKYI NYIMA as the 11th reincarnation of the Panchen Lama, Tibet's second most senior spritual leader.</p>
<p>(Compiled from ABC ARCHIVES, ABC RADIO NATIONAL, &quot;On This Day&quot; published by REED INTERNATIONAL BOOKS LIMITED, &quot;The Chronicle Of The 20th Century&quot; published by PENGUIN BOOKS and &quot;Rock And Pop (Day By Day)&quot; published by BLANDFORD BOOKS.)</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
