<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579071" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALDIVES: S.Asian nations vow to have free trade by 2001.</title>
<headline>S.Asian nations vow to have free trade by 2001.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>KURUMBA, Maldives 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seven South Asian nations, frustrated over slack cross-border commerce, decided on Tuesday to advance a deadline for forming a free trade area by four years to 2001, Indian Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral said.</p>
<p>Gujral told a news conference on a resort island in the Maldives that leaders of the South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation (SAARC) reached the decision on the second day of a three-day summit.</p>
<p>The seven-nation SAARC had previously agreed to form the South Asian Free Trade Area (SAFTA) preferably by 2000, but no later than 2005.</p>
<p>&quot;We have agreed that the introduction of SAFTA should be accelerated to 2001 as the target year,&quot; Gujral said.</p>
<p>The SAARC member states -- Bangladesh, Bhutan, India, Maldives, Nepal, Pakistan and Sri Lanka -- will commit themselves to the new deadline in a joint declaration to be issued at the conclusion of the summit on Wednesday, Gujral said.</p>
<p>The SAARC leaders met at the Kurumba Village beach resort, a tiny island in the sparkling necklace of 1,190 islands that make up the Maldives, the host nation and smallest member of the bloc.</p>
<p>SAARC leaders have openly lamented the slow pace of economic integration in the South Asian region, where the annual per capita income of $309 lags behind even sub-Saharan Africa's $555, according to the Islamabad-based Human Development Centre.</p>
<p>Trade within the region's states, which have 1.2 billion people -- one fifth of the world's population -- still accounts for only three percent of SAARC's total world trade.</p>
<p>At this week's meeting, SAARC leaders openly expressed disappointment over the slow pace of regional integration, especially in trade and investment.</p>
<p>Pakistani Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif urged member states at Monday's opening meeting to &quot;wake up from the slumber of inaction&quot;.</p>
<p>Maldivian President Maumoon Abdul Gayoom, SAARC's new chairman, called for more political dialogue, while Sri Lankan President Chandrika Kumaratunga suggested more frequent, informal and confidential talks among SAARC leaders.</p>
<p>Gujral said the leaders had agreed to set up a 15-member &quot;eminent persons group&quot; to lauch a review to revitalise the bloc.</p>
<p>The Indian leader said it was also agreed that SAARC representatives would meet more often, dispensing with much of the ceremony and adopting a more informal format in order to build closer ties.</p>
<p>Gujral said the SAARC declaration would call for fresh efforts to promote education, lend support to female children and halt the trafficking of women and child prostitution.</p>
<p>The opening day of the summit was dominated by a meeting between the prime ministers of the region's two biggest states, India and Pakistan, whose rivalry has frustrated SAARC's efforts to pull the region out of poverty.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALDR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KURUMBA, Maldives"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALDIVES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
