<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579085" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan fires Peru ambassador over hostage siege.</title>
<headline>Japan fires Peru ambassador over hostage siege.</headline>
<byline>Eugene Moosa</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan fired its ambassador to Peru on Tuesday, forcing him out over security lapses that allowed rebels to storm his residence and take hundreds hostage.</p>
<p>&quot;We have heard yet again Ambassador Morihisa Aoki's desire to step down and after considering many things, we have decided to ask him to leave the post,&quot; Foreign Minister Yukihiko Ikeda told a special parliamentary session on the hostage crisis.</p>
<p>Aoki sat in a wheelchair beside Ikeda when the foreign minister announced the decision to accept the ambassador's resignation, which had been regarded as only a symbolic offer.</p>
<p>On his return from Lima last month, Aoki told reporters he could not wait to get back to work and wanted to return to Lima as ambassador to thank Peruvian authorities for rescuing him.</p>
<p>Aoki, 58, will remain in the diplomatic service, initially helping Japanese authorities work out ways to avoid future hostage situations, government officials said.</p>
<p>The courtly, silver-haired ambassador hosted an official reception at his residence last December 17 when it was stormed by Peruvian Marxist rebels, who took nearly 500 party-goers hostage.</p>
<p>Most of them, except for Aoki and 71 fellow hostages, were released in the weeks before the siege ended on April 22 after a daring operation by Peruvian commandos who took the rebels by surprise during their daily game of indoor soccer.</p>
<p>Two commandos and a hostage -- as well as all 14 rebels -- died in the raid.</p>
<p>The rebels from the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) wanted the release of jailed comrades and chose Japan as a target because of its major economic aid to Peru.</p>
<p>Aoki arrived at the hearing on crutches, a legacy of injuries when he leaped to freedom during the rescue raid.</p>
<p>Initially hailed as a hero who stoutly defended fellow hostages during the 127-day siege, Aoki fell from grace on his return home when the spotlight switched from the fate of the captives to how the incident happened.</p>
<p>In a clear sign that Aoki was to be the scapegoat for the siege, chief government spokesman Seiroku Kajiyama told a news conference Aoki's departure &quot;was an important element of closing the book on the hostage crisis.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;In the case of a number of recent incidents in Japan, in both government and in the private sector, the question of responsibility has been left very vague,&quot; Kajiyama added.</p>
<p>Aoki's resignation was accepted despite a letter Peruvian President Alberto Fujimori sent to Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto two weeks ago praising Aoki and asking that he be posted back to Lima as ambassador.</p>
<p>Since returning to Japan, Aoki has been pilloried by some media, mainly over the lax security precautions.</p>
<p>But he was even criticised for chain-smoking during a news conference and many Japanese lawmakers said his initial apology over security measures was insufficient.</p>
<p>In Tuesday's testimony in parliament, Aoki repeatedly apologised for his role in the affair.</p>
<p>&quot;I deeply apologise for the pain the hostages suffered during the crisis and especially for the deaths of the two military officers and the hostage,&quot; Aoki said. &quot;I am responsible and I have tendered my resignation.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I especially feel responsible for the fact that we did not give enough concern to the possibility that the reception could become a terrorist target,&quot; Aoki said.</p>
<p>However, in his defence, he said Peruvian authorities advised him anti-government rebels were no longer a threat.</p>
<p>&quot;We were informed the terrorists were inactive,&quot; Aoki said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
