<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57910" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Bullish trade keeps Nigerian bourse moving.</title>
<headline>Bullish trade keeps Nigerian bourse moving.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue chip shares, with the exception of breweries, made further gains in bullish Tuesday trading on the Nigerian stock exchange, dealers said.</p>
<p>The all-share index rose to 6,296.25 from 6,270.89 on Monday.</p>
<p>Construction firm G. Cappa rose 30 kobo, almost five percent, to 6.50 naira.</p>
<p>Unipetrol and West African Portland Cement both rose 30 kobo to close at 36.30 naira and 30.30 naira, respectively.</p>
<p>Cadbury closed 20 kobo higher at 24.20 naira. Nigerian Bottling Company was higher by the same margin at 27.00 naira.</p>
<p>National Oil at 28.50 naira and Mobil at 36.50 naira both closed 20 kobo higher. Trading ended mixed in the conglomerates sector. While strong demand pushed PZ industries up 25 kobo to 34.45 naira and Lever Brothers up 20 kobo to 25.20 naira, lack of interest in CFAO depressed its shares by five percent, down 25 kobo to 4.75 naira.</p>
<p>Nigerian Breweries closed down 10 kobo at 13.00 naira and Guinness down five kobo at 9.20 naira. New bank Guaranty Trust was 12 kobo better at 12.30 naira but NAL Merchant Bank fell by 10 kobo to 5.60 naira. ($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>--Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
