<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579137" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Nomura suspended from auctions, underwriting--MOF.</title>
<headline>Nomura suspended from auctions, underwriting--MOF.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Ministry of Finance said on Tuesday that it was suspending Nomura Securities Co Ltd from Japanese government bond (JGB) auctions and bond underwriting until the implementation of administrative punishments against the brokerage proposed by the Securities and Exchange Surveillance Commission (SESC).  </p>
<p>Asked how long the suspension would last, a MOF official told reporters: &quot;We will consider the appropriate steps when the administrative punishments are actually implemented.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday the SESC filed complaints with prosecutors alleging that Nomura, Japan's biggest brokerage, and three of its three former executives illegally compensated a corporate client for losses.</p>
<p>Government officials said that the SESC would start drawing up recommendations for penalties against Nomura immediately although they added that it was too early to say when these would be submitted to the Finance Ministry.</p>
<p>The MOF official said that Nomura currently had a 5.98 percent share in the JGB underwriting syndicate.  </p>
<p>He said MOF would consult with the underwriting syndicate to arrange for other underwriters to take over Nomura's share.</p>
<p>He declined to comment when asked what the impact would be on JGB issuance.</p>
<p>MOF suspended Nomura from bond underwriting and participating on JGB auctions for two months after a similar scandal in 1991.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
