<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579232" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS - API crude build sparks selling, confusion.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - API crude build sparks selling, confusion.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>This week's report from the American Petroleum Institute (API) cut bearishly into energy prices Tuesday evening, but fueled ongoing complaints about the data's credibility, traders said.</p>
<p>Indeed, an off-the-charts crude build of nearly seven million barrels shown in the report sparked a quick 30 cents selloff for June crude in late-day ACCESS trade, but also left traders with a sense the report did not make sense.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't get it,&quot; said Gerald Samuels, managing director of ARB Oil.</p>
<p>API said crude stocks stood at 322.6 million barrels at the end of last week, 6.9 million over the prior week, and nearly 23 million over prior year levels.</p>
<p>Samuels and others questioned how stocks could have built so much when refinery utilization rates also rose sharply, and yet crude oil imports did not.</p>
<p>Refinery run rates rose by a completely unexpected 2.4 percentage points last week to a very high 96.7 percent of total capacity, while imports stood at 8.22 million barrels per day (bpd)-- 149,000 bpd less than in API's prior report.</p>
<p>&quot;It's messed up,&quot; said another trader in New York.</p>
<p>But the New York trader and others cautioned that despite the report's obvious logical lapses, it also contained unimpeachable bearishness on the gasoline front in the form of a way-above-expectation build of 6.5 million barrels.</p>
<p>&quot;This throws a big bucket of cold water on gasoline bullishness. It kills the demand and stock hype,&quot; said Bob MacMinn, president MPAS Inc in Toronto.</p>
<p>Gasoline futures on ACCESS were down by over a cent a gallon to around 63.75 cents a gallon, with the data showing a surprising jump in domestic output to 8.11 million bpd.</p>
<p>Also, the implied demand data came off to 7.48 million bpd per day from the hard-to-believe highs of 8.7 in the API's last report.</p>
<p>A good part of that build was the result of a 2.9 million barrels build of reformulated gasoline stocks on the East Coast, which explains part of the NYMEX selloff since the gasoline contract is deliverable in New York Harbor.</p>
<p>The API's distillate data also provided a bit of a surprise, but on the bullish side of the ledger. The report showed stocks dropping by 1.1 million barrels to 96.5 million barrels against expectations for a build of over two million barrels.</p>
<p>Still, the NYMEX heating oil contract was infected by the broader bearish reactions to the data, with the June contract shedding over 0.50 cent on ACCESS to 55.95 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>&quot;It was pretty wild,&quot; ARB's Samuels said of the API report.</p>
<p>-- Oliver Ludwig New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1633</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
