<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579381" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MGE spring wheat ends mixed but above session lows.</title>
<headline>MGE spring wheat ends mixed but above session lows.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spillover strength from outside markets and local short-covering helped MGE spring wheat futures settle mixed but well above session lows, traders said.</p>
<p>Wheat weakened at the opening on followthrough technical selling from Monday's weak close. Losses were limited after Continental Grain stepped in and bought at least one million July bushels, prompting more scale-down buying by commission houses such as Linnco and Prudential, traders said.</p>
<p>But wheat sagged again at midsession until it was lifted by strength in CBOT corn and beans and KCBT wheat.</p>
<p>&quot;It was really when beans came off their lows that (local traders) scurried to cover their shorts,&quot; a MGE trader said. &quot;Part of that was also due to the firmness in Kansas City.&quot;</p>
<p>MGE spring wheat settled five cents per bushel lower to one cent higher, with May down five cents at $4.15. July, which had fallen as low as $4.12 on the day, settled up 1/2 cent at $4.17.</p>
<p>Traders said Continental's purchase of at least one million July bushels was likely pricing related to export business.</p>
<p>((--Greg Frost, 816 561-8671))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
