<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579488" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX Hub natgas still down late on soft cash.</title>
<headline>NYMEX Hub natgas still down late on soft cash.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures remained lower late Tuesday in moderate activity, with more long liquidation in the face of mild weather and softer cash still undermining the complex, industry sources said.</p>
<p>At 1410 EDT, June was still down by 2.9 cents at $2.195 per million British thermal units. July was 2.6 cents lower at $2.205. Most others were off by one-half to four cents.</p>
<p>&quot;We got a bounce off of $2.15 (basis June), but I don't think we'll go a whole lot higher from here. I'm not that bearish, but the weather is getting milder and I expect we'll drift lower for a couple of weeks,&quot; a Texas trader said.  </p>
<p>But he said he expected June to hold above $2, then move up as better cooling demand kicks in.</p>
<p>With funds still long, technical traders said a June close below $2.19 could trigger a flood of liquidation.</p>
<p>&quot;If June closes near here (in the teens), you could see a move to the $2.05-2.10 area, but I don't think we'll get below that,&quot; another Texas-based trader said.</p>
<p>Chart traders agreed there was minor support in June at $2.14-15, but major buying was expected in the $2.05 area, a double bottom and key trendline support. Resistance was still seen at the contract high of $2.43.</p>
<p>Maintenance work on Transco's Texas line, which began Saturday, will cut the line's total capacity of about 600 mmcfd from May 14-19, with 400 mmcfd still cut for May 20-22.</p>
<p>Forecasters expected only limited cooling demand this week in Texas and the South, with normal to below-normal East and Midwest temperatures offering a slim chance for modest heating loads. Hot weather will persist in the Southwest.</p>
<p>Estimates for a build in Wednesday's weekly AGA storage report ranged from 50 to 80 bcf.</p>
<p>In the cash, Gulf Coast prices slipped more than a nickel to the high-teens. Midcon pipes were down a similar amount to the high-$1.90s. New York city gate gas skidded a dime or more to the low-$2.40s.</p>
<p>NYMEX Hub open interest on May 12 fell 2,734 contracts to 206,928.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, June remained 4.5 cents lower at $2.035, while deferreds were steady to down by 3.5 cents. The East/West spread widened by 1.6 cents to 16.0 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>((J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
