<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579435" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida alleges toilet paper price conspiracy.</title>
<headline>Florida alleges toilet paper price conspiracy.</headline>
<dateline>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Florida's attorney general filed a civil complaint Tuesday accusing 10 paper companies of fixing the prices they charged commercial and institutional buyers for toilet paper and other sanitary products.</p>
<p>The complaint was filed in U.S. District Court in Gainesville, Fla., against Kimberly-Clark Corp and its Scott Paper Co unit, Georgia-Pacific Corp, Fort Howard Corp, Bay West Paper Corp, Cascades Industries Inc, Encore Paper Co, James River Corp, Marcel Paper Mills Inc and Wisconsin Tissue Mills Inc.</p>
<p>The complaint alleges that the companies violated antitrust laws by fixing the prices of sanitary paper products sold to schools, hospitals, prisons, hotels, restaurants, factories and other large-scale purchasers.</p>
<p>Attorney General Bob Butterworth said the complaint seeks triple damages from each company, plus penalties of $1 million per violation of Florida's antitrust statute and $10,000 for each violation of the state's Deceptive and Unfair Trade Practices Act.</p>
<p>&quot;Beginning in 1993, these companies increased the wholesale prices of their commercial sanitary paper products dramatically,&quot; Butterworth said.</p>
<p>&quot;Those price increases were made in virtual lockstep, indicating that the companies were working together to ensure higher prices to commercial consumers and larger, illegal profits for themselves,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Butterworth said the price hikes could not be justified by economic conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact, the price of wood pulp, the major component in poaper manufacturing, had declined 18 percent since 1989, while the wholesale price of commercial sanitary paper had increased by 41 percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Five of the companies -- Fort Howard, Georgia-Pacific, James River, Kimberly-Clark and Wisconsin Tissue -- together account for more than 80 percent of the national market for sanitary paper products, Butterworth said.</p>
<p>The five sell a combined $9 billion of products annually, one-third of which is bought by commercial users.</p>
<p>((--Miami Bureau, 305-374-5013))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLAHASSEE, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
