<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57946" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>COMOROS: Murderer publicly executed in Comoro Islands.</title>
<headline>Murderer publicly executed in Comoro Islands.</headline>
<dateline>MORONI 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A 25-year-old man convicted of murdering a pregnant woman was publicly executed on Tuesday by a five-man army firing squad on the Indian Ocean Comoro islands.</p>
<p>Ali Youssouf was given a bottle of a Fanta soft drink at his request before being tied to a post at the port in the capital Moroni. Magistrates turned down his request to speak to a reporter.</p>
<p>He was told to say his final prayers and then his head was covered in a hood. The five-man shooting squad, their faces covered by balaclavas, climbed out of a car which was parked nearby, took up their firing positions and gunned him down.</p>
<p>The squad returned to the car and drove out of the port at high speed to cheers and applause from thousands of onlookers who witnessed only the second public execution in Comoran recent history.</p>
<p>Youssouf's body was handed over to his family. He had been found guilty last month of murdering a pregnant woman in April.</p>
<p>The first public execution in Comoros since independence from France in 1975 was of a murderer put to death in 1978.</p>
<p>President Mohamed Taki, elected in March, has ordered the death penalty to be carried out for murder in a crackdown on crime. Ten people have been murdered in the last five months.</p>
<p>&quot;Someone who is tempted to kill a fellow human being will think twice before carrying out his foul enterprise,&quot; Taki said last month when he ordered the death penalty to be enforced.</p>
<p>Taki has also banned the import and sale of alcohol except to diplomats and tourists, and has condemned the wearing of miniskirts and short dresses in the mainly Islamic republic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MORONI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COMOROS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
