<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579476" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OPTIONS - Dollar vols pared as spot stabilizes.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - Dollar vols pared as spot stabilizes.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatilities for dollar-pair options retreated in U.S. trading Tuesday as the dollar steadied after a two-day selloff.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a lot of selling of yen volatility across the curve, in two, three and six months,&quot; said an options trader for a U.S. brokerage firm.</p>
<p>He said market participants were looking for dollar/yen to settle into a band between 117.00 and 121.00 yen. &quot;People are thinking the dollar is going to be rangebound,&quot; he said, but added that a fresh dip to 117.50 would reignite concern.  </p>
<p>The dollar was bid at 118.63 yen in early afternoon, near levels at midsession Monday.</p>
<p>A trader at a Japanese bank said the spot was still a little &quot;shaky&quot; and had the potential to push lower still, toward a test of important support around 115.00 to 114.50 yen.</p>
<p>As a result, said the trader, there was interest in buying one- and two-week dollar/yen options with high gamma. Shorter-dated options have higher gamma, which provides quicker premium acceleration when the spot moves.  </p>
<p>Implied volatility for one-week dollar/yen options was 11.5/12.5 percent, down 1.2 point from the previous session.</p>
<p>One-month fell to 9.7/9.9 percent from 11.0/11.3 percent quoted Monday. Three-month was 9.4/9.6 percent and one-year 9.3/9.5 percent, registering softer declines as the curve's inversion narrowed.</p>
<p>Dollar/mark volatilities edged back, with the curve essentially flat as the spot hovered around 1.6955 marks. One-month fell to 8.8/8.95 percent from 9.0/9.2. Tthree-month was 8.7/8.8 percent and one-year 8.65/8.8 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;People are not really panicking in dollar/mark as they were in dollar/yen,&quot; said the Japanese bank trader.</p>
<p>Mark/yen volatility, however, retained a strong bid, holding at 9.7/10.1 percent for one-month options as the focus remained on the downside after the cross on Monday broke through major support at 70.00, traders said.</p>
<p>One-month 25-delta dollar/pair risk reversals narrowed their currency call skew to 0.8/1.1 for yen calls and flat/0.3 for mark calls.</p>
<p>Chicago Derivatives Desk ((312-408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
