<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579581" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CoCensys licenses product to American Home.</title>
<headline>CoCensys licenses product to American Home.</headline>
<dateline>IRVINE, Calif. 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>CoCensys Inc said Tuesday it had licensed its new anxiety treatment product to Wyeth-Ayerst, a unit of American Home Products Corp, in an agreement that could be worth up to $59 million to CoCensys.</p>
<p>CoCensys said Wyeth-Ayerst will fund the development of the product, Co 2-6749, and its backup compounds.</p>
<p>Wyeth-Ayerst will make an up-front licensing payment of $5 million, and American Home Products will purchase $5 million of convertible preferred stock of CoCensys.  </p>
<p>The $59 million figure excludes clinical development costs, royalties and profit-sharing for the lead candidate.</p>
<p>Wyeth-Ayerst also will support CoCensys's research to identify back-up compounds and pay CoCensys up to $40 million in milestone payments depending on key development events and the outcome of product labeling, CoCensys said.</p>
<p>CoCensys and Wyeth-Ayerst will co-promote any resulting product in certain market segments in the United States. Wyeth-Ayerst will have rights to any resulting products in the rest of the world, subject to royalty payments.</p>
<p>Co 2-6749 is a synthetic version of a class of compounds called epalons, naturally occurring neuroactive compounds that have a calming role in the brain, CoCensys said.</p>
<p>CoCensys shares were up 1/8 to 4-1/4 in morning trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="IRVINE, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
