<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="57960" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Lebed says Russian Chechnya withdrawal will go on.</title>
<headline>Lebed says Russian Chechnya withdrawal will go on.</headline>
<byline>Arbi Zubairayev</byline>
<dateline>NOVYE ATAGI, Russia 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian security chief Alexander Lebed pledged on Tuesday that Moscow would push ahead with a planned troop withdrawal from Chechnya which was suspended last week.</p>
<p>Lebed, smiling and relaxed after talks with separatist leader Zelimkhan Yandarbiyev and rebel commander Aslan Maskhadov, said both sides had reconfirmed their commitment to a peace deal last month which set out terms for the pull-out.</p>
<p>&quot;We are continuing to move towards a durable, long and perhaps everlasting peace,&quot; Lebed told reporters in Novye Atagi, 20 km (12 miles) south of the Chechen capital Grozny.</p>
<p>He stood side by side with Maskhadov after the talks and they shook hands firmly. In a sign of improved relations between the two sides, Russian soldiers and rebel fighters quietly drank tea together outside the meeting.</p>
<p>Lebed, who is President Boris Yeltsin's personal envoy to Chechnya, flew to the mountainous southern region on Tuesday to try to shore up the August 31 peace deal after signs of strains.</p>
<p>The deal, which includes a five-year deferral of the question of Chechnya's future status, is intended to halt a 21-month-old conflict which has killed tens of thousands.</p>
<p>Lebed said he and the rebels had agreed to push ahead with the &quot;demilitarisation&quot; of Grozny under the deal and agreed in principle on the formation of a coalition government in Chechnya -- one of the potential sticking points.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no differences in principle between the federal side and the Chechen opposition on the formation of a coalition government,&quot; Lebed said.</p>
<p>An initial meeting to discuss the formation of the new government last week was boycotted by Chechnya's pro-Moscow leadership which says it is too early to talk about a coalition.</p>
<p>Lebed had held talks earlier on Tuesday with General Vyacheslav Tikhomirov, the Russian army commander in the region who suspended the withdrawal foreseen by the peace deal, citing a dispute over exchanging prisoners.</p>
<p>Lebed said he would also discuss setting up a &quot;joint commission&quot; in the near future, whose job would be to administer federal funds to rebuild Chechnya after nearly two years of war.</p>
<p>On his way to Chechnya, Lebed said he was unlikely to join Maskhadov at a meeting of the Council of Europe's parliamentary assembly in Strasbourg on September 23 because the separatists' Islamic legal code did not respect human rights.</p>
<p>The peace deal has received a lukewarm response from officials in Moscow. Some of these critics say the agreement amounts to capitulation by Moscow, whose troops have failed to crush the rebels' independence bid.</p>
<p>Lebed's role in Chechnya and beyond has been questioned by rivals in what appears to be a power struggle as Yeltsin prepares to have a heart operation.</p>
<p>The press service of Russia's Security Council, a group of top officials of which Lebed is secretary, issued a statement condemning critics who questioned Lebed's powers beyond Chechnya but said some reservations over his peace moves were &quot;normal&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The Security Council apparatus reacts calmly to the ambiguous assessments of the actions undertaken by A.I.Lebed to solve the Chechen crisis as a completely normal reaction to bold and extraordinary steps which need some time to be understood correctly,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NOVYE ATAGI, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
