<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579646" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Richardson hopeful of &quot;soft landing&quot; in Zaire.</title>
<headline>Richardson hopeful of &quot;soft landing&quot; in Zaire.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. ambassador Bill Richardson said on Tuesday he was hopeful of a peaceful transition in Zaire as a result of talks scheduled this week between leaders of both warring sides.</p>
<p>Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko and rebel leader Laurent Kabila were scheduled to meet on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Richarson, the U.S. top envoy to the United Nations, was speaking to reporters after briefing Security Council members on his own efforts during a recent visit to many of the countries involved in the Zaire crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is very important that the international community, the U.N., support South Africa's mediation efforts to bring Kabila and Mobutu (to) face-to-face talks,&quot; Richardson said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am encouraged with the potential of this meeting tomorrow, that it will lead to a soft landing, a peaceful transition,&quot; he said. &quot;It's my view that South Africa deserves enormous credit, (President) Nelson Mandela in particular, whose moral force has brought these two Zairean leaders together twice now. And I think we have to hope for the best in this meeting that will happen, hopefully, tomorrow.&quot;</p>
<p>Richardson said that during two meeting with Kabila he had &quot;pressed hard ... for a soft landing, for an inclusive transition, for an end to some of these disturbing humanitarian problems, and lastly for elections.&quot;</p>
<p>The United States had played the role of catalyst &quot;and now it's up to the African parties to come together and resolve this problem,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But I am optimistic that there will be a soft landing and a peaceful, inclusive transition, mainly because of South Africa's very strong and effective and skilful efforts in the past two days at mediating this crisis,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
