<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579640" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's Arthuis says EMU deficit target 3.0 pct.</title>
<headline>France's Arthuis says EMU deficit target 3.0 pct.</headline>
<byline>Myra MacDonald</byline>
<dateline>SENS, France 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Finance Minister Jean Arthuis said on Tuesday the target for budget deficits as a percentage of gross domestic product in the Maastricht treaty on monetary union was 3.0 percent.</p>
<p>Arthuis spoke to Reuters Financial Television before addressing a campaign rally for the ruling conservative coalition as France approaches the first round of a snap parliamentary election called by conservative President Jacques Chirac for May 25 and June 1.</p>
<p>Chirac, who had a crushing parliamentary majority, called the election on April 21 saying the country needed a &quot;new elan&quot; to build closer European integration and a single European currency from a position of strength.</p>
<p>In the interview, Arthuis was asked exactly what the target was in the treaty for allowing countries to join monetary union in 1999. Asked if it was 3.0 percent, he said &quot;Yes, 3.0 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>The Maastricht treaty allows the trend towards three percent to be taken into account in judging readiness for economic and monetary union (EMU), fueling speculation about whether a deficit of up to say, 3.4 or 3.5 percent would be acceptable.</p>
<p>As Europe nears a spring 1998 deadline for the start of the single currency, many countries, including EMU stalwarts Germany and France, are struggling to meet the three percent limit.</p>
<p>Arthuis also said he hoped as many countries as possible would join EMU in 1999.</p>
<p>He had been asked whether Italy would qualify to join at the launch of the euro.</p>
<p>&quot;We need the most members in the euro area on January 1, 1999. We trust Italian authorities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He gave no further details on this but said Europe would in any case &quot;have to support monetary stability&quot; between the euro and currencies of countries waiting to join.</p>
<p>Rome is imposing tough austerity measures on Italy to qualify on time for EMU and is furious with some European officials for casting doubt on whether it will meet the targets.</p>
<p>Arthuis also said French economic growth would be at least 2.3 percent in 1997 and a minimum of 2.8 percent next year.</p>
<p>The government's official forecasts are for 2.3 percent this year and 2.8 percent in 1998 though economists have suggested these forecasts could be distorted by the effect on investment of an early May-June parliamentary election.</p>
<p>&quot;Growth is on the right trend. At least 2.3 percent for 1997 and certainly 2.8 percent for 1998,&quot; he said. He added that 2.8 percent &quot;is a minimum for 1998.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SENS, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
