<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579614" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Chirac seeks political, trade boost in China trip.</title>
<headline>Chirac seeks political, trade boost in China trip.</headline>
<byline>Marie-Benedicte Allaire</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac will be seeking both a political boost and a bigger slice of trade with one of the world's fastest-growing economies when he begins a four-day visit to China on Thursday.</p>
<p>On the first state visit to China by a French leader for 14 years, Chirac aims to renew the warm relations his mentor, Charles de Gaulle, established with Beijing in 1964 and reap lucrative benefits for French industry.</p>
<p>Presidential spokeswoman Catherine Colonna stressed Chirac's first objective, in talks with President Jiang Zemin and Prime Minister Li Peng, was to build a political partnership with one of the great world powers of the turn of the 21st century.</p>
<p>But the president is taking along 56 business leaders, underlining the scale of his economic hopes, and will in Shanghai tour the biggest French technology fair ever staged abroad.</p>
<p>The trip has been curtailed due to France's parliamentary election campaign, with a planned stopover in Hong Kong dropped.</p>
<p>Political sources said Chirac hoped to help his centre-right coalition in the May 25-June 1 vote with pictures of himself building a new partnership with Chinese leaders and promoting French and European goods in the giant Chinese market.</p>
<p>He may also use two speeches to French residents in Beijing and Shanghai to comment on domestic politics.</p>
<p>Paris has been wooing China for months, blocking efforts for a joint European Union resolution criticising Beijing's human rights record at the United Nations and suggesting the time has come to ease an EU embargo on arms sales to the Asian giant.</p>
<p>France missed out on China's economic boom in the early 1990s after the late Socialist president Francois Mitterrand criticised a 1989 crackdown on a student-led democracy movement in Beijing and sold fighter planes and warships to Taiwan.</p>
<p>Partly as a result, Paris ranks a lowly number 13 in exports to China, and trade growth has been slow since relations were normalised in 1994 under former prime minister Edouard Balladur.</p>
<p>Colonna said Chirac wanted to establish an &quot;industrial partnership&quot; with Beijing and open up new sectors such as insurance, agriculture and the space industry while developing cooperation between China and the European Airbus consortium.</p>
<p>On the economic front, &quot;his ambition is that China becomes one of our major partners. He wants France to participate fully in the development and modernisation of China,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Airbus Industrie has bid for China's requirement for 100 narrow-body passenger aircraft, estimated to be worth about $5 billion.</p>
<p>The European rival to the U.S. Boeing Co scored a commercial and political coup last April, during an official visit to France by Li Peng, when the Chinese authorities ordered 30 Airbus planes and signed a deal to work on a new 100-seater jet.</p>
<p>Colonna said Chirac would sign a joint political declaration and ministers would sign five inter-government agreements during the visit.</p>
<p>Asked whether the president would raise human rights issues, she said he would stress that during this &quot;important, delicate phase&quot; of reforms in China, he would stress dialogue rather than confrontation. But he might take up individual cases discreetly.</p>
<p>The French League of Human Rights (LDH) asked Chirac to meet or pay tribute to dissidents, including Wei Jingsheng who is serving a 29-year sentence and Ding Zilin who has been compiling the names of those who died in the repression of pro-democracy supporters since her son was killed on Tiananmen square.</p>
<p>Chirac will also make a speech on &quot;the rule of law&quot; at Beijing's civil service college on Friday.</p>
<p>French officials insist China is making progress in enacting laws enshrining civil rights, despite fierce criticism by human rights organisations.</p>
<p>Balladur's 1994 visit was marred by the detention of prominent human rights activists apparently timed to show that Beijing's Communist rulers were immune to foreign pressure.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
