<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="579816" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Bajaj Auto growth seen slowing.</title>
<headline>India's Bajaj Auto growth seen slowing.</headline>
<byline>Priya Ramani</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's scooter giant Bajaj Auto will see sluggish growth in the financial year ended March 31 due to a prolonged industrial slowdown that hit vehicle sales during the period, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said the firm -- among the world's largest makers of two-wheel vehicles -- was likely to announce a net profit of 4.5 billion rupees ($125 million), up about eight percent from 4.18 billion in 1995/96. Results for the 1996/97 financial year are due on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Bajaj Auto's net profit surged nearly 40 percent in 1995/96 from the previous year.</p>
<p>&quot;Fundamentally it's a very strong company, but a number of two-wheeler manufacturers were caught at the back end of a cycle in the second half of the financial year,&quot; said Rakesh Parekh, automobile analyst at Caspian Securities.</p>
<p>Parekh was referring to an industrial slowdown that has dampened consumer demand across-the-board since the middle of calendar 1996.</p>
<p>Latest government data shows industrial output grew at just 7.5 percent in the first 10 months of 1996/97, compared with 11.7 percent in the corresponding period.</p>
<p>Bajaj Auto manufactures scooters, motorycles, mopeds -- lightweight mini-powered scooters -- and three-wheel vehicles.</p>
<p>Its overall vehicle sales climbed a modest 113,857 units, or 8.7 percent, to 1.41 million units during 1996/97, according to industry data released last month.</p>
<p>&quot;Bajaj is in a price-sensitive market...where sales have a big correlation to economic trends,&quot; said K.N. Sreenivasan, automobile analyst at Jardine Fleming India Broking.</p>
<p>&quot;The sales slowdown is a reflection of the general weakness in the economy,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Automobile analyst Anupam Thareja at securities firm HSBC B&amp;K Securities said scooter sales were hardest hit as urban demand for consumer durables slackened.</p>
<p>&quot;Urban demand just didn't pick up. It was a turmoil-filled year for urban areas with high interest rates, a petrol price hike and political uncertainties,&quot; Thareja said.</p>
<p>He said the slowdown in scooter demand also reflected a shift to motorcycles and other hybrid vehicles.</p>
<p>Analysts said they expected scooter sales to remain weak during the first quarter of the current fiscal year.</p>
<p>They estimated April sales figures for Bajaj Auto at 87,862 units, down from 105,967 units in April 1996. Official figures are due to be released later this month.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem of economic weakness is continuing,&quot; said Sreenivasan. He said his firm expected a recovery to begin by September when lower interest rates would kickstart the economy.</p>
<p>The federal budget for 1997/98 (April-March) -- which slashed personal and corporate taxes across the board -- would also raise disposable incomes, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a cyclical stock which can be bought at lower levels of below 800 rupees,&quot; Sreenivasan said.</p>
<p>Bajaj Auto shares have fallen more than 100 rupees, or 11 percent, since the March automobile figures hit the market. It was trading 6.25 rupees lower at 840 in late trade on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're asking investors to wait and watch and get into the stock after three months,&quot; HSBC's Thareja said.</p>
<p>($1 = 35.85 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
