<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="580114" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - UK's C&amp;W confirms Singapore fixed-line plans.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - UK's C&amp;W confirms Singapore fixed-line plans.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cable and Wireless Plc, Britain's second biggest telecoms company, confirmed on Tuesday that it was joining its subsidiary Hong Kong Telecommunications Ltd and two Singapore groups in a bid for a fixed-wire licence in Singapore.</p>
<p>The consortium -- which includes diversified conglomerate The Keppel Group and publisher Singapore Press Holdings Ltd and is called MobileOne or M1 -- had already indicated that it wanted to bid for a fixed licence.</p>
<p>The licence will complement its mobile telephone services -- the first network to compete against incumbent Singapore Telecommunications' (SingTel) monopoly.</p>
<p>Cable and Wireless' arch-rival, British Telecommunications Plc has already signed up with Japan's Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Corp and two Singapore companies to bid for a fixed-line licence. A bid for a licence to provide cellular services has also not been ruled out.</p>
<p>The Singapore government, which will award a second basic telecoms licence in 1998, has said it will allow one, or possibly two, new groups to operate such services from 2000 to compete with the current monopoly held by SingTel.</p>
<p>Foreign investment in any project in Singapore is limited to 49 percent and C&amp;W said the shareholding structure of the new joint venture company was still being finalised.</p>
<p>&quot;We are keenly interested in the fixed wire opportunity in Singapore, as it would enable us to dig our roots deeper in a market where we have quickly become established though M1,&quot; C&amp;W's chief executive Richard Brown said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The combination of Cable and Wireless' worldwide expertise, Hong Kong Telecom's regional experience and the local market knowledge of Keppel and SPH makes us a powerful contender.&quot;</p>
<p>The Keppel Group is one of the largest and most widely diversified conglomerates in Singapore whose businesses span ship repair, shipbuilding, property, banking, telecoms and engineering.</p>
<p>Singapore Press Holdings (SPH) is one of the region's largest publishers and a key information and communications company in Singapore.</p>
<p>Cable and Wireless said in a statement released in London that its M1 partnership wanted to operate a fixed-line network from April 1, 2000.</p>
<p>The Singapore government is also offering two new mobile telephone licences as part of its plans to open up its telecommunications industry after the year 2000.</p>
<p>These licences will be &quot;synchronized&quot; with the mid-1998 announcement of basic service network licences. Bidders who win both types of licence will be able to integrate their network roll-outs when basic services competition begins in 2000.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday, the M1 partnership, which began operating a cellular and pager network last month, stepped up Singapore's pager war, slashing prices by 37 percent and undercutting SingTel.</p>
<p>To date, the venture has won over 40,000 customers from Singapore's three million population, Cable and Wireless said on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
