<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="58017" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: High radiation in Chernobyl &quot;sarcophagus&quot;.</title>
<headline>High radiation in Chernobyl &quot;sarcophagus&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Rostislav Khotin</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Radiation levels rose sharply inside the Chernobyl nuclear power plant's ruined fourth reactor and scientists are investigating whether this could lead to a chain reaction, a director said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Valentyn Kupny, in charge of the &quot;sarcophagus&quot; surrounding the reactor, said meters inside the cracking steel and concrete structure had shown big increases for a time on Monday.</p>
<p>Kupny said three of 10 meters had shown increases in neutron radiation inside the sarcophagus, the protective casing hurriedly erected after the fourth reactor exploded on April 26, 1986 and sent radiation over much of Europe.</p>
<p>He said a commission had been set up to examine the incident, the third in 10 years.</p>
<p>&quot;The latest increases were temporary. No final conclusions were drawn from the earlier instances whether a chain reaction had been started,&quot; Kupny said by telephone from Chernobyl, 140 km (90 miles) north of Kiev.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything that is inside has not been fully studied or understood. We do not have a sufficiently complete control system.&quot;</p>
<p>If a chain reaction was produced, he said, &quot;it would not be an explosion or some huge noisy process. But it could involve a big release of radiation into the atmosphere&quot;.</p>
<p>Ukrainian officials say rebuilding the sarcophagus is the top priority in making safe and closing down the Chernobyl plant, where two reactors still produce five percent of the country's electricity.</p>
<p>President Leonid Kuchma has promised to close the two reactors still functioning at Chernobyl by the year 2000, but officials say they cannot meet the deadline unless the West begins providing some of the more than $3 billion it has agreed to provide in aid and loans.</p>
<p>Experts differ on how much fuel remains inside the reactor, with estimates ranging from 90 to 160 tonnes.</p>
<p>A Western-backed project to build a new sarcophagus, estimated to cost $1.2 billion, was first made public three years ago but no steps have yet been taken to build it.</p>
<p>Kupny said the project, designed by a Franco-British consortium was a &quot;dead letter&quot; as no financing had been found.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
