<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="580356" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Novartis buys Merck unit for $910 mln.</title>
<headline>Novartis buys Merck unit for $910 mln.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Novartis AG said Tuesday it had bought Merck &amp; Co Inc's crop protection business for $910 million.</p>
<p>The company said the deal included the worldwide rights to the unit's business, which had 1996 sales of $200 million.</p>
<p>&quot;(It had) a strong position in the high-value acaricide/insecticide and post-harvest fungicide markets,&quot; it said, referring to the products that protect crops against mites, insects and fungi.  </p>
<p>Novartis, which specializes in chemicals and pharmaceuticals, said the deal also included about $21 million in product inventories.</p>
<p>It said it expected to close the deal &quot;this summer.&quot;</p>
<p>Merck said in a separate statement that the sale of the unit was part of its strategy to focus on its core human and animal health businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;Merck and Rhone-Poulenc will combine their animal health and poultry genetics businesses to form a new company, called Merial,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>A spokesman for Merck said Novartis made what the company considered was the best offer despite a number of other &quot;financially aggressive&quot; bidders.</p>
<p>Novartis said crop protection activities have been &quot;very consistently profitable&quot; with sales growing at a compounded annual growth rate of 12 percent during the last four years.</p>
<p>&quot;Gross profit and operating income have grown at a compounded annual growth rate of 12 and 13 percent, respectively,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The closing of the deal is subject to government approvals and other customary closing conditions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
