<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="580491" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Portugal's EDP to cut jobs by year 2000.</title>
<headline>Portugal's EDP to cut jobs by year 2000.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Portuguese state electricity company EDP-Electricidade de Portugal, due to be partially sold off next month, will cut its workforce by less than 2,500 before the year 2000, its president Antonio de Almeida said.</p>
<p>&quot;The job cuts will not be confrontational and will be based on early retirement and agreements between the company and workers,&quot; Almeida said at a seminar on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will reduce personnel by less than half what has been said in the newspapers,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He was referring to a report in Diario de Noticias newspaper on Saturday, which said the company would cut some 5,000 jobs, almost a third of the workforce, in a cost cutting programme.</p>
<p>Almeida's remarks were confirmed on Tuesday by a source linked to the board of the company.</p>
<p>Almeida told the Portuguese news agency Lusa: &quot;Without the foreseen job cuts, EDP's growth plan up to 2000 would be compromised.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he expected that around 30 percent of EDP would be privatised, but a final decision would depend on a decision from the Socialist government of Prime Minister Antonio Guterres.</p>
<p>&quot;If the state sold up to 49 percent of the company, it would be committing a financial and political error, and would risk losing money,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added: &quot;By privatising just 30 percent of the capital, expectations are created for a new phase of privatisation, and this will push up the value of the shares in the capital market.&quot;</p>
<p>By law, the government may sell off up to 49 percent of EDP, Portugal's dominant electricity generator and distributor.</p>
<p>The Portuguese cabinet was expected to set maximum and minimum prices in the privatisation on Thursday, a source close to the process has said.</p>
<p>After the start of the bookbuilding, and based on these price indications, the cabinet would set the quantities to be sold in the public offer for sale (OPV) and the direct sale.</p>
<p>The price in the OPV will be fixed at a level between the maximum and minimum prices by Under-Secretary for Finance Fernando Teixeira Santos on June 16, the date of the OPV.</p>
<p>-- David Brough, Lisbon newsroom +(351-1) 3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
