<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="580457" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Ireland airports operator upbeat after record 1996.</title>
<headline>Ireland airports operator upbeat after record 1996.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Irish airports authority Aer Rianta said on Tuesday it expected an &quot;excellent&quot; year after a record 11.96 million passengers passed through the Republic of Ireland's three main airports in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Business has been very strong for the Aer Rianta group and all the indications are that 1997 will be another excellent year. Passenger traffic is ahead of budget and duty free sales are again outperforming their projected levels,&quot; Aer Rianta said in a statement.</p>
<p>In 1996, pre-tax profit totalled 42.4 million Irish pounds ($64.1 million), up 13 percent from a year earlier. That matched the percentage increase in passenger numbers, which was driven by strong economic growth and low fares, Aer Rianta said.</p>
<p>Total group revenue rose by nine percent to 231 million Irish pounds while net profit increased by 16 percent to 39.4 million.</p>
<p>Aer Rianta said Dublin, Shannon and Cork airports were all in surplus last year. Dublin airport, the group's biggest earner, returned a record pretax profit of 37.9 million Irish pounds and accounted for just over nine million passengers.</p>
<p>Cork airport had a surplus of 2.4 million and Shannon reported a 2.38 million surplus.</p>
<p>Aer Rianta said the cargo sector had also performed well, growing by 18 percent last year to 146,681 tonnes.</p>
<p>The group said while consistent passenger traffic growth was welcome as one of the key drivers of profitability in Aer Rianta, it placed a tremendous strain on existing infrastructure and facilities at its airports.</p>
<p>Aer Rianta said a major capital development programme was now well under way to cater for the expected growth and approximately 140 million Irish pounds would be invested at Dublin, Cork and Shannon airports over the next five years.</p>
<p>Capital expenditure in 1996 dipped 5.8 percent to 22.6 million Irish pounds. ($ = 0.661 Irish Pounds)</p>
<p>-- Tony Roddam, Dublin newsroom +353-1-661-3377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
