<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="58055" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech bank policy takes new turn, analysts.</title>
<headline>Czech bank policy takes new turn, analysts.</headline>
<byline>Robin Shepherd</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech National Bank (CNB) on Tuesday moved to avert the country's most serious banking crisis so far putting the largest fully-private domestic bank, Agrobanka a.s., under temporary forced administration.</p>
<p>Agrobanka, which the CNB said had liquidity problems connected with the collapse of another bank last month, is the 12th Czech bank to be put under the supervision of the CNB since the economic reform process began in earnest in 1991.</p>
<p>But the pre-emptive nature of the latest moves marks a new departure for policy makers accustomed to allowing market forces to take their course, stepping in to clear up the mess only as failing banks crash through the floor.</p>
<p>On Tuesday morning the CNB said that it would guarantee all Agrobanka's obligations, including interest payments, which are on the books of Agrobanka's accounting as of September 17, 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;I think its a landmark. The government will regulate the banking sector more closely from now on,&quot; said Michael Gartner of ING Barings in Prague.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has had its fingers burnt with a tide of failures and...decided it would be political suicide if Agrobanka went under, even if at considerable cost to the taxpayer,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In 1995 Agrobanka had four percent of the country's loan portfolio and five percent of total deposits making it by far the biggest Czech bank to have run into serious problems.</p>
<p>Although significantly smaller than the Czech Republic's &quot;banking four&quot; - Komercni Banka a.s, Ceska Sporitelna a.s. Ceskoslovenska Obchodni Banka a.s. and IPB a.s. - it is a major holder of deposits of state institutions such as the health and agricultural funds.</p>
<p>Jan Vlachy, vice-chairman of investment bank Patria Finance, interpreted the official response to the Agrobanka situation not so much as a move away from laissez-faire as a simple need to protect its own finances.</p>
<p>&quot;Agrobanka holds huge deposits by government institutions like the health fund and probably huge losses can be avoided by the government this way,&quot; said Vlachy.</p>
<p>The Czech banking sector has long been viewed with caution by analysts sceptical of the strength of loan portfolios and the quality of management.</p>
<p>Questions have also been raised about the integrity and motives of secretive investment groups which have become involved throughout the country's financial sector.</p>
<p>But most investors draw a sharp distinction between the troubled smaller and medium-sized banks and the &quot;Big Four&quot;, in which the state has significant stakes and have solid credit ratings.</p>
<p>Ironically, most analysts said that the Agrobanka crisis could have the effect of strengthening confidence in the big banks, since investors now have evidence that the government will intervene when the troubled bank is big enough.</p>
<p>&quot;Size was the most important crtiteria here so it may even be welcomed by investors,&quot; said Pavel Sobisek of Zivnostensk Banka.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
