<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="580536" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: FOCUS - De Boer, Unigro detail merger.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - De Boer, Unigro detail merger.</headline>
<byline>Christine Lucassen</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Food wholesaling and supermarket groups De Boer Winkelbedrijven NV and unlisted Unigro on Tuesday unveiled details of the merger which will propel them to the number two slot in the Dutch grocery sector after Ahold NV.</p>
<p>The deal, finalised on May 2 subject to shareholders' approval and retroactive to January 1 this year, will create a combine with annual turnover of more than six billion guilders ($3.1 billion). The merger was announced in October.</p>
<p>Benefits are expected to kick in almost straight away, resulting in a clear increase in net profits per share in 1997, the new combine said.</p>
<p>&quot;Barring unforeseen circumstances (and) based on the present state of affairs...the boards of both companies expect a clear increase of the net result per De Boer Unigro share for the financial year started January 1, 1997,&quot; they said.</p>
<p>The combine's pro-forma net profit for 1996 amounted to 90.1 million guilders or 8.48 guilders per share on combined turnover of 6.4 billion guilders, the companies said.</p>
<p>In the years after 1997, De Boer Unigro is targeting average annual net profit growth of 10 percent, they said, adding the combine would maintain De Boer's current dividend policy of an average 35 percent pay-out from ordinary profits after tax.</p>
<p>In its year ending January 31 1997 Unigro posted net profits of 32.2 million guilder on turnover of 4.25 billion.</p>
<p>De Boer was smaller but more profitable with a 1996 net profit of 35.2 million guilders on turnover of 2.11 billion.</p>
<p>The new combine will operate a string of large Super De Boer supermarkets and local Spar convenience stores throughout the Netherlands, as well as drugstore and liquor store chains.</p>
<p>In Belgium it also operates a Spar chain and in Spain it owns Super El Arbol supermarkets, where annual turnover is targeted to double to 2.5 billion guilders within five years.</p>
<p>In the Netherlands, the combine will restructure to boost efficiency, shedding an estimated 250-300 jobs, and closing four distribution centres over the next three years. The two companies combined currently employ 10,000 people.</p>
<p>The restructuring will be financed by a 72 million guilder provision to be charged to De Boer Unigro shareholders' equity.</p>
<p>The firms said they planned a five-for-two stock split after the merger, which will be effected by means of a share swap.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the merger all Unigro shares will transferred to De Boer, which will subsequently place 6.05 million new shares plus one million warrants with Unigro's original shareholder, it said.</p>
<p>After the merger, the Unigro holding company will own some 57 percent of outstanding De Boer Unigro shares, which it will reduce to 49.9 percent at most within six months.</p>
<p>In addition the holding company has undertaken to transfer all shares held above 35 percent to an independent foundation.</p>
<p>&quot;Partly as a result, the major shareholder will not have a controlling interest in De Boer Unigro's business,&quot; the companies added.</p>
<p>De Boer shares were up 8.50 guilders or 5.6 percent at 159.50 on the news at 1020 GMT, markedly outpacing a 1.2 percent rise on the Amsterdam MidCap index. ($ = 1.910 Dutch Guilders)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
