<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="580626" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss bank SBC optimistic on 1997 outlook.</title>
<headline>Swiss bank SBC optimistic on 1997 outlook.</headline>
<dateline>BASLE, Switzerland 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss Bank Corp chairman Georges Blum said he was cautiously optimistic about prospects for 1997.</p>
<p>SBC in a statement quoted chief executive Marcel Ospel as adding that the group anticipates net profit after tax of 1.7 billion Swiss francs ($1.2 billion) in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Commenting on the 1996 group financial statements, chairman of the board Georges Blum assessed the prospects for the current year as cautiously optimistic,&quot; SBC said in a statement summarising speeches prepared for the annual shareholders meeting.</p>
<p>The statement also quoted from chief executive Marcel Ospel's speech to the meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if we cannot simply extrapolate the good results of the first quarter for the whole year, we still anticipate net profits after-tax of 1.7 billion Swiss francs in 1997,&quot; Ospel said.</p>
<p>SBC on May 9 said first quarter results were excellent, benefiting from restructuring moves launched last year and from a strong performance in securities markets in the first three months.</p>
<p>SBC posted a 1996 net profit before extraordinaries of 1.328 billion Swiss francs, but took a one-off charge for provisioning and restructuring that knocked the results to a net loss of 1.955 billion.</p>
<p>SBC last September forecast a 1997 net profit of 1.7 billion francs.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340 ($ = 1.433 Swiss Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BASLE, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
