<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="580758" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia govt plans crackdown on dividend washing.</title>
<headline>Australia govt plans crackdown on dividend washing.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Treasurer Peter Costello said on Tuesday the government planned to crack down on the trading of franking credits, known as dividend washing, and on dividend streaming to protect the tax base.</p>
<p>The move is seen restricting trade of franking credits and the practice of dividend streaming, which are worth hundreds of millions of dollars a year.</p>
<p>&quot;I am announcing measures to protect the integrity of the company tax imputation system, to deal with dividend streaming and franking credit trading,&quot; Costello said in his 1997/98 budget speech.  </p>
<p>In an accompanying statement, Costello said arrangements that allow franking credits to be transferred by separating legal ownership from the economic risks of share ownership undermined the principles under which franking credits tax law was created.</p>
<p>&quot;To allow such arrangements to continue would bring into question the affordability of the imputation system as originally designed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The government would change tax law to;</p>
<p>* limit the source of franking credits available for trading,  </p>
<p>* prevent short term credit trading,</p>
<p>* prevent longer term transfer arrangements,</p>
<p>* and, provide for a general anti-avoidance rule.</p>
<p>Costello said the government would also introduce measures to stop the unintended use of franking credits through dividend streaming arrangements.</p>
<p>He said dividend streaming undermined accepted tax principles by attributing tax paid on behalf of shareholders to only some of them by allowing the streaming of franking credits to maximise their value to certain shareholders over others.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
