<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="58115" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - September 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - September 17.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the reports carried by Estonia's newspapers on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- USAID is to end its programme in Estonia on September 30, saying the country no longer needs its support.</p>
<p>SONUMILEHT</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Tiit Vaehi is unworried by Russia's threats of economic sanctions but the parliament economics commission head Mati Moes described the threats as serious.</p>
<p>- State Inspector Hindrek Meri described the sale of shares of Eesti Gaas in 1993 as unethical, saying the economy minister at the time, Toivo Jurgenson, also benefited from the sale.</p>
<p>- Over 89 percent of Estonians consider their country worth defending and over 60 percent support doubling defence spending.</p>
<p>EESTI PAEVALEHT</p>
<p>- Parliament vice-chairman Tunne Kelam is expected to agree to stand as presidential candidate today.</p>
<p>- The Baltic Assembly arts and literature jury gave the 1996 science award to Estonian art historian Juhan Maiste; Latvian composer Peteris Vasks received the art award and Lithuanian poet Juditas Vaiciunaite the literature award.</p>
<p>POSTIMEES</p>
<p>- Former defence forces chief Aleksander Einseln accused President Lennart Meri of being behind what he calls his persecution by the security police.</p>
<p>- The criminal police says it doubts the existence of a serial killer in the northeastern town of Narva where five women have been attacked in August and September, four of whom were murdered.</p>
<p>- Alternative presidential candidates may be put up today as Tunne Kelam and the Centre Party's Siiri Oviir are expected to announce their decisions. So far the only definite candidates are Arnold Ruutel and incumbent Lennart Meri.</p>
<p>ARIPAEV</p>
<p>- Swedish Finance Ministere Erik Asbrink announced during his visit to Estonia that Sweden supports Estonia's policy of joining the European Union (EU) but stressed the importance of measures against inflation and money laundering.</p>
<p>- Shipping firms argue with the tax department about millions of kroons of unpaid taxes.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
