<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="581370" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian Occidental CEO Hentschel resigns.</title>
<headline>Canadian Occidental CEO Hentschel resigns.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian Occidental Chief Executive David Hentschel, having just engineered the oil company's biggest-ever merger, said on Wednesday he would step down as top officer after just a year and a half at his post.</p>
<p>Hentchel said he would rejoin CanOxy's parent company, Los Angeles-based Occidental Petroleum Corp, as chairman and chief executive of unit Occidental Oil &amp; Gas effective June 1.</p>
<p>CanOxy chairman Ray Irani told the company's annual meeting that Vic Zaleschuk, now CanOxy's chief financial offer, would replace Hentchel.  </p>
<p>Also as part of the management shuffle, Vice-President Charlie Fischer, in charge of North American oil and gas operations since 1994, was promoted to chief operating officer.</p>
<p>Hentschel, a 63-year-old career oilman, has been credited with building on the company's successful Yemen operations by bolstering exploration and production activity in North America, the United States, Southeast Asia, west Africa and South America.  </p>
<p>His major achievement, which has been lauded by analysts and investors, was CanOxy's C$2-billion takeover of Regina, Saskatchewan-based heavy oil producer Wascana Energy Inc. last month.</p>
<p>The deal, which places CanOxy among Canada's top three oil and gas companies in production, was aimed at giving the company low-risk production and cash flow immediately to balance off high-risk international exploration plays.</p>
<p>CanOxy's stock on the Toronto Stock Exchange climbed to a high this week of C$28.86 from from C$23.50 just before it announced its friendly offer for Wascana on March 17.  </p>
<p>The company's shares were off by 40 cents after Hentschel's announcement to C$28.15 in busy volume of 1.5 million shares.</p>
<p>Kansas-born Hentschel told reporters after the meeting that he did not come to Canada out of retirement in late 1995 to specifically ink a major deal, but the move satisfied his objectives as chief executive.</p>
<p>&quot;I came up here to hopefully supervise the growth of the company. The Wascana opportunity only surfaced in about November of last year,&quot; he said. The successful deal, however, did hasten his departure, he said.</p>
<p>Hentschel, a veteran of the Oxy organization, said one of his tasks was to take the helm while successors from within Canada could be groomed, which was accomplished with the promotions of Zaleschuk and Fischer.</p>
<p>&quot;There are two guys who have come to the front and they're really the guys most of us suspected,&quot; Craig Langpap, analyst with Peters &amp; Co Ltd said. &quot;David really helped position them mentor them, develop them...to be ready to take on that role.&quot;</p>
<p>CanOxy on Wednesday reported first-quarter earnings of C$73 million or C$0.53 a share, up from C$50 million or C$0.37 a share last year.</p>
<p>Cash flow rose to C$217 million or C$1.59 a share, up from C$188 million or C$1.39 a share in the first quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>Hentchel said he expected 1997 earnings to fall by a maximum of C$50 million this year from C$190 reported in 1996 as a result of the Wascana acquisition. But profits were expected to be back on track in 1998, he said.</p>
<p>Production for 1997 is projected at an average of 230,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day, up from 178,000 in 1996.</p>
<p>CanOxy is 30 percent owned by Occidental. ((Jeffrey Jones, Reuters Calgary Bureau (403) 531-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
