<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="581668" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GOLF-LANGER REFUSES TO BE WRITTEN OFF.</title>
<headline>GOLF-LANGER REFUSES TO BE WRITTEN OFF.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>When Bernhard Langer ended his 1996 season on the European Tour without a victory, there was a tendency to write him off as one of the game's leading players.</p>
<p>But since then he has rebuffed his critics in comprehensive style, culminating last weekend in his second successive win on the European Tour.</p>
<p>It had all looked very different just a few months ago. After all, he was in his 40th year, he had just seen a streak of 16 years each containing at least one Tour victory broken, health problems had dogged him all year and his putting had turned sour again.</p>
<p>Seve Ballesteros of Spain, one of his great rivals through those halcyon years, had already been sucked into the downward spiral. Now it looked as if it was Langer's turn.</p>
<p>Yet the doughty and highly respected German wasted no time putting to rest the notion that he was a fading force. Within a week of the European season ending, he bounced back by winning the Alfred Dunhill Classic in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>It was his first victory for 13 months and it set him up for a return to the sort of form that had yielded 34 wins in Europe as well as two U.S. Masters triumphs over a 16-year span.</p>
<p>This month he boosted that European total to 36 -- and his international total to 49 -- with consecutive triumphs in the Italian Open at Brescia and the Benson and Hedges International at the windswept and rain-plagued Oxfordshire Course northwest of London on Sunday.</p>
<p>Not only did that hoist him to the top of the European Order of Merit -- a list he headed in 1981 and 1984 -- it also lifted him into second place on the Ryder Cup list, virtually ensuring a ninth successive appearance against the Americans at Valderrama in September.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought it might be July or August before that happened. I'm surprised it has come so quickly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Langer had problems with both shoulders last year, the right early in 1996 and the left after his opening round in the British Open, where he withdrew the following morning.</p>
<p>He also had pains in both forearms as well as a problem with a knuckle on his right hand which still hurts.</p>
<p>The most important change for Langer, however, was his switch last year to a long-handled putter to help overcome his recurring problem with the &quot;yips&quot;, the involuntary spasm that sometimes hits players when they are putting.</p>
<p>He had solved the problem three times before, the third time with a bizarre variation on the putting grip which involved holding the club down the shaft with one hand and clasping the grip and the other forearm together further up the shaft.</p>
<p>He was successful with it for a time but even that failed him last year.</p>
<p>So with no ideological qualms at all about  shifting to a method that notables including American Tom Watson had always regarded as being against the spirit of the game, Langer made the change to the long-handled putter late last year.</p>
<p>He had no reservations about joining the growing number using the longer club, which players grip halfway down with one hand and at the top with the other, swinging it with a pendulum motion.</p>
<p>&quot;You still have to make a stroke, the only difference is that you have your hands apart, but you can have your hands apart on a short putter if you want,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;You've still got to move the putter, it doesn't go by itself just because it's longer.&quot;</p>
<p>He had tried it a few years earlier. &quot;I had a few gos with it and thought there's no way I can putt with that thing. I just didn't think I could use it.</p>
<p>&quot;But once I spent a bit of time with it I got more and more confident and comfortable with it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt a lot better on the shorter ones and I didn't have much problem with the longer ones either. I'm just more relaxed over the ball.&quot;</p>
<p>He made the change for the Lancome Trophy event near Paris last October, just a few weeks after he had been quoted as saying he was actually thinking of giving up the game.</p>
<p>He denies ever suggesting such a thing. &quot;I'm not one to chuck it in and give it up, I'm one to grind it out and find a solution,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm far too competitive to give it up. I still enjoy playing tremendously and I'd like to do it for many more years so there was never any serious thought about that,&quot; he said. Now that his best form has come flooding back, Langer is hoping to boost his meagre total of major titles from the pair he won at Augusta in 1985 and 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel I have more majors in me,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He is taking this week off before returning to England for the Anderson Consulting European Championship, the two-day match play event next Monday and Tuesday that will produce a European semifinalist for next January's world final in Arizona.</p>
<p>Then three days later he will set out in search of a fourth British PGA title at Wentworth where he has won three times before -- and where he holds the 18-under-par championship record of 270 for the event rated second to the British Open on the European Tour.</p>
<p>That was back in 1987, in the middle of his good years which many had felt were over for the resolute German.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
