<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="581685" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL ICE HOCKEY-RANGERS CRASH STANLEY CUP FINAL FOUR.</title>
<headline>NHL ICE HOCKEY-RANGERS CRASH STANLEY CUP FINAL FOUR.</headline>
<byline>Bill Berkrot</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>By picking off the two best defensive teams in the National Hockey League, the New York Rangers crashed the Stanley Cup final four, joining three clubs with legitimate invitations to the party.</p>
<p>The defending champion Colorado Avalanche, perennial contenders the Detroit Red Wings and the oversized Philadelphia Flyers were all expected to still be on their feet at this late stage of the Stanley Cup dance marathon.</p>
<p>But the ageing Rangers, an inconsistent, middle-of-the pack team throughout the regular season, suddenly have all kinds of spring in their step long after they were supposed to have traded their dancing shoes for golf cleats.</p>
<p>And while New York will again be prohibitive underdogs when they face the Flyers in the best-of-seven Eastern Conference finals beginning Friday in Philadelphia, they come in with the single most valuable commodity any team with its eye on the Stanley Cup can have -- a red hot goaltender.</p>
<p>Asked what strategy they employed to subdue the New Jersey Devils in the previous round, Rangers coach Colin Campbell admitted: &quot;Obviously our sytem was basically Mike Richter.&quot;</p>
<p>The Devils, the top team in the East, finished the regular season 18 points ahead of the Rangers and had not lost more than two games in a row before dropping four straight to New York -- thanks primarily to Richter's heroics.</p>
<p>The Most Valuable Player of September's World Cup after backstopping the United States to a surprise victory over Canada, Richter is at it again, turning in one stunning performance in goal after another.</p>
<p>The Rangers have played surprisingly disciplined defence this post-season. But each time the increasingly frustrated Devils turned up the heat, Richter loomed large in his net, allowing just four goals in five games against New Jersey.</p>
<p>In the last two, Richter faced 82 shots and gave up one goal -- and that on a play when he was badly screened.</p>
<p>&quot;Ricky's been spectacular the whole playoffs, each and every night. He's on a roll,&quot; said Wayne Gretzky, enjoying something of a rebirth in his first post-season as a Ranger.</p>
<p>That's the other reason for the Rangers' surprising run -- the play of those former Oilers who learned how to win Stanley Cups in Edmonton in the 1980s and helped end New York's 54-year title drought in 1994.</p>
<p>There's the captain, Mark Messier, who somehow still has the fire in his belly after collecting six Stanley Cup rings; Gretzky with four rings and six post-season goals, pesky Esa Tikkanen (five rings, seven goals) and gritty Adam Graves (two rings and the game winning goal the last two games.)</p>
<p>Gretzky and Messier are the two leading scorers in Stanley Cup playoff history. The Great One is 6-0 in career conference final appearances, while Messier is 7-1 in final four play.</p>
<p>Already depleted by injuries to key role players, standing up to the punishment from the physical Flyers will test the Rangers in an entirely different way than the middle-clogging, defence-minded opponents of the first two rounds.</p>
<p>Unlike the Florida Panthers and New Jersey, the Flyers can score goals in bunches, and much like movie theatre popcorn, they only come three sizes -- large, extra large and humongous.</p>
<p>Eric Lindros, who has come into his own this season both as a team leader and major talent, and John LeClair and Mikael Renberg form the feared and appropriately nicknamed &quot;Legion of Doom&quot; line.</p>
<p>The trio, who have combined for 15 goals and 31 points in 10 playoff games, and their burly yet talented teammates such as Rod Brind'Amour (six goals) spelled swift and certain doom for the Pittsburgh Penguins and Buffalo Sabres.</p>
<p>Philadelphia raced out to demoralising 3-0 leads in both series before finishing off their overmatched opponents in five games each.</p>
<p>The Flyers also acquired their own ex-Oiler this season in crafty veteran Paul Coffey, who owns four Stanley Cup rings and virtually every NHL scoring record by a defenceman.</p>
<p>While scoring the game's first goal seemed to be a determining factor for the Rangers against both the Pathers and Devils, the Flyers have the weapons to come from behind and blow right by you.</p>
<p>Their one exploitable weakess is in goal, with playoff newcomer Garth Snow, who started the first nine post-season games, and veteran Ron Hextall, who worked the clincher against Buffalo, both vulnerable between the pipes.</p>
<p>But they can count on the kind of offensive support that New Jersey's Martin Brodeur never received.</p>
<p>The Rangers may not match up physically to the Flyers, but they beat them twice in April to take the season series, 3-2-1, despite finishing 17 points back in the standings.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going against the best team in the Conference now in Philadelphia, but we are proud we have earned this and will compete hard,&quot; Gretzky promised.</p>
<p>So prepare the frozen mosh pit, this next dance will definitely not be a waltz.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
