<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="581742" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: RADIO ROMANIA AFTERNOON HEADLINES AT 1 PM.</title>
<headline>RADIO ROMANIA AFTERNOON HEADLINES AT 1 PM.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Radio Romania news headlines:</p>
<p>* The Romanian ambassador to the United States, Mircea Geoana, has been heard by a U.S. Senate defence commission on the Balkan country's bid to for early NATO membership.</p>
<p>Commission members hailed Romania's &quot;huge democratic progresses&quot; in the past few months and said &quot;the U.S. must nominate Romania among countries to join NATO in a first wave of admission&quot;, Geoana told the state radio.</p>
<p>* The government discusses new banking laws, including a bill on the organisation of the central bank and one on the status of the savings bank Casa de Economii si Consemnatiuni.</p>
<p>The cabinet will also discuss a bill on foreign investment and a government decree to set up a special tax for road maintenance and repairs.</p>
<p>* Central bank governor Mugur Isarescu is expected to present the new banking legislation during a press briefing later this afternoon.</p>
<p>* The president of United States's Procter &amp; Gamble, John Pepper, met President Emil Constantinescu on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Pepper told Constantinescu that his company had chosen Romania as its headquarters for central and Eastern European operations due to its domestic stability and skilled labour.</p>
<p>* Foreign Minister Adrian Severin wil visit the Vienna headquarters of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation (OSCE) in Europe.</p>
<p>* Severin will also travel to Yugoslavia on Friday to meet his counterpart Milan Milutinovic and will go to Zagreb on Monday to meet his Croatian counterpart Mate Granic.</p>
<p>* Trade union federation CNSLR Fratia said it will start month-long protests against price increases and delays in issuing reform legislation and social protection measures.</p>
<p>-- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
