<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="581840" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Euro oil swaps tumble, CFDs down 14 cts, fuel down.</title>
<headline>Euro oil swaps tumble, CFDs down 14 cts, fuel down.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>European oil swaps tumbled on Wednesday after bearish U.S. oil stock figures revealed big builds in both crude and gasoline.</p>
<p>Despite those builds crude and gasoline have been the strongest area of the market in Europe in recent days. But on Wednesday the took the brunt on the downmove.</p>
<p>Brent CFDs lost 14 cents to trade at 14 cents under June for next week, having been at evens on Tuesday. The following two weeks were also 14 or 15 cents under July.</p>
<p>Monthly CFDs remained stubbornly in contango as they did even when the market soared last week. June talked 17 cents under the IPE, July and the third quarter 13 cents under, the fourth quarter 10 cents under and the first quarter next year five cents under.</p>
<p>Gasoline stayed under the cosh, having lost $4 a tonne during the morning.</p>
<p>June held around $201 with July $4.50 lower and August another $3.50 below that.</p>
<p>Dealers said the June-July spread was well bid as traders speculated on the possibility of a tax rise in the U.K. in the near term. Physical barges traded at $201.50 and $202.25 early but later at $201.</p>
<p>The third quarter crack spreads was slightly firmer with bids at $4.13 a barrel but the fourth was steady at at $3.10.</p>
<p>Heavy fuel fell another $1 a tonne with June barge swaps around $84 by late afternoon and July just 50 cents higher.</p>
<p>Dealers said the weakness reflected lower Rotterdam barges which traded down to $83.</p>
<p>Despite firmer Singapore levels, market confidence has been eroded by chronically poor bunker demand in the main bunker market of Rotterdam.</p>
<p>Jet premiums were little changed, with June and July at $20 a tonne and $22 a tonne above the IPE respectively.</p>
<p>Gas oil crack spreads held at $4.30 a barrel (3Q97), $4.85 (4Q97) and $4.75 (1Q98). -- Sam Arnold-Forster, London Newsroom +44 171 542 4984</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
