<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="581920" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CONGO: Kabila will join Zaire talks only at sea.</title>
<headline>Kabila will join Zaire talks only at sea.</headline>
<byline>William Wallis</byline>
<dateline>POINTE NOIRE, Congo 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Confusion over the whereabouts of rebel leader Laurent Kabila delayed Zaire's peace talks on Wednesday, a senior mediator said on the South African ice-breaker that will host the meeting.</p>
<p>A rebel spokesman told Reuters by telephone that Kabila, whose forces have been advancing on Zaire's capital Kinshasa, was insisting on joining the ship only after it was in international waters.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want to go to Pointe Noire for security reasons. We've been here in Cabinda for five and a half hours now. We are still talking about how we can go. We are willing to go to the ship and that is why we are here. But not to Pointe Noire.&quot;</p>
<p>South Africa's Nelson Mandela, who is trying to broker a transitional agreement and avert a rebel attack on Kinshasa, and Zaire's embattled president, Mobutu Sese Seko, waited on shore in Congo's main port of Pointe Noire where the craft was docked.</p>
<p>In Kinshasa, an anti-Mobutu opposition stay-home protest all but closed down the usually teeming city of five million people. Shops and markets stayed closed.</p>
<p>&quot;The success of today's operation has clearly shown that the people don't want Mobutu any more, and people know exactly what to do when the rebels come,&quot; said Laurent Mbayo, an adviser to Mobutu's veteran political opponent, Etienne Tshisekedi.</p>
<p>Zairean state radio said that Wednesday would be a fateful day that could determine the future of Africa's third largest and potentially one of its richest countries.</p>
<p>U.N. and Organisation of African Unity special envoy Mohamed Sahnoun announced the talks delay. Speaking in mid-afternoon, he predicted the talks, described by another senior mediator as a last chance for peace, would start &quot;within a few hours&quot;.</p>
<p>Kabila had been expected in the Angolan port of Soyo but had gone north to Cabinda enclave, officials said. &quot;We were waiting for them somewhere, they landed somewhere else,&quot; Sahnoun said.</p>
<p>Mobutu agreed at a first meeting on May 4 to hand power to an elected president. Kabila, both then and in public statements since, has insisted Mobutu hand power at once to his Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire.</p>
<p>Mandela spokesman Joel Netshitenzhe said on the eve of the talks that mediators had won agreement in a number of areas. &quot;They have a skeleton of the main areas of agreement that are supposed to be ratified,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Rebel radio suggested that Kabila's forces were nearing the approaches to Kinshasa. The government dismissed such reports.</p>
<p>Just in case, well over 4,000 Western soldiers remained on standby in Congo's capital Brazzaville or at sea off Zaire to evacuate foreign nationals from Kinshasa if need be.</p>
<p>Mobutu, 66 and suffering from cancer, has dominated Zaire since seizing power in 1965, reputedly amassing a huge personal fortune. Western powers supported him as a Cold War bastion against Soviet communism.</p>
<p>The rebels, who took up arms in October demanding Zairean nationality for ethnic Tutsis, now control three-quarters of the impoverished, corruption-plagued nation.</p>
<p>Zairean state television, in its main afternoon bulletin, quoted the government as saying that fighting was going on in and around Kenge, more than 200 km (125 miles) from Kinshasa.</p>
<p>It said the Kwango River Bridge, about 180 km (110 miles) by road from the capital, was still in the hands of Mobutu forces. Rebels and Kinshasa residents in contact with the area said earlier it had been abandoned by the army on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CONGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="POINTE NOIRE, Congo"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CONGO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
