<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="582038" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: NATO and Russia embrace in new partnership pact.</title>
<headline>NATO and Russia embrace in new partnership pact.</headline>
<byline>Adam Tanner</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>NATO and Russia agreed a deal on forging a peaceful new relationship between the former Cold War enemies on Wednesday, symbolised by a warm embrace between their top negotiators.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a big victory for reason, it is a big victory for the world community and it is a big victory for Russia and all governments in the world interested in peace and cooperation,&quot; Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov declared.</p>
<p>He clasped an arm around NATO Secretary General Javier Solana at a joint news conference in the garden of a foreign ministry mansion in Moscow after the breakthrough which ended months of negotiations described by Solana as &quot;very tough&quot;.</p>
<p>The agreement, intended to placate Russia before NATO invites new members in eastern Europe, was reached on the second day of the latest talks between Primakov and Solana.</p>
<p>It cleared the way for President Boris Yeltsin and NATO to sign the deal in Paris on May 27, providing the text is approved by the Kremlin leader and the heads of government of the 16 NATO countries.</p>
<p>A joint statement said NATO and Russia had made &quot;decisive progress&quot; on key issues including military problems, which had been the main obstacles to agreement.</p>
<p>But it gave no details of the text, leaving lingering doubts over whether they had resolved their longstanding problems or simply agreed to gloss over them.</p>
<p>The usually sombre Primakov was in a bouyant mood and smiling. He and Solana praised each other as tough negotiators before reporters at the 19th-century, neo-Gothic ministry mansion.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to praise Mr Primakov for the way he defended the interests of the country, as I have defended with the same determination the interests of NATO,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I do think we can be very proud about what we have achieved at this point in the agreement and without any doubt we will open a new age in the history of NATO relations with Russia and the stability of our countries,&quot; Solana said.</p>
<p>Primakov said the text of the agreement should be on President Boris Yeltsin's desk by the end of Wednesday. Solana was to forward the agreement to NATO's 16 governments for approval.</p>
<p>&quot;If approved, the path to signing the document in Paris will be clear,&quot; Primakov said.</p>
<p>Solana added: &quot;Reason has prevailed. The road to signing on May 27 is clearly open.&quot;</p>
<p>The two men had worked hard to agree the final details before the target date Yeltsin had set for signing the accord.</p>
<p>NATO officials were anxious to conclude a deal with Russia before a summit in July at which the Western defence alliance is expected to invite several former Soviet allies to join.</p>
<p>Russian leaders have spoken out strongly against NATO expansion, calling it a threat to its security.</p>
<p>As recently as Tuesday Yeltsin had said he would not sign an unsatisfactory agreement and he told Primakov to take a tough line in the sixth round of Russia-NATO talks on the pact.</p>
<p>A breakthrough had been blocked until now by disagreements over whether the pact should include written guarantees that NATO will not station military structures and nuclear weapons on the territory of new member states.</p>
<p>The North Atlantic Treaty Organisation has been reluctant to give such guarantees in writing.</p>
<p>Yeltsin had spoken to Solana by telephone at around midday but it was not clear if he intervened in the talks before the pact was finalised.</p>
<p>Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic are expected to receive the first invitations to join NATO, although Romania and Slovenia also hope to be in the first wave.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
