<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="582199" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian president asks UDF's Kostov to form govt.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian president asks UDF's Kostov to form govt.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgarian President Petar Stoyanov on Wednesday formally asked Union of Democratic Forces leader Ivan Kostov to form a government, following his coalition's victory in the April 19 parliamentary elections.</p>
<p>Kostov, elected on a promise to reform the economy and fight organised crime, said he expected to present his cabinet to Stoyanov on Monday, though the draft list is already known.</p>
<p>&quot;Happily the majority of the economic team remains, although modelled in a different way, but it will continue its work so that there will be no problem especially in the economic sphere,&quot; Kostov said.</p>
<p>He said the ministers would use the time until next week to work on their programmes for the next four years.</p>
<p>Muravei Radev, former deputy chairman of the economic committee in the previous parliament, is expected to be the new finance minister, while interim deputy prime minister Alexander Bozhkov is expected to retain the industry portfolio, overseeing the restructuring of the unwieldy state sector.</p>
<p>UDF spokeswoman Nadezhda Mihailova is expected to become foreign minister, and interim interior minister Bogomil Bonev will continue his high-profile campaign against organised crime and corruption.</p>
<p>Kostov will create a ministry of state administration to oversee reforms promised to reduce bureaucracy and improve the flow of information. The energy ministry will be downgraded to a committee.</p>
<p>Parliament is expected to approve the new government on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will present the programme, we will seek the support of parliament, and with this Bulgaria's political crisis which started on December 21 will probably end well for all of us,&quot; Kostov said.</p>
<p>One of the first tasks of the new government will be to introduce a currency board, a restrictive fixed exchange rate mechanism intended to improve monetary discipline and stabilise the national currency.</p>
<p>An International Monetary Fund mission arrived in Sofia on Tuesday to finalise details of the currency board and the 1997 budget, which has been delayed by the political upheaval.</p>
<p>Elections were held 20 months ahead of schedule after mass protests forced out the former Socialist government in February.</p>
<p>An interim cabinet led by Sofia's popular UDF mayor Stefan Sofianski has governed since then, tackling bread and fuel shortages and bringing inflation under control.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
