<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="582284" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine president pleads for labor reform.</title>
<headline>Argentine president pleads for labor reform.</headline>
<byline>Axel Bugge</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine President Carlos Menem made an impassioned plea Wednesday to the country's unions, business leaders and lawmakers, urging them to support labor market reforms to fight unemployment.</p>
<p>&quot;In the search for a consensus, months and months have been lost. The government has proposed it (labor market reform) to business leaders and unions. There is no way of achieving it.  </p>
<p>Instead, forceful measures have been announced and when the government proposes renewing the dialogue, there are no results,&quot; the president wrote in an article published by state news agency Telam Wednesday afternoon.</p>
<p>After months of disagreement, the government Friday reached a preliminary deal on labor reform with the CGT labor federation, which could lead unions to drop plans of staging a general strike this month. But the agreement needs the approval of business leaders to go ahead.  </p>
<p>The government argues that making the labor market more flexible, which would curtail powers the unions have had for decades, is crucial to reducing employer costs that prevent hiring. That is key to decreasing the near-record unemployment rate of 17.3 percent, it argues.</p>
<p>Menem's article coincided with the lifting Wednesday of a blockade of a highway to the Bolivian border by protesters in the Northwest of the country after the provincial government promised measures to create jobs.  </p>
<p>Union militancy scuttles dialogue, Menem said, and makes any solution &quot;impossible. We have to analyze together the reality of the hour,&quot; said Menem.</p>
<p>He also reminded members of Congress who have opposed the labor reforms that the Constitution has assigned Congress &quot;to generate employment.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Congress has to understand that social peace and the question of unemployment make it absolutely necessary to adopt measures that are of unequivocal necessity and urgency,&quot; Menem said, citing the term usually used to justify presidential decrees.  </p>
<p>Menem signed a series of presidential decrees early this year on labor reform, but they were overturned by the courts as unconstitutional.</p>
<p>Menem made the plea for action by asking provincial governments &quot;who desire to put in government hands the solution to the problem of unemployment,&quot; to come directly to central government with their suggestions.</p>
<p>The labor reforms proposed by Menem include swapping severance payouts for unemployment insurance and allowing workers to make salary and labor condition deals directly with employers with no centralized union intervention.  </p>
<p>The World Bank added its voice to the issue Wednesday. Friday's agreement between the government and the unions made &quot;tremendous progress,&quot; the World Bank's Argentine representative, Patricio Millan, was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Nevertheless it must not be considered as definitive, but a step in the right direction and should be completed &quot;with more progress on flexibility,&quot; Millan added.</p>
<p>(( -- Buenos Aires Newsroom, 541 318-0668))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
