<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="582202" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian shares ease, traders mixed on day's trend.</title>
<headline>Russian shares ease, traders mixed on day's trend.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading Russian shares dipped in early trade and traders differed on whether the market would steady or ease towards the end of the day.</p>
<p>The Russian Trading System 22-share index opened at 353.29 after closing on Tuesday at 353.99.</p>
<p>Market benchmark UES  EESR.RTS eased to $0.2915 at GMT 0900 from $0.2975 at Tuesday's close. Regional energy company Mosenergo  MSNG.RTS slipped to $1.345 from $1.385. Oil producer LUKoil  LKOH.RTS firmed to $14.750 from $14.730.</p>
<p>&quot;Yesterday evening we saw demand from Russian operators, now they're taking profits,&quot; said CentreInvest trader Sergei Bukin.</p>
<p>&quot;But there's no big demand. Volumes are low,&quot; he said, adding that he expected buying on the lower prices to provide support for the market to steady towards the end of the day.</p>
<p>Trinfiko trader Ilya Galtsov said Mosenergo was also falling on continuing uncertainty over whether it would issue new shares. The Moscow utility dropped plans for a controversial share issue last month after big investors protested.</p>
<p>He said he saw the market closing slightly lower as Western investors sat out, fearing another interest rate hike coming out of the U.S. Federal Reserve meeting on May 20.</p>
<p>&quot;I see a slight fall compared to yesterday's close. Western investors will be in waiting positions until the end of the week -- not selling, but demand will be very small,&quot; Galtsov said.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial index fell 18 points to 7,274 on growing investor speculation about a possible rise in Fed interest rates.</p>
<p>But other traders were optimistic the Russian market would grow again in the long term.</p>
<p>&quot;More people will be back in their offices next week and usually May is very upside -- the atmosphere is very optimistic and we can definitely see a rise,&quot; said Bobby Meshoyrer, head trader at Aton.</p>
<p>--Christina Ling, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
