<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="58248" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: FEATURE - Argentine director thanks Evita for his trousers.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Argentine director thanks Evita for his trousers.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Brown</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The man who is making Argentina's own patriotic answer to Alan Parker's and Madonna's movie &quot;Evita&quot; has to thank Eva Peron for more than just a good storyline.</p>
<p>&quot;My home was humble and we didn't have much in the way of clothes, so my mother used to sew us a sort of skirt made of flour sacks from the mill. Evita gave me my first pair of trousers,&quot; said &quot;Eva Peron&quot; director Juan Carlos Desanzo.</p>
<p>Peronist fervor permeates the movie, which will cost $3 million compared to the $73 million spent by Parker for his musical extravaganza starring Madonna as Eva Peron, Briton Jonathan Pryce as Juan Peron, the populist who ruled Argentina from 1946 to 1955 and from 1973 until his death in 1974, and Spaniard Antonio Banderas.</p>
<p>Esther Goris, an Argentine actress who plays the poor girl turned radio starlet who became the second wife of Peron in Desanzo's film, lost so much weight to portray Evita in the last months of her life that the producers put her under a doctor's supervision. Eva weighed 73 pounds (33 kg) when she died of cancer in 1952 at the age of 33, plunging Argentina into mourning for a woman who even now is revered as a saintly champion of the poor, the &quot;descamisados&quot; or shirtless ones as she called them.</p>
<p>&quot;My health is not at risk. Even if it were, I would do it anyway,&quot; Goris said of her weight loss. She is prettier and more ethereal than the glamorous but earthy Eva, but with her dyed-blonde hair tied back she has an undeniable &quot;Evita&quot; air.</p>
<p>Local stage star Victor Laplace put on weight and had his hairline shaved to play the general. He speaks in terms of historical accuracy rather than Goris' mystical enthusiasm, typical of even modern-day Peronists. &quot;My motivation is historical rigour and a chance to tell the story of a movement that, whether you like or not, has played an important role in changing society,&quot; Laplace said.</p>
<p>Parker and Madonna got a hostile reception when they came here to make their movie of the Lloyd-Webber/Tim Rice 1970s stage musical. Many Peronists were indignant at its portrayal of Evita as a manipulator using her sex appeal to amass power.</p>
<p>Madonna likened filming here to &quot;surviving a war.&quot; Carlos Menem, the current Peronist president, was reluctant to let her film on the balcony of the Casa Rosada government house, where the Perons made their fiery speeches to adoring crowds hundreds of thousands strong.</p>
<p>But Madonna persuaded him that her intention was to &quot;portray Evita as a human being, not in the superficial way she was portrayed in the musical.&quot;</p>
<p>The steamy pop star, whose sexy stage stunts made her an offensive choice for Peronists to play a woman revered as &quot;Santa Evita,&quot; claimed she researched &quot;the rise and fall of 'fascism' in South America&quot; -- a term unlikely to endear her to her Argentine audience. Peronists dislike comparisons of their founder to European fascists, although Peron proclaimed his admiration for Italian dictator Benito Mussolini.</p>
<p>Parker plans his U.S. premiere for Christmas Day. Desanzo's premiere will be on the red-letter day of the Peronist calender -- Oct. 17, anniversary of the &quot;Day of Loyalty&quot; in 1945 when hordes of workers invaded central Buenos Aires and forced the military to free Peron, paving the way for his landslide election victory the next year.</p>
<p>Desanzo dismisses talk of rivalry with Parker. &quot;Someone of Eva Peron's greatness doesn't just deserve two homages, she deserves 20 or 30,&quot; he said. Such sentiments meant he had no trouble getting the Casa Rosada balcony for his movie.</p>
<p>So thin that the veins stand out on her pale forehead, Goris smiles and waves from the balcony to curious crowds in the Plaza de Mayo; as the camera starts to roll she shrinks into a coughing, pained Evita, supported by Laplace in shirt sleeves and bow tie and backed by two nurses in starched caps.</p>
<p>But as she makes Evita's last speech from the balcony on May 1 1952, just weeks before her death, the frail figure with clenched fists spits venom at &quot;traitors within&quot; and urges the workers not to abandon Peron when she is gone. &quot;Dead or alive, I will march with the women and the descamisados of this country to make sure not one brick is left standing that is not Peronist,&quot; she cries, before collapsing back into the stout general's arms.</p>
<p>Signing autographs after the scene has been shot, Goris asks the Argentine public to be &quot;merciful&quot; if her portrayal of Evita does not match up to the ideal of &quot;a woman whose death still causes pain, and whose vision still gives us strength.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES, Argentina"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
