<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="58256" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-TIMELINES-Today in History - Sept 18.</title>
<headline>RTRS-TIMELINES-Today in History - Sept 18.</headline>
<text>
<p>** BIRTHDAYS **</p>
<p>English writer SAMUEL JOHNSON was born in 1709. His Dictionary was used as the authorative reference book for more than a century.</p>
<p>Swedish-born Hollywood film star GRETA GARBO (GRETA LOVISA GUSTAFSSON) was born in 1905. GARBO went to the United States in 1925 and her leading role in &quot;The Torrent&quot; a year later made her one of Hollywood's first silent film stars. Her later films included &quot;Mata Hari&quot; in 1931, &quot;Queen Christina&quot; in 1933, &quot;Anna  </p>
<p>Karenina&quot; in 1935, &quot;Camille&quot; in 1936 and &quot;Ninotchka&quot; in 1939. Her on screen qualities of ethereality and romantic beauty together with her obsession with a secluded private life created an aura of mystery. The retired in 1941 and died in 1990.</p>
<p>American singer BOB DYLAN (ROBERT ALLEN ZIMMERMAN), songwriter and poet, was born in 1933. He became something of a cult figure with folk songs such as &quot;The Times They Are A-Changin'&quot; (1964). His early songs were associated with the US civil rights movement and anti-war protests against US involvement in Vietnam.  </p>
<p>American singer and actor FRANKIE AVALON was born in 1939. He began his career as a child trumpeter and later had hits as a singer with &quot;Venus&quot; and &quot;Why&quot;.</p>
<p>US guitarist, pianist, and songwriter for 'Kansas' KERRY LIVGREN was born in 1949.</p>
<p>US bass player DEE DEE RAMONE (DOUGLAS COLVIN), who co-founded the 'Ramones' in 1974, was born in 1952.  </p>
<p>US singer RICKY BELL was born in 1967. He was a singer with the children's group 'New Edition' formed in 1982.</p>
<p>				  ** EVENTS **</p>
<p>    1759 :    The French forces at Quebec surr*ndered to the</p>
<p>British.  </p>
<p>    1911 :    Russian premier PYOTR STOLYPIN died from a gunshot</p>
<p>wound he received at the Kiev opera. Emperor NICHOLAS II and his daughters witnessed the shooting from the royal box. The assassin was a police double agent. STOLYPIN was a ruthless leader who had few fri*nds and had fallen out with the Tsar.</p>
<p>    1931 :    Japan invaded Manchuria. Japanese troops guarding</p>
<p>the South Manchurian railway launched the surprise attack. The Manchurian Governor ordered his forces not to retaliate because he believed the attack was designed to provoke an incident to provide an excuse for Japanese occupation.  </p>
<p>    1955 :    Four years after they fled to Russia, the British</p>
<p>government admitted that DONALD MACLEAN and GUY BURGESS were Soviet spies.</p>
<p>    1964 :    Australia's JOHNNY FAMECHON won the national</p>
<p>featherweight title.  </p>
<p>    1970 :    Rock superstar JIMI HENDRIX died. Hendrix left a</p>
<p>message on his ex-manager's answering machine saying &quot;I need help bad&quot;. A few hours later he was pronounced dead on arrival at St Mary's Hospital from a suspected overdose of sleeping pills. He was only 27. He was the highest-paid act at the 69 Woodstock Festival. HENDRIX was also plagued by law suits over royalties and contracts.  </p>
<p>    1975 :    Newspaper heiress PATTY HEARST was refused bail on</p>
<p>bank robbery charges. The 21-year-old daughter of WILLIAM RANDOLPH HEARST was kidnapped twenty months earlier by a radical terrorist group, the Symbionese Liberation Army. She was filmed on closed circuit television with other SIA members robbing a San Francisco bank. She was captured by the FBI in September 1975.  </p>
<p>    1978 :    President ANWAR SADAT of Egypt and Israel's prime</p>
<p>minister MENACHEM BEGIN reached a peace agreement. Meeting at Camp David in the US under president JIMMY CARTER's sponsorship. They agreed that Israel would withdraw from the Sinai, but not yet from other occupied territories of Gaza and the West Bank.</p>
<p>    1981 :    Under President MITTERAND France abolished the</p>
<p>guillotine.</p>
<p>    1988 :    The military siezed power in Burma.</p>
<p>    1989 :    A GORBACHEV adviser claimed the USSR's state-run</p>
<p>newspaper 'Pravda' was full of lies and should be closed down.</p>
<p>(Compiled from ABC ARCHIVES, ABC RADIO NATIONAL, &quot;On This Day&quot; published by REED INTERNATIONAL BOOKS LIMITED, &quot;The Chronicle Of The 20th Century&quot; published by PENGUIN BOOKS and &quot;Rock And Pop (Day By Day)&quot; published by BLANDFORD BOOKS)</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
