<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="582587" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel, PLO officials meet, Arafat not optimistic.</title>
<headline>Israel, PLO officials meet, Arafat not optimistic.</headline>
<byline>Hisham Mawajdeh</byline>
<dateline>HERZLIA, Israel 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli and Palestinian cabinet ministers held U.S.-brokered talks on Wednesday on restarting formal peace negotiations but Palestinian President Yasser Arafat played down chances of a breakthrough.</p>
<p>Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai and Yitzhak Molcho, an adviser to Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, met Palestinian cabinet ministers Saeb Erekat and Nabil Shaath at the residence near Tel Aviv of the U.S. ambassador to Israel.</p>
<p>They made no comments to reporters at the start of the night-time talks held against the backdrop of a crisis over Israeli settlement in East Jerusalem. PLO officials described the session as informal.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a meeting in Tel Aviv between Israelis and Palestinians, attended by (U.S. envoy Dennis) Ross,&quot; Arafat said in a speech to visiting members of the Socialist International.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope that this will make something concrete. I am not optimistic but I hope so,&quot; the Palestinian leader said.</p>
<p>Israel and the PLO dug in to their opposing positions on Jewish settlement on land claimed by both sides before the session began at the home of U.S. ambassador Martin Indyk.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister David Levy said Israel wanted the meeting to restore full cooperation with the Palestinian Authority. But he said Israel's position on the Har Homa settlement, under construction in East Jerusalem, would not change.</p>
<p>&quot;We will clarify the issues together...It is our responsibility in order to try to return to full cooperation so the process will return to its course,&quot; he told Israel Radio.</p>
<p>&quot;Israel's position on Har Homa is known,&quot; Levy said.</p>
<p>Erekat said after talks with Ross in self-ruled Jericho earlier on Wednesday that the Palestinian side intended to discuss settlements and peace deals at the meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;We will discuss all issues with Mordechai, specifically settlement activities. If it is not discussed then we will be moving in a vicious circle,&quot; Erekat told reporters.</p>
<p>Peace negotiations have been largely stalled since Israel broke ground for the East Jerusalem settlement on March 18, igniting a wave of Palestinian protest and one Islamic militant bombing in which three Israeli women were killed.</p>
<p>&quot;You are definitely aware of the real and very dangerous crisis through which the peace process is currently passing,&quot; Arafat said in his speech to the Middle East committee of the Socialist International.</p>
<p>&quot;This is because of the arbitrary practices and the provocative and stubborn policies of the current Israeli government,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Palestinians have said they would not agree to resume peace talks until the Jewish state stopped all settlement building, including in Israeli-annexed East Jerusalem which they envisage as the capital of a future state.</p>
<p>Arafat said that by building the East Jerusalem settlement, Israel was &quot;strangling the city&quot; and trying to determine Jerusalem's future ahead of talks on a final peace agreement.</p>
<p>Levy, who was due to meet U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright in Washington on Friday, said he hoped for a quick resumption of Israel-PLO talks on implementing peace deals.</p>
<p>Asked when he wanted to renew the talks, Levy said: &quot;I wish today, yesterday. But we must not give up and we must put things back on a constructive track.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HERZLIA, Israel"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
