<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="582693" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Blue-chip stocks buoyed by good inflation news.</title>
<headline>Blue-chip stocks buoyed by good inflation news.</headline>
<byline>Mary Kelleher</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue-chip stocks soared Wednesday as unexpectedly good news on inflation calmed fears of another interest rate hike, but the rally stalled in the absence of support from technology shares.</p>
<p>At 1 p.m. EDT, the Dow Jones industrial average was up 41.62 points at 7,315.83 after gaining more than 75 points initially.</p>
<p>In the broader market, advancing issues swamped declines 14-8 on active trading of 291 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index, which is laden with technology stocks, was up just 2.44 points at 1,336.03.</p>
<p>The strength in blue-chips was ignited by news that wholesale prices fell 0.6 percent in April -- the biggest drop in nearly four years. Excluding food and energy, the Producer Price Index was down 0.1 percent.</p>
<p>It was the fourth straight month that producer prices have fallen and followed a 0.1 percent slide in March.</p>
<p>Analysts said the big drop in the producer prices lowered the odds that the Federal Reserve would raise interest rates at next Tuesday's policy-setting meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;The market reacted positively to the PPI but it is starting to look overextended, losing technology leadership,&quot; said Don Ascani, president of Global Market Strategists Inc.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond jumped 19/32, lowering its yield to 6.88 percent from Tuesday's 6.93 percent. The bond's price and yield move in opposite directions.</p>
<p>&quot;The stock market is losing a little bit of steam,&quot; said Warren Epstein, head trader at Richard Rosenblatt Co. &quot;Bonds are staying relatively strong and, given the bond market rally, I'm surprised the market's not higher.&quot;</p>
<p>He said if Thursday's consumer price report &quot;confirms the PPI report, and the bond market rally continues, it raises the question of whether the Fed will raise rates next week.&quot;</p>
<p>Some analysts said they expected the stock market to stick to safe ground ahead of both the CPI report and the Fed's meeting next week.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has had quite a rally in the past month and traders are more cautious near the 7,350 level,&quot; Ascani said. &quot;Both stocks and bonds are due for a correction, and that might happen going into the Fed meeting next Tuesday.&quot;</p>
<p>Among technology shares, Intel Corp. stock was initially hit hard after Digital Equipment Corp. said it filed a patent infringement suit against Intel and would seek a &quot;huge&quot; damage award.</p>
<p>Intel stock was off 1-3/4 at 150-5/8 after falling as low as 146, while Digital was down 1/2 at 34-3/4.</p>
<p>Microsoft Corp. fell 5/8 to 117-1/8, while Cisco Systems lost 1/2 to 61-7/8. But International Business Machines Corp. continued to trek higher, trading up 5/8 at 174-1/4.</p>
<p>Micron Electronics Inc. shares extended losses, trading down 2 at 16-5/8, after the firm said its results would likely be hurt by price cuts in PC systems.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
