<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="582756" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT - Dlr bearish all around, mainly vs yen.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Dlr bearish all around, mainly vs yen.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar outlook is turning increasingly bearish on the charts, mainly against the yen where the loss of 117.60 signals a deeper retreat, possibly all the way to 115.00, chartists said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar/yen pullback from the May 4 high led to the test of 117.60, a support level in a bull channel from September,&quot; said MCM CurrencyWatch senior analyst Scott Siller. &quot;We lost that, it was taken out today.&quot;</p>
<p>Siller said the loss of that key level confirmed a dollar/yen bear flag formation started on May 11 with the loss of 118.25.  </p>
<p>In New York on Wednesday, the dollar closed at 117.30/40 versus 118.65/70 at the open and 118.55/65 at the prior close.</p>
<p>Traders reported large sell orders just under 117.80, confirming the market sentiment that a loss of 117.60 would signal a fresh downward trend for dollar/yen.</p>
<p>Chris Turner, a senior technical analyst at the consulting firm I.D.E.A., had predicted that &quot;a move below 117.50 yen would be a nasty one... a break to the downside,&quot; echoing Siller's bearish views on dollar/yen.</p>
<p>Siller noted the weekly studies were turning bearish, compounding the negative tone set by the daily charts.  </p>
<p>&quot;The weekly studies are taking a strong bearish tone and we could go lower. When the weekly and daily studies are aligned, you have to pay attention to that. It's bearish all around,&quot; noted Siller who did not see &quot;any good support until 115.00 yen.&quot;</p>
<p>Dollar/mark looked relatively sturdy on the near term, as support at 1.6905/10 held, analysts said. However, bearish divergence on the hourly studies pointed to a possible test of 1.6825/30-mark support down the road, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;1.6825 was the dollar/mark low on Friday, and this gives me the feeling we're going to resume weakness,&quot; Siller said.  </p>
<p>Analysts also said:</p>
<p>-- Cable remains bullish and a retest of $1.6550, the high on April 1, cannobe ruled out.</p>
<p>-- Dollar/Swiss is suffering a setback after a good recovery but key 1.43 support appears well protected on the near term.</p>
<p>-- Mark/yen remains weak, but strong support at 68.90 does not seem in jeopardy on the near term.</p>
<p>((N.A. Treasury, 212-859-1660))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
