<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="582834" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Jury selection continues in trial of Ariz. Gov.</title>
<headline>Jury selection continues in trial of Ariz. Gov.</headline>
<byline>David Schwartz</byline>
<dateline>PHOENIX, Ariz. 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jury selection continued at a snail's pace Wednesday in Arizona Gov. Fife Symington's federal trial on fraud, extortion and perjury charges.</p>
<p>Five more potential jurors were selected in the morning session in U.S. District Court to join the 16 chosen Tuesday on the first day of the trial. Judge Roger Strand wants a final 39-person pool from which 12 jurors and five alternates will be selected.</p>
<p>There was a minor drama Wednesday when a court official told reporters there had been a break-in Tuesday night in the hotel room occupied by a member of Symington's defence team.</p>
<p>Defence attorney John Dowd confirmed a camera was stolen and that the break-in was being investigated. However, he told reporters: &quot;It is nothing to do with the case.&quot;</p>
<p>Symington, a colourful, 51-year-old Republican, faces 22 felony charges. Federal prosecutors will try to prove to the jury that Symington committed fraud, extortion and perjury in connection with real estate deals during the last decade.</p>
<p>If convicted on even a single count, the two-term governor would be booted from the office he has held since 1991. He also faces a possible prison term.</p>
<p>Two prospective jurors were rejected Wednesday by the defence because of their opinions on bankrupcy, which they said could effect their view of the governor.</p>
<p>When the 39 potential jurors are selected, they will face more detailed questions from both sides. The prosecution will be allowed up to nine challenges and the defence may ask for up to 13 to be rejected for specific reasons.</p>
<p>One member of the defence team is a jury analyst, Howard Varinsky, who advised the U.S. government on the makeup of the jury for the Timothy McVeigh bombing trial in Denver.</p>
<p>Varinsky also worked for the defence in recent trials of accused New York subway gunman Bernard Goetz and Jack Kevorkian, the Michigan doctor accused of assisting suicides.</p>
<p>During the trial, expected to last 12 weeks, prosecutors will detail what they claim are lies told by Symington from the mid-1980s to the early 1990s, when he was a developer, to secure credit lines and business and personal loans.</p>
<p>The government contends Symington made false statements to lenders to prevent his real estate empire from crumbling. Prosecutors also will try to prove Symington extorted an agreement from six union pension funds to release him from a personal loan guarantee he made to obtain a $10 million loan for a shopping centre in downtown Phoenix.</p>
<p>The government also will try to prove the governor lied under oath during court proceedings when he filed for Chapter 7 bankruptcy in September 1995.</p>
<p>The charges stem from a probe into the 1989 collapse of Southwest Savings &amp; Loan Association. Symington served on the thrift's board of directors.</p>
<p>After settling the case, the U.S. Attorney's office in Los Angeles continued its probe into the governor's financial dealings for several years. Last June, Symington was indicted.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHOENIX, Ariz."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
