<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="582983" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cold Midwest weather slowing U.S. corn growth.</title>
<headline>Cold Midwest weather slowing U.S. corn growth.</headline>
<byline>Anna Driver</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>An extended period of abnormally cold weather across the U.S. Midwest is slowing the growth rate of early-planted corn, agronomists said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there is any question that we need warm temperatures to move the crops along,&quot; said Ellsworth Christmas, agronomist with Purdue University in West Lafayette, Ind.</p>
<p>In Indiana, the corn that has emerged has good stand establishment, but the plants are very light in color because of recent cloudy and cool conditions, Christmas said.  </p>
<p>Developmental problems have also been noted in Iowa and Illinois -- the country's two largest corn-producing states as well as Ohio, according to weekly crop data from the U.S. Department of Agriculture.</p>
<p>Crop scouts in those states reported Monday that farmers were concerned about germination of early-planted corn, corn plants that had emerged were yellow, and warmer temperatures were needed to spur growth.  </p>
<p>In Iowa, nighttime temperatures this week have dropped below freezing in the northern half of the state, but there is little corn emerged there, so the weather was not seen as a threat, said Mark Carlton, a crop specialist for Iowa State University in Monroe County in southern Iowa.</p>
<p>&quot;I think in the northern part of the state, there will be little or no weather damage to the corn crop,&quot; Carlton said.</p>
<p>In eastern Corn Belt states, more and more talk of the need to re-plant corn acreage has been surfacing, cash dealers and extension agents said.  </p>
<p>&quot;There's a fellow that is a customer of ours that planted in April, and he's going to have to tear up and replant nearly 1,000 acres,&quot; one Ohio grain dealer said.</p>
<p>In a weekly report circulated by Ohio State University crop extension agents, a section was devoted to factors that should affect the decision to replant corn.</p>
<p>&quot;Although it's probably premature to raise the issue of replanting corn, below average temperatures and slow crop emergence have prompted requests for this information,&quot; the report said.  </p>
<p>However, most agronomists agree it is still too early in the planting season to determine whether or not the corn crop's slow start will have an impact on yields and said a change in the weather would help the crop quickly recover.</p>
<p>&quot;If we would warm it up 10 degrees and have clear skies, I think in a matter of four or five days, things would change dramatically,&quot; Christmas said.</p>
<p>However, near-term forecasts don't show much relief for Midwest farmers.</p>
<p>The weather outlook for the Midwest included scattered showers on Wednesday and Thursday, with temperatures staying below normal during that period, meteorologists said.</p>
<p>On Friday and Saturday, temperatures are forecast to drop to below-normal and much below normal levels but turn warmer on Sunday, according to a forecast from Weather Services Corp. in Lexington, Mass.</p>
<p>However, some other meteorologists expect a warming trend to begin Friday and last into the weekend.</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
