<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="583094" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: No N.Caledonia mine deal this week-Eramet.</title>
<headline>No N.Caledonia mine deal this week-Eramet.</headline>
<dateline>DUESSELDORF 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Legal talks scheduled this week between Societe Miniere de Sud Pacifique (SMSP) and French nickel group Eramet will not settle a long-standing mining assets conflict, Eramet chairman Yves Rambaud said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Rambaud, who was talking to Reuters during a stainless steel industry meeting here, said the discussions would cover further &quot;necessary professional work&quot; mapped out in a May 2 meeting but further negotiations would be necessary.</p>
<p>&quot;The problems fall into three areas -- legal, technical and financial,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be difficult to resolve the financial problems so close to the (French end-May and early June) elections.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing can be finalised until all of the three areas have been tackled.&quot;</p>
<p>The meetings are aimed at arranging a mining titles swap under which SMSP and Canadian group Falconbridge would gain access to Eramet's Koniambo reserve to feed a jointly operated smelter, which is yet to be built.</p>
<p>Eramet is under pressure from the French government, through its majority shareholder, Erap, to exchange Koniambo for SMSP's Poum field in a deliberate political gesture to appease Kanak nationalists, who control SMSP.</p>
<p>Erap in the light of Eramet's reluctance has threatened to take control of the Eramet board and to replace Rambaud.</p>
<p>The dispute has far-reaching implications for Eramet's future and that of French privatisations.</p>
<p>Wilhelm Scheider, a German board member at Eramet, said the French government had made mistakes in the process.</p>
<p>&quot;The French state can of course push through its ideas via its majority ownership of Eramet, but this might go against commercial reason and it will need personnel ready to carry them out,&quot; he told 120 industry delegates.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential damage appears higher than the possible political gains in New Caledonia.&quot;</p>
<p>-Vera Eckert, Duesseldorf newsroom, +49-211-3882-242</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUESSELDORF"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
