<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="583163" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian call money ends down, gilts steady.</title>
<headline>Indian call money ends down, gilts steady.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian call money ended Wednesday at 7.25-8.0 percent, down from the opening quotes of 8.0-8.5 but off the day's low of 7.0 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said rates fell by mid-session but rose again in afternoon trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the day's trade was between 7.25 and 7.75 percent,&quot; said a dealer at a state-run bank. &quot;Although market perception is that rates should come down to 5.0-6.0 percent, lenders are still keeping them high.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said prices of government securities were marginally up in moderate trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices were steady to slightly up,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;But volumes were poor.&quot;</p>
<p>He said market attention was focussed in short- and medium-term securities with maturities up to 2002.</p>
<p>The 13.40 percent 1999 government of India stock traded on Wednesday at 104.55 rupees against Tuesday's 104.5, the 13.50 percent 1997 dropped to 101.85 from 101.92 while the 13.85 percent 2001 rose to 104.9 from 104.85, dealers said.</p>
<p>The latest auctioned stock, 12.69 percent 2002 was traded at 100.16 and 100.24 rupees against 100.23.</p>
<p>The treasury bill maturing in December yielded 9.12 percent against 9.20 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
