<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="583117" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka troops, rebels locked in battle in north.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka troops, rebels locked in battle in north.</headline>
<byline>Mohan Samarasinghe</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Separatist Tamil Tiger rebels hit back at advancing soldiers in northern Sri Lanka on Wednesday shortly after troops captured a heavily fortified, frontline town, military officials and aid workers said.</p>
<p>Reports from the north said heavy fighting broke out after troops captured Omanthai, along the strategic Jaffna-Vavuniya north-south highway, following a virtually unopposed thrust into the rebels' heartland Wanni region that began on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is severe fighting just north of Omanthai. Ambulances (helicopters) have begun to fly in and out with casualties,&quot; a military officer in the frontline town of Vavuniya told Reuters.</p>
<p>At least two soldiers were killed and more than 25 were wounded in fighting close to Omanthai, 14 km (nine miles) north of Vavuniya, the officer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Casualties are heavier on the LTTE (Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam) side, both dead and wounded,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Officials in the north earlier said at least eight rebels were killed and more than 15 wounded in the two-day-old offensive code-named &quot;Jaya Sikuru&quot;, or &quot;Sure of Victory&quot;.</p>
<p>The LTTE's international spokesman in London, Anton Raja, said the village of Puliyankulam, about 25 km (15 miles) north of Omanthai, had come under heavy attack by army artillery and air force Mi-24 helicoper gunships.</p>
<p>&quot;We have received information from the Wanni that the heavily populated village of Puliyankulam has come under attack,&quot; Raja told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;Even Omanthai is heavily populated. We hear thousands of civilians are fleeing for their lives,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Aid workers in the north said at least 1,500 civilians living along the army's path have left their homes and moved to safer areas near Madhu and Mannar in the northwest.</p>
<p>Troops backed by helicopter gunships, artillery and tanks broke out of bases in Vavuniya, 220 km (135 miles) north of the capital Colombo, and captured Omanthai on Wednesday morning.</p>
<p>Omanthai, a small agricultural community, constituted the southern forward defences of the LTTE, who control vast swathes of land to its north.</p>
<p>Military officials said the troops had destroyed a network of at least 20 rebel bunkers.</p>
<p>The LTTE are fighting for an independent homeland for minority Tamils in predominantly Sinhalese Sri Lanka's north and east in a 13-year-old war in which the government says more than 50,000 people have died. The LTTE say the toll is higher.</p>
<p>Analysts said the aim of the offensive was to open a land supply route linking Vavuniya with Jaffna peninsula, about 100 km (60 miles) further north.</p>
<p>The main highway that links the Indian Ocean island's south with the war-ravaged north has been cut by the war. But the LTTE's Raja said the rebels would fight to keep the road from falling into government hands.</p>
<p>&quot;The LTTE will offer the toughest resistance to advancing armed forces,&quot; Raja said. &quot;They will be defeated. It is the eventuality Sri Lankan forces will face when they march into Tamil territory like this.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
