<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="583336" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. April oil use up 3 pct from year ago - API.</title>
<headline>U.S. April oil use up 3 pct from year ago - API.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. petroleum deliveries, a key indicator of demand, were up three percent in April from a year ago, averaging 19.37 million barrels per day, the American Petroleum Institute said Wednesday.</p>
<p>April's imports of crude oil and petroleum products averaged a record high 10.14 million bpd, up 8.3 percent from a year ago in April, and slightly higher than the previous record 10.00 million bpd set in February 1977.</p>
<p>Crude oil imports jumped 9.4 percent to 8.0 million bpd from a year ago in April, while products imports rose 4.4 percent to 2.13 million bpd.  </p>
<p>The growth in April's total petroleum deliveries was about double the API's estimate for the underlying trend and was the largest year-to-year increase for deliveries since November, the API said. More demand for gasoline and distillate contributed to the increase, it said.</p>
<p>Prompted partly by lower retail prices, gasoline deliveries rose 2.3 percent from a year ago, to 8.05 million bpd from 7.87 million.</p>
<p>Gasoline stocks ended April at 191.1 million barrels, down 2.7 percent from March and down 3.2 percent from April 1996.</p>
<p>Distillate deliveries rose 4.7 percent to 3.54 million bpd from April 1996's 3.39 million on strong economic growth and colder than normal temperatures. High sulfur deliveries accounted for almost all the year-to-year growth, and demand growth was centered in the transportation sector.</p>
<p>Kerosine jet fuel deliveries exceeded last year's levels for the first time since January. At an average 1.543 million bpd, deliveries were 2.5 percent higher than a year ago, boosted by record levels of commercial air traffic.</p>
<p>However, kerosine jet fuel deliveries for the year to date were down 1.7 percent from a year ago because of the decline in the amount of fuel used in seasonal non-aviation uses.  </p>
<p>Deliveries of residual fuel in April dropped 3.6 percent to 718,000 bpd from 745,000 a year ago, following the seasonal pattern.</p>
<p>Deliveries of other oils averaged 4.55 million bpd in April, up 4.5 percent from a year ago, with part of that attributed to below-trend deliveries a year ago and part to April's cold snap that boosted propane heating demand.</p>
<p>Total U.S. crude oil production was up a slight 0.1 percent in April from a year ago, averaging 6.45 million bpd compared with 6.44 million bpd. Production in the lower 48 states that reached the highest level in more than a year, offset a decline in Alaska.</p>
<p>Refinery input to distillation units was up a slight 0.5 percent in April from a year ago at 14.47 million bpd from 14.40 million, and refinery utilization was at 93.8 percent in April compared with 93.7 percent a year ago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
