<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="583739" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Solidere slides in Beirut.</title>
<headline>Solidere slides in Beirut.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Solidere A and B shares continued to slide on the Beirut Stock Exchange on Wednesday and brokers said they expected them to fall back to levels they maintained before last week's surge.</p>
<p>Solidere A and B both fell to $11 from $11.5 and $11.375 respectively.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect Solidere shares to reach the $10.25-$10.75 levels because of the big supply of A shares dumped in the market,&quot; Fouad Salame, Assistant Treasurer at Banque D'Affaires du Liban et D'outre Mer, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The A and B shares hit 16-month highs of $11.75 and $12.25 last week after the company's GDRs soared in London on reports of buying by U.S. and European emerging market funds, but they have fallen back this week.</p>
<p>Banque Libanaise pour le Commerce also fell on Wednesday for the third successive session, to $16.25 from Tuesday's $16.75, after rising sharply for four-and-a-half months.</p>
<p>The other two listed banks, Banque Audi and Bank of Beirut, were unchanged at $20 and $3.5625 respectively.</p>
<p>The LIBX bank index fell 1.01 percent to 137.71. The LISPI general index fell 0.98 percent to 86.64 and the BLOM general index fell 3.26 percent to 953.47.</p>
<p>Salameh said the banks had good fundamentals that should sustain them.</p>
<p>&quot;The fundamentals are there. They should sustain Audi and BOB at their current levels. As for BLC, it should stabilise around $16.25 for a while and then start moving up,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>BLC's quarterly profit announced on Monday of $3.39 million excluding $1.8 million realised on the sale of real estate assets was &quot;positively surprising&quot;, Salame added.</p>
<p>&quot;The fundamentals are also there for Solidere but as long as there is supply of A shares the stock will keep moving down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Supply of Solidere A shares at the first fixing was 260,837 to demand of 14,942 shares. Supply of B shares was 103,497 against a demand of 11,500 at the same fixing.</p>
<p>Salame said a zero turnover on the second fixing of A shares on Monday dampened the market. There was no demand on that fixing as opposed to 195,798 shares in supply.</p>
<p>&quot;That was a mistake that should not have happened. It scared investors who thought liquidity was running away. They wanted to sell rather than buy,&quot; Salame said.</p>
<p>Total BSE turnover was 216,164 shares for a value of $1,859,785 compared with 201,666 shares and $2,144,311.</p>
<p>There was no trade in the four listed industrial companies: Ciments Libanais, Ciments Blancs, Eternit and Uniceramic.</p>
<p>- Zeina Soufan, Beirut editorial (9611) 745307  745308</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
