<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="583700" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: PRESS DIGEST-Canada-May 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-Canada-May 14.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the headlines selected from Canadian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE GLOBE AND MAIL:</p>
<p>- Debate stopped without winner: No leader manages to claim upper hand before moderator's collapse ends political jousting.</p>
<p>- Early end of debate costs Bloc leader his chance at key unity question: Duceppe misses the prize.</p>
<p>- Changing goals/Canadian hockey needs to develop better. How best to do it?: Game plan needed to fix system.</p>
<p>- Ontario Hydro to cut staff by 950.</p>
<p>- IDs at fingertip, Harris predicts: Coded images could replace health and hospital cards.</p>
<p>- Zairian rebels close in on Kinshasa: Government imposes curfew, calls on residents to take up arms to defend capital.</p>
<p>REPORT ON BUSINESS:</p>
<p>- Demand for office space soars: Major Canadian cities face shortage of large blocks in prime buildings, survey reveals.</p>
<p>- Digital accuses Intel of illegal copying: Files lawsuit seeking to stop computer chip maker from selling any more Pentium products.</p>
<p>- IBM stock sets 9-year high: Record close in sight, analysts say.</p>
<p>- 'Free market' urged by panel: 'Cornerstone' of task force's approach to financial services.</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL POST:</p>
<p>- Pipelines duel for shippers: TransCanada goes head to head with Alliance in the race to sign up shippers for new capacity that's set to come on stream in 1999.</p>
<p>- Sweetened offer turns up heat in Merfin battle.</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
