<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="583972" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Russia-NATO deal eases alliance expansion - Spain.</title>
<headline>Russia-NATO deal eases alliance expansion - Spain.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain endorsed an historic NATO-Russia accord on Wednesday, saying it was needed to reassure Moscow and facilitate &quot;necessary expansion&quot; of the western alliance to incorporate former Eastern bloc nations.</p>
<p>The deal, agreed in Moscow by Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov and NATO Secretary General Javier Solana after months of tough negotiations, was aimed at soothing Moscow's deep concerns about its former Warsaw Pact allies joining the defence alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;This is very good news...(The accord) paves the way for this necessary expansion toward the democracies of central Europe,&quot; Foreign Minister Abel Matutes told a news conference.</p>
<p>Spain will host the NATO expansion summit in July where Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic are expected to receive invitations to join the 16-member alliance. Romania and Slovenia also hope to be in the first wave.</p>
<p>The accord will contribute to greater stability and understanding in Russia-NATO relations, Matutes said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is important that Russia feel secure and has nothing to fear from its western flank,&quot; said Matutes, adding this would enhance western security.</p>
<p>A NATO-Russia joint statement said they had made &quot;decisive progress&quot; on key issues including military problems, which had been the main obstacles to agreement.</p>
<p>But the text gave no details, leaving it unclear whether the two sides had resolved disagreements over whether the pact should include written guarantees that NATO will not station military structures and nuclear weapons on the territory of new member states.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
