<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="584007" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-DepFa gearing up for acquisitions.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-DepFa gearing up for acquisitions.</headline>
<byline>David Crossland</byline>
<dateline>WIESBADEN, Germany 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's DePfa-Bank AG, one of the largest private sector bond issuers in Europe, said on Wednesday it planned to create authorised capital to prepare itself for acquisitions.</p>
<p>Deutsche Pfandbrief- und Hypothekenbank AG said it would ask shareholders to approve measures which, based on a share price of 100 marks ($58.76), would enable it to raise a total of more than 1.6 billion marks in fresh capital until June 25, 2002.</p>
<p>The shares closed at 95 marks on Wednesday, down two marks.</p>
<p>The bank stressed it did not need fresh capital to fund its operating business and would only resort to a capital increase to make &quot;strategic investments.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Targeted acquisitions can substantially increase the earnings potential and return on equity of our group,&quot; chief executive Thilo Koepfler told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;That is why our board has taken the decision to ask the annual shareholder meeting to create authorised and conditional capital.&quot; The shareholder meeting is on June 25.</p>
<p>Koepfler would not say whether DePfa was already in talks with a prospective takeover candidate, whether it was planning a purchase in Germany or abroad, or the business area in which it was seeking to make the acquisition.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't talk in concrete terms about that today, it would only make the process more expensive and might hurt our negotiating position,&quot; Koepfler said.</p>
<p>DePfa will ask shareholders to approve the creation of two sets of up to 25 million marks of authorised capital plus an additional 40 million marks of authorised capital.</p>
<p>It is also seeking permission to issue up to 300 million marks of convertible and warrant bonds.</p>
<p>DePfa itself unwittingly sparked market speculation in March that it may be a candidate for takeover when it alleged Swiss giant UBS had bought nine percent of its shares.</p>
<p>But confusion reigned after UBS repeatedly and categorically denied that it held a stake of that size and there has been no final clarification since.</p>
<p>There was none forthcoming on Wednesday either. DePfa declined to comment further on the matter and merely issued a brief chronology of events from the time it received a confidential tip-off that UBS held a stake.</p>
<p>&quot;We think it appropriate with such a sensitive issue to limit ourselves to the facts,&quot; Koepfler said. &quot;I won't interpret the facts.&quot;</p>
<p>Outlining its results, DePfa said operating profits before provisions rose 11 percent to 167 million marks in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>Koepfler predicted its earnings per share, calculated under stricht DVFA accounting standards, would rise to &quot;not under&quot; six marks in 1997 from 5.12 marks in 1996. The bank aimed to raise its return on equity after tax to between nine and 10 percent by 1998 from 7.3 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Depfa is the biggest private sector issuer of mark-denominated bonds which it sells to refinance loans made to the public sector.</p>
<p>It has also been at the forefront of the switch to larger volume Pfandbrief mortgage bond issues aimed at boosting liquidity in the market and attracting international investors.</p>
<p>&quot;It is our aim to be be regarded by investors as a domestic issuing bank in all core countries of the euro by the launch of monetary union,&quot; Koepfler said.</p>
<p>DePfa is a major lender to the German government and its overall lending volume rose 14.2 percent to 150.2 billion marks in 1996.</p>
<p>Its lending accounts for nine percent of Germany's public sector debt to banks which totals more than one trillion marks.</p>
<p>The public sector has funded an additional 1.3 trillion marks of its debt through debt issues. The overall public debt totals 2.3 trillion marks.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.701 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WIESBADEN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
