<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="584131" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French shares rally on polls but outlook unclear.</title>
<headline>French shares rally on polls but outlook unclear.</headline>
<byline>Marcel Michelson</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>French shares rallied on Wednesday on opinion polls showing the centre-right government is set to win the May 25 and June 1 elections, but dealers wondered how far the market could rise.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is clearly playing on a win by the centre-right,&quot; said a head trader at a German bank in Paris. &quot;But we have to be cautious after the first round (of the elections),&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The French blue-chip share index set a series of all-time highs on Wednesday and at 0940 GMT it was up 1.39 percent at 2757.48, below its latest high of 2,765.91.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we can go as far as 2,780 today and to 2,850 in the coming days, but then it's time to take profits,&quot; another added.</p>
<p>A recent poll of brokerages conducted by financial newspaper L'Agefi showed that they saw the CAC-40 rising to 3,000 in 12 months and expected a level of 2,640 in three months' time.</p>
<p>&quot;What we are going to see is a big rally on the election after which we will get consolidation,&quot; said an analyst at a French bank who preferred not to be named. He saw the index dipping after the election but possibly resuming its upward trend in the second half.</p>
<p>Jacques Chahine Finance recently asked fund managers about their expectations concerning the elections. They saw the CAC-40 fall to 2,400 and 10-year government bond yields rise to 6.5 percent if the Socialists won.</p>
<p>Were the current government to be re-elected, the CAC could quickly head to 3,000 and the 10-year yield could come down to 5.5 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to be very careful after the first round,&quot; said the head trader at the German bank. &quot;If the centre-right gets a big boost in the first round there could be a drawback in the second,&quot; he said, adding: &quot;And if the left advances in the first round, the government could still win the second round.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;In France, people vote with their heart in the first round and with their wallet in the second round,&quot; he said. Were the government to win the election, there would be only a brief period in which it could prove its new commitments.</p>
<p>&quot;There would very soon be a credibility test,&quot; Francois Langlade-Demoyen of CSFB in London said.</p>
<p>The financial sector, banks and insurers, are expected to benefit if the government gets re-elected. Analysts said that there is still much scope for restructuring in the French financial sector, which will undoubtedly take the form of large redundancies.</p>
<p>These would be easier to implement with a centre-right government than under the Socialists, they added.</p>
<p>Financial shares rose strongly on Wednesday. BNP was up 5.74 percent at 263.50 francs at midday, Paribas was up 3.46 percent at 406.50 francs and Societe Generale was up 2.99 percent at 688 francs.</p>
<p>Market strategists said that while Paris had now progressed well, it was unlikely to outperform other markets in the short term but would follow them.</p>
<p>Key external factors determining the French share market's direction will be U.S. data, such as the Producer Price Index on Wednesday and the Consumer Price Index on Thursday and, last but not least, the Federal Reserve Open Market Committee (FOMC) of May 20.</p>
<p>In the longer run, six to 12 months, the French market could rise quicker than other European markets because French companies still have a lot of profit recovery potential, Jacques Chahine said.</p>
<p>First quarter sales published recently, such as a 12.1 percent increase at Alcatel Alsthom on Tuesday, are confirming the profit recovery and could translate in upgrades in earnings outlook.</p>
<p>Alcatel closed 3.57 percent higher on Tuesday on the back of its sales figure and on midday on Wednesday it was up another 3.89 percent at 694 francs.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
