<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="584252" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Reuters French Advertising &amp; Media Digest - May 14.</title>
<headline>Reuters French Advertising &amp; Media Digest - May 14.</headline>
<text>
<p>---------------- FAM -----------------</p>
<p>REUTERS FRENCH ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA DIGEST</p>
<p>---------------- May 14, 1997 -----------------</p>
<p>News from Reuters and the French press on Advertising, Marketing, Media, the Internet, Brand-name Products and Consumer Trends.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>ADVERTISING &amp; MARKETING:</p>
<p>PARIS - Carat Expert, the measurement arm of French advertising space specialist Carat, says there has been a serious slide in the number of people watching television in France in the first part of this year. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - France's La Rochefortaise de Communication will seek to raise funds on the Paris bourse to finance a telemarketing operation in the U.S., its chairman says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - Mediametrie's figures for television viewing in France show a slide in audience for the general, terrestrial channels and a big rise for the smallest category, other TV, which has risen 18.75 percent since the start of this year. (Le Figaro).</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>MEDIA &amp; THE INTERNET:</p>
<p>PARIS - French pay television group Canal Plus denies an Italian newspaper report it is close to an accord over the stake held by German media magnate Leo Kirch in Italian pay TV firm Telepiu.</p>
<p>(Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - Two French films get big box office success in their first week in Paris, a historical first for French cinema. &quot;La Verite Si Je Mens&quot;, a film set in Paris's garment district, has culled 200,000 entries, while Luc Besson's &quot;The Fifth Element&quot; has pushed above 400,000, probably putting it on a par with mega-hits like Steven Spielberg's Jurassic Park with nearly two million French viewers in its first week. (Liberation)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - French broadcasting watchdog le Conseil Superieur de l'Audiovisuel (CSA) decides to put 300 FM radio frequencies on the market. (Liberation)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>BRAND NAME PRODUCTS &amp; MARKETS:</p>
<p>PARIS - French cigarette maker Seita's turnover rises 0.8 percent in the first quarter to 4.05 million francs ($705,000). An 8.7 percent price rise in December only partially compensated a 12.7 percent fall in sales volume due to competition from low-priced products, the company says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - French car maker PSA Peugeot Citroen says its first quarter turnover rose 0.6 percent to 43.51 billion francs. Unit sales to Peugeot and Citroen cars in Western Europe fell 9.8 percent to 381,000 due to a sharp fall in the French market, it says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - French car maker Renault says its first quarter turnover rose 3.03 percent to 47.20 billion francs. An upturn in the Western European car market and a favourable trend in exchange rates offset a decline in the French car market in the period, it says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>CONSUMER TRENDS:</p>
<p>PARIS - Fast food takes hold in the home of haute cuisine. The French are the second biggest spenders on hamburgers in Europe, behind the British, according to a study by Britain's Marketing Intelligence carried out in February 1997. (Le Parisien)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - New car registrations rise 9.3 in Western Europe in April, the European Automobile manufacturers Association (ACEA) says. It also gave market share figures for the main manufacturers. (Reuter)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>Paris Editorial, Sue Landau</p>
<p>Tel 33 1 42 21 53 33</p>
<p>Fax 33 1 42 36 10 72</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>For further information and news, see Reuters Advertising &amp; Media Briefing. And visit us on the Internet at http://www.Bizinfo.reuters.com</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>($ = 5.742 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
