<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="584205" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU's gene-food law to leave consumers no wiser.</title>
<headline>EU's gene-food law to leave consumers no wiser.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Chalmers</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union laws on genetically modified foods and food ingredients are due to come into effect on Thursday amid criticisms that rules are unclear and fail to tell consumers what they are eating.</p>
<p>The new rules, which apply to a variety of foods in addition to gene-modified organisms (GMOs), define market authorisation procedures for foods not previously eaten by humans.</p>
<p>Euro-MPs, European environmental groups and some in the food industry say the regulation has unworkable labelling clauses which risk fragmenting the EU's single market.</p>
<p>Food industry bodies, meanwhile, have welcomed the legislation, saying repeated delays had damaged companies' competitive positions by keeping new products off the market.</p>
<p>Yves Goemans, European counsel to the Belgian-based food company Protein Technologies International, said the new rules had already spawned three different interpretations of their labelling requirements in Britain, Denmark and the Netherlands.</p>
<p>At issue is how authorities test for differences between traditional varieties of a food and genetically modified versions. Novel foods must carry labels only when deemed to be &quot;no longer equivalent&quot; to existing varieties.</p>
<p>But confusion has emerged from the compromise text agreed earlier this year between EU industry ministers and Euro-MPs.</p>
<p>Goemans said the European Commission had two options to clear up the mess: by ordering strict adherence to the scientific equivalence tests or by going for blanket labelling.</p>
<p>&quot;If (the first) is politically unsustainable, then the Commission should be busy drafting amendments to the novel food regulation to bring it in line with what politically the EU wants. This would involve altering the legislation to require labelling,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Goemans fears the Commission will settle for a middle way, requiring labelling for GMO-derived proteins while allowing other derivatives to pass unlabelled, a route he said lent more to expediency than scientific logic. He did admit that it would also damage his company's market for isolated soy proteins.</p>
<p>Food labelling has become a highly political issue in the EU in the wake of the mad-cow beef scare and rows about EU authorisation for market release of a maize strain sold by Novartis and Monsanto 's gene-altered soybeans.</p>
<p>The environmental campaign group Greenpeace branded the regulation a &quot;disgrace&quot; which denied consumers the chance to decide what they ate.</p>
<p>&quot;From the outset, it was clear there was no intention by the European Commission that these goods should be labelled, nor for genetically engineered food products to be identifiable for customers,&quot; Greenpeace said in a statement on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Politicians and industrialists are ensuring that consumers are completely confused and bereft of the opportunity to choose... &quot; Greenpeace's Louise Gale said in the statement.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very clear that unless genetically modified organisms are segregated from the farm to the supermarket shelf, this labelling regulation is a nonsense,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>A spokesman for European Industry Commissioner ruled out any immediate rule changes.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not going to modify a regulation that's just come into effect,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;People wanting to put novel food on the market will have to follow this authorisation procedure. There's no urgency to do something in the very next days. If things are unclear or not, I have my doubts,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
