<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="584412" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Howard sees RBA noting budget, lower rate climate.</title>
<headline>Howard sees RBA noting budget, lower rate climate.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard said on Wednesday that the Reserve Bank of Australia (RBA) would note government budgetary action when it next considered interest rates.</p>
<p>The government's Tuesday budget, for the year to June 1998, had set the climate for lower rates, he said on Perth radio 6PR.</p>
<p>&quot;... cutting debt further, producing a surplus in year two of this budgetary cycle -- that's 98/99 -- that means that there is downward and not upward pressure on interest rates,&quot; Howard said when asked whether the budget would bring down interest rates.  </p>
<p>When the bank next considered monetary settings it would know that the government &quot;has done its bit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The interviewer suggested that the government had set the climate for lower rates and Howard responded: &quot;Of course we have set the climate.&quot;</p>
<p>The budget included measures that would improve the fiscal balance by A$352 million in 1997/98 and, more importantly, A$1.9 billion in the following year, when the government would deliver an underlying surplus -- that is, excluding asset sales.  </p>
<p>The bank eased monetary policy 1.5 percentage points last year, to bring overnight cash rates down to 6.0 percent, and markets see little chance of further easing this year.</p>
<p>This is the full exchange between Howard and the interviewer, Neil Mitchell:</p>
<p>Interviewer: &quot;Do you think this will now bring interest rates down?&quot;</p>
<p>Howard: &quot;Well that is a matter ultimately to be determined, if I may say so, by market forces.&quot;</p>
<p>Interviewer: &quot;Of course.&quot;  </p>
<p>Howard: &quot;Well, I mean, exactly. Exactly. Of course it's going to be set by market forces.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;But I tell you this, Neil, that cutting debt further, producing a surplus in year two of this budgetary cycle -- that's 98/99 -- that means that there is downward and not upward pressure on interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;In other words when the monetary authorities next look at interest rates -- and I'm not tellilng them what they ought to do, that's a matter for the monetary authorities -- but when they next look at interest rates they will know that the government has done its bit.  </p>
<p>&quot;The government has not added to interest rate pressure. The government this year will repay A$5 billion of the debts of the Australian people.</p>
<p>Interviewer: &quot;At least, the government has set the climate for lower interest rates.&quot;</p>
<p>Howard: &quot;Of course we have set the climate.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2370</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
