<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="584748" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan Semicon in $350 mln convertibles.</title>
<headline>Taiwan Semicon in $350 mln convertibles.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co, Taiwan's largest semiconductor maker, said on Wednesday its board had approved overseas issuance of up to US$350 million in convertible bonds to raise funds for capital expenditures.  </p>
<p>Taiwan Semiconductor issued a statement saying the bond issue would raise funds for the company's long-term investments over the coming two years. It did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Taiwan Semiconductor has embarked on an ambitious expansion. In mid-April, it announced it would build six advanced wafer-fabrication plants as part of a T$400 billion investment at southern Taiwan's Tainan Scienced-based industrial park.</p>
<p>The Tainan investment would be worth T$400 billion over 10 years, making it Taiwan's largest single industrial project -- bigger even than Formosa group's huge T$240 billion petrochemical plant at central Yunlin county.  </p>
<p>The chipmaker's board had approved the promotion of Rick Tsai as executive vic-president, Gary Tseng, Quincy Lin and Stephen T. Tso as senior vice-presidents, and J.B. Chen as vice-president, the statement said.</p>
<p>The company has become the world's largest custom maker of integrated circuits, a strategy that has attracted many imitators because of its success.</p>
<p>The firm's foundry business does not design and sell its own IC products, but custom makes them according to customers' specifications.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I48100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
