<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="584767" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALDIVES: Pakistan urges India to pull troops from Kashmir.</title>
<headline>Pakistan urges India to pull troops from Kashmir.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>MALE, Maldives 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif said on Tuesday he was confident India would agree to discuss the future of divided Kashmir in bilateral talks and urged Delhi to withdraw troops from the Himalayan region.</p>
<p>Sharif told Reuters Television before leaving a regional summit in the Indian Ocean nation of the Maldives that he was satisfied with face-to-face talks on Monday with his Indian counterpart, Inder Kumar Gujral.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the situation has taken a good turn. We have held talks yesterday after a deadlock of four years. The talks were very constructive, very meaningful, and we've agreed to talk more,&quot; Sharif said on the tarmac of Male's airport before boarding his aircraft.</p>
<p>Sharif said the two countries' most senior diplomats would meet in Islamabad next month and hopefully form working groups to discuss the issues dividing the two neighbours.</p>
<p>The Pakistani leader was asked if he agreed with his foreign minister, Gohar Ayub Khan, who on Monday said the Indian army had &quot;more or less gone beserk&quot; in Jammu and Kashmir where Moslem guerrillas are fighting Indian rule.</p>
<p>&quot;I did mention this point to the Indian prime minister,&quot; Sharif said. &quot;I told him that the Indian government must consider withdrawing the troops or the paramilitary troops from Kashmir, and also at the same time pave the way for a dialogue between India and Pakistan.&quot;</p>
<p>Later, Gujral was asked at a news conference to comment on Khan's remark about the Indian army in Jammu and Kashmir.</p>
<p>&quot;My reaction was and is that our armies in Jammu and Kashmir have not gone there for an excursion. They are responding to a situation. And when that situation ceases, we will also perhaps bring them down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Delhi accuses Pakistan of training and arming guerrillas fighting a seven-year insurgency in mostly Hindu India's only Moslem majority state. Islamabad denies the charge.</p>
<p>Gujral said he had pointed out to Sharif &quot;terrorism in our region and the urgent need to stop it&quot;. The Indian leader said South Asian leaders would condemn terrorism in a declaration to be issued at the end of a three-day summit on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Asked if one of the working groups should be devoted to the Kashmir issue, the Pakistani leader said: &quot;Certainly, because Kashmir is the core issue, and we have to address this issue very seriously.&quot;</p>
<p>Sharif, questioned over what would happen if India refused to discuss Kashmir in a working group, said: &quot;I think they will listen to us.&quot;</p>
<p>The Pakistani leader was scheduled to fly to Iran to deliver financial aid to earthquake victims there, and then go to Turkmenistan later on Tuesday for a regional summit.</p>
<p>At their 90-minute talks on a resort island in this tropical archipelago, Sharif and Gujral agreed their foreign secretaries would identify subjects to be discussed in the working groups.</p>
<p>&quot;We should not expect dramatic results,&quot; Gujral said. &quot;It is encouraging that both of us feel that there is a need for an improvement in relationships and shedding all those issues which possibly can cause strain between us.&quot;</p>
<p>Pakistan's Foreign Secretary, Shamshad Ahmed, said after the talks on Monday that one of the working groups would be devoted to Kashmir -- the cause of two of the three wars the two countries have fought since independence in 1947.</p>
<p>But Indian Foreign Secretary Salman Haider later said no decision had yet been taken on the issues to be discussed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALDR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MALE, Maldives"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALDIVES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
