<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="584780" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul prosecutors to question Kim's son again.</title>
<headline>Seoul prosecutors to question Kim's son again.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean state prosecutors will summon for questioning President Kim Young-sam's son on Thursday in connection with a probe into a scandal involving the younger Kim, a prosecution official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Kim Hyun-chul has denied allegations that he took kickbacks from companies in return for influence-peddling and that he meddled in state affairs.</p>
<p>The official confirmed a report by state-run Korean Broadcasting System (KBS) television that Kim Hyun-chul, president Kim's second son, would be summoned by 2:00 p.m. (0500 GMT) on Thursday. He declined to give any more information.</p>
<p>The younger Kim, who helped engineer his father's win in the 1992 presidential election, is also under investigation over allegations that he had kept part of the unspent funds.</p>
<p>He was questioned by prosecutors in February but cleared of any wrongdoing in connection with a loans-for-kickbacks scandal uncovered by the collapse in January of Hanbo Steel Co.</p>
<p>Hanbo's failure under some five trillion won ($5.6 billion) debt revealed a web of corrupt alliances between politicians, businessmen and bankers.</p>
<p>Two of his business associates have been arrested on charges that they took bribes in return for promises to lobby the younger Kim to help obtain government broadcast licences.</p>
<p>Last week the Chosun Ilbo newspaper reported Kim Ki-sup, a former top intelligence officer, had asked the Hansol Group to manage seven billion won. Hansol has denied the report.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
