<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="584718" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: ININTERVIEW - Placer keen on Philippines.</title>
<headline>ININTERVIEW - Placer keen on Philippines.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's Placer Dome Inc, which sold its stake in a Philippine copper mine which suffered a major leak of tailings, said on Wednesday it will agressively pursue other ventures in the country.</p>
<p>&quot;We are active in the Philippines. We've got a number of exploration properties there that we either have or we're negotiating for,&quot; Ian Austin, chief financial officer of Placer Dome, told Reuters in an interview at a mining conference here.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has made it clear that we are welcome in the Philippines and we intend to aggressively pursue opportunities there,&quot; he added without elaboration.  </p>
<p>Placer Dome divested its 39.9 percent stake in Marcopper Mining Corp last March.</p>
<p>The accident at the copper mine in March 1996 on the central island of Marinduque triggered a furore in the Philippines with several environmental groups demanding tougher safety measures.</p>
<p>The leak in a tunnel of the mine was estimated to have dumped 1.5 million cubic metres of tailings or mine wastes and affected wide stretches of the 25 km (15.5 mile) long Boac river on Marinduque.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Marcopper event was an unfortunate accident, but I think the way we dealt with it shows we've taken responsibility for it,&quot; Austin said.</p>
<p>Placer Dome said last March that it continued to provide money to settle the more than 2,000 claims for about 19 million pesos from people in the 44 villages affected by the spill.</p>
<p>The Philippine government later filed criminal charges against two Placer executives at Marcopper for the accident.</p>
<p>-- Rene Pastor, Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
