<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="584914" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - May 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - May 14.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Greek Cypriot press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>ALITHIA</p>
<p>- The behaviour of the Greek and Turkish Cypriot sides in the Cyprus dispute are coming under the scrutiny of the European Union.</p>
<p>- Swiss media pokes fun at Cyprus Airways pilots, one of whom last week landed a planeload of Swiss tourists at the wrong airport because he did not want to work overtime.</p>
<p>CYPRUS MAIL</p>
<p>- An Armenian woman who went to a police station to collect her missing son was arrested as an illegal immigrant. Attorney-general orders an inquiry into deportation action against the woman, under United Nations protection.</p>
<p>- President Glafcos Clerides leaves hospital after heart tests.</p>
<p>FINANCIAL MIRROR</p>
<p>- Former bosses of Cyprus Airways have started blaming one another for the airline's demise.</p>
<p>- Laiki Factors claims a 49 percent local market share.</p>
<p>HARAVGHI</p>
<p>- Protectionism policies towards Cypriot businesses has an expiry date, Communications and Works Minister Leondios Ierodiakonou tells parliament.</p>
<p>- Police used batons and teargas to disperse students of the Higher Technical Institute on a protest march to the Labour Ministry. The students want a legislation framework for the operation of the institute.</p>
<p>PHILELEPHTHEROS</p>
<p>- International mediators on the Cyprus dispute have still not extracted a &quot;yes&quot; out of Turkish Cypriot leader Rauf Denktash for a give and take procedure during upcoming talks on the basic elements of the problem.</p>
<p>SIMERINI</p>
<p>- Denktash rejects compromise on basic aspects of the Cyprus dispute such as sovereignty, the guarantor system and issues of security.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
