<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="585042" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Study finds cocktail drastically cuts HIV deaths.</title>
<headline>Study finds cocktail drastically cuts HIV deaths.</headline>
<byline>Maggie Fox</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>AIDS researchers from four continents have published the results of a key study which is changing the way HIV-positive patients are treated.</p>
<p>Their report showed that adding a third drug, lamivudine (Glaxo-Wellcome's Epivir), to anti-AIDS combinations based on Glaxo's AZT (zidovudine) greatly increased survival of those infected with the HIV virus and stopped them getting worse.</p>
<p>The results were so striking that the study was stopped in July to allow everyone in the trial to get Epivir. The full results of the study are published on Friday in the Lancet medical journal.</p>
<p>The CAESAR (Canada, Australia, Europe and South Africa) trial included 1,895 patients from around the world who got a year's treatment with either AZT, or AZT plus either Roche's Hivid (ddC) or Bristol-Myers Squibb's Videx (ddI).</p>
<p>All also got either a placebo or Epivir or Epivir plus loviride, an experimental non-nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitor (NNRTI) made by Janssen Pharmaceutica NV, a Belgian unit of Johnson &amp; Johnson.</p>
<p>There were 57 percent fewer cases of progression to AIDS or death in those who got the extra drugs. The more drugs the better, and doctors have been advised to abandon using just two drugs.</p>
<p>The most advanced regimes now also include a protease inhibitor, a class of drugs that attacks the virus at a different point of its replicative cycle than the AZT class of reverse transcriptase inhibitors. The NNRTIs add a third dimension.</p>
<p>&quot;In the final analysis of 1,840 patients, progression (to AIDS) had occurred in 20 percent of 471 placebo-treated patients, nine percent of 907 lamivudine-treated patients and nine percent of 462 patients who received lamivudine plus loviride,&quot; the team, coordinated by David Cooper of the University of New South Wales in Sydney, wrote.</p>
<p>Adding loviride did seem to help a little but the researchers said the study was not big enough to determine this and urged further research.</p>
<p>Mark Feinberg of the Office of AIDS Research at the National Institutes of Health in Maryland said the study served historical rather than current needs, but nonetheless would help doctors decide how to treat patients with HIV.</p>
<p>Because HIV rapidly develops resistance, there was no point in using a combination of just two drugs, he said in a commentary on the study.</p>
<p>&quot;Thus at present the most effective and reliable way of preventing the emergence of drug-resistant viruses and of achieving maximum protection from HIV-induced immune-system damage is to use two nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitors (eg, zidovudine and lamivudine) with a potent...protease inhibitor,&quot; Feinberg wrote.</p>
<p>The CAESAR group noted that it is expensive to treat HIV-infected patients, but said the costly drugs could save money in the end.</p>
<p>&quot;In this study we observed that the delayed disease progression associated with lamivudine use resulted in significantly fewer patients needing hospital admission, unscheduled outpatient and emergency-care visits, and HIV-related medications,&quot; they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
