<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="58517" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. funds buy into Mexico recovery despite rebels.</title>
<headline>U.S. funds buy into Mexico recovery despite rebels.</headline>
<byline>George Lerner</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brushing off the rise of a new rebel group in Mexico, U.S. investors are placing their bets on economic recovery south of the Rio Grande, U.S. portfolio managers said.</p>
<p>The emergence of the Popular Revolutionary Army (EPR) in June raised prickly memories of rebellions past but did not arouse alarm on Wall Street.</p>
<p>The unrest seemed unlikely to unravel U.S. interest in committing fresh funds, evidenced by Mexico's $1.0 billion bond issue priced Tuesday, U.S. investors said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't think people have lost their sensitivity to the political situation in Mexico, but this resurgence in political instablity comes at a time when the economic picture has shown improvement,&quot; said Nathan Sandler, portfolio manager at Trust Co of the West.</p>
<p>The balance of political and economic fundamentals favored sharp improvement in Mexico, Sandler added, who also noted that the country always held potential for surprises.</p>
<p>The rise of EPR brought up images of the Zapatista National Liberation Army, which launched an armed movement in the southern state of Chiapas in January 1994.  </p>
<p>But analysts drew sharp contrasts between EPR and the Zapatistas, who have been in peace talks with the government and expressed intentions to convert into a political force.</p>
<p>Mexican President Ernesto Zedillo has condemned the elusive EPR rebels as criminals and vowed to hunt them down, but the guerrillas pledged to step up their attacks.</p>
<p>The EPR strikes last month in the states of Oaxaca and Guerrero initially rattled the currency and equity markets, but players soon settled down when the attacks seemed to be limited in scope and have little popular support.  </p>
<p>One U.S. portfolio manager who recently visited Guerrero said the EPR's ideology and base remained foggy.</p>
<p>Several U.S. investment banks, including Santander Investment Securities, Bear Stearns and Lehman Brothers, recently issued reports dispelling concerns that EPR was a lasting destabilizing force.</p>
<p>&quot;People have gotten inured to (the movement),&quot; said Darryl McLeod, senior economist at Lehman brothers. &quot;(EPR) is not going to be a major problem in the near future.  It's going to be an annoyance, but not a major source of disruptions.&quot;  </p>
<p>Evidence of recovery, characterized by the stunning 7.2 percent growth year-over-year in the second quarter, led many U.S. firms to raise their allocations to the country's assets.</p>
<p>This confidence was manifested in Mexico's ability to raise $1.0 billion in 20-year bonds to yield 11.51 percent this week via Goldman Sachs and Merrill Lynch International.</p>
<p>The country set $750 million on Monday, and the following day added $250 million and lowered the spread to 445 basis points from 450-462 basis points over U.S. Treasuries.  </p>
<p>&quot;It seems like there are new buyers in this market and existing buyers are scrambling for yield,&quot; said Richard Segal, Santander Investment's chief of emerging market research.</p>
<p>But some investors warned that the optimism may have gone too far.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm optimistic on Mexico from a fundamental perspective that growth seems to be returning to the country,&quot; said Steve Merrell, senior portfolio manager at American Express Financial Advisors.  &quot;The thing that causes me concern is that everybody is going in the same direction.&quot;</p>
<p>Mexican assets seemed overbought at current levels, Merrell said. The key question is whether the numerous new players - the &quot;crossover&quot; U.S. high yield investors - are game to ride out any potential market instability, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If we get a blowup somewhere, do they just dump and run for cover again or do they stick with it and realize the fundamental value?&quot; Merrell said.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
