<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="585269" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar ends firmer in U.S., eyes German gold talk.</title>
<headline>Dollar ends firmer in U.S., eyes German gold talk.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar ended higher against the mark and yen, bolstered partly by concern Germany may revalue its gold to help shrink its yawning budget deficit this year and by a rise in a key U.S. inflation barometer, currency experts said.</p>
<p>BZW Securities Inc chief economist Chris Iggo said the news from Germany is helping the dollar against the mark because of the suspicion that the German government will have to resort to &quot;creative accounting&quot; in order to meet their budget deficit target for this year.  </p>
<p>Nations aiming to join the proposed single European currency must cut public budget deficits to 3.0 percent of gross domestic product in 1997. Germany's deficit currently exceeds that level.</p>
<p>German Finance Minister Theo Waigel on Thursday told a news conference that the Bundesbank's gold reserves should be revalued at close to the market level.</p>
<p>Gold is valued at an average of 144 marks per ounce on the Bundesbank balance sheet, less than the market price of around 600 marks. Revaluation would provide windfall profits of about 40 billion marks based on current market prices.  </p>
<p>The news about the possible revaluation of German gold reserves came on the same day that tax experts revealed Germany faces an estimated 18 billion mark ($10.6 billion) shortfall in tax revenues this year, which might hurt its efforts to qualify for the single European currency.</p>
<p>The dollar closed at 1.6965/70 marks, up from 1.6905/10 marks at the open. Against the yen, the dollar rose to 115.75/85 from 115.40/50.</p>
<p>The Labor Department reported the Consumer Price Index (CPI) rose 0.1 percent in April. The index climbed 0.3 percent in the core, which excludes volatile food and energy items.  </p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters had expected the CPI to gain 0.1 percent in April, with the core up 0.2 percent.</p>
<p>BZW's Iggo noted that the dollar was a &quot;little bit bid&quot; after the increase in the core component of the Consumer Price Index, which prompted investors to think about the Federal Reserve raising interest rates again next week.</p>
<p>Fed policymakers will meet next Tuesday to decide whether to tighten credit again. On March 25, they had increased the federal funds target rate to 5.50 percent from 5.25 percent.</p>
<p>Some traders also felt remarks by U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin provided mild support to the embattled currency.  </p>
<p>Rubin repeated his support for a strong dollar and said a strong dollar boosts market confidence, cuts interest rates and keeps inflation low.</p>
<p>When asked if Rubin's remarks aided the dollar, Mark Gargano, managing director of currency derivatives at First Union National Bank, said: &quot;I think so. I think they are getting to a point -- Rubin and also the Japanese officials -- where they think dollar-yen's fallen far enough in the short run.&quot;</p>
<p>In Europe, the dollar had plummetted to 114.70 yen, its lowest level since December 27.  </p>
<p>The dollar had slid to 114.70 yen on Thursday as traders bet official interest rates in Japan are headed higher.</p>
<p>Ben Strauss, an assistant vice president at Bank Julius Baer and Co, cited &quot;the outlook for Japanese rates and people unwinding the positions that they've had on for a couple of years now&quot; as reasons for the dollar's sharp decline.</p>
<p>&quot;Soon as we got under the 115 level, there was some short covering interest and it took us right back up to 116,&quot; Strauss added.  </p>
<p>Growing speculation that record low official Japanese rates could rise stemmed partly from remarks made by a senior Japanese legislator on Thursday.</p>
<p>Jiji news agency quoted Koichi Kato, secretary-general of the ruling Liberal Democratic Party, as saying Japan may face pressure to change its current low interest rates as it progresses with financial market deregulation.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the dollar rose to 1.4280/90 Swiss francs from 1.4268/73, but fell to Canadian $1.3709/14 from C$1.3835/40. Sterling climbed to $1.6428/38 from $1.6415/25.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar rose to $0.7770/75 from $0.7767/72.</p>
<p>((-- Donna Sells, 212-859-1668))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
