<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="585329" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE world sugar ends lower, maintains support.</title>
<headline>CSCE world sugar ends lower, maintains support.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A late session bout of trade selling pressured CSCE July world sugar below its downside target, but the contract climbed over the key level to close only slightly down.</p>
<p>Traders said activity was thin ahead of the annual U.S. Cane Sugar Refiners' Association dinner on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of people are traveling already from Europe,&quot; a New York-based  broker said, adding that the market is likely to hold its range for the next week.</p>
<p>The July contract closed down 0.04 cent at 11.01 cents per lb, having ranged from the recent low of 10.98 to 11.08 cents. Second-position October settled 0.04 weaker at 10.81 cents.</p>
<p>Cargill was noted as a late-session seller over 11.05 cents. Trade buying in the July/October spread helped to hold July over 11.00 cents, dealers said.</p>
<p>Firm support was pegged around 10.92, a former resistance point, below which sell stops are said to be lurking, followed by 10.85 cents in July.</p>
<p>Resistance was cited at 11.11 cents and then at 11.20 cents.</p>
<p>An estimated 7,152 lots changed hands on the day, compared with Wednesday's official 11,527 lots.</p>
<p>In fundamental news, Brazil exporters may begin to ship sugar earmarked for the 1997/98 crop plan, without a 40 percent export tax.</p>
<p>((Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities Desk 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
