<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="585515" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: CYCLING-INJURED RUSSIAN AND ITALIAN AMONG GIRO CONTENDERS.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-INJURED RUSSIAN AND ITALIAN AMONG GIRO CONTENDERS.</headline>
<byline>Mike Price</byline>
<dateline>VENICE 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Russian with a broken hand and an Italian with a rebuilt leg are among the contenders for the 80th Giro d'Italia starting on Saturday.</p>
<p>Pavel Tonkov defied injury to triumph in the six-day Tour of Romandie last Sunday, strengthening his resolve to repeat last year's Giro victory.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel ready for the Giro. Winning in Romandie has proved that my form is coming at the right time,&quot; he said in the countdown to Saturday's 128 kms circuit race on the roads of the Venetian Lido, the first of 22 stages and 3,892 kilometres.</p>
<p>Tonkov rode the Swiss race without any support on his injured right hand, and said: &quot;It did not give me any great trouble, but there is still some pain.&quot;</p>
<p>He believes as many as 15 riders are capable of winning the Giro, and Luc Leblanc could be top of his list, especially after Tonkov lost to the Frenchman by seven seconds in the Giro del Trentino.</p>
<p>The candidacy of Marco Pantani for the race leader's pink jersey is based on optimism, and memories of his last Giro three years ago when his fire on the mountain passes scorched a few hopes including the hat-trick dream of Miguel Indurain.</p>
<p>Pantani finished second overall to Russia's Yevgeny Berzin. Then after two stage wins in the 1995 Tour de France, Pantani's career was under threat after a head-on collision with a car during a race.</p>
<p>Sixteen months and three operations later he returned to competition in February, but reckoned he tried too hard in those early days.</p>
<p>&quot;I had to find out what I was capable of. I had to push myself to the limit while others treated those opening races as training. Now as they reap the benefits of an easy start I am feeling tired.</p>
<p>&quot;Still I cannot turn down the challenge,&quot; said Pantani who had four large pins inserted to help restore his shattered left shin.</p>
<p>Leblanc the first Frenchman to win the four-day Trentino tour has ambitions to bring France their first Giro success since Laurent Fignon in 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;I am in great form. I am getting stronger, and thinking more and more about the Giro,&quot; said the 1994 world champion whose best showing in a major tour was fourth the same year in the Tour de France.</p>
<p>Over the last 26 years France has won four Giro but the hosts have managed only eight victories. Their last came from Franco Chioccioli six years ago, and Italy look to their rising hopes such as Pantani, Enrico Zaini, second overall to Tonkov, and Ivan Gotti, next best Italian in fifth spot last year.</p>
<p>Yevgeny Berzin wrote himself into Giro history in 1994 as the first Russian winner at a time when the honours list was taking a more international appearance with Irish, American, and Spanish successes.</p>
<p>Berzin has the time trialing talent to make an early impression as he showed with his 52 kph ride, a Giro record, to beat Indurain three years ago.</p>
<p>His first opportunity will be the 18 kms time test to San Marino on Monday.</p>
<p>Whether it will be a lasting impression depends on his form in the Dolomites where last June former world champion Abraham Olano parted Tonkov from the pink jersey by 46 hundredths of a second after finishing one place ahead of him at the Passo Pordoi finish.</p>
<p>Then next day Tonkov recaptured the colours as Olano lost nearly two and a half minutes in less than 12 uphill kilometres.</p>
<p>The Dolomites are sure to decide again. This year after the second and final time trial to Cavalese the riders face three brutal days in those spectacular and daunting mountains before the traditional finish at the Parco Sempione in Milan on June 8.</p>
<p>Five climbs including the 2,214-metre Passo di Sella and the highest of the race, the 2,239-metre Passo Pordoi, dot the 222 kilometres to Falzes on the 19th day.</p>
<p>The next stage finishes on the 1,883-metre Passo del Tonale, and the survivors exit the mountains a day later via the 1,943-metre Goletto di Cadino and the smaller but deceptively testing Mortirolo.</p>
<p>Tough enough for the mountain specialists and misery aplenty for the train of toiling men in their wake especially after a Giro that will race the length of Italy before returning to the north for the last 11 days.</p>
<p>It includes an official rest day on May 27, that will be spent by many driving 900 kilometres from Taranto in the heel of Italy to the Tuscan resort of Camaiore on the north west coast.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VENICE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
