<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="585565" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLISH PARTY WORKS ON BILL PROBING RICH.</title>
<headline>POLISH PARTY WORKS ON BILL PROBING RICH.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Polish party belonging to powerful opposition Solidarity Election Action (AWS) said on Thursday it was readying a bill obliging people with more than $500,000 to show the origins of their wealth, PAP news said.</p>
<p>The party, the Confederation for an Independent Poland -- Patriotic Camp (KPN-OP), will start collecting citizens' signatures this month under the planned draft law, which it called the bill on economic vetting, PAP reported.</p>
<p>&quot;Our proposal aims at unveiling illegally gathered wealth,&quot; PAP quoted the party spokesman, Adam Sokolowski, as saying.</p>
<p>Sokolowski was quoted as saying that under the bill Poles who own assets worth more than $500,000 would have to produce declarations of wealth and its sources. The bill would apply to wealth accumulated after 1987.</p>
<p>A person who would honestly disclose illegal source of his wealth would be embraced by an abolition or would be obliged to invest part of his or her assets in a government-supported project.</p>
<p>Punished would be those concealing illegal roots of their wealth.</p>
<p>The KPN-OP is one of dozens of small rightist parties which have formed the Solidarity alliance around the Solidarity trade union in hopes of winning parliamentary polls due around September.</p>
<p>The party's controversial proposal looks set to be the platform of its campaign to polls, in which the Solidarity hopes to defeat the ruling ex-communists and a peasant party, in power since 1993.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, the party's leader Adam Slomka said a newly-rich class which had emerged when many state assets were privatised since the 1989 fall of communism, presented a bigger menace than people who had secretly collaborated with the old communist security police.</p>
<p>Right-leaning parties have long argued that much of Poland's wealth has been snapped up by people who used links with the network of old communist officials to acquire former state firms cheap at the expense of other Poles.</p>
<p>The AWS officials were not immediately available for comment on whether they supported the KPN-OP proposal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
