<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="585844" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin hails NATO pact despite minister's doubts.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin hails NATO pact despite minister's doubts.</headline>
<byline>Adam Tanner</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin said on Thursday a new pact charting relations between Russia and NATO would help boost world stability, but his defence minister said it left some problems unresolved.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, in a telephone call with German Chancellor Helmut Kohl, described the accord as &quot;a really major step aimed at more stability in Europe and the world overall&quot;, the Kremlin said in a statement.</p>
<p>NATO and Russia, former Cold War foes, said on Wednesday they had reached agreement to create a new partnership. It came as NATO prepares, in the teeth of Russian opposition, to admit new members from the former Soviet bloc.</p>
<p>But Russian Defence Minister Igor Rodionov, in Hawaii on the last leg of a visit to the United States, said the agreement did not address all outstanding issues between NATO and Russia.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the agreement reached in Moscow...Russia-NATO problems have not disappeared,&quot; Interfax news agency quoted Rodionov as telling reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as NATO remains a military and political alliance, this will raise a certain lack of understanding and acceptance in Russia,&quot; he added. &quot;It will take a lot of work to establish a trusting partnership between Moscow and Brussels.&quot;</p>
<p>The agreement includes creation of a new NATO-Russia permanent joint council, which will meet twice a year at both foreign and defence minister level.</p>
<p>But some details remain vague, and comments by Yeltsin and U.S. President Bill Clinton on Wednesday gave differing accounts of what the two sides had agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;Decisions can be taken only by consensus. If Russia is against some decision, it means this decision will not go through,&quot; Yeltsin said in a television interview broadcast on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>But Clinton, who has said NATO will not treat new members as &quot;second-class citizens&quot;, was adamant Russia would have no veto over alliance decisions.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia will work closely with NATO but not in NATO, giving Russia a voice but not a veto over NATO's business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov acknowledged at a news conference with U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan on Thursday that Russia did not expect veto power over NATO decisions.</p>
<p>&quot;Not being a member of NATO, of course Russia cannot hope to to have a veto regarding internal NATO questions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time if common questions arise on joint operations and activities, we hope in this instance decisions would be reached on a consensus basis,&quot; he said, referring to actions such as Russian-NATO peacekeeping operations.</p>
<p>Primakov also repeated Russia's opposition to NATO's expansion into former communist-ruled countries of eastern Europe. &quot;As before, we are against NATO expansion and consider it a big mistake,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The liberal newspaper Sevodnya suggested Russia's grumbling about NATO had been aimed at domestic critics of the deal.</p>
<p>The foreign minister &quot;understands perfectly well that the current NATO cannot pose any threat to Russia today under its current leadership&quot;, the daily said. &quot;Thus, all this theatening anti-NATO rhetoric is for Russian internal consumption.&quot;</p>
<p>Other commentators on Thursday said the Russia-NATO pact -- which still must be approved by NATO's 16 member governments before leaders meet for a planned May 27 signing ceremony in Paris -- was a significant document.</p>
<p>&quot;The two sides succeeded not only in avoiding a dead end in the talks, which was a real danger throughout the consultations, but they also achieved compromise on all aspects of the future agreement,&quot; the liberal daily Nezavisimaya Gazeta wrote.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
