<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="585846" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech PX50 slides after crown turmoil.</title>
<headline>Czech PX50 slides after crown turmoil.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>1400 GMT - The Czech PX50 closes down on Thursday as a hectic day in the foreign exchange markets rocks confidence.</p>
<p>* PX50 falls 3.6 points, 0.69 percent, to 514.6.</p>
<p>*  .RPIX falls 9.3 points, or 0.87 percent, to 1,064.5.</p>
<p>* Komercni Banka down 55 crowns to 1,995.</p>
<p>* SPT Telecom down 15 crowns to 3,235.</p>
<p>* Overall, 172 shares rise, 176 fall, 102 unchanged. Turnover, 1.4 billion crowns. Volume, 1,094,518 shares.</p>
<p>Czech shares fell back on Thursday with dealers saying volatility on the foreign exchange market, where the central bank intervened to prop up the crown, had created great uncertainty in the equity market as well.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody's waiting for what's going to happen next. If foreign investors evaluate the intervention news as bad, they'll go ahead with offers of large blocks and the market will go down pretty much,&quot; said Tomas Michalek of Raiffeisen Capital and Investment.</p>
<p>The PX50 closed down 0.7 percent to 514.6.</p>
<p>Trading on the bourse had stopped before the central bank announced it would raise the repo rate on Friday. It did not say by how much the rate would be raised and gave no indication of any change to other interest rates.</p>
<p>Komercni Banka was the biggest loser among the highly capitalised shares, falling 55 crowns to 1,995. SPT Telecom fell 15 crowns to 3,235 and power utility CEZ dropped two crowns to 955.</p>
<p>Overall, activity was higher with turnover of almost 1.4 billion crowns.</p>
<p>-- Robin Shepherd, Prague Newsroom, 420-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
