<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="585800" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Mobutu was to quit day after Zaire accord - radio.</title>
<headline>Mobutu was to quit day after Zaire accord - radio.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Mobutu Sese Seko might have resigned in favour of an all-party transitional authority on Thursday if Zairean peace talks scheduled for Wednesday had gone ahead, South African state radio said.</p>
<p>The radio said it had obtained a copy of President Nelson Mandela's two-page proposal for an agreement which said Mobutu would step down within 24 hours of signing it.</p>
<p>The meeting at which Mandela was to offer his proposal to Mobutu and rebel leader Laurent Kabila were cancelled after Kabila, citing security concerns, refused to join the other two aboard a South African ship in Congo.</p>
<p>State radio said the document proposed a 10-point agreement calling for Zaire to be run by a transitional authority comprising representatives of all parties in proportions agreed to by Mobutu and Kabila until elections are held.</p>
<p>The proposal said immediate measures would be taken to end the seven-month-old civil war before work was to start to set up the transitional authority, according to state radio.</p>
<p>&quot;Another point states that Mobutu will vacate his post within 24 hours of signing the document.</p>
<p>&quot;He will play no future role in government structures, but his safety and that of his family will be guaranteed. He will also be given the courtesy and dignity usually afforded to a former head of state,&quot; the radio said.</p>
<p>Mandela's spokesman, Parks Mankahlana, told Reuters earlier that Mandela had drafted a two-page proposal for submission to the Wednesday meeting that never happened.</p>
<p>He said Kabila was expected in Cape Town on Thursday for further discussions with Mandela, who remained hopeful of a negotiated peace based on his proposal.</p>
<p>Government and diplomatic sources said the division of power within the transitional authority between followers of Mobutu and of Kabila was a current sticking point.</p>
<p>An initial proposal for a 60-40 split in Kabila's favour had been scrapped, partly as a result of French government objections, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;If he (Kabila) had gone to the ship, a process of transition would have started this morning. This process (the Mandela document) would be a lot shorter than the military option,&quot; a government source said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
