<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="585805" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ETHIOPIA: Ethiopia sells record 119,804 tonnes of coffee.</title>
<headline>Ethiopia sells record 119,804 tonnes of coffee.</headline>
<byline>Tsegaye Tadesse</byline>
<dateline>ADDIS ABABA 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ethiopia sold a record 119,804 tonnes of coffee in the first 10 months of 1996/97, worth $352.5 million, coffee authorities said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Some 91,182 tonnes of coffee worth $255 million have already been exported while the balance represented export contracts already signed, said Kassahun Kurutu, acting planning head at the state Ethiopian Coffee and Tea Development Authority.</p>
<p>That balance, 28,622 tonnes, will be shipped in the next two months, Kassahun told Reuters in an interview. He did not say whether there would be any additional exports before end-June.</p>
<p>Ethiopia's coffee year is October/September but computation of sales is normally based on the fiscal year (July/June).</p>
<p>The exports are far in excess of the 108,000 tonnes forecast for 1996/97.</p>
<p>Local coffee prices have risen to 600 birr ($90.62) per feresula (17 kg or 37.485 pounds) from around 250 birr earlier in the year.</p>
<p>Kassahun said good rains, better technology and encouraging government policy created incentives and helped all those involved in the coffee industry to produce even more.</p>
<p>Ethiopia is Africa's third largest producer of coffee after Uganda and Ivory Coast, with annual estimated production now ranging between 250,000 and 300,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Coffee is Ethiopia's main export commodity and accounts for about 60 percent of the country's currency earnings.</p>
<p>Ethiopia exported 102,000 tonnes of coffee in 1995/96 and earned $279.5 million, which compared to earnings of $300.9 million from 78,420 tonnes in 1994/95.</p>
<p>Its earnings this year have been mainly boosted by a shortage of quality coffees in the world market.</p>
<p>Kassahun said Ethiopia's private coffee exporters, benefiting from the liberalisation policies of the government of Prime Minister Meles Zenawi, accounted for 65,162 tonnes of coffee already shipped, worth $182 million.</p>
<p>The state-owned Ethiopian Coffee Export Enterprise accounted for 26,020 tonnes of the coffee for around $73 million.</p>
<p>Ethiopia is also a major consumer of its own coffee.</p>
<p>($1=6.621 birr)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ETHPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADDIS ABABA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ETHIOPIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
