<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="585926" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria lev ends weaker on expected main rate cut.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria lev ends weaker on expected main rate cut.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bulgarian lev fell to around 1,534-1,536 per dollar at close from the morning's 1,520-1,522, in anticipation of a cut in the central bank main interest rate, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The lev fell as banks and clients stepped up bidding for foreign currency in the afternoon, expecting the central bank to pare the main interest rate today,&quot; a bank dealer said.</p>
<p>The main rate has been set at 5.2 percent monthly since Monday.</p>
<p>Central bank officials were unavailable for comment.  </p>
<p>Traders said the central bank was likely to cut the main rate in line with the falling yield of short-term government securities auctioned this week.</p>
<p>The central bank adjusts the rate weekly to the average weighted effective monthly yields on one-week and four-week discount T-bills, sold by the Finance Ministry during the week.</p>
<p>Yields to maturity on one- and four-week T-bills have persistently declined from 0.82 and 4.68 respectively on Friday to 0.58 and 3.84 percent today, central bank figures showed.  </p>
<p>-- Anastas Petrov, Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 91188</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
