<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586080" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru guerrillas say they regret crisis deaths.</title>
<headline>Peru guerrillas say they regret crisis deaths.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Imprisoned Marxist guerrillas blamed the Peruvian government on Thursday for the deaths of two commandos and a judge when troops assaulted the Japanese ambassador's home to free hostages held by leftist rebels.</p>
<p>&quot;We express our condolences to the families of the military men, and that of the judge, who were victims of the military intervention,&quot; said a letter smuggled out of Lima's high-security Canto Grande prison.</p>
<p>The letter was posted on the Internet by the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement's international office in Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;We consider the abrupt assault on the residence as a criminal act, we put the blame on President Fujimori, his questionable armed forces command and the Japanese government,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>The MRTA held 72 hostages for four months inside the diplomatic residence, demanding the release of 450 imprisoned comrades. Peruvian troops stormed the house on April 22, killing the 14 hostage-takers and saving all but one captive.</p>
<p>Peru plans to try for treason the international spokesman of the MRTA, Isaac Velazco, who is based in Germany, the state news agency Andina reported on Wednesday. It said he would be tried in his absence for publicising the group's actions.</p>
<p>The agency said Peru asked Germany to revoke Velazco's status as a political exile.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
