<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586023" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - May 15.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - May 15.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the reports carried by Estonia's newspapers on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL PAPERS</p>
<p>- According to an immigration officials' estimation, 20,000 illegal immigrants in Estonia have received pensions and subsidies regularly while the former red passport was accepted for identification; the passport is invalid from May 15.</p>
<p>- President Lennart Meri was given the Hungarian Cross of Merit by the President of Hungary as an acknowledgement for developing relations between the countries; Meri will leave Budapest today and begin a visit to Slovenia.</p>
<p>- Representatives of the Estonian and Russian foreign ministries will meet in Helsinki at the beginning of June, Finnish prime minister Paavo Lipponen said.</p>
<p>- The visa-free regime between Estonia and Finland that came into force on May 1 has not caused a travel rush between Tallinn and Helsinki, shipping companies say.</p>
<p>POSTIMEES</p>
<p>- Police have arrested a man suspected of killing several older women in south Estonia last year.</p>
<p>SONUMILEHT</p>
<p>- The Russian Foreign Ministry criticized the recent remarks of President Lennart Meri in Hungary who said that the signing of the Estonian-Russian border agreement was delayed because of Russia.</p>
<p>- EESTI PAEVALEHT</p>
<p>- Municipal Water and Sewage Department in Tallinn sold shares in the Bank of Tallinn that belonged to the city without the council's permission, the fiscal commission of the city reported.</p>
<p>- Tallinn city council opposition will today express no- confidence in the Centre Party deputy mayor Kalev Kallo; the motion is not expected tp pass.</p>
<p>ARIPAEV</p>
<p>- The government plans to set up a coordination commission for increasing the spread of information on Euro-integration to the public, the prime minister said.</p>
<p>-- Riga newsroom, +371 721 52 40</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
