<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="58616" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORECAST -- API distillate build seen heating up.</title>
<headline>FORECAST -- API distillate build seen heating up.</headline>
<byline>Oliver Ludwig</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>This week's data from the American Petroleum Institute (API) should show that the long-awaited seasonal rise in distillate stocks is finally starting to heat up, according to oil industry sources.</p>
<p>Even so, some forecasts for rising heating oil and diesel stocks were tempered by concerns exports to Europe from the U.S. Gulf and East Coasts might cut down any big builds.</p>
<p>&quot;That's going to be the wildcard,&quot; Victor Yu, vice president of futures trading at Refco said, referring to the question of how distillate exports might affect a stock build.  </p>
<p>Distillate stocks were seen rising anywhere from 500,000 to 2.5 million barrels over week-ago levels of 108.9 million barrels, with the average calculated at 1.96 million barrels. Distillate stocks are now 17 million below year-ago levels.</p>
<p>Views on crude supplies were more divided, hinging on questions of import volumes and the extent to which late-summer-to-autumn refinery maintenance is underway.</p>
<p>But most subscribed to the notion crude imports would enjoy a resurgence after being tempered by Hurricanes Edouard, Fran and Hortense, which have rendered Atlantic Ocean and Carribean Sea waters nearly unnavigable since late last month.  </p>
<p>Crude stocks were seen rising an insignificant 100,000 barrels from the 313.1 million barrels shown in API's previous report, though some said crude stocks could fall by as much as three million barrels.</p>
<p>Analysts predicting such a draw said the post-hurricane import resurgence would not show up in this week's report, and also added that refiners likely ran more crude through their plants last week in preparation for autumn maintenance aimed at increasing distillate yields ahead of winter.</p>
<p>This sort of thinking also played into predictions for a rise in refinery utilization rates, traders said.  </p>
<p>But traders cited the return to service of certain downed refinery units in California as the main reason runs were forecast to rise by just under 0.5 a percentage from the 94.4 percent posted in API's previous report.</p>
<p>Traders were meanwhile predicting gasoline supplies would fall by an insignificant 400,000 barrels a day amid poor demand related to lukewarm activity in spot markets. Spot unleaded markets have been quiet recently due to the Iraq-related volatility on the NYMEX, traders said.</p>
<p>But some said the poor demand could fuel a 3.5 million barrel rise in gasoline stocks from 192.8 million last week.</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
