<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586134" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru hands back captured Ecuadorean soldiers.</title>
<headline>Peru hands back captured Ecuadorean soldiers.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peru's armed forces handed back to Ecuador on Thursday seven Ecuadorean soldiers captured after crossing a disputed border zone with high-tech arms and dozens of anti-personnel mines.</p>
<p>&quot;At 8:15 a.m. (1315 GMT) the Ecuadorean soldiers were handed over to Ecuador,&quot; Capt. Juan Sanchez, of the Bagua military post in the border region, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The incident has inflamed tensions between the two Andean neighbours, who fought a bloody, month-long war at the border in 1995 and are negotiating in Brazil over a permanent solution to the decades-old dispute.</p>
<p>Peru claims the Ecuadorean soldiers violated its territory and were seeking to lay mines, but Quito sought to minimise the incident as an &quot;accidental&quot; incursion.</p>
<p>Gen. Paco Moncayo, head of Ecuador's joint chiefs of staff, admitted his soldiers may have strayed into Peruvian territory but denied they were laying mines.</p>
<p>The soldiers were handed over &quot;in perfect health&quot; to the head of the Ecuadorean military's representative on an international observer mission, Col. Jorge Brito, local Peruvian radio reported.</p>
<p>Peruvian troops said they caught one Ecuadorean sergeant, two corporals and four soldiers on Tuesday with a haul that included 60 anti-personnel mines, German-made guns, infra-red binoculars, five rocket and grenade launchers, maps of the territory and cameras.</p>
<p>Peru's acting Foreign Minister Jorge Gonzalez Izquierdo said he regretted the Ecuadorean incursion, but was confident the peace dialogue would stay on track.</p>
<p>Dozens of soldiers were killed and hundreds injured from both sides in the 1995 conflict, the latest in a series of armed flare-ups in recent decades.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
