<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586189" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian Broadcasting Corp Midday Update.</title>
<headline>Australian Broadcasting Corp Midday Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>SAVINGS REBATE DEBATE CONTINUES</p>
<p>The Prime Minister has defended the scope of the Government's tax rebate on savings, and says making it means tested would reduce the rebate's effectiveness.</p>
<p>The Opposition disagrees, and will proceed with changed to block people on high incomed from claiming it.</p>
<p>Shadow Treasurer, Gareth Evans, says paying the rebate regardless of people's means breaks an election promise.</p>
<p>Mr Howard has told Channel Seven's 11 AM means testing it would be stupid.</p>
<p>He said he's comfortable about his decision not to claim the rebate, and while he yesterday called on the Opposition to follow suit, he now says it's a matter of personal choice.</p>
<p>But the Opposition leader, Kim Beazley, will match Mr Howard's move.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BHP MANAGEMENT DOESN'T FORESHADOW ANY ACTION OVER STRIKE</p>
<p>BHP management says while it understands the emotion that surrounds the closure of the Newcastle steelworks, today's national strike by is counterproductive to both sides.</p>
<p>BHP's Steel spokesman John Devers, says the company will work with employees to develop new opportunities at Newcastle where the company is closing it's steel making operations.</p>
<p>He doesn't expect BHP to take any action over the strike.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>WOOLDRIDGE SAYS AMA CRITICISMS ALARMIST</p>
<p>Federal Health Minister, Michael Wooldridge, has dismissed the AMA's criticisms of budget cuts to pharmaceutical benefits as &quot;alarmist nonsense&quot;.</p>
<p>As of February next year, the Government will reduce the range of drugs it subsidises in the areas of hypertension, depression, ulcers and high cholesterol.</p>
<p>The AMA has warned the cut of 561-million dollars over four years could result in some patients being forced to use drugs which have undesirable side effects.</p>
<p>But Dr Wooldridge says the government has set up a panel of experts to ensure patients won't suffer under the changes.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>NATIONAL PARTY CALLS FOR TRIAL TO BE STOPPED</p>
<p>In New South Wales, the National Party has called on the Government to stop the a trial program in Sydney primary and secondary schools to combat the vilification of gay students.</p>
<p>The Gay and Lesbian Teachers and Students Association says eight Sydney inner-west schools have been chosen to pilot the program.</p>
<p>Students will use books that normalise gay lifestyles and take part in role playing between gay and straight students.</p>
<p>However National Party leader, Ian Armstrong, says public funds are being used to promote homosexuality and he's accused the government of losing touch with family values.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CAUSLEY SAYS LEADERSHIP ISSUE NOT OVER</p>
<p>National Party MP Ian Causley says the issue of Tim Fischer's leadership wasn't raised at a meeting of backbenchers on Monday, because the Wik issue is more imprtant at this stage. The meeting made no move against Mr Fischer, despite his invitation for them to do so.</p>
<p>But Mr Causley says it wasn't the right moment, and the matter will go to another meeting.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>EVANS DEFENDS IMMIGRATION POLICY</p>
<p>Former Foreign Affairs Minister Gareth Evans says Australia has a sensible refugee policy.</p>
<p>His comments come in the wake of a critical report from a United Nations committee, which has found Australia guilty of human rights breaches, in a case related to 26 Cambodians held in detention for four years.</p>
<p>The Federal Government says laws relating to detention of asylum seekers have since been changed.</p>
<p>And Mr Evans says people need to understand all the policy issues involved in administering a sensible refugee regime.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
