<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586248" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: FOCUS-Asian stocks end down, led by shaky Thailand.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Asian stocks end down, led by shaky Thailand.</headline>
<byline>Christina Toh-Pantin</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's slowing economy and battered baht set off shockwaves throughout Asia on Thursday, with southeast Asian markets bearing the brunt of heavy foreign selling, fund managers said.</p>
<p>Worries about the stability of the Thai currency and the liquidity of the banking system sent Thai stocks deeper into retreat.</p>
<p>By the close, Bangkok's SET index was down 13.43 points, or 2.35 percent, at 557.87 after a late rally lifted the market off its lows.</p>
<p>The Thai currency bounced back following assurances by Prime Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh that he had no plans to devalue the baht and that he would keep his Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan.</p>
<p>The baht was quoted at around 25.2700/25.3700 to the dollar at 1000 GMT compared with 26.330/26.430 late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Even though other Asian economies are more robust than Thailand's -- which is grappling with its worst growth rate in 10 years -- neighbouring markets were not spared.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a major pan-Asian (sell) program going on,&quot; said the head of equity research at a foreign broker in Malaysia. &quot;You've got everyone saying they don't want to be in Asia.&quot;</p>
<p>He said there was talk the sell program totalled $1.2 billion.</p>
<p>Financial markets linked to concerns about property values were among the worst hit. Financial authorities in Thailand, Malaysia, Singapore and the Philippines have all taken measures to quell speculation in their booming sectors.</p>
<p>Malaysia's Composite Index was down 2.91 percent at the close. In Singapore, the Straits Times Industrials Index sank 1.36 percent and Philippine shares ended off 2.77 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;This is institutional money,&quot; said Liew Yin Sze, chief economist at J.M. Sassoon in Singapore. &quot;The phenomenal asset inflation we've had in the last five to 10 years appears to be unsustainable in the eyes of investors.&quot;</p>
<p>Most Asian equity markets ended down although the damage varied. Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index eased 0.79 percent and Tokyo's Nikkei-225 dropped 0.76 percent.</p>
<p>Indonesian shares lost 1.98 percent, partly on jitters ahead of general elections at the end of the month, while Taiwan shares ended off 2.27 percent after hectic profit-taking in electronic stocks.</p>
<p>Bucking the trend, South Korean shares jumped 2.35 percent at the close on hopes that corporate earnings would be helped by the strong yen.</p>
<p>&quot;Our stance on southeast Asia is that we think more consolidation needs to occur,&quot; said Kim Teo, managing director at Credit Lyonnais International Asset Management in Singapore.</p>
<p>The firm, which manages about $800 million in Asian stocks, has about half its portfolio in north Asia, 10 to 15 percent in cash and the balance in southeast Asia, Teo said.</p>
<p>He said the decline in the region had not prompted his firm to change its stance, although his fund had been looking to increase its Singapore weighting a bit.</p>
<p>The jury remained out on whether Thursday's selling marked a pullout from the region, although Liew at J.M. Sassoon said there appeared to have been a sea change in views.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the weakness in the baht jolted a lot of institutional investors. They are saying if it can happen to Thailand, which country will be next?&quot; Liew said.</p>
<p>Hugh Young, managing director at Abtrust Fund Managers in Singapore, which has about $850 million in Asia excluding Hong Kong, thought differently.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, people are worried but I don't think there's a major shift going on at the moment. We are staying put. I think there are always people looking for reasons to shift.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
