<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586367" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Koreans call for arrest of President's son.</title>
<headline>S.Koreans call for arrest of President's son.</headline>
<byline>Jane Lee</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>As state prosecutors prepared to arrest President Kim Young-sam's son for corruption on Thursday, most South Koreans showed little sympathy for the junior Kim and called for severe punishment.</p>
<p>They said President Kim, who jailed two of his predecessors as part of his anti-graft campaign, failed to cleanse his own administration and those around him.</p>
<p>&quot;Kim Hyun-chul must pay for his sins, and must be judged by the law,&quot; said Kyung Yoon-duk, 43, who works at a food processing company.</p>
<p>Prosecutors say they have evidence that Kim Hyun-chul received billions of won (millions of dollars) from companies, some as kickbacks in return for influence-peddling.</p>
<p>&quot;It's unfortunate that all our presidents are connected to corruption. I hope we elect a clean leader this year,&quot; said saleswoman Kim Chum-soo, referring to presidential elections to be held in December.</p>
<p>&quot;After his term, it will be hard to avoid the criticism his predecessors received,&quot; Park Jung-ran, who runs a coffee shop, said of President Kim.</p>
<p>Many other Koreans said they felt betrayed by yet another sleaze scandal following the imprisonment of former presidents Chun Doo Hwan and Roh Tae-woo for raising hundreds of millions of dollars in slush funds while in office.</p>
<p>&quot;This is too much. Even President Kim Young-sam's son is no different from Chun and Roh,&quot; said saleswoman Kim who added that most of her clients wanted to see the president's son behind bars.</p>
<p>&quot;I have talked about Kim Hyun-chul when I met my customers, and most say he deserves to be arrested,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>President Kim came to office on an anti-graft ticket and his second son, who helped engineer his victory in the 1992 election campaign, now symbolised the failure of his administration's hopes of ending corruption.</p>
<p>Already, eleven people, including close aides to President Kim, ruling and opposition party lawmakers, a former cabinet minister, bankers and businessmen are on trial over a loans-for-kickbacks scandal surrounding failed Hanbo Steel Co.</p>
<p>But few Koreans said they would like to see President Kim stepping down over his son's wrongdoing.</p>
<p>&quot;The country is going through hard times. I wouldn't want to see more chaos with the president resigning,&quot; said Lee Byung-ok, an 81-year-old pastor.</p>
<p>&quot;The Korean people and politicians should use this opportunity to look back on themselves and make a fresh start.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Kim Young-sam should use the rest of his term to straighten out the current mess,&quot; said coffeeshop owner Park.</p>
<p>Kwang Ee-do, 53, a chef at a Chinese restaurant, expressed scepticism that the expected arrest of Kim Hyun-chul would lead to a cleaner society.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
