<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="58638" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tyson Foods lobbyist is indicted in Espy probe.</title>
<headline>Tyson Foods lobbyist is indicted in Espy probe.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Washington lobbyist for the biggest U.S. poultry processor was indicted on Tuesday in the investigation of former Agriculture Secretary Mike Espy, a spokesman for the independent counsel heading the probe said.</p>
<p>A federal grand jury charged Tyson Foods lobbyist Jack Williams with making false statements to the Agriculture Department's Office of Inspector General and the FBI as part of the preliminary investigation of Espy, the spokesman, Charles Bakaly, said.</p>
<p>The alleged crime took place before Independent Counsel Donald Smaltz was named to head the special investigation, Bakaly said.</p>
<p>The indictment is the fifth set of indictments returned in the sprawling two-year probe of Espy, which has led to the bringing of criminal charges against more than a dozen individuals and concerns.</p>
<p>Williams' indictment marks the first time in the investigation that a Tyson official has been officially charged with criminal conduct and could prove embarrassing for the Clinton White House. President Bill Clinton, as a former governor of Arkansas, has long had close relations with the Arkansas-based company and its chairman, Don Tyson.</p>
<p>The indictment said Williams reported directly to Archie Shaffer, media, government and public affairs director of Tyson Foods, who reported to John Tyson, who reported to his father, the company chairman, Bakaly said.</p>
<p>Espy resigned as agriculture secretary in 1994 under a cloud of accusations that he had illegally accepted gifts and favours for companies his agency was responsible for regulating.</p>
<p>Tyson Foods was mentioned early in the Espy case as having given him tickets and transportation to sports events, and it was criticised for awarding a scholarship to his girlfriend.</p>
<p>The company, which denies it tried to use its clout with Espy and the White House to scuttle a plan by the Agriculture Department to tighten safety regulations for the poultry industry, has promised to fight any indictments until the &quot;bitter end.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
