<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586458" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Swiss Bank Corp. to buy Dillon Read for $600 million.</title>
<headline>Swiss Bank Corp. to buy Dillon Read for $600 million.</headline>
<byline>Cal Mankowski</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss Bank Corp. said Thursday it agreed to buy Wall Street investment bank Dillon Read &amp; Co. for about $600 million, the latest merger in the rapidly consolidating global securities business.</p>
<p>The announcement came a day after Holland's ING Group, which owns 25 percent of Dillon Read, broke off talks to buy the other 75 percent from the firm's partners.</p>
<p>While the price Swiss Bank agreed to pay was rich, it signalled how much a European company would pay to get a foothold in the securities business in the United States, a must-have for global players in high finance, analysts said.</p>
<p>The giant Swiss bank said it planned to merge Dillon Read with SBC Warburg, the investment bank it acquired in 1995. There was little overlap between the two investment banks, which once merged would be known as SBC Warburg Dillon Read.</p>
<p>The acquisition will not push SBC to the top of the heap in U.S. investment banking. But Dillon Read has a solid reputation and strong relationships with a roster of blue-chip corporate clients, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The key relationships will make or break the deal,&quot; Salomon Brothers banking analyst John Leonard said.</p>
<p>Dillon Read Chairman John Birkelund said ING had failed to articulate a clear vision of what a combined company would look like, prompting the decision to sell to Swiss Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no clear definition from our friends at ING about an ongoing operation,&quot; Birkelund said in a telephone interview. &quot;This lack of clarity, which continued for months and months, made it impossible for us to believe this was going to be a promising combination for our people.&quot;</p>
<p>Birkelund said Thomas Wyman, one-time chairman of CBS Inc. and a senior adviser at SBC Warburg in New York, set up a meeting with Swiss Bank Chief Executive Marcel Ospel, and that at a luncheon in late March, they outlined how a merged SBC Warburg and Dillon Read would function.</p>
<p>&quot;They presented us with an opportunity so different and compelling that we pursued it,&quot; he said, noting there were inquiries from other potential buyers he would not identify.</p>
<p>He said there was &quot;no personal animosity whatsoever&quot; between Dillon Read and the people at ING Barings, the Dutch company's investment bank.</p>
<p>Swiss Bank said it would finance the deal with stock and that it would not dilute earnings.</p>
<p>SBC is paying about three times book value for Dillon Read, outstripping the multiple paid in deals such as Bankers Trust New York Corp.'s $1.7 billion acquisition of Alex. Brown Inc., which was announced on April 7.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Group Inc. and Dean Witter Discover &amp; Co. announced a $10.7 billion merger in February.</p>
<p>The rash of deals prompted a a Merrill Lynch director to say last month that six global &quot;superbanks&quot; were likely to emerge from the consolidation of banks, insurance and securities firms.</p>
<p>Of other European companies, only Credit Suisse Group has a significant U.S. presence thought its Credit Suisse First Boston investment banking unit.</p>
<p>SBC Warburg, established when SBC took over British merchant bank SG Warburg, is based in London and employs 9,000 people in 40 countries, 2,000 of them in the United States.</p>
<p>Dillon Read, founded in 1832, employs 730 people and has offices in New York, Boston, San Francisco, Dallas, London, Paris and Tokyo. Last year, it advised on 50 mergers and acquisitions worth $45 billion, and it is active in high-yield debt and stock underwriting.</p>
<p>Birkelund noted there was little overlap since SBC Warburg's U.S. operations focus on complex investments known as derivatives.</p>
<p>The merger is subject to winning approval from regulators.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
