<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586428" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Morocco's bourse pursues downward trend.</title>
<headline>Morocco's bourse pursues downward trend.</headline>
<dateline>CASABLANCA 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Casablanca stock exchange closed on Thursday 0.34 percent lower with drops in blue chips, mainly ONA group and Wafabank, and profit-taking on the part of small shareholders, traders said.</p>
<p>The all-share index closed at 668.43 points from 670.68 points on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Small shareholders are selling their stocks for fear of seeing a bigger decline in value,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>ONA Group, the country's largest private conglomerate, dropped 15 dirhams to close at 790 dirhams.</p>
<p>Wafabank fell 10 dirhams to 850 along with Credit du Maroc which shed 11 dirhams to 450.</p>
<p>Societe Nationale d'Investissement, the second largest private conglomerate, closed unchanged at 747 dirhams.</p>
<p>Credit firms went lower from Wednesday, including, Credor minus 13 dirhams to 800 dirhams and mortgage bank Credit Hotelier et Immobilier which fell seven dirhams to 280.</p>
<p>Samir, Morocco's main oil refinery, was among the few good performers, up 10.2 dirhams to 366.25 dirhams, Banque Nationale pour le Developpement Economique up five dirhams to 240 dirhams and Banque Commerciale du Maroc, up two dirhams to 864.</p>
<p>Total volume traded on the official market stood at 39.8 million from 43.9 million dirhams on Wednesday.</p>
<p>On the over-the-counter market, volume dropped to 88.7 million from 157.4 million dirhams on Wednesday.</p>
<p>($1= 9.3 dirhams)</p>
<p>- Rabat newsroom +212-7 72 65 18</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CASABLANCA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
