<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586462" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Expert identifies parts from Oklahoma bombing truck.</title>
<headline>Expert identifies parts from Oklahoma bombing truck.</headline>
<byline>Judith Crosson</byline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>An expert testifying on Thursday in the Oklahoma City bombing trial identified the vehicle used in the April 1995 attack as a Ryder truck allegedly rented by defendant Timothy McVeigh.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that there was only one vehicle used in the Oklahoma City bombing. That vehicle, built for and sold to Ryder, had a specific and unique vehicle identification number,&quot; said Edward Paddock, who worked for a consulting firm that specialises in analysing accidents.</p>
<p>Paddock read out the unique 17-digit identification number, 1FDN7F2J4PVA26077, which matched the number of the truck prosecutors said McVeigh rented from Elliott's Body Shop in Junction City, Kansas, two days before the bombing that killed 168 people.</p>
<p>Earlier, McVeigh politely replied to U.S. Judge Richard Matsch's questions when asked if he agreed to a series of stipulations between prosecutors and defence attorneys. Both sides had agreed to accept as authentic handwriting samples by McVeigh and co-defendant Terry Nichols, who is to be tried separately later.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes sir, I do,&quot; McVeigh told Matsch in a clear and confident voice, when asked if he agreed that the stipulations were acceptable to him. &quot;Yes, I have your honour,&quot; McVeigh said when Matsch asked him if he had consulted with his attorney before making his decision.</p>
<p>The jury was not in court when McVeigh, who is portrayed by prosecutors as an extreme right-wing firebrand who hates the U.S. government, politely answered the judge. McVeigh has rarely spoken in court proceedings.</p>
<p>Paddock said he based his conclusions on an analysis of the parts recovered from the crime scene, the Ryder purchase order and an invoice from Ford.</p>
<p>A key break for investigators came hours after the April 19, 1995, bombing of the Alfred P. Murrah federal building when they discovered the vehicle identification number on a rear axle found near the bomb site.</p>
<p>The number enabled investigators to identify the truck as coming from a Ryder rental depot in Junction City.</p>
<p>Paddock told of the painstaking process of identifying the pieces and putting them together on a scale sketch of the truck at the FBI laboratory in Washington. He said there was a gap between the rear axle and the cab where parts were not found.</p>
<p>To make the comparison easier to understand in court, Ford bought from Ryder the next truck off the assembly line from the one allegedly used in the bombing and cut it to pieces.</p>
<p>Paddock, a mechanical engineer who worked for 34 years for the Ford Motor Co., compared for the jury the twisted pieces recovered from the bomb site with the identical, but intact, pieces taken from the undamaged truck.</p>
<p>Paddock, who retired from Ford in 1996 to work for the consulting firm, picked up vehicle parts recovered from the bomb site, including pieces of the frame, brake system and axle attachments, and showed the jury where they fit on the intact truck frame. Jurors leaned forward or stood up to get a better look at the pieces strewn on the courtroom floor.</p>
<p>Last week the owner of the rental location identified McVeigh as the person who rented the truck.</p>
<p>McVeigh, who pleaded not guilty but faces the death penalty if convicted, also paid close attention when Paddock was explaining the truck parts to the jury.</p>
<p>After Paddock, U.S. Customs Service employee Priscilla Salyers told the court how she fell from the ninth floor of the Murrah building to a heap of debris near the ground level and became disheartened when a rescue worker left her side.</p>
<p>&quot;Then they told me they had to leave and I didn't want to let the man go. He started crying,&quot; she testified. Fears that a second bomb was about to go off had sent rescue workers scrambling for safety. The fears proved unfounded.</p>
<p>The prosecution's case has moved along more rapidly than expected and could wrap up next week. The defence would then present its case.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
