<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586546" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GM loses $24 million verdict over credit card.</title>
<headline>GM loses $24 million verdict over credit card.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A New York state jury Thursday ordered General Motors Corp. to pay $24.05 million plus interest to a New York company that claimed it helped the world's largest automaker develop its popular GM credit card programme.</p>
<p>The New York Supreme Court jury deliberated about four hours here Thursday before finding in favour of 23/23 Communications Corp., which does business as Communications Diversified, said John Callagy, an attorney for Communications Diversified.</p>
<p>That company said it developed the credit card -- which allows users to earn rebates on GM cars based on purchases made with the credit card -- with General Motors in the mid-1980s for use with GM's Chevrolet line.</p>
<p>GM chose not to use the concept, but in 1992 began a GM Mastercard programme.</p>
<p>A GM spokesman said the programme used today was developed internally by Electronic Data Systems, a unit which GM spun off last year.</p>
<p>The Communications Diversified programme would have required several hundred participants to pay for the rebate, while the current GM programme will have no other partners paying the rebate by the end of June, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>GM plans to appeal the verdict.</p>
<p>GM has said it has sold more than 1 million cars to cutomers using rebates from the programme.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
