<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586652" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pamela Anderson Lee describes movie sex scenes.</title>
<headline>Pamela Anderson Lee describes movie sex scenes.</headline>
<byline>Paul Iorio</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former &quot;Baywatch&quot; TV star Pamela Anderson Lee, sued for backing out of a movie deal, told a court on Thursday about the simulated sex scenes she had objected to in the film.</p>
<p>Reading from the script for &quot;Hello, She Lied,&quot; Lee quoted stage directions for four specific scenes, including &quot;he reaches under her dress; they make passionate love,&quot; and &quot;he kisses her breast.&quot;</p>
<p>Lee, called to the stand by her defence lawyer, contends she withdrew from the film project because of objectionable graphic sex scenes.</p>
<p>Cross-examined by plaintiffs' lawyer Robert Wolfe, Lee stated emphatically: &quot;You will never see me in another simulated sex scene for the rest of my life.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want to be touched by people I don't know,&quot; she said. &quot;If I had gone to Florida (to shoot the film) they would have made me do simulated sex -- I know that, I'm not stupid.&quot;</p>
<p>When Wolfe pressed her about on-screen lovemaking and simulated sex, Lee became exasperated. &quot;I don't even know what you're asking me ... Ask me a real question,&quot; she snapped.</p>
<p>Judge David Horowitz adjourned the session for a lunch break before Wolfe could continue.</p>
<p>Lee is being sued for $5 million by The Private Movie Co., which alleges she broke an agreement to star in &quot;Hello, She Lied&quot; because she was offered $500,000 to make the feature film &quot;Barb Wire,&quot; which was a box-office flop.</p>
<p>The Canadian-born actress, married to rock drummer Tommy Lee of the band Motley Crue, claimed she changed her mind about making &quot;Hello, She Lied&quot; after seeing the script.</p>
<p>In testimony last week, she told the court that although she was not opposed to nudity, she did object to graphic sex scenes in &quot;Hello, She Lied.&quot;</p>
<p>Even when a proposed naked shower scene was rewritten because of her complaints, she said, it was replaced with a scene in which her character was to have sex on a pool table.</p>
<p>&quot;Hello, She Lied&quot; was later made as &quot;Miami Hustler&quot; with model Kathy Ireland in the lead role for the Showtime cable TV channel. Ireland had a &quot;no-nudity&quot; clause in her contract.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
