<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586689" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME pork bellies end limit up, hogs tumble.</title>
<headline>CME pork bellies end limit up, hogs tumble.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Technical strength and the bullish impact of packer slaughter cutbacks pushed CME pork belly futures to close up as much as the limit of 3.000 cents per lb, while hog futures ended sharply lower, traders said.</p>
<p>Pork bellies closed 3.000 to 0.525 higher with July and August limit up. July settled at 92.025 cents. Hog futures ended 1.150 cent lower to 0.025 higher with only April up and June off most at 82.325 cents.</p>
<p>Technicals took over after pork pits were influenced by the announcement packers were cutting kills, traders said.</p>
<p>Traders started to sell hog futures and buy pork belly futures Wednesday when packers said they would be cutting their kill rates due to tight margins and an undersupply of slaughter hogs. The trend continued Thursday and pushed belly futures up through technical resistance and hog futures down through technical support, touching off stops in the respective directions, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's technical in nature -  probably the selloff we had over the last several sessions (in bellies) was overdone,&quot; said Doug Harper, senior livestock analyst for Brock Associates Inc.  </p>
<p>Harper noted the cutback in packer hog slaughter rates was bullish to bellies because there would be fewer fresh bellies to sell while there would be less demand for cash hogs. Technicals then took over, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The announcement that IBP is going to cut hours the next couple of weeks sent some shock waves through and that was reflected in the cash (hogs),&quot; Harper said.</p>
<p>Technicians noted that bellies rose to a one week high in July when it went through the 20-day average at about 90.500 and a trend line at 91.500. Hogs fell to a one month low and touched off sell stops through support at 82.700 cents.</p>
<p>Pork bellies may also be benefiting from talk that Japan continues to buy U.S. pork bellies for export.</p>
<p>&quot;Earlier this week, talking to a processor, he said the Japanese are starting to place a few more orders than they had been. More on frozen pork (bellies) than the chilled product,&quot; Harper added.</p>
<p>Cash rose $3 to $4 per cwt with 14-16 lb bellies at $83 in the noon USDA wire after dipping to $78 earlier this week.</p>
<p>Hog futures fell to a discount to cash on the setback as the latest index was higher. The latest CME lean hog index was up $1.33 to $82.50 per cwt.</p>
<p>Rand Financials and LFG notably bought pork bellies late after early buying from Cargill Investor Services, R.J. O'Brien, Lind-Waldock and Hammer Trading. R.J. O'Brien, LIT division of First Options, LFG and Rand Financials sold hogs, pit sources said.</p>
<p>In options trade, Lind-Waldock bought August 76 puts, Rand Financials sold June 81 puts and Rosenthal Collins bought June 82 puts on hogs. August bellies ended synthetically at 91.300 after futures closed at 90.825, pit sources added.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
