<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586717" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME to debut Internet order routing test in June.</title>
<headline>CME to debut Internet order routing test in June.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chicago Mercantile Exchange plans to debut testing of Internet-based futures order routing in late June, a CME official said Thursday.</p>
<p>In conjunction with several member firms, the CME will roll out the test of the Internet to route futures orders into CME trading pits, said Ellen Resnick, CME vice president of corporate communications.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea is to wire the world to our exchange and give us the broadest possible reach,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>LIT Investor Services, Rosenthal Collins Group and RB&amp;H Inc are the initial Internet trading participants.  </p>
<p>Les Rosenthal, managing partner of Rosenthal Collins, said his firm would invite some of its top-tier customers to first try out the plan.</p>
<p>&quot;We have great hopes for it,&quot; Rosenthal said. &quot;We hope that this could eventually automate our order entry system (and) make it less expensive for the customer and the brokerage firm itself,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rosenthal said the plan to launch Internet order entry has come a long way in the past 18 months, with the development of a so-called &quot;smart card&quot; to satisfy security concerns.  </p>
<p>The credit-card sized security card features a password and personal identification code.</p>
<p>The idea is to allow so-called introducing brokers quick access into the CME's futures markets from anywhere in the world.</p>
<p>When the launch begins, introducing brokers selected by the firms and equipped with smart cards will be able to gain access through a computer with an Internet browser. Connected to a clearing firm through the system, they can enter orders from laptop or desktop computers anywhere in the world.</p>
<p>If all goes well, the CME hopes to allow other member firms access to Internet order entry sometime in the third quarter, CME's Resnick said. The test initially will only be available for pit session trading.</p>
<p>--Chicago Derivatives Desk ((312 408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
