<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586737" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NATO-Russia deal fails to move critics.</title>
<headline>NATO-Russia deal fails to move critics.</headline>
<byline>Carol Giacomo</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>This week's hard-won NATO-Russia accord gives momentum to U.S. President Bill Clinton's push for alliance expansion, but domestic opponents remain unimpressed and say the deal may intensify differences.</p>
<p>&quot;I am opposed to expansion. It brings no benefits; it has potential serious costs and this doesn't change anything,&quot; said Michael Mandelbaum, a leading American critic of NATO expansion and a professor at John Hopkin's University's Nitze School of Advanced International Studies.</p>
<p>&quot;This (accord) simply adds another potential cost in misunderstanding and acrimony and recriminations with Russia,&quot; he said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>After months of negotiation, NATO and Russia on Wednesday announced the agreement, which set terms for alliance expansion into the former communist countries of eastern Europe and for NATO-Russia ties into the next century.</p>
<p>Clinton called the accord historic and said it brought Europe closer to being undivided, democratic and at peace.</p>
<p>The deal must be approved formally by Moscow and the 16 NATO states, which were due to sign the accord on May 27 in Paris, roughly six weeks before NATO meets in Madrid on July 8-9 to choose its first post-Cold War new members.</p>
<p>Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic wer the top contenders but Romania and Slovenia were under consideration.</p>
<p>Although NATO made the decision to expand, it was concerned that without a special negotiated relationship, an angry Moscow would feel isolated from the evolving European security structure. This has been alleviated.</p>
<p>Perhaps more profoundly, the agreement was expected to have an impact on what is already becoming an impassioned debate in the United States, where the Senate must approve any change in NATO's makeup. Other NATO member legislatures must vote as well.</p>
<p>Although administration officials insist this is not so, American conservatives who remain suspicious of Moscow's intentions have already begun questioning whether NATO surrendered too much influence over the alliance's policies to Russia in the accord.</p>
<p>The Russia-NATO text was just being made available so there was some uncertainty about specific details and whether there may have been last-minute changes of any significance.</p>
<p>But as described by officials, the accord appears to vindicate U.S. policymakers who believed they could reach an accommodation with Moscow on NATO enlargement.</p>
<p>Russia strongly has opposed expansion as a threat to its security but President Boris Yeltsin -- faced with U.S. and NATO insistence that expansion would go forward regardless of Moscow's reaction -- was eventually brought on board after pressing his weak hand for the best deal possible.</p>
<p>The accord thus undercuts critics who said expansion would foster a break with Moscow, because some Russians view the alliance in Cold War terms -- a military bulwark arrayed against the remnants of the former communist superpower.</p>
<p>The deal codifies earlier NATO commitments that it had no intention of stationing &quot;substantial&quot; foreign forces on the territories of new members. The alliance also promised that it had no current intention, no plans and no need to deploy nuclear weapons on the soil of new member states.</p>
<p>Further, the agreement established a permanent mechanism for NATO-Russia consultation and cooperation on security issues called the joint council. Russia will have no veto over decisions taken by NATO as an alliance but it could veto issues that come before the joint council, officials said.</p>
<p>The New York Times, an ardent opponent of expansion, argued in Thursday's editions that despite the agreement, &quot;Russia's role itself remains very much in doubt.&quot;</p>
<p>The paper faulted the accord for being a &quot;political agreement&quot; not a binding treaty and asserted the commitments on forces and nuclear weapons were &quot;shallow.&quot; The deal &quot;merely papers over vitally important agreements (and) by masking them, it may end up exacerbating the differences in the future,&quot; the newspaper said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
