<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586713" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Inflation data tame but rate debate continues.</title>
<headline>Inflation data tame but rate debate continues.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kelley</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Retail prices barely rose in April, the government said Thursday, the latest sign inflation was in check, but other reports kept investors wondering if the Federal Reserve will raise interest rates next week.</p>
<p>The Consumer Price Index rose 0.1 percent last month, matching an identical rise in March, the Labour Department said a day after it reported that prices at the wholesale level fell 0.6 percent last month, the biggest drop in nearly four years.</p>
<p>The report added to speculation about whether the Fed will raise rates when its policy-makers meet on Tuesday. The central bankers raised short-term rates in March in a bid to ward off inflation.</p>
<p>While Fed Chairman Alan Greenspan has indicated he is concerned about guarding against future inflation, the April data could make the central bankers' decision more difficult, economists said.</p>
<p>Still, several said the Fed may raise rates anyway.</p>
<p>&quot;Last month's inflation is no guide to what the Fed should be doing today, but it's a public relations problem to be tightening now,&quot; said Bill Cheney, chief economist at John Hancock Financial Services in Boston.</p>
<p>&quot;If I had to bet, I'd say they're going to do it anyway,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Current inflation is not what is worrying the Federal Reserve,&quot; said Joel Naroff, chief bank economist at First Union in Philadelphia. &quot;They are looking at future problems and the tightness in the labour markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Predicting that &quot;the odds still lie on the side of&quot; a rate increase next week, Naroff said a separate report Thursday of a drop in new unemployment claims &quot;will scare the monetary authorities as much as it did the bond market.&quot;</p>
<p>The Labour Department's weekly report showed that new claims for jobless benefits fell a larger-than-expected 31,000 to 319,000 in the week ended May 10.</p>
<p>Bond investors sold on the news, which pointed to more tightness in job markets that could push wages higher, feeding inflation, but prices later rebounded and were little changed along with stocks as investors played a waiting game.</p>
<p>A.G. Edwards &amp; Sons chief economist Raymond Worseck said recent economic reports, especially the retail and producer price data, gave the Fed &quot;an excuse to do nothing&quot; at next week's meeting.</p>
<p>But the timing may be right for another increase, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our sense is that the April lull is fading and that we will do a little bit better here in May in terms of the economy,&quot; he said. &quot;We think the Fed anticipates by the end of the year there will be an inflation uptick.&quot;</p>
<p>Separately, the Fed reported that production at mines, factories and utilities was flat in April for the first time since last summer as strikes and related plant shutdowns slowed auto production.</p>
<p>The performance of the industrial sector, which has been racing along for months, was weaker than the 0.2 percent rise Wall Street economists had expected.</p>
<p>The Fed's bank in Philadelphia also reported a drop in business activity in its region last month.</p>
<p>In the consumer price report, the so-called core rate of inflation, which excludes volatile food and energy components, rose 0.3 percent after rising by 0.2 percent in March.</p>
<p>Wall Street had predicted the overall index would rise by 0.1 percent, but economists had expected the core rate to climb by just 0.2 percent.</p>
<p>The department said the larger gain in the April core rate of consumer prices reflected an upturn in the index for clothing and other items.</p>
<p>Clothing prices jumped 0.9 percent last month after falling 0.3 percent in March. The April increase was the biggest since February 1993, when prices rose 1.1 percent.</p>
<p>The department said energy prices fell 1.5 percent last month after dropping 1.7 percent in March, while food prices declined 0.2 percent after being unchanged.</p>
<p>Prices of tobacco and smoking products rose 2.4 percent, the biggest jump in nearly seven years. In July 1990 tobacco prices rose 2.5 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
