<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586731" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX crude hovers about unchanged late session.</title>
<headline>NYMEX crude hovers about unchanged late session.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX crude recovered from session lows by Thursday afternoon to hover about unchanged amid building bullish sentiment following Wednesday's rebound from sharply lower levels.</p>
<p>&quot;By and large the psychology of the market has changed after we were able to discount the bearish build in gasoline stocks. We had what is called an API reversal,&quot; said Nauman Barakat, trader with Prudential Securities in New York.</p>
<p>At 1448 EDT, June crude was up one cent at $21.40 a barrel after falling to a session low of $21.18 early afternoon.  </p>
<p>Spot crude retraced around a 50 cent loss Wednesday, falling initially on large builds in crude and gasoline stocks reported by the American Petroleum Institute (API) Tuesday evening.</p>
<p>But, June crude was under some pressure on Thursday amid selling in the June/July crude spread by a commercial player, dealers said.</p>
<p>The June/July spread was flat versus a 10 cent backwardation on Wednesday. Backwardation means the contract nearer in time is more expensive than the later one.</p>
<p>June heating oil was up 0.18 cent at 56.60 cents a gallon. June gasoline was under pressure, off 0.28 cent at 64.10 cents a gallon after Tosco Corp announced the restart of its Trainer, Pennsylvania refinery.</p>
<p>The Trainer refinery will add about 100,000 barrels per day of gasoline supply. It had been shut since early 1996 for a $50 million modernization after Tosco acquired the plant from British Petroleum.</p>
<p>Tosco had said the official restart would be mid-May and dealers had known the refinery, which has total capacity of 150,000 barrels per day, was being tested by Tosco this week.</p>
<p>-- Harry Milling, New York Energy Desk, 212-859-1761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
