<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586867" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Waigel says cannot rule out tax rise, no proposal.</title>
<headline>Waigel says cannot rule out tax rise, no proposal.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Finance Minister Theo Waigel, after a meeting with parliamentary deputies from Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrats, said there were no proposals to raise taxes to fill a widening budget gap.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no such proposals, but nothing is ruled out,&quot; he said after the meeting.</p>
<p>Waigel said he told the meeting of lawmakers that the government was counting on &quot;stepped up privatisations&quot; to offset a shortfall in tax revenues that is forecast at 18 billion marks below previous estimates that formed the basis of the government's 1997 budget.  </p>
<p>Earlier on Thursday, a panel of government and private tax experts presented the latest tax estimate that predicted 1997 revenues would be around 18 billion marks below previous forecasts. Federal tax receipts alone would come in 9.1 billion marks below forecasts.</p>
<p>Germany's 1997 budget sees a deficit of 53.3 billion marks. Economists expect Waigel to present a supplementary budget to account for this gap in revenue.</p>
<p>In an interview with Germany's ARD television after the meeting, Waigel said of the total tax shortfall for 1997 only around five billion marks would affect the federal budget.</p>
<p>The government would now set about drafting measures to close the financing gap.</p>
<p>&quot;We could impose a spending freeze and we will step up privatisations,&quot; Waigel said.</p>
<p>Waigel mentioned the Deutsche Postbank AG, the banking arm of the former Deutsche Bundespost, telecommunications group Deutsche Telekom AG and government-owned real estate.</p>
<p>He said government plans to revalue Bundesbank gold and currency reserves was justified because it meant West German savings of over 50 years could be employed to offset the liabilities that arose when Bonn assumed the debt of communist East Germany after unification in 1990.</p>
<p>This in turn would help Germany meet the strict criteria for entry into Europe's planned economic and monetary union (EMU), even though the gains from Bundesbank reserves would not flow into the federal budget, but into a fund to pay off debt.</p>
<p>&quot;It will have an impact on the debt position and on the deficit position, which are important for Maastricht,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- William Boston, Bonn Newsroom, 49 228 26097 150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
