<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="586844" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Prosecutors lift cloud on Iran-German relations.</title>
<headline>Prosecutors lift cloud on Iran-German relations.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Fleck</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>German prosecutors have issued arrest warrants for three Iranian intelligence officers over the 1992 killing of four Iranian Kurdish dissidents in Berlin.</p>
<p>But, lifting a cloud hanging over Germany's relations with Iran, they said on Thursday they would not pursue a Berlin court judgment that Iran's leaders ordered the shootings.</p>
<p>A month after the court convicted one Iranian and three Lebanese for the killings, badly straining relations between Bonn and Tehran, the Federal Prosecutor's Office said it ruled out fresh investigations into the Iranian leadership.</p>
<p>Laying to rest media speculation that an even higher profile investigation could be in the offing, angering Iran again, it said such an inquiry would not serve the public interest.</p>
<p>The Berlin judge had said a secret &quot;special operations committee&quot; whose members included Iran's president, religious leader, intelligence minister and head of foreign policy, ordered the killing of the four Iranian Kurds.</p>
<p>He stopped short of explicitly naming Iranian President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani and religious leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, who had been accused by prosecutors of ultimate responsibility for the shooting.</p>
<p>Prosecutors believe two of the latest suspects helped to prepare the attack and the third led the hit squad.</p>
<p>They said a warrant issued last year against Intelligence Minister Ali Fallahiyan on suspicion of ordering the attack would remain in force but it was not clear to what extent other leaders enjoyed immunity under international law.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no basis for investigating the precise circumstances of the committee's decision or to prove the concrete participation of the committee members, apart from Fallahiyan,&quot; the prosecutor's office said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;In this situation it is not in the public interest to start an investigation against the committee members.&quot;</p>
<p>Last month's verdict was the first time a European court had clearly attributed political responsibility to Iran for any of the dozens of killings of Iranian opposition figures abroad since the Islamic revolution in 1979.</p>
<p>Iran rejected the accusations and the verdict prompted a diplomatic row. Almost all European Union states recalled their ambassadors for consultations and the EU abandoned its policy of &quot;critical dialogue&quot; with Iran.</p>
<p>Germany has since repeatedly called on Tehran to respect international law and distance itself from terrorism. EU states said two weeks ago they would sending their envoys back, but Tehran said they were not welcome.</p>
<p>The arrest warrants charged the intelligence officers, identified only as Asghar A., Ali K. alias &quot;Khali&quot; and Abdolrahman B. alias &quot;Sharif&quot;, with murder and attempted murder,</p>
<p>Prosecutors said Asghar A. and &quot;Khali&quot; were believed to have helped to prepare the attack on orders from the Iranian secret service, while the court was told that &quot;Sharif&quot; was rewarded in Iran with a silver Mercedes car for leading the hit squad.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
