<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="58686" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Over 900 U.S. POWs believed left behind in Korea.</title>
<headline>Over 900 U.S. POWs believed left behind in Korea.</headline>
<byline>Jim Adams</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than 900 U.S. prisoners of war were believed to have been left behind in North Korea when the Korean War ended in 1953, a congressional aide said on Tuesday, citing newly declassified records.</p>
<p>Some of the Americans may have been subjected to deadly medical experiments, Al Santoli, the House of Representatives aide who helped gather the information for a hearing to be held on Tuesday, said.</p>
<p>The disclosure that many prisoners were left behind supports recent reports that some Americans may still be detained in North Korea. Santoli said one purpose of the House National Security personnel subcommittee hearing was to show that some Americans might still be held by Pyongyang.</p>
<p>&quot;In discussions with North Korea, that should be a top priority,&quot; Santoli said. He said there had been several reports, one by a former North Korean secret police defector, that Americans had been seen not in North Korean prisons but in guarded villages and encampments.</p>
<p>North Korea has said it is not holding any Americans prisoner. A small number of U.S. soldiers who defected during the Korean War still live in North Korea in addition to those reported seen in villages and encampments, Santoli said.</p>
<p>He said a U.S. Defence Department document obtained by the subcommittee and written months after the Korean War armistice of July 27, 1953, said 610 Army and 300 Air Force people were believed still held prisoner in North Korea.</p>
<p>The document is a Pentagon memorandum written in December 1953 and is among papers the subcommittee obtained from the Eisenhower Library in Abilene, Kansas, and had federal agencies declassify, Santoli said.</p>
<p>Retired Army Col. Phillip Corso, who was an aide to President Dwight Eisenhower, planned to testify that 500 sick and wounded American prisoners were still being held within 10 miles (16 km) of the armistice signing site in 1953.</p>
<p>A Czech defector who now works for the U.S. Defence Intelligence Agency, Jan Sejna, was prepared to testify that Russian and Czech doctors conducted medical experiments on American prisoners during the Korean War, Santoli said.</p>
<p>He said some Americans were drugged in a programme to develop interrogation techniques and others were exposed to toxic war agents and then executed, according to Sejna.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
