<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="58690" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cool U.S. Midwest weather could cut soybean yields.</title>
<headline>Cool U.S. Midwest weather could cut soybean yields.</headline>
<byline>Emily Kaiser</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Below normal temperatures in key U.S. Midwest soybean growing regions will likely limit pod fill and lower test weights and yields, agronomists said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm looking for smaller than average seed size and reduced yields,&quot; said Gary Pepper, University of Illinois extension specialist. &quot;The ability of the soybean to fill seed is reduced when it is chilled during the night to temperatures below 50 degrees (Farenheit).&quot;</p>
<p>Temperatures dipped to the mid-40s F in parts of Illinois last week and fell as low as 29 degrees F in Minnesota.  </p>
<p>When lows drop below 50 degrees F, the soybean plant slows down and does not resume normal development pace until temperatures warm into the 70s, said James Sinclair, interim director of the National Soy Research Lab in Illinois.</p>
<p>&quot;During the day, the plant manufactures the complex carbohydrates and starches that eventually go into the seeds,&quot; Sinclair said. &quot;At night, it is transferred into the seeds. When it gets cool, the transport of these things gets slowed down. (The seed) just doesn't fill out.&quot;</p>
<p>In Iowa last week, temperatures fell to 32 degrees in Marshalltown, northeast of Des Moines.  </p>
<p>Iowa's soybeans as of Sunday were rated 16 percent excellent, 50 percent good, 27 fair, six poor and one very poor, the Iowa Agricultural Statistics Service said in its weekly update released late Monday afternoon.</p>
<p>In southwest and south central Iowa districts, beans &quot;are setting a lot of pods with two beans as opposed to three beans per pod,&quot; the update said.</p>
<p>In Illinois, the second largest U.S. soybean producing state behind Iowa, soybeans were rated four percent excellent, 31 good, 41 fair, 18 poor and six percent very poor.  </p>
<p>Temperatures in the 40s and 50s F in Illinois last week signaled to the soybean plants it was time to finish filling pods but lows were not cold enough to permanently stop development, Pepper said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's telling the plant that it might as well quit,&quot; he said, referring to cold nights. &quot;I don't look for any pods to fall off. It will just be smaller seeds forming.&quot;</p>
<p>In Indiana, conditions were similar as cool nights further slowed development of late-planted soybeans, said Dave Mengel, Purdue University extension agronomist.  </p>
<p>&quot;Things haven't moved very fast and it's quite noticeable,&quot; Mengel said. &quot;There's a lot of concern, particularly with the later-maturing varieties. A lot of them have a ways to go yet and (cool weather) isn't going to help.&quot;</p>
<p>Indiana's soybeans as of Sunday were rated six percent very poor, 16 percent poor, 43 fair, 31 percent good and four percent excellent, about the same as the previous week.</p>
<p>Fifteen percent of Indiana's soybeans were shedding leaves, behind the 41 percent average.</p>
<p>The overall U.S. soybean crop was rated 53 percent good to excellent as of Sunday, down two points from the previous week's ratings, the National Agricultural Statistics Service said. Nationwide, 17 percent of the crop had begun dropping leaves, behind 29 percent for the five-year average.</p>
<p>The U.S. Agriculture Department on September 11 estimated overall yields for this year's soy crop would average 35.8 bushels per acre against last year's actual yield of 34.9 bushels.</p>
<p>-Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8749</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
