<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="587001" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Gujral holds crucial meeting on oil prices.</title>
<headline>India's Gujral holds crucial meeting on oil prices.</headline>
<byline>Hari Ramachandran</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Prime Minister I.K. Gujral, met the finance and petroleum ministers on Thursday on measures to plug a mounting oil subsidy bill, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;I briefed the prime minister on the state of the oil pool deficit,&quot; junior petroleum minister T. R. Balu told Reuters after the meeting.</p>
<p>The United News of India (UNI) said the meeting took no decision on steps to contain the deficit. Further discussions would be held on the issue before arriving at a decision, UNI said.</p>
<p>The petroleum ministry had been pressing the finance ministry for cuts in import duties on crude and oil products to offset the ballooning deficit.</p>
<p>Both Gujral and Chidambaram have said the government must decide soon how to pay off money owed to oil companies, which totalled 155 billion rupees ($4.3 billion) at the end of March, for selling subsidised petroleum products below market prices.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a routine meeting,&quot; said Finance Minister P. Chidambaram. He declined to give details.</p>
<p>Chidambaram has said oil import duties can be cut only if other sources of government revenue are found elsewhere.</p>
<p>The Press Trust of India (PTI) said the finance ministry had on Thursday rejected demands for slashing customs and excise duties on oil products leaving the government with no option but to raise prices.</p>
<p>India's demand for petroleum products is growing at over eight percent per annum, much faster than the growth of domestic supplies.</p>
<p>The Indian government has targeted crude oil production in 1997/98 at 34.37 million tonnes compared with an estimated 33.72 million in 1996/97.</p>
<p>The 15-member United Front coalition, which Gujral heads, is in a dilemma over raising state-controlled prices. The Front's steering committee is meeting on May 25 to discuss oil prices.</p>
<p>Leftist members of the 15-party coalition oppose any increase in prices.</p>
<p>Analysts said the situation called for a 20-25 percent increase but there have been widespread predictions of a 15-20 percent increase in diesel and liquefied petroleum gas, and that the government might restrict the increase for kerosene, used by India's poor as the main fuel for cooking and lighting.</p>
<p>The government might leave gasoline prices untouched as they were raised by 25 percent in July last year, they said.</p>
<p>The deficit - the money owed by the government to oil companies for selling their products below world prices - will hit 245 billion rupees by the end of the fiscal year 1997/98 (April-March) if nothing was done, Balu said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
