<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="587334" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lower UK April RPI will not stop early rate rise.</title>
<headline>Lower UK April RPI will not stop early rate rise.</headline>
<byline>Rosemary Bennett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>April's UK inflation report, showing lower-than-expected headline and underlying rates, will not stop the Bank of England raising interest rates in the summer as the breakdown clearly shows overheating in the dynamic services sector.</p>
<p>&quot;This release shows clear evidence that the service sector is overheating and it will continue to until growth in aggregate slows,&quot; said David Mackie, UK economist at JP Morgan.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bank of England will be more concerned about activity there than it is comforted by these lower inflation numbers.&quot;</p>
<p>The headline rate of inflation fell to 2.4 percent from 2.6 percent in March while the underlying rate fell to 2.5 percent -- hitting the government's target -- from 2.7 percent in March.</p>
<p>Many economists believe the newly empowered central bank will hold off from raising rates at its first meeting in June, and instead wait to see the contents of Chancellor of the Exchequer Gordon Brown's first budget.</p>
<p>But Mackie forecasts the increasing imbalance between goods and services, in terms of both output and inflation, will prompt the Bank to take action in July.  </p>
<p>In its latest qyarterly inflation report, the Bank said it was concerned about the implications of the increasing imbalance between the growth rate in manufacturing and the services. The breakdown of components in April's RPI release shows it has some cause.</p>
<p>The all-services index showed inflation unchanged at 3.3 percent in the year to April, but this was flattered by a surprise dip in rents.</p>
<p>Prices in the bigger shop and non-shop services sectors ratcheted higher, up 5.0 percent and 4.1 percent respectively in the year to April.  </p>
<p>Adam Cole, UK economist at James Capel, agreed rates will have to go higher to address the overheating in services.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bank is right to say rates will have to rise if it is to meet the 2.5 percent target in two years time.</p>
<p>He said inflation in goods -- up 1.7 percent in the year to April compared with 2.0 percent in March -- is being held back by a number of factors, but in particular falling seasonal food prices, helped in turn by the strong pound.</p>
<p>&quot;That alone (seasonal food) is knocking a quarter of a percentage point off the headline and underling rates.</p>
<p>Cole said it was also disappointing that retailers were not fully passing on the benefits of lower input prices to cusomers.</p>
<p>&quot;Retailers are taking the bulk of lower input prices on their margins and not passing them on to consumers. And they will be able to get away with it because of higher earnings and solid consumer demand.&quot;  </p>
<p>The inflation report comes a day after the labour market report showed softer earnings growth in the services sector. While the two together paint a favourable picture for inflation short term, the inflation report makes it clear the Bank has already factored that in and its concerns lie with the services sector.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bank has focused on the uptrend in services as a reason to be worried about the medium term outlook for inflation as the impact of sterling's rise starts to fade,&quot; said Michael Saunders, UK economist at Salomon Brothers.</p>
<p>&quot;So today's figures will not deter the Bank from seeking a further policy tightening the next couple of months.&quot;</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7715</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
