<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="587494" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwait share index rises 1pct in easy trade week.</title>
<headline>Kuwait share index rises 1pct in easy trade week.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kuwait's share index edged up one percent in thin trade in the week to Wednesday starting what dealers called a &quot;normal&quot; recovery after dipping in the previous week amid crash fears, dealers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The correction witnessed was mainly caused by talk of a crash. The market could regain the April levels in the coming weeks,&quot; said an investor.</p>
<p>The index and trade levels hit record high levels in April.</p>
<p>&quot;It is normal that prices recover,&quot; said another, echoing the views of fellow dealers.</p>
<p>The index finished the week at 2,320.2 points with gainers leading losers 28-20. Ninteen shares did not change.</p>
<p>Earlier this month some parliamentarians warned of a market crash potential. Officials were swift to issue reassuring statements, but some economists said market fundamentals did not explain big rises in prices and trade levels.</p>
<p>Analysts have said some big investors are forming pools to drive prices up, and warn of negative effects on smaller investors.</p>
<p>In the week to Wednesday the daily average value of traded shares fell to 37 million dinars ($122.8 million) from 70 million. Volume eased to a daily average of 119.4 million shares from 237.4 million, Kuwait Stock Exchange (KSE) figures showed.</p>
<p>Investment firms were the most active in terms of traded value with 59 million dinars, followed by real estate firms with 39.4 million and banks with 39.2 million.</p>
<p>United Realty, Kuwait Real Estate, Investment Projects, The International Investor, Real Estate Bank and Gulf Bank were among the most active shares.</p>
<p>Only nationals of Gulf Arab states -- Saudi Arabia, Bahrain, United Arab Emirates, Qatar, Oman and Kuwait -- can trade on the exchange. Foreign residents can invest in mutual funds.</p>
<p>($1 = 0.302 dinar)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
