<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="587637" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: B-52 pilot may be allowed honorable discharge.</title>
<headline>B-52 pilot may be allowed honorable discharge.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Secretary of the Air Force may be willing to allow the nation's first female B-52 pilot, who is under fire for adultery charges, to resign with an honourable discharge, the New York Times said.</p>
<p>In its Thursday edition, the Times quoted unnamed senior Air Force officials as saying that Secretary Sheila Widnall is looking for a way to avoid a high-profile court-martial proceeding against Second Lt. Kelly Flinn.</p>
<p>However, Widnall is in a delicate position because under military rules she is barred from formally offering leniency in exchange for avoiding a trial, the Times reported.</p>
<p>Under usual Air Force rules, individuals facing court martial are allowed to ask to be given the chance to resign, a procedure known as resignation in lieu of a court martial, or R.I.L.O.</p>
<p>&quot;There is some concern the reputation of the Air Force is being unfairly tarnished,&quot; one senior Air Force official told the Times. &quot;Widnall would certainly consider the facts in this case, and if the R.I.L.O. came she would most probably accept it. I can't necessarily say a discharge would be honourable, but she would certainly consider the ramifications of the range of discharges.&quot;</p>
<p>Flinn is facing charges of adultery, fraternisation, disobeying a direct orer and making a false sworn statement. The charges stem from an affair she has acknowledged she had with a married civilian.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
