<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="587622" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Who has veto power under NATO-Russia accord?.</title>
<headline>Who has veto power under NATO-Russia accord?.</headline>
<byline>Laurence McQuillan</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian President Boris Yeltsin says a new NATO-Russia pact gives Moscow veto power over key decisions by the alliance, a view President Bill Clinton says is wrong. Both are right.</p>
<p>NATO and Russia reached agreement on Wednesday on an accord designed to placate the Kremlin before the military alliance invites some former Warsaw Pact nations to join. A signing ceremony has been set for May 27 in Paris.</p>
<p>Appearing on Russian television, Yeltsin said that although he remained adamantly opposed to NATO's expansion into Eastern Europe he foresaw only &quot;calm&quot; relations.</p>
<p>&quot;Decisions can be taken only by consensus,&quot; Yeltsin said in describing the accord to his countrymen. &quot;If Russia is against some decision, it means this decision will not go through. That is of capital importance.&quot;</p>
<p>At the White House in Washington, the assessment appeared to be far different.</p>
<p>Clinton spoke of building &quot;a new relationship with Russia that benefits all of us&quot; but made it clear there were limits to the power Moscow can exercise.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia will work closely with NATO, but not within NATO,&quot; he said, &quot;giving Russia a voice in, but not a veto over, NATO's business.&quot;</p>
<p>How can two world leaders agree on something involving detailed negotiations that took so long and then make such differing statements about what they agreed to? In diplomacy all things are possible.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no secret understandings,&quot; a senior administration official insisted, adding &quot;it is very clear and explicit that there is no veto that any country has.&quot;</p>
<p>However, under the agreement, a new NATO-Russia Permanent Joint Council will be created. Foreign and defence ministers will meet twice a year and ambassadors will gather once a month.</p>
<p>In that council, Yeltsin in reality will be able to wield veto power, according to administration officials who have read the documents that have not yet been made public.</p>
<p>&quot;The new body ... will operate by consensus,&quot; another senior administration official acknowledged. &quot;If Russia doesn't want something to happen under the auspices of the NATO-Russia joint council, it won't happen.&quot;</p>
<p>So Yeltsin is right when he speaks about the council. Clinton, however, is correct as well because his remarks were not limited to the actions of the joint council.</p>
<p>Under the new agreement the North Atlantic Council -- which currently is made up of the 16 NATO members -- will continue to set policy. &quot;That is sovereign,&quot; the senior official said. &quot;It doesn't take orders from anybody but itself.&quot;</p>
<p>While consensus-building will be essential in the joint council, &quot;that does not mean that NATO can't do what it feels is in the interests of its members.&quot;</p>
<p>So in a world that perhaps only diplomats fully appreciate, Bill Clinton and Boris Yeltsin are able to say things that appear to clash. In the end, however, both are right.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
