<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="587644" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Eddie Murphy sues over transsexual hooker stories.</title>
<headline>Eddie Murphy sues over transsexual hooker stories.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Comedian Eddie Murphy sued two supermarket tabloids on Wednesday, alleging they printed lies about his sexual habits after he was stopped by undercover police with a transsexual prostitute in his vehicle.</p>
<p>Murphy's suits, filed in Los Angeles Superior Court, each seek $5 million in general damages and unspecified punitive damages from the National Enquirer and the Globe for slander, libel and invasion of privacy.</p>
<p>A third suit seeks at least $1 million for the same reasons, from Ioane Seiuli, a relative of the prostitute who was in his car the morning of May 2.</p>
<p>Atisone Seiuli was arrested by sheriff's deputies on an outstanding prostitution warrant in the incident on Santa Monica Boulevard in West Hollywood. Murphy, 36, was not charged with any offence.</p>
<p>After the 4:45 a.m. incident, Murphy said in interviews and through his publicist that he had been giving Seiuli a ride home and that he was a &quot;good samaritan&quot; who often helped the homeless and prostitutes.</p>
<p>Murphy, described in the suits as &quot;an internationally renowned comedian and actor,&quot; alleged the two tabloids printed articles knowing they were false or without reasonable grounds for believing they were true.</p>
<p>The tabloids printed interviews with transvestite prostitutes suggesting Murphy had a &quot;secret sex life&quot; and a &quot;sick obsession.&quot;</p>
<p>His suit against Ioane Seiuli, whose gender was not known, related to comments Seiuli made to the New York Post.</p>
<p>There was no immediate comment from any parties in the suits.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
