<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="587679" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany ready to sign NATO-Russia accord-Kinkel.</title>
<headline>Germany ready to sign NATO-Russia accord-Kinkel.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl on Thursday telephoned Russian President Boris Yeltsin to express satisfaction with a cooperation deal between NATO and Russia agreed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel made clear Germany was ready to sign the accord, agreed on Wednesday by NATO Secretary General Javier Solana and Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov but not yet approved by the 16 NATO member governments.</p>
<p>Kohl and Yeltsin agreed in their assessment of the deal as a &quot;fundamental, far-reaching step towards ensuring lasting stability and security in Europe&quot;, government spokesman Peter Hausmann said in a statement.</p>
<p>The agreement, known as the NATO-Russia Founding Act, is intended to formalise Russian input into European security structures as NATO expands to include eastern European countries which used to be Russia's allies in the communist Warsaw Pact.</p>
<p>Kinkel said there was an agreement not to reveal the details of the accord until 10 a.m. (0800 GMT) on Friday, and that he could therefore not yet make any final judgment.</p>
<p>&quot;But I believe that we can accept what has been agreed,&quot; he told German Radio.</p>
<p>Kinkel said the agreement, which is due to be signed at a ceremony in Paris on May 27 by NATO members and Moscow, would form the basis of a new European security structure in which Russia would be included.</p>
<p>&quot;This naturally meant that we had to make certain concessions to Russia. But on the other hand there could be no question of weakening NATO in any way or of creating a first- and second-class NATO. I believe we have found that middle way.&quot;</p>
<p>NATO has pledged not to station nuclear weapons on the territory of its new members and says it also foresees no need to station troops from other alliance members there.</p>
<p>But Kinkel said there was absolutely no need to site atomic weapons on the territory of the new members -- the first of whom are expected to be Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic -- in order to take them under NATO's &quot;nuclear umbrella&quot;.</p>
<p>Kinkel also said it would be possible for NATO to station integrated multinational troop units and headquarters in the new member states -- some of the points which are to be set down in a new international treaty on Conventional Forces in Europe.</p>
<p>He said he did not expect Russia's continued opposition in principle to NATO enlargement to have practical consequences, and that new members could now be invited to join as planned.</p>
<p>He said Primakov had summarised Moscow's stance in two sentences during a visit to Bonn. &quot;The first was: 'We are opposed to enlargement. The second was: 'But we are realists.'&quot;</p>
<p>Kinkel emphatically rejected the idea that Russia had a veto over aspects of NATO policy or over new admissions.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no veto on admissions to NATO. That is decided by the 16 NATO members alone, and in future by the other countries that will be members,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
