<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="587785" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Booming Ireland to hold June election.</title>
<headline>Booming Ireland to hold June election.</headline>
<byline>Carmel Linnane</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish Prime Minister John Bruton on Thursday called a June 6 national election, gambling that the &quot;feelgood factor&quot; from a booming economy will cut back the opposition's widening lead in opinion polls.</p>
<p>Bruton, whose three-party left-right coalition came to power in late 1994, had until November to call the election but opted to stage it six months after what was billed as the biggest tax giveaway budget in the 75-year history of the state.</p>
<p>Opinion polls show the popularity of his so-called rainbow coalition fading fast in the wake of revelations that an Irish tycoon, Ben Dunne, paid millions of pounds to politicians from all parties, including Bruton's own Fine Gael.</p>
<p>A Bruton protege, Michael Lowry, resigned as transport minister last year after admitting that Dunne paid for the renovation of his private home in a complex business deal.</p>
<p>An official inquiry was told that former Prime Minister Charles Haughey of the opposition Fianna Fail party also received more than a million pounds ($1.6 million) from Dunne to ease cash problems, but the party does not seem to have suffered.</p>
<p>A poll last week showed that Bertie Ahern's Fianna Fail, the most powerful political party in modern Irish history, would win 43 per cent of votes in an election, against 26 for Fine Gael. His most likely coalition allies, the Progressive Democrats of Mary Harney, would win eight per cent.</p>
<p>Bruton's coalition allies, the Labour party of Dick Spring and Democratic Left of Proinsias de Rossa, would win 12 and two percent of the vote respectively, giving the combined opposition a lead of 11 per cent.</p>
<p>This reversed a six point gap the opposition held over the coalition until the so-called payments-to-politicians tribunal began its hearings this month.</p>
<p>Polls apart, history is against Bruton. For almost 30 years no incumbent Irish government has been returned at the polls.</p>
<p>Ahern effectively launched his election campaign in April with a national poster campaign promising &quot;people before politics.&quot;</p>
<p>Unemployment, the management of one of Europe's most successful economies, law and order and the Northern Ireland peace process are expected to dominate the campaign.</p>
<p>Fine Gael argues that in the two years since it came to power it has created jobs at the rate of one thousand per week to bring the jobless rate down from around 13 percent to 11.</p>
<p>With an expected growth rate of some five per cent this year Finance Minister Ruairi Quinn shaved taxes by a percentage point in his January budget to share out the spoils of one of the fastest growing economies in the European Union.</p>
<p>But Ahern is expected to make a firm pledge to get the top rate of tax down from 48 per cent to 43 per cent in the next five-year parliament, a vote-winning promise that may sway a nation that complains of one of Europe's heaviest tax burdens.</p>
<p>Both opposition and government parties have promised to crack down on crime, especially drug trafficking, after the unsolved murder last year of Veronica Guerin, Ireland's top investigate reporter, by the drugs underworld.</p>
<p>Both are committed to a peaceful settlement of the Northern Ireland conflict but Ahern says Fianna Fail will be much more assertive in dealing with Britain, Dublin's partner in a slow-moving peace process.</p>
<p>Ahern has said that he will appoint former Prime Minister Albert Reynolds, who helped broker a ceasefire by Irish Republican Army (IRA) guerrillas fighting British rule, to a job in the peace process and to try to win a new IRA truce.</p>
<p>Reynolds' coalition collapsed when its then ally, Spring's Labour party, withdrew its support in November 1994 in a row over legal appointments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
