<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="587727" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Le Pen says Chirac's Europe is Hitler's dream.</title>
<headline>Le Pen says Chirac's Europe is Hitler's dream.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>French far-right leader Jean-Marie Le Pen said on Thursday that President Jacques Chirac's idea of Europe would be &quot;Hitler's dream come true&quot; and urged a leftist victory in a parliamentary election to block Chirac's plans.</p>
<p>&quot;This sort of Europe, dominated by Germany and organised in 'Lander'-like provinces ignoring existing nations, will make Hitler's dream come true,&quot; Le Pen told the daily Le Parisien.</p>
<p>Le Pen said a leftist win in the May 25-June 1 election would help his cause by paralysing the country and blocking its drift towards European integration including a single currency.</p>
<p>He urged supporters to back leftist candidates in the second round of the May 25-June 1 election in constituences where Front candidates did not survive the first-round ballot.</p>
<p>A period of cohabitation, forcing the conservative head of state to work with a leftist government, &quot;would tie Chirac's hands on Europe, and will lead to a new dissolution within a year,&quot; Le Pen said in a separate interview on Radio Luxembourg.</p>
<p>&quot;And perhaps the next time around, the National Front will be better placed to win power than it is now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While the Front itself will win at most three seats in the 577-seat National Assembly, its supporters are in a position to play a decisive role in the second round of the election, pollsters said.</p>
<p>But while Le Pen has said repeatedly that his top priority is to deprive Chirac of a majority in parliament, polls find that Front voters, who make up about 13 percent to 15 percent of the total, look set to ignore his advice.</p>
<p>Opinion polls show that they are likely to prefer government candidates over opposition Socialists or Communists in run-offs.</p>
<p>Le Pen played down the advice he has given supporters.</p>
<p>&quot;In the second round they will do what they want. I will offer my opinion, and they will follow it or not, as they wish,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Socialist Party head Lionel Jospin, campaigning in the southern city of Avignon, warned the right against trying to use Le Pen's words against his party in the campaign saying that all mainstream parties were united in condemning the Front.</p>
<p>&quot;We are quite clear on the matter of the extreme right's ideas,&quot; Jospin said. &quot;There is no leakage between our ideas and those one finds on the right,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gaullist Prime Minister Alain Juppe, who is leading the government campaign, got a mixed reception while campaigning for a fellow Gaullist candidate in a Paris marketplace.</p>
<p>&quot;What we must fight is scepticism, because we are accomplishing things,&quot; Juppe told one voter who complained to him that he no longer believed what politicians said.</p>
<p>But a fruit and vegetable merchant told him: &quot;Things are starting to get better.&quot;</p>
<p>Chirac urged the right to stop squabbling on Wednesday after allies of the unpopular prime minister accused him of dragging down the government campaign and hinted he should be replaced if the right wins the election.</p>
<p>But aides said Juppe was not too worried by the criticisms and &quot;had not ruled out succeeding himself&quot;.</p>
<p>The election campaign has coincided with a bout of labour unrest. French farmers dumped tonnes of fruit and vegetables in the streets in several cities in protest at a flood of low-price foreign produce, and about 200 protesters temporarily occupied the Bank of France to accuse the central bank of causing poverty with its free-market policies.</p>
<p>In addition, train controllers worried about job cuts and bonuses threatened to prolong a strike restricting rail traffic across the country, and pilots at state-owned Air France and Air France Europe said they would walk out for four days beginning next Tuesday in a dispute over wages and working conditions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
