<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="587729" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Pricing critical for San Paolo share offer.</title>
<headline>Pricing critical for San Paolo share offer.</headline>
<byline>David Jones</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's biggest bank San Paolo di Torino is set to launch its public share issue next week with analysts expecting good interest for the stock although the share price may have to drift lower to ensure plenty of buyers.</p>
<p>San Paolo is to launch a global offer for 26.96 percent of its capital to public and institutional investors which will create Italy's first &quot;true publicly-held&quot; bank, but in a poorly-performing banking sector pricing will be critical.</p>
<p>Analysts believe the offer should go well as it has been well publicised on television and through the bank's some 1,000 branches in Italy, but they see the stock price drifting lower this week and next ahead of the offer price been set.</p>
<p>San Paolo has made big changes in the last 18 months ahead of privatisation selling off non-performing assets, increasing its non-interest income such as from fund management and also cutting personnel in an over-staffed domestic banking industry.</p>
<p>&quot;It has a good chance of going well with San Paolo coming to the market at a time when the bank has made changes to diversify away from interest income and into other area,&quot; said Anthony Mannara, head of equity sales at Milan brokers Milla.</p>
<p>In a banking sector woefully behind some other European nations in financial returns, San Paolo shows a return on equity currently of 6.1 percent compared to double-digit figures at its British and German banking cousins.</p>
<p>&quot;The bank has shown it can stimulate its branch network to sell managed funds and other products and we think the core shareholders are an interesting element in the privatisation process,&quot; said Francesco Ricciulli at brokers Pasfin.</p>
<p>Analysts believe the share offer price will need to be set below 10,500 lire a share to see good demand and the closer the price is to 10,000 lire the more interested international investors will become.</p>
<p>One Milan analyst sees a price range of 10,300-10,400 lire as appropriate pointing out San Paolo initial share offer in 1992 was set at 12,200 lire. At 1350 GMT, San Paolo share price was up 1.18 percent at 10,830 lire.</p>
<p>The public offer of San Paolo shares is for some 220 million ordinary shares with a minimum of 70 million assigned for the public, leaving institutions 150 million or less. At the current share price the offer is set to raise around 2.4 trillion lire ($1.4 billion).</p>
<p>If the offer is oversubscribed, there is a green shoe extra allocation of 33 million shares for institutions.</p>
<p>On May 18, the bank is expected to announce the maximum price of the share offer and the size of the discount from the prevailing price when the final price is calculated.</p>
<p>The offer will run from May 19-23, and at the end of the week the final offer price will be set at the lower of either the May 18 maximum price or the closing price of San Paolo shares on the last day of the offer, May 23, minus the discount.</p>
<p>The foundation that controls San Paolo has already conducted a private placing of a 20 percent stake in the bank to a stable core of shareholders including Spain's Banca Santander and Italian investment bank IMI, bringing the foundation's stake in the bank to 45.6 percent from 65.6 pct.</p>
<p>In addition, the Italian Treasury, the Italian state railway and another related bank will sell most of their own combined 7.4 percent stake, adding to the public offer.</p>
<p>$=1,673 lire</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
