<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="58778" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: MEPs bewail cuts in development budget.</title>
<headline>MEPs bewail cuts in development budget.</headline>
<dateline>STRASBOURG 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union should divert to the world's poorest countries some of the funds it has allocated to its Mediterranean neighbours for 1997, members of the European Parliament's development committee said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>British Socialist Glenys Kinnock said the 15 percent cut which EU ministers planned to make in the EU's external relations budget for 1997 was &quot;appalling&quot; at a time when aid to developing countries was at its lowest level since the early 1970s and 1.6 billion people were worse off now than 15 years ago.</p>
<p>EU ministers plan to set a austere overall budget for 1997 which is only 2.2 percent higher than the 1996 budget.</p>
<p>Foreign policy expenditure, particularly development cooperation has taken a heavy blow to maintain this austerity, with some budget lines being cut as much as 22.5 percent.</p>
<p>The only exception to this trend is EU funding for the Union's Mediterranean neighbours, which is set to leap from 400 million Ecus this year to 800 million in 1997.</p>
<p>Parliament's development committee is demanding a string of amendments to the draft budget, including the transfer of some 150 million Ecus from the so-called MEDA budget to poorer areas of the world, namely Africa, the Caribbean and the Pacific.</p>
<p>The committee wants a further 20 million to be diverted to development projects carried out by non-governmental organisations.</p>
<p>&quot;We need a fairer and a more balanced distribution of our money across the world,&quot; Kinnock told a news conference.</p>
<p>She said the development committee did not question the desirability of aiding the Mediterranean countries but that it queried their ability to absorb the massive amount of money made available to them.</p>
<p>They had only taken up 2.5 percent of the EU funds available in 1995, she said.</p>
<p>Sam Biesmans, from the Liaison Committee representing Europe's 800 NGOs, said there was deep concern about the apparent lack of information about where MEDA funds were actually going.</p>
<p>&quot;We need more transparency and more democratic control by the European Parliament,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STRASBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
