<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="588076" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian dlr lurches lower in jittery trade.</title>
<headline>Australian dlr lurches lower in jittery trade.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar looked shaky at the midsession after lurching to a month low in brisk trade.</p>
<p>Dealers said a local-based U.S. bank had led the selling the last few of days and was joined by a couple of the local banks when US0.7750 support cracked this morning. Japanese investors had also been dumping AUD/yen as US$/yen slumped. Bids had emerged at US$0.7735 and again at US$0.7725 with exporters and a Chinese name in the frame as buyers.</p>
<p>But fresh offers capped it at US$0.7745 and the market was anxiously waiting to see if Reserve Bank governor Ian Macfarlane provided new direction in a speech at 1.20 pm (0320 GMT).  </p>
<p>Traders reported loose talk the RBA was arranging an emergency meeting of its policy board to discuss a cut in interest rates. This seemed a bizarre rumour to most observers given Macfarlane only last week said the bank saw no economic benefit in moving rates.</p>
<p>Some said the same U.S. bank which had been leading the AUD selling had been seen buying bill futures this morning and the market began to wonder if it knew something was afoot.</p>
<p>Indeed, the bank in question has been advising clients there was still a good chance the RBA could yet cut, even after last week's comments from Macfarlane.  </p>
<p>Those of a more Machiavellian bent wondered instead if the bank was not simply finessing the market in the classical hope of selling high and buying low.</p>
<p>Whatever the subtleties by 12.00 pm (0200 GMT) the dollar was down at US$0.7735/40 having slipping from a US$0.7803 high offshore and US$0.7782/87 late here Wednesday.</p>
<p>It took a worse beating on the crosses where a plunging US$/yen was spooking Japanese investors into cutting unhedged A$ bond positions as well as carry trades -- where investors borrow in yen at low rates and lend in A$ at much higher yields. The dollar dived to 89.89/99 yen from 92.57/67 late here Wednesday.  </p>
<p>The latest slide brought its losses to a whopping 10 percent since it peaked just above 100.00 yen on May 1. In this it has mirrored the U.S. dollar which has dived from a 127.46 yen high to briefly touch 115.95 this morning.</p>
<p>The reversal partly refected fears the Japanese authorities had been preparing to intervene to end the yen's slide and were also considering raising interest rates from their record lows.</p>
<p>The U.S. dollar's decline was fuelled overnight when a soft producer price report encouraged speculation the Federal Reserve might not hike rates at its policy meeting next week and rumours circulated the Treasury wanted to see US$/yen at 115.00 yen.  </p>
<p>There was no confirmation from the Treasury, and dealers felt it highly unlikely given Treasury Secretary Rubin's oft-stated desire to see a strong dollar.</p>
<p>But it did mesh with recent thinking in Japanese circles that MOF forex guru Sakakibara favoured 115.00 as the mid rate for US$/yen. Technical analysts said the break of key 117.50 support confirmed a trend reversal was underway and the next key chart target would be 109.25 with 103.00 even possible.</p>
<p>The matching targets for the local currency would be 84.35 yen and 79.50. The selling took its toll on the trade weighted index which skidded to 58.8 from 59.5 late Wednesday.  </p>
<p>The fortunes of US$/yen were set to dominate the A$ crosses, but Macfarlane's speech could give it direction against the U.S. dolalr itself.</p>
<p>Anslysts were interest to see if he remained as bullish on the economy as during last week's testimony to parliament and stuck to the line that no further eaisng was needed.</p>
<p>Some, the earlier metioned U.S bank included, felt he might yet hold out the prospect of a cut should wage and price data prove favourable. His reaction, if any, to the budget would also be of great interest.</p>
<p>-- Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
