<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="588039" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian police corruption endemic - report.</title>
<headline>Australian police corruption endemic - report.</headline>
<byline>Michael Perry</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police corruption is systematic and entrenched in Australia's largest force, similar to the New York police force in the early 1990s, with officers involved in the drugs trade and competing with criminals to commit crimes.</p>
<p>An official report into corruption in the New South Wales state police force released on Thursday said the force had &quot;rarely been free of corruption&quot; in its 135-year history.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps the most disturbing of all was the extent to which police admitted to being directly involved in the supply of cocaine, heroin and cannibis,&quot; said Supreme Court Judge James Wood in his three-volume report.</p>
<p>In one incident a drug dealer provided police with A$12,000 (US$9,360) to finance a &quot;buy-bust&quot;. The drugs, two ounces of heroin, were seized by police, but the money &quot;lost&quot; in the raid. Later the police divided the drugs up with the dealer.</p>
<p>Police were also involved in theft and extortion, took bribes to protect drug dealers and bookmakers, lied in court to ensure prosecution and assaulted and arrested innocent people.</p>
<p>Most of the corruption cited in the 1,020-page report took place in units in Sydney, whose officers dominate the force.</p>
<p>&quot;On any view, the inquiries of the royal commission disclosed a very serious state of corruption that was widespread and of long-standing origin,&quot; Wood said.</p>
<p>&quot;The culture was such, and the management and internal investigative systems were so deficient, that the state of corruption found can only be regarded as systematic and entrenched,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The service has rarely been free of corruption.&quot;</p>
<p>Wood said the rise of drug crime in the past 20 years significantly increased police corruption, exposing more police to the &quot;temptations of easy money&quot;, and expanding corruption from the traditional areas such as gambling and alcohol.</p>
<p>&quot;What is of concern...is the active involvement of police in planning and implementing criminal activity, sometimes in partnership with known criminals, and on other occassions, in competition with them,&quot; Wood said.</p>
<p>&quot;This finding mirrors the experience of the 1994 Mollen Inquiry which similarly found that corruption within the New York Police Department was no longer confined to fortuitous opportunity...but often arose because police created and actively planned similar activities.&quot;</p>
<p>The Mollen Commission report, released in July 1994 after a 22-month inquiry, found that some groups of New York City police officers had become virtual street gangs that terrorised minority neighbourhoods and trafficked in drugs.</p>
<p>Wood said that corruption occured because of &quot;rotten apples&quot;, a police culture called the &quot;brotherhood&quot; where police put up a code of silence to protect each other, and because policing and corruption &quot;go hand in hand&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The simple fact is that corruption does not emerge suddenly. By its nature it is spawned in stealth and grows in a climate in which it is comfortable.&quot;</p>
<p>Wood said that relationships between police and informants had become &quot;so corrupted that in many cases the informant ran the police officer&quot;.</p>
<p>Wood said that unless fundamental changes in the culture and operation of New South Wales Police Force were implemented then corruption would continue.</p>
<p>Wood recommended random field inspections of police operations, greater use of uniformed police in investigations, the use of tape recorders for police interviews, proper management of informants and a move towards the decriminalisation of heroin use.</p>
<p>The New South Wales state government in February agreed to implement recommendations from Wood's interim report, such as creating a new all-powerful anti-corruption body which will have the power to bug telephones and access police files.</p>
<p>There have been no prosecutions yet as a result of Wood's inquiries, but law officers are examining all his files.</p>
<p>(AS1 = US$0.78)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
