<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="58828" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU to query Credit Lyonnais, Clabecq rescue plans.</title>
<headline>EU to query Credit Lyonnais, Clabecq rescue plans.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission, back to normal competition business after its summer break, is to start a formal probe on Wednesday into a suspected violation of the Credit Lyonnais rescue plan, Commission sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>At issue is the decision by Lyonnais, once Europe's largest bank which is being restructured with French public money, to regain control of Societe de Banque Occidentale (SDBO) -- a formerly owned subsidiary hived off into a state-backed vehicle created to rid Lyonnais of its loss-making assets.</p>
<p>The Commission is also expected to query Belgium's plan to restructure troubled steel maker Forges de Clabecq SA, which includes a cash injection of 1.5 billion Belgian francs and writing off some 500 million Belgian francs in debts.</p>
<p>It will also request more information on another French salvage plan in the banking sector for Societe Marseillaise de Credit, a regional bank scheduled for privatisation that was promised 2.1 billion fresh money.</p>
<p>But, surprisingly, it is due to nod through a request to pay French state-controlled insurer GAN 2.86 billion French francs as part of a recovery plan without first starting formal proceedings, the sources said.</p>
<p>The Commission increasingly consults rival companies on big rescue plans before it actually takes a decision, by way of opening formal probes and publishing details on the plans in the Oficial Journal.</p>
<p>Although it was not the first, the GAN exception raised a few eyebrows at the Commission's preparatary meeting on state aid, especially from its more liberal members, a source said. &quot;We need to avoid this in the future because interested parties must have the possibility to express their views.&quot;</p>
<p>Under EU rules on restructuring aid, subsidies can be allowed if they are strictly intended to help a company return to profitability and do not distort competition. The Commission also takes a favourable approach if the company being aided is to be privatised shortly thereafter -- as is the case of GAN whose sale has been announced for the end of the year.</p>
<p>On the purchase of SDBO, the sources said the Commission had suspicions that Credit Lyonnais had paid less than it should be under the conditions set in the July 1995 restructuring plan.</p>
<p>SDBO was the banker for French entrepreneur-turned-politician Bernard Tapie who has been declared bankrupt and ineligible for public office. Tapie has filed a court action against both Credit Lyonnais and SDBO.</p>
<p>The 1995 plan says that the purchase by Lyonnais of any of its some 135-billion-franc worth of assets divested into the state-backed vehicle known as the EPFR should be made at the price they were paid for or at market price if higher.</p>
<p>The sources said they had not discussed any changes to the Lyonnais rescue plan, despite intense French press speculation that the terms of a loan granted by the bank to EPFR to finance the acquisition of the bad assets would have to be softened.</p>
<p>The spokesman for European Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert also said last week that the French authorities had not requested permission to change the plan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
