<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="58833" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: 1997 estimates for Michelin seen rising.</title>
<headline>1997 estimates for Michelin seen rising.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share analysts appear set to cut their earnings forecasts for tyremaker Michelin for 1996 to take into account a restructuring charge included in the first-half results but raise their forecasts for 1997.</p>
<p>Michelin reported a 10 percent drop in net profit to 1.35 billion francs after taking a 709 million franc charge to restructure its Spanish subsidiary to cuts its costs further.</p>
<p>But its profit excluding tax and exceptionals items rose 50 percent to 2.88 billion francs, boosted by higher sales and lower production costs, and its operating profit rose 31 percent to 3.62 billion francs.</p>
<p>&quot;The operating results were a lot better than we were expecting,&quot; said a Paris-based analyst who expects to cut his 1996 forecast but raise his forecast for the following year.</p>
<p>Another analyst with a French brokerage said he would raise his 1997 forecast, but cut it for 1996 to take the charge into account. &quot;This is a restructuring story, and you have to pay for it. This is part of that,&quot; he said, referring to the charge.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that they're pressing ahead with a restructuring is a good thing. You don't worry about restructuring charges,&quot; said analyst Nick Snee at JP Morgan. He said he would probably change his estimates after today's results.</p>
<p>&quot;They were very good,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The blot on Michelin's results was the rise in its debt. &quot;They're poor at managing inventories,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;A company with that much free cash flow and no reduction in its debt -- that bothers me,&quot; said another.</p>
<p>But the overall reaction was bullish. Brokerage Cheuvreux de Virieu added Michelin to its list of recommended stocks.</p>
<p>The share was the biggest gainer on the CAC 40 on Tuesday, rising 2.27 percent to 266 francs in late trading. Market operators said they liked Michelin's limited exposure to the European economy and the car industry cycle, its commitment to restructuring and the fruits of its past restructuring moves.</p>
<p>The consensus earnings per share forecast compiled by Jacques Chahine Finance is for 27.5 francs for Michelin in 1996 and 30.7 francs for 1997.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I48110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
