<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="588686" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Metrobank sheds 7.5 pct on foreign selloff.</title>
<headline>Metrobank sheds 7.5 pct on foreign selloff.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Metropolitan Bank &amp; Trust Co (Metrobank) dipped by 45 pesos, or 7.5 percent, to 555 pesos in mid-trade on Thursday on foreign selling as brokers said the Philippines is once again being compared with Thailand.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a reaction to what is happening in Thailand, rumours of a possible devaluation of the baht. People are concerned about possible attacks on the peso and on the exposure of banks,&quot; said Dennis Rayala, research head at Abacus Securities Corp.</p>
<p>On Wednesday there was speculation that the baht will be devalued.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's the parallel (drawn) to Thailand,&quot; said Nathan Lozada, assistant vice-president at Philippine Asia Equity.</p>
<p>Earlier on Thursday, the Philippine Central Bank raised overnight interest rates by 0.75 percentage points to 12 percent.</p>
<p>The Bank said it was prepared to boost interest rates again to protect the peso. It said the rise in overnight rates was a preemptive move in case there is any spillover from the problems in Thailand.</p>
<p>Metrobank was the most heavily-traded issue at mid-session with turnover of 140.36 million pesos.</p>
<p>The bank led several blue chips in dragging the Manila stock market main index down two percent in mid-session.</p>
<p>-- MANILA NEWSROOM (63 2) 841-8939 Fax 817-6267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
