<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="588688" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks seen cautious on lingering baht worry.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks seen cautious on lingering baht worry.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>After plunging to near eight-year lows on Wednesday, Thai stocks were expected to remain cautious on Thursday with continued foreign selling likely on persistent concerns about the battered baht, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be some hangover from the foreign sell-off yesterday,&quot; said one broker at local house. &quot;The market would remain fragile as the baht remains under selling pressure in the foreign exchange market.&quot;</p>
<p>The Thai baht firmed early on Thursday after intervention on Wednesday to defend the currency. But selling pressure still persists in the market, traders said.  </p>
<p>The baht was quoted at 25.910/25.940 early against the dollar versus 26.330/26.430 in late trade on Wednesday. The Bank of Thailand fixed the mid-rate at 25.81 to the dollar against 25.85 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Bank of Thailand on Wednesday teamed up with the Monetary Authority of Singapore to intervene in the Singapore market to stabilise the baht.</p>
<p>The SET index tumbled 28.94 points or 4.82 percent to close at 571.30 on economic worries and baht jitters. Turnover amounted to 6.6 billion baht trade.</p>
<p>-- Anuchit Nguyen (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
