<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="588761" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Thailand to fight currency speculation -- Amnuay.</title>
<headline>Thailand to fight currency speculation -- Amnuay.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand will defend its currency against attacks in the market by currency speculators, Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are determined to fight speculation,&quot; Amnuay told an international conference on Asia, in response to a question about speculative moves in the Thai currency.  </p>
<p>On Wednesday, the Bank of Thailand and the Monetary Authority of Singapore intervened in the Singapore market to stabilise the baht after the Thai currency fell to 26.250-26.300 to the U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>Amnuay also told the conference that the Thai economy is in a process of recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in a process of recovery,&quot; he said. &quot;We are through the worst, but there is much left to do,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Thai economy is in its worst shape in 10 years, with gross domestic product projected to expand about five to six percent this year, after 6.7 percent in 1996 and 8.6 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>Amnuay also dismissed questions about a possible devaluation of the currency. &quot;That's a silly question,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>He said that currency instability was due partly to dollar/yen fluctuations and partly to speculators trying to take advantage of such moves.</p>
<p>&quot;We are determined to fight speculation. I repeat we are determined to fight speculation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Referring to the Thai economy, he said the economy had gone through its worst, but much was still to be done. &quot;You can't solve economic ills in a few weeks or months.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he was pleased with many economic indicators, especially the drastic decline in the current account deficit and the decline in inflation, adding that exports looked to be improving.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had some financial sector problems that would make the recovery process perhaps slow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe some measures we have launched have had some positive effects and we will be able to resolve the problems in the near future.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked about regional financial cooperation, he said: &quot;Concerted action on the part of member countries in the region will be needed because of the magnitude of the flow of funds in the region.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
