<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="588760" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Bank of Thailand urges market to ignore baht rumours.</title>
<headline>Bank of Thailand urges market to ignore baht rumours.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Thailand urged investors to ignore rumours in the market of a possible devaluation of the baht, and repeated its stance that it would not change the currency exchange mechanism.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank would like to ask the private sector to have confidence in the government policy and not to listen to the rumours,&quot; the bank said in a statement received on Thursday. &quot;To listen to the rumours would be supporting speculators who like to destroy confidence and the stability of the country.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank wishes to stress that there would be no devaluation or changes in the currency exchange mechanism which were mentioned by rumors.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;(On Wednesday) there was fierce speculation on the baht in the overseas market,&quot; the statement said. &quot;At present the situation has eased to a certain degree. The Bank of Thailand has closely followed and solved the problem in both the value of the baht and the liquidity of the money market system.&quot;</p>
<p>On Wednesday the central bank and the Monetary Authority of Singapore jointly intervened in the foreign exchange market to defend the baht.</p>
<p>The Thai central bank said the intervention was meant to protect against speculation on the currency and to preserve the stability of the Thai and regional money markets.</p>
<p>The Thai baht was firmer in early dealings on Thursday, with the bid/ask around 25.870/25.900 compared with around 26.330/26.430 in late dealings on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
