<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="588938" id="root" date="1997-05-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FOCUS - UPM-Kymmene Q1 profit dips.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - UPM-Kymmene Q1 profit dips.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's largest forestry group UPM-Kymmene Oy on Thursday reported a dip in first-quarter profits in line with market expectations, but voiced a more cautious view on full-year prospects than some rivals.</p>
<p>Profit before extraordinary items and tax fell two percent to 1.35 billion markka from 1.37 billion in the year-ago period -- a less sharp fall than reported by some of its rivals. UPM said it expected 1997 earnings to be about the same as 1996.</p>
<p>It then made a profit before extras and tax of 3.6 billion markka and operating profit of 5.6 billion.</p>
<p>UPM-Kymmene's outlook contrasted with an expected improvement in full-year earnings from Finland's Metsa-Serla and a generally upbeat market view from Sweden's AssiDoman, which both reported earlier this week.</p>
<p>UPM's net sales in Q1 dipped to 13.09 billion markka from 13.27 billion in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Analysts' median forecast for UPM-Kymmene's Q1 profit had been 1.35 billion markka in a 952 million to 1.58 billion range.</p>
<p>Overall, UPM-Kymmene said strong economic growth in Europe would underpin an increase in paper consumption, but it voiced fears of overcapacity in fine paper in the second half.</p>
<p>&quot;Sales prices for printing and writing papers are expected to rise, although only marginally during the first half of the year,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>In fine paper, it said European production capacity threatened to rise faster than demand in the second half.</p>
<p>&quot;Market pulp prices probably bottomed out in April,&quot; UPM-Kymmene said.</p>
<p>Overall paper stocks held by customers and distributors were &quot;estimated to be about normal&quot;, the company said.</p>
<p>Demand for most of its packaging materials and special products was expected to remain strong, and UPM-Kymmene said good demand for sawn timber and plywood was likely to continue.</p>
<p>Engineering group Rauma, in which UPM's holding will fall to around 35 percent after an offering by UPM, had increased its orderbooks and received more new orders in Q1 1997 than in the year-ago period, UPM said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
