<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589295" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-WOODS SHARES LEAD AFTER TWO ROUNDS IN TEXAS.</title>
<headline>GOLF-WOODS SHARES LEAD AFTER TWO ROUNDS IN TEXAS.</headline>
<dateline>IRVING, Texas 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tiger Woods, in his first tournament since winning the Masters five weeks ago, dusted off his clubs and took a share of the second-round lead at the $1.8 million Byron Nelson Classic on Friday.</p>
<p>Woods had just 13 putts in the first 11 holes on his way to a six-under-par 64 in benign morning conditions on the short Cottonwood Valley course.</p>
<p>&quot;My swing's kind of iffy, but my putting is what carried me through,&quot; said Woods, who used his driver just five times.</p>
<p>He was joined at 12-under 128 by fellow-American Lee Rinker, who birdied the final three holes for a 63 at Cottonwood Valley.</p>
<p>They were one stroke ahead of Mike Standly, who shot 63 on the more demanding Las Colinas TPC host course.</p>
<p>There was a sense of something special in the air when Woods birdied seven of the first 11 holes, which left him needing to pick up just four more strokes in the final seven holes to become only the third player to break 60 on the PGA Tour.</p>
<p>However, Woods, 21, said later that he never once thought such a scenario was likely, perhaps because he was not happy with his long game.</p>
<p>And he pointed out that when he shot 59 in practice at Isleworth, his home course in Florida recently, he had been 10 under through nine holes.</p>
<p>With his round at Cottonwood out of the way, he was looking forward to returning to the TPC for the final two rounds: &quot;You can be a little more aggressive off the tee at the TPC, because it doesn't have the severity in the doglegs that Cottonwood has,&quot; he said. &quot;I hit a lot of two irons and three woods off the tees today.&quot;</p>
<p>Since going four over par after nine holes of the first round at the Masters, Woods is 34 under for the past 99 holes. (He was 22 under the last 63 holes at Augusta National).</p>
<p>Barely eight months after turning professional, there is little argument he is the world's best player, even if this is not yet reflected in his current world ranking of fifth.</p>
<p>The less-heralded Rinker, meanwhile, earned a chance to play with Woods in the third round.</p>
<p>&quot;The last two days the putter has come around,&quot; said Rinker, 36, who last year finished 111th on the money list.</p>
<p>The cut fell at two-under 138, and among those to miss it were last week's Atlanta Classic runner-up David Duval and two-time 1997 PGA Tour winner Mark O'Meara.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="IRVING, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
