<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589598" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Placer faces Kazakh claim, slim risk seen.</title>
<headline>Placer faces Kazakh claim, slim risk seen.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Kazakhstan government has made a counterclaim against Placer Dome Inc for US$270 million before an arbitration panel considering a dispute between them, but analysts on Friday saw little chance of Kazakhstan prevailing.</p>
<p>Placer has been trying to recover a US$35 million deposit paid to the Kazakhstan government for the Vasilkovskoye gold project. Placer in 1995 decided to drop the project and said its deposit should have been refunded.</p>
<p>An accord between Placer and the government stipulated that any disputes would be put to a London arbitration panel. That panel is now weighing submissions by the two sides.</p>
<p>A Placer spokesman said Friday that Kazakhstan submitted its arguments to the panel about two months ago. It contended then that instead of owing Placer money, Placer should pay Kazakhstan US$270 million. That amount is what the Canadian company would have paid if it went ahead with the Vasilkovskoye project.</p>
<p>Placer contends the Kazakhstan claim is far-fetched and several mining analysts agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;What a load of rubbish,&quot; said one Toronto analyst, who asked not to be identified, about the Kazakhstan claim.</p>
<p>&quot;Kazakhstan is trying to build a wall of defense, saying we'll sue you. But I don't put much value on what Kazakhstan says. Look at who is out money over this matter, and that is Placer.&quot;</p>
<p>Placer Dome stock was done 0.60 at 25.30 on the Toronto Stock Exchange. Analysts said a front-page article about the Kazakhstan claim in Canada's Financial Post newspaper alarmed some investors.</p>
<p>((Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
