<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589627" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Facts about Zaire.</title>
<headline>Facts about Zaire.</headline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire, a sprawling but volatile republic strategically placed at the heart of Africa, is potentially one of the continent's richest nations.</p>
<p>Blessed with vast mineral wealth, fertile soil and rivers able to generate enough power to light up the whole continent, its more than 40 million people from numerous ethnic groups should be the envy of their neighbours.</p>
<p>But a combination of rampant corruption, administrative chaos and bitter ethnic and political rivalry have made them among the poorest on the world's poorest continent.</p>
<p>At the height of the 19th century European Scramble for Africa, what became Zaire caught the eye of Belgian King Leopold, who duped rivals into thinking his intentions were humanitarian and turned it into a private commercial monopoly.</p>
<p>The huge nation straddling three time zones has lurched from one crisis to another since independence from Belgium in 1960.</p>
<p>Veteran strongman Mobutu Sese Seko, taking advantage of superpower rivaly, ruled virtually unchallenged from 1965 until a combination of foreign and domestic forced him to embrace multi-party politics in 1990.</p>
<p>Elections, repeatedly postponed, were promised by July 1997.</p>
<p>Mobutu, presenting himself as the one symbol of national unity in a nation where individual regions such as copper-rich Shaba and diamond-rich Kasai enjoyed de facto autonomy, had planned to stand.</p>
<p>But prostate cancer surgery in Europe in August 1996 and a revolt by Tutsi-dominated rebels who took up arms in October have weakened his grip on Africa's third largest nation.</p>
<p>He had recently said he would not take part in the elections. On Friday, it was announced in Kinshasa that Mobutu had left the government in charge of national policy, but would retain his title as head of state.</p>
<p>Rebels, led by Laurent Kabila, control three quarters of Zaire, including its economic heartland with its diamonds, copper, cobalt and gold.</p>
<p>Some key facts about Zaire:</p>
<p>* A Belgian colony that became independent in 1960</p>
<p>* Africa's third largest country after Sudan and Algeria</p>
<p>* Spectacular rivers -- the mighty Zaire (Congo) River is</p>
<p>the world's eighth longest -- dissect tropical rainforest,</p>
<p>plateaux, savannas and mountains.</p>
<p>* Its population is 43.8 million (U.N. 1995 estimate)</p>
<p>* Its capital is Kinshasa, which has five million people</p>
<p>* Most Zaireans are nominally Christian, half Roman</p>
<p>Catholics</p>
<p>* Its official language is French, its main local tongue</p>
<p>Lingala</p>
<p>* Its currency is the new zaire</p>
<p>* Diamonds, copper, cobalt, gold and others minerals</p>
<p>are its main source of wealth</p>
<p>* 19th century explorer Henry Morton Stanley, who won fame</p>
<p>tracing missing missionary David Livingstone in the</p>
<p>African jungle, spearheaded European colonisation of what</p>
<p>became modern-day Zaire</p>
<p>* English novelist Joseph Conrad based his bleak classic</p>
<p>&quot;Heart of Darkness&quot; on its river and jungles</p>
<p>* The deadly Ebola virus is named after a river there</p>
<p>* Latin American revolutionary Che Guevara fought there</p>
<p>briefly with rebels, including Laurent Kabila, in the</p>
<p>1960s. He left questioning their revolutionary resolve.</p>
<p>* U.N. Secretary-General Dag Hammarskjoeld died in mystery</p>
<p>plane crash in neighbouring Zambia in 1961 while trying</p>
<p>to help ease Zaire's independence birth pangs</p>
<p>* Its musicians and music -- the late Franco and his Okay</p>
<p>Jazz rumba rhythms at the forefront -- are renowned</p>
<p>throughout Africa</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
