<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589606" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>LIBERIA: Liberian leaders meet Nigerian ruler on elections.</title>
<headline>Liberian leaders meet Nigerian ruler on elections.</headline>
<dateline>ABUJA 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Liberian warlords on Friday began talks with Nigerian military ruler General Sani Abacha to decide when to hold Liberia's presidential and legislative elections, originally scheduled for May 30.</p>
<p>Abacha told the gathering of about 100 Liberians that there was a limit to how much sacrifice West African nations could make to maintain peace in their country.</p>
<p>&quot;It must be appreciated that the sacrifices which these countries have made in the interest of peace and stability in our sub-region and in the finest spirit of African brotherhood should not be over-stretched,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The May date was part of a peace plan brokered in Abuja last August by the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS), of which Abacha is chairman, and backed by the Nigerian-led African peacekeeping force ECOMOG.</p>
<p>Most of the Liberian leaders have called for a postponement for security reasons and lack of voter education.</p>
<p>&quot;May 30 now looks impossible but we on our part are looking at the end of June,&quot; said an aide to former warlord Charles Taylor, who launched the Liberian civil war in 1989 and is a leading presidential candidate.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a consensus on a date but the delay should not be too long because Liberia needs a president as soon as possible to lead the nation,&quot; the Taylor aide told Reuters.</p>
<p>Nigerian officials said the talks were being attended by the presidential candidate and chairman of each of the 16 political parties in Liberia, the West African country founded by freed American slaves in 1847.</p>
<p>Fifteen of the parties, except Taylor's National Patriotic Front of Liberia (NPFL), have asked for the polls to be delayed until August or September to ensure credible results.</p>
<p>Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf, the only woman among the presidential candidates, told reporters in Lagos this week that all parties except Taylor's NPFL felt May 30 was not feasible logistically.</p>
<p>&quot;Before too long we will be in a position to make formal pronouncements on those issues of concern to you particularly regarding the date fixed for the election,&quot; Abacha said.</p>
<p>Abacha will next week host a meeting of the ECOWAS Committee of Nine on Liberia to decide finally whether to shift the polls.</p>
<p>Apart from killing more than 150,000 people, the Liberian civil war now ended by ECOMOG displaced half the pre-war population of 2.5 million.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of Liberians are refugees in neighbouring Ivory Coast, Guinea and Sierra Leone. Others are in Ghana and Nigeria.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABUJA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LIBERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
