<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589619" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHAD: Chad government resigns.</title>
<headline>Chad government resigns.</headline>
<dateline>N'DJAMENA 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chad's prime minister, Djimasta Koibla, and his government tendered their resignation on Friday and President Idriss Deby accepted it, officials said.</p>
<p>The move followed the decision of Deby's southern rival, General Wadal Abdelkader Kamougue, on May 8 to rally to the president in the name of national unity.</p>
<p>Officials said Deby would nominate a new prime minister in due course.</p>
<p>Parliament elected Kamougue speaker of the 125-seat national assembly on May 9. &quot;I have accepted to manage the country with President Idriss Deby to preserve democratic gains, unity and peace in Chad, which is still a fragile country,&quot; Kamougue after rallying to Deby.</p>
<p>Deby's Patriotic Salvation Movement (MPS) party won an 63-seat absolute majority in parliament in January and February elections. Kmougue's Union for Renewal and Democracy (URD) came second, picking up 29 seats.</p>
<p>Deby, a former guerrilla leader from the Moslem north, seized power in a 1990 French-backed coup after decades of civil war or conflict with Libya. After repeated electoral delays, he won a multi-party presidential poll in July.</p>
<p>Chad, one of the world's poorest countries, has discovered significant reserves of oil in the predominantly Christian south and north of Lake Chad.</p>
<p>The government has reached preliminary agreement with foreign oil companies on exploiting the oil and also envisages a pipeline to a sea terminal in Cameroon. Chad is landlocked.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHAD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="N'DJAMENA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHAD"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
