<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589609" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire's Mobutu, facing rebel threat, leaves capital.</title>
<headline>Zaire's Mobutu, facing rebel threat, leaves capital.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Hamilton</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's President Mobutu Sese Seko left the capital Kinshasa on Friday for his stronghold of Gbadolite where he was expected to make an announcement on the Zaire crisis, political and diplomatic sources said.</p>
<p>His departure followed talks with army chiefs who told him they could not defend the capital against Laurent Kabila's advancing rebel forces and that he should leave for his own safety, they said.</p>
<p>Earlier, the U.S.-based television network CNN reported from Kinshasa:</p>
<p>&quot;A close associate of President Mobutu told us that the Zairean leader is headed to the northern Zairean town of Gbadolite where he will remain while, the aide says, the Zairean government and the rebels continue to discuss a South African peace proposal for a peaceful transition here in Zaire.&quot;</p>
<p>CNN, quoting a reliable diplomatic source, later reported that the Gbadolite stop would be a short one and that Mobutu would continue on to Morocco and exile.</p>
<p>A senior parliamentary source in Kinshasa also raised the possibility that Cairo would be Mobutu's first stop.</p>
<p>A close Mobutu family member said that members of Mobutu's entourage were told on Thursday night to pack their bags and be ready to leave Kinshasa by dawn on Friday morning.</p>
<p>There was no immediate rebel comment.</p>
<p>Although there was no official confirmation of Mobutu's departure, as word of the reports spread through the streets of the capital opponents of his regime expressed cautious satisfaction.</p>
<p>&quot;We are waiting for confirmation but if he has left we are very, very happy. Zaire can get a new beginning. He's done nothing for this country. We are waiting now for Kabila. We hope there has been an agreement to avoid bloodshed,&quot; Blaise Bomba, a member of the unofficial opposition &quot;street parliament,&quot; said.</p>
<p>Mobutu, 66, who reputedly amassed a huge personal fortune over the years, seized power in 1965. Western powers supported him as a Cold War bastion against Soviet communism.</p>
<p>The rebels, who took up arms in October demanding Zairean nationality for ethnic Tutsis, now control three-quarters of the impoverished, corruption-plagued nation.</p>
<p>Kabila flew home to Lubumbashi from South Africa on Friday after agreeing in talks with South African President Nelson Mandela to give Mobutu until Monday to study peace proposals.</p>
<p>Presidential spokesman Parks Mankahlana said Mandela would move from Cape Town to Johannesburg on Friday and would keep in touch from there with all parties involved in efforts to avert a battle for control of the Zairean capital.</p>
<p>Mandela has consulted regularly with African leaders and the British, U.S. and French governments in his efforts to avert a military showdown in Kinshasa between Mobutu's government forces and Kabila's rebel army.</p>
<p>Mobutu has agreed to hand over to an elected successor, but Kabila has insisted on an immediate transfer of power to his alliance.</p>
<p>Kabila refused at the last moment to attend talks with Mobutu in Congo on Wednesday, but flew to Cape Town on Thursday to be briefed by Mandela on meetings the South African negotiators had with the ailing Zairean president.</p>
<p>Kabila told the news conference on Thursday: &quot;We shall wait until Monday to receive another answer from the Mobutu side.&quot; Asked if he would halt his rebel advance on the capital Kinshasa, Kabila said: &quot;I have nothing to say about it.&quot;</p>
<p>Mankahlana said the two-page peace plan that Mandela took to Congo for Wednesday's aborted meeting with Mobutu and Kabila was still part of the peace process.</p>
<p>South African public radio said the proposal included a commitment by Mobutu to resign after 32 years in power within 24 hours of signing the accord.</p>
<p>It also called for a transitional authority to rule Zaire, Africa's third largest country, until democratic elections can be organised.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
