<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589716" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia seen to have 4 pct yr/yr GDP growth in Dec.</title>
<headline>Russia seen to have 4 pct yr/yr GDP growth in Dec.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia could see four percent growth year-on-year by December this year, but taking the average of monthly gross domestic product (GDP), growth for the year as a whole would be flat, a government economic adviser said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;If we talk about year-on-year growth then we expect growth will be about zero,&quot; Yevsey Gurvich, an analyst with the Ministry of Finance Economic Expert Group, told a news briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;And with about zero percent growth year on year we're expecting a growth of about four percent December on December.&quot;</p>
<p>The four percent growth in December reflects both a forecast upturn in the second half of the year and the statistical impact of a sharp decline in late 1996.</p>
<p>The analysis is in line with an earlier estimate by an Economy Ministry official who said Russia would see growth over the course of the year in the economy, but overall GDP growth would be flat.</p>
<p>Government officials have forecast GDP growth of about two percent since early in the year, but while figures from the State Statistics Committee show a turnaround in the economy, analysts have been wary of hailing it as economic growth.</p>
<p>Official figures show GDP grew 0.2 percent year-on-year in the first quarter of 1997, but statisticians said an increase of this order could not be counted as proper economic growth, while analysts query the accuracy of the numbers themselves.</p>
<p>Some economists say the committee increased the weighting given this year to the booming unofficial or &quot;shadow&quot; economy in calculating GDP without making the same changes to last year's figures.</p>
<p>But Aleksei Ponomarenko, deputy head of the committee's department for national accounts, said although the 1996 figures were being revised, the results would not change significantly.</p>
<p>The growth now being registered was due to recovery in the official economy, not just the shadow sector, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to emphasise you cannot attribute the change in the tendency of development in the Russian economy solely to informal production,&quot; Ponomarenko said.</p>
<p>&quot;The main thing is that the trend has changed in the ordinary, official production. The economy is really beginning to come alive.&quot;</p>
<p>He said April year-on-year GDP growth would be flat.</p>
<p>--Christina Ling, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
