<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589740" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin pieces together Russian security jigsaw.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin pieces together Russian security jigsaw.</headline>
<byline>Timothy Heritage</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin has put together two important pieces of a security jigsaw this week which he hopes will increase stability in Russia and improve the climate for economic reforms.</p>
<p>Yeltsin signed a peace treaty with the separatist Chechnya region on Monday. Two days later, Moscow reached an agreement with NATO Intended to protect Russian interests as the Western defence alliance expands eastwards.</p>
<p>Other pieces in the jigsaw are also falling into place. Yeltsin is due next week to sign a treaty on deeper integration with Belarus, and he hailed a new era in relations after a summit with China's president in Moscow last month.</p>
<p>&quot;It may be coincidence that these moves are all at once but it is part of a general pattern to secure long-term Russian interests in relationships with various centres of power,&quot; said Andrei Piontkovsky, head of Moscow's Strategic Studies Centre.</p>
<p>&quot;We see Russia is very vulnerable going into the 21st century and it is important not to be the ally of just one of these centres of power.&quot;</p>
<p>Defence and political analysts doubt all these moves are part of a carefully conceived plan and say it is probably coincidence that they are happening simultaneously.</p>
<p>But they say They reflect a trend in Russian diplomacy of non-confrontation and forging alliances on all fronts rather than with just one main partner.</p>
<p>The peace treaty signed on Monday with mainly Moslem Chechnya builds on a truce signed last August after nearly 21 months of conflict, but also has the additional benefit of helping keep relations with Moslem countries on track.</p>
<p>Wednesday's deal with NATO, expected to be signed on May 27, sweetens ties with the West and is designed to reduce tensions as the alliance takes in members from the former Soviet bloc.</p>
<p>Closer links with China reduce the risk of instability in Russia's Far East and offer a strategic alliance which could be particularly useful if ties with the West go sour over NATO enlargement, despite Wednesday's agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;The NATO deal shows Moscow's concern to prevent ties with the West getting worse but Russia also sees a need to improve cooperation with China as a balance,&quot; said Alexander Zhilin, defence analyst for the Moscow News newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chechnya deal, although I would not link it with foreign policy, is also aimed at getting stability in Russia.&quot;</p>
<p>Stability in Russia is a much-sought ingredient which would provide a better environment for reforms.</p>
<p>Peace in Chechnya has clear economic benefits. The conflict there discouraged foreign investors and sucked money out of Russia's state coffers.</p>
<p>Chechnya is an oil-refining centre, already has a pipeline running through it and is a possible transit point for future pipelines carrying oil through that part of southern Russia.</p>
<p>The deal with NATO also has some side effects which could benefit the economy. Russia has used negotiations during the debate over NATO expansion to boost its chances of joining economic organisations such as the Group of Seven industrial powers and the Paris Club of foreign creditors.</p>
<p>Other thoughts may be at the back of Yeltsin's mind as he tries to increase stability and push through reforms.</p>
<p>Under the constitution he cannot seek re-election when his four-year second term expires in 2000 and he has made clear he wants to down in history as a &quot;builder&quot; of peace and reforms rather the man who helped destroy the Soviet Union in 1991.</p>
<p>Peace with Chechnya, an unprecedented partnership with NATO and rapprochement China could all fit the bill. Union with Belarus, a former Soviet republic, is a particularly good chance for Yeltsin to improve his popularity with nostalgic Russians.</p>
<p>&quot;He sees this as his 'big achievement' and a chance to reverse the tide of disintegration associated with his role in the break-up of the Soviet Union,&quot; Trenin said.</p>
<p>How successful or lasting each of the agreements or partnerships will be remains in question. The NATO deal appears to leave some military issues vague and problems could still emerge as NATO expansion starts.</p>
<p>Relations with China are improving but neither side wants more than a strategic alliance.</p>
<p>The Chechnya peace deal does not solve the main dispute over the region's demands for independence, which Moscow has ruled out, and the danger of attacks on Russian towns by radical separatists remains.</p>
<p>Even in ties with Slav neighbour Belarus, signs of disagreement have started to appear over the union treaty due to be signed by Yeltsin and President Alexander Lukashenko.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
