<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589748" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin to challenge trophy art bill in court - TASS.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin to challenge trophy art bill in court - TASS.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin will challenge in constitutional court a bill asserting Russia's ownership of art seized from Germany at the end of World War Two, Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin said on Friday.</p>
<p>Itar-Tass news agency quoted Chernomyrdin as warning that the law, should it come into force, could encourage other countries not to give back Russian art taken away during the war.</p>
<p>&quot;One should not forget that not only are we expected to return trophy art treasures to other countries but other countries have to return to us far more of our treasures,&quot; said Chernomyrdin.</p>
<p>In March Yeltsin vetoed the legislation, which says trophy art acquired by Russia during World War Two and immediately afterwards was compensation for its huge wartime losses and as such could not be returned to the original owners.</p>
<p>The State Duma lower house and then the Federation Council upper chamber of parliament rallied enough votes to overrule the presidential veto.</p>
<p>Germany has said it wants back some trophy art seized by the Soviet Union in the end of World War Two including a rare Gutenberg Bible and paintings by impressionists Claude Monet and Henri Matisse.</p>
<p>But many Russians argue the artworks were fair compensation for the losses during the war in which Nazi Germany destroyed or took away much art from Russia.</p>
<p>About 27 million Soviet citizens were killed in the war too.</p>
<p>On Thursday Chernomyrdin expressed hope that Germany would hand over a newly-discovered fragment of the Amber Chamber, a tsarist treasure seized by the Nazis during the war and recently discovered by police in the German town of Potsdam.</p>
<p>&quot;If we don't give away the booty we will get nothing back,&quot; Tass quoted Chernomyrdin as saying in Kaliningrad, in what used to be the German territory of East Prussia which Moscow absorbed at the end of World War Two.</p>
<p>After the Federation Councils made public results of a postal ballot overruling the veto on Wednesday, Yeltsin faced the choice of signing the act into law within seven days or challenging it in the Constitutional Court.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin did not say when Yeltsin would formally file the appeal with the court, whose ruling would be final.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
