<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589866" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Ex-Venezuela official calls for early elections.</title>
<headline>Ex-Venezuela official calls for early elections.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Venezuelan Attorney General Jesus Petit Da Costa said on Friday presidential elections should be brought forward to avoid a political crisis in the event of President Rafael Caldera's death.</p>
<p>It was the first time a leading political figure had spoken publicly of the possibility that the 81-year-old statesman might not complete his five-year term.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot wait until February 1999 without exposing ourselves to the risk of President Caldera's illness or death precipitating a political crisis,&quot; Da Costa told a news conference.</p>
<p>Da Costa, who resigned as attorney general in February citing differences with members of Caldera's cabinet of ministers, said that as well as suffering from ill health, the president's popularity had plummeted and his fragile support in Congress had disintegrated.</p>
<p>Stuttering economic growth and Latin America's highest inflation rates have seen Caldera's popularity drop from over 70 percent when he started his second term in February 1994 to under 30 percent in the latest opinion polls.</p>
<p>Once an energetic and rousing speaker, Caldera has appeared increasing frail and stiff in recent months, creating much speculation about his health. Government officials insist the president could not be more fit.</p>
<p>Da Costa said elections should be moved from December 1998 to later this year to name a successor who could take over should Caldera die or resign.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not proposing that President Caldera quit, what I'm proposing is simply that we elect his successor in advance,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The president of Venezuela's Supreme Electoral Council, Enrique Yespica, said Da Costa's proposal was impossible under the existing Constitution and cast doubt on the allegations of Caldera's ill health.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think President Caldera is an any way unwell,&quot; Yespica said.</p>
<p>Presidential palace officials could not be reached for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
