<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589879" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil's Cardoso defends his government as honest.</title>
<headline>Brazil's Cardoso defends his government as honest.</headline>
<byline>William Schomberg</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-05-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian President Fernando Henrique Cardoso, facing his biggest corruption scandal, said on Thursday his government was an honest one and called for a thorough investigation of an alleged cash-for-votes scam.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no danger. The government is calm. The government is honest,&quot; Cardoso said. &quot;I would never take part...in this type of foul play. If there was any, and there could have been, it did not involve the government.&quot;</p>
<p>Newspaper Folha de Sao Paulo rocked the Brazilian capital and financial markets this week with reports suggesting Communications Minister Sergio Motta bought the votes of lawmakers for a bill allowing Cardoso to stand for re-election.</p>
<p>Folha on Thursday published a transcript of a recorded conversations in which a lawmaker Ronivon Santiago allegedly tells an anonymous &quot;Mr X&quot; he was given a television concession for his vote.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, Folha quoted Santiago as saying he was paid $188,000 in cash for his vote. The lawmaker admitted on Wednesday he made the comments but said he had been &quot;joking.&quot;</p>
<p>Motta, a close friend of Cardoso and the most influential member of his cabinet, denied the allegations. In a statement he said the reports were &quot;absurd, untruthful and, I would say, surreal.&quot;</p>
<p>The re-election bill was approved in the Chamber of Deputies in January in what was considered the biggest political victory of the Cardoso administration. It was due to be put to a first of two votes in the Senate next week and would allow presidents, state governors and mayors to run for a second consecutive term.</p>
<p>Cardoso, whose comments were broadcast by the government's radio network Radiobras, said he was confident an ongoing inquiry in Congress would get to the bottom of the allegations.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever happened, it is up to Congress...to punish and to punish in an exemplary manner,&quot; the president told reporters as he arrived in the city of Belo Horizonte for a meeting of trade ministers from across the Americas.</p>
<p>About 400 students outside the meeting blew whistles and chanted slogans comparing this week's crisis to a 1992 corruption scandal that toppled former president Fernando Collor.</p>
<p>The Sao Paulo stock exchange began recovering Thursday from a fall of more than three percent on Wednesday, when Motta was first linked to the alleged scandal. But shares fell again in the afternoon on rumors that further allegations were being prepared by the media, traders said.</p>
<p>The internal inquiry in Congress was due to announce its findings next week. Left-wing opposition parties are seeking to set up a wider-ranging congressional probe, a move the government fears could paralize its reform drive.</p>
<p>The Workers Party also asked Brazil's highest court, the Supreme Federal Tribunal, to advise on whether Motta could be charged immediately with corruption.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
