<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589805" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech cbank says to keep current exchange policy.</title>
<headline>Czech cbank says to keep current exchange policy.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech National Bank (CNB) said on Friday that it would stick to its current exchange rate policy and that the exchange rate was manageable within the current +/-7.5 percent fluctuation band.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still keeping our exchange rate policy, it means to maintain the exchange rate within the fluctuation band,&quot; CNB Vice-governor Jan Vit told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We still think that the proper level of the exchange rate is within the fluctuation band, and we are using our own instruments including intervention to keep it in,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Vit confirmed that the CNB had intervened on the market for the second consecutive day on Friday to support the crown, but that it was only &quot;small amounts&quot;. &quot;The pressure on the crown is not so strong as the day before,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said  the central bank was not considering implementing a crawling peg for the crown at this time.</p>
<p>Late on Thursday the CNB said it had decided to raise its repo rate, but had not set a target for how much it would rise, instead allowing &quot;market conditions&quot; to be the determining factor.</p>
<p>Early on Friday the CNB then announced a one-week repo tender at 12.9 percent, up from 12.4 percent.</p>
<p>Vit said the move was made to allow the repo rate to more reflect the market and that if the central bank had kept its previous rate, &quot;it would be under market and not supporting our aims in today's situation&quot;.</p>
<p>Dealers said they thought the move was far too little to provide any real support for the crown.</p>
<p>Just before the repo rate change, the crown was trading at 3.84 percent on the depreciation side of its dollar/mark basket parity. After the announcement, the crown slipped to -3.93 percent. At 1030 GMT the crown was trading at -3.91 percent.</p>
<p>-- Alan Crosby, Prague Newsroom, 420-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
