<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589977" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine sanctions may end soon - US Commerce Sect..</title>
<headline>Argentine sanctions may end soon - US Commerce Sect..</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Commerce Secretary William Daley said Friday Washington may soon lift trade sanctions on some Argentine products on which countervailing duties have been clamped.</p>
<p>&quot;A preliminary review by .... the Department of Commerce has recommended the rescission of those,&quot; Daley told a news conference on the second day of a three-day visit. &quot;That will be final shortly.&quot;</p>
<p>Argentina has been saying for weeks that the United States would soon revoke countervailing duties on imports of Argentine wool, hides, seamles steel tubes and rolled steel.  </p>
<p>Thursday evening Argentine Economy Minister Roque Fernandez said Daley told him the sanctions may be lifted soon but gave no precise dates.</p>
<p>Daley also said he expected a U.S. announcement soon on the possible approval of a 20,000-tonne annual import quota of Argentine beef.</p>
<p>Argentine beef has been denied access for decades to major markets because of its problems with foot-and-mouth disease, but international health authorities are due to declare the country free of the desease within the next few weeks.</p>
<p>Daley said President Bill Clinton had told his Agriculture Secretary last year to give a review of policy on Argentine beef imports &quot;a very very high priority&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I am hopeful that in the very near future there will be an announcement,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Daley met Thursday Foreign Minister Guido Di Tella and President Carlos Menem. He flies back home on Saturday.</p>
<p>((--Jason Webb, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541-318-0695))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
