<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="589991" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil govt popularity falls on votes scandal-poll.</title>
<headline>Brazil govt popularity falls on votes scandal-poll.</headline>
<byline>Simona de Logu</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A newspaper poll shows the popularity of President Fernando Henrique Cardoso's government has dropped seven percentage points due to a cash-for-votes scandal involving Communications Minister Sergio Motta.</p>
<p>Folha de Sao Paulo, which broke news of the alleged vote buying scheme in an exclusive front-page story Tuesday, said a poll of Sao Paulo residents showed that the government's approval rating has fallen to 34 percent from 41 percent before the scandal.  </p>
<p>Of the 1,080 people interviewed, 42 percent thought the government's performance was average, 34 percent said it was good and 23 percent said it was bad.</p>
<p>The poll also found that 57 percent of those surveyed were in favor of Motta stepping down temporarily, 23 percent thought he should resign for good and 17 percent said Motta should continue in office.</p>
<p>Folha de Sao Paulo reported Tuesday that five deputies from the northern state of Acre allegedly had received money from the governors of Acre and Amazonas state so they would vote in favor of the re-election bill.  </p>
<p>The bill would allow Cardoso, and also state governors and mayors, to run for a second consecutive term.</p>
<p>On Wednesday and Thursday, Folha de Sao Paulo published allegations that Communications Minister Sergio Motta had helped provide the bribes offered to the lawmakers.</p>
<p>A Special Parliamentary Inquiry (CPI) to investigate the allegations was backed by 91 percent in the poll, and 64 percent thought congressional voting on the government's re-election bill should be put on hold, while 32 percent thought it should proceed as normal.  </p>
<p>Motta, an old friend of Cardoso's and the most influential member of his cabinet, has denied all accusations and said he would take legal steps against the allegations.</p>
<p>&quot;The transcript of the conversation does not contain a single real fact or a concrete accusation,&quot; Motta said in a statement Thursday, after the latest Folha report which cited secretly taped telephone conversations as its source.</p>
<p>&quot;The facts mentioned are absurd, untruthful and I would say, surreal,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Congress watchers say Motta's response to the newspaper reports has been uncharacteristically low key, perhaps to avoid further aggravation of an already tense situation.  But should new allegations surface, not even his special relationship with the president might be enough to save his job.</p>
<p>Cardoso has also defended his government, saying it was an honest one, and added that an ongoing congressional inquiry, due to report next week, would get to the bottom of allegations.</p>
<p>Left-wing opposition parties are seeking to set up a wider-ranging congressional probe, CPI -- a move the government fears could paralyze its reform drive.</p>
<p>Financial markets in Sao Paulo, which fell earlier this week on Folha's stories, were awash with rumors of new allegations late Thursday, traders said.</p>
<p>The re-election bill was approved in the Chamber of Deputies in January in what was considered the biggest political victory of the Cardoso administration.  It was due to be put to a first of two votes in the Senate next week.</p>
<p>((--Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 507 4151))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
