<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="590015" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine peso ends shade up on steep rate hike.</title>
<headline>Philippine peso ends shade up on steep rate hike.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>--------------------------- May 16 -------------------------</p>
<p>* Volume reaches record $655.5 million</p>
<p>------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The Philippine peso ended a shade up on Friday at 26.374 to the dollar from 26.375 after the Central Bank made a bold move to raise its overnight borrowing rate by seven percentage points to 20 percent, traders said.</p>
<p>The peso had reached a high of 26.368 in midsession on Friday after the rate hike. But speculators weakened the peso again in anticipation of a cut in the overnight rate.  </p>
<p>&quot;Foreign funds were already flowing in after the rate hike. There was no pressure on the exchange rate. So what do you need the 20 percent overnight rate for,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>The speculation prompted the Philippine Central Bank to say it was keeping its overnight borrowing rate at 20 percent to punish speculators.</p>
<p>The peso had been under attack due to the spillover effects of the crisis in the Thai baht. This forced the Central Bank to raise its overnight borrowing rate by a total of 8.75 percentage points in two days.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
