<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="590060" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Poor demand seen hitting Thai rubber exports.</title>
<headline>Poor demand seen hitting Thai rubber exports.</headline>
<byline>Anchalee Koetsawang</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bearish global demand and high stocks in major rubber consuming countries are set to hit Thai rubber exports this year while sliding prices will reduce earnings, a trade group said on Friday.</p>
<p>Thai 1997 rubber exports could drop to 1.6 million tonnes, below a target of 1.7 million tonnes and the 1.76 million tonnes exported in 1996, Wate Thainukul, manager of the Thai Rubber Association (TRA) told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The volume will drop, but the value will be even worse as the prices have been pressured by the bearish market condition since the beginning of the year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Although the exports performance projection for the first two quarters was poor, Wate said he expected the demand to pick up in the latter half of the year.</p>
<p>According to TRA's figures, rubber exports during the first quarter totalled 480,000 tonnes but were likely to drop to 270,000 tonnes in the second quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;The projection for the second quarter, which dropped more than 10 percent from the same period last year, actually reflected the real market situation during the first half of 1997,&quot; Wate said.</p>
<p>&quot;First quarter exports were in a way inflated because it was mostly the covering of last year's contracts,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But the association expected rubber exports in the second half of to pick up to 850,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;We see stock problems, especially in China, easing. We also expect demand in the US and Japan to improve during the later half of 1997,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;China overbought last year, resulting in a glut. Many said China's rubber imports this year will be close to that of last year. I have my doubt but hope that will be the case,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Japan is the biggest market for Thai rubber, representing 30-34 percent of the total Thai rubber exports, followed by China, the European Union, the United States and Malaysia.</p>
<p>Wate said government intervention was important to prop up prices as overall demand remained poor. The Thai government recently agreed to raise the intervention prices of grade-3 unsmoked sheet rubber to 29.00 baht from 27.50 baht. However, the scheme will last only until July.</p>
<p>&quot;The government should continue its intervention programme beyond July. If the exports this year fall short of target, the surplus of around 100,000 tonnes should be kept by the government in stock,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Since most Thai rubber producers are smallholders, one cannot manage supplies by asking them to cut production to prop up prices. Government help is therefore important,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Thailand's rubber output for 1997 is seen at 1.91 million tonnes, of which 193,800 tonnes will be used domestically.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
