<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="590166" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New York judge drops charges in Danish baby case.</title>
<headline>New York judge drops charges in Danish baby case.</headline>
<byline>Jeanne King</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A New York City judge on Friday dropped criminal charges against a Danish woman who was arrested and briefly jailed after leaving her baby parked in a stroller outside a Manhatten restaurant.</p>
<p>The case sparked trans-Atlantic debate after Danish actress Annette Sorensen was jailed for two days on Saturday and her 14-month-old baby put into foster care for four days in what her lawyer described as a &quot;clash of cultures.&quot;</p>
<p>Sorensen, 30, and the baby's American father, Exavier Wardlaw, left the baby outside an East Village restaurant while they were having a drink and watching her through the window, police said.</p>
<p>Passers-by, who said 14-month-old Liv was cold and crying, called police.</p>
<p>The mother's attorneys said Sorensen did not think twice about leaving the child outside the restaurant because it was common practice in Copenhagen and a Danish newspaper called on President Bill Clinton to apologise when he visits Denmark in July.</p>
<p>But city officials questioned the wisdom of being so trusting in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;Leaving a child unattended on a city street for an hour in New York seems to me pretty inappropriate,&quot; said Nicholas Scoppetta, head of the city's Administration of Children's Services.</p>
<p>Sorensen smiled at a crowd of waiting reporters as she left the Manhattan Criminal Court after Friday's hearing. Her baby, with whom she was reunited on Wednesday night, was not with her.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very happy for the result. I will now go home to my daughter and as soon as possible I will go home to Denmark,&quot; she said. She declined to comment when asked how she felt about her treatment by New York City police.</p>
<p>Under terms of the deal reached before Judge Michael Gross by her attorney, the Manhattan District Attorney and the Danish Consulate, the criminal charges of endangering the welfare of a child were dismissed and the case will be sealed in six months.</p>
<p>&quot;It is our belief that this was a clash of cultures and a lack of understanding,&quot; her attorney Todd Barnet said.</p>
<p>Sorensen still must appear in Family Court on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Her attorney says she has a plane ticket to leave the United States on May 27.</p>
<p>Sorensen had been in the United States less than 48 hours when her daughter was taken from her.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
