<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="590153" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gingrich defends new ethics deal, groups question it.</title>
<headline>Gingrich defends new ethics deal, groups question it.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>House Speaker Newt Gingrich said Friday his decision to pay much of a $300,000 ethics penalty from his own pocket should finally silence critics who had accused him of trying to wriggle out of the fine.</p>
<p>The speaker announced late Thursday he had made an initial $50,000 payment and cut in half the size of a loan he planned to take out from Bob Dole to meet part of the balance.</p>
<p>The new arrangement was the result of negotiations between Gingrich and the House ethics committee, congressional sources said. The ethics panel was unwilling to accept an original proposal under which Gingrich was expected to borrow the full amount from Dole.</p>
<p>&quot;We tried to listen to everybody to work to ensure, as I said all along, that we would do this in a legal and ethical way designed to set the right standards for the House,&quot; Gingrich told reporters.</p>
<p>He said the $50,000 payment should &quot;satisfy everybody who had any concerns&quot;, adding, &quot;I feel very good about it.&quot;</p>
<p>The speaker had been expected to borrow $300,000 from Dole under a loan unveiled last month that would not have required repayment for eight years. Because Gingrich plans to retire in 2002, he would not have had to make any payments until after he left Congress under that plan.</p>
<p>Democratic critics had called the loan a sweetheart deal and some members of his own party had urged Gingrich to pay at least part of the fine out of his own pocket.</p>
<p>The ethics panel sought changes to ensure the arrangement met standard requirements for a loan, rather than a gift.</p>
<p>The new package seemed to silence Democratic critics.</p>
<p>House Minority Whip David Bonior, a Michigan Democrat who has been Gingrich's harshest critic, was &quot;satisfied&quot; with the new arrangement, a spokeswoman said. &quot;We knew all along the original deal was a sweetheart deal.&quot;</p>
<p>Public interest groups said that by finding that a personal loan did not constitute a gift, the ethics panel had undermined House rules barring most gifts to lawmakers.</p>
<p>&quot;In approving this arrangement the committee has engaged in Alice-in-Wonderland logic,&quot; Common Cause president Ann McBride said. &quot;This is a dangerous and unacceptable precedent. The ethics committee should not just make up new rules to reach a result they predetermine.&quot;</p>
<p>Under the new arrangement worked out with the ethics panel, Gingrich is scheduled to make additional $50,000 payments on June 1 and Nov. 30, 1998. A final $150,000 payment would be due Jan. 2, 1999.</p>
<p>The speaker could borrow up to $150,000 from Dole at the time the final instalment came due. The loan would have to paid back over five years, beginning Jan. 2, 2000.</p>
<p>Dole, whom Gingrich has described as a close personal friend, was also required to sign a letter to the committee stating that the loan would come from his personal funds and not income from his new law firm.</p>
<p>Dole recently joined the law firm of Verner, Liipfert, Bernhard, McPherson and Hand that represents a number of large defence firms and was involved in tobacco issues.</p>
<p>Dole also agreed not to contact Gingrich directly or indirectly on behalf of any clients while the loan was in effect. Should Dole lobby, the loan would be nullified.</p>
<p>As collateral, the speaker put up his home in Georgia and proceeds from a second book to be published by Harper Collins Publishing Inc. under an existing contract.</p>
<p>Gingrich was the first House speaker ever reprimanded for ethics violations. He was punished for his aggressive use of tax exempt groups to advance his political agenda.</p>
<p>Gingrich insisted he had not intentionally done anything wrong, but failed to safeguard against tax abuses by the groups as well as submitting false and misleading information to the ethics committee.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
