<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="590303" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OPTIONS - U.S. T-bond vols stay soft, June expires.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - U.S. T-bond vols stay soft, June expires.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatilities for U.S. Treasury bond options remained soft as the underlying bond prices stayed within recent tight ranges and the weekend time-decay weighed on premiums, dealers said.</p>
<p>June T-bond futures options on Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) expired at noon without causing any significant turbulence, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;It (expiration) was really a non-event, especially with the market trading at the 110-handle,&quot; a broker at CBOT said. &quot;If you recall, May (options) went out at 108-even a month ago. Well, here we are again.&quot;  </p>
<p>Traders have pointed at the high level of open interest in the 110 strike price as one of the reasons for June T-bond futures' range-trade around 110 in recent sessions.</p>
<p>The at-the-money strike price tends to have a magnetic effect when expiration approaches as delta-hedgers who have the gamma-rich, short-dated contracts tend to be forced to quickly sell futures when the market goes up and buy futures when the market goes down.</p>
<p>For instance, a call option holder's delta increases as futures rise, generating the need to sell futures to keep delta near zero.  </p>
<p>Likewise, put options' negative delta decreases as futures go up, also calling for futures selling.</p>
<p>Shorter maturities have higher gamma, the rate of change in delta per move in the underlying asset price.</p>
<p>Many delta-neutral market-makers were thought to have been on the long side in gamma lately because of end-users' general reluctance to buy options, which has been evidenced in the steady erosion of implied volatilities, traders said.</p>
<p>Still, caution ahead of next Tuesday's Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting underpinned volatilities, even though it was also dampening bond price movement.  </p>
<p>Implied volatility for CBOT July and September T-bond futures options stood at around 8.4 percent and 8.6 percent, off about 0.1 each.</p>
<p>&quot;No one is sure if the Fed's going to do it or not,&quot; said a second CBOT trader, referring to possible credit tightening at the FOMC meeting. &quot;It's a close call.&quot;</p>
<p>T-bond futures ended off 11/32 at 109-31/32, just 1/32 below the 110-strike price.</p>
<p>In the Eurodollar market at the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME), option trading was relatively calm, with several apparent hedge deals in the front-June options.  </p>
<p>A CME floor analyst at a European bank noted that a lot of slightly out-of-the-money June 94.00 traded today.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears to be a hedge against cash books,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said there was little dealing interest like that Thursday, when a lot of short-Junes -- options expiring next month but priced off 1998 futures -- traded. Because front-month futures gravitate toward cash deposit rates near expiration, Eurodollar option trading usually focuses on a few quarters out or the mid-curves like short-June.</p>
<p>Implied volatilities for September and December Eurodollar options softened a touch to 9.2 and 11.5 percent respectively.</p>
<p>-- Shin Kishima/Chicago Derivatives Desk ((312-408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
