<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="590319" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT wheat closes higher on weather, exports.</title>
<headline>CBOT wheat closes higher on weather, exports.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT wheat futures closed higher on dry weather in portions of the Kansas wheat growing region and on spillover from Thursday's supportive USDA weekly export sales report, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are some signs of a little better demand. The export sales (Thursday's USDA weekly) were better than some people thought,&quot; said Jack Scoville, Vice President for Price Futures Group. &quot;Also there are some forecasts for differing amounts of rain over the weekend.&quot;</p>
<p>Dry hard red winter wheat areas of western Kansas should be missed by next week's storm systems, meteorologists said.</p>
<p>Instead the storm system may bring rain to eastern Kansas, Oklahoma and Texas, they said.</p>
<p>The supportive demand picture surfaced this week with U.S. net export sales of old- and new-crop wheat combined during the week ended May 8 totaling 705,500 tonnes, according to the USDA.</p>
<p>That tally was above trade expectations for 350,000 to 500,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Wheat closed four cents higher to three lower, with May up four at $3.87 and new crop July 1/4 cent higher at $3.88-3/4.  </p>
<p>There also remained some concern about lingering dry weather in portions of Europe's wheat growing region.</p>
<p>&quot;There's some world weather concerns about the wheat,&quot; said Charlie Sernatinger, analyst with E.D. and F. Man International. &quot;We've got dryness in (Europe) and in western Kansas.&quot;</p>
<p>Technicians said the wheat market was oversold recently and was due for a correction. The nine day relative strength index (RSI) for the July reached a recent low of 31 percent at Wedneday's close and Friday closed at 34 percent. An RSI of 30 or less is indicative of an oversold market.</p>
<p>Refco Inc bought 2.5 million bushels of July, E.D. and F. Man International bought one million July and Rosenthal Collins bought one million bushels of July, traders said.</p>
<p>Wheat futures volume was estimated by the CBOT at 14,000 contracts, below the 17,147 traded Thursday.</p>
<p>In wheat options, Refco Inc sold 450 July $3.90 puts at 12-3/4 to 13 cents and bought 200 July $4.50 calls at two cents, traders said.</p>
<p>Wheat options volume was estimated at 5,000 contracts, below the 8,310 traded Thursday.</p>
<p>((Sam Nelson 312-408-8721))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
