<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="590329" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: First Albany settles NASD charges on muni payments.</title>
<headline>First Albany settles NASD charges on muni payments.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>NASD said Friday it reached a final settlement with First Albany Cos and its chief of municipal bond operations concerning payments to another bond firm with political connections to former New Jersey Gov. Jim Florio.</p>
<p>Reuters reported Thursday that National Association of Securities Dealers was poised to charge that First Albany kept inadequate books and records of at least one payment to the other bond firm, which NASD identified as Armacon Securities.</p>
<p>Under the settlement, First Albany agreed to pay NASD $10,000 and to a censure of the firm and its muni department chief Frank Murphy.</p>
<p>Barry Goldsmith, executive vice president of enforcement at NASD, said, &quot;We are looking at a number of investigations growing out of Armacon. This was the first case. The other investigations are continuing.&quot;</p>
<p>First Albany paid Armacon a total of $20,000 in 1991 and 1992 to help it get bond business with New Jersey Health Care Facilities Financing Authority and other issuers, NASD said.</p>
<p>But First Albany, at the direction of Murphy, recorded the two $10,000 payments in its books as a &quot;co-manager's fee,&quot; in the case of the 1991 deal, and a &quot;consulting fee,&quot; in the case of the 1992 offering, NASD charged.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr. Murphy knew Armacon had not served as a co-manager for the offering or provided any services in connection with the offering,&quot; NASD said of the September 1991 Oneida, New York Health Care Corporation mortgage revenue bond deal.</p>
<p>Similarly, Murphy knew Armacon was not a consultant concerning a Falls Township, Pa., Hospital Authority revenue bond refunding in February 1992, NASD said.</p>
<p>NASD said First Albany violated, and Murphy caused the firm to violate, anti-fraud provisions of the federal securities laws and the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board's recordkeeping rule G-8.</p>
<p>Federal investigators have been probing Armacon off and on since 1993 when an examination of the Clementon, N.J., firm's records showed evidence that Armacon may have been getting payments from a number of muni bond firms.</p>
<p>No charges have been brought against any firms connected to Armacon until today's settlement.</p>
<p>Former NASD examiner Theresa Carr told SEC officials in October 1996 that NASD district officials failed to pursue evidence that a dozen dealer firms made payments to Armacon in the early 1990s in return for bond business.</p>
<p>Carr is alleging in a $20 million lawsuit against NASD that the association effectively fired her for pressing an investigation.</p>
<p>Goldsmith said Friday, however,  &quot;We have a number of active investigations going.&quot;</p>
<p>But Carr lawyer William Singer said NASD's action comes too late and is disingenuous. &quot;They chose to look the other way and do nothing,&quot; he said. &quot;Now all of a sudden they are going to do something about Armacon. It doesn't give the money back to the public.&quot;</p>
<p>First Albany said in a two-page written statement that its five-year-old offense is &quot;solely a books and records violation&quot; that had no &quot;adverse effect&quot; on any locality or other market participant.</p>
<p>&quot;At no time was there any effort to conceal the fact that First Albany had made payments to Armacon,&quot; the firm said.</p>
<p>First Albany said it recorded the fees as &quot;expenses on its internal records in connection with two health care transactions. Had First Albany recorded these fees in a general consulting account, there would have been no violation at all,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The firm said it plans to revise its written procedures &quot;to make clear to all personnel handling public or private securities offerings that expenses are not to be charged to such offerings&quot; unless they are directly related.</p>
<p>First Albany added that the fees were for &quot;lawful advisory services actually rendered in connection with the development of First Albany's health care financing business. Such services did not in fact produce any business for First Albany.&quot;</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
