<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="590545" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch shares slip at close after record opening.</title>
<headline>Dutch shares slip at close after record opening.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares closed very slightly off on Friday, slipping from opening highs and given a downward shove from higher than expected U.S. housing starts in the afternoon, traders said.</p>
<p>At the opening, the AEX index of 25 leading shares rose past the 800 point mark for the first time, reaching 801.27. However, the index struggled to hold above 800 and subsequently slid to just below Thursday's close after figures showed U.S. housing starts rose a higher-than-expected 2.6 percent.</p>
<p>At the close, the index was down 0.72 points, or 0.09 percent to 704.30.</p>
<p>Traders said the U.S. figures and the Dow's response was the main reason for the late weakness, but added that many players were in any case wary of seeing the market end on a high ahead of a three-day weekend and the expiry of options contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;It has to do with the long weekend of course. A number of options traders would also have been unhappy with the AEX above 800,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>However, few saw the market failing to rise next week, with the index pushing through 800 points once more.</p>
<p>Of individual shares, one of the greatest losers was food group CSM which fell 5.90 guilders to 104.50. The weakness resulted from some disappointment over its 1996/97 half year results which were published late on Thursday.</p>
<p>Insurer Aegon also published figures on Thursday, but was viewed more favourably by the market. Its first quarter profit rose 24 percent and it raised its forecast for the full year. Its shares were stable at 143.70, but fundamentally rose as the stock turned ex a dividend of 1.61 guilders.</p>
<p>&quot;It really looks to have done very well indeed,&quot; one trader said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
