<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="590621" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Cotton rates seen down in Pakistan, up in India.</title>
<headline>Cotton rates seen down in Pakistan, up in India.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cotton rates in Pakistan could fall next week on surplus stocks and slack demand from mill owners, while prices in India are likely rise on higher demand, dealers said on Friday.</p>
<p>In Pakistan, dealers said, the price downtrend would continue as ginners still have more than 800,000 (170-kg) bales of unsold cotton from the 1996/97 (July-June) crop, while the new crop is due to start arriving next month.</p>
<p>Ginners, fearing that the overhang will depress new crop prices, are offering cotton on credit, the dealers added.</p>
<p>&quot;Mill owners are short of funds because of a slump in the international yarn market,&quot; dealer Naseem Usman said. &quot;Only exporters are showing some interest.&quot;</p>
<p>He said exporters were unlikely to buy more than 150,000 tonnes by the end of this month.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said next year could again prove difficult for Pakistani cotton as world cotton consumption was declining.</p>
<p>The private Karachi Cotton Association's spot rates in rupees per maund including a 10 percent sales tax:</p>
<p>				 Friday		 May 9</p>
<p>		NIAB-78	2,146.50 ($53.07)  2,196</p>
<p>		K-68	   2,366.50	     2,416</p>
<p>		MNH-93	 2,370.50	     2,426</p>
<p>In India, cotton prices gained on the domestic market this week after sustained buying by mills, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said mill demand pushed prices up at a time of thin supply at the end of the season.</p>
<p>&quot;Daily average arrivals in the Punjab region dropped to 1,000/1,500 bales (170 kg each) during the week,&quot; they said.</p>
<p>Arrivals in other parts of the country also fell.</p>
<p>In spot deals, Bengal-deshi rose to 900/935 rupees per maund (37.32 kg) from 885/930 rupees, while F-414 rose 10 rupees to 1,900/1,935 rupees per maund. Gujarat Kalyan (medium-staple) gained 200 rupees to 13,700/14,200 rupees per candy (355.56 kg).</p>
<p>&quot;Mill consumption of cotton has gone up considerably in the last three to four months,&quot; said dealer Chandubhai Thakkar, adding that it now averaged 1.3 million bales a month.</p>
<p>Traders said cotton arrivals had dropped as the bulk of the 1996/97 (October/September) crop had already been marketed.</p>
<p>&quot;The overall short-term price trend will remain firm, while the long-term trend will depend on the progress of the monsoon which will set in next month in India,&quot; Thakkar said.</p>
<p>-- Karachi newsroom 9221-5685192</p>
<p>-- Bombay commodities 9122-2659000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
