<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="590690" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenian shares ease, EU association treaty eyed.</title>
<headline>Slovenian shares ease, EU association treaty eyed.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenian shares eased 0.61 percent on Friday and traders said the SBI index was expected to tread water over next week as investors were awaiting the ratification of Slovenia's European Union association treaty.</p>
<p>&quot;If Slovenia ratifies the agreement by the end of May then shares will start rising slowly, but if that does not happen the index could fall to its January level (of around 1,150 points) over the next months,&quot; said Davor Dubokovic, a trader of Eastbrokers.</p>
<p>Parliament this week postponed a vote on ratifying the agreement, which was signed in June 1996, for a week in order to give parties more room to clarify their stand on possible EU membership. The new date of the vote has not yet been set.</p>
<p>&quot;If the agreement is not ratified, we will see virtually no foreign investors for a year or more, which would cause the market to remain bearish in poor liquidity for a very long time,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>The blue-chip SBI index fell 8.03 points to close the week at 1,298.29.</p>
<p>Health resort operator Terme Catez was the most actively traded, down 3.03 percent to 11,520 tolars on volume of 1,372 shares.</p>
<p>Traders said Catez fell because of generally poor liquidity but added the share was not expected to decline further because of the firm's good business results and solid expansion plans.</p>
<p>&quot;However, if the parliament fails to ratify the agreement, Catez could fall by another 20 percent over the next couple of months as is true for most other shares,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Overall five shares fell, seven rose, four were unchanged and 12 were untraded. Turnover fell to 69.7 million tolars from 108.3 million.</p>
<p>Bank UBK was the leading decliner, down 7.9 percent to 5,710 on volume of only five shares. Traders said the small volume diminished the significance of the move and added the share's future direction was impossible to predict.</p>
<p>Mineral water producer and health resort operator Radenska was the day's top gainer, up 4.87 percent to 1,679 tolars on volume of 1,284 shares in a technical correction of Thursday's 5.82 percent decline.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Radenska bottomed out yesterday but because of relatively poor business results it is unlikely to rise over 1,700 tolars in the short-term,&quot; a broker said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
