<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="590722" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bonn's gold, Telekom plans do EMU few favours.</title>
<headline>Bonn's gold, Telekom plans do EMU few favours.</headline>
<byline>Kate Kelland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Selling off state assets and revaluing gold reserves may not bring Germany much closer to meeting deficit criteria for Europe's single currency and will probably weaken the euro, economists said on Friday.</p>
<p>But it does increase the chance that European economic and monetary union (EMU) will go ahead on time and will be taken by financial markets as another clear signal of German political will to bring currency union into being in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;It all smacks of a German government hitting the panic button, and what they are actually doing is opening up the whole EMU game to creative accounting methods,&quot; said David Brown, chief European economist at Bear Stearns in London.</p>
<p>Graham McDevitt, economist at Paribas Capital Markets in London said: &quot;The fact that a lot more fudges are being used, rather than structural adjustments, does lend itself to the view that we could have a weaker euro.&quot;</p>
<p>The key point, analysts said, was that neither profits from the sale of a further stake in Deutsche Telekom AG, nor from revaluing the Bundesbank's gold reserves, would feed directly into Germany's budget deficit hole.</p>
<p>The finance ministry said on Thursday that tax revenues for 1997 would now leave the government 18 billion marks ($10.6 billion) short.</p>
<p>Privatisation proceeds used to pay off old national debt would reduce interest payments, taking a slight strain off the government's coffers, but economists say Bonn will pay a high credibility price in the eyes of the rest of Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;These plans give the impression of hasty action and a desperate need for money,&quot; said Armin Kayser, German economist at SBC Warburg in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>The likelihood is, however, that the political drive that prompted Bonn to effectively swallow its words on strict interpretation of the Maastricht EMU criteria, will also push it to change Bundesbank rules and take a one-off profit payment from revalued gold reserves and book it into 1997's budget.</p>
<p>This in turn could bring the deficit closer to the three percent of gross domestic product (GDP) laid down in the Maastricht Treaty, allowing Germany to escape its uncomfortable current position.</p>
<p>Analysts still expect Germany will miss its own 2.9 percent deficit target for 1997, reaching instead a 3.2-3.5 deficit, which in the end would be acceptable for EMU entry.</p>
<p>The German government usually takes an annual profit transfer from the Bundesbank, and this year's payment, from 1996 profits, has already been made.</p>
<p>But Thomas Mayer, economist at Goldman Sachs in Frankfurt, said he thought Bonn was planning to take an additional &quot;extraordinary profit transfer&quot; from the central bank for 1997.</p>
<p>Indeed, the ministry said on Friday that a revaluation of gold reserves could have an impact on the 1997 budget if the central bank made an interim account this year, but sources immediately said the central bank had concerns about this.</p>
<p>A Bundesbank official told Reuters the central bank had no further comment to make on Bonn's revaluation plans.</p>
<p>McDevitt at Paribas agreed a transfer of Bundesbank profits was likely.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not really a fudge, because it is allowed under EU rules, but for all intents and purposes it is a fudge,&quot; McDevitt said.</p>
<p>-- Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.702 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
