<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="590801" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. blue chips extend slide, NYSE curbs set.</title>
<headline>U.S. blue chips extend slide, NYSE curbs set.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. stocks extended their morning slide on Friday, nearly reversing Thursday's rally to a record high, led down by Dow component Hewlett-Packard Co, which posted earnings below forecasts.</p>
<p>The New York Stock Exchange said it set curbs in index-arbitrage orders at 1038 EDT/1438 GMT after the Dow Jones industrial average fell 50 points, or 0.7 percent, to about 7282.</p>
<p>The Dow later slipped about 53 points to 7281. The Nasdaq composite was down eight to 1346.</p>
<p>Analysts said profit taking helped bring the market lower.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is giving back some of the profits from the last couple of weeks,&quot; said Frank Calta, a trader at Dain Bosworth. &quot;We've had one heck of a run.  A little profit taking is healthy.  I don't see a sentiment change.&quot;</p>
<p>Hewlett-Packard also weighed down stocks after the company posted quarterly earnings $0.75 per share, below consensus estimates of $0.80 per share, after the market closed on Thursday.  Hewlett-Packard fell 5-1/8 to 53-3/4.</p>
<p>Stocks felt the effect of Treasuries, where the long bond was off 12/32 to yield 6.90 percent after April housing starts and University of Michigan consumer sentiment data.</p>
<p>((-- Patricia Willens, Wall St desk, 212-859-1730))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
