<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="591179" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Turkish forces cement grip on northern Iraq.</title>
<headline>Turkish forces cement grip on northern Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Osman Senkul</byline>
<dateline>ON THE IRAQI-TURKISH BORDER 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish forces solidified their hold on northern Iraq on Friday, reopening the border to deliveries of humanitarian aid even as they pounded rebel Kurdish positions for the third day running.</p>
<p>Air force jets flew dozens of bombing runs from Turkish bases against suspected camps of the separatist Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK), which is waging a 12-year insurgency for autonomy or independence from Turkey.</p>
<p>Military officials in Diyarbakir, headquarters for the anti-PKK fight, said heavy fighting was continuing in the Sinaht Valley, east of the main Iraqi border town of Zakho.</p>
<p>They said one member of Turkey's Kurdish militia was killed and four were injured in the clashes. State-paid village guards from the southeast often join the army on cross-border operations.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan, an early advocate of a political solution to the Kurdish insurgency, said the army had been invited in to help the biggest Iraqi Kurdish GROUP in its own fight with the PKK. The Iraqi Kurds have yet to confirm this.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the most important leaders in northern Iraq...called upon our help while engaging in clashes with terrorist forces.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Turkey is always respectful of Iraq's territorial integrity. This is a limited operation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The incursion -- the biggest in two years and involving at least 10,000 troops -- has been carried out under a complete &quot;news blackout&quot;, with reporters barred from the area and calls blocked from Turkey to satellite telephones inside Iraq.</p>
<p>Independent confirmation of the casualty reports, as well as the full scope of operations, was impossible.</p>
<p>Earlier, the general staff said 87 PKK rebels had been killed in Turkey's border provinces of Sirnak and Hakkari as they fled the Turkish advance from positions inside Iraq.</p>
<p>Security sources told Reuters 30 PKK rebels and four soldiers were killed in the first two days of the Iraq operation, most in the early hours before dawn on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The security sources also said 18 rebels were killed and four members of the security forces injured in fighting inside Turkey on the border of eastern Tunceli and Elazig provinces.</p>
<p>But in a sign of growing confidence, the army reopened the border, closed since just before the attack, to deliveries of food and other supplies under United Nations auspices. Traders with Iraqi passports were also permitted to pass.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been waiting for three days -- we are 10,000 trucks -- but now we are expecting to cross,&quot; said one lorry driver at the border. Many trucks had already crossed.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to let in traders with Iraqi passports and United Nations trucks with humanitarian supplies,&quot; a colonel at the border told reporters.</p>
<p>U.N. guards contacted by satellite telephone said all was quiet in the main Iraqi border town of Zakho, and that the soldiers had left the immediate area.</p>
<p>Helicopters flew back and forth across the border, which was tightly controlled by Turkish security forces through a checkpoint about 500 metres (yards) before the Habur crossing into Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ON THE IRAQI-TURKISH BORDER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
