<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="591388" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austrian bonds end soft ahead of new bond issue.</title>
<headline>Austrian bonds end soft ahead of new bond issue.</headline>
<text>
<p>1530 GMT - Austrian bonds ended weaker in hectic trade ahead of the weekend, with the short end of the market under pressure after the announcement of a new five year issue on Tuesday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was chaotic today. The whole short end came under pressure,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>An additional factor weighing on the market was the uncertainty over the Fed meeting on Tuesday, which traders fear could result in a U.S. rate hike.</p>
<p>Traders said there was little upside potential for the time being.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the German Bund future has seen its high at 102.50,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>* 10 year benchmark 5.75 pct bond maturing July 2006 down up 10 bps at 100.60 to yield 5.67 (5.68) pct in bourse trade, quoted post-market at 99.84/92 to yield 5.77/76.</p>
<p>* Latest five-year 4.375 bond maturing February 2002 closed down 15 bps at 98.85 in bourse trade to yield 4.60 (4.57) pct, quoted post-market at 98.55/63 to yield 4.67/65 percent.</p>
<p>* Austrian bond future up four bps at 109.44 on turnover of 382 lots.</p>
<p>* 10-year spread over Germany up one at zero, five-year spread down five bps at 10.</p>
<p>* Money market rates steady with three-month VIBOR lower at 3.437 and overnight money higher at 3.15/3.40. -- Vienna newsroom, +431 53112 257</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
