<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="591395" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O.Licht - Daily sugar report.</title>
<headline>F.O.Licht - Daily sugar report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from commodity statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>SUGAR - World market for May 15, 1997</p>
<p>White sugar futures in London closed barely changed in quiet dealings. Front-month August finished 10 cents firmer at $318.00 per tonne, while October lost 30 cents to close at $307.40 per tonne. There was no fresh news to influence prices.</p>
<p>Raw sugar futures in New York closed lower across the board with July and October losing 4 points to close at 11.01 and 10.81 cents/lb, respectively. The outer months lost between 2 and 3 points.</p>
<p>Reports that 90,000 tonnes of raws, mostly, if not all, of Cuban origin, were held up at the port of Novorosijsk and problems related to the financing of tolling operations gave rise to speculation that Russia may import more white sugar. Traders said as many as 5 cargoes of white sugar might have entered Novorosijsk in recent weeks, while there was talk of 20,000 tonnes going into St. Petersburg. But information is sketchy and unconfirmed.</p>
<p>However, large scale white sugar imports are unlikely as exporters to Russia have to reckon with a 10 per cent value- added tax plus a hefty 25 per cent import duty. This will make sure that the emphasis is on raw imports. Czarnikow's reduced world production forecast for 1996/97 had no impact on prices.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>C. CZARNIKOW - C. Czarnikow said in its May 1997 sugar report that there has been a further slight contraction in world crops since the company's last assessment of the 1996/97 (crop years) season in February. World production is now likely to close 0.54 million tonnes below the previous season at 122.80 million tonnes, down on the 123.34 million tonnes turned out in 1995/96. The month ago it appeared likely that production would exceed the previous season by 0.28 million tonnes, Czarnikow said.</p>
<p>At the same time the company scaled back its consumption figure by 0.56 million tonnes since February and the total for this year is now put at 120.44 million tonnes which is still 2.16 million tonnes above the CY 1996 level. Czarnikow said that on the assumption of a disappearance factor of 0.75 million tonnes, raw value (unrecorded disappearance) the addition to stocks is now put at 1.61 million tonnes after the much larger gain of 4.41 million tonnes that developed in 1995/96.</p>
<p>RUSSIA - Sugar beet sowings are still behind those of last year. As of May 12, 745,000 ha had been sown to sugar beet, down from 852,000 ha sown at the same date last year. The total area in 1997 is planned to reach 1.080 million ha, slightly up from last year's figure of 1.071 million ha.</p>
<p>THAILAND - It now seems to be almost certain that Thai sugar production in 1996/97 will be below that of last year. Total production up to May 13 reached 6.040 million tonnes, raw value, down from 6.224 million tonnes produced the same period in 1995/96. Moreover, only one mill was still open at that date in 1997 compared to ten mills last year. Last season the harvest ended in June but it will finish earlier in 1996/97.</p>
<p>CUBA - Sugar exports from Cuba still lag behind last year's level with the total in February reaching not more than 800,764 tonnes, raw value, down from 877,547 tonnes in February 1996. This brought cumulative exports in the first 5 months of 1996/97 (October/February) up to 1.088 million tonnes against 1.155 million tonnes, figures by the International Sugar Organization show. Total exports in 1995/96 reached 3.816 million tonnes against 2.760 million tonnes in 1994/95.</p>
<p>Major countries of destination in October/February 1996/97 were Russia with 280,822 tonnes raws, sharply down from last year's 562,267 tonnes, China with 140,563 tonnes compared to 39,245 tonnes, Iran with 129,552 tonnes against nil, Japan with 122,824 tonnes against nil and Egypt with 114,766 tonnes, sharply up from last year's 40,402 tonnes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
