<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="591609" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hewlett-Packard stock tumbles after earnings report.</title>
<headline>Hewlett-Packard stock tumbles after earnings report.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Perry</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hewlett-Packard Co. stock tumbled Friday as disappointed investors reacted to the computer company's weaker-than-expected profits and Wall Street analysts sliced earnings estimates.</p>
<p>Hewlett-Packard was off $5.875 to $53 in afternoon trading on the New York Stock Exchange, where it was the most active issue and the biggest loser of the session.</p>
<p>The slide in HP, one of the stocks in the Dow Jones industrial average, contributed to a 69-point loss in the blue-chip index in midday trading, and spilled over to another Dow stock, International Business Machines Corp., which lost $2 to $172.375, as well as other technology companies.</p>
<p>HP, a Palo Alto, Calif.-based maker of computers and printers, said after the market closed on Thursday that earnings rose 8 percent to $784 million, or 75 cents a share, in its second quarter from $723 million, or 69 cents a share, a year earlier. Revenue rose 5 percent to $10.3 billion from $9.9 billion.</p>
<p>But the results were below industry analysts' estimates of 80 cents a share, prompting several analysts to cut their ratings and shave earnings estimates.</p>
<p>HP blamed the weaker-than-expected performance on a strong year-ago period, a stronger dollar and slowing in some markets, especially the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;Hewlett-Packard reported second quarter results in which revenues, orders and earnings were all below Street expectations,&quot; Lehman Brothers analyst George Elling said in a research note.</p>
<p>The company said Friday that would raise its quarterly dividend to 14 cents a share from 12 cents, payable July 9 to shareholders of record June 18.</p>
<p>Comments by Hewlett-Packard executives, in a conference call Thursday with analysts, that it was difficult to pin the weakness on any specific reason troubled investors.</p>
<p>The company, which is the dominant supplier of personal and office printers in many of its markets, reported soft growth in its Inkjet printer business and a decline in orders and revenue for its LaserJet printers, leading some analysts to conclude the market was showing signs of maturing.</p>
<p>Sales of its high-end Unix servers -- powerful machines that run networks of computers -- were also weak ahead of new products due to be introduced next Thursday, although HP said business is usually not strong in the second quarter.</p>
<p>The company said overall U.S. orders fell 2 percent in the quarter while orders in other countries rose 7 percent.</p>
<p>Before the market opened, Alex.Brown brokerage said it downgraded HP stock to market underperform from market perform. Gruntal also cut its rating, to outperform from strong buy and Cowen cut its rating to neutral from buy.</p>
<p>But not all analysts were negative and some saw the weakness in HP shares as a buying opportunity. The stock had run up near its 52-week high of $60 on hopes it would report favourable results.</p>
<p>&quot;The more (selling) pressure, the bigger the opportunity,&quot; said Salomon Brothers analyst John Jones, who trimmed this year's estimate by three cents a share to $3.20 but kept his fiscal 1998 estimate steady at $3.65 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;The point I'm making is it's not fallen apart. The business looks pretty healthy, the margins look healthy, the balance sheet is awesome,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
