<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="591770" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila share index hits year-low close.</title>
<headline>Manila share index hits year-low close.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Manila share index dived 54.96 points, or 2.09 percent, to close at a year-low of 2,576.13 points on Friday initially weighed down by PLDT's loss in New York and exacerbated by lingering concerns of the Philippine currency following Thailand's path.</p>
<p>&quot;People are still affected by negative sentiment triggered by Thailand's baht. The preferred position right now is to be liquid,&quot; said Dennis Rayala, research head at Abacus Securities.  </p>
<p>&quot;Even small investors are liquidating. People are very tentative,&quot; said Jose Ricardo Garcia, executive vice-president at Diversified Securities.</p>
<p>In early trade, the main index broke through a difficult 2,600 support.</p>
<p>PLDT which suffered a beating due to a $1-1/4 loss of its ADR in New York helped drag the index in early trade, shedding as much as four percent at 700 pesos. It recovered at the end of the session at 735 pesos.</p>
<p>In the broader market, losers trounced gainers 116 to 19 but turnover was amodest at 2.13 billion pesos.</p>
<p>&quot;There's still the Thai baht scare and the Philippines is seen defending the peso. I think the market next week will still depend on the volatility of the currency market in the region,&quot; said Luz Lorenzo, research head at Peregrine Securities.</p>
<p>Philipine Asia Equity assistant vice-president Nathan Lozada said that the Central Bank's move to raise interest raise could be a signal for banks to jack up interest rates making borrowing cost for companies prohibitive which in turn would adversely affect their bottomline.</p>
<p>The Bank raised overnight borrowing rate to 20 percent from 13 percent on Friday.</p>
<p>Traders said investors will remain cautious until the Federal Reserve meeting on May 20 and the release of the eagerly-awaited first quarter Gross National Product (GNP) figures.</p>
<p>Analysts were mixed on the new support with some seeing a low of 2,200 points and a high of 2,500.</p>
<p>-- KATHERINE ESPINA  (63 2) 841-8939 Fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
