<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="591721" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Telecom of New Zealand targets earnings growth.</title>
<headline>Telecom of New Zealand targets earnings growth.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Brockett</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Telecom Corp of New Zealand is targeting a return to the double-digit earnings growth rates of the past, chief executive Roderick Deane said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is certainly our objective to get back to much stronger earnings rates, and I don't regard the golden years...as by any means being over,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Telecom on Wednesday reported a sharp decline in its annual profit to NZ$581.4 million (US$404 million) from NZ$716.8 million a year ago, due mostly to one-off provisions.</p>
<p>But the phone utility's normalised earnings growth rate fell from 19.5 percent in 1996 to just 3.2 percent.</p>
<p>Deane said the slower growth, partly a product of the sluggish economy and partly of competition, was a concern.</p>
<p>&quot;The real dilema over the last couple of quarters is that these big volume increases that we've had to generate in order to offset the price declines have themselves been generating very large cost increases,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;What we'll really do in this next year is get a better handle on our costs again. And if we can get that rate of increase in costs down, we'll be able to grow earnings again.&quot;</p>
<p>He said provisioning of almost NZ$190 million in the 1996/97 accounts would &quot;clean out the shop and tidy up our affairs&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got a really good base now for growing our earnings again.&quot; Earnings growth would be achieved by providing value.</p>
<p>&quot;By enhancements to the core, by doing things that provide customers with that extra bit of value that will make them want to prefer Telecom,&quot; Deane said.</p>
<p>&quot;The other factor is smart marketing, innovative products and services, to rollout more and better products and services than our competitors, and they have to be better priced.&quot;</p>
<p>Deane said prices would continue to fall as competition intensified. &quot;Prices can fall a lot further and will over the next few years. That's why we've got to get our costs down.&quot;</p>
<p>Redundacies were planned and that would eat a significant proportion of a NZ$43.2 million restructuring provision taken.</p>
<p>Deane said it was now unlikley that Telecom would spend all of the $800 million capital expediture planned for fiscal 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd like to be NZ$100 million less than that. So we're actually re-doing our budgets at the present time to see whether we can come it at significantly less than that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>About two thirds of capital expenditure would go into growth areas and a small amount into maintaining core businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;The vast bulk of it is driven by new requirements for growth, and that growth is occuring in the broad band cable rollout, it's occurring in (Internet vehicle) Xtra, it's occurring in the celluar network -- sometimes we do over $100 million a year on expanding the cellular network,&quot; Deane said.</p>
<p>Deane was cricitcal of New Zealand fund managers, who he said had typically been underweight in Telecom, which as New Zealand's largest listed company accounts for about a quarter of the Stock Exchange's market capitalisation.</p>
<p>&quot;They've been a bunch of doubters,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Most New Zealand funds managers in the last four or five years have been typically underweight in Telecom stock relative to the stock exchange index, and that's been one of the principal reasons why many of them have underperformed the stock index -- oh ye of little faith!&quot;</p>
<p>A return to 15 percent-plus earnings growth was unquestionably the company's intention.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether we'll succeed, people have to make their own judgment call about, but that is certianly our objective, to do much better,&quot; Deane said. &quot;We would be disappointed if we don't get back onto an earnings growth path over the course of the next year. We'd be very disappointed.&quot;</p>
<p>US$1=NZ$1,44</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
