<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="591807" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Forex market has fully absorbed G7 pact-MOF's Kato.</title>
<headline>Forex market has fully absorbed G7 pact-MOF's Kato.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Takatoshi Kato, Japan's vice finance minister for international affairs, said on Friday that participants in the forex market have fully absorbed the intent of the currency accord struck in late April by the Group of Seven (G7) industrialised nations.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters, Kato said the basic stance of the ministry towards the currency market was to carefully watch the trend in the market.  </p>
<p>In an April 27 statement, economic policymakers of the G7 countries - Britain, Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan and the United States said that deviation of exchange rates from economic fundamentals is undesirable.</p>
<p>The G7 also stressed the importance of avoiding exchange rates that could lead to a &quot;re-emergence of large external imbalances&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We observe that the intention of the G7 accord has been sufficiently understood by market participants,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked if he was satisfied with the yen's recent rise against the dollar, Kato said he would like to refrain from making an assessment on currency movements.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;Our stance now is to carefully monitor the trend in the currency market.&quot;</p>
<p>Since the G7 agreement, the dollar has fallen below 115 yen from the 127 yen level. The dollar was hovering at around 115-116 yen in late Tokyo trading on Friday.  </p>
<p>Kato also declined to say whether the rise of the yen against the dollar since the accord was excessive or not.</p>
<p>Turning to the economy, MOF's Kato said that Japan's economic recovery trend remained intact. The recovery was being led by private sector demand, such as capital spending, he said.</p>
<p>He said that it would be premature to make a judgement on the impact the rise in the consumption tax has had on the economy, adding that more data was needed to make an accurate assessment. The sales tax was raised to five percent from three percent on April 1.  </p>
<p>Kato said that he does not see the surplus in Japan's trade and services account expanding greatly.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not worried about a resurgence in the surplus in the trade and services account since Japanese manufacturers' production overseas is picking up and imports of capital goods are increasing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked if an expected sharp year-on-year rise in Japan's customs-cleared trade surplus for April, due out next Monday, is a worrying factor, Kato said the trade surplus fluctuates from month to month due to special factors.</p>
<p>&quot;We would like to look at the surplus trend over the long-term, such as half a year or a year,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
