<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="591903" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Seapower Int'l unaware of talks with Next.</title>
<headline>Seapower Int'l unaware of talks with Next.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seapower International Holdings Ltd and Paramount Publishing Group Ltd said on Friday they are unaware of any talks with the Next Media Group relating to a purchase by Next of a substantial interest in Paramount.</p>
<p>&quot;The directors of the respective Seapower and Paramount wish to state that none of them has any knowledge of any such proposed acquisition and that neither Seapower nor Paramount nor any of their respective directors is holding discussions or is in negotiations or has any present intention to do so with the Next Media Group,&quot; the companies said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>Seapower holds about a 63 percent stake in Paramount.</p>
<p>The companies said the statement was made in response to press reports and market rumours that a third party, the Next Media Group, was contemplating the acquisition of a substantial interest in Paramount.</p>
<p>Paramount, a printing and paper bag making firm, also said it was not aware of any reason for the recent increase in the price and trading volume of shares of the company.</p>
<p>The stock eased HK$0.04 to HK$1.66 on Friday afternoon after it rising about 13 percent from HK$1.47 on April 30.</p>
<p>Seapower and Paramount warned investors to exercise caution when dealing the shares of the companies.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6369</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
