<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="59218" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan stocks fall 0.36 pct in profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Jordan stocks fall 0.36 pct in profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Profit-taking hit the Amman stock exchange for a second day on Tuesday as investors cashed in on a five percent rise in prices in the first half of the month.</p>
<p>The official Amman Financial Market 60-share index slipped 0.36 percent to 151.03 points in quiet trade worth 791,000 dinars ($1.12 million).</p>
<p>&quot;It's no surprise that a few people are cashing in their profits -- the market's gone up nearly 10 points,&quot; said broker Nasser al-Amad. &quot;They've made a good profit which they haven't seen for a long time.&quot;</p>
<p>The market started its rise to four-month highs last week as optimism over goverment commitment to economic reform and a healthy batch of half-year results pushed blue-chip shares up.</p>
<p>Heavyweight Arab Bank, which drove the index upwards in the first half of September, slipped two dinars on Tuesday to 245 dinars in relatively subdued trade worth 113,000 dinars.</p>
<p>&quot;Even the recent investors in Arab Bank bought at around 220 so they must be making good profit,&quot; Amad said.</p>
<p>Brokers said they expected the market to consolidate for a few days.</p>
<p>One share to buck the falling trend was Livestock and Poultry, which rose five percent to 0.79 dinars after dominating business and accounting for 40 percent of the value of Tuesday's trading.</p>
<p>One broker said the stock was still rising on market belief of Gulf Arab investor interest.</p>
<p>Of 52 stocks traded, 24 fell, 21 advanced, and seven closed unchanged.</p>
<p>The private Pearl Investable Index of the 45 best performing shares on the exchange fell 0.1 percent to 82.71 points, still 13.4 percent down from the same time last year.</p>
<p>-- Amman newsroom, 962 6 623 776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
