<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="592426" id="root" date="1997-05-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore first quarter economic growth down.</title>
<headline>Singapore first quarter economic growth down.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore's economy grew by 3.8 percent in the first quarter of 1997, down from the previous quarter's 5.8 percent, the Trade Development Board (TDB) said on Friday.</p>
<p>The manufacturing sector remained weak while entrepot trade and shipping continued to be affected by the global slowdown in the electronics industry and slower regional growth, it said in a statement.</p>
<p>The slower first quarter growth compares with 5.8 percent in the fourth quarter and seven percent for the whole of 1996.  </p>
<p>The TDB said, however, that electronics demand would improve in the later part of the year and that should keep the economy on a steady path toward recovery.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Trade and Industry retains its earlier growth forecast for 19977 of five to seven percent, it said.</p>
<p>Manufacturing, dampened by the cyclical slowdown in global demand for electronics, shrank by 6.7 percent after contracting by 0.7 percent in the previous quarter.</p>
<p>The TDB said that all major industries, with the exception of chemicals, declined during the first quarter this year.  </p>
<p>Electronics growth fell 10.3 percent, against a drop of 2.3 percent a quarter earlier.</p>
<p>It said that apart from disk drives and telecommunications equipment, other segments of the industry, such as consumer electronics, personal computers and semiconductors, stayed weak.</p>
<p>Commerce sector growth slowed to 3.0 percent, down from 5.4 percent previously with entrepot trade hurt by slower regional growth and a retail industry hit by structural factors, it said.</p>
<p>But the financial and business sectors grew strongly by 10.5 percent, up from 10 percent in last quarter, the TDB said.  </p>
<p>It said the financial services sub-sector benefitted from robust foreign exchange and Asian currency unit activity.</p>
<p>Business services also performed well, expanding by 8.4 percent on the back of growth in information technology.</p>
<p>In telecommunications, growth stablised at 7.6 percent, aided by the liberalisation of the paging and the communications markets on April 1.</p>
<p>The TDB also said that despite the cooling of the Singapore property market, construction growth remained healthy at 10.7 percent.  </p>
<p>Contracts awarded in the first quarter fell by 1.6 percent to Singapore $3.7 billion, but public-sector residential demand kept construction robust, it said.</p>
<p>On employment, the TDB said that with the exception of manufacturing and commerce, all sectors saw an increase in jobs.</p>
<p>Labour remains tight. The seasonally adjusted unemployment rate in March was 1.8 percent against 1.9 percent in December.</p>
<p>But in line with weaker economic growth, overall labour productivity shrank by 1.7 percent in the first quarter.</p>
<p>--Singapore newsroom (65 8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
