<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="592713" id="root" date="1997-05-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-TAYLOR IN THE RUNS AGAIN AS AUSTRALIA BEAT NORTHANTS.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-TAYLOR IN THE RUNS AGAIN AS AUSTRALIA BEAT NORTHANTS.</headline>
<dateline>NORTHAMPTON, England 1997-05-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia captain Mark Taylor gave himself another confidence booster when he top-scored with 76 as the tourists beat Northamptonshire in a rain-affected one-day match on Saturday.</p>
<p>Taylor, who has acknowledged that failure in the upcoming Ashes test series against England would probably cost him his job, set Australia on their way to a total of 232 from 47.4 overs.</p>
<p>He shared a solid opening partnership with Michael Slater (33) and also added runs with Mark Waugh (38) before finally falling lbw.</p>
<p>Reserve wicketkeeper Adam Gilchrist hit a crisp 40 as Australia, who face England in the first one-day international next week, amassed a commanding total in difficult circumstances.</p>
<p>&quot;It wasn't the world's best wicket and I was a bit slow early on but I improved as I went along,&quot; Taylor said. &quot;I was concentrating on using this match as practice because I want to make the one-day side (to face England) on merit.</p>
<p>&quot;That's the best my feet have moved for two or three months although there is still room for improvement.</p>
<p>&quot;On Thursday, in the first match against England, I will have to start a bit more positively, but I'm sure I will.&quot;</p>
<p>Taylor's 76 came on the back of his 45 in the opening match of the tour at Arundel on Thursday and suggests a much-needed return to form. It was his highest score in any competition for three months.</p>
<p>In reply, Northampton hit 134 for five from 35 overs before rain stopped play. Australia won on a faster run rate.</p>
<p>Northants opener Mal Loye made 65 not out which included a tremendous six over mid-wicket off the leg-spin of Shane Warne, who finished his first match of the tour with figures of two for 21.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NORTHAMPTON, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
