<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="592718" id="root" date="1997-05-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER SHOWCASE-DI MATTEO HELPS CHELSEA REWRITE RECORD BOOKS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-DI MATTEO HELPS CHELSEA REWRITE RECORD BOOKS.</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian Roberto Di Matteo's memorable first-minute goal and an Eddie Newton volley seven minutes from time gave Chelsea a deserved 2-0 win over Middlesbrough in a tense, closely fought English F.A. Cup Final on Saturday.</p>
<p>In a match that rewrote English Cup history, Chelsea secured their first Cup win since their only success in 1970 and meant defeat for Middlesbrough in both major domestic cup finals as well as relegation from the premier league this season.</p>
<p>Chelsea went ahead with a goal from Di Matteo officially timed at only 43 seconds -- the fastest Cup Final goal in Wembley's 74-year history.</p>
<p>Sent clear by Dennis Wise, he ran 30 metres from just inside his own half before unleashing an unstoppable 25-metre strike which flew in off the underside of Ben Roberts' crossbar giving the 21-year-old keeper no chance.</p>
<p>&quot;I was so confused at the time I didn't realise I had scored,&quot; Di Matteo said afterwards.</p>
<p>Newton clinched the victory, starting the move that led to the second goal. He passed wide to Dan Petrescu who crossed to the far post where Ginafranco Zola knocked the ball back for Newton to volley home from close range.</p>
<p>&quot;It was my first goal for 18 months, and it was worth the wait,&quot; said Newton, who was out for eight months last year after breaking a leg.</p>
<p>Middlesbrough, who lost the League Cup final a month ago and were relegated last Sunday, were bidding to become the first team to win the Cup in the same season as going down.</p>
<p>But they were knocked out of their stride after conceding the early goal and apart from a period on either side of halftime, never looked like achieving that distinction, or clinching the first major prize in their 121-year history.</p>
<p>They were unlucky when Gianluca Festa had a headed goal disallowed for offside just before halftime, and Steve Vickers went close in the second half with a shot that Frode Grodas did well to save.</p>
<p>But there was no doubting Chelsea's superiority and their deserved success on a hot, humid afternoon that visibly sapped the players' energy.</p>
<p>This was a very different performance than the one Chelsea produced when they lost 4-0 to Manchester United in the 1994 Cup Final.</p>
<p>&quot;We played a perfect, professional game today,&quot; said their Dutch coach Ruud Gullit, who became the first overseas coach to lead his side out in the final.</p>
<p>Middlesbrough manager Bryan Robson, whose multi-national team look set to disintegrate in the next few weeks, said afterwards: &quot;I'm very disappointed. We didn't perform particularly well today. It's bad enough being relegated, but losing two cup finals in the same season doesn't bear thinking about.&quot;</p>
<p>As well as di Matteo and Gullit producing Cup final records, the match also produced a record for Chelsea's Mark Hughes who became the first man for 106 years to win a fourth winner's medal and the first to do so at Wembley. He had earlier won three medals with Manchester United in 1985, 1990 and 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;It gets better and better coming here to play in the Cup final,&quot; said the 33-year-old Welshman, who was appearing in his fifth Cup final.</p>
<p>&quot;Chelsea will go on from here. We know what it takes to win a trophy now and we can build on this success.&quot;</p>
<p>There were more overseas players from nine countries represented than ever before and the match was shown live on 151 countries around the world -- another record.</p>
<p>The pre-match build-up focused on the ability of the diminutive Zola of Chelsea, the newly crowned English Player of the Year and Middlesbrough's Brazilian Juninho, the runner-up.</p>
<p>But neither player made a huge contribution to the game. For most of the first half at least, Juninho, closely watched by Newton and quickly closed down when he attempted to break, had little impact.</p>
<p>He had more influence after the break and his best moment came when he broke from his own half, carrying the ball almost into Chelsea's penalty area, when Di Matteo brought him down.</p>
<p>The goalscorer was a little fortunate just to escape with a yellow card, but Juninho's freekick summed up Middlesbrough's ineffectiveness -- he just thumped it into the Chelsea wall.</p>
<p>Juninho's compatriot Emerson also had a largely disappointing match in what could well have been his last game for the club.</p>
<p>There was also disappointment for Middlesbrough's Fabrizio Ravanelli, whose hamstring injury forced him out of the game after only 24 minutes. Five minutes later Middlesbrough lost Robbie Mustoe with a knee injury and it was hard at that stage to see any way back for Robson's men.</p>
<p>However, for about 20 minutes in the middle of the match they looked the more threatening side, and only some excellent defending by Franck Leboeuf, Frank Sinclair and Newton kept Middlesbrough at bay.</p>
<p>There were emotional scenes at the end with Chelsea's fans celebrating wildly and the TV cameras focusing on the widow of Matthew Harding, Chelsea's 42-year-old vice-chairman who was killed in a helicopter crash last October and whose money helped revitalise Chelsea after many years in the doldrums in the late 1970s and 1980s.</p>
<p>Di Matteo's goal was two seconds quicker than Jackie Milburn's opening goal for Newcastle in their 3-1 win over Manchester City in 1955 and arguably the quickest goal in Cup final history.</p>
<p>The only goal of the 1895 final was said to have been scored in &quot;around 40 seconds&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
