<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="592741" id="root" date="1997-05-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-LIONS CHASE PLACE IN SPRINGBOK HALL OF FAME.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-LIONS CHASE PLACE IN SPRINGBOK HALL OF FAME.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kitson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The nostalgia market in British Lions stories continues to do a roaring trade but the 1997 touring side cannot afford to dwell on past glories if their South African adventure is to become the stuff of rugby legend.</p>
<p>No Lions team embarking on a mission to tackle the Springboks on the high veldt can avoid the inevitable references to 1974, Willie John McBride and wild nights in Port Elizabeth hotels.</p>
<p>Even the mere sight of tour manager Fran Cotton, one of the forward bastions upon which the Lions' unbeaten record was based, invites comparisons with the old days, when rugby men were men and fire extinguishers were essential party aids.</p>
<p>This time, though, the 35-strong party are professionals to their bootlaces and rugby has changed so radically that, in terms of the laws, just about the only things that haven't moved are the goalposts.</p>
<p>Cotton has a muscular captain in Martin Johnson and has specifically chosen players with the character to cope with the special pressures the Lions will encounter on their first tour of South Africa for 17 years.</p>
<p>But he and coach Ian McGeechan know that old-fashioned tactics stand little chance of defeating the world champions, exposed to dazzling, high-speed Super 12 rugby on a weekly basis.</p>
<p>Luck with injuries and locating the right mix in midfield will be equally critical, yet McGeechan, another 1974 Lion, is primarily looking for men with the mental strength to rise to the challenge.</p>
<p>&quot;For eight weeks we become part of South Africa and we have to take on that mentality. It's the environment that we have to become part of,&quot; said McGeechan, who masterminded the Lions' 2-1 series win in Australia in 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a number of quick, talented players. What we need to do is pull them together to move on to another level, which playing in South Africa demands.&quot;</p>
<p>There are those, including Joel Stransky, who feel the Lions will be hard-pressed in the provincial games but offer a more potent threat in the tests against a Springbok side coached by Carel du Plessis, something of an unknown quantity in his new role.</p>
<p>Cotton acknowledges it as &quot;one of the toughest Lions tours in history&quot; and says the selectors &quot;only chose players who weren't going to take a step back from that challenge&quot;.</p>
<p>Welsh centre Scott Gibbs echoes his manager. &quot;When you play for the Lions it is never a party,&quot; he said. &quot;The provincial games are going to be just as tough, but we do have the right players to be victorious.&quot;</p>
<p>Should injuries strike, an unprecedented number of reserves have been placed on standby. The fate of the tour, however, rests squarely with the original choices, none more so than Gregor Townsend.</p>
<p>McGeechan earmarked his fellow Scot as test fly-half from the moment he took the job, suggesting the Lions will aim to play an expansive game.</p>
<p>Asked about his side's attitude to discipline, the 50-year-old McGeechan offered a further hint. &quot;If we play the way we want to, we won't have time to think about anything else.&quot;</p>
<p>A documentary team will follow the Lions around South Africa, making a fly-on-the-dressing-room-wall film chronicling the tour's highs and lows. Whatever the outcome, the 1997 Lions will have a story to tell.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
