<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="592864" id="root" date="1997-05-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>TANZANIA: Tanzania says it will work with Kabila in Zaire.</title>
<headline>Tanzania says it will work with Kabila in Zaire.</headline>
<dateline>DAR ES SALAAM 1997-05-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tanzania said on Saturday it would work with any government in Zaire formed by rebel leader Laurent Kabila and President Mobutu Sese Seko could keep a ceremonial title.</p>
<p>Tanzanian President Benjamin Mkapa told a news conference with visiting Finnish President Martti Ahtisaari that he had no objection to dealing with Kabila, who declared himself head of state on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will deal with him because he will be head of government,&quot; said Mkapa, adding that Mobutu giving up his power was a positive move towards a peaceful transition to democracy.</p>
<p>Mkapa said Mobutu could keep the title of president, as decided by the emergency government he left behind in Kinshasa when he flew to his northern jungle palace at Gbadolite on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;He can keep that title if it pleases him. There are places, including the United States, where former presidents are still addressed as Mr President,&quot; said Mkapa in Tanzania's capital.</p>
<p>Ahtisaari, who arrived in Dar es Salaam on Friday, leaves on Sunday with a delegation including prominent businessmen. Mkapa called for greater Nordic investment in his country.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAR ES SALAAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TANZANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
