<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="592890" id="root" date="1997-05-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>KYRGYZSTAN: Tajik talks hard going, officials say.</title>
<headline>Tajik talks hard going, officials say.</headline>
<dateline>BISHKEK 1997-05-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tajikistan's Islamist opposition said it had yet to make headway on Saturday in talks with the government on national reconciliation after a four-year civil war.</p>
<p>The talks between Tajik President Imomali Rakhmonov and opposition leader Sayid Abdullo Nuri were being held amid unprecedented security at a presidential mansion in neighbouring Kyrgyzstan.</p>
<p>&quot;No serious progress so far. There is a desire on both sides to continue talks, and we hope for a compromise,&quot; Khodzha Akbar Turadzhonzoda, deputy Tajik opposition leader, told reporters.</p>
<p>Rakhmonov and Nuri are trying to hammer out an agreement on legalising several major opposition parties, as well as the opposition press. They are also expected to discuss security guarantees for the opposition and its leaders.</p>
<p>Last December Rakhmonov's secular government and the Islamists agreed a ceasefire to end four years of civil war which killed tens of thousands of people in the Central Asian state and drove many more from their homes.</p>
<p>Military terms for the peace deal and a power-sharing agreement have been agreed. Legalisation of the opposition is the main outstanding issue.</p>
<p>Tajik presidential spokesman Zafar Saidov told reporters that Rakhmonov was ready to legalise the former Soviet republic's main opposition parties, including the Islamist Party of Revival. But he said the government demanded that armed opposition units must first disband.</p>
<p>&quot;We want the opposition to reckon with the realities of life and the will of the majority of the population, who elected the government and the president,&quot; Saidov said.</p>
<p>The press was later asked to leave the presidential mansion, and a Kyrgyz press officer said details of the talks would be made available to reporters only on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;The final agreement is likely to be signed in Moscow in the presence of the presidents of the guarantor states,&quot; Saidov said. Russia, Iran and the United Nations are the main brokers of the peace talks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KIRGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TADZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BISHKEK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KYRGYZSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
