<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="592819" id="root" date="1997-05-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Sinn Fein to talk to London/Dublin.</title>
<headline>Sinn Fein to talk to London/Dublin.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Hill</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-05-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The President of the IRA's political wing, Sinn Fein, on Saturday accepted an offer of preliminary peace talks from the new British government but ruled out any negotiation of a new IRA truce.</p>
<p>Irish Prime Minister John Bruton also gave the go-ahead for Dublin to talk to Sinn Fein but stressed the talks would be exploratory.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein leader Gerry Adams said his party, which seeks to end British rule of Northern Ireland, had contacted the British government to arrange a meeting. &quot;It should be done without delay,&quot; Adams said.</p>
<p>Adams was reacting to an initiative by Britain's new Prime Minister, Tony Blair, who on Friday softened Britain's ban on official contact with Sinn Fein and said his officials would meet the party without seeking an IRA ceasefire first.</p>
<p>Bruton followed suit on Saturday, saying in a statement: &quot;We are not going to have meetings for the sake of meetings because that would compromise the safety of this state and its people.</p>
<p>&quot;But if there is a genuine prospect of a ceasefire, a meeting can be organised to see if we can help bring that about.&quot;</p>
<p>Sinn Fein said Adams and his chief lieutenant, Martin McGuinness, would be travelling to London on Monday. They won seats in Britain's May 1 elections but have refused to take them because it would entail allegiance to Britain.</p>
<p>Adams said that he would be talking to British officials on the basis of Sinn Fein's electoral mandate. The party polled 16 per cent of votes in the Catholic, Irish nationalist community in Northern Ireland in May.</p>
<p>But he ruled out any negotiation of a new truce by the Irish Republian Army (IRA), which ended a ceasefire in February 1996 and resumed its war to end British rule of Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>&quot;I have always refused to engage in any speculation about the IRA because Sinn Fein is not the IRA and we have neither the responsibility or authority or ability to negotiate a cassefire.&quot;</p>
<p>Blair's initiative opened the door to talks which both Adams and McGuinness have called for since last year without demanding a prior IRA ceasefire.</p>
<p>The IRA has not carried out any attacks since a sniper fired a bullet through the back of a policewoman in Londonderry last month. She is recovering but was badly wounded.</p>
<p>Britain, Ireland and the U.S. administration says that the IRA must call a new, lasting truce to secure a seat for Sinn Fein at mult-party peace talks from which it is currently banned because of IRA violence.</p>
<p>McGuinness, Sinn Fein's chief negotiator, said the preliminary talks with the British government would determine whether the Belfast peace negotiations were &quot;credible.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;What we have to do is establish in those discussions with British government representatives whether or not we are going to have on offer a real, and meaningful and credible process of peace negotations,&quot; he told the BBC.</p>
<p>&quot;And if we can establish that, then we might have a case to put that persuasively to the IRA,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Adams said the Irish government which comes to power after June 6 elections should also recognise Sinn Fein's electoral mandate in the light of the Blair offer.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein says it wants the Belfast talks, which group pro-British Unionists and the SDLP Irish nationalist party, to have a set time frame and to negotiate &quot;core issues&quot; including the withdrawal of Britain's 18,000 troops from the province.</p>
<p>It fears that the talks will strengthen the hand of Unionists, who want the province to stay British, and block the way to the united Ireland Irish nationalists seek.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
