<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="592878" id="root" date="1997-05-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Rebel radio says Kabila to address Zaire.</title>
<headline>Rebel radio says Kabila to address Zaire.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-05-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zairean rebel leader Laurent Kabila will address the nation on Saturday on the rebel position on political developments and the transition of power in Zaire, rebel radio said.</p>
<p>Rebel Voice of the People radio said Kabila, leader of the Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire (AFDL), would broadcast from Zaire's second city of Lubumbashi.</p>
<p>It gave no time for the address.</p>
<p>&quot;The management of the transition will definitely be dealt with during the address,&quot; added the radio, monitored by the British Broadcasting Corporation.</p>
<p>&quot;But already, on that particular point, we all know that the ADFL's position has not changed: the transition must be conducted without Mobutu or the Mobutists and under the Alliance's leadership,&quot; the radio added.</p>
<p>On Friday, Zaire's veteran leader Mobutu Sese Seko departed the capital for his northern jungle stronghold and it was announced that he had left his emergency-rule government in charge of national policy while keeping the title of president.</p>
<p>Kabila earlier on Saturday told Reuters his forces, singing as they marched, were entering the Zairean capital Kinshasa from the airport about 25 km (16 miles) away.</p>
<p>There was no confirmation of the report.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
