<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="592888" id="root" date="1997-05-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish PM lauds constitution ahead of vote.</title>
<headline>Polish PM lauds constitution ahead of vote.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-05-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz on Saturday praised Poland's new draft constitution and rebuffed its critics ahead of a national referendum set for May 25.</p>
<p>&quot;We face the prospect of having a basic law friendly to people that does not impose a worldview or way of life on anyone,&quot; he said on prime time public television.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a mature and modern constitution...guaranteeing basic rights and liberties...which, in addition to those found in all democratic constitutions, contains certain new rights.</p>
<p>These include the right of  citizens to lodge complaints with a special tribunal, if they feel their constitutional rights have been violated.</p>
<p>&quot;Every group of 100,000 citizens will now have the right the submit their own bills to parliament,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But Cimoszewicz, an ex-communist, said he was irritated by what he called &quot;nonsensical arguments&quot; against the constitution.</p>
<p>&quot;They include scaring people that their children will be taken away, the Church will be persecuted and Poland will lose its sovereignty.&quot;</p>
<p>In the referendum, Poles will be able to approve or reject the parliamentary draft. Parliament has refused to consider a proposal to include an alternative draft prepared by the right-leaning Solidarity movement.</p>
<p>The pro-Catholic right has criticised the draft for not giving precedence to &quot;natural law&quot; (Christian values) over man-made legislation and failing to protect human life from the moment of conception.</p>
<p>It also complains that the draft constitution limits the influence of trade unions in solving labour disputes.</p>
<p>&quot;Together, on May 25, we shall decide the fate of a good constitution, of which we will not have to be ashamed either tomorrow or many years from now,&quot; Cimoszewicz concluded his address.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
