<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="593167" id="root" date="1997-05-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-YANKEES' 20 HITS BEAT RANGERS 11-5.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-YANKEES' 20 HITS BEAT RANGERS 11-5.</headline>
<dateline>ARLINGTON, Texas 1997-05-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bernie Williams went 4-for-4 with four RBI and Tino Martinez and Paul O'Neill homered in a six-run first inning to lead the New York Yankees to a 20-hit, 11-5 rout of the Texas Rangers on Saturday.</p>
<p>Martinez's 17th homer, a three-run shot off starter John Burkett (2-3), increased his major-league leading RBI total to 50. O'Neill added his eighth homer two batters later.</p>
<p>Williams had four run-scoring singles before leaving for a pinch runner in the seventh.</p>
<p>Cecil Fielder also had four hits and O'Neill and Tim Raines added three hits apiece for the Yankees, who won their ninth of 11 games.</p>
<p>In Kansas City, Tim Pugh allowed three hits over eight innings in his 1997 debut and Tony Clark homered twice as the Detroit Tigers trounced the Kansas City Royals 9-2 for their fifth win in seven games.</p>
<p>Pugh was called up Tuesday from Triple-A Toledo, where he was 3-1 with a 3.65 ERA.</p>
<p>Clark hit a two-run homer that capped a four-run third inning and added a solo shot in the eighth, his 16th for the season.</p>
<p>At Minnesota, Tom Gordon pitched a four-hitter for his first complete game and shutout of the season, and the Boston Red Sox halted a seven-game losing streak by blanking the floundering Minnesota Twins 4-0.</p>
<p>Gordon limited the Twins to three singles and a double with four walks and 10 strikeouts.</p>
<p>Terry Steinbach had two hits for the Twins, who have lost eight of their last 11 games and 19 of 25.</p>
<p>In Oakland, Dave Martinez hit a three-run homer and Frank Thomas went 3-for-3 with three RBI as the Chicago White Sox continued their dominance over the Oakland Athletics with a 7-6 victory.</p>
<p>The White Sox have won seven straight games against the Athletics and are 6-0 against them this season.</p>
<p>Chicago nursed a one-run lead into the fifth inning until Martinez broke the game open with his third homer of the season to put the White Sox ahead, 7-3.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd say the last couple of weeks I'm starting to hit the ball pretty good,&quot; said Martinez.  &quot;It's good to win a couple of games, let's hope we finish strong tomorrow.&quot;</p>
<p>Danny Darwin, 41, picked up his first American League win since August 21st, 1995. He allowed four runs and six hits in six innings.</p>
<p>&quot;I think I've thrown the ball well enough to have three or four wins, but it just hasn't worked out,&quot; said Darwin.</p>
<p>Steve Karsay fell to 0-5 after giving up seven runs in just 4 1/3 innings. Oakland has lost nine of its last 11 games.</p>
<p>In Toronto, Albie Lopez pitched five scoreless innings for his first win of the year and Jim Thome blasted a grand slam to lead the Cleveland Indians to an 8-1 victory over the Toronto Blue Jays.</p>
<p>Lopez scattered three hits and one walk with four strikeouts.</p>
<p>&quot;Any time our team puts up a four spot, you can relax a bit and pitch your game,&quot; said Lopez. &quot;I did good. I did what I had to do. I threw strikes. I tried to put the ball in play.&quot;</p>
<p>Thome, who was 4-for-22 prior to the grand slam, hit the first homer off Williams in 36 innings.</p>
<p>In Anaheim, Darin Erstad's RBI single in the bottom of the eighth inning capped a comeback from a five-run deficit as the Anaheim Angels edged the Milwaukee Brewers 6-5 for their sixth straight win.</p>
<p>The Angels rallied from a 5-0 deficit for the third time this week and notched their 13th come-from-behind victory of the season.</p>
<p>Four Anaheim relievers combined for 5 1/3 scoreless innings after starter Allen Watson yielded five runs and eight hits in 3 2/3 frames.</p>
<p>In Seattle, Jimmy Key went 5 2/3 innings to become the first eight-game winner in the majors and B.J. Surhoff homered as the Baltimore Orioles held on for a 4-3 victory over the Seattle Mariners.</p>
<p>Key (8-0), who has won his last six starts, allowed one run and six hits, walking three and striking out three. He has given up just three runs in his last 27 innings. The left-hander has a 1.80 ERA.</p>
<p>Surhoff went 3-for-4 with two RBI for Baltimore.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ARLINGTON, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
