<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="593255" id="root" date="1997-05-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - May 25.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - May 25.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the major events to have occurred on May 25 in history:</p>
<p>1787 - A convention under George Washington met for the first time to draw up the new U.S. constitution.</p>
<p>1803 - Ralph Waldo Emerson, American poet, essayist and leading exponent of New England Transcendentalism, born.</p>
<p>1810 - A revolution began in Rio de la Plata (later Argentina), when an autonomous government was set up in Buenos Aires.</p>
<p>1826 - Tom Sayers, bare-knuckled English pugilist who once took part in a 42-round fight over two hours, born.</p>
<p>1879 - Lord Beaverbrook, English statesman and newspaper owner, born as William Maxwell Aitken. He was a cabinet minister in both World Wars and owned the Daily and Sunday Express newspapers.</p>
<p>1889 - Igor Sikorsky, Russian-born aeronautical engineer and inventor of the helicopter, born.</p>
<p>1895 - Writer Oscar Wilde was sentenced to two years hard labour in Britain for being a sodomite.</p>
<p>1897 - Gene Tunney, American heavyweight boxing champion, born as James Joseph Tunney.</p>
<p>1911 - President Porfirio Diaz resigned after revolutionist forces defeated government troops in the Mexican Civil War.</p>
<p>1915 - In Europe, the second Battle of Ypres ended with casualties around 105,000. The Germans used poison gas for the first time.</p>
<p>1923 - Britain recognised the country of Transjordan with Abdullah as its leader; On this day in 1946 a new treaty recognised it as a sovereign state called Jordan with Abdullah as King.</p>
<p>1926 - Miles Davis, U.S. jazz trumpeter and composer, born.</p>
<p>1929 - Beverley Sills, U.S. operatic soprano renowned for her role in &quot;La Traviata&quot;, born.</p>
<p>1934 - Gustav Holst, English composer notably of the suite &quot;The Planets&quot;, died.</p>
<p>1935 - American athlete Jesse Owens set six world records in 45 minutes.</p>
<p>1951 - Guy Burgess and Donald Maclean, British foreign office officials, disappeared from London. It was later discovered they had spied for Russia.</p>
<p>1963 - A summit conference of African states ended in Addis Ababa with agreement to set up the Organisation of African Unity.</p>
<p>1969 - The Sudanese government was overthrown in a military coup led by Col. Jaafar Nimeiri.</p>
<p>1979 - America's worst-ever air disaster occurred when a DC-10 crashed at Chicago's O'Hare airport killing 273.</p>
<p>1983 - A fire on board three vessels on a trip on the Upper Nile in Egypt killed over 300 people.</p>
<p>1986 - 30 million people worldwide joined in Bob Geldof's &quot;Race Against Time&quot; to raise money for the starving in Africa.</p>
<p>1989 - Mikhail Gorbachev was elected to the new post of Executive President in the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>1990 - Winnie Mandela's chief bodyguard, Jerry Richardson, was found guilty of the murder of 14-year-old Stompie Seipei.</p>
<p>1991 - 15,000 Falashas - Ethiopia Jews - were airlifted from Addis Ababa to Israel as rebel forces approached the Ethiopian capital.</p>
<p>1992 - Veteran Italian politician Oscar Luigi Scalfaro was elected President.</p>
<p>1993 - Guatemalan President Jorge Serrano dissolved congress and suspended the constitution amid fears of a coup.</p>
<p>1994 -  Russian writer Alexander Solzhenitsyn, ending a 20-year exile in the West, left his home in Cavendish, Vermont to begin his long journey back to Russia.</p>
<p>1995 - A major flare-up in the Bosnian war began when NATO launched air strikes against ammunition bunkers near Pale.</p>
<p>1996 - Bulgaria's King Simeon II came home after 50 years of exile to a rapturous welcome from royalist crowds and a cold-shoulder from the socialist government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
