<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="59335" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. knew of N. Korean holding POWs in 1953 - report.</title>
<headline>U.S. knew of N. Korean holding POWs in 1953 - report.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States knew at the end of the Korean War that North Korea failed to turn over more than 900 surviving American prisoners, the New York Times reported on Tuesday, citing newly declassified documents.</p>
<p>The Pentagon knew in December 1953 that the U.S. troops were still alive at the end of the conflict but were never released, the article said.</p>
<p>The documents were obtained from the Dwight D. Eisenhower Presidential Library and other government files by the House of Representatives National Security subcommittee.</p>
<p>The subcommittee will meet on Tuesday and will hear testimony from a Czechoslovakian defector, Jan Sejna, who now works for the U.S. Defence Intelligence Agency.</p>
<p>Sejna was a defence official for the former Czechoslovakia, and had access to information about medical experiments carried out on American prisoners by Russia and Czechoslovakia. He said the prisoners were drugged in experiments aimed at testing interrogation techniques and then subsequently executed.</p>
<p>One memo obtained from the Eisenhower library said the U.S. Army thought that 610 Army personnel and 300 U.S. Air Force personnel were still being held a prisoners five months after the war ended with an armistice on July 27, 1953.</p>
<p>The U.S. Defence Department has said it does not have any evidence that Americans are still being held against their will, something also denied by the North Korean government, the Times said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
