<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="593336" id="root" date="1997-05-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenya interests rates seen unlikely to drop.</title>
<headline>Kenya interests rates seen unlikely to drop.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-05-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Daniel arap Moi's government wants to lower the high interest rates which are deterring investment in Kenya. But drought, excess government spending and election jitters will jeopardise the objective, diplomats and financial experts said.</p>
<p>World Bank Vice-President for Africa Callisto Madavo said after meeting Moi and his senior economic managers last week that there was a genuine government commitment to lower high interest rates that undermine investment.</p>
<p>&quot;The leaders do not want to keep the rates as high as they are. They know what the effects of the high rates are on investment and would like to act about it,&quot; Madavo said.</p>
<p>But Professor Joseph Kimura of the private Institute of Policy Analysis and Research said drought that ended in March, elections this year and a central bank policy of single-digit inflation all undermined hopes of lower interest rates.</p>
<p>Kenya holds presidential and parliamentary elections this year. Financial experts say such elections in Africa mean great uncertainty and interest rates are unlikely to drop.</p>
<p>On Saturday, Moi said he would win the polls and retire from politics at the end of a five-year term, in the year 2002.</p>
<p>Lending rates in commercial banks stand in the 25-35 percent range while mortgage rates average 30-40 percent. Commercial banks say their rates are pegged to benchmark 91-day T-bills which have yielded 20-24 percent over the last year.</p>
<p>Kimura said that income disparities between the rich and the poor, perceived insecurity, declining quality of life, banking inefficiencies, a low level of trust in government policies and the sorry state of Kenya's infrastructure also helped keep interest rates at their current levels.</p>
<p>&quot;If anything drastic happens to the agricultural sector, prices in that sector will go up as they are doing now due to drought that affected most areas of the country,&quot; Kimura said.</p>
<p>Three-month annualised inflation eased to 32.5 percent in April from 35.6 percent in March, while the month-on-month annualised rate rose to 16.1 percent in April from 15.6 percent in March.</p>
<p>Monthly annualised inflation was only 7.0 percent in February of last year, according to central bank figures.</p>
<p>&quot;The position is that a range of interest rates of 25-35 percent is not inconsistent with the current economic reality in the country. Lower rates are not tenable,&quot; Kimura said.</p>
<p>But last week, Governor Micah Cheserem of the Central Bank of Kenya (CBK) said he saw no justification for high rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The level of interest rates amounts to killing the goose that lays the golden egg,&quot; Cheserem said, blaming commercial banks for the high interest rates that appear poised to rise.</p>
<p>Alexander Kaminchia, Executive Chairman at leading retail bankers Kenya Commercial Bank, said &quot;Interest rates remain stubborn at high levels which adversely affect lending.&quot;</p>
<p>Commercial banks argued that if the government significantly reduced its borrowing, it would not have to pay high interest on treasury bills and the market would adjust accordingly.</p>
<p>Government officials have said that drought relief is the reason for excess spending. Independent economists said slow progress in privatising state utilities meant the cash to cover the budget deficit was slow in coming.</p>
<p>The Nairobi Stock Exchange Chairman Jimnah Mbaru said many fund managers were targetting their &quot;cheap money&quot; for Kenya's treasury bills which guaranteed them excessively high returns.</p>
<p>Madavo said infrastructure and rates posed Kenya's biggest headaches, with the state of roads, the energy sector, posts and telecommunications and water all affecting investment decisions.</p>
<p>&quot;These things are in a poor state in Kenya,&quot; Madavo said. &quot;Kenya has the potential and ability to do far better.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
