<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="593478" id="root" date="1997-05-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korean Kasan acquires U.S. firm to go global.</title>
<headline>S.Korean Kasan acquires U.S. firm to go global.</headline>
<byline>Yoo Choon-sik</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-05-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's Kasan Electronics Co believes its recent acquisition of a Silicon Valley company provides a much-needed channel into the exploding global market for computer multimedia add-in cards.</p>
<p>Kasan officials said its teamwork with Jazz Multimedia Inc proved fruitful when their joint booth at the '97 CeBIT show, held in March in Hanover, Germany, drew an overwhelming response from foreign buyers.</p>
<p>During the world's largest multimedia and communication trade show, Kasan negotiated orders worth $45 million for product ranging from video graphics array (VGA) cards and modems to digital video disc (DVD) players.</p>
<p>In early March Kasan took over a 52 percent stake in Jazz Multimedia, the seventh-largest multimedia firm in the United States, with an option to buy a further eight percent this year.</p>
<p>Founded in 1993, Jazz posted $10 million in sales last year, offering a variety of MPEG (motion picture experts group) cards and VGA boards, including the market hit G-Force series.</p>
<p>&quot;We have already been in need of a U.S. subsidary and were actually considering opening one before we decided to take over Jazz,&quot; Kasan's founder and chief executive Oh Bong-hwan said.</p>
<p>Oh said the combination of Kasan's technical capability and Jazz's expertise in international marketing would help the company realise its dream of conquering the world market.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we've become able to concentrate on research, development and production because Jazz will provide powerful support in marketing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He forecast sales would rise to a minimum of 80 billion won ($89.6 million) this year from 40 billion won in 1996, with its net profit growing to seven billion won from 4.06 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;In this sector, forecasting something is very difficult because the market is on the brink of explosion,&quot; said Oh.</p>
<p>He said the world market for DVD players was estimated to grow to a minimum of $80 million per year from almost none at present and Kasan's share would reach $10-$40 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody knows how much the market's maximum value would be as the market is now growing at a pace which people hardly expected,&quot; said Oh.</p>
<p>Analysts agreed with Oh, saying the multimedia sector was still in its infancy.</p>
<p>&quot;The sector is changing day by day and the future growth potential is almost limitless,&quot; said Kim Ik-hwan, an analyst at Hyundai Securities.</p>
<p>Kasan's family of VGA cards range from the low-end Xper 64 which supports all the basic multimedia functions to the WinX Perfect series of multimedia boards.</p>
<p>Kasan has recently obtained Microsoft Windows 95 logo licences for its five VGA board models -- WinX Perfect II and IV, WinX Pro, and Xyper 64 and 64T.</p>
<p>At the moment, VGA cards account for 70 percent of Kasan's total sales with modems and sound cards the remainder.</p>
<p>Once the DVD market is properly in place, DVD boards will make up 40 percent of Kasan's total sales, VGA cards 40 percent, modems 15 percent and sound cards five percent.</p>
<p>Oh said its ultimate goal was to combine the functions of modems, DVD players, sound cards, VGA cards and control of electronic home devices into a single unit of set-top box.</p>
<p>&quot;We are maintaining R&amp;D spending at six to eight percent of annual sales, among the highest by any standards,&quot; said Oh.</p>
<p>Last September, Kasan obtained listing on South Korea's over-the-counter market, Kosdaq. The company plans to list its shares on the Korea Stock Exchange early next year.</p>
<p>On the Kosdaq, Kasan's shares are now trading at 70,000 won per share, compared with 60,000-65,000 won for the country's electronics giant, Samsung Electronics Co.</p>
<p>(Conversion: $1 = 893 won)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
