<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="593474" id="root" date="1997-05-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Report warns Vietnam reform benefits wearing thin.</title>
<headline>Report warns Vietnam reform benefits wearing thin.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Edwards</byline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-05-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The benefits of Vietnam's decade-old economic transformation may be close to exhaustion without reforms in trade and a rethink of policies which favour state enterprises, Swedish economists have warned.</p>
<p>A report by the Stockholm School of Economics and European Institute of Japanese Studies released on Sunday called on the communist government to restate urgently its commitment to foreign trade liberalisation.</p>
<p>It said Hanoi would need to engage in active export promotion using efficient exchange rate policies and work to tackle a trade environmment &quot;characterised by a large degree of uncertainty&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential benefits of past reforms are nearly exhausted,&quot; it said. &quot;... further change is needed to sustain macroeconomic stability and a high rate of economic growth.&quot;</p>
<p>The report added that while policy was biased in favour of large import-substituting state-owned enterprises (SOEs), it was &quot;crucially important&quot; that this should not be the basis for long-term investment decisions.</p>
<p>&quot;... it is not much of an exaggeration to characterise the present financial situation of the SOE sector as a time bomb,&quot; it said, adding that in 1995 the sector's aggregate debt amounted to around $24 billion, some 20 percent more than aggregate turnover.</p>
<p>It said a key problem was opposition among state firms and foreign multinationals to policies favouring trade liberalisation due to vested interests in keeping Vietnam's markets protected.</p>
<p>Vietnam, which joined the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) in 1995, has committed itself to meeting reduced tariff requirements of the ASEAN Free Trade Area (AFTA) by 2006, three years after the rest of the regional grouping.</p>
<p>But the report warned that little had been done so far and said that unless policy contradictions were recognised, there was a risk that Hanoi would not be able to meet its AFTA commitments.</p>
<p>Vietnam introduced free market reforms in 1986 following the failure of a Soviet-style command economy.</p>
<p>The result was spectacular economic lift-off a couple of years later accompanied by social reforms and growing overseas respectability for a country which had been regarded as a virtual international pariah.</p>
<p>But the merits of reform have come under scrutiny in the past two years, with mismanagement of the process being blamed for emerging social and economic problems.</p>
<p>A growing trade gap, which was around 15 percent of gross domestic product, has spurred calls for policies of import substitution.</p>
<p>The report said that despite government commitments to the contrary it was &quot;no exaggeration to claim that the Vietnamese trade regime remains complex and highly restrictive&quot;.</p>
<p>It said that in the short term Hanoi needed to restate its commitment to liberalising foreign trade and make its policy environment more predictable.</p>
<p>In addition it said the authorities would have to engage in active export promotion over the coming decade to curb the costs of trade reform in terms of unemployment, lower budget revenues and slower growth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
