<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="593669" id="root" date="1997-05-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India shares seen easy ahead of oil price increase.</title>
<headline>India shares seen easy ahead of oil price increase.</headline>
<byline>Anshuman Daga</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-05-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Looming uncertainty about an impending increase in Indian government-set oil prices is expected to keep buyers away from stock markets this week, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market should take a decent run, but only after the bad news is out,&quot; Prashant Purker, head of institutional sales at Peregrine Capital told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;People want the oil price hike to get off the list.&quot;</p>
<p>The steering committee of India's coalition government will meet on May 25 to raise prices of oil that it imports but sells to domestic customers at below world prices.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral and Finance Minister P. Chidambaram have said the government must decide soon how to pay off money owed to oil companies, which totalled 155 billion rupees ($4.3 billion) at the end of March, for selling subsidised petroleum products below market prices.</p>
<p>Uncertainty over the timing of the hike has made market players jittery, traders say, though analysts have already factored in higher oil prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The long term outlook remains good, but in the short run, there are some reservations about the oil price rise,&quot; said Girish Desai, research head at brokerage Prabhudas Lilladher.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears that the government is not in a position to take a decision on the oil price increase and that is a dampener for the markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Bombay's top 30-share index lost 9.70 points last week to close at 3,759.64.</p>
<p>Small cap stocks driven by cheaper valuations are likely to remain in the spotlight, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has gone totally stock specific,&quot; said Ashish Kacholia, head of research at Prime Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a clear-cut demarcation between two types of companies -- the efficient users of capital such as software and engineering and relatively inefficient users of capital like commodity firms, petrochemicals, cement, steel, paper and tyres,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Investors have become more selective, focussing on bargain-priced stocks after a spate of company results showed the effects of an economic slowdown and tighter margins, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sectors that can be bought at current levels are software and pharmaceuticals,&quot; said Prabhudas Lilladhers' Desai.</p>
<p>&quot;These stocks remain evergreen and are not hit by the oil price hike.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We still remain convinced of the bullishness of the market, which has now spread across a wider range of stocks,&quot; brokerage Khandwala Securities said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the market to touch the 4,000 level in the next two months,&quot; it said in a report.</p>
<p>Earnings announcements for fiscal 1996/97 (April-March) are due this week from India's largest private steel maker, Tata Iron &amp; Steel Company Ltd (TISCO) and tobacco conglomerate ITC Ltd</p>
<p>&quot;There are investment opportunities available,&quot; said Prime's Kacholia. &quot;The market should turn bullish after the oil price increase.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
