<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="593658" id="root" date="1997-05-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Hindu party is betting on mid-term polls.</title>
<headline>India's Hindu party is betting on mid-term polls.</headline>
<byline>Sabyasachi Mitra</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-05-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's political picture is growing murkier with the main opposition Hindu party expecting the government to tumble before year's end and dissent deepening within the ruling coalition.</p>
<p>The Congress party, which reluctantly provides key support for Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral's government, offers little succour to the ruling coalition, analysts said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The largest single group in parliament's lower house, the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), is racing to position itself for mid-term elections it is convinced will be called later this year.</p>
<p>BJP president Lal Krishna Advani is set to begin a march across the nation later on Sunday that is a thinly veiled start to the party's campaign to woo more voters.</p>
<p>&quot;Naturally the impact of it (the march) will go to build the image of the party,&quot; BJP vice-president Jana Krishnamurthy told Reuters.</p>
<p>Opinion polls favour the BJP, which now holds 162 of the 545 seats in the Lok Sabha, in the event an election.</p>
<p>Advani is trying to repeat history.</p>
<p>A similar march he led in 1991 saw a surge in the BJP's fortunes; the party grabbed 120 seats in elections that year, up from 86 in the previous parliament.</p>
<p>BJP leaders say they are convinced Gujral's centre-left coalition is short-lived and will tumble by the year-end.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect elections to take place any time between October and February,&quot; Krishnamurthy said.</p>
<p>A mid-term election could be the best shot at power for the BJP, whose hardline Hindu credentials are viewed with suspicion by the other parties in India's political spectrum.</p>
<p>&quot;Elections are the only hope for the BJP,&quot; said Rasheed Talib, an independent political analyst.</p>
<p>The BJP's hopes rose after disaffection grew within Gujral's fractious Janata Dal party, the largest in the ruling coalition, and corruption charges were levelled against its chief.</p>
<p>Federal police have sought permission to prosecute Laloo Prasad Yadav, the Janata Dal president who is also chief minister of the crime-ridden eastern state of Bihar, in connection with a $280 million animal-feed scandal.</p>
<p>The cracks in Gujral's government, which managed to get a trail-blazing budget for the 1997/98 (April-March) fiscal year approved by parliament last week, were embarrassingly evident last Friday when parliament adjourned until July.</p>
<p>Janata Dal lawmakers angrily tried to prevent Gujral from moving a bill seeking to provide a 33 percent quota for women in the lower house and in state legislatures. The government later managed to move the bill for debate.</p>
<p>&quot;The divisions within Janata Dal will only help to bring the elections closer,&quot; said Talib.</p>
<p>The waters have been muddied further by the entry of Sonia Gandhi, the Italian widow of former prime minister Rajiv Gandhi, into the Congress party earlier this month.</p>
<p>Sonia Gandhi's emergence from six years of seclusion after her husband was assassinated by a Tamil suicide bomber could imply a move to reassert authority over the tired and weak party dominated for over four decades by the Nehru-Gandhi family.</p>
<p>That may not be welcome to a Congress leadership that has learnt to live without the family's charisma.</p>
<p>&quot;The dissensions within the Congress are likely to be more embarrassing,&quot; said B.G. Verghese, a political analyst at the independent Centre for Policy Research.</p>
<p>All this ferment can only benefit the BJP, which probably has the most disciplined cadres in India's heaving political landscape.</p>
<p>Advani's march, cleverly pegged to the 50th anniversary of India's freedom from British colonial rule, aims to cash in on the stability factor.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
