<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="593621" id="root" date="1997-05-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian separatists fly flag from Venice belltower.</title>
<headline>Italian separatists fly flag from Venice belltower.</headline>
<dateline>VENICE, Italy 1997-05-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A small group of supporters of Italy's separatist Northern League on Sunday flew their party's flag from the top of the the belltower in Venice where an armed band staged a bizarre separatist stunt nine days ago.</p>
<p>Police said several dozen League supporters tried to gain access to the landmark in St Mark's Square after a rally addressed by leader Umberto Bossi.</p>
<p>A small group was eventually allowed up after paying the entrance fee. Once at the top, they hung out a white and green League flag, emblazoned with the symbol of a sun.</p>
<p>A police spokesman said no-one had been arrested. &quot;It was just a demonstration,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Venice's world-famous belltower, one of the most recognisable symbols of the city, was the scene of a dramatic siege and raid on May 9.</p>
<p>Eight armed men, claiming to be members of the &quot;Venetian Liberation Army&quot;, took over the belltower for five hours until police stormed in and arrested them. No shots were fired.</p>
<p>The incident was linked to the 200th anniversary on May 12 of the fall of the Venetian empire.</p>
<p>The eight are due to stand trial from May 21 on charges of kidnapping for subversive ends after they hijacked a ferry to take them and a home-made armoured vehicle to the square. They could face a prison sentence of 30 years if convicted.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VENICE, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
