<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="593632" id="root" date="1997-05-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Albanian future at stake over vote - Italy's Prodi.</title>
<headline>Albanian future at stake over vote - Italy's Prodi.</headline>
<dateline>MODENA, Italy 1997-05-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi said on Sunday he had told Albania's political parties that the whole future of their country was at stake in a crisis over planned elections.</p>
<p>&quot;In these days, in the last few hours, I have continued to have contact with all the Albanian parties and the different forces represented in Albania to highlight to them the importance of an accord to hold the elections on time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I told them that the future of the country was at stake and that only by undertaking reconstruction from the inside could it achieve peace and a political and economic relaunch,&quot; Prodi told reporters in the northern town of Modena.</p>
<p>Albania plunged into violent unrest earlier this year after the collapse of high-yielding pyramid investment schemes in which thousands of people lost their life savings.</p>
<p>Political parties issued an ultimatum to President Sali Berisha on Saturday, demanding changes in what they said were flawed electoral laws pushed through parliament by Berisha's rightist Democratic Party, which has a huge majority.</p>
<p>Berisha has called the election for June 29 but most of the parties in Prime Minister Bashkim Fino's national unity government have threatened to boycott the vote.</p>
<p>Western governments have warned that aid depends on a deal leading to free and fair elections. Italy, leader of a multinational troop force to protect aid supplies, has said it may pull out unless the elections go ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole international community is waiting for an effort of unity from the Albanian people so that the efforts being made by the international community can bear fruit,&quot; Prodi said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MODENA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
