<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="594060" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOTSWANA: BOTSWANA STOCKS WEEK - DOMESTIC MKT CONTINUES STRONG.</title>
<headline>BOTSWANA STOCKS WEEK - DOMESTIC MKT CONTINUES STRONG.</headline>
<dateline>GABORONE 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>All but three of the 12 domestic</p>
<p>stocks listed on the Botswana Stock Exchange (BSE) traded up</p>
<p>last week as the market gained 17.11 points to close at 459.86</p>
<p>points.</p>
<p>Brewery holding company Sechaba jumped 9.3 per cent</p>
<p>to close at 350 thebe on the back of a large order from an</p>
<p>overseas institutional investor while Barclays </p>
<p>continued its strong run and ended up 20 thebe at 750 thebe.</p>
<p>Standard Chartered advanced 45 thebe to close at 630</p>
<p>thebe and Botswana Insurance rose 25 thebe to 245 thebe</p>
<p>following good results.</p>
<p>First National traded up 10 thebe to 510. A large</p>
<p>block of investment company Kgolo ya Sechaba traded at</p>
<p>190 thebe, up five thebe on the week.</p>
<p>Food and tobacco wholesaler Metsef climbed 10 thebe</p>
<p>to close at 660 thebe, clothing chain Pep rose five</p>
<p>thebe to finish the week at 305 thebe and milling company and</p>
<p>food wholesaler Sefalana continued its good run closing</p>
<p>the week at 445 thebe.</p>
<p>Unchanged were security group Inco trading at 90</p>
<p>thebe and variable loan stock counter RDC Properties at</p>
<p>170 thebe.</p>
<p>Engen was untraded at 445/475 thebe.</p>
<p>Turnover was down with 563,475 shares changing hands from</p>
<p>864,745 previously, valued at 1,701,510 pula over 3,780,322 pula</p>
<p>before.</p>
<p>On the foreign, dual-listed board, De Beers was the</p>
<p>only counter traded, in a small parcel of 320 shares at 12,719</p>
<p>thebe, but down 35 thebe on the week.</p>
<p>The foreign index dropped a fraction of a point to close at</p>
<p>391.85 from 392.50.</p>
<p>The overall index also closed fractionally down at 393.59</p>
<p>against 393.80 a week ago.</p>
<p>-- Gaborone newsroom +267 347-182</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GABORONE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOTSWANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
