<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="594083" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECH CBANK MOVES MAY NOT STOP A DEVALUATION - ANALYSTS.</title>
<headline>CZECH CBANK MOVES MAY NOT STOP A DEVALUATION - ANALYSTS.</headline>
<byline>Alan Crosby</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Recent Czech central bank rate hikes to support its beleaguered currency are a costly short-term measure and may be insufficient to prevent a devaluation of the crown, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>After raising its Lombard rate on Friday to 50 percent from a previous 14 percent, the CNB, which insists a devaluation is not on the cards, on Monday held three repo tenders all at a maximum rate of 45 percent, up from 12.9 percent on Friday.</p>
<p>The moves appeared to hit their mark with the crown steadying at about 2.8 percent below parity of the central bank's mark/dollar basket by midday after trading between -2.9 to -3.1 ahead of the rate rise and -3.8 percent on Friday.</p>
<p>But analysts warned the measures come with a heavy monetary cost -- on top of an estimated $500 million to $1 billion in direct market intervention -- as well as an economic impact that the country can ill afford.</p>
<p>&quot;The open market interventions are extremely short-term measures and very costly, and didn't work. The rate hike may deter for a short period, but it simply stops the economy from running,&quot; said Jiri Krovak, an economist at Wood and Company.</p>
<p>Last week the crown fell below the five percent level of its basket parity, prompting the CNB to intervene on the market for the first time in more than a year. But this failed to stem the tide of bearish sentiment against the crown, forcing the central bank to raise rates late on Friday.</p>
<p>The central bank has said the crown's fall is due to fluctuations on financial markets abroad.</p>
<p>Krovak and others said the crown has simply become over- valued in recent months, and a devaluation of the currency has more or less become inevitable.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think that it is necessary to devalue by something like 15 percent, a better solution would be to devalue by somewhere between five and 10 percent,&quot; Krovak said.</p>
<p>Added Jan Svejnar, head of the Economics Institute of the Czech Academy of Sciences: &quot;(Intervention) is a short-term solution and it is negative as it wastes wealth, reserves, and certain devaluation would be positive for exports and a revival of the economy.&quot;</p>
<p>After years of consumption-led growth, the Czech economy has shown signs of heading toward a recession in recent months.</p>
<p>In the first three months of 1997, official data showed real industrial output falling 4.2 percent compared with the first quarter of 1996 and construction output fell 5.2 percent.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus said on Monday that preliminary data showed Czech exports grew 25.9 percent in April, narrowing the trade deficit for the month to 11.4 billion crowns from 13.4 billion in March.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope this is news to which the foreign exchange markets will react positively,&quot; Klaus told a news conference.</p>
<p>Pavel Sobisek of Zivnostenska Banka said the trade data could help determine the direction of the crown but added that the pressure on the crown was more linked to speculation than economic fundamentals.</p>
<p>&quot;I would give about a 50 percent chance that the central bank will manage to withstand the pressure and not be forced to devalue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The government rejects any talk of a crisis, while the independent central bank, determined to keep up the battle against inflation, is adamant there will be no devaluation.</p>
<p>However, Klaus does acknowledge there will be almost no growth in the economy this quarter and he has admitted that full year GDP growth of 2.7 percent, half the government's original 1997 forecast, would be a &quot;success&quot;.</p>
<p>In response to the downturn, the government introduced a package of measures to boost growth by supporting exports and slashing public spending to balance the budget.</p>
<p>It also promised to regulate the capital markets better and tackle economic crime, seen as undermining general confidence in the economy and shutting off new capital to industries.</p>
<p>But so far, the government's plans have failed to impress the markets, and last week, investors pushed the crown lower in a wave of short selling, pushing it to a record low of five percent on the depreciation side of its basket parity.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now it (the crown) looks fine, I don't expect any big changes in the crown rate,&quot; said one local trader. &quot;But the solutions were only for the short-term, the central bank must follow up if it wants peace for the crown.&quot;</p>
<p>The central bank fixed the crown at 30.548 against the dollar and at 18.026 to the mark on Monday, implying a deviation of 2.7 percent below basket parity, after -3.8 percent on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 420-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
