<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="594054" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-STUNNED FRANCE CANNOT BELIEVE CANTONA HAS QUIT.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-STUNNED FRANCE CANNOT BELIEVE CANTONA HAS QUIT.</headline>
<byline>Francois Thomazeau</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>France was so taken aback by the announcement that Eric Cantona was retiring that many of the country's leading soccer figures just did not believe it.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not sure that he is quitting. Big stars bid farewell more than once. It's one of his first goodbyes, I'm sure they will be encores,&quot; said Auxerre coach Guy Roux, who discovered Cantona in Marseille and offered him his first professional contract in 1983.</p>
<p>&quot;I will wait for his departure to be confirmed the more so as I'm used to surprises with Cantona,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Roux said he had talked to the Manchester United striker after his team's 1-0 loss to Borussia Dortmund in a European Cup semifinal second leg earlier this month and he had made no hint about retirement.</p>
<p>The decision by the 30-year-old Cantona was announced at a news conference at United's Old Trafford ground by club chairman Martin Edwards.</p>
<p>Cantona, who will be 31 on Saturday, has had a moderate season for United, although the club retained the English premier league title -- their fourth league triumph in five seasons.</p>
<p>Roux has grounds for believing that Cantona may again be misleading his fans.</p>
<p>In December 1991, the player announced he was retiring after being banned for throwing a ball at a referee.</p>
<p>&quot;I quit, I can't stand football any more,&quot; he said at the time.</p>
<p>Instead, Cantona, who had just endured one of his worst seasons with Nimes, moved to England and became one of the biggest foreign stars ever to play in the premier league.</p>
<p>Sunday's decision was all the more surprising for French fans as it came just one year before the start of the 1998 World Cup, the biggest soccer event ever to be staged in France.</p>
<p>For most French people, Cantona should have been the man to lead France in their World Cup campaign.</p>
<p>In a poll published in March, Cantona, who last played for France in a January 1995 friendly against the Netherlands, was named by 76 percent of respondents as their first choice in France's ideal team.</p>
<p>If his departure turns out to be definite, the &quot;enfant terrible&quot; of French soccer will undoubtedly be courted by the French media.</p>
<p>In 1994, he commented on the World Cup for state channel France-2 alongside journalist Didier Roustan. His performance on the air received mixed reviews, to say the least.</p>
<p>Since then, Roustan has become the chairman of the International Association of Football Professionals (AIFP), the union Cantona launched with Diego Maradona two years ago. Cantona may become more involved in this project from now on.</p>
<p>In his native country, Cantona has been considered more as a media star than a sports personality since national manager Aime Jacquet decided to drop him in early 1995.</p>
<p>He received warm reviews for his screen debut in the film &quot;Le Bonheur Est Dans Le Pre&quot; (&quot;Happiness Is In The Meadow&quot;) and may also opt for an acting career even though no plans have been announced yet.</p>
<p>Those who accepted his decision as definite said Cantona was right to retire while at the top.</p>
<p>&quot;I've known Eric as a kid since we both lived in the same Marseille suburb. I wish him as much success in his new life,&quot; said Monaco coach Jean Tigana.</p>
<p>Barcelona and France defender Laurent Blanc said: &quot;True champions usually retire at their best. He stops on a new title. As a friend, I'd like to tell him that I'm going to miss him&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
