<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="594293" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire capital slowly regains normalcy under rebels.</title>
<headline>Zaire capital slowly regains normalcy under rebels.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Hamilton</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's sprawling capital slowly regained its vibrant pace on Monday, the first working day after the dramatic rebel overthrow of dictator Mobutu Sese Seko.</p>
<p>Laurent Kabila, self-proclaimed president of the new Democratic Republic of Congo, was expected to unveil a new transitional government on Tuesday after his Number Two held consultations with politicians in Kinshasa.</p>
<p>South African deputy president Thabo Mbeki, who was involved in last-ditch mediation in the conflict in the Central African nation, gave a positive preview of the planned government.</p>
<p>&quot;President Kabila will address tomorrow night the question of free political activity for everyone. It will be a broad- based government, as inclusive as possible of the various political forces,&quot; Mbeki told reporters in Johannesburg.</p>
<p>&quot;A new government will be announced tomorrow night,&quot; said Mbeki, who held two hours of talks with Kabila on Sunday.</p>
<p>South Africa earlier recognised Kabila as head of state and voiced satisfaction with his first steps as national leader.</p>
<p>In a strong sign of confidence in Kabila, the Zaire currency more than doubled in value against the dollar. Moneychangers on Kinshasa's &quot;Wall Street&quot; posted the zaire at about 70,000 to the U.S. currency, against 185,000 to the dollar last week.</p>
<p>Kabila's second-in-command, Deogratias Bugera, told a news conference in Kinshasa that elections would be held in the country only after the people had been re-educated, starting at the level of peasant collectives.</p>
<p>In an ideological statement redolent of the rhetoric of 1960s anti-colonial campaign, Bugera said elections would be transparent and open to all, but were only a means to an end.</p>
<p>&quot;Be patient,&quot; he said when asked for a date.</p>
<p>The capital was generally calm after the mixture of euphoria and bloodshed that greeted Saturday's rebel takeover, sweeping aside Mobutu's discredited rule after 32 years.</p>
<p>The local Red Cross put the death toll over two days at about 200, many of them looters shot by rebel troops trying to keep order but also former Mobutu soldiers killed by lynch mobs.</p>
<p>Witnesses reported scattered looting as well as pockets of resistance from diehard presidential guards on Monday.</p>
<p>Many city shops were open and the streets of central Kinshasa were again bustling with traffic and people. Groups of students chanting anti-Mobutu slogans kept up scattered demonstrations of support for Kabila and his Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo (AFDL).</p>
<p>The ferry crossing between Kinshasa and Brazzaville, capital of neighbouring Congo across the river, remained blocked.</p>
<p>Newspapers appearing for the first time since Friday's climax to a seven-month rebel offensive against Mobutu toasted Kabila, who declared himself head of state of Zaire, renamed Democratic Republic of Congo.</p>
<p>&quot;Kabila - president of the Republic,&quot; headlined the independent daily Potentiel in a special edition.</p>
<p>It also fronted a file photo of Mobutu's last defence minister and army chief, General Mahele Bokungo Lieko, killed by loyalist troops after trying to strike a deal with Kabila to avert a violent rebel takeover of the capital.</p>
<p>&quot;General Mahele spilled his blood to save the people of Kinshasa from carnage,&quot; the caption read.</p>
<p>Bugera said Kabila was not expected to arrive in Kinshasa from southern Lubumbashi for several days, possibly one week.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be three days, five days, a week. It could be in a week,&quot; said Bugera, Secretary-General of the AFDL.</p>
<p>Japan, a major importer of metals from Zaire, hinted it would recognise Kabila's government, following a similar move by South Africa and cautious endorsement by the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;Although we have to consult with the Foreign Ministry, I think we will recognise it,&quot; Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto told reporters on Monday. &quot;I hope it will swiftly restore peace so that racial conflict does not intensify.&quot;</p>
<p>Germany said on Monday it was ready to cooperate with Kabila and joined Western calls for a rapid transition to democracy.</p>
<p>Mobutu's precise whereabouts remained unknown.</p>
<p>Togo's state television said on Sunday a rebel attack had forced the ousted leader to flee his lavish jungle palace at Gbadolite in northern Zaire. It said he stopped over in Togo.</p>
<p>Officials in Morocco have been expecting Mobutu since Saturday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CONGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
