<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="594435" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech bonds languish in unstable crown's shadow.</title>
<headline>Czech bonds languish in unstable crown's shadow.</headline>
<byline>Robin Shepherd</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Instability in the Czech crown pulled domestic bonds lower again on Monday, as low liquidity, wide spreads and general nervousness about the central bank's interest rate policy suffocated the market, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Ceska Sporitelna BICS 100 index, measuring the top domestic paper, lost another 1.795 percentage points on Monday to 99.570. It has fallen from 102.57 on last Wednesday, just before heavy downward pressure on the crown began.</p>
<p>The Czech National Bank (CNB) early on Monday hiked its overnight repo rate to 45 percent from 12.9 percent after raising its last-resort Lombard rate to 50 percent from 14 on Friday to protect the crown against speculative selling.</p>
<p>Worries over downside crown risk and the CNB's next move have sapped liquidity from an already thin market.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign exchange is dominating everything right now. Even when you see some trades it is done at very low volumes,&quot; said one local bond dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;Compared with before the problems with the crown last Thursday, the main bonds, of 5-7 years maturity, are around four (percentage points) lower in price and in yield to maturity up over one percent,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Yield on SPT Telecom's February 2004 bond was quoted at 12.3 percent on Monday with a price of 95.5 compared with around 11.3 percent and 99.5 last week.</p>
<p>Last Thursday the crown came under severe pressure from speculative selling connected to the country's weakening economic performance and hints of political instability.</p>
<p>The CNB intervened directly and pushed up the Lombard rate on Friday to deter speculators from borrowing on the interbank market to sell on spot forex dealing.</p>
<p>With very little activity in bonds -- dealers said spreads were between one and two percent compared with 30 basis points normally -- all eyes were fixed on the foreign exchange market and movements from the CNB.</p>
<p>Some said current interest rate policy would cripple the sputtering economy and was therefore unsustainable.</p>
<p>&quot;Ask the industrials, ask the building companies, whoever depends on the financing from the banks...it's killing them. It's definitly killing the economy,&quot; said Oto Otepka of ING Barings.</p>
<p>&quot;We are carefully watching the exchange rate because this is the key for our expectations. I don't see anything positive out of this crisis,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The CNB fixed the crown, which remained mostly steady throughout Monday, at 30.548 against the dollar and at 18.026 to the mark on Monday, implying a deviation of 2.7 percent below basket parity, after -3.8 percent on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 420-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
