<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="59443" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek rates hold in late trade, outflows continue.</title>
<headline>Greek rates hold in late trade, outflows continue.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek interbank rates were holding morning levels in late lacklustre dealing despite forex outflows of 170 million ecus at the fixing on short covering ahead of the elections on Sunday, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Interbank rates have been virtually unchanged since this morning with a few deals in forex swaps in six-and nine-month periods,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;Outflows of 170 million ecus at the fixing will squeeze liquidity on Thursday.&quot;</p>
<p>The central bank drained overnight money at an unchanged 12.40 percent.</p>
<p>However the dealer said no one knews whether money would enter the sustem from other unspecified sources.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is controlled to a great extent and it might not be necessary for the central bank to revert to its overnight offer to inject liquidity,&quot; he said. &quot;There are other ways to achieve the same outcome.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said forex outflows were likely to continue until Friday.</p>
<p>All late polls have shown the two major parties, the conservatives and the socialists, tied in first place with smaller parties holding on to gains recorded in earlier polls.</p>
<p>The crucial debate between Prime Minister Costas Simitis and conservative leader Miltiadis Evert last Friday ended in a tie and two polls conducted by TV stations afterwards gave Simitis a slight edge.</p>
<p>Early elections will be held September 22 but the market has taken a positive attitude towards them on the ground that the winner will have no option but to follow Greece's EU convergence plan.</p>
<p>The mark was quoted at 159.10/15 drachmas from Tuesday's 159.220 fix, the dollar at 240.66/76 drachmas from 240.710 and the Ecu at 301.52/62 from 301.580 drachmas.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank held ecu/drachma basically stable at 301.58 despite the demand for ecus at the fixing which reflects position squaring,&quot; a forex dealer at a foreign bank said.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Greece, the domestic money market's biggest player, quoted the following late rates:</p>
<p>** Overnight at 12.20-12.70</p>
<p>** T/N at 12.25-12.75</p>
<p>** S/N at 12.40-12.90</p>
<p>** One week at 12.65-13.15</p>
<p>** Two weeks at 12.65-13.15</p>
<p>** Three weeks at 12.65-13.15</p>
<p>** One month at 12.60-13.10</p>
<p>** Two months at 12.60-13.10</p>
<p>** Three months at 12.60-13.10</p>
<p>** Six months at 12.70-13.20</p>
<p>** Nine months at 12.85-13.35</p>
<p>** Twelve months at 13.00-13.50</p>
<p>--Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
