<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="59463" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: UNHCR urges holding off on Bosnian repatriation.</title>
<headline>UNHCR urges holding off on Bosnian repatriation.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations refugee agency said on Tuesday that Bosnia's elections had shown the difficulty of people returning to ethnic minority areas and it urged countries of asylum to delay forcing Bosnian refugees back home.</p>
<p>In Germany, state interior ministers are to meet on Thursday to discuss a return home of more than 300,000 Bosnian refugees, due to begin leaving gradually from October 1.</p>
<p>Germany is home to more Bosnian refugees than any other country outside former Yugoslavia and its policy is being closely watched by European neighbours which took in refugees fleeing brutal ethnic cleansing during the 43-month civil war.</p>
<p>Ruth Marshall, spokeswoman of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), said that fewer than 15,000 people had crossed entity lines to vote in Bosnia's first post-war elections.</p>
<p>&quot;This is very disappointing and a strong indication of the difficulty of ensuring freedom of movement and return to minority areas,&quot; she told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It also illustrates how carefully we should be looking at the whole question of pushing Bosnian refugees back to Bosnia.&quot;</p>
<p>Marshall said: &quot;It is UNHCR's position that before temporary protection of Bosnian refugees in Western Europe or elsewhere can be lifted -- even for people who would be returning to areas where their ethnic group is in the majority -- we need to very carefully assess the post-election phase and look at progress on the holding of the crucial municipal elections.</p>
<p>&quot;These are going to be very important elements to look at before we can approve any Bosnian refugee being forced back to his or her home area, regardless of what ethnic group is the majority in that area,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Roughly 35,000 Bosnian refugees voluntarily left Germany during a two-month period during the summer, according to UNHCR.</p>
<p>&quot;So we would encourage governments to encourage and assist families who are volunteering to go back, rather than force people to return,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
