<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="594614" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>HAITI: Haitian anti-government groups call general strike.</title>
<headline>Haitian anti-government groups call general strike.</headline>
<byline>Nicole Volpe</byline>
<dateline>PORT-AU-PRINCE 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Businesses and schools were closed and streets were empty in Haiti's capital on Monday after opposition groups called a general strike in the wake of angry demonstrations and mob violence in the city last week.</p>
<p>&quot;Most people are afraid because the streets were very hot last week,&quot; said one of the few taxi drivers to venture out. He said he had not seen any violence, but nor had he had any customers.</p>
<p>Several gross-roots political organisations, collectively known as &quot;Whatever happens, happens,&quot; which oppose the government's plans to privatise state-run industries called the general strike and threatened &quot;guerilla warfare&quot; after last week's violence.</p>
<p>Angry mobs rampaged through the streets on Thursday and Friday, exchanging gunfire with police, burning tires and beating journalists as days of demonstrations by rock-throwing students angry about a teachers' strike flared into general rioting.</p>
<p>Teachers in the city's public schools walked out just before final exams because their salaries had not been paid in over a year.</p>
<p>A few tires were set on fire in the business district on Monday morning, but they were extinguished immediately without violence. A woman was killed on Sunday night when a Molotov cocktail was thrown into her car as she was leaving the city.</p>
<p>Politicians urged the population to stay calm and police patrolled the streets, arresting those believed responsible for last week's violence, according to Secretary of State for Public Security Robert Manuel.</p>
<p>In a radio statement on Sunday, President Rene Preval urged Haitians to &quot;stay on guard against anarchy,&quot; and acknowledged government problems were at the root of the violence.</p>
<p>&quot;The state is working badly, and it is creating despair,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Former President Jean-Bertrand Aristide repeated his opposition to privatisation to reporters over the weekend, calling the plan a &quot;cigarette burning at both ends.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;When I was in power, the situation did not go out of control,&quot; he said. Some 20,000 U.S.-led troops restored Aristide to power in September 1994, ending three years he spent in exile following a bloody military coup.</p>
<p>There were many reports of violence against foreigners during the rioting. Canadian Ambassador Christopher Poole said rioters had thrown rocks at Canadian U.N. peacekeepers last week, but that there were no serious injuries.</p>
<p>Other embassies reported violence against employees travelling through the city, although the U.S. embassy declined comment on the violence.</p>
<p>&quot;Haitians feel betrayed by the international community because their lives have not gotten better, and at times I can't help to feel like a target or a symbol of the privatisation scheme,&quot; said one long-time U.S. resident of Port-au-Prince.</p>
<p>In the northern city of St. Marc, anti-American, anti-privatisation demonstrators displayed Cuban flags, while in the southern city of Petit Goave citizens flew the black and red national flag used during the 30-year dictatorship of Francois and Jean-Claude Duvalier.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT-AU-PRINCE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HAITI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
