<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="59478" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian metalworkers see no way out of strike.</title>
<headline>Italian metalworkers see no way out of strike.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian metalworking unions said on Tuesday they saw no way of averting their planned eight-hour strike set for September 27 over the renewal of contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;With things as they stand we don't think the strike can be avoided,&quot; Claudio Sabattini, leader of the FIOM trades union, told reporters. Labour Minister Tiziano Treu said on Monday that he thought there was still time to avert the stoppage.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know of any meetings planned at all or efforts on the part of the government to relaunch negotiations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gianni Italia, leader of the FIM union, said he had no idea what was behind Treu's confidence.</p>
<p>Metalworking and engineering unions called the strike over the renewal of contracts for some 1.5 million engineer and metalworkers. Negotiations broke down earlier this month.</p>
<p>Unions have demanded an overall wage rise of 10.1 percent for their members over the next two years, while employers have offered between seven and nine percent.</p>
<p>If the stoppage goes ahead, it would be the sector's first nationwide strike over contracts since November 1990.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
