<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="594708" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Orogen focus turns to new developments.</title>
<headline>Orogen focus turns to new developments.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Papua New Guinean mining investor Orogen Minerals Ltd said at its annual meeting on Tuesday that while it expected continued strong performance from existing assets it was now focussing on new developments.</p>
<p>Chief among these was the Lihir Gold Ltd mine with the first oxide gold pour expected by the end of May and full sulphide production by October, 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;It is expected the mine will produce 175,000 ounces by the end of the year, with annual production rising to 600,000 ounces within two years,&quot; Orogen managing director Charles Lepani told the annual meeting.  </p>
<p>Orogen holds 6.81 percent of Lihir.</p>
<p>The Gobe oil and gas field, in which Orogen holds a 20.5 percent stake, was seen as a key future project with estimated reserves of 116 million barrels of oil and about 400 billion cubic feet of gas and planned production to start early 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;Present targets are to bring the Gobe oil fields into production towards the end of the first quarter 1998, with production building up to a peak of 50,000 barrels of oil per day within several months of the commencement of production,&quot; Lepani said.  </p>
<p>Further energy interests include the Moran field where oil was discovered in 1996 in which it has a 15.75 percent interest in the Moran 1X exploration well.</p>
<p>Orogen said the field offered excellent prospects with extended well testing to commence from October, 1997.</p>
<p>From existing producing projects, the Kutubu oil field bettered prospectus forecasts for both production and profit.</p>
<p>&quot;Production was 38.6 million barrels of oil which is actually marginally above the prospectus forecast,&quot; Lepani said.  </p>
<p>&quot;In addition, profits from Kutubu for the financial year ended December 31 1996 were significantly higher than forecast due to the continued high price of oil.&quot;</p>
<p>Revenue from its 15 percent owned Porgera gold mine bettered prospectus forecast for the 1996 financial year due to a strong final quarter improvement in production. While prospectus forecasts for 1997 were unlikely to be met, Lepani said a new mine plan had allowed sharper falls in production to be avoided.  </p>
<p>&quot;While it is expected that Porgera will fall marginally short of the prospectus forecast of 899,000 ounces in 1997, it is no longer likley to face the substantial fall in production which had been forecast in the prospectus for 1998,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
