<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="594886" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordanian union chiefs may quit over new press law.</title>
<headline>Jordanian union chiefs may quit over new press law.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The heads of Jordan's professional unions on Monday condemned amendments to the country's press laws as a threat to public freedom and threatened to resign within a week unless the laws were revoked.</p>
<p>They said in a statement the law, issued by the government without recourse to parliament, was a &quot;violation of the constitution, a bypassing of parliament and an attack on freedom of opinion, thought and expression&quot;.</p>
<p>The amended press law sets sweeping restrictions on reporting, stiffens fines for offenders and imposes financial obligations on newspapers which journalists say will force most of Jordan's small but vocal opposition weekly papers to close.</p>
<p>&quot;To show their rejection of this law (the union heads) decided to submit their resignations jointly on Saturday if the government has not withdrawn the law by then,&quot; they said.</p>
<p>The union leaders represent 13 unions which have a grassroot membership of tens of thousands of Jordanians working in both the private and public sector. They have traditionally spearheaded opposition to government measures widely viewed as curbing public liberties. In the past the government has sought legal means to disband them.</p>
<p>Minister of State for Information Samir Mutawae said the government wanted to ensure that &quot;journalistic freedom will be a responsible freedom at the service of the country and its people&quot;.</p>
<p>But the press law has rallied opposition to the government.</p>
<p>&quot;The presidents of the unions in their meeting were very much alarmed at the deterioration of the situation of liberties in Jordan and the outrageous behaviour of the government,&quot; said Laith Shubeilat, head of the Islamist-dominated Engineers Union and one of the 13 union leaders threatening to resign.</p>
<p>The revised press law was issued, along with a law reforming the stock exchange and another governing elections scheduled for November, as a &quot;provisional law&quot; while parliament is in recess.</p>
<p>Opponents are considering appealing the law, since Jordan's constitution limits the government to issuing provisional laws &quot;covering matters which admit of no delay&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;There is nothing urgent about this law,&quot; said Shubeilat. &quot;They claim there is democracy, but we are insulted&quot;.</p>
<p>Nine out the 10 board members of the journalists' union have already announced their resignation in protest at the new law. Union chief Seif Sharif is the only one who has not yet stepped down.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
