<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="594841" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Top HK official worried people will &quot;pull punches&quot;.</title>
<headline>Top HK official worried people will &quot;pull punches&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's chief secretary Anson Chan said on Monday she was worried the territory's normally self-confident residents would be cowed by China's takeover of the British colony on July 1.</p>
<p>&quot;Indeed, I will worry for Hong Kong when people -- particularly those in the community whose views carry real weight with their fellow citizens -- start pulling their punches, or start consulting some real or imagined catalogue of political correctness,&quot; Chan told businessmen in Manila.</p>
<p>Speaking at the 30th international general meeting of the Pacific Basin Economic Council (PBEC), an organisation composed of more than 1,200 companies from the region, Chan said several surveys had shown people were confident about Hong Kong's continued economic success after the handover.</p>
<p>But the surveys had also shown that people were less certain when it came to their political freedoms and civil liberties, Chan said.</p>
<p>&quot;The community will, I hope, have an opportunity, and take the opportunity with its usual self-confidence, to say what it thinks about the kind of electoral arrangements we need to replace the present legislature,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>China plans to disband the sitting Legislative Council and replace it with an interim body which it appointed in December. Pro-democracy parties have threatened to raise court challenges to the body, calling it illegal.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's future administration has pledged to hold legislative elections not long after the sovereignty handover.</p>
<p>Chan said the future administration had an obligation to its people to ensure that they were represented by a credible legislature in which they and the international community had confidence.</p>
<p>&quot;Otherwise, the credibility and authority of the future administration itself will be weakened,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Chan, deputy to departing British governor Chris Patten, is among the territory's top tier of civil servants who have been reappointed by Hong Kong's future leader Tung Chee-hwa.</p>
<p>Chan will serve as Tung's number two when Hong Kong reverts to China, with the new title of Administrative Secretary.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
