<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="594957" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. defends Ross against Arafat's criticisms.</title>
<headline>U.S. defends Ross against Arafat's criticisms.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. State Department on Monday defended U.S. Middle East peace envoy Dennis Ross against Palestinian criticism of his handling of Israeli-PLO peace talks.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just totally inappropriate for the Palestinians to take shots at Dennis Ross, because they need him and they know that. They need a mediator and Israel does too,&quot; spokesman Nicholas Burns told reporters.</p>
<p>Ross failed after a nine-day mission that ended last week to revive the talks between Israel and the Palestine Liberation Organisation, which have been frozen since Israel launched construction on a new Jewish settlement in East Jerusalem in March.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat, disappointed with Ross's performance during the nine-day mission, asked President Bill Clinton in a letter sent on Thursday to get involved personally in efforts to break the impasse.</p>
<p>Burns added he found it &quot;curious&quot; that after making the criticism, Arafat invited Ross to meet with him on Friday. &quot;I would listen more to their (the Palestinians') actions than their words,&quot; Burns said.</p>
<p>Arafat spoke out again on Monday, saying the lack of American pressure on Israel had contributed to the impasse in peacemaking.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
