<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="595470" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Penske buys stake in speedway.</title>
<headline>Penske buys stake in speedway.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Penske Motorsports Inc said Monday it acquired a controlling interest in North Carolina Motor Speedway from Carrie DeWitt, its majority shareholder, by exercising its option to purchase her shares.</p>
<p>In exchange for her shares, DeWitt received 906,542 shares of Penske stock. Penske said it now owns approximately 70 percent of North Carolina Motor Speedway.  </p>
<p>In April, Penske said DeWitt owned about 65 percent of North Carolina Motor Speedway stock.</p>
<p>Penske said it proposed a merger with North Carolina Motor Speedway earlier this year at a meeting of the speedway's board of directors.</p>
<p>As previously announced, North Carolina shareholders would receive, at their option, either $18.61 in cash per share of speedway stock held or an amount of Penske stock. The number of shares would be equal to $18.61 multipled by the amount of speedway shares, divided by $30 (approximately 6/10ths of a share of Penske for each share of the speedway).  </p>
<p>Penske said that, under its merger plan to increase its ownership in the speedway to 100 percent, it has asked the speedway board to proceed with its current analysis of the Penske proposal and a competing offer.</p>
<p>In April, Speedway Motorsports Inc said it increased its offer to merge with North Carolina Motor Speedway by 39 percent. Speedway said its proposal was worth $71.6 million in cash, and included $32 a share in cash or the equilvalent amount of its stock.</p>
<p>Penske said it will vote in favor of its merger plan at an upcoming meeting of the North Carolina Motor Speedway board.</p>
<p>&quot;In light of the transaction, I have asked the board of directors of NCMS to accelerate consideration of our merger proposal which I believe is in the best interest of all NCMS shareholders and other constituents,&quot; Richard Peters, president of Penske, said in a statement.</p>
<p>North Carolina Motor Speedway is a one-mile oval track in Rockingham, N.C., which was constructed in 1965 by a group of investors, including DeWitt and her late husband.</p>
<p>Penske owns and operates Michigan Speedway in Brooklyn, Mich.; Nazareth Speedway in Nazareth, Penn.; and California Speedway in San Bernadino County, Calif.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
