<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="595507" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Berlusconi ally to face trial on Mafia charges.</title>
<headline>Berlusconi ally to face trial on Mafia charges.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marcello dell'Utri, a former business colleague of Italian opposition leader Silvio Berlusconi, was on Monday ordered by a Sicilian judge to stand trial on charges of mafia association.</p>
<p>Dell'Utri, a parliamentary deputy for centre-right opposition leader Berlusconi's Forza Italia party, is already on trial in Milan and Turin on charges of false billing, false accounting and tax fraud.</p>
<p>The Sicilian-born politician resigned as chairman of advertising firm Publitalia, part of Berlusconi's Fininvest empire, in 1995 when false billing charges against him emerged.</p>
<p>He denies all charges against him.</p>
<p>The mafia trial will start in the Sicilian capital Palermo on October 15, together with alleged mafioso Gaetano Cina.</p>
<p>Cina is accused of being a link man between the Mafia and the former businessman, who is not accused of being a member of the Mafia but of ties with the Sicilian crime body.</p>
<p>Dell'Utri, who met anti-Mafia investigators several times last year to answer questions, is accused of meeting Mafia leaders and helping launder Mafia money in a prosecution document summarised into 53 main points.</p>
<p>He said the investigators were waging a political campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;My only fault is to have become famous alongside personalities that a certain, minority, fringe group of politicised magistrates does not like,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;They want to force a political trial.&quot;</p>
<p>Dell Utri said he had been targeted by turncoats seeking to gain favour with investigating magistrates.</p>
<p>He later told RAI state television that the decision was a foregone conclusion. &quot;I didn't expect anything else. I now prepare myself calmly for the hearings.&quot;</p>
<p>Dell'Utri's lawyer Enzo Trantino said the trial would prove that Dell'Utri was an innocent victim. &quot;The battle is over, now we're preparing for the war,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Accusation by mob turncoats form the basis of the prosecution case against the politician.</p>
<p>They have reportedly claimed that Dell'Utri's ties with the Mafia began in the 1960s as an occasional point of contact between the Mafia, Milanese business circles and institutional authorities, and that they continued until 1995.</p>
<p>Berlusconi, who was premier in 1994, is himself on trial in two separate corruption trials.</p>
<p>Judicial sources have said that investigators dropped a probe into allegations the media billionaire also had Mafia ties on grounds of insufficient evidence.</p>
<p>Palermo prosecutors never confirmed that they were probing Berlusconi, whose party had strong support in Sicily at the last general election, although the investigation had been widely reported in the Italian media.</p>
<p>The island had previously been a stronghold of the now-defunct and corruption-tainted Christian Democrats, one of whose former leading lights Giulio Andreotti is also on trial in Palermo on charges of Mafia ties.</p>
<p>Fininvest said in a statement on Monday that it repeated it &quot;has never paid anything to illegal organisations and has never even received requests to do so&quot;.</p>
<p>It said any attempt to link the group to the Mafia was &quot;absurd and has a whiff of persecution&quot;.</p>
<p>Berlusconi defended Dell'Utri last year by saying he could more easily imagine him as a Martian than a Mafioso.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
