<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="595595" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Palladium suppply edges ahead of 1996 demand - JM.</title>
<headline>Palladium suppply edges ahead of 1996 demand - JM.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palladium use increased 30,000 ounces worldwide in 1996 to 6.15 million ounces but availability expanded by 480,000 ounces on record sales by Russia and South Africa, the Platinum 1997 survey published on Monday by Johnson Matthey said.</p>
<p>Increased palladium use by car makers in the United States and Europe offset lower use by the Japanese electronics industry which overstocked with the metal in 1995. Johnson Matthey is the world's leading refiner of platinum group metals.</p>
<p>Russia exported 4.60 million ounces of palladium in 1996, a 400,000-ounce increase on 1995 and South African supplied 90,000 ounces more at 1.69 million ounces of a total supply of 6.82 million ounces, according to the survey.</p>
<p>&quot;Russian shipments surged during the final quarter when nearly 1.5 million ounces were exported to the U.S. We believe that some market participants accumulated stocks, either for speculative reasons or to secure metal to meet consumers' future requirements,&quot; the survey said.</p>
<p>The higher Russian exports would &quot;significantly&quot; exceed output at Norilsk, the country's production complex where production was estimated at two million ounces.</p>
<p>&quot;During the past two years we estimate that a total of around five million ounces of palladium has been withdrawn from Russian government stocks,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Johnson Matthey precious metals division's general manager marketing Jeremy Coombes estimated the government palladium stockpile would be wiped out by &quot;the first couple of years of the next century.&quot;</p>
<p>The car makers used 510,000 ounces more palladium last year than in 1995 for a total demand of 2.31 million ounces with around 60 percent of European gasoline burning cars carrying palladium catalysts and Ford using palladium for most of its U.S. models.</p>
<p>Auto industry demand was forecast to increase this year in Europe and North America and tighter emission standards in both areas were likely to stimulate further consumption increases.</p>
<p>However, use in electronics sank 560,000 ounces to 2.06 million ounces including a 40 percent pull-back in Japan as the industry's growth rate slipped resulting in production cuts and surplus stocks.</p>
<p>Consumption was also affected by continuing miniaturisation and the substitution by nickel by some Japanese capacitor makers.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate that a third of all MLCCs (multi layer ceramic capacitors) made in Japan last year contained nickel rather than palladium electrodes,&quot; the survey said.</p>
<p>Sales increases in other end use areas including dental alloys were modest but Johnson Matthey estimated China imported about 60,000 ounces from the West to meet growing demand from the jewellery, chemical and electronics sectors.</p>
<p>The survey forecast prices between $130 and $160 per ounce this year although the unpredictability of Russian shipments could mean &quot;significant excursions&quot; above and below this range.</p>
<p>-- Brian Spoors London Newsroom +44 171 542 8058</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
