<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="595593" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Funds shift into Japan on U.S. fears - poll.</title>
<headline>Funds shift into Japan on U.S. fears - poll.</headline>
<byline>James Saft</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Global fund managers are swapping assets into Japanese equities and cash on worries about interest rates and currencies and a perception that the U.S. stock market may be near its peak.</p>
<p>A Reuters monthly global asset allocation survey of mostly UK-based fund managers showed an increased underweight position in U.S. equities with Japan and cash the main beneficiaries.</p>
<p>&quot;Japan is a classic defensive strategy,&quot; said Tony Robinson, head of equities at Lombard Odier. &quot;We see a rise in Japanese rates later this year putting a cap on the dollar and making some capital repatriate from dollar assets to Japan.&quot;</p>
<p>Among global equity funds, assets allocated to Japan rose to 16.80 percent from 15.10 percent in April, while cash rose to 5.65 percent from 3.70 percent. At the same time, the North American allocation sank to 25.27 percent from 27.20 percent.</p>
<p>Japan was seen as being at a favourable point in its economic cycle compared with the U.S. and much of Europe, strategists said. Key points were a recovering consumer economy and &quot;a chink of light in the financial sector&quot;, said Michael Hughes, chief economist at BZW.</p>
<p>Fund managers also use exposure to Japanese equities to give a proxy to the robust recovery in China. Equity funds leaving Hong Kong in anticipation of the July 1 handover were also finding a home in Japanese equities.</p>
<p>A desire to take gains from the U.S. and elsewhere off the table was driving the move to cash. &quot;We are at benchmark for cash for the first time in many years,&quot; said BZW's Hughes.</p>
<p>Global bond funds have made a general move to Europe, especially British gilts, as U.S. long bond returns have moderated slightly and the new Labour government's move to give the Bank of England independence changed the relative value equation, managers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We see the U.S. long bond at fair value at around 6.75 percent,&quot; said Shaun Roache, investment strategist at ING Barings.</p>
<p>Some fund managers also saw gilts gaining at the expense of British equities. &quot;It all depends on what we see in the Chancellor's (finance minister's) budget,&quot; Roache said.</p>
<p>&quot;His hands are tied monetary policy-wise and sterling is riding high. Raising corporate taxation is a possible avenue, slowing things down from the equity side of things and favouring gilts.&quot;</p>
<p>Another political unknown which may move British pension funds into gilts over equities is the possibility that Advanced Corporation Tax (ACT) will be cut, a move the Chancellor is said to be mooting. ACT allows pension funds to claim back the 20 percent payment of tax on dividend payments, thus making equities more attractive.</p>
<p>The view that an independent Bank of England will be quicker to raise rates is also a negative for equities, as it will lessen the yield premium investors demand to hold gilts.</p>
<p>Managers said currency movement considerations were taking a larger weighting in investment decisions.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom, +171 542 2734</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
