<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="59575" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austrian shares firmer but muted ahead of expiry.</title>
<headline>Austrian shares firmer but muted ahead of expiry.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian shares closed higher on Tuesday, but activity was muted ahead of the expiry of futures and options contracts on Friday, traders said.</p>
<p>The blue chip ATX index climbed 5.33 points or 0.52 percent to close at 1,028.71 points, just off the day's high of 1,029.27. Among its constituents 17 gainers outweighed three decliners and one remaining unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say the tone is generally positive, but with some uncertainty ahead of Friday's expiry,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;The mood is cautiously optimistic. On the buying side we've seen continuing modest interest,&quot; said another.</p>
<p>Buying interest focused on airport operator Flughafen, which led the gainers, jumping 2.6 percent to 590 schillings, on turnover of 44,000 lots. The stock plunged as much as 22 percent last week on news of lower-than-expected first-half earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;Flughafen has now run out of steam,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Luxury hosiery maker Wolford also firmed, gaining 2.49 percent to 2,680 schillings.</p>
<p>Insurer EA Generali was the leading decliner, shedding 1.64 percent to 2,831.90.</p>
<p>The broad-based Vienna Bourse index inched up 0.21 percent to 401.26 points.</p>
<p>On the Vienna futures and options exchange, ATX contracts for September delivery were up two points at 1,027 schillings ahead of Friday's expiry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
