<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="59585" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: VOLVO YET TO DECIDE ON MITSUBISHI MOTOR.</title>
<headline>VOLVO YET TO DECIDE ON MITSUBISHI MOTOR.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish vehicle maker AB Volvo said on Tuesday no decision had yet been taken about using Mitsubishi Motor Corp's new fuel efficient GDI engine but said it hoped to cooperate on projects. </p>
<p>&quot;Discussions are continuing about purchasing this engine for our four cylinder S40/V40. No decision has yet been made,&quot; Volvo Car spokesman Ingmar Hesslefors told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We see it as a possibility to widen our motor programme. &quot;Our purchase of this motor would be in line with our ambition to cooperate on concrete projects,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The fuel-efficient Mitsubishi 1.8 litre, 16-valve GDI engine (Gasoline Direct Injection) is said to use 35 percent less fuel than ordinary engines and emit 35 percent less carbon dioxide, Mitsubishi has said.</p>
<p>The emission of other dangerous gases, such as nitrous oxide, is reduced by 95 percent, according to Mitsubishi.   </p>
<p>Hesslefors said the cost of the motor would prohibit it from becoming a standard feature.</p>
<p>&quot;The GDI engine is more expensive than the conventional gasoline engine. It will therefore not replace other engines, but instead be a complementary feature,&quot; said Hesslefors. </p>
<p>He said the GDI engine holds many possibilities for Volvo and Mitsubishi had managed to solve some problems of direct injection in gasoline engines.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi displayed the new engine in August this year and is set to launch it in its Galant model. Next year the engine will also be used in its Carisma model, produced in the NedCar plant in the Netherlands.</p>
<p>Volvo also produces its S40/V40 models in the NedCar Netherlands plant.</p>
<p>-- Henrik Alberius, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
