<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="595987" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - Bunds to bounce then dip to test 101.42.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Bunds to bounce then dip to test 101.42.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Technical indicators suggest Bund futures may enjoy a short term bounce on Monday to the 102.00 area, before falling back to test support around 101.42, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Daily stochastics look pretty bad but the 30 minute charts are improving suggesting we could get a short term bounce,&quot; said Elizabeth Miller, technical analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>&quot;Short term we could get to around 102.05, then we should come off to test 101.42 channel support.&quot;</p>
<p>By 0650 GMT, the June Bund future on LIFFE was down two basis points at 101.85.  </p>
<p>Trade was expected to be thin with German markets closed for a public holiday.</p>
<p>Miller said an initial prop at Friday's low of 101.65 would slow any fall before the 101.42 channel support.</p>
<p>Below that, retracement support at 101.24 will kick in, she said. This is the 38.2 percent retracement of the rally from the April 3 low of 99.05 to the May 14 high of 102.59.</p>
<p>On the upside, above 102.05 next resistance is at 102.20, said Miller. &quot;But I don't think we'll get that high today.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts at Chase here said as long as the contract stabilised above 101.71 it would resume its medium term uptrend.  </p>
<p>&quot;But in order to reduce short term selling pressure, it has to move above 102.10, while an Elliott buy signal will be triggered on a break of 102.37,&quot; they said in a note for clients.</p>
<p>By 0707 GMT, September Euromarks were unchanged at 96.74.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
