<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="596003" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia's Colonial surges on stock market debut.</title>
<headline>Australia's Colonial surges on stock market debut.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian financial services group Colonial Ltd made a strong debut on the Australian share market on Monday, its share price soaring on listing.</p>
<p>Colonial shares closed at A$3.31 (US$2.56), well above the A$3.10 paid by institutional investors in the company's public share offer, which closed last Friday.</p>
<p>The market price eclipsed the A$2.60 paid by members of the public in the A$690 million float, but those who took their stag profits and ran on Monday failed to dent the price.</p>
<p>The closing price, just four cents off the day's high, gives the company a market capitalisation of A$1.9 billion and puts it in the top 50 Australian companies. A whopping 32.3 million shares traded hands during the day</p>
<p>&quot;We are obviously delighted that we have come on with a premium. It's a strong market response,&quot; Colonial managing director Peter Smedley said after watching the opening share price flash up on the stock exchange boards in Melbourne.</p>
<p>Colonial on Monday became only the second life office to list on the local exchange, after one of its bigger rivals, National Mutual Holdings Ltd, made its debut last October.</p>
<p>Australia's biggest, the Australian Mutual Provident Society, will soon follow. It plans to shed its old mutual structure and list in Australia and New Zealand next year.</p>
<p>Smedley said he did not feel the share offer had been priced too low. &quot;I think the end result is a reflection of the fact we have set the price well,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;There was very heavy over-subscription from the public and a very positive response from institutions.&quot;</p>
<p>Each share issued came with an underwritten option to buy more, enabling the company to raise another A$200 million between September this year and June 1998.</p>
<p>Colonial also made a strong debut on Monday on the New Zealand exchange, wher it has a secondary listing.</p>
<p>&quot;It's certainly been an outstanding success,&quot; said Melbourne-based broker Kevin Lourey, of Peake Lands Kirwan.</p>
<p>Colonial is devoting some of the float proceeds to development of its life insurance business in Asia.</p>
<p>The group is spending US$163 million to buy out its old Asian partner, Jardine Matheson Holdings Ltd, from their equal life insurance joint venture based in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Colonial has applied for a licence to sell life insurance in China and has operations across Southeast Asia, including Hong Kong, Singapore, Indonesia, the Philippines and Thailand.</p>
<p>Its traditional offshore markets are Britain, New Zealand and Fiji.</p>
<p>Colonial will also use A$50 million of the float proceeds to complete the 1994 purchase of the State Bank of New South Wales, now renamed Colonial State Bank.</p>
<p>Colonial has total assets of A$29.7 billion and has forecast a net profit before preference dividends of A$180 million for calendar 1997, a-50 percent rise on its 1996 earnings.</p>
<p>(A$1 = US$0.7745)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
