<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="596179" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: E.Asia Grain - Japan sees U.S. corn premiums rising.</title>
<headline>E.Asia Grain - Japan sees U.S. corn premiums rising.</headline>
<byline>Eiichiro Tokumoto</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese traders said on Monday they are rushing to cover their U.S. corn requirements for shipment in the third quarter of 1997 in anticipation of further increases in U.S. corn premiums.</p>
<p>&quot;Corn premiums are firming mainly due to strong U.S. cash prices. We'd like to buy more before the premiums advance further,&quot; a corn trader at a major trade house in Japan said.</p>
<p>Japan's corn premiums were quoted at 92 to 93 U.S. cents a bushel over CBOT May futures, against 90 cents last week.  </p>
<p>Traders said Japan's corn imports from South Africa this season are expected to fall because of a drop in the country's output and higher South African offer prices.</p>
<p>South Africa's National Crop Estimates committee pegged the country's 1997 corn harvest at 7.66 million tonnes, sharply down from 9.694 million tonnes in 1996. The committee is expected to give its new estimate on May 20.</p>
<p>&quot;We usually start shipping South African maize from July, but their offer prices this season are too high to attract Japanese importers. Lower output estimates are also a negative factor,&quot; a corn trader in Japan said.  </p>
<p>In South Korea, buyers are expected to stay out of the market this week as they are believed to have completed buying their grain requirements for September arrival, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no tender to buy corn from local buyers for the time being,&quot; a trader with the National Livestock Cooperatives Federation (NLCF) said.</p>
<p>The only action may come from one or two companies expected to buy between 20,000-40,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat this week for July shipment, a flour miller said.  </p>
<p>There is also talk in the market that Cargill sold three 12,500-tonne shipments of Chinese corn to a South Korean buyer for October arrival, traders said.</p>
<p>Freight rates for nearby shipments on the U.S. Gulf/Japan route for Panamax-sized vessels were quoted at about US$21.50 a tonne, traders said.</p>
<p>An official with Pan Ocean Shipping Co Ltd in South Korea said rates from the U.S. Pacific Northwest were steady at $12 a tonne over the past week for Panamax-sized nearby shipments.</p>
<p>Panamax rates from the U.S. Gulf were also unchanged at $22 a tonne.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
