<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="596533" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan stocks end down, sentiment hurt by Bahamas.</title>
<headline>Taiwan stocks end down, sentiment hurt by Bahamas.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan share prices closed lower on Monday as investors moved to the sidelines after Taipei's unexpected late Sunday decision to cut ties with the Bahamas, which plans to switch recognition to China, brokers said.</p>
<p>The weighted index finished down 33.58 points or 0.41 percent to 8,107.54, off an intra-day low of 8,055.40.</p>
<p>Turnover fell dramatically to just T$58.34 billion, lower even than the T$62.3 billion of Saturday's abbreviated two-hour session and far below Friday's muted T$98.5 billion.</p>
<p>The surprise Bahamian snub fuelled worries of a domino effect among Taiwan's remaining 30 allies, brokers said.  </p>
<p>Increasingly isolated by communist China, Taiwan said it was severing ties with the Bahamas after learning the Caribbean island was preparing to exchange ties with Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is being hurt by a series of non-economic factors. Not many people are willing to take risk at the moment,&quot; said Allen Huang, an analyst of National Securities.</p>
<p>Brokers said the index had shown support against any further downturn at around 8,000 points.</p>
<p>Hopes that the government would orchestrate a rally for the one-year anniversary of President Lee Teng-hui's inauguration on May 20 were gradually evaporating, brokers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Some people are still pinning hopes on the so-called 520 (May 20) rally, but more have simply given up such hopes,&quot; said Chen Han-chung, an analyst of Yungli Securities.</p>
<p>Taiwan's top securities watchdog flatly denied lawmakers' charges that the government would engineer such a politically motivated celebration rally on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Brokers, however, did not rule out the possibility that some shares having close government links might rise on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Some high-technology shares rebounded in late trade, with leading chipmaker Taiwan Semiconductor rising T$2 or 1.96 percent to T$104 after early selling.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
