<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="59672" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Long Australian bond yields in steady decline.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Long Australian bond yields in steady decline.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>----------(Snapshot at 4.35 P.M./0635 GMT)------------------</p>
<p>FUTURES					  CASH YIELD</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS  (DEC) 93.32  (- 0.03)    6.97    (+ 0.01)</p>
<p>3-YR T-BONDS  (DEC) 92.77  (+ 0.02)    7.07    (- 0.02)</p>
<p>10-YR T-BONDS (DEC) 92.080 (+0.105)    7.91    (- 0.10)</p>
<p>AUD/USD  0.7885 (PREV 0.7893) US 30-YR  6.95   (6.95 NY)</p>
<p>---------------------(Sept 17)------------------------------</p>
<p>*Long Australian bond yields made a steady decline throughout the day, spurred on by an aggressively bid T-bond tender, taking the 10-year bond back below 8.0 percent.</p>
<p>*U.S. faces August industrial production and capacity usage.  </p>
<p>Long-dated Australian bond yields made a steady decline throughout the session, spurred on by an aggressively bid A$700 million Treasury bond tender, to close at their lowest level in three weeks.</p>
<p>The benchmark November 2006 bond yield dived below 8.0 percent for the second successive session, but this time the move held once it became clear that the supply had been easily absorbed, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The 2001 stock had been tight for sometime, and it's always nice to see a long bond (2008) go off well at a tender. It's looks as if someone took the whole lot,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>The January 2001 stock went off at an average yield of 7.44 percent and the August 2008 at 8.04 percent.</p>
<p>However, the market again finds itself dependent on the U.S. to maintain the current rally with no major data due for release until Wednesday's local merchandise imports for August.</p>
<p>U.S. Treasuries face August industrial production and capacity usage later today, which could provide another clue to the policy action that the FOMC might take on September 24.</p>
<p>Recent inflation data seemed to suggest that the Fed will be on hold this time round, but the bond market continues to debate the issue, leaving it fairly flat after Friday's prices spike.  </p>
<p>-----------------------(SPREADS)-------------------------</p>
<p> AUD VS   3-YR	   10-YR	* AUD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p> USD	 78 (- 04)   118 (- 11) * FUTURES   69   (- 08)</p>
<p> CAD	145 (UNCH)    63 (- 13) * CASH	84   (- 08)</p>
<p> NZD     -111 (- 06)   -50 (- 13) *</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The Australian/U.S. 10-year bond yield spread reversed an early widening trend as the local market rebounded on the tender. The local yield curve also flattened amid switching to the long end to cover short positions placed prior to the bond sale.  </p>
<p>--------------------(TECHNICALS)-----------------------------</p>
<p>FUTURES	*DAY'S HILO  *SUP/RES     *RSI    *MA-10 *MA-20</p>
<p>10-YEAR (DEC)*92.08-91.93 *91.06-92.11 *59 PCT *91.84 *91.88</p>
<p>3-YEAR  (DEC)*92.77-92.70 *92.74-92.82 *60 PCT *92.55 *92.59</p>
<p>90-DAY  (DEC)*93.34-93.31 *93.30-93.35 *60 PCT *93.19 *93.24</p>
<p>-------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The December 10-year bond's bounce from an initial 91.930 and through Monday's 92.030 high sees the contract begin to fill a chart gap between 92.060 to 91.110, inherited from the now expired September position.</p>
<p>-- Colin Brinsden 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
