<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="596756" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: PRESS DIGEST - Ireland, May 19.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Ireland, May 19.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the highlights of stories from the Irish press on Monday.</p>
<p>IRISH TIMES</p>
<p>- Fine Gael, the main government party, has decided to concentrate its 1.5 billion Irish pounds tax reform package on people with middle and low incomes.</p>
<p>- Some of the most severe laws ever drawn up to combat crime in the State have been proposed by an Irish-government appointed group reviewing the operation of the Irish police.</p>
<p>- British government officials and Sinn Fein representatives will meet this week, possibly as early as on Tuesday, in the wake of the authorisation of such a meeting by the British Prime Minister, Tony Blair, on Friday.</p>
<p>- State-owned Irish airports operator Aer Rianta has won its biggest ever overseas contract, to sell spirits and tobacco at 12-duty free shops in Hong Kong's giant new airport which is due to open in April next year, according to industry sources in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>IRISH INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>- Ireland's Labour Party is proposing double child benefit payouts for August and December, the two most expensive months of the year for families.</p>
<p>- State-owned Irish airports operator Aer Rianta has landed a 125 million Irish pounds a year contract to run 12 duty free shops at a massive new airport in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>- Anglo Irish Bank is to raise well over 100 million Irish pounds in additional capital through the issue of new preference shares, according to reliable sources.</p>
<p>THE EXAMINER</p>
<p>- The Irish government on Sunday scotched opposition claims that the main government party had gone behind the backs of its coalition partners with a 1.5 billion Irish pounds tax package unveiled without the support of the Labour Party or the Democratic Left.</p>
<p>-Dublin newsroom 353-1-661-3377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
