<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="59697" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ govt to appeal High Court's Equiticorp ruling.</title>
<headline>NZ govt to appeal High Court's Equiticorp ruling.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand Attorney General Paul East said on Tuesday the government would be appealing the High Court decision against it over the 1987 sale of New Zealand Steel to Equiticorp.  </p>
<p>&quot;After the Court's decision in July, there was much public comment about the likelihood of a Crown appeal. A comprehensive assessment of the Crown's position has been undertaken and continues,&quot; East said.</p>
<p>He said senior counsel, who had not earlier been involved with the trial, advised that there were good grounds for appeal. East said as a consequence of the decision to appeal he could not comment further, as the matter was now sub judice.</p>
<p>The court in July ordered the government to pay NZ$189 million to the statutory managers of Equiticorp, which collapsed in 1989.  </p>
<p>The government was later ordered to pay $133 million in interest and $4.7 million in costs.</p>
<p>The verdict impacted on the government's operating surplus for the year to June 1996. The final surplus of NZ$3.31 billion was after a provision of NZ$328 million relating to the case.</p>
<p>The case ran for 13 months and was one of the longest running civil cases in New Zealand history, hinging on the government's sale of New Zealand Steel to Equiticorp on the day of the 1987 sharemarket crash.  </p>
<p>The judge ruled that the government of the day knew, or should have known, that the way the transaction was paid for was ultimately illegal.</p>
<p>New Zealand Steel was paid for with Equiticorp shares, later exchanged for cash, with the shares ending up in the hands of companies associated with Equiticorp founder and former executive chairman Allan Hawkins.</p>
<p>Hawkins was sentenced in 1993 to six years jail for fraud involving NZ$520 million.</p>
<p>It transpired at his trial that the shares were paid for from sources within Equiticorp.  </p>
<p>The statutory managers argued that the government was &quot;unjustly enriched&quot; when it settled the New Zealand Steel deal in 1988 above post-crash levels.</p>
<p>It argued the transaction was in breach of laws preventing use of company funds to buy company shares, and also breached the duties of directors.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
