<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597084" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: SOCCER-WORLD CUP CO-HOSTS READY FOR SHOWDOWN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-WORLD CUP CO-HOSTS READY FOR SHOWDOWN.</headline>
<byline>Brian Williams</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan and South Korea, uneasy co-hosts of the 2002 World Cup, take their rivalry on to the field on Wednesday in a match with far more than national pride at stake.</p>
<p>The main prize in what is officially described as a friendly match to commemorate the two nations' successful World Cup bid, is a potential bargaining tool in the forthcoming tortuous negotiations about how the event will be staged.</p>
<p>But the match is also a badly needed shot-in-the-arm for Japan's flagging soccer league - the J-League - and a chance for South Koreans to unleash passions on a subject other than the country's present domestic political turmoil.</p>
<p>The game is already a sell-out, a rarity in Japanese soccer which underlines the appeal of a fixture which, like England-Germany or Brazil-Argentina, transcends normal sporting boundaries.</p>
<p>J-League matches this year have attracted average crowds of only 10-12,000 -- well below the average of around 17,000 in the first four years.</p>
<p>Wednesday's match at Tokyo's National Stadium, however, is likely to draw a crowd of about 55,000, including special tour groups who have flown in from South Korea for the match.</p>
<p>If the official line is harmony and celebration, police are taking no chances on patriotism spilling over.</p>
<p>Extra security precautions are to be taken to separate Japanese and Korean fans.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll have a thin line of security officials between the fans,&quot; a police spokesman said. &quot;And entry gates for Japanese and Korean fans will be at opposite sides of the stadium.&quot;</p>
<p>The two teams' rivalry is rooted in Japan's colonialisation of Korea at the turn of this century and its actions there during World War Two.</p>
<p>When Japan beat South Korea in a 1993 World Cup qualifier a headline in a Seoul newspaper at the time read:&quot;A national shame unmatched since the annexation by Japan&quot;.</p>
<p>Accusations of skullduggery flew in Japan and South Korea's campaign to win the right to stage the 2002 World Cup.</p>
<p>Soccer's world governing body FIFA was reduced to passing a Solomon-like judgement, announcing the tournament would be co-hostiedfor the first time.</p>
<p>Since then, the World Cup has been on the agenda of every meeting between Japanese and South Korean political leaders, with each assuring the other there would be no attempt to get an advantage in staging the cup.</p>
<p>In soccer at least, history is on South Korea's side.</p>
<p>In matches between the two teams since they first clashed in 1954, Korea has won 32, Japan nine with 13 drawn. Japan have not beaten South Korea in a match in Japan for 25 years.</p>
<p>In the just-concluded East Asian Games in Pusan, South Korea, the Koreans won the gold medal but Japan came away with some consolation when they beat Korea 1-0 in the final match of the tournament when the gold medal was already decided.</p>
<p>South Korean coach Cha Bum-kun goes into the game confident his team can continue their winning ways.</p>
<p>Japanese coach Shu Kamo, under fire for a string of recent poor performances by the national team, including their failure to reach the final round of last year's Asian Cup, has less high hopes.</p>
<p>&quot;We just want a good game,&quot; he says.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
