<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="59705" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Canberra announces terms for health inquiry.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Canberra announces terms for health inquiry.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Treasurer Peter Costello on Tuesday released the terms of reference for the government's inquiry into the private health insurance industry.</p>
<p>The Industry Commission inquiry, announced by Prime Minister John Howard on August 30, would review the condition and cost pressures on the industry and effectiveness of private health incentives for contributors.</p>
<p>The inquiry will be headed by the Executive Commissioner Gary Banks of the commission, Commissioner Helen Owens and part-time Associate Commissioner Brendon Kearney.  </p>
<p>The Liberal-National government announced in its 1996/97 budget it would implement tax incentives worth about A$500 million a year to encourage people to take out private health insurance and to wean high earners off the public Medicare health system.</p>
<p>Under the terms of reference, the commission would review cost pressures including the impact of declining membership, increasing health care costs, use of private hospitals, the impact of setting premiums for 100 percent private health cover, and the costs to industry of beds in private and public hospitals.  </p>
<p>The inquiry, to report by February 28, would also look at industry competitiveness and regulations.</p>
<p>Costello said the commission would be asked to recommend ways of improving the overall economic performance of the industry.</p>
<p>-- Canberra bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
