<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597190" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIA SELLS STAKES IN 587 FIRMS FOR VOUCHERS.</title>
<headline>BULGARIA SELLS STAKES IN 587 FIRMS FOR VOUCHERS.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than half of Bulgarian state enterprises earmarked for mass privatisation have passed into private ownership after the second mass sell-off tender, a government official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The capital of 587 enterprises of a total of 1,050 listed (for mass privatisation) is now majority private-owned,&quot; Mass Privatisation Center director Pirin Atanassov told reporters.</p>
<p>In 439 the state firms the private share is more than 67 percent, he added.</p>
<p>Under Bulgaria's mass privatisation programme launched last year to speed up restructuring, some 1,050 enterprises with capital of around 95 billion levs were offered for mass sell-offs.</p>
<p>Around three million Bulgarians or 46 percent of the eligible population bought voucher booklets, each with a face value of 25,000 levs, which enabled them to take part in the programme.</p>
<p>They participated directly in the auctions, through the local post stations, or through 81 privatisation funds approved by the Stock Exchange and Securities Commission.</p>
<p>In the second voucher sell-off tender, which ended in April, 54.374 million shares in 820 firms were offered of which 24.187 million shares were bought.</p>
<p>Privatisation funds and individuals took part in the second tender with 23.6 billion levs worth of vouchers of which 14.3 billion levs were spent.</p>
<p>Voucher capital of 9.3 billion levs remained for the third tender, where shares in seven new companies and 30.187 million shares remaining from the first and second tenders will be offered.</p>
<p>The third tender is due to be held later this year, said Atanasov. The enterprises slated for mass privatisation include metal smelters, chemical fertaliser producers, a tyre maker, food processing plants among others.</p>
<p>The remainder of shares after the end of the third tender are expected to be collected in a post-privatisation fund, which is expected to be mostly private-owned, said Atanassov.</p>
<p>The European Bank for Reconstruction and Development has proposed backing for such a fund.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-91188</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
