<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597149" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: BUDAPEST RESTAURANT CLOSED DOWN OVER $6,000 DINNER.</title>
<headline>BUDAPEST RESTAURANT CLOSED DOWN OVER $6,000 DINNER.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Budapest restaurant which charged two Danish tourists and two women companions more than $6,000 for dinner and drinks was closed down for three months by local authorities on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Budapest Fifth District Council decided to close the restaurant pending further investigation.</p>
<p>&quot;We have closed the restaurant provisionally for 90 days while we conduct a more thorough investigation to decide whether we will close it permanently,&quot; council spokeswoman Judit Xantus told Hungarian television.</p>
<p>Consumer protection authorities said last week they had begun a legal proceeding against the Dreher Halaszcsarda after Preben Olsen lodged a complaint at a tourist office, saying he had been charged more than 1 million forints, newspapers said.</p>
<p>However, a successful claim against the restaurant's owner woulds only result in  maximum fine of 30,000 forints ($176) under Hungarian law.</p>
<p>The U.S. Embassy in Budapest earlier this month warned about overpricing and strongarm tactics employed in some Budapest cafes and nightclubs, although the Halaszcsarda was not among them.</p>
<p>Xantus added that her authority, which covers Budapest's main commercial district, would conduct checks on 250 establishments in the area.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
