<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597385" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Confusion over Kabila's plans for Kinshasa trip.</title>
<headline>Confusion over Kabila's plans for Kinshasa trip.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Wright</byline>
<dateline>LUBUMBASHI 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Confusion reigned over whether self-declared Zaire president Laurent Kabila would leave on Tuesday for his first visit to the capital Kinshasa since his forces ended decades of dictatorship and renamed the country.</p>
<p>A DC-9 plane carrying his aides and top officials left Zaire's second city Lubumbashi on Tuesday afternoon for Kinshasa, but there was no immediate sign of Kabila hiself.</p>
<p>Zambian President Frederick Chiluba's plane landed at the airport in Lubumbashi earlier on Tuesday, apparently to fly out Kabila, and alliance troops secured the area.</p>
<p>But after the DC-9 left for Kinshasa, troops withdrew from around Chiluba's aircraft aboard two trucks. &quot;We do not discuss the president's movements,&quot; said a senior AFDL official.</p>
<p>Aboard the DC-9 in addition to Kabila's aides were alliance political teachers to educate people about his rebellion and a large number of businessmen from Lubumbashi and the east of the country.</p>
<p>Other officials earlier on Tuesday gave contradictory signals on when Kabila would fly to Kinshasa, with one saying at the airport that he might not go on Tuesday and another saying earlier he would.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible Mr Kabila will not go to Kinshasa today,&quot; Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo (AFDL) finance commissioner Mawampanga Mwana Nanga told reporters.</p>
<p>Mawampanga later left aboard the DC-9 for Kinshasa, where thousands of residents headed for the airport hoping to catch a first glimpse of Kabila but were turned back by rebel troops.</p>
<p>In Kinshasa, another official said Kabila would not fly to the capital on Tuesday and acting security minister Paul Kabongo told Reuters Kabila would go at an &quot;opportune time&quot;.</p>
<p>Kabila declared himself president on Saturday, changing Zaire's name to the Democratic Republic of Congo, as his rebels entered Kinshasa one day after president Mobutu Sese Seko relinquished power and fled, ending 32 years of autocratic rule.</p>
<p>Mawampanga said the AFDL would stick to its long-standing policy of holding elections within one year, but he said supporters of Mobutu would be excluded from a transitional government, expected to be announced by Kabila on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a time for electioneering and campaigning, but this is the time when we need to come together. The president has said and repeated (elections) within 12 months,&quot; Mawampanga said.</p>
<p>The United States and South Africa have led appeals to the alliance to form a broad-based government in the wake of their victory including members of the civilian opposition to Mobutu.</p>
<p>Individual politicians, but not political parties, would be represented in the transitional government and Mobutu supporters would not be involved, Mawampanga said.</p>
<p>He said that reforming the banking system and overhauling the economy were priorities over creating a new currency.</p>
<p>&quot;The first priority is to jump-start the economy and create jobs and restore growth. We want to get economic activities to a threshold level without any distinction of sector. They (the private sector) are better at creating jobs and they have more money,&quot; Mawampanga said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUBUMBASHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
