<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597302" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British regulators unsure about government changes.</title>
<headline>British regulators unsure about government changes.</headline>
<byline>Alexander Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Government proposals to streamline Britain's financial services regulation were greeted on Tuesday with a mixture of relief and caution.</p>
<p>&quot;The current method of reporting is rather cumbersome and anything to simplify that will be very welcome. Its much too early to tell if it will make a difference,&quot; one banker said.</p>
<p>The Labour government, which came to power on May 1, had widely signalled its intention to alter the system of self-regulation devised by the Conservative government.</p>
<p>Under the proposals announced by Chancellor of the Exchequer Gordon Brown, top financial watchdog the Securities and Investments Board (SIB) will become the sole regulator.</p>
<p>It will take in the previously self-regulating organisations set up by the Financial Services Act of 1986 as well as the responsibility for banking supervision, which was previously the role of the Bank of England.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome the Chancellor's statement. Clearly we have a major task ahead of us,&quot; an SIB spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We and our fellow regulators will be starting work immediately with a view to reporting back to the Chancellor as requested by the end of July,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Brown told parliament that the reforms would start immediately and the current system of self-regulation would be replaced by a new statutory system which put public interest first and increase public confidence.</p>
<p>The Investment Management Regulatory Organisation (IMRO) -- one of the so-called &quot;frontline&quot; regulators which will be wrapped into the new enlarged SIB -- said the announcement lifted an element of uncertainty.</p>
<p>&quot;Following the period of uncertainty, we are pleased to learn of government's intentions and look forward to early and full participation as envisaged by the Chancellor,&quot; IMRO spokeswoman Judy Delaforce told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The success of the new system will depend on the implementation,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Another of the self-regulators, the Securities and Futures Authority (SFA), said it welcomed the fact that the Chancellor's plans included more than just the SIB and the SROs.</p>
<p>&quot;I am happy to see the Chancellor's recognition of the importance of continuing practioner input, and the necessary division between wholesale and retail regulation,&quot; SFA chairman Nick Durlacher said in a letter to Chief Secretary to the Treasury Alistair Darling.</p>
<p>The third SRO, the Personal Investment Authority (PIA), was not immediately available for comment on the proposed changes, which will involve legislation.</p>
<p>While in opposition, the Labour government had said one of the main objectives of changing the regulatory system would be to cut costs but regulatory sources said the number of staff would not change dramatically under the new system.</p>
<p>They said it would be hard to cut down on the  number of compliance staff without adversely affecting regulatory standards, adding that staff cuts would more likely be made as a result of duplication of support personnel.</p>
<p>While the Chancellor answered the big question of who would be replacing Sir Andrew Large as chairman of the SIB by announcing the appointment of Howard Davies to the role, regulatory sources said there was precious little detail of how the new regulator would work.</p>
<p>Among the question marks left hanging over the system were what would happen to the existing chief executives and chairmen of the three frontline watchdogs, where the merged entity would be based and how it would be paid for.</p>
<p>The various regulators are currently spread around the City of London in individual offices and are entirely separate from the SIB.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
