<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597303" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's new SIB head Davies is freethinking high-flier.</title>
<headline>UK's new SIB head Davies is freethinking high-flier.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deputy Bank of England governor Howard Davies, who on Tuesday was named as the head of a new powerful regulatory body, is an irreverent freethinker famed for his toughness.</p>
<p>A Bank spokeswoman said Davies would shortly take over as head of the new, strengthened Securities and Investment Board designed to regulate banks, security firms and insurance companies.</p>
<p>The new Labour government wants Davies, at 45 a career high-flier, to tighten supervision of the financial services industry after a series of embarrassing scandals.</p>
<p>Davies, who often likes cracking jokes, has in his time been seen as an ally by both right and left but prefers to steer his own course and deflects questions about his political allegiances.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not an ideologist. What I'm really interested in is running things. I find myself more comfortable when someone says: 'Here's the framework. Help us make it work',&quot; he once told an interviewer.</p>
<p>Davies' track record is nothing if not impressive and it was almost predictable that he should be asked to take on a more important post less than two years after he became deputy Bank of England governor in September 1995.</p>
<p>He moved to the bank after serving for three years as director general of the Confederation of British Industry, where he was credited with sharpening both the image and the effectiveness of the organisation.</p>
<p>&quot;I've always been ambitious except that some people think that means you have an overriding goal...I'm prepared to take risks. But if you ask where I'll be in 15 years, I am at a loss,&quot; he once said.</p>
<p>Davies is a driven man who colleagues says does not possess much sentimentality.</p>
<p>Archie Norman, boss of superstore chain Asda, said Davies possessed the best &quot;five-second mind&quot; he knew, referring to an ability to sum up situations very quickly and then take important decisions.</p>
<p>After graduating from Oxford University Davies worked for three years as a diplomat before joining the Treasury in 1976, where he made friends with middle-ranking executive Eddie George -- who now heads the bank.</p>
<p>Davies, who is married with two children, is a keen soccer and cricket fan and likes reviewing books.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
