<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597319" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BA to meet EU soon to discuss alliance.</title>
<headline>BA to meet EU soon to discuss alliance.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Airways Plc said on Tuesday it would meet European Commission representatives &quot;as soon as possible&quot; to discuss its planned alliance with American Airlines.</p>
<p>A company spokesman added the group welcomed the chance to assuage any competition concerns the European Commission might have about the proposed deal.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been waiting for the Commission to tell us  any concerns it might have about our proposed alliance...The Commission has indicated that it would like to meet us and we welcome the opportunity,&quot; the BA spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;What we've got to do is listen to what these concerns are,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Although the alliance was far from the stage at which one could talk about &quot;doing deals&quot;, he noted that BA remained confident of convincing British, European and U.S. regulators of the link-up's consumer benefits.</p>
<p>A Commission source told Reuters in Brussels earlier that the European Union's executive would tell the British government at a meeting on Tuesday morning that the planned alliance would harm fair competition unless the terms of the deal were changed.</p>
<p>Critics say that the transatlantic route into London's Heathrow airport is one of the most lucrative in the world and an alliance between BA and American would dominate the gateway into Europe.</p>
<p>Industry experts say that the only likely way BA would win Commission approval for the alliance would be to hand over more slots from Heathrow to rivals.</p>
<p>Both BA and American have already relinquished slots.</p>
<p>Last December, BA and American were told by British regulators to give up 168 weekly slots at Heathrow -- but the Commission said that was not enough and more concessions would be needed.</p>
<p>However, BA noted there are 350 worldwide airline alliances with which it has to compete and it would be unprecedented to give up airport slots ahead of forming an alliance.</p>
<p>Another central condition to clearance is the agreement of an &quot;open skies&quot; deal between the U.S. and British governments, opening the way for liberalisation of transatlatic flights.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
