<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597346" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK 1997 cereals yield seen down after dry spell.</title>
<headline>UK 1997 cereals yield seen down after dry spell.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>British cereal yields are likely to fall this year, after a prolonged dry spell through much of the growing period, farming sector analysts said.</p>
<p>But a small increase in area over plantings for the previous year means that any reduction in crop will be limited.</p>
<p>The UK had a bumper crop of just over 16 million tonnes of wheat in 1996, compared with 14.31 million tonnes in 1995, agriculture ministry figures show. The 1995 barley crop was also good, at 8.739 million tonnes, compared with 8.077 million in the previous year.</p>
<p>Despite the bumper 1996 crop, plantings for this year's harvest rose by 2.2 per cent for wheat and 8.3 per cent for barley, according to December census figures published by the Home Grown Cereals Authority.</p>
<p>After showery weather in much of May, the UK's developing barley crop has reached the point where it has had enough moisture to see it through, and wheat is close to that point, they said.</p>
<p>But wheat on some light soils could face stress if the weather were turn hot and dry from now on, an expert at the ADAS agricultural consultancy said.</p>
<p>Developing crops in some areas have been damaged by thunderstorms, he added. But it remains to be seen how well they can recover.</p>
<p>The driest start to the year since 1929 in Britain has been followed by showery weather for much of May and more showers are predicted for the period to mid-June.</p>
<p>But although the wet weather is solving immediate soil and plant moisture problems, it will not be enough to solve longer term groundwater supply worries, water industry sources said.</p>
<p>--Christopher Lyddon, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7928</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
