<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597389" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TOGO: Mobutu son denies any link with army chief's death.</title>
<headline>Mobutu son denies any link with army chief's death.</headline>
<dateline>LOME 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The soldier son of Zaire's ousted president Mobutu Sese Seko on Tuesday denied any link with last week's murder in Kinshasa of army chief of staff and defence minister General Mahele Lieko Bokungo.</p>
<p>Captain Mobutu Kongolo, speaking in the capital of Togo, told Reuters that he was now a businessman and had resigned from Zaire's armed forces on May 17 -- the day he fled the Zairean capital and Laurent Kabila's rebels.</p>
<p>&quot;I had nothing to do with this matter (Mahele's murder). I have nothing to reproach myself with, my hands are clean and I will respond at the appropriate time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dipolomats in Kinshasa said  Mahele was killed late on Friday night by a member or members of a unit of Mobutu's presidential guard at the TshTshi army camp.</p>
<p>Kongolo, an officer in the presidential guard, said  he had warned Mahele that he was in danger and had tried to persuade him not to go to Camp Tshatshi.</p>
<p>He said Mahele had telephoned him for help but that as he went to help him, his own vehicle had been targeted and he had turned round and left.</p>
<p>Kongolo, heading into exile like many of Mobutu's clan, said he was on a brief visit to Togo, where his father prolonged a technical stopover on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A source close to the government said the veteran strongman had been &quot;very weak&quot; when he arrived in Lome by plane from his jungle palace in Gbadolite, northern Zaire.</p>
<p>The ousted president, who has cancer, left Kinshasa on Friday. Diplomats said Mahele had been among those who had told him that his army could not defend the city. Mahele had been due to meet Kabila to discuss a handover of power, one said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TOGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TOGO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
