<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597412" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Sudan rebels say they capture town.</title>
<headline>Sudan rebels say they capture town.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sudanese rebels said they captured the southern town of Gogrial on Tuesday and now controlled most of the Bar el Ghazal region.</p>
<p>George Garang Sudan People's Liberation Army (SPLA) spokesman in Nairobi said: &quot;Today (Tuesday) very early in the morning operation Deng Mhial captured Gogrial...we have now cleared the whole of Gogrial.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It is very significant as it lies in Bahr el Ghazal region and the only major place which is left (in government hands) is Wau, which is the capital,&quot; Garang said after speaking to Sudan rebels by telephone.</p>
<p>There were no more details on the capture and no independent confirmation.</p>
<p>The SPLA has been active in the Bar el Ghazal region for years but regional capital Wau is a secondary target compared to the main southern city of Juba.</p>
<p>Gogrial is a small town 60 km (37 miles) north of regional capital Wau and around 100 km (60 miles) northwest of Tonj, a town the SPLA says it captured last Wednesday.</p>
<p>The SPLA is part of the National Democratic Alliance (NDA), a coalition between southern and northern opponents of the Islamist government in Khartoum. The rebels have seized a string of towns in the south and east since launching their current offensive in January.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
