<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597575" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Albania - May 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Albania - May 20.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Albanian press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>KOHA JONE</p>
<p>- Editorial says President Sali Berisha has launched a ghost electoral campaign while opposition parties still hesitate over participating in upcoming elections.</p>
<p>- An interview with Vlore residents says two people shot dead on Monday were allegedly killed by the Shik secret police.</p>
<p>- Germany holds the Democratic Party and Berisha responsible for the deadlock over the electoral law.</p>
<p>- Local currency lek is losing ground against the dollar which is quoted at 160 leks, up from 155 last week.</p>
<p>- Two-page interview with Bashkim Driza, boss of the Populli investment scheme that collapsed in January, accusing former Prime Minister Aleksander Meksi of stealing $20 million from Populli to cover the budget deficit.</p>
<p>ALBANIA</p>
<p>- Leftist parties are scared they might fail to enter the next parliament.</p>
<p>- The Kardhiqi bridge linking Gjirokaster with the rest of the country was rocked by a strong explosion. Specialists say that the movement of trucks is impossible.</p>
<p>- President Sali Berisha remains the backbone of the Democratic Party and will help it to win the June 29 elections, party leader Ylli Vejsiu said.</p>
<p>- Rightest parties will share more than 70 percent of seats in the next parliament, Berisha told a crowd of Democratic Party supporters in Shijak town on Sunday.</p>
<p>GAZETA SHQIPTARE</p>
<p>- Political parties have yet to agree on the electoral law. The south is plunged into violence and anarchy.</p>
<p>- Berisha said he would not decree opposition amendments on the new election law passed by the Democrat-dominated parliament.</p>
<p>- Social Democratic Party has threatened to withdraw from national reconciliation government unless Berisha's Democratic Party includes opposition opinion in the electoral law.</p>
<p>RILINDJA DEMOKRATIKE</p>
<p>- President Sali Berisha accused Finance Minister Arben Malaj of blocking transparency on pyramid investment schemes.</p>
<p>- The winter of communist rebellion is over, the spring of democracy has come, paper says blaming the Socialist Party for the violence and chaos which hit Albania in February.</p>
<p>ZERI I POPULLIT</p>
<p>- Paper alleges that criminal bands roaming the country are the armed wing of Democratic Party and Shik.</p>
<p>- &quot;Down with Berisha&quot; and &quot;We want our money back&quot; people cried out in Kurbin as the Albanian President was about to adress an electoral rally.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
