<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597753" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico opposition accuses PRI of misuse of funds.</title>
<headline>Mexico opposition accuses PRI of misuse of funds.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's left-leaning Party of the Democratic Revolution (PRD) on Monday accused the ruling party of using public funds to win votes, a PRD spokesman said.</p>
<p>The PRD alleged that the Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI) handed out free parcels of publicly funded medicine in the southeast state of Campeche as if they were donations from President Ernesto Zedillo's party.</p>
<p>Campeche is one of six Mexican states where elections are scheduled to take place in July. Mexico City residents will vote for the first time to elect a mayor of the capital, and the country's Congress is also up for grabs.</p>
<p>PRD spokesman Arturo Moo said complaints were lodged with Campeche state's Health Ministry, and the PRD also planned to lodge complaints with Campeche state electoral authorities.</p>
<p>The PRI, which has held the presidency, control of Congress and most state governorships for 68 consecutive years, denied the misuse of state resources for electoral purposes.</p>
<p>&quot;The party does not use illegal resources to obtain votes&quot; said Enrique Ibarra, the party's spokesman at the Federal Electoral Institute. Ibarra said there was no internal investigation pending the allegations.</p>
<p>Misuse of public funds in Mexico for election purposes is not uncommon. Opposition parties have long argued that the PRI has held on to power through the use of fraud in elections and through &quot;buying&quot; votes from the country's poor.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
