<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597843" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK firms avoid criticising handover - C.Lyonnais.</title>
<headline>HK firms avoid criticising handover - C.Lyonnais.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong firms are not speaking up enough about the future under Chinese rule, fearing Beijing's reactions if they criticise post-handover policies, the chairman of Credit Lyonnais Securities Asia said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think business people in Hong Kong probably don't speak up enough. They would pay a huge penalty. People in China are very sensitive to criticism,&quot; Gary Coull told Reuters.</p>
<p>Hong Kong firms face an unlevel playing field after the British colony is returned to Chinese rule this July 1, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the short term the status quo is absolutely tattooed on everyone's forehead but in the medium term there is bound to be a slightly more uneven playing field in terms of business.</p>
<p>&quot;I would guess that increasingly (Chinese) companies will have greater influence in Hong Kong than they already do and that there will be a realignment of the political power forces in Hong Kong,&quot; Coull said.</p>
<p>Coull said the investment community generally was not concerned about plans to curb civil rights in Hong Kong after the sovereignty change, the major issue of debate in Hong Kong political circles over the past month.</p>
<p>He said while Hong Kong had been run in a &quot;balanced way&quot; with British and Chinese influences, &quot;the new government will want to run Hong Kong pro-actively for China&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I suspect that it won't be as smooth and possibly as efficient but it does not mean it won't be successful.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question that there is going to be an adjustment process between a British-run commercial centre and one that is run by Hong Kong people,&quot; Coull said.</p>
<p>Credit Lyonnais published a handover confidence survey on Tuesday which showed that while Hong Kong residents did not expect the handover government to be more fair, open or effective against corruption than the British administration, they were positive about post-handover economic prospects.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong News Room (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
