<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="597927" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Minor Metals -- Cobalt seen easing as Zaire calms.</title>
<headline>Minor Metals -- Cobalt seen easing as Zaire calms.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cobalt prices are expected to ease in the near future as the world's leading countries say they will cooperate with the new leader of Zaire Laurent Kabila, traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Kabila's rebel forces ousted President Mobutu Sese Seko over the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;The future is bright,&quot; said one cobalt trader at a major Japanese trading house. &quot;We had been worried over the supply of some materials, such as petrol, necessary for cobalt and copper production in Zaire.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said Japanese as well as Chinese cobalt users were withholding purchases of the metal hoping that prices would soon come down from the current high levels.</p>
<p>Only few cobalt deals were struck, and prices for high-grade cobalt were quoted at $24.00/26.00 per lb and low-grade at $22.00/24.00, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Users are waiting for the prices to come down. Yet they might start buying again. The dollar's fall helps,&quot; said another Japanese trader.</p>
<p>The dollar fell to below 112 yen on Tuesday, its lowest level since December 6, 1996.</p>
<p>Traders also expect the U.S. Defense Logistics Agency (DLA) will soon resume sales of its cobalt stockpiles, which have been suspended since March. The U.S. court of Federal Claims is set to announce its decision over a claim by Minor Metals Inc later today, they said.</p>
<p>Senior traders of Minor Metals are currently visiting customers in Japan, and are expressing their interest in selling cobalt, traders said.</p>
<p>Sources close to Zambia's ZCCM said its cobalt output was likely to rise towards 300 tonnes this month after output fell to 250 tonnes in April because of production problems.</p>
<p>In the cadmium market, Japanese traders said sentiment here was weak even though overseas' market sentiment was strong amid talk of low producer and consumer stocks.</p>
<p>Japanese traders said high-grade cadmium was quoted at 52/63 cents per lb, while low-grade stood at 49/53 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;We had offers from Europe and Latin America. Traders might be artificially trying to push up the price,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>&quot;With the situation in Japan pretty poor, I can't imagine the global market is getting tight,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Official data shows Japan, the world's largest cadmium user, consumed 8,364 tonnes of the metal last year, which accounts for about 43 percent of the world's total consumption.</p>
<p>Traders said nickel-cadmium batteries, which account for more than 90 percent of Japan's cadmium demand, faced strong competition from other types such as lithium ion batteries.</p>
<p>They also noted supplies of cadmium, a by-product of zinc, were set to rise in view of the world's higher zinc production.</p>
<p>In the molybdenum market, the price fell to $4.50/4.55 per lb from $4.50/4.60 last week, but there were few offers in the market following strong demand from pipe makers, traders said.</p>
<p>In Shanghai, traders said bismuth was set to advance towards $4.00 per lb as Chinese producers withheld stocks in anticipation of higher prices. No activity was reported.</p>
<p>Manganese exports from China have almost doubled during the early months of 1997, but the rise comes on the back of slow exports in late 1996, another trader in Hong Kong said.</p>
<p>&quot;They just took advantage of an increase in the price in the early part of the year because they were desperate to make more money whenever they could,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Official Chinese figures showed China's manganese exports in the first three months of 1997 soared 97 percent to 12,518 tonnes over same period in 1996.</p>
<p>The market price of $1,275/1,375 per tonne quoted ex-warehouse Rotterdam was not making money for Chinese producers, he said. The production cost in China is 11,000 yuan ($1,310) a tonne, he said.</p>
<p>-- Lynne O'Donnell, Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-8544</p>
<p>-- Nao Nakanishi in Tokyo +81-3-3432-6179</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
