<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="598027" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Air Force awaits Pentagon word to launch trial.</title>
<headline>Air Force awaits Pentagon word to launch trial.</headline>
<byline>Greg Frost</byline>
<dateline>MINOT, N.D. 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Local Air Force officials waited on Tuesday for permission from the Pentagon to launch a court-martial of the first female B-52 bomber pilot on charges including adultery.</p>
<p>Dozens of journalists shuffled around a windowless room at Minot Air Force Base as officials sought word on whether to move forward with the trial of Lt. Kelly Flinn.</p>
<p>Meanwhile in Washington, Senate Republican leader Trent Lott said on Tuesday he believed Flinn was being &quot;badly abused&quot; by the Air Force and pledged to take the issue up with Defence Secretary William Cohen if the case moves ahead.</p>
<p>The trial was put on hold while the Pentagon's Military Justice Division considered Flinn's bid to resign from the Air Force with an honourable discharge to avoid a court-martial on charges including adultery and fraternisation.</p>
<p>Flinn, who is 26 and single, has acknowledged having an affair with a married civilian and also having sex with a lower-ranking enlisted man, violating the military code of conduct. She has also been charged with lying during an official investigation and failing to obey a direct order.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday, Flinn walked into the military personnel building which houses the small courtroom where she was due to face trial. She wore a blue Air Force uniform and was accompanied by her civilian lawyer, Frank Spinner.</p>
<p>But as the court-martial was supposed to begin, Air Force officials told reporters that the trial would be delayed while the Pentagon mulled what to do.</p>
<p>Maj. Joe LaMarca said base officials had asked the Pentagon whether to go ahead with the trial after Flinn's lawyers submitted her conditional resignation on Monday. He would not comment on how long it would take the military justice division to respond.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be today. It could be tomorrow. I don't know,&quot; said Maj. Ed Worley, an Air Force spokesman at the Pentagon. &quot;Because of the visibility of this case we're hoping to get it (the reply to the prosecutors) as soon as we can.&quot;</p>
<p>Even if the Pentagon allows the trial to proceed, the judge in the case could delay the court-martial amid legal manoeuvrings by Flinn's lawyers, who are hoping to delay the trial until June 2 to give the Air Force time to consider her request and to give Flinn's lawyers more time to prepare.</p>
<p>Unnamed Pentagon officials said on Monday that Flinn was unlikely to receive an honourable discharge from Air Force Secretary Shiela Widnall, who sits atop the chain of command considering her request.</p>
<p>Conviction on adultery charges in a military trial is punishable by penalties that could range from a dishonourable discharge to fines and imprisonment. Critics have argued Flinn's case highlights a double-standard in the way the U.S. Armed Forces treats the issue of adultery among its male and female staff.</p>
<p>Flinn's lawyers say she is being unfairly persecuted for something commonplace in civilian life, a position echoed on Tuesday by Senator Lott.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't understand why she is being singled out and punished the way she is. I think at a minium she ought to get an honourable discharge,&quot; the Mississippi Republican said.</p>
<p>Calling the Pentagon &quot;not in touch with reality,&quot; Lott said that if Flinn's case does not turn out &quot;better than it looks like it's going to be worked out, I am going to take it up with him (Defense Secretary Cohen) because I think she has been badly abused.&quot;</p>
<p>Air Force officials have argued the matter boiled down to broader violations of the code of conduct, including disobeying orders and lying during an official investigation.</p>
<p>Marc Zigo, the civilian man with whom Flinn had an affair, said on CNN that he was ready to testify in Minot and had not been pressured by the Air Force to do so.</p>
<p>&quot;I did tell the truth and that's what I intend to do when it comes to trial,&quot; Zigo said, adding that during their affair Flinn had been aware of his marriage, which has since ended.</p>
<p>While he noted that he &quot;hoped for the best,&quot; Zigo implied that he supported the legal moves against Flinn.</p>
<p>&quot;You will see what the law is. And that's what she signed up for,&quot; Zigo said.</p>
<p>Flinn's lawyers said if she recieved a less-than-honourable discharge from the Air Force, it could preclude her from flying for the National Guard or the military reserves. It might also hinder her civilian job prospects such as becoming a commercial airline pilot.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINOT, N.D."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
