<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="598026" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Maxwell ups coffee prices; producers warn of slump.</title>
<headline>Maxwell ups coffee prices; producers warn of slump.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Maxwell House Coffee Co. Tuesday boosted the price of coffee as producers warned that a speculative bubble that has lifted prices by up to 100 percent since January might burst just as dramatically as it began.</p>
<p>Maxwell House, a division of Philip Morris' Kraft Foods, said it was raising the list price on its standard 13-ounce cans of regular and decaffeinated ground coffees by 30 cents due to higher prices of coffee on the world's futures markets.</p>
<p>The increase, which follows a similar price hike Monday by Folgers Coffee Co., the largest U.S. roaster, brings the new price for a standard can of regular ground coffee to $3.36, and decaffeinated ground Maxwell House to $4.06.</p>
<p>Folgers' prices are now 50 percent higher than they were before it started raising prices in February.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the International Coffee Organisation said coffee futures prices, which last week soared to 20-year highs, could slump if commodity funds, which have been big buyers, start to sell the holdings that they have built up in the past few months.</p>
<p>&quot;With cumulative purchases by investment funds, there is always a possibility that a massive liquidation of positions could trigger large falls in prices,&quot; the coffee group said.</p>
<p>Such a prospect is unlikely before the end of Brazil's winter season, which runs from June to August, when there is a risk of a damaging frost in the world's biggest coffee grower.</p>
<p>But the speculative character of the rally in coffee, the longest unbroken run-up in two decades, has fanned concerns.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the price of the July contract closed 6 cents lower at $2.4025 a pound on New York's Coffee, Cocoa and Sugar Exchange, after rising last week to a 20-year high of $2.775.</p>
<p>Coffee producers are enjoying a windfall now, but fret about future volatility and a risk that, as roasters pass on the high cost of beans at the shops, consumers may switch to tea or soft drinks.</p>
<p>Reacting to this danger, the 14-nation Association of Coffee Producing Countries, meeting in London Tuesday, is considering making export quotas more flexible, delegates said.</p>
<p>They said one idea is that producers would agree to meet again if prices rose to predetermined &quot;trigger&quot; levels.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a concern that as the market approaches $3.00 you start to impact consumption,&quot; said Steve Platt, an analyst at Dean Witter in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;And producers don't want to shut off consumption.&quot;</p>
<p>Helping to fuel the rise in coffee prices are low inventories at the big coffee-drinking countries, which were down to 7 million bags at the end of last year or only about one-third of levels early in the 1990s.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
