<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="598168" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Air Force orders delay in adultery trial.</title>
<headline>U.S. Air Force orders delay in adultery trial.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Air Force on Tuesday ordered a delay in the adultery trial of its first woman bomber pilot until Air Force Secretary Sheila Widnall can decide whether to accept the pilot's request for an honourable discharge from the service to end the case.  </p>
<p>The court martial of 1st Lt. Kelly Flinn had been scheduled to begin at Minot Air Force Base in North Dakota on Tuesday. She is charged with adultery, fraternisation and other violations of Air Force rules, including lying.</p>
<p>But the Air Force said in a brief announcement from the Pentagon late on Tuesday that Flinn's request to quit the service under honourable circumstances was making its way through the chain of command to Widnall's office.</p>
<p>&quot;In order to provide the chain of command and the secretary with an opportunity to review and give due consideration to this matter, the request (by Air Force officials in Minot) to proceed to trial, including pre-trial sessions, has been denied,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Flinn, who is 26 and single, has acknowledged having an affair with a married civilian and also having sex with a lower-ranking enlisted man, violating the military code of conduct. She has also been charged with lying during an official investigation and failing to obey a direct order.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
