<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="598314" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. cotton planting progresses rapidly in week.</title>
<headline>U.S. cotton planting progresses rapidly in week.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cotton planting progressed rapidly in most U.S. producer states in the week ended May 18 with some concerns about dry, cool weather cited in the southeast, according to a weekly crop reports from state agricultural statistics services.</p>
<p>MISSISSIPPI - Cotton was 89 percent planted versus 34 a week ago, 96 a year ago and 84 on a 5-year average. Cotton was 46 percent emerged vs 9 last week, 86 last year and 69 average. Rain is needed in much of state, though dry weather conditions have been favorable for crop planting. Soil moisture conditions were rated 6 percent very short, 33 percent short, 56 percent adequate, and 5 percent surplus.  </p>
<p>LOUISIANA - Dry weather across the northern portion of the state allowed fieldwork to proceed at a brisk pace. Cotton planting reached 90 percent complete vs 96 a year ago, 91 on average. Cotton was 55 percent emerged, vs 85 a year ago and 81 on average. Soil moisture was 7 percent surplus, 70 adequate, 22 short and 1 very short.</p>
<p>GEORGIA - Cotton planting made excellent progress and is currently less than a week behind average at 71 percent complete vs 77 last year, 78 average. Cotton was rated 51 percent excellent, 36 good, 7 fair, 1 poor. Emerged cotton continues in fair to good condition. Producers continued to replant some cotton fields. Soils dried rapidly with topsoil moisture ratings falling to short to mostly adequate. The continued cool weather has some farmers concerned.  </p>
<p>TEXAS - Planting in the Plains was slowly increasing as soil temperatures warmed up and fields dried. Emergence has been slow. Planting was 38 percent complete versus 35 a year ago and 42 on a 5-year average. Cotton was 3 percent squared versus 4 last year and 6 on average. Growth has been slow in the Blacklands and Central Texas where warm temperatures and slightly drier conditions are needed in many fields. Fields continued to square in the Coastal Bend and Rio Grande Valley. Statewide cotton was rated 75 percent of normal vs 54 in 1996.</p>
<p>CALIFORNIA - Field activities progressed normally under clear skies and hot temperatures in most areas. Cotton planting was virtually complete. Emerged fields were cultivated, irrigated, weeded and treated for aphids and mites. Replanted fields showed good germination and the warm weather helped to accelerate growth.  </p>
<p>ARIZONA - Temperatures continued well above normal during the week providing favorable growing conditions for cotton. Statewide, temperatures were 5 to 13 degrees (F) above average with some precipitation reported in eastern sections. Cotton planting was 97 percent complete and 18 percent squared. This compared to 24 percent squared a year ago and 8 on average. Some cotton acreage was beginning to bloom in the west. Cotton was rated 36 percent excellent, 48 good, 14 fair.</p>
<p>((Eileen Houlihan, NY Commodity Desk 212 859-1645))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
