<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="59831" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Australian PM Howard wants to meet Dalai Lama.</title>
<headline>Australian PM Howard wants to meet Dalai Lama.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard said on Tuesday he would meet Tibet's exiled spiritual leader, the Dalai Lama, on his current visit to Australia if their schedules permitted.</p>
<p>&quot;Providing our mutual programmes make it possible, I will see him in Australia next week,&quot; Howard told a media conference in Jakarta during a three-day official visit.</p>
<p>China on Tuesday expressed anger over the visit to Australia by the Dalai Lama who Beijing believes is leading a pro-independence battle for the Himalayan region invaded by Chinese troops in 1950.</p>
<p>&quot;With regard to the Australian side...allowing the Dalai Lama to visit and arranging meetings with senior government officials, we express deep regret and strong dissatisfaction,&quot; a Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman said in Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese side reserves the right to make further response depending on the development of the situation,&quot; the spokesman added.</p>
<p>The Dalai Lama arrived in Canberra on Tuesday as part of a two-week Australian tour.</p>
<p>&quot;I have explained to the Chinese authorities that naturally the Australian prime minister decides according to Australian interests who the Australian prime minister sees,&quot; Howard said.</p>
<p>&quot;I understand the sensitivities of the Chinese government and I also understand the Dalai is a religious leader who has been to Australia before,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a proper reputation as a country of religious and political tolerance and in that context the meeting between us, if it can be arranged, will take place,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>China routinely opposes all overseas tours by the Dalai Lama, who has been in exile since an abortive uprising against Chinese rule in Tibet in 1959, and who won the 1989 Nobel Peace Prize for his peaceful campaign for Tibetan autonomy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
