<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="598418" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU reaches accord on &quot;pig hotels&quot;.</title>
<headline>EU reaches accord on &quot;pig hotels&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Peter Blackburn</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union farm ministers on Tuesday struck a political deal on rules for &quot;pig hotels&quot; -- rest centres for farm animals on marathon journeys across the continent, diplomats said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was agreed by consensus,&quot; a German diplomat said, adding the European Commission was asked to examine possible special measures demanded by Britain, Denmark and Ireland for high-value breeding pigs and to report back as soon as possible.</p>
<p>A British official said Britain abstained from the political agreement. It can only be finalised, probably in June, after a legal text has been drafted.</p>
<p>&quot;We wanted to take it further forward,&quot; the official said, adding, &quot;It's less stressful for the animals to remain in the vehicles.&quot;</p>
<p>But Britain, which sees itself as a nation of animal lovers, did not want to be seen voting against animal welfare, especially as the new Labour government has adopted a more constructive approach towards Europe.</p>
<p>Along with the Danes and Irish, Britain had argued that the pigs did not need to be unloaded at rest centres and that this put them at risk of disease.</p>
<p>A European Commission spokesman said member states would have to implement the rest centre rules by the end of 1998. Proposals for standards for &quot;pig pullman&quot; vehicles are due to be presented in the next few weeks.</p>
<p>The EU's executive also recently proposed linking export subsidies to animal welfare but a decision is not expected for some time due to problems over implementation.</p>
<p>The rest centres were part of a deal in June 1995, after five years of argument, to ease the pain of millions of animals crammed annually into lorries for trips of up to 50 hours from northern producer states to southern slaughter houses.</p>
<p>Swedes and other northerners have denounced transport conditions as cruel but southerners, such as Italy, protest that the new rules will raise costs, making imports of live animals uneconomic and throwing tens of thousands of people out of work.</p>
<p>They set a basic eight hours journey limit for cattle, pigs, sheep and other farm animals, after which they must be unloaded from their vehicles and rest for 24 hours before continuing their journeys.</p>
<p>The rest centre rules cover animal feeding, watering, loading, unloading and disease controls.</p>
<p>Germany has criticised delays in agreeing minimum standards for rest centres and vehicles which have prevented implemention of the animal transport rules by an original deadline of end-1996.</p>
<p>The Commission says the target date was unrealistic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100119">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
