<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="598457" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Demand in Portugal EDP sale over 100 mln shares.</title>
<headline>Demand in Portugal EDP sale over 100 mln shares.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Demand for shares in the forthcoming privatisation of Portugal's state electricity company EDP is well over 100 million shares, representing more than half the stock likely to be on offer, banking sources said.</p>
<p>The government has said it hopes to sell off up to 30 percent of EDP, or 180 million shares, but it is ready to float even more if the demand is there.</p>
<p>The privatisation, which is due to take place on June 16, could raise a maximum of 400 billion escudos and will be the country's biggest ever state sell-off.</p>
<p>The initial pre-registration period for buying EDP shares opened on Monday and will continue until May 28. The coordinators of the privatisation say they will provide information on how the sale is going at the end of this week.</p>
<p>Sources at Portugal's top banking groups said most of the investment orders were made through special share-buying accounts in which investors deposit payment for EDP shares ahead of the sale.</p>
<p>&quot;The majority of demand is coming through the so-called 'super accounts',&quot; one source told Reuters.</p>
<p>Demand had been so strong that banks had had to ask for more order forms and one source said he believed final demand would outstrip supply fivefold.</p>
<p>-- Lisbon editorial +(351-1) 3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
