<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="598472" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: UPS Germany workers plan May 22 protests.</title>
<headline>UPS Germany workers plan May 22 protests.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Parcel Service of America workers in Germany plan to demonstrate at locations across the country on Thursday during a worldwide day of action, union officials said.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the OeTV transport workers union told Reuters that employees of the global express company will be protesting for better conditions, more full-time posts and improved safety.</p>
<p>A UPS spokesman told Reuters that the company was not expecting a significant staff response to the day of action.</p>
<p>He added: &quot;The service for clients will take place according to plan, not only in Germany but across Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>The London-based International Federation of Transport Workers (ITF) has called rallies at UPS offices in Atlanta and Brussels and at other locations in nine countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Demonstrations will take place in front of UPS works. The actions will last several hours,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>&quot;The problems are the same in Germany and around the world - part-time jobs and job safety with heavy loads,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The main demonstrations would be in North Rhine Westphalia, Hesse, Baden-Wuerttemberg and Bavaria but she could not say how many of the 14,000 UPS staff in Germany would take part.</p>
<p>A UPS statement added that the company had gradually re-structured operations in some European countries in recent years.</p>
<p>&quot;Market demands have changed and UPS has adjusted its operations to the new demands so that the long-term success of the company in Europe is also ensured in the future,&quot; the statement said. -- Reuters Air Cargo Newsroom. Tel +44 171 542 7706; Fax: 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
