<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="598576" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Chidmabaram warns of banking shake-out.</title>
<headline>India's Chidmabaram warns of banking shake-out.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's plans to make the rupee fully convertible during the next few years will lead to a shake-out among public sector banks, Finance Minister P. Chidambaram told a news magazine.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, there will be a shake-out. And some banks will suffer because of capital account convertibility. That is bound to happen. In any case, the pressure is on the banks now,&quot; Chidambaram said in an interview with the fortnightly magazine Business India.</p>
<p>He said banks were required to put stricter covenants in place before tax payers money would be put into ill-performing, under-capitalised banks.</p>
<p>&quot;I have declined to recapitalise Indian Bank. Not yet, anyway. The others I am re-capitalising under very strict conditions. For instance, UCO Bank I will recapitalise only after they begin implementing the turnaround plan that they have worked out. Only then will they get the funds. And that's going to be the rule of the game for the three or four others.&quot;</p>
<p>Indian Bank and UCO Bank are loss-making public sector banks.</p>
<p>Indian Bank reported a loss of 13,364 million rupees for the year ended March 31, 1996.</p>
<p>UCO Bank reported a net loss of 2,366.6 million rupees for the year ended March 31, 1996.</p>
<p>The banks are yet to report their performance for 1996/97 (April-March).</p>
<p>Chidambaram said a broad swathe of financial sector reforms were on his agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;We have given some autonomy to the banks. This has to be increased much more. We need to segregate the men from the boys,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Then there is the insurance sector, which is crying out loud for reforms and greater competitiveness. The market for insurance is vast and we haven't tapped it yet. The insurance regulatory authority has to be given teeth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Stockmarkets, futures, options, derivatives, merchant banking, more transparent regulations...,&quot; were all areas reforms needed to address and the role of the Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI) will be under scrutiny, he said.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said his long term target for the Indian economy was the eradication of poverty.</p>
<p>&quot;My goal is simple. In my lifetime, I want to see India grow at 8 to 8.5 percent per annum, year after year, and so eliminate the poverty that we have known for five thousand years.</p>
<p>&quot;In my estimate, that requires a per capita income of $1,500. If we grow at 8 percent per year, we can reach this target in 18 to 20 years.&quot; -- Bombay newsroom (91) 22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
