<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="598926" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Traders ponder fate of final Iraqi crude cargoes.</title>
<headline>Traders ponder fate of final Iraqi crude cargoes.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>No liftings of Iraqi Kirkuk crude have been set for the final two weeks of the first 180-day period of the U.N. oil-for-food exchange, indicating Baghdad is close to its $2 billion revenue target under the scheme, traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>And if crude prices remain firm cargoes could be at risk of deferral or cancellation if the scheme's revenues are judged by U.N. overseers to have overshot the target.</p>
<p>The final loading on May 25 of a one million barrel cargo at the Turkish port of Ceyhan is a full two weeks ahead of the expiry of the six-month scheme on June 7, they said.</p>
<p>Some traders said there was doubt about whether the loading, planned by Trafigura under a term contract with Iraq's State Oil Marketing Organisation (SOMO), would be given final U.N. approval.</p>
<p>In addition, there was uncertainty over the fate of  two cargo of Iraq's Basrah light due to load from the Gulf port of Mina al-Bakr in the final two weeks of the programme.</p>
<p>&quot;The last cargoes to be scheduled are definitely at risk,&quot; a Mediterranean crude trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a complete reversal of the situation in the first quarter of the programme when they had to increase loadings in a falling market.&quot;</p>
<p>Lifters said U.N. overseers were taking &quot;quite a time&quot; to approve liftings, in marked contrast to the early months of the programme when approval would be given by the overseers within two days of application.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is to get U.N. approval. Then you are safe,&quot; one European lifter said.</p>
<p>&quot;Remember that under this scheme a loading programme is just a schedule. It's not binding. It doesn't mean you have final approval. You can have SOMO approval but without the U.N. approval it won't happen.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sure the U.N. operates within a safety net. That is to say that the U.N. only approves a lifting when they are sure it will not violate the revenue limit.&quot;</p>
<p>Iraq's agreement with the U.N., which began on December 10, allows Baghdad to sell $2 billion over the six months and must be reviewed for possible renewal by the Security Council before it expires.</p>
<p>Receipt limits are actually pegged at $2.14 billion over the six months to June 7, allowing an extra $140 million to pay Turkey pipeline fees.</p>
<p>Nearly two-thirds of oil proceeds are earmarked for food and medicine purchases, as part of a humanitarian exception to sanctions placed on Iraq after it invaded Kuwait in 1990.</p>
<p>Before June 7, U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan is to issue a report on the accord's effectiveness in alleviating suffering in the country, within a broad progress report on the deal's implementation.</p>
<p>The U.N. Security Council was then to take action on renewing the accord.</p>
<p>The programme has been bedevilled by its value-based structure. This has ensured that in a falling international oil market Iraqi must increase exports to meet the target and thereby accelerate the losses. In a rising market, it must curb exports thus helping lift oil market values.</p>
<p>One lifter was resigned to the continuance of the structure. &quot;I don't really know if the structure of the deal will change in the second period. Yes, it means a lot of time and effort and uncertainty getting approvals, but no one ever said this was going to be easy.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders say Total, which has a cargo loading on Tuesday at Ceyhan, had to wait 10 days for the May 9 approval from the overseers for a 360,000 barrel top-up.</p>
<p>SOMO has not signed any new contract since the end of April.</p>
<p>Another Mediterranean trader said he felt the Trafigura cargo would be loaded but he added there was &quot;complete uncertainty&quot; about how the revenue would be accounted -- possibly, but not inevitably, on the books of a second 180-day programme.</p>
<p>Trafigura, a trading company, is understood already to have committed the cargo to a refinery buyer.</p>
<p>Traders have said Kirkuk exports in May are expected to rise slightly to around 445,000 barrels per day (bpd) from an original 430,000 bpd programme for April.</p>
<p>Full Iraqi exports under the oil sale, including sales of Basrah Light from Iraq's Gulf terminal at Mina al-Bakr, have been running at around 750,000 bpd in recent weeks.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 7646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
