<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="599142" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE-Jewish newspaper celebrates 100th birthday.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Jewish newspaper celebrates 100th birthday.</headline>
<byline>Jon Kalish</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The newspaper of America's Jewish immigrants did its job so well that it practically put itself out of business.</p>
<p>The Forward, which as one admirer put it taught Yiddish-speaking immigrants from Eastern Europe how to use a handkerchief and how to use a vote, celebrated its 100th birthday on Sunday.</p>
<p>But the future of the paper that exhorted &quot;Workers of the World Unite&quot; on its masthead is uncertain, and the main hope of keeping its proud tradition alive lies with an English edition run by a man who used to work at the Wall Street Journal.</p>
<p>&quot;There really is no more distinguished newspaper in this city and country than the Forward,&quot; said David Remnick, a writer with the New Yorker magazine. &quot;No paper has had a bigger heart, no paper has been more informative and literary and brave.&quot;</p>
<p>The Forverts, as it's known in Yiddish, was started in 1897 by a group of peddlers, tailors and cigar makers who gave a day's pay to start a paper to trumpet the socialist dream.</p>
<p>It debuted as a daily and reached its peak circulation of 275,000 in the 1930s. It claims to be the first American newspaper to have a national circulation but its readership and influence began to erode in the post-war period as more and more American Jews achieved the Forward's dream and assimilated.</p>
<p>PAPER'S WRITER WINS NOBEL</p>
<p>&quot;It's the only newspaper in history to have won the Nobel Prize beacuse Isaac Bashevis Singer got the Nobel for stories that were written for the Forward,&quot; said Seth Lipsky, a veteran of the Wall Street Journal editorial board and now the editor of the seven-year-old English Forward.</p>
<p>Besides Singer's writing, the Forward was famous for its Bintel Brief column, a letters-to-the-editor advice column. Poor Jewish women on the Lower East Side wrote the column asking for someone to adopt their children because they were going hungry.</p>
<p>But not all of the correspondence was doom and gloom. A letter in 1908 from a man who was reluctant to marry his girlfriend because she had a dimple asked if it was true that people who have a dimple on their chin lose their first spouse. The editors replied: &quot;The tragedy is not that the girl has a dimple on her chin but that some people have a screw loose in their heads.&quot;</p>
<p>The founding editor of the paper was Abraham Cahan, a Russian-born novelist and revolutionary who quit during the first year because he didn't want the Forward to be a mouthpiece for socialist ideology. Cahan came back four years later and ran the paper until he died 50 years later.</p>
<p>&quot;Very few English language dailies today have the personal stamp of the editor the way the Forverts did,&quot; said Zachary Baker, head librarian of the YIVO Institute for Jewish Research, where all 100 years of the Yiddish Forward are available on microfilm.</p>
<p>&quot;Abe Cahan was opinionated, cantankerous and prone to feuds. But at heart he was a strong believer in the American way and the Jewish people.&quot;</p>
<p>PAPER HAD DETRACTORS</p>
<p>Of course the Forward has its detractors. Intellectuals grumbled about it corrupting Yiddish with Americanisms. Religious Jews wouldn't touch it because it was secular. And Yiddish-speaking communists had their own daily, the Freiheit.</p>
<p>The Forward's influence in the first half of the 20th century was undeniable. In 1914 the paper helped make Meyer London the first socialist elected to Congress.</p>
<p>And over the years it broke a number of spectacular stories, including the introduction of slave labour in the Soviet Union. During the Second World War, the Forward played a role in mobilising the American public against the Nazis.</p>
<p>&quot;As much as any paper in the world, and more than most, the Forward broke the story of the Holocaust,&quot; Lipsky says proudly. Long before other papers, the paper printed stories about Jewish communities in Eastern Europe disappearing.</p>
<p>The English-language Forward has continued its tradition of publishing original literary works, serializing the Holocaust comic strip Maus and Phillip Roth's novel &quot;Operation Shylock.&quot;</p>
<p>And like the old Yiddish Forverts, it aggressively covers what it considers anti-semitism. The English edition has also been hawkish on foreign affairs. In 1991 it became the first U.S. paper to call for a declaration of war against Iraq.</p>
<p>To some critics, however, the paper has at times allowed its ideology to creep into its news pages. &quot;I think it's a first rate piece of work,&quot; says New York Times columnist A.M. Rosenthal, &quot;but I've been noticing that some of its news stories are heavily editorialised. It's not overwhelming at this point but I can smell those things in any paper.&quot;</p>
<p>After seven years of publication, the English Forward's circulation is about 24,000 and, according to one editor, the paper is losing $1 million a year. The Yiddish edition has a weekly readership of 10,000. Both papers are subsidised by the sale a few years ago of a radio station the paper owned.</p>
<p>Despite the yearly losses, Lipsky says he plans to eventually make it a daily. That may sound like a pipe dream, but at least one newspaper analyst believes Lipsky has a shot.</p>
<p>&quot;A lean and mean Jewish Forward can survive on circulation revenue alone if it can get up to a critical mass of somewhere between 50,000 and a 100,000 copies a day,&quot; said Porter Bibb of the Ladenburg, Thallman &amp; Co, an investment banking firm.</p>
<p>&quot;An awful lot of Jews in New York would buy a daily Jewish Forward because it could provide a sense of identity for the hundreds of thousands of affluent Jews in New York who have lost a connection with their faith.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
