<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="599140" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tennis star Chang urged to shun tobacco sponsorship.</title>
<headline>Tennis star Chang urged to shun tobacco sponsorship.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anti-tobacco advocates and Asian American groups appealed on Monday to tennis star Michael Chang to stop participating in the Salem Open and other tournaments sponsored by cigarette companies.</p>
<p>The group said that by playing in the tournaments and appearing in advertisements for them, Chang was helping tobacco companies sell cigarettes to youths in Asia.</p>
<p>While Chang is not the only American tennis player to participate in such tournaments, as an Asian-American he is particularly influential to teenagers in Asia, the group said.</p>
<p>&quot;Asian youth, especially girls, are a major target of U.S. tobacco companies and these companies are using Michael's popularity as a role model to legitimize their deadly product,&quot; said Rod Lew, a spokesman for the American Lung Association of Alameda County.</p>
<p>That branch of the American Lung Association, along with the Chinese Progressive Association, the Vietnamese Community Health Promotion Project and the Asian Pacific Islander Tobacco Education Network, kicked off a letter-writing campaign to Chang on Monday.</p>
<p>Chang, ranked a career-high second in the world, won the French Open at the age of 17 in 1989, becoming the youngest player to ever win that tournament. Last month, he also won the Salem Open in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Chang was not immediately available to comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
