<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="599194" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Saltwater sites the sweeter for EU bathers.</title>
<headline>Saltwater sites the sweeter for EU bathers.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Chalmers</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union bathers should head for the sea rather than fresh water this summer according to data released on Tuesday in the European Commission's 1996 bathing water report.</p>
<p>In the 13 EU countries posting quality standards both for the sea beaches and inland freshwater sites, all recorded better results for their saltwater bathing areas, the figures showed.</p>
<p>Greece topped the list of 13 EU countries for the quality of water at coastal bathing areas, with more than 19 out of 20 sites meeting all the recommended parameters.</p>
<p>Chillier perhaps but nearly as clean was Denmark, where more than nine in 10 of the saltwater bathing areas came up to scratch, followed by Ireland, Italy, Spain, the Netherlands and Finland.</p>
<p>Belgium came bottom in terms of meeting the recommended standards with only 15.4 percent making the grade, although it met minimum requirements at 97.4 percent of designated sites.</p>
<p>Other laggards included Britain, where fewer than half the sea bathing areas met recommended standards, France, where two thirds did and Germany, with just over 70 percent meeting the recommended figures.</p>
<p>Looking from the other angle, namely failure to meet even the minimum standards, Germany was worst with a 13.5 percent rate followed by Portugal, Britain, the Netherlands, Italy and France.</p>
<p>On fresh water standards, European Environment Commissioner Ritt Bjerregaard hit out at Germany, France, Spain, Portugal and the Netherlands, all with fewer than half their designated sites meeting recommended standards, and urged them to make greater efforts to clean up.</p>
<p>Britain avoided any potentially unhelpful observations on the quality of its freshwater bathing areas by refusing to designate any sites under the 1976 rules.</p>
<p>New EU entrant Austria has until next year to begin supplying data on its freshwater bathing sites while Sweden and Finland, the other newcomers of 1995, have yet to come up to speed with all the data monitoring requirements.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G156">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
