<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="599378" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INTERVIEW - Royal Sun buyback has green light.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Royal Sun buyback has green light.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>British composite insurer Royal &amp; Sun Alliance Group Plc said on Tuesday it remained on course to realise the 175 million pound ($287.7 million) of cost savings identified at the time of the merger last year.</p>
<p>The comments came as the company posted a 24 percent rise in first quarter pre-tax operating profits to 195 million pounds.</p>
<p>With the results now out of the way, chief executive Richard Gamble told Reuters that the buyback of five percent of the share capital approved at the annual meeting would go ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;We're now in a position that brokers can start to  move into market to do the buyback. The signal has gone to green. How long it will take is just a matter of timing and it's something we're discussing closely with our brokers,&quot; said Gamble.  </p>
<p>The future outlook was for more of the same, he said, with the focus on integration, driving down unit costs and getting profits out of the business.</p>
<p>Following last year's six billion pound merger of Royal Insurance with Sun Alliance Insurance, the reduction in staff numbers is likely to accelerate in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;By the end of March some 1,500 people had left the company, of which 200 were managers. The annualised savings attibuted to those people plus properties vacated are 44 million pounds, which is right on target,&quot; said Gamble.</p>
<p>Profits for the first three months of the year rose to 195 million pounds, up from 157 million pounds in 1996.</p>
<p>Royal Sun said the figures represented an encouraging start to the year with a strong performance in North America, a broadly unchanged result in the UK and a rise in life profits.</p>
<p>The merger had not affected the group's ability to pick up new business nor retention levels which, he said, were holding up to expected levels.</p>
<p>&quot;We've actually found that the merger has been welcomed worldwide and we're picking up new bsuiness as a result,&quot; said Gamble.</p>
<p>The company was seeing some realism coming into the rating environment with stability becoming evident and a four percent increase in motor market rates last autumn sticking.</p>
<p>Over the first quarter, a 34 million pound fall in weather-related costs contributed to a rise in U.S. general business profits to 51 million pounds.</p>
<p>In contrast, a 10 million pound rise in UK subsidence costs more than accounted for the five million pound drop in UK general business profits to 50 million pounds.</p>
<p>&quot;Subsidence is a worry. The good news is the recent rain but it has been one of driest winters on record following on from other dry periods,&quot; said Gamble.</p>
<p>&quot;We do anticipate subsidence is going to be with us for some time to come but that is being built into the cost of household insurance.&quot;</p>
<p>A rise in European fire losses contributed to a fall in profits in the international business to 22 million pounds from 37 million pounds.</p>
<p>Royal Sun is to continue to keep an eye on opportunities for small, bolt-on acquisitions such as the recent purchase of Prudential's Italian life assurance and pensions business, but is not actively pursuing larger acquisitions.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not aggressively in the market. Money is not burning a hole in our pocket - that's the indication given by the share buyback. We're, realistically managing our capital base,&quot; said Gamble.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
