<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="599398" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Brown announces audit of UK Treasury forecasts.</title>
<headline>Brown announces audit of UK Treasury forecasts.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chancellor of the Exchequer Gordon Brown announced on Tuesday an independent audit of the Treasury's forecasts.</p>
<p>&quot;There must be honest finances as well as sound finances,&quot; Brown said on BBC radio 4.</p>
<p>The National audit office would look at the assumptions behind the official forecasts, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think people right across the country will welcome the fact that the books are being opened to an independent body which will look at these matters and report on them,&quot; Brown said.</p>
<p>Asked if he had an utter commitment to transparent Treasury forecasts, Brown replied &quot;of course.&quot;</p>
<p>He also pledged to publish a Green Paper six months before every budget &quot;so that people have a chance to have a real debate about the budget.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be openness as well as soundness in the public finances,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Brown said he was determined that decisions would be taken for the long term. &quot;People are fed up with the stop/go, with the boom/bust. They want a long-term footing for both the National finances and the National economic policy.</p>
<p>He said that Britian was 21st on the OECD's league table and that this was not good enough. &quot;We have got to do better,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Brown also said that he would not renege on his manifesto commitments, in the budget expected within a few weeks. &quot;We have only made promises that we can keep and the promises we have made we will keep and I am determined on that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Cheryl Juckes +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
