<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="599435" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</title>
<headline>Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>HANSON ABSENT AS PARTY LAUNCHED IN VICTORIA</p>
<p>A Victorian branch of Pauline Hanson's One Nation Party has been officially launched in Geelong amid protests, and a rival meeting to condemn racism.</p>
<p>About 30 protesters jeered and abused people going into the One Nation meeting, even though Miss Hanson was not present.</p>
<p>Convenor, Andrew Carne, says the party will now seek support in western Victoria, with meetings planned in the Wimmera and at Bendigo.</p>
<p>On the other side of Geelong, about one thousand people attended a meeting where supporters of multiculturalism claimed most Geelong residents oppose Miss Hanson.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SYDNEY OLYMPICS FACES PROBLEMS WITH ACCOMMODATION</p>
<p>The New South Wales Opposition says the imposition of the bed tax has produced the first major problem in the 2000 Games preparations.</p>
<p>The Motel, Hotel and Accommodation Association has called on its members to delay signing contracts which guarantee the supply of accommodation during the Olympics.</p>
<p>The contracts between operators and SOCOG are designed to ensure supply of rooms at acceptable rates.</p>
<p>Opposition leader Peter Collins says delays in signing contracts could affect both the availability and price of accommodation during the Sydney games.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BORBIDGE WARNS GST NOT POPULAR</p>
<p>The Queensland Premier says he hopes the Coalition has learnt that a Goods and Services tax is not a popular electoral option.</p>
<p>Rob Borbidge has warned the Federal Government against introducing a Goods and Services Tax as part of any tax reform package.</p>
<p>Mr Borbidge says the last time the Coalition considered a GST, business loved it but the general community didn't.</p>
<p>He says it's not clear if John Howard is moving towards a GST in his comments on tax reform, but he should look at reviewing federal/state taxation arrangements.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TERRITORY TO SUPPORT DOUBLE DISSOLUTION</p>
<p>The Acting Northern Territory Chief Minister says he believes a double dissolution federal election, triggered by amendments to the Native Title Act, is possible.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard has failed to rule-out a double dissolution, if the Senate doesn't pass his ten-point Wik plan.</p>
<p>Acting Chief Minister Mike Reed says it's of fundamental importance that security of land tenure is passed in the Senate. And he says if the Senate is obstructonist to Mr Howard's native title plan, it's appropriate for the Prime Minister to go to the people.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>APPLE AND PEAR GROWERS EXAMINING POSSIBLE ACTION</p>
<p>Victoria's Apple and Pear Growers are investigating action they may take, if a fireblight disease is not confirmed in the State.</p>
<p>They warn some companies may sue New Zealand for loss of income, after all States banned Victorian produce when tests revealed the disease in two trees at Melbourne's Botanic Gardens.</p>
<p>New Zealand has apologised to Australia for the behaviour of a plant scientist who says he discovered fireblight in samples he took from Melbourne recently.</p>
<p>Doctor Chris Hale took cuttings from two trees back to New Zealand for tests, which confirmed they were infected with the disease.</p>
<p>Australia's Primary Industries Minister, John Anderson, says the New Zealand Government has apologised for the actions, and assured it will never happen again.</p>
<p>Mr Anderson says while there's no evidence of sabotage, Australia will seek independent tests in Europe or the U-S, because of discrepancies between New Zealand's tests and those done in Australia.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MINISTERS TO REPORT TO CABINET AFTER NEWCASTLE MEETING</p>
<p>Federal Cabinet will today consider proposals put forward at a meeting in Newcastle, aimed at helping the city following the announcement that BHP is to close its steelworks there.</p>
<p>Cabinet will be briefed on a meeting which took place between three Ministers and local business and civic leaders.</p>
<p>Industry Minister John Moore says he agrees with many of the proposals, including the need to develop sustainable manufacturing industries, and boost training opportunities for BHP workers able to move into other industries such as tourism. Mr Moore says Mr Sharp was also impressed with the optimism with which Newcastle is facing the decision.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
