<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="599601" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo aluminium futures plunge, eyes on FOMC.</title>
<headline>Tokyo aluminium futures plunge, eyes on FOMC.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo yen-based aluminium futures finished mostly at their limit-lows on Tuesday, hit by stop-loss selling triggered by the dollar's renewed decline, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Now, we're watching the FOMC meeting, which should determine the dollar's further direction,&quot; said one trader, referring to the U.S. Federal Reserve's Open Market Committee later today.</p>
<p>Benchmark April 1998 shed six yen to 190.4 yen per kg, the contract's low since it was launched on April 25. Other contracts also finished at their limit-lows, except for the February contract that pared its loss to 5.9 yen by the close.</p>
<p>The dollar sank on Tuesday to below 113 yen in Asian trade from above 115 yen early in the morning.</p>
<p>Traders said the metal's weakness on the LME during the Asian trade also depressed the yen-based futures. Three months aluminium was quoted at $1,648/1,652 at 0655 GMT, down from $1,653 at the kerb close in London.</p>
<p>One LME trader said: &quot;We've seen quite a lot of Japanese buying because of the yen's strength. But players are testing the strength of the support at $1,650.&quot;</p>
<p>Estimated volume was 4,169 lots, bloated by arbitrage trade by trading houses between the LME and TOCOM. It stood at 2,216 lots on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Commodities Desk +81-3-3432-7431</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
