<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="599963" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: British soldiers may face cane on robbery charges.</title>
<headline>British soldiers may face cane on robbery charges.</headline>
<byline>Chris Johnson</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two British soldiers facing at least 12 strokes of the cane and three years in a Singapore jail for stealing Singapore $43 (US$30) were remanded in custody for two months on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Richard George Britten, 22, and John Thomson King, 20, are charged with robbing taxi driver Tong Chim Huat, 53, in the early hours of May 3. Neither prosecution nor defence gave details of the alleged robbery.</p>
<p>Judge Tan Siong Thye set bail at S$10,000 each but neither man was able to come up with the money.</p>
<p>Defence lawyer Shashi Nathan told reporters after the hearing the men were trying to raise the money. If they did, there would be another court hearing and they could be released on bail later this week.</p>
<p>Britten, a Royal Marine from Plymouth in southern England, and King, a Royal Engineer from Aberdeenshire, Scotland, intend to plead not guilty, he said.</p>
<p>They were in Singapore serving on board the British naval support ship Sir Galahad which was taking part in exercises when the alleged robbery took place.</p>
<p>Nathan said the charge of robbery at night was serious and he expected the court to deal with the men as if they were Singaporean defendants.</p>
<p>&quot;The offence is quite serious. It is one of robbery which carries quite a severe punishment. They are looking at a minimum of three years imprisonment and a minimum of 12 strokes of the cane. On the present charge caning is mandatory,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But we are making attempts to get the charge reduced or perhaps get the charges thrown out,&quot; he said. &quot;We want to take instructions from our clients and we also want to make certain representations to the Attorney General chambers.&quot;</p>
<p>He declined to comment on British media reports that Singapore authorities had agreed to release the two men into the custody of the Royal Navy for a military court hearing.</p>
<p>Singapore has a strict legal system which imposes tough punishments on a range of offences.</p>
<p>Three years ago it faced controversy over the caning of American teenager Michael Fay, who was flogged for vandalism.</p>
<p>His sentence was reduced to four lashes from six after a personal appeal by U.S. President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>Singapore-style canings are carried out with a rattan cane, a bamboo-like stick that splits the skin and leaves permanent scars, sources familiar with the process said. A doctor is in attendance and checks the person between each strike.</p>
<p>Nathan said the two British soldiers were holding up well in prison but were obviously worried about the threat of the cane.</p>
<p>($1 = S$1.43)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
