<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="600146" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore property shares kick up, trade data eyed.</title>
<headline>Singapore property shares kick up, trade data eyed.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore property stocks kicked up in early trade on Tuesday following changes to public housing sector policies.</p>
<p>&quot;The impact on property stocks is positive as it would encourage upgraders to opt for private property,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>Among the new rules announced by the Housing Development Board (HDB) on Sunday were a 10-year waiting period for a second HDB flat instead of five and a hike in resale levies.</p>
<p>But dealers said it was too early to tell what the combined impact of various measures, introduced by the government over the past year to curb speculation, would be.</p>
<p>The property index rose 5.39 points to 683.06 at 0216 GMT with City Development and DBS Land up Singapore $0.10 each.</p>
<p>Dealers said the rest of the market was quiet as investors awaited the release of Singapore's April non-oil domestic export data at noon.</p>
<p>The Straits Times Industrials Index inched up 5.14 points to 2,056.08.</p>
<p>Expectations of whether the U.S. Federal Reserve would hike rates later in the day were mixed. Various block trades were seen in Singapore Telecom, Fraser &amp; Neave and Natsteel. --Josephine Ng (65-8703094)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
