<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="600348" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Frankfurt bourse seen remaining under pressure.</title>
<headline>Frankfurt bourse seen remaining under pressure.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares were expected to remain under pressure on Tuesday as Friday's decline on Wall Street continued to undermine support and traders took defensive positions ahead of the Federal Reserve meeting today.</p>
<p>The IBIS DAX, which reflects all-day computer trade in the DAX index, was down 29.08 points at 3.540.18. The DAX ended floor trade on Friday at 3,569.26.</p>
<p>But traders said the market was unlikely to make any major move ahead of the decision on U.S. interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;Due to conflicting U.S. economic data, it is completely open as to if U.S. rates will be increased,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>The weaker dollar is also likely to weigh on prices after falling two pfennigs to 1.6865/70, hurting chemical companies in particular.</p>
<p>Hoechst AG was down 2.52 percent to 65.65 marks while Bayer AG was down 1.76 percent to 64.15 marks.</p>
<p>Shares in BASF AG, meanwhile, fell more than four percent to a day's low of 62.10 marks at the start of pre-bourse trade on Tuesday after news that it faces an $8.5 billion lawsuit in the U.S.. The shares later recovered to 63.75 marks, a decline of 3.04 percent.  </p>
<p>Shares in Deutsche Telekom AG, meanwhile, came under pressure amid profit taking as a tax break on trading the shares took effect.</p>
<p>Shortly after the open, Telekom shares were down 1.78 percent to 38.06, significantly lower than the overall market which suffered a modest decline. They later rebounded to 38.49 and traders did not expect selling to continue.</p>
<p>Under German law, investors can sell shares in a company without having to pay a capital gains if they hold the shares for six months.  </p>
<p>Shares in Deutsche Bank AG, meanwhile, were barely changed at 96.90 marks after the bank said first quarter profit climbed 28 percent to 1.4 billion marks and that the results confirmed its forecast of higher profit for the year as a whole.</p>
<p>-- Frankfurt Newsroom + 49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
