<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="600310" id="root" date="1997-05-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - May 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - May 20.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Greek Cypriot press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>ALITHIA</p>
<p>- Bicommunal peace concert sends message of hope that the youth of Cyprus want to live in a United Cyprus...but irresponsible elements give a different picture.</p>
<p>- Madeleine Albright and British Foreign Secretary Robin Cook discussed the Cyprus issue in Washington yesterday.</p>
<p>CYPRUS MAIL</p>
<p>- Anti-concert protest erupts into violence. Pop stars Sakis Rouvas and Burak Kut send a message for peace in Cyprus.</p>
<p>HARAVGHI</p>
<p>- Britain is expected to take on a regulatory role during the upcoming meeting between President Clerides and Turkish Cypriot leader Rauf Denktash.</p>
<p>- 4,000 people attend the concert of peace. Regrettable incidents are caused by nationalists.</p>
<p>PHILELEPHTHEROS</p>
<p>- All night clashes in the streets of Nicosia. Dozens of people are rounded up and arrested, while scores are injured.</p>
<p>SIMERINI</p>
<p>- The results of the peculiar rapprochement concert of partition: the fury of Greeks and the divergence in views of the political leadership.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
