<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60049" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Sonae sees lower extraordinaries in 1996.</title>
<headline>Sonae sees lower extraordinaries in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>OPORTO, Portugal 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Retail to wood products group Sonae Investimentos sees extraordinary earnings of 5.6 billion escudos ($36.2 million) in 1996, down from 8.3 billion the previous year.</p>
<p>The company said on Monday it expected full-year profit to rise to 13.9 billion escudos this year from 12.9 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>The extraordinaries would be generated by the sale of real estate interests, the group said.</p>
<p>Sonae Imobiliaria, its real estate arm, is negotiating the sale of 50 percent of its holding in shopping centre Cascaishoping in a deal that would earn the group some 1.8 billion escudos in book profit, Sonae Investimentos executive board member Edgar Pinto Ribeiro told journalists.</p>
<p>The stake is being bought by  Pricoa, a European subsidiary of the U.S.  Prudential Insurance. Pricoa would also be taking a stake in Gaiashopping, another shopping centre owned by Sonae.</p>
<p>The group said that it expects Sonae Imobiliaria to boost profit in 1996 by 400 percent to 2.7 billion escudos.</p>
<p>Overall sales were seen rising 185 percent to 15.7 billion, due to the property sales. Turnover rose 65 percent to 3.8 billion over the first six months.</p>
<p>($1=154.53 escudos)</p>
<p>--Jose Barata, Lisboa bureau 3511-3113121</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OPORTO, Portugal"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
