<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="600601" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Courtaulds hit by strong pound, viscose.</title>
<headline>Courtaulds hit by strong pound, viscose.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>British chemicals group Courtaulds Plc said on Wednesday it expected to make further advances this year despite the strong pound and weak viscose markets.</p>
<p>The two factors were the main feature of results for the year to March, when pre-tax profits rose modestly to 134 million stg from 131 million, towards the higher end of analysts' expectations.  </p>
<p>Courtaulds said its best-selling new fibre Tencel had moved &quot;firmly into profit reflecting a strong sales advance,&quot; while operating profits across all its continuing businesses were up 11 percent at 166 million pound ($274.7 million).</p>
<p>The group, which is Europe's biggest producer of viscose, said demand for the fibre was still weak. The viscose market has been hit by overcapacity.</p>
<p>Sales in the fibres operation fell 3 percent to 874 million stg, but Tencel helped to boost profits, which rose 14 percent to 65 million stg. Operating profits at coatings and sealants, where Courtaulds supplies the aerospace and shipping industries, advanced by 13 percent to 81 million stg.</p>
<p>At polymer products, which are directed at packaging for consumer goods and toiletries, operating profits rose 22 percent 22 million stg despite only a modest rise in sales.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717 ($ = 0.604 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
