<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="600726" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli shares end higher.</title>
<headline>Israeli shares end higher.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli shares closed slightly higher on Wednesday with a positive mood in the market, traders said.</p>
<p>The benchmark Mishtanim index of the top 100 shares rose 0.53 percent, or 1.41 points, to 266.75 on an all-share turnover of 130 million shekels against 135 million shekels on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Maof 25 blue chip index closed 0.48 percent higher at 274.85.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is very positive and it is rising at a very moderate pace which is a good sign. The market continues to rise despite the fact that foreign investors are waiting to see what will happen with the peace process,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;The positive trend is very clear. Share prices are still attractive, volume is rising and the market does not react to negative political developments. This is a market that wants to rise,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Middle East peace process has been at a virtual standstill ever since relations between Israel, the Palestinians and the Arab world plunged into a deep crisis in March when work began on a Jewish settlement in East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>A trader at United Mizrahi Bank said the recovery of the primary market was another positive factor adding to investor optimism.</p>
<p>&quot;Option prices also reflect expectations for a continued rise on Thursday,&quot; the Mizrahi trader said.</p>
<p>Industrial Building surged 4.25 percent to 518 agorot and traders said the share rose in anticipation of the company share-offering next week.</p>
<p>Supersol rose 3.0 percent to 1,066 agorot. Lehman Brothers said in a report released on Wednesday that it was lowering its 1997 and 1998 earnings forecasts for Supersol but maintaining its 2 Outperform rating for the food retailer.</p>
<p>Tadiran gained 1.75 percent to 9,111 agorot. The company said on Wednesday that earnings per share fell in the first quarter of 1997 to $0.79 from $0.95 a year earlier.</p>
<p>Matav-Cable Systems Media rose 2.0 percent to 2,653 agorot. Matav said on Wednesday that net income per share rose in the first quarter to $0.63 from $0.40 in the same quarter last year.</p>
<p>The most active shares were Israel Discount Bank, which gained 0.5 percent to 361 agorot on volume of 6.7 million shekels; Bank Leumi, which gained 0.25 percent to 531 agorot on turnover of 5.4 million shekels; and Teva Pharmaceutical Industries, which lost 1.75 percent to 20,138 agorot on turnover of 4.9 million shekels.</p>
<p>- Dan Gerstenfeld, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
