<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="600872" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Staples argues Wal-Mart may compete against it.</title>
<headline>Staples argues Wal-Mart may compete against it.</headline>
<byline>David Lawsky</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Staples Inc. and Office Depot Inc., responding to government charges their proposed $4 billion merger would give them power to raise prices, tried to prove in court Wednesday a merged firm could face tough competition.</p>
<p>The two office supply superstores opened their defense case after two days of testimony by witnesses for the Federal Trade Commission.</p>
<p>U.S. Court District Judge Thomas Hogan, who is conducting the five-day hearing, has said he will decide by mid-June whether to grant the FTC request for a preliminary injunction to stop the merger.</p>
<p>Lawyers for the two office superstores focused on the possibility of competition from Wal-Mart Stores Inc., the No. 1 U.S. retailer.</p>
<p>The president of Wal-Mart said in videotaped testimony played before the court that his chain was expanding its offerings of office supplies.</p>
<p>&quot;We have expanded office supplies year by year for the past several years,&quot; said David Glass, president and chief executive officer of Wal-Mart. Asked if the office superstores were competition, Glass replied:</p>
<p>&quot;Anyone who sells anything that we do is a competitor.&quot;</p>
<p>Lawyers for Staples and Office Depot offered testimony that Wal-Mart now carries upwards of 2,500 different kinds of office and home stationery items, with hundreds more scheduled to be added. By contrast, office superstores carry about 6,000 to 6,500 different kinds of items.</p>
<p>An official of Office Depot said during a break that the same 2,500 items Wal-Mart chooses to sell are those that account for about 80 percent or more of the dollar volume for Office Depot and Staples.</p>
<p>A retailing expert called by the defense testified that he believed Wal-Mart could pose a threat to office superstores.</p>
<p>Stephen Mandel, a senior managing director of the investment firm of Tiger Management in New York, testified that in 1991 or 1992 the chain Toys &quot;R&quot; Us permitted its prices to drift upward, taking the attitude that &quot;we have all the toys and no one else does.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This provided an opening for Wal-Mart to go aggressively after the toy business,&quot; he said. Mandel said as a result, Wal-Mart has become the second largest toy retailer in the United States after Toys &quot;R&quot; Us.</p>
<p>Mandel said if office superstores permitted their prices to go up -- as the FTC has alleged will happen if the two merge -- then Wal-Mart would be poised to take away its business.</p>
<p>During cross-examination by an FTC lawyer, Mandel acknowledged that Staples had in fact permitted its prices to drift up in the early 1990s in Boston.</p>
<p>It was only when it learned that a competing office superstore, OfficeMax, was going to open up a store in Boston that its prices were reduced, Mandel testified.</p>
<p>The FTC contends that only competing office superstores have the ability to constrain price increases by other office superstores.</p>
<p>The government says that a combined chain of Staples and Office Depot would have the ability to raise prices with impunity in areas of the country where they did not face competition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6540030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
