<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="600852" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - TOBACCO DEBATE RAISES QUESTIONS FOR FORMULA ONE.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - TOBACCO DEBATE RAISES QUESTIONS FOR FORMULA ONE.</headline>
<byline>Helen Jones</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Formula One, the world's most</p>
<p>glamorous and expensive motor racing event, is looking for new</p>
<p>sponsors as a growing number of countries introduce restrictions</p>
<p>on tobacco sponsorship.</p>
<p>Tobacco companies represent the biggest group and the most</p>
<p>important chunk of revenue among all sponsors that spend money</p>
<p>on big motor racing events.    Formula One -- where teams</p>
<p>compete in 16 Grand Prix races in 16 countries every year --</p>
<p>receives an estimated 100 million pounds ($163.8 million) in</p>
<p>sponsorship money from tobacco companies, experts say.</p>
<p>But as countries such as Britain, France, Germany and Canada</p>
<p>introduce total or partial bans on tobacco advertising and the</p>
<p>use of tobacco company logos in TV broadcasts, motor racing</p>
<p>teams are looking for alternative sponsors.</p>
<p>These might include soft-drink and high-tech companies.</p>
<p>On Monday Britain's new Labour government announced it was</p>
<p>banning sponsorship of sporting events by tobacco companies.</p>
<p>That dealt a blow not only to Formula One but other sports</p>
<p>that flourish from tobacco sponsorship -- cricket, golf, darts,</p>
<p>rugby</p>
<p>league and horse show-jumping.</p>
<p>Experts told Reuters that in Britain tobacco companies began</p>
<p>pouring money into sponsoring car racing and other sports after</p>
<p>tobacco advertising on television was banned in the 1960s. </p>
<p>&quot;Tobacco sponsorship is very important to Formula One. As</p>
<p>tobacco companies cannot advertise on TV they have put their</p>
<p>advertising budgets into sponsorship,&quot; said John Fitzpatrick,</p>
<p>secretary general of the British Racing Driver's Club.</p>
<p>SPONSORSHIP ESSENTIAL FOR FORMULA ONE</p>
<p>Without sponsorship of some kind, Formula One would not</p>
<p>exist.</p>
<p>The sport was once the preserve of wealthy amateurs but</p>
<p>industry observers estimate it now costs between 30 million and</p>
<p>50 million pounds for a team to make a serious bid to win the</p>
<p>Formula One world championship.</p>
<p>Although most teams have a number of sponsors, tobacco</p>
<p>companies are among the most visible and their logos appear on</p>
<p>the racing cars, drivers' clothing and advertising hoardings</p>
<p>around the track.</p>
<p>The Renault-Williams team which was victorious last season</p>
<p>with Damon Hill behind the wheel is sponsored by Rothmans, the</p>
<p>Benetton team is sponsored by Japanese cigarette brand Mild</p>
<p>Seven and the Jordan team has the support of Benson &amp; Hedges.</p>
<p>Experts say Formula One has a few options in the face of</p>
<p>growing restrictions on tobacco sponsorship -- secure other</p>
<p>sponsors, move the event to countries that don't restrict</p>
<p>tobacco promotion and find ways to live with existing curbs.</p>
<p>Steve Herrick, managing director of CSS Internetional, a sports</p>
<p>marketing agency, cites the search for new, non-tobacco</p>
<p>sponsorship money.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Formula One organisers) are not daft and I'm sure</p>
<p>they are looking at other potential sponsors as restrictions are</p>
<p>introduced,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>To comply with existing regulations on tobacco promotion,</p>
<p>Formula One teams have to be careful not to display tobacco</p>
<p>logos when racing in certain countries.</p>
<p>At the British and German Grand Prix, tobacco logos must be</p>
<p>adapted for television coverage to meet local tobacco</p>
<p>advertising guidelines. Brand names must be dropped although</p>
<p>corporate colours are allowed.</p>
<p>So Rothman's, for example, replaces its name with the word</p>
<p>&quot;racing&quot; in the same colours and logotype.</p>
<p>But at other venues such as the Argentine Grand Prix, no</p>
<p>such</p>
<p>restrictions exist. So television viewers in Britain or Germany</p>
<p>watching the Argentine race see the cigarette brand names that</p>
<p>cannot be displayed at home events.</p>
<p>Some experts say Formula One could simply move to countries</p>
<p>with no bans on tobacco promotion if things get too tough in</p>
<p>main event locations.</p>
<p>Herrick says that if strict legislation is introduced in Europe</p>
<p>then Formula One organisers may move the event to Asia and South</p>
<p>America where there are fewer restrictions on tobacco</p>
<p>sponsorship.</p>
<p>&quot;Twenty years ago it was a European event. Now there is a</p>
<p>Japanese Grand Prix, and (South) Korea, Malaysia and the</p>
<p>Philippines may follow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Darren Marshall, general manager for ISL US, a part of</p>
<p>Switzerland-based ISL, a sports marketing group, says that is an</p>
<p>unlikely scenario because &quot;the flagship races such as the</p>
<p>British and Monaco Grand Prix are in Europe&quot;.</p>
<p>TOBACCO FIRMS WILL CONTINUE INVOLVEMENT IN SPORT</p>
<p>Industry observers say that despite the introduction of tougher</p>
<p>rules regarding tobacco sponsorship, tobacco companies will</p>
<p>continue to be involved in the sport.</p>
<p>&quot;Canada issued a death sentence on tobacco sponsorship, but</p>
<p>granted special concessions to the Montreal Grand Prix because</p>
<p>it is huge event and is vital to the local economy,&quot; Marshall</p>
<p>told Reuters.</p>
<p>He says he does not expect tobacco sponsorship to disappear</p>
<p>as the whole structure of Formula One racing would change if it</p>
<p>did.</p>
<p>&quot;It (car racing) is so expensive and so instead of each team</p>
<p>spending millions of dollars building their own cars they would</p>
<p>follow the example set by Indy car racing (which is big in the</p>
<p>U.S.) and all the competing teams would use one manufacturer to</p>
<p>build the chassis and a couple of others to build the engines to</p>
<p>keep the costs down.&quot;</p>
<p>As for finding non-tobacco sponsors, experts told Reuters</p>
<p>they did not expect Formula One to have a hard time since the</p>
<p>sport attracts a huge global TV audience of up to 800 million</p>
<p>people.</p>
<p>If tobacco sponsorship did eventually dry up, those close to</p>
<p>the event said Formula One would survive because lots of big</p>
<p>brand-name</p>
<p>companies would be eager to sponsor Grand Prix events.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be a temporary glitch because other international</p>
<p>brands would step in,&quot; said John Fitzpatrick of the British</p>
<p>Racing Drivers' Club.</p>
<p>($ = 0.610 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
