<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60109" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN chief seeks woman for Afghan mission.</title>
<headline>UN chief seeks woman for Afghan mission.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Nations Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali on Monday took steps to appoint a woman to the U.N. mission in Afghanistan, despite known objections from both the government and Islamic rebels.</p>
<p>U.N. spokeswoman Sylvana Foa said he had asked Assistant Secretary-General Rosario Green, a Mexican diplomat who is in charge of monitoring women's participation in U.N. activities, to look for women political officers who could serve there.</p>
<p>The United Nations has a small group of political and military officers in addition to aid agencies in Afghanistan. Two political officer positions are currently vacant, Foa said.</p>
<p>Green on Monday met a group of Afghan women, headed by Rukhsana Sarwar, a professor who fled her country for Pakistan two years ago after her Kabul neighbourhood was in ruins and run by Islamic militants.</p>
<p>Sarwar, who works in Pakistan for Save the Children U.S.A., is part of the Afghan's Women's Network, a group that organised at the U.N. women's conference in Beijing a year ago after the Kabul government refused to send a delegation.</p>
<p>Without the involvement of women, now the majority of the adult population, there would never be peace, she told the New York Times last week. Sarwar said she wanted the United Nations to name a woman to its missions working for peace and reconstruction.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.N. Charter as you know forbids discrimination on the issue of gender,&quot; Foa said, adding that this was one issue Marrack Goulding, the undersecretary-general for political affairs, brought up on his current mission to the region. Goudling has been visiting Afghan leaders in a bid to hammer out a peace formula.</p>
<p>&quot;That is a big issue, such as the education of women, the employment of women and particularly the employment of women, by U.N. agencies,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The Taleban, a militant Sunni Moslem movement started by Afghan students at religious schools in Pakistan two years ago, captured the main eastern city of Jalalabad last Wednesday, a centre for United Nations operation.</p>
<p>Both the Taliban and the coalition Afghan government has told the United Nations not to send any women officials.</p>
<p>Islamic guerrillas have been battling each other since the Soviet Army pulled out in 1989 and they took over the capital, Kabul, a few years later.</p>
<p>UNICEF, the U.N. Childrens Fund, after strong protests from women's groups, last year withdrew support from educational programmes in the Herat region taken by some of Taliban's stricter followers.</p>
<p>U.N. officials said women were not allowed to work there except in health professions and girls were not allowed to go to school. They said the withdrawal of funds from schools hit Afghans particularly hard as they felt they had lost an entire generation during the war.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
