<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60124" id="root" date="1996-09-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish brewer Brok says Holsten to up stake.</title>
<headline>Polish brewer Brok says Holsten to up stake.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish brewer Brok said on Tuesday Germany's Holsten brewer planned to raise to a majority the stake it held in the group, and it would enter the Warsaw bourse in 1997's first half after a public offering.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll be on the bourse's (now vacant) third market because for the time being we don't fulfil the qualifications to be on the main or parallel floors,&quot; spokeswoman Agnieska Pluszcz told Reuters.</p>
<p>Shareholders will vote on September 23  on whether  Zaklady Piwowarskie Brok SA -- will conduct a one-to-five share split and issue 575,000 new shares to AHK Beteiligungsgesellschaft.</p>
<p>AHK is jointly owned by Holsten and another German investor, AMS of Hamburg.</p>
<p>Brok, which currently has 230,000 shares, would then issue another 287,500 shares in a public offering likely in the second quarter of 1997, after which AHK's stake would rise to 51 percent from the current 40 percent.</p>
<p>Management would hold 33 percent, individual investors 17 percent,  Bank Pekao SA nine percent and the state treasury one percent.</p>
<p>Funds from the AHK share issue would go toward modernising one of Brok's three breweries in northwestern Poland, with funds from the second issue buying a new brewing plant at the company's headquarters in Koszalin.</p>
<p>Brok plans to invest 90 million zlotys over the next three years, more than doubling production from the current 550,000 hectolitres annually.</p>
<p>The brewer now has a three-percent market share.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
