<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="601396" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Kabila jets in to Kinshasa after dark to lead Zaire.</title>
<headline>Kabila jets in to Kinshasa after dark to lead Zaire.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Kotch</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-05-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Laurent Kabila flew in to Kinshasa on Tuesday evening to take control of Africa's third largest country after his rebel army drove Zaire's President Mobutu Sese Seko from power and he declared himself head of state of the renamed Democratic Republic of Congo.</p>
<p>Kabila arrived at Kinshasa's Ndjili international airport in darkness, touching down at about 6.50 p.m. (1750 GMT) from the southern city of Lubumubashi.</p>
<p>He crossed the vast country he now controls from east to west aboard a Canadair Challenger jet, a flight of some two hours.</p>
<p>Kabila was met by officials of his Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo (AFDL) who flew in earlier from Lubumbashi, the provisional rebel capital near the border with Zambia.</p>
<p>Wearing a charcoal grey safari suit of the cut he has made his trademark since he emerged from obscurity to lead the seven-month whirlwind revolution, Kabila was awaited by television cameras, reporters and photographers.</p>
<p>He made no statement but quickly climbed into a Landrover with smoked glass windows and shot off for the capital city, with pickup trucks full of soldiers and cars full of dignitaries in tow in a motorcade of some 20 vehicles.</p>
<p>Officials expect Kabila to address the five million people of the capital, and the rest of the nation of 47 million, sometime later this week.</p>
<p>The victorious rebel alliance had promised to establish a transitional government by Tuesday, but there was no indication as of the early evening that an administration team was about to be announced.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
