<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="601427" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: FOCUS-Southern Africa strives for free-trade area.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Southern Africa strives for free-trade area.</headline>
<byline>Ben Hirschler</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southern African leaders said on Wednesday they were determined to forge a common market in the region which could eventually include former Zaire, the continent's third largest country.</p>
<p>Such a free-trade bloc, agreed in principle by the 12-nation Southern African Development Community (SADC) last year, is seen as vital for the region to compete on the global stage.</p>
<p>But the task is formidable with South Africa and Zimbabwe, the two largest economies, still fiercely fighting their corners in protracted bilateral trade liberalisation talks.</p>
<p>&quot;No country in Southern Africa can succeed on its own,&quot; South Africa's President Nelson Mandela told the opening session of a World Economic Forum (WEF) conference in the Zimbabwean capital.</p>
<p>&quot;Interdependence amongst our neighbours and the pressures of a globalised economy increasingly defined by regional blocs dictate that we work together as a region.&quot;</p>
<p>Kaire Mbuende, SADC's executive secretary, said implementing a free trade area as soon as possible was important to allow the free movement of capital and labour, a prerequisite for improving the area's competitive position.</p>
<p>South Africa and Zimbabwe both scored badly in the WEF's 1997 Global Competitiveness Report released on Wednesday, ranking 44th and 51st respectively out of a field of 53.</p>
<p>Some businessmen at the conference complained that SADC's target of creating a common market of around 140 million people within eight years was too slow.</p>
<p>But Mandela said trade barriers had to be dismantled in a way that took account of the relative strengths and employment problems of different economies.</p>
<p>&quot;We have set out of a path to a single regional market, in the knowledge that it is no easy path,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe's Robert Mugabe said Southern African had an opportunity to build economic success on recent political success, highlighted by the end of civil war in Mozambique and the recent creation of a government of national unity in Angola.</p>
<p>&quot;And it can work also in Zaire, Rwanda and Burundi...We need to disabuse the world of the idea that Africa is no more than an area of poverty and strife,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>South African Foreign Minister Alfred Nzo said he hoped that the newly renamed Democratic Republic of Congo might eventually join SADC after the ousting of Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko, boosting the potential market by a further 40 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Hopefully it will be possible for them to be included in SADC as the 13th country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Throughout the 1980s and early 1990s southern Africa's economic growth failed to keep pace with a population expanding at three percent a year.</p>
<p>In the last two years growth in several countries has spurted ahead, helped by good rains, rekindling foreign interest and boosting industrial shares on the Zimbabwe Stock Excgange -- the region's largest bourse outside Johannesburg -- by 90 percent in dollar terms in 1996.</p>
<p>Now the region's leaders hope to convert that short-term portfolio investment into long-term fixed investment, and in some places it is already happening.</p>
<p>South African Finance Minister Trevor Manuel said the planned development corridor between the Mozambican capital of Maputo and the Gauteng region around Johannesburg had already generated investment commitments in Mozambique of over US$4 billion, double the impoverished country's GDP.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no doubt in my mind that it is going to be the southern African region that transforms the Africa continent,&quot; Manuel told businessmen.</p>
<p>SADC consists of Angola, Botswana, Malawi, Mozambique, Mauritius, Lesotho, Namibia, Tanzania, South Africa, Swaziland, Zambia and Zimbabwe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SADCC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
