<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="601564" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Slowing imports seen as threat to Yugo industry.</title>
<headline>Slowing imports seen as threat to Yugo industry.</headline>
<byline>Amra Kevic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A slowdown in Yugoslavia's imports could affect the country's industrial output and exports, the Belgrade-based Foreign Trade Institute (IST) said in its latest report.</p>
<p>&quot;The pronounced slowdown in imports in the first quarter continued in April and May and the question is whether this is now a long-term trend and can it reflect on exports,&quot; said IST director Radovan Kovacevic.</p>
<p>Official statistics showed April's imports dropped by 12.9 percent to $242 million from $278 million in April 1996 and were down a massive 39 percent from $396 million in December last year.</p>
<p>Exports however grew 19.3 percent in April to $184 million from $155 million in April 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Fortunately, exports have not reacted to the imports slowdown yet and are maintaining their pace, while industrial output growth is more or less steady,&quot; Kovacevic said.</p>
<p>April's industry output fell 0.1 percent from March, when it rose 7.4 percent against February. Cumulative January-April output rose 7.3 percent over the same period last year.</p>
<p>Semi-manufactured goods and raw materials dominated imports which is the key reason why industrial output has not slowed down more, the institute said.</p>
<p>But a continued slowdown in imports growth could jeopardise Yugoslavia's import dependent industry in the coming months by reducing production and hence the amount of goods available for exports.</p>
<p>&quot;It is strange how the constant downward trend in imports in the past three-four months has not influenced the industry yet,&quot; said Zivojin Jevtic, another expert with the institute.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be very interesting to see next month what will happen to imports which have slowed so much. The trend must begin to reflect on production,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Yugoslavia welcomed the restoration of European Union (EU) trade preferences earlier this month, but firms still face an uphill battle to increase exports, the key problem being what to offer EU markets.</p>
<p>The EU has grown into a very demanding market with regard to quality and standardisation of goods. Yugoslavia has not yet done much to adjust to those standards.</p>
<p>The economy is stifling under lack of working capital and a financial injection could partially revive production for both domestic and foreign markets, but it is unclear where the money could come from, the institute said.</p>
<p>Economists said a lack of export earnings and declining official forex reserves could gradually build up pressure on the dinar exchange rate.</p>
<p>Kovacevic regretted the government was inactive in implementing an overall economic development programme, including an exports strategy.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot leave the foreign trade completely to the market, without an active role of the state in intensifying exports,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Belgrade newsroom +381 11 222 4305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
