<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="601682" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: IMF backs Argentina on growth, warns on poverty.</title>
<headline>IMF backs Argentina on growth, warns on poverty.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>International Monetary Fund chief Michel Camdessus expressed confidence Wednesday in the Argentine government's forecast of 6.0 percent gross domestic product growth for 1997.</p>
<p>But Camdessus, addressing a banking conference in Buenos Aires, also warned that Argentina's economic reforms risked failure if they did not tackle the issues of unequal income distribution and poverty.</p>
<p>Camdessus, taking his turn on the podium ahead of Economy Minister Roque Fernandez, said: &quot;The minister tells me the economy is going to grow 6.0 percent, and I believe him.&quot;</p>
<p>The IMF chief then turned to Argentina's worrying social problems, such as high unemployment of over 17 percent and constant and often violent protest about rising poverty.</p>
<p>&quot;The promising perspectives for Argentine reform could turn to failure if efforts are not intensified to reduce the inequality in income and even more importantly, to create more opportunities for the underprivileged,&quot; said Camdessus.</p>
<p>But he also emphasized that these social problems were not the fault of the free-market reforms carried out in recent years, especially under the guidance of former Economy Minister Domingo Cavallo, sacked last year, and whose &quot;courage&quot; Camdessus praised.</p>
<p>&quot;This deterioration was produced by the periods of high inflation and low growth during the debt crisis of the 1980s,&quot; said the IMF chief.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the moment for Latin America to undertake a second generation of reforms,&quot; said Camdessus, urging the region to overhaul its legal system and labor relations.</p>
<p>(( - Patrick Adam, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0695))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
