<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60171" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Coalition urges swift passage of Canadian MMT ban.</title>
<headline>Coalition urges swift passage of Canadian MMT ban.</headline>
<byline>Randall Palmer</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>An unlikely coalition of carmakers, environmentalists and health groups urged the Canadian government on Wednesday to pass a bill swiftly to ban the gasoline additive MMT in Canada.</p>
<p>The contentious bill has pitted carmakers against the oil industry, a U.S. manufacturer against the Canadian government, with environmental and health lobbyists also joining the fray.</p>
<p>The government has put the bill high on its agenda, despite complaints from the manufacturer of MMT, Richmond, Va.-based Ethyl Corp., that studies about its ill effects are inconclusive or ill-founded.</p>
<p>MMT, methylcyclopentadienyl manganese tricarbonyl, boosts octane while cutting emissions of carbon monoxide and nitrogen oxide. But the groups advocate using other octane enhancers.</p>
<p>The environmentalists backed claims by the Big Three as well as international automakers that MMT gums up auto emission diagnostic systems and charged that manganese is a potential neurotoxin that might hurt brain development.</p>
<p>&quot;Strong action is needed, not only to protect the diagnostic systems on board our automobiles, but to protect those diagnostic systems found in a more important piece of equipment, the human brain,&quot; Elizabeth May, executive director of the Sierra Club of Canada, told a news conference.</p>
<p>Canadian Automobile Association President Brian Hunt said MMT has been shown to hurt catalytic converters.</p>
<p>&quot;Manganese from MMT coats the surfaces of the catalyst, reducing its ability to remove pollutants from exhaust passing through,&quot; Hunt said.</p>
<p>He added that MMT coats oxygen sensors that send vital information to a car's on-board computer, and, if the wrong oxygen readings are sent, the wrong mixture of air and fuel will be used, consuming more fuel and spewing more emissions.</p>
<p>The government bill to ban the import and inter-provincial trade of MMT was first introduced in May 1995, but it became overshadowed by the turmoil over whether Quebec should leave Canada.</p>
<p>The office of Herb Gray, who runs the government's legislative programme in the House of Commons, Parliament's lower chamber, said the bill was now fourth on the list of priorities.</p>
<p>&quot;We're hoping we'll get to it next week,&quot; Gray's spokesman Dan Rogers said.</p>
<p>The situation is complicated by Ethyl Corp.'s announcement on Sept. 10 that it intended to submit a claim under the North American Free Trade Agreement for US$200 million against the Canadian government for damages to its Ethyl Canada subsidiary because of the legislation.</p>
<p>Ethyl has quoted the government department Health Canada as saying that the amount of manganese entering the environment is so tiny that it does constitute a health risk.</p>
<p>Sierra Club's May said it was important for the public not to view this as a clash merely between the oil and auto industries.</p>
<p>&quot;They've been hearing about it as if it was entirely a conflict between the gas guys and the car guys, and it's time to make sure people understand that there's a health and environment risk that C-29 (this bill) will remove,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Opposition parties have argued that it makes little sense to ban MMT shortly after the United States lifted its own ban.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
