<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="601779" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News-May 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News-May 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>In a dramatic increase in the money invested in Australia's booming petroleum industry off the country's north-west coast, Shell Australia and Woodside Petroleum announced yesterday they are hoping to build a A$10 billion liquefied natural gas plant near Darwin. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After telling News Ltd shareholders last year that there was great potential for the company under plans for a chain of multimedia satellite platforms covering the world, Rupert Murdoch has stumbled badly, with the A$3.9 billion project all but dead due to his failure to secure the US satellite television project ASkyB, a critical link in his planned worldwide coverage. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following the posting of a net profit for the 12 months to March of A$94.7 million, a 116 percent increase in full-year earnings, shares in Rothmans Holdings Ltd rose nearly 10 percent to A$9.00 a share, their highest level since early 1992. The group also announced a special dividend of A$1.00 a share. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After being ordered by the Federal Government to reduce its 76 percent share in the Ten television network to 57.5 percent, Canada-based CanWest Global Communications Inc wants its 57.5 percent enshrined in law, and has threatened to sell out if the Government does not respond. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>ICI Australia managing director Warren Haynes last night announced a joint venture with the only other domestic PVC manufacturer Auseon Ltd, a move that will see the new company reaping revenues of more than A$220 million a year and a retention of profit, despite the current low level of PVC prices. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Amcor Ltd managing director Don Macfarlane said yesterday the budgets of Amcor's loss-making German cardboard box group Holfelder and US McKinley Paper operations will be reviewed in the next month, and from there a decision will be made on whether to sell the operations. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Shell Australia and Woodside Petroleum yesterday announced the formation of the Northern Australia Gas Venture, a proposed A$10 billion liquefied natural gas and domestic gas project to rival the North West Shelf project. The project, near Darwin, would ensure Australia's strong standing as a major energy supplier to the Asian region. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After an Australian Broadcasting Authority finding in March that CanWest Global Communications Inc's 76 percent ownership of the Ten Network was in breach of the foreign ownership limits of the Broadcasting Services Act, CanWest executive chairman Izzy Aper said yesterday a share market float would be his preference to reduce the company's interest in the group. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Amcor Ltd managing director Don Macfarlane said yesterday the company has set a July deadline for a decision on the future of its three loss-making overseas operations - the Holfelder German paper mill, and Cello Bag and McKinley operations in the United tates. However, analysts believe the move casts doubt on Amcor's ability to find buyers for the operations in the depressed world paper market. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a bid to mop up the damage after the Busang scandal, officials from the Toronto and Vancouver stock exchanges were in Sydney yesterday, moving to assure Australian miners, explorers and financial institutions that the Canadian mining industry is still worth investing in. Page 24.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following yesterday's Industrial Relations Commission order to avert possible strike action, Qantas has agreed to form a steering committee with unions to look at contacting out customer service and ramp handling functions at three privatised airports. Uions agreed to suspend action until the airline and unions return to the Commission on June 10. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Under a joint statement from the Securities Institute of Australia and the Australian Investment Managers Association, the two bodies said they would oppose a proposal by the Australian Institute of Company Directors to reintroduce the &quot;true and fair view override to local financial reporting. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>After signing a letter of intent for a feasibility study on a A$10 billion liquefied natural gas project based in Darwin, Shell Oil and Woodside Petroleum yesterday estimated the project, which would draw gas from the fast growing Timor Sea reserves, could deliver gas into the Asian markets by 2005. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After being listed on the sharemarket for three days, Colonial's investors, and especially its elite band of executives led by group head Peter Smedley, have benefited from a windfall. The executives already share an option pool of almost A$13 million inprofit, with Smedley sitting on a A$2.5 million paper profit on the three million options he received as part of the float. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After being ordered by Federal Treasurer Peter Costello to reduce its 76 per cent share in the Ten Network to 57.5 per cent, CanWest Global Communications chairman Izzy Asper said the group is considering all options, including the possible purchase into the Ten Group by a consortium of local investors. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following comments by Prime Minister John Howard that the Labor Opposition could be described as &quot;yesterday's men&quot; for opposing tax reform, Federal Treasurer Peter Costello said yesterday the main priority of the Howard Government's second term would be a restructuring of Australia's archaic indirect tax system. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>As Federal Industry Minister John Moore said yesterday he would be concerned if changes to the media laws in Australia reduced diversity of ownership, the Federal Government came under attack from News Ltd executive Ken Cowley, who claimed the Budget was &quot;politically safe and careful&quot;. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The AMP Society has laid down a raft of rules relating to its proposed demutualisation. The rules, outlined in a briefing document for financial advisers and product distributors, could see group and individual superannuation policyholders lose substantil share entitlements. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Shell Australia and Woodside Petroleum, already partners in the A$12 billion North-West Shelf LNG project, announced yesterday they plan to develop a A$10 billion liquefied natural gas project in Darwin. The project, working on proven and yet-to-be discovered gas reserves 400 kilometres off shore in the Timor Sea, should be operational by 2005. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a move that could raise more than A$1 billion, Boral yesterday left the way open for the possible floating of its natural gas pipeline assets as one of several options in the restructuring of its energy assets. No decision has been made yet, as Boral relies on its large natural gas division to provide some stability in cashflows. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Unions, environmentalists, and non-Government associations yesterday used CRA's annual meeting as a platform for protests, which mainly centred on its investment in Freeport, its environmental performance and human rights issues. The often tense two-hour meeting was the last for the group before it changes its name to Rio Tinto on June 2. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries again reached a record high yesterday, jumping 12.5 points to 2543.2 on the back of the announcement that United States interest rates would remain as they are. Banking and insurance stocks benefited from the result after concerns over rate rise saw shares tumble. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Shares in tobacco company Rothmans Holdings lifted 70 cents to A$9 yesterday on the back of a doubled net profit of A$94.7 million and a A$1 special dividend reward for shareholders. However, the company has predicted static earnings in the next 12 month, saying it could not rule out another cigarette price war. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The latest newsletter from the Australian Retailers Association has attacked American Express for charging higher merchant fees than Visa and Mastercard on its new Amex blue credit card. The card, Amex's first move into credit cards, combines a low interest rate and comprehensive rewards program. Page B3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
