<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="601715" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico bids awkward farewell to controversial cleric.</title>
<headline>Mexico bids awkward farewell to controversial cleric.</headline>
<byline>Michael Stott</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico bade an awkward farewell on Tuesday night to its Papal envoy who negotiated an historic reconciliation between church and state but whose meetings with fugitive drug lords landed him in hot water.</p>
<p>Vatican nuncio Geronimo Prigione held a grand reception at his residence to mark his retirement after nearly 20 years in Mexico -- but those who showed up did not include the rich and powerful who graced his parties during his heyday.</p>
<p>Guests were checked with a metal detector as they entered the residence in the south of Mexico City, an unusual precaution for a diplomatic reception in Mexico.</p>
<p>For some participants, the heavy security brought back memories of the less happy moments of Prigione's tenure -- the 1993 assassination of a cardinal at Guadalajara airport, apparently by drug cartel hitmen, and the nuncio's two meetings with top drug traffickers at the Vatican residence.</p>
<p>Prigione said at the time that he received the drug-dealing brothers Ramon and Benjamin Arellano Felix in December 1993 and January 1994 to discuss &quot;personal&quot; matters -- news reports said he believed the capos could shed light on the airport murder of Cardinal Juan Jesus Posadas.</p>
<p>&quot;As I am accustomed to do with everyone, I received them in private and I listened to them. It was a confidential conversation,&quot; the nuncio said in a statement.</p>
<p>Mexicans, already suspicious of the nuncio for his conservative views and promotion of right-wing bishops, were outraged.</p>
<p>Newspapers called for his removal and columnists poured scorn on him. The matter was not helped by Prigione's subsequent claim that he had informed then-president Carlos Salinas de Gortari before meeting the traffickers.</p>
<p>Prigione, a career Vatican diplomat with the rank of archbishop, had earlier won fame by negotiating a historic accord with Salinas to re-establish diplomatic relations with the Vatican after a break of more than a century.</p>
<p>In a now-famous phrase, he said &quot;God has been returned to Mexico and Mexico has been returned to God.&quot; Emphasising the closer ties, Pope John Paul made three visits to Mexico and beatified a national hero.</p>
<p>Scrapping 140 years of legal discrimination against the church, Mexico also amended its constitution in 1992 to grant the church legal status and allow its priests to vote.</p>
<p>But the hundreds of guests who lined up around a block to gain entry to Tuesday night's reception did not include Salinas, now living in self-imposed exile in Dublin, Ireland, after falling into disgrace.</p>
<p>Jose Cordoba Montoya, Salinas's all-powerful chief of staff, was not there either.</p>
<p>Cordoba, a shadowy figure associated in the public imagination with many of the worst excesses of the Salinas administration, has rarely been seen in public since relinquishing his post in early 1994.</p>
<p>Pablo Chapa Bezanilla, a top detective who was seen at past Vatican receptions and led investigations into the cardinal's slaying, was also absent.</p>
<p>Chapa was arrested in Madrid last Friday on charges of criminal association, evidence-planting and body-snatching.</p>
<p>President Ernesto Zedillo's government, much less enthusiastic than Salinas's about close relations with the church, sent only an under-secretary to bid Prigione farewell. Business and political leaders were mostly absent and the U.S. ambassador to Mexico, James Jones, stayed only a few minutes.</p>
<p>Church figures and a diplomat gave effusive speeches praising Prigione but the 75-year-old nuncio himself, a heavy bejewelled gold cross hanging from his neck, gave a curiously low-key speech that avoided mention of his historic church-state accord or his controversial meetings.</p>
<p>&quot;The future of Mexico lies in its Christian roots,&quot; Prigione concluded.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
