<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60192" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Aviation industry gathers speed for takeoff.</title>
<headline>Aviation industry gathers speed for takeoff.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Little more than a year ago, Boeing Co. enticed more than 8,300 workers to retire early, taking a $600 million charge against earnings to complete the last in a series of painful cutbacks.</p>
<p>Today the world's largest airplane manufacturer is seeking job applicants aggressively, placing full-page advertisements in newspapers across the country as it rapidly ramps up production to meet rising airline demand.</p>
<p>The sudden reversal is an indicator of how quickly the long-awaited aviation industry upturn has taken off.</p>
<p>&quot;The airlines are in a buying mood again,&quot; said James Woolsey, senior editor of the monthly trade magazine Air Transport World.</p>
<p>Indeed both Boeing and its main rival, Airbus Industrie, already have far surpassed last year's order totals as the world's airlines, flush with cash after years of massive losses, have begun a new buying spree.</p>
<p>Singapore Airlines and United Airlines are among those that have announced massive new orders this year, and many analysts expect U.S. giants American Airlines and Delta Air Lines Inc. to weigh in soon with orders for new wide-body planes, from either Boeing or Airbus.</p>
<p>Boeing, Airbus and No. 3 manufacturer McDonnell Douglas Corp. announced a bumper crop of sales at the biennial Farnborough, England, air show this month, where total announced orders more than tripled the comparable 1994 figure.</p>
<p>&quot;Farnborough was just lots more evidence that the uptrend is continuing to gather momentum,&quot; said Wolfgang Demisch of BT Securities.</p>
<p>Boeing already has announced three production rate increases this year, and Airbus has boosted production 37 percent this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy, traffic, and airline profits show we've entered a growth stage of the business cycle,&quot; Boeing Commercial Airplane Group Executive Vice President Richard Albrecht said in a recent speech. &quot;After the horrendous early 1990s it's great to be back on track.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts, judging from the historical peaks and valleys of the industry, see the current upturn lasting until the end of the decade.</p>
<p>Bill Whitlow at Pacific Crest Securities expects Boeing to deliver more than 400 airplanes annually from 1998 through 2002, compared with about 215 this year and 206 in 1995, when a 10-week strike hampered production.</p>
<p>The danger, he said, was that Boeing would boost production too quickly and be forced to go through another series of layoffs when airlines begin pulling back despite the company's avowed effort to smooth out the business cycle.</p>
<p>&quot;In every cycle there's the comment that this one will be different,&quot; Whitlow said. &quot;Right now the way Boeing is going it kind of looks like deja vu all over again.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition to boosting production rapidly, Boeing is beginning a costly project to enlarge its jumbo 747, and Airbus and McDonnell Douglas also have ambitious new airplanes on their drawing boards.</p>
<p>After forecasting earlier that they would need to add 10,000 workers to the company's 105,000-member work force this year, Boeing executives last month raised the target by 3,000.</p>
<p>Because of the early-retirement offer, virtually all available workers who had been laid off previously already have been offered new jobs, so the company has been forced to scour the country for employees.</p>
<p>An advertisement appearing in nearly two dozen newspapers offers prospective employees a &quot;FREE LATTE&quot; -- a mainstay of the Seattle coffee scene -- if they are invited to interview for one of dozens of engineering, technical, manufacturing or administrative positions listed.</p>
<p>&quot;Business is good in Seattle,&quot; declares the ad. &quot;Especially in the aerospace industry.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
