<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="602024" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX electricity ends lower, retrenches from Tues.</title>
<headline>NYMEX electricity ends lower, retrenches from Tues.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX electricity futures finished lower Wednesday in line with lower physical power prices and retrenching Tuesday's strong gains, industry sources said.</p>
<p>NYMEX June Palo Verde (PV) finished down $2.13 at $27.68 per megawatt hour (MWh) following trades at $27.25-28.80, while July ended down $1.40 at $29.10 from trades at $28.25-29.50 per MWh.</p>
<p>Remaining PV deferreds closed down between 30 cents and $1.21 per MWh.</p>
<p>June California Oregon Border (COB) closed $1.35 lower at $21.06 after trades at $20.00-21.25, while July ended down $1.25 at $21.00 following trade as high as $21.50 per MWh.</p>
<p>Remaining COB deferreds ended mostly down between 15 cents and $1.40 per MWh.</p>
<p>An estimated total of 331 COB and 541 PV contracts traded Wednesday.</p>
<p>In the physical markets, firm, peak COB electricity for Thursday was assessed at $23.50-24.50 a MWh, down from $24.50-26.00 for Wednesday, while firm, peak PV power for Thursday fell to $24.00-28.00 from as high as $35.00 for Wednesday.</p>
<p>The lower futures were seen as a retrenchment from lofty contract highs hit at both NYMEX COB and PV contracts Tuesday. But while the futures backed off Wednesday in line with lower physical power prices, sources said the power deferreds could repeat Tuesday's over the next while.</p>
<p>&quot;You're going to see it come off and then pop up again,&quot; said one New York-based futures trader. &quot;We're coming up to the summer peak demand months, and you can't store (electricity).&quot;</p>
<p>Trade of the July and August contracts will likely show good strength when physical power prices again pick up, especially in the event of any unexpected cutbacks in power generation in the U.S. West during heat spells, the trader said.</p>
<p>NYMEX June Henry Hub electricity futures ended up 1.5 cents at $2.206 per million British thermal units.</p>
<p>Extended forecasts showed temperatures in the Northwest would average above normal to well-above normal over the next several days.</p>
<p>Readings in the eastern area of the Southwest would run near normal, while those in western area would average above normal.</p>
<p>Separately, Bonneville Power Administration said the DC lines on the Pacific Intertie will be reduced by as much as 414 megawatts (MW) this week for scheduled maintenance, while the AC portion will be lowered by 400 MW today.</p>
<p>At least 7,000 MW of power remained off line in the West for either planned or unplanned maintenance, although a much of the capacity was expected to return to operation over the next several weeks.</p>
<p>As part of the service resumptions, Pacific Gas &amp; Electric's 1,087 MW Diablo Canyon 1 was scheduled to begin production May 25 after completing a scheduled refueling and maintenance outage which began April 19.</p>
<p>COB open interest for May 20 fell 354 to 5,608 while PV open interest fell 506 to 6,427, NYMEX said.</p>
<p>((--New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1627))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
