<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="602064" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soybeans end higher ahead of USDA export data.</title>
<headline>CBOT soybeans end higher ahead of USDA export data.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT soybean futures ended higher on a late rally tied to short covering ahead of Thursday's USDA weekly export sales report, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;People are waiting to see what the weekly export sales will be,&quot; said Jerry Gidel, analyst with Dean Witter.</p>
<p>Trade estimates for the report, due at 0730 CDT on Thursday, ranged from 100,000 to 200,000 tonnes. While those figures were low, Gidel said the export pace needed to remain at or below those levels to meet USDA's projections.</p>
<p>New crop months ended slightly higher amid ideas cool weather is slowing crop emergence and early development.</p>
<p>There was scattered talk of a frost warning issued for the eastern Corn Belt for early Thursday. Cash merchants there said crops in the northern tier had not yet emerged and would likely be protected from the cold but in the southern parts of Ohio and Indiana, some fields would be at risk.</p>
<p>Reports that Argentina's Agricultural Secretariat planned to shave one million tonnes off its crop production figures also lent support. After the close, the secretariat cut its production forecast by 1.4 million tonnes to 11.5 million.</p>
<p>Soybeans ended 2-1/4 to 1/4 cents per bushel higher with July up 2-1/4 at $8.47-1/4.  </p>
<p>On the day, ABN-AMRO Chicago Corp bought 4.5 million bushels November, ING bought 3.5 million July and Merrill Lynch bought three million July and sold four million.</p>
<p>In options trade, CIS bought 400 November $6.75 puts and sold 200 November $7.25 calls and another 200 November $7.50 calls at 14 to 17 cents.</p>
<p>Soybean futures volume was estimated by CBOT at 64,000 contracts, compared with Tuesday's actual volume of 75,781.</p>
<p>((Emily Kaiser 312-408-8749))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
