<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="602335" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Is Italy's Albania force on a mission impossible?.</title>
<headline>Is Italy's Albania force on a mission impossible?.</headline>
<byline>Jude Webber</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The multinational security force Italy is leading in Albania is under fire at home as concerns mount that Operation Alba is in fact a &quot;mission impossible&quot;.</p>
<p>Italy won praise for seizing the diplomatic initiative when the crisis blew up on its doorstep in February and March and thousands of Albanian refugees poured across the Adriatic sea.</p>
<p>But six weeks since the first of the force's 6,000 troops landed, and with a political crisis in Tirana over elections threatening to unleash fresh chaos, analysts are questioning whether Operation Alba has any hope of success.</p>
<p>&quot;The mission was begun amid strong doubts it could achieve its objectives,&quot; Sergio Romano, a respected commentator and former diplomat, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Italy, which invaded Albania during World War Two, hastily assembled a coalition of forces with United Nations backing and a strictly humanitarian brief after an uprising in the south over failed savings schemes spread.</p>
<p>But Operation Alba, the first such mission under Rome's control, ran into flak from the start.</p>
<p>Critics said it took too long to get under way and by the time the troops landed, the worst of the violence that swept Albania to the edge of anarchy after thousands lost their life savings was already over.</p>
<p>The force's ostensible role -- to safeguard humanitarian aid -- raised eyebrows when agencies said there was no widespread hunger or medical emergency.</p>
<p>A limited U.N. mandate also left it powerless to disarm Albanians who looted army barracks of weapons, putting a Kalashnikov in virtually every home.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no point pretending any more,&quot; the influential daily La Stampa said.</p>
<p>&quot;The international mission in Albania, led by Italy, failed even before it could hit its stride, having achieved none of its three real objectives...restoring order and normality ...preventing mass illegal immigration...and ensuring a climate of order and legality for the elections.&quot;</p>
<p>President Sali Berisha has called elections, seen as a major milestone on the road back to normality, for June 29.</p>
<p>But most parties have threatened to boycott them unless electoral rules they say are biased are changed. Marathon talks have so far failed to solve the deadlock and the West has warned it could end aid unless there is a breakthrough.</p>
<p>Patrick McCarthy, a professor of European studies at Bologna's Johns Hopkins University, said the mission gave Italy the chance to display its diplomatic skills.</p>
<p>Rome was stung when other powers at first left it out of the inner circle of Western mediation in Bosnia, and it has battled to be considered a heavyweight in NATO and the European Union.</p>
<p>But Operation Alba has been tinged with tragedy and farce and McCarthy admitted: &quot;The jury's still out.&quot;</p>
<p>More than 80 Albanians were feared killed when an Italian navy ship patrolling the sea to discourage would-be immigrants collided with a packed refugee ship in March.</p>
<p>Then, as troops began arriving in Albania, Italy's own navy flagship Vittorio Veneto ran aground off the port of Vlore, a flashpoint in the troubled south.</p>
<p>Romano said the mission needed more soldiers, a mandate to intervene more actively and more specific aims. Its mandate runs out on June 28, a day before the planned poll.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, McCarthy said Italy deserved credit for taking on a difficult situation where the conflict was not just a clear-cut fight between two rivals. &quot;Italy deserves a fair bit of sympathy,&quot; he said. &quot;But it won't get it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
