<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="602410" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian June castor drops on speculative selling.</title>
<headline>Indian June castor drops on speculative selling.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Castorseed June delivery dropped further to 1,083/1,084 rupees per quintal from 1,088 rupees on fresh speculative selling, dealers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Continued pressure of arrivals at the producing centres and sluggish overseas demand dragged prices lower but trading volume remained very slow,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Trading has dropped considerably following introduction of daily clearing system by the exchange authorities,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Castorseed September delivery nominally quoted at 1,170/1,175 rupees per quintal but no trading took place today,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Daily average arrivals of castorseed in the Gujarat region remained higher at 25,000/30,000 bags (75 kg each). Foreign buyers demanded Indian castoroil at 690 dollars per tonne but Indian offers were at 705/710 dollars.</p>
<p>Groundnut oil held steady at 355/357 rupees per 10 kg on stray seasonal buying but sentiment was subdued on continued arrivals of imported edible oil at Bombay port. Imported palm-oil fell by 1/2 rupees at 279/280 rupees per 10 kgs. In Rajkot spot groundnut oil was steady at 560 rupees per 15 kgs.</p>
<p>The Bombay oil and oilseed ready market will be open on Thursday but exchange authorities have decided to close the castorseed forward delivery category for a Buddhist festival.</p>
<p>--Bombay Commodities +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
