<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="602534" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OFAC says existing Burma contracts can proceed.</title>
<headline>OFAC says existing Burma contracts can proceed.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Treasury's Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) said Wednesday that all existing Burma contracts entered into by U.S. companies and persons can proceed, regardless of the stage they have reached.</p>
<p>U.S. companies, particulary three major oil companies with licences to explore for oil and gas offshore Burma, have been waiting to see the effect on their projects of unilateral U.S. sanctions against Burma, signed into law by President Bill Clinton on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as a U.S. company has a contract, a deal, to go Zinto Burma, to build a factory, an oil refinery, explore for oil or whatever, then that can go ahead,&quot; said Beth Weaver, spokesperson for OFAC.  </p>
<p>The executive order signed by President Clinton Tuesday, and coming into effect from 0001 EDT May 21, banned in broad terms &quot;new investment in Burma&quot; by U.S. citizens.</p>
<p>U.S. companies have criticized the unilateral approach of the administration but there had been particular anxiety that the interpretation of the sanctions law, which is under the aegis of OFAC, might prohibit any further investment in projects which already have had millions of dollars committed to them but were still at relatively early stages.</p>
<p>There are around 20 U.S.-based companies with direct ivnestment or employees in Burma, according to Washington-based Investor Responsibility Research Center, a non-profit think tank funded mainly by institutional and public sector investors.</p>
<p>Most are involved in the oil and gas sector and among the largest are Unocal, Texaco Inc and Atlantic Richfield Co .</p>
<p>Unocal will be allowed to continue with its $1.2 billion Yadana project to bring natural gas from offshore Burma onshore, mainly to Thailand, a project already well advanced in the construction stage. Unocal has a 28.26 percent stake.</p>
<p>It will also be allowed to honor its contract to explore and develop the M8 block adjacent to the Yadana field offshore Burma, a project which would take major new investment, as well as other gas transport and distribution contracts.</p>
<p>Texaco, which is operator and holds a 42.9 percent share in the Yetagun gas field, located 125 miles off Burma's western coast in the Indian Ocean, will be able to proceed with that project if current evaluation proves the field to be commercially viable.</p>
<p>Los Angeles-based ARCO has invested $30 million dollars in two offshore exploration blocks, though it has yet to determine if they are commercially viable.</p>
<p>--New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1623</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
