<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="602633" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SAUDI ARABIA: Small European firms seek deals in Gulf markets.</title>
<headline>Small European firms seek deals in Gulf markets.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Drees</byline>
<dateline>RIYADH 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Small and mid-sized European firms are eager to cash in on lucrative Gulf consumer markets and invest in a region which is still uncharted territory for many, delegates at a Gulf-EU business conference said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Many of the 120 European firms attending the three-day conference in Riyadh are looking to the oil-rich Gulf as an export market for their goods, such as food and beverages, chemical products and construction materials, they said.</p>
<p>Other firms are seeking to establish joint ventures in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;The financial strength of the region is promising and clients are able to pay,&quot; said Thorsten Hildebrand, adviser at the chamber of commerce in Magdeburg, Germany, which brought 16 companies to the conference.</p>
<p>The German delegation of 27 companies is the largest at the meeting, followed by France with 25 firms and Italy with 15.</p>
<p>Several companies attending the European Union-Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) forum said the region -- especially Saudi Arabia -- was a good export market because about half the population of around 25 million is under the age of 16.</p>
<p>In addition, per capita income in the GCC -- Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Oman, Bahrain, Qatar and the United Arab Emirates -- is among the world's highest, ranging from about $7,000 a year in Saudi Arabia and Oman to $16,800 in Kuwait.</p>
<p>Miriam Teuwen, national counsellor of the German team, agreed the conference was helping firms break into the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Yesterday one German company made contact with a Saudi firm. Today the German firm visited the Saudi one and made a sale of 10,000 marks ($5,900). He thinks it's just the beginning,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Some European and Gulf companies reported the conference had paved the way for possible joint ventures.</p>
<p>&quot;I have held talks with three or four potential joint venture companies,&quot; said a representative of a Saudi medical group.</p>
<p>Several European companies were also seriously considering joint venture deals, one EU representative said.</p>
<p>In the absence of the developed capital markets in the region, liquid Gulf firms are keen to couple their money with companies which already have established businesses and brands.</p>
<p>Hussein Mirghani, economic adviser at the Federation of GCC Chambers of Commerce, said while GCC investments in Europe amounted to about $150 billion to date, European investments in Gulf Arab states barely exceeded $2 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIYADH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SAUDI ARABIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
