<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="602665" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain to ban landmine manufacture.</title>
<headline>Britain to ban landmine manufacture.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's new Labour government is to ban the import, export and manufacture of anti-personnel landmines, Prime Minister Tony Blair said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He told Parliament an official government announcement of the ban will be made later in the day.  </p>
<p>Officials said Britain would destroy all its stocks of anti-personnel landmines by 2005 and would scrap the idea of replacing them with so-called &quot;smart mines' which destroy themselves after a set period.</p>
<p>This marks a significant change from the policy of the previous Conservative administration, which although dedicated to destroying existing stocks of landmines made clear it retained the option to buy smart mines.</p>
<p>The officials also said Britain intended to sign up to the so-called Ottawa Process, a Canadian initiative which groups 50 nations who want to sign a treaty by the end of this year to ban the production, stockpiling, export and use of mines.</p>
<p>Since taking power earlier this month, Labour has stressed the need for action on landmines, blamed for killing 25,000 people a year and maiming many more. Most of the victims are women and children.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
