<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="602726" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran shuts candidate's poll offices for violations.</title>
<headline>Iran shuts candidate's poll offices for violations.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iranian authorities have shut down the headquarters of a main presidential candidate for violations of campaign laws, an election official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The action dealt another political blow to Mohammad Khatami, a main rival of leading conservative presidential candidate Ali Akbar Nateq-Nouri who has been supported by key clerical groups.</p>
<p>Gholamhossein Rahbarpour, an official in charge of overseeing the campaigning for Friday's poll, said the Tehran headquarters of Khatami's campaign were closed after officials determined that it was located in a state-owned building, the daily Kayhan reported.</p>
<p>Khatami, who enjoys wide support among women, intellectuals and youths, has come under mounting pressure in the run-up to the elections from hardliners and conservatives for his relatively liberal views.</p>
<p>Rahbarpour said Khatami's headquarters were in violation of election laws banning the use of state funds and facilities for political campaigns, the newspaper added.</p>
<p>He said the building was owned by Tehran's municipality, which is headed by the capital's pro-Khatami mayor, but did not specify the terms under which the candidate was using the offices.</p>
<p>Khatami, who is backed by centrist state officials and left-wing Islamists, is a main candidate facing leading presidential hopeful Ali Akbar Nateq-Nouri who has been supported by key clerical groups.</p>
<p>Rahbarpour said 200 of some 280 people arrested for violating election rules were still in custody.</p>
<p>The nature of the violations leading to the arrests was not specified but campaign posters plastered on city walls have been defaced and rumours have been spread about what life would be like under this or that candidate.</p>
<p>A war of words has been mounting during the campaign despite calls by Iranian officials, including President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani, on supporters of the four candidates running in the election to avoid attacking each other.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
