<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="602814" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee futures get a boost from ACPC news.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee futures get a boost from ACPC news.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A decision by the Association of Coffee Producing Countries (ACPC) to extend coffee export quotas drove CSCE coffee futures sharply higher Wednesday morning, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Talk the ACPC was loosening quotas was part of the bearish news affecting the market over the last few days,&quot; said Allendale analyst Jim Cordier. &quot;The fact they're not going to follow through on that is bullish.</p>
<p>&quot;Coffee consolidated a couple of days and I'm buying coffee on a technical trade here. I expect coffee to go up 10.00 cents today,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The benchmark July contract jumped 7.00 cents per lb as of 0958 EDT, to 247.25 cents, after trading from 248.75 to 239.00. Second-month September was 6.80 higher, at 221.50, while the back months traded up 1.80 to 6.00 lower.</p>
<p>After talks in London on Wednesday, the ACPC put out a statement announcing it set export limits for one year at 52.75 million bags starting July 1.</p>
<p>&quot;The priority of the established policy is to ensure prices remain at a level remunerative to producers, but allowing continuing growth in worldwide consumption of coffee,&quot; the ACPC said.</p>
<p>The ACPC said the seasonal allocations of the programme for the whole year would be decided at a later stage, to allow a more flexible and adequate flow of coffee to the market.</p>
<p>But while the market was likely to view the ACPC as friendly, some analysts said its impact should be minimal.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think this should have an affect on the market,&quot; said Smith Barney analyst Walt Spilka. &quot;I don't think it's an overly effective program anyway.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodity Desk, +1 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
