<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="602965" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Zurich keen on asset management expansion.</title>
<headline>Zurich keen on asset management expansion.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zurich Group wants to expand asset management as one of its core businesses and is open to expansion either by internal means or acquisition, Zurich chairman Rolf Hueppi said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are strategically developing this new core business and plan to coordinate our expansion and utilise our existing resources on a global level,&quot; Hueppi said at a news conference.</p>
<p>He said the group now has a solid base in the fund and asset management sector through its 1996 acquisition of Kemper Corp in the U.S.</p>
<p>At the end of 1996 the Zurich Kemper organisation had some 78 billion Swiss francs of investments under management. Of this total 60 billion were as mutual funds and 18 billion in institutional investments, Hueppi also said.</p>
<p>He said the Kemper acquisition secured the group's presence in selected life insurance markets and particularly in asset management.</p>
<p>However, performance did not meet management's mid-and long-term expectations during the transition period following the acquisition.</p>
<p>But in the past months companies comprising Zurich Kemper strengthened their market presence considerably and their contribution had a positive impact on 1996 consolidated profit, he added. -- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
