<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="603054" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - May 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - May 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - May 21st 1997 Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>-- BRITAIN SEVENTH IN 'WORLD COMPETITIVENESS LEAGUE'</p>
<p>The Geneva-based World Economic Forum has released its latest Global Competitiveness Report which ranks the world's most competitive economies, with Britain ranked seventh overall, up from 15th in 1996. Helping the country move up were success in the overhaul of the welfare state, cuts in tax rates, increased labour market flexibility and sustained growth coupled with falling unemployment. Singapore, Hong Kong and the US placed first, second and third respectively.</p>
<p>-- RACAL OUT OF 1.5 BILLION STG RADIO CONTRACT BID</p>
<p>UK electronics defense group Racal Network Services has pulled out of the 1.5 billion stg contract to supply new technologically-advanced radios to the UK police force, causing a further delay in the project. Racal officials stated that the commercial return which the contract would supply was not enough to cover the potential risks of taking the project on. The remaining bidder for the radio system is Quadrant, a consortium led by British Telecommunications.</p>
<p>-- SIMON SET FOR EUROPE ROLE</p>
<p>Sir David Simon, former chairman of British Petroleum and current UK minister for trade and competition in Europe is expected to make a smooth transition to the 'Euro-scene' at his first Council of Ministers meeting on Wednesday. Simon's multilingual skills and membership on the European Round Table and EC's Competitiveness Advisory Group should prove to be an advantage in his efforts to convince the EU to accept a proposal for his British 'supply side' vision for Europe. The vision comprises employment flexibility through job creation and a push for competition in the single market.</p>
<p>-- 100 MILLON STG TELECOMS CONTRACT AWARDED</p>
<p>The UK's Central Computer and Telecommunications Agency has awarded a five-year, 100 million stg contract for Government Telecommunications Services and Government Telecommunications Mobile to Mercury Communications, one of the four companies which make up Cable and Wireless' C&amp;W Communications subsidiary. A CCTA spokesman said the deals would cover data, voice and mobile products provided for the public sector, including government, local authorities, universities and private sector organizations.</p>
<p>-- RAILTRACK TO SPEND 1 BILLION STG ON UPDATING STATIONS</p>
<p>British rail network operator Railtrack has announced plans for a $1 billion upgrade of its railway stations, which could mean future stations would include such services as business centres, doctors' surgeries and dental clinics. The updating is hoped to lead to commercial development of stations and higher quality services for all customers. Railtrack hopes the majority of its 2,500 UK stations will be improved by 2001, beginning with a goal of 300 for 1997.</p>
<p>-- GAZPROM SET TO NAME BANKS FOR 600 MILLION STG SALE</p>
<p>Russian gas monopoly Gazprom is likely to announce this week</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
