<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="603021" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Tobacco debate raises questions for Formula One.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Tobacco debate raises questions for Formula One.</headline>
<byline>Helen Jones</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Formula One, the world's most glamorous and expensive motor racing event, is looking for new sponsors as a growing number of countries introduce restrictions on tobacco sponsorship.</p>
<p>Tobacco companies represent the biggest group and the most important chunk of revenue among all sponsors that spend money on big motor racing events.</p>
<p>Formula One -- where teams compete in 16 Grand Prix races in 16 countries every year -- receives an estimated 100 million pounds ($163.8 million) in sponsorship money from tobacco companies, experts say.</p>
<p>But as countries such as Britain, France, Germany and Canada introduce total or partial bans on tobacco advertising and the use of tobacco company logos in TV broadcasts, motor racing teams are looking for alternative sponsors.</p>
<p>These might include soft-drink and high-tech companies.</p>
<p>On Monday Britain's new Labour government announced it was banning sponsorship of sporting events by tobacco companies.</p>
<p>That dealt a blow not only to Formula One but other sports that flourish from tobacco sponsorship -- cricket, golf, darts, rugby league and horse show-jumping.</p>
<p>Experts told Reuters that in Britain tobacco companies began pouring money into sponsoring car racing and other sports after tobacco advertising on television was banned in the 1960s.</p>
<p>&quot;Tobacco sponsorship is very important to Formula One. As tobacco companies cannot advertise on TV they have put their advertising budgets into sponsorship,&quot; said John Fitzpatrick, secretary general of the British Racing Driver's Club.</p>
<p>SPONSORSHIP ESSENTIAL FOR FORMULA ONE</p>
<p>Without sponsorship of some kind, Formula One would not exist.</p>
<p>The sport was once the preserve of wealthy amateurs but industry observers estimate it now costs between 30 million and 50 million pounds for a team to make a serious bid to win the Formula One world championship.</p>
<p>Although most teams have a number of sponsors, tobacco companies are among the most visible and their logos appear on the racing cars, drivers' clothing and advertising hoardings around the track.</p>
<p>The Renault-Williams team which was victorious last season with Damon Hill behind the wheel is sponsored by Rothmans, the Benetton team is sponsored by Japanese cigarette brand Mild Seven and the Jordan team has the support of Benson &amp; Hedges.</p>
<p>Experts say Formula One has a few options in the face of growing restrictions on tobacco sponsorship -- secure other sponsors, move the event to countries that don't restrict tobacco promotion and find ways to live with existing curbs.</p>
<p>Steve Herrick, managing director of CSS Internetional, a sports marketing agency, cites the search for new, non-tobacco sponsorship money.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Formula One organisers) are not daft and I'm sure they are looking at other potential sponsors as restrictions are introduced,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>To comply with existing regulations on tobacco promotion, Formula One teams have to be careful not to display tobacco logos when racing in certain countries.</p>
<p>At the British and German Grand Prix, tobacco logos must be adapted for television coverage to meet local tobacco advertising guidelines. Brand names must be dropped although corporate colours are allowed.</p>
<p>So Rothman's, for example, replaces its name with the word &quot;racing&quot; in the same colours and logotype.</p>
<p>But at other venues such as the Argentine Grand Prix, no such restrictions exist. So television viewers in Britain or Germany watching the Argentine race see the cigarette brand names that cannot be displayed at home events.</p>
<p>Some experts say Formula One could simply move to countries with no bans on tobacco promotion if things get too tough in main event locations.</p>
<p>Herrick says that if strict legislation is introduced in Europe then Formula One organisers may move the event to Asia and South America where there are fewer restrictions on tobacco sponsorship.</p>
<p>&quot;Twenty years ago it was a European event. Now there is a Japanese Grand Prix, and (South) Korea, Malaysia and the Philippines may follow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Darren Marshall, general manager for ISL US, a part of Switzerland-based ISL, a sports marketing group, says that is an unlikely scenario because &quot;the flagship races such as the British and Monaco Grand Prix are in Europe&quot;.</p>
<p>TOBACCO FIRMS WILL CONTINUE INVOLVEMENT IN SPORT Industry observers say that despite the introduction of tougher rules regarding tobacco sponsorship, tobacco companies will continue to be involved in the sport.</p>
<p>&quot;Canada issued a death sentence on tobacco sponsorship, but granted special concessions to the Montreal Grand Prix because it is huge event and is vital to the local economy,&quot; Marshall told Reuters.</p>
<p>He says he does not expect tobacco sponsorship to disappear as the whole structure of Formula One racing would change if it did.</p>
<p>&quot;It (car racing) is so expensive and so instead of each team spending millions of dollars building their own cars they would follow the example set by Indy car racing (which is big in the U.S.) and all the competing teams would use one manufacturer to build the chassis and a couple of others to build the engines to keep the costs down.&quot;</p>
<p>As for finding non-tobacco sponsors, experts told Reuters they did not expect Formula One to have a hard time since the sport attracts a huge global TV audience of up to 800 million people.</p>
<p>If tobacco sponsorship did eventually dry up, those close to the event said Formula One would survive because lots of big brand-name companies would be eager to sponsor Grand Prix events.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be a temporary glitch because other international brands would step in,&quot; said John Fitzpatrick of the British Racing Drivers' Club. ($ = 0.610 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
