<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60316" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Chrysler says new deal won't hurt expansion.</title>
<headline>Chrysler says new deal won't hurt expansion.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chrysler Corp's Canadian unit said on Wednesday the new labor deal reached last night with the Canadian Auto Workers union will allow the automaker to continue to expand in Canada.</p>
<p>At a joint news conference Chrysler Canada and the CAW agreed that the new deal, which requires the company to replace outsourced work with new work, will not interfere with Chrysler's plans to outsource some work for space and quality considerations while exanding production and hiring new workers in other areas.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're constantly looking at how we can make things better. Often that requires additional jobs,&quot; said Chrysler lead negotiator Ken Francese. &quot;It also may require some outsourcing, in a judicious way. We fully expect not only to replace those jobs, but to create additional jobs because of the continued success of our products.&quot;</p>
<p>CAW president Buzz Hargrove said the good relationship between the union and Chrysler will offset costs associated with the new contract, seen as generous by some analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;The productivity gains should more than offset the costs that are related to this agreement,&quot; said Hargrove.  </p>
<p>During the previous three-year contract, Chrysler created about 2,500 jobs through expansions of its operations, including the introduction of a third shift at its minivan plant in Windsor.</p>
<p>Francese said a similar increase in its workforce over the next three years is not out of the question.</p>
<p>He said Chrysler plans to expand its Bramalea and Pillette assembly plants and has undertaken a C$44 million expansion of its Etobicoke casting plant. A company spokesman said the Bramalea investment was &quot;in the realm&quot; of C$600 million, while the Pillette investment was of lesser value.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's a very substantial investment,&quot; said Francese. &quot;We've got a good workforce, they produce quality, they produce efficiently, and they're being rewarded not only in this contract but in the investments we're making in the facilities they work in.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the creation of a third shift at the Bramalea car assembly plant is a long-term possibility.</p>
<p>The outsourcing agreement reached by the CAW with Chrysler gives the union unprecedented say in management decisions about contracting out, but Chrysler said it will not interfere with management's ability to run a competitive business.  </p>
<p>&quot;The enemy is outside the room, not within the walls of our plants,&quot; Francese said.</p>
<p>Both sides said the cosy relationship between the CAW and Chrysler is key to the continued success of the company.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's give Chrysler credit for the last three years, and let's just make sure they keep that momentum,&quot; said Ken Lewenza, chairman of the union's Chrysler bargaining committee. &quot;They hired 2,500 to 3,000 in the last three years. And this relationship is so wonderful we're going to try to get 2,500 or 3,000 in the next three.&quot;</p>
<p>Chrysler employs about 12,600 workers in Canada.</p>
<p>-- Andrea Hopkins (416) 941-8102</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
