<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="603222" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria to launch currency board July 1-fin min.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria to launch currency board July 1-fin min.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's Finance Minister Muravei Radev said on Wednesday the new government would introduce a currency board, under which the lev will be pegged to an anchor currency, on July 1.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to pass this year's budget by the end of June...We need to achieve financial stabilisation urgently and will introduce a currency board (system) on July 1,&quot; Radev told Reuters.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's parliament appointed earlier on Wednesday a new cabinet headed by the leader of the reformist Union of Democratic Forces with a majority vote of 179.</p>
<p>Radev's other priorities include curbing white collar crime, prosecuting corrupt officials and strengthening the tax collecting adiministration to boost budget revenues.</p>
<p>Under a $548 million 14-month standby agreement sealed with the IMF, Bulgaria pledged to introduce a self-regulating monetary mechanism, known as a currency board, where the levs in circulation must be fully matched by the foreign exchange reserves.</p>
<p>The currency board system, designed to stabilise the country's unstable banks and volatile currency, bans central bank lending to the government and commercial banks. The lev will be pegged to an anchor currency at a rate that can not be adjusted.</p>
<p>An International Monetary Fund mission is in Sofia to help draft legal amendments needed to make the board operational.</p>
<p>The outgoing interim cabinet proposed two days ago to peg the lev to the German mark hoping to boost investment from the European Union and harmonise Bulgaria's currency with the European Monetary Union.</p>
<p>The mark was traded at around 934 levs on the interbank domestic forex market on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
