<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="603268" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Computer boom, chips to benefit Japan elec makers.</title>
<headline>Computer boom, chips to benefit Japan elec makers.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong demand for computer networks and a stable semiconductor market are seen lifting profits at Japan's electronics makers this year, after they were hit last year by a spectacular collapse in chip prices.</p>
<p>Aggressive investment by Japanese firms in digital information is steadily raising sales of personal computers, servers, mainframes and software, benefitting network system builders like Fujitsu Ltd, analysts say.</p>
<p>Stable chip prices, on the other hand, are boosting profits at Japan's biggest chip maker NEC Corp, which is heavily investing in dynamic random access memories (DRAMs) while others are having second thoughts about raising capacity.</p>
<p>The stable chip prices will support the bottom lines of other big electronics giants -- Hitachi Ltd, Toshiba Corp and Mitsubishi Electric Corp -- as well.</p>
<p>Starting this week, the big five makers will announce their business results for the year ended on March 31, as well as forecasts for the year that began on April 1.</p>
<p>NEC will announce parent and group-based results and forecasts on May 22. Toshiba, Fujitsu and Mitsubishi Electric plan the announcements on May 27, and Hitachi, on May 29.</p>
<p>In fiscal 1996/97, a global overcapacity and slowdown in PC sales caused a year-long free fall in DRAM prices, hitting hard Japanese electronics makers, which depend on DRAM production.</p>
<p>But production cuts by South Korean chip makers halted the price slides early this year and helped to stabilise the market, although a substantial recovery is yet to come.</p>
<p>Under still uncertain market conditions, analysts say higher sales of computer systems will have a distinctive impact on earnings, in particular Fujitsu and Hitachi.</p>
<p>Many big businesses are moving to replace their computer systems to solve &quot;millenium bug&quot; problems, analysts said.</p>
<p>The so-called millenium bug results from the fact that computer systems use a two-digit format to show the year. At the turn of the century, many computers will interpret the year as 1900 rather than 2000, potentially creating havoc.</p>
<p>&quot;Fujitsu, having computer clients spread evenly in many industrial sectors, may emerge as the biggest gainer,&quot; said Mami Indo, analyst at Daiwa Institute of Research.</p>
<p>Hiroyuki Iba, analyst at Nikko Research Centre, expects Fujitsu to reap 165 billion yen profit from its information business this fiscal year, up from an estimated 115 billion yen in 1996/97.</p>
<p>Analysts expect Fujitsu's group net profit in 1997/98 to double to around 80 to 90 billion yen.</p>
<p>Hitachi, however, may see slower profit growth in the sector because its major customers --  financial institutions -- are still suffering from Japan's bad-loan crisis.</p>
<p>At NEC, analysts say operating profit in the semiconductor business will grow six-fold to around 60 billion yen this fiscal year, helped by the improved chip market.</p>
<p>But group net profit will edge down to around 80 to 85 billion yen because of higher tax payments.</p>
<p>&quot;NEC will benefit most from the stable chip prices and the effects of the volume production,&quot; said Daiwa's Indo.</p>
<p>A sqeeze on public works spending, on the other hand, is expected to deal a blow to Mitsubishi, Toshiba and Hitachi, strong in heavy industrial machines.</p>
<p>Following are forecasts from analysts for the companies' group net profit, in billions of yen, for the 1996/97 results and estimates for the current year, 1997/98. The actual business results for 1995/96 are also given.</p>
<p>		    Fujitsu   NEC   Hitachi    Toshiba   Mitsubishi</p>
<p> 95/96 result    63.11    77.17  141.77    90.39	   59.21</p>
<p>Nikko</p>
<p>	 96/97	45	90	80	 60		10</p>
<p>	 97/98     105	85     115	 85		28</p>
<p>Yamaichi</p>
<p>	 96/97	48	90	80	 60		10</p>
<p>	 97/98	85	85     115	 65		25</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
