<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60337" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ford's UAW workers see gains under new pact.</title>
<headline>Ford's UAW workers see gains under new pact.</headline>
<byline>David Lawder</byline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Auto Workers union Wednesday disclosed that its tentative labour pact with Ford Motor Co. gives a typical worker $13,910 in new economic gains over the life of the deal, but allows the automaker greater freedom to contract with outside companies for new parts work.</p>
<p>According to an outline of the new pact distributed to members of the UAW's National Ford Council, union members will receive a lump sum payment of $2,000 in the first year of the three-year contract, followed by 3 percent base wage increases in the second and third years of the agreement.</p>
<p>The tentative agreement covering 105,000 UAW members at the No. 2 automaker was reached Monday. Union officials expect rank and file members to ratify the pact by Sept. 29.</p>
<p>The deal includes a historic commitment from Ford to guarantee employment for 95 percent of its current work force -- a first for the auto industry.</p>
<p>But in an important concession to Ford, which is seeking to reduce costs, the proposed agreement allows the company to pay lower wages and benefits to workers in new parts businesses it chooses to establish them.</p>
<p>Ford may pay those workers the prevailing wage and benefits for that industry segment or the geographic area in which it is located.</p>
<p>The new parts provision, however, does not allow Ford to pay lower wages in new businesses that would compete with component work already covered by the UAW-Ford Master Agreement.</p>
<p>It also prohibits Ford from undercutting wages and benefits of non-Ford UAW workers in the same industry or geographic area.</p>
<p>Older workers will find some generous encouragements for them to retire during the new contract. Monthly pension payments will increase by $265 to $2,295 after Oct. 1, 1998, a 13 percent increase from the $2,030 paid under the previous contract. The pension benefits apply to workers who retire during the life of the new agreement after 30 years of service before age 62.</p>
<p>The base wage for assembly workers will be $21.60 an hour at the end of the new contract vs. $17.945 at the end of the old contract.</p>
<p>Including a cost-of-living-adjustment payment that adds $1.03 an hour, the base assembly worker wage is $18.975 at the start of the new contract.</p>
<p>Other benefits include an annual Christmas bonus of up to $600 each; a total of 48 paid holidays during the three-year agreement, including a newly negotiated holiday on Veterans Day, Nov. 13, 1998</p>
<p>Including all wage gains, bonuses and cost-of-living adjustments and other payments, the typical Ford UAW worker's total cash compensation will increase by about $13,910 over the life of the new agreement.</p>
<p>Under the new contract, workers retain their fully paid health care benefits and receive several improvements in coverage. The annual maximum dental benefit increases to $1,400 per worker from $1,200 currently.</p>
<p>Workers also receive new coverage for prostate cancer tests and increased benefits for vision and selected medical devices.</p>
<p>The union said it rejected company attempts to force workers to pay part of their health insurance premiums and to restrict the health care providers they can see. Prescription drug co-payments for Michigan workers increased to $5 from $2.50.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
