<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="603959" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK stocks seen breaking more records on U.S. rates.</title>
<headline>HK stocks seen breaking more records on U.S. rates.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks are expected to continue breaking records on Wednesday following Tuesday's decision by the U.S. Federal Reserve to leave interest rates unchanged, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Dow Industrials rose 74.58 points, or 1.03 percent, on the news to 7,303.46 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The Hong Kong market should continue to move higher on better overseas stocks and a stable interest rate environment since there are not too many negative factors around,&quot; said Ben Kwong, director of research at Dharmala Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems the index will again test new highs.&quot;  </p>
<p>But the pace of the rise would be slower as fund managers turn a bit cautious at current price levels, Kwong said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the Hang Seng Index rose 127.38 points, or 0.90 percent, to a record close of 14,236.20. Later, the Hang Seng London Reference Index eased 32.95 points to 14,203.25.</p>
<p>Charles Cheung, executive director at J &amp; A Securities, said profit-taking was expected later in the day since the rise on Tuesday indicated the market had discounted the interest rate factor. &quot;The market may open up and gradually move down to close at the 14,000 level,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6369</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
