<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60409" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMF downplays risk Fed rate hike may shake markets.</title>
<headline>IMF downplays risk Fed rate hike may shake markets.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Rich Miller, Economics Correspondent</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund on Wednesday played down concerns that a modest U.S. interest rate increase would spark a massive, bone-jarring sell-off in U.S. stock and bond prices or in emerging markets.</p>
<p>Writing in the organization's annual international capital market report, IMF staff argued that free-wheeling global financial markets have turned more sober and appear better able to shrug off periods of turbulence.</p>
<p>&quot;There's less concern and less worry,&quot; IMF research department Assistant Director David Folkerts-Landau said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Reserve is slated to meet on September 24 to consider whether to raise short-term interest rates for the first time in 1-1/2 years in order to keep inflation in check.</p>
<p>Wall Street pundits are divided over whether the central bank will act but some are worried that a rate hike could spark a sharp decline in U.S. stock and bond markets, as occured when the Fed first started tightening credit in February 1994.</p>
<p>But the IMF report said large-scale speculators have sharply curtailed their operations since then -- perhaps by as much as a third -- and the bond market as a whole is thus not nearly so highly leveraged.  </p>
<p>&quot;That is not to say that instances of extreme market movements are a thing of the past, but it does suggest that for now the probability of a major bout of market turbulence is relatively low,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Consistent with that, it said that bond market players are not overly concerned that a modest increase in rates by the Fed over the next six months would again trigger serious bond market turbulence and financial stress.</p>
<p>The IMF staff also took issue with those who argue that the high-flying U.S. stock market is primed for a massive sell-off.</p>
<p>&quot;The evidence suggesting significant risk of a massive correction is not overwhelming,&quot; they said in their report.</p>
<p>While saying that a sharp, sustained share sell-off was not impossible, they argued that the buoyant stock market does not seem out of line with the yields available in the long-term bond market.</p>
<p>Price-earnings ratios are not as lofty as they were nine years ago before the last big stock market crash in 1987 and the market as a whole seems better able to cope with significant price swings.  </p>
<p>The emerging markets also seem in better shape than they did nearly two years ago, when an economic crisis in Mexico prompted international investors to yank money out of developing countries around the world, the report said.</p>
<p>While a modest increase in U.S. interest rates would put a crimp in money flows to emerging markets, it seems unlikely to trigger wholesale capital flight such as occured in 1995.</p>
<p>Financial institutions themselves also seem less at a risk if the U.S. central bank raises rates, the report added.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a relatively lower risk that an upward adjustment in U.S. interest rates could precipitate another round of major losses for international financial institutions, such as the one in early 1994,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The report generally painted a picture of a global financial system that has weathered a series of crises in the early part of this decade -- from Europe's currency crisis in 1993 to Mexico's in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;The global financial markets have emerged stronger and more resilient from the costly crises,&quot; Folkerts-Landau told a news conference unveiling the report.  </p>
<p>Banks and other financial institutions in most industrial countries have tightened their internal systems so they can better control risk. Speculators, such as hedge funds, have turned more cautious after suffering big losses in 1995.</p>
<p>Regulators have also made strides in improving their oversight, particularly in industrial nations. &quot;Many emerging market countries have also initiated reforms to strengthen their domestic financial sectors,&quot; the IMF said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
