<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60430" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natgas futures end steady to up, AGAs neutral.</title>
<headline>Natgas futures end steady to up, AGAs neutral.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natural gas futures, helped by short covering after downside momentum stalled early, ended steady to higher Wednesday in lackluster trade, then turned narrowly mixed after a neutral AGA  report.</p>
<p>October climbed 3.4 cents to close at $1.968 per million British thermal units. November settled 5.3 cents higher at $2.204. Other deferreds ended unchanged to up 6.7 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw some shorts cover and others get long ahead of the (AGA) number, but it was a fairly neutral number,&quot; said one East Coast trader, adding he was surprised by the day-session rally with cash soft today.  </p>
<p>AGA said late Wednesday that U.S. gas inventories rose last week by 84 bcf, roughly in line with expectations, but were still 312 bcf, or 12 percent, below year-ago levels. Eastern stocks climbed to 80 percent of capacity, while producing region inventores lagged at just 60 percent full.</p>
<p>While favorable cash-to-futures spreads were expected to encourage more stock building near-term, traders said mild 6-10 day weather forecasts could still keep the cash on the defensive.</p>
<p>Technically, traders said October remained within recent ranges. They pegged support at the $1.88-1.885 gap and psychological resistance at $2.</p>
<p>Cash sources said Gulf Coast prices lost about five cents Wednesday to the low-to-mid $1.80s. Midcon pipes were several cents lower in the low-$1.70s. New York city gate gas slipped almost five cents to $2.05 on mild weather there.</p>
<p>The 12-month Henry Hub strip gained 1.8 cents to $2.102. NYMEX said 28,284 Henry Hub contracts traded, up from Tuesday's revised tally of 38,162.</p>
<p>NYMEX October Henry Hub natgas expires Tuesday, Sept 24.</p>
<p>NYMEX October Permian natgas closed unchanged at $1.65, while deferreds settled 1.5 to three cents higher. NYMEX said 29 Permian contracts traded versus 41 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>NYMEX October Permian natgas expires Thursday, Sept 26.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, October finished five cents higher at $1.77, while deferreds ended up by 3.6 to eight cents. The East/West spread narrowed by 1.6 cents to 19.8 cents (NYMEX premium). KCBT said 140 lots traded, down from Tuesday's total of 244.</p>
<p>KCBT October natgas expires Wednesday, Sept 25.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
