<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="604491" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBS to launch seven new prime time shows.</title>
<headline>CBS to launch seven new prime time shows.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Westinghouse Electric Corp's CBS television unit said Thursday it would launch seven new prime time shows this fall, including three comedies, three dramas and a news magazine.</p>
<p>Leslie Moonves, president of CBS Entertainment, told reporters at a breakfast meeting that the network was also rejigging its schedule by moving ratings powerhouse &quot;Murphy Brown,&quot; and &quot;Chicago Hope&quot; to Wednesday evening from Monday.</p>
<p>The two programs will sandwhich the new Bryant Gumbel news program, which will air at 2100 ET. Gumbel, who was a longtime host on General Electric Co's NBC &quot;Today Show&quot;, signed a contract with CBS earlier this year.</p>
<p>Moonves and other CBS executives were scheduled to formally unveil the new lineup to advertisers at Carnegie Hall Thursday afternoon.  </p>
<p>Among the new programs filling the Monday schedule, &quot;George and Leo,&quot; starring veteran comedic actor Bob Newhart, will air at 2130 ET, followed by &quot;Brooklyn South,&quot; a new police drama produced by Steven Bochco, at 2200 ET.</p>
<p>CBS decided to counter-program against NBC's powerhouse Thursday night lineup, which includes &quot;Seinfeld,&quot; &quot;ER,&quot; and &quot;Friends,&quot; by aiming for older viewers.</p>
<p>The network will move the drama, &quot;Promised Land&quot; to Thursday at 2000 ET from Tuesday and change the Thursday time for drama &quot;Diagnosis Murder&quot; an hour later to 2100 ET.  </p>
<p>The network will go head to head against Walt Disney Co ABC Television's TGIF Friday sitcom programming aimed at younger and family audiences by picking up two former ABC sitcoms, &quot;Family Matters,&quot; and &quot;Step by Step.&quot;</p>
<p>CBS will premiere two other comedies on Friday: &quot;Meego,&quot; which stars Bronson Pinchot as an alien, and &quot;The Gregory Hines Show,&quot; with the actor playing a widower with a 12-year old son.</p>
<p>&quot;Cosby&quot; and &quot;Cybill&quot; will stay on Mondays, although both shows will get tuneups. Moonves said that the Bill Cosby program will get a five year-old character, a neighbor.  </p>
<p>While he did not disclose any specifics, he said the network was in discussions with the show's producers about changes for the Cybill Shepherd sitcom.</p>
<p>Moonves said one of the network's toughest decisions was over the fate of &quot;Ink,&quot; which was ultimately dropped. The sitcom, which aired Monday, starred Ted Danson, of &quot;Cheers&quot; fame, and his real-life wife, actress Mary Steenburgen.</p>
<p>Moonves said he personally called the couple with the news of the cancellation, and told reporters CBS may bring one or both of them back on another series.  </p>
<p>Moonves said the network's goal this year was to attract more younger viewers, the favorite targets of advertisers, as well as a larger urban audience.</p>
<p>&quot;To take advantage of our ratings momentum and position the network for further growth, we need to expand our audience base,&quot; Moonves said. &quot;Therefore, we are introducing some exciting new programs and acquiring two already successful series that will attract a younger and more urban audience, yet still appeal to our loyal CBS viewers.&quot;  </p>
<p>Moonves said both the number of households watching and total viewers for the network rose eight percent in the U.S. this season.</p>
<p>In answer to a question, he said he felt &quot;a lot safer&quot; unveiling seven new shows for the coming season, compared to 10 last autumn. Last fall all the networks unloaded a record number of new prgrams on viewers.</p>
<p>Responding to another question, Moonves said too many sitcoms were going to hit the air this autumn. He joked to reporters that they should encourage their children to become comedy writers because of all the work available.</p>
<p>Aside from the four major networks, both Chris-Craft Industries Inc's United Paramount Network and Time Warner Inc's WB network were offering programs on four nights.</p>
<p>((--Jeff Benkoe, 212-859-1735))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
