<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="604512" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ATHLETICS-U.S. OFFICIALS HOPING SAGGING SPORT WILL BOUNCE BACK.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-U.S. OFFICIALS HOPING SAGGING SPORT WILL BOUNCE BACK.</headline>
<byline>Gene Cherry</byline>
<dateline>RALEIGH, North Carolina 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>On an evening when Michael Johnson was expected to regenerate America's flagging interest in track and field, only the wind blew through a deserted San Jose stadium.</p>
<p>The Californian venue, which launched the grand prix series 12 years ago, was empty last Sunday after organisers were forced to cancel the annual meeting through lack of financial support.</p>
<p>Only months after spectators packed the 80,000-seat Atlanta Olympic Stadium, athletics is ailing in the United States.</p>
<p>Two of the three U.S. grand prix have been cancelled, indoor competitions have been called off and the national governing body is struggling financially.</p>
<p>Even a new athletics chief is needed.</p>
<p>Ollan Cassell, an International Amateur Athletic Federation vice-president, will surrender his post as USA Track &amp; Field's (USATF) executive director in March, booted out of office by an unhappy majority of the sport's leaders, many of whom blame Cassell for its demise.</p>
<p>A committee will meet this weekend near the  San Jose stadium to interview finalists for the job and Cassell's replacement could be announced in June.</p>
<p>It is a reversal of course that could not come too soon for some.</p>
<p>&quot;For 20-some years we had someone who could not communicate, who had no sense of marketing and a great sense of how to survive,&quot; said Atlanta Track Club executive director Julia Emmons. &quot;Ollan just didn't have any vision.&quot;</p>
<p>Nike marketing executive Steve Miller spread the blame more broadly.</p>
<p>&quot;For all of our medals, for all of our successes, and all of the things that we point to with a great deal of pride, what we have forgotten are the hundreds of thousands of kids that have not run track because we have not marketed the sport correctly,&quot; Miller said from his Tokyo office.</p>
<p>&quot;There are thousands of kids who could have been great track and field athletes who we have not reached.&quot;</p>
<p>Miller, a former college coach, has indicated he was not be a candidate for Cassell's job, despite rumours to the contrary. He said if he talks to the search committee, &quot;it will not be an interview, but my point of view.&quot;</p>
<p>And views, he has. The sport has suffered, Miller said, because of its inability to take advantage of two Olympics in the United States in the last two decades and had been hurt by failure to land healthy television contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going head-to-head with the NBA, Major League Baseball and the NFL, and we have to be able to negotiate and play in those arenas,&quot; he noted.</p>
<p>&quot;If you can't you're going to lose out every time.&quot;</p>
<p>The sport has survived in the United States despite itself, Miller and others said. One reason is the unique collegiate system that has produced hundreds of international performers although there have been problems there too.</p>
<p>Financial cutbacks have forced universities to reduce the number of scholarships offered in the sport. And at the youth level, more and more parents, tired of sitting through 10-hour meetings, are pushing their children toward other sports that offer big bucks to top professionals or at least can be completed in a few hours' time.</p>
<p>&quot;The structure is boring,&quot; said Joe Douglas, the long time business manager for nine times Olympic gold medallist Carl Lewis. &quot;Elite track and field has to be streamlined.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States does not have even one quality meet, not even one, and hasn't had for years besides the Olympic Games and maybe the Goodwill Games in 1990. We've never had a meet such as Zurich. You can't conduct a second-class show and expect a first-class audience.&quot;</p>
<p>Interviewees called for more innovations, such as the highly publicised Johnson-Donovan Bailey duel over 150 metres in Toronto on June 1.</p>
<p>&quot;It happens every time,&quot; Johnson said. &quot;After the Olympics are over, track and field isn't new and exciting any more. It's the same old track and field. It's not something that people can be excited about. It's the same track and field that was being run back in 1940, maybe even 1930.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody's just kind of sitting back. They're not looking at the crisis and saying something's got to change.&quot;</p>
<p>Johnson said if promoters were willing to be more inventive, more sponsors, more athletes and more television coverage would emerge.</p>
<p>Not everyone preaches doom and gloom.</p>
<p>&quot;I see blue skies ahead for the sport,&quot; said Ed Fox, publisher of the prestigious Track &amp; Field Magazine.</p>
<p>Former international miler Craig Masback, an acknowledged candidate for Cassell's job, and Bob Hersh, USATF's legal counsel, were also upbeat.</p>
<p>&quot;The organisation has finally realised that it has to do things differently,&quot; Masback said. &quot;It's been steering a single course for 30 years and it's turned the boat around. And whoever the new captain is, is going to take us in that new direction.</p>
<p>&quot;To focus on losing a meet here or there is irrelevant. There may be more bad news. But we will be better.&quot;</p>
<p>Hersh said new leadership would provide new opportunities for sponsorship and growth.</p>
<p>Bert Bonanno, promoter of the San Jose meeting which finally collapsed after years of struggling, said there was no doubt that Cassell's lame-duck status had hurt his quest for sponsors.</p>
<p>As for companies such as international shoe and clothing giant Nike, the degree of assistance to the sport in the United States would depend on the goals and abilities of the sport's new U.S. leader, Miller said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are always going to be involved,&quot; he said. &quot;What level we are going to be involved is a different thing.</p>
<p>&quot;If someone could show us a plan, if someone could revive the sport, it would be a dream come true for all of us.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RALEIGH, North Carolina"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
