<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="604687" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK refers two National Express deals to MMC.</title>
<headline>UK refers two National Express deals to MMC.</headline>
<byline>Mike Elliott</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The British government on Thursday referred transport operator National Express Group Plc's planned purchase of regional ScotRail rail network to the Monopolies and Mergers Commission (MMC).</p>
<p>The new Trade and Industry Secretary, Margaret Beckett, also referred its planned acquisition of the Central Trains Ltd rail franchise in the West Midlands to the MMC for investigation.</p>
<p>National Express, which only moved into rail services last year and now one of Britain's largest rail and bus operators, had no immediate comment. It has won five of 25 passenger franchises awarded since the controversial privatisation of the national rail grid began in 1995.</p>
<p>It was awarded the ScotRail franchise -- which provides most of the passenger rail services in Scotland -- in February and said it would receive an average annual subsidy of 237.5 million pounds ($390.7 million) for the seven-year franchise.</p>
<p>Shares in National Express, down around five pence before the announcement, fell on the news to 490-1/2 pence, off 28-1/2.</p>
<p>&quot;I consider that the acquisition by National Express of ScotRail raises competition concerns in the market for the supply of public transport passenger services in Scotland,&quot; Beckett said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Separately, I consider that the acquisition by National Express of Central Trains raises competition concerns in the supply of public transport services in the West Midlands region,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The MMC have to make their reports by September 19.</p>
<p>As well as ScotRail and Central Trains, National Express has also been awarded the North London Railways, the Gatwick Express and Midland Mainline franchises.</p>
<p>Earlier, National Express said it was confident of meeting regulators' targets to extend its Midland Mainline franchise.</p>
<p>To help cope with the line's increasing passenger levels, it has ordered 38 million pounds worth of rolling stock from Adtranz -- a joint venture between Germany's Daimler-Benz AG and Swiss-Swedish engineering group ABB AG.</p>
<p>&quot;I would be very disappointed if passenger levels didn't rise by 50 percent or more over the next seven years,&quot; Richard Brown, managing director of its train division, told a news conference.</p>
<p>With this investment Brown said the company was &quot;more than meeting&quot; conditions that would allow National Express to extend the franchise to 10 years from seven.</p>
<p>While railway service levels have come under more scrutiny, OPRAF officials were pleased with Midland Mainline.</p>
<p>&quot;The signals we're getting are that National Express is well on target to providing the services they're committed to,&quot; OPRAF franchise manager Cedric Pierce told the news conference.</p>
<p>Britain's railway services have been under growing scrutiny.</p>
<p>The new Labour Government earlier this month called on the rail watchdog to look into ways of beefing up his powers in clamping down on errant train operators.</p>
<p>This was partly in response to a poor performance by South West Trains, a unit of Stagecoach Holdings Plc, which had to cancel trains earlier this year after axing too many drivers in its post-privatisation restructuring.</p>
<p>South West Trains escaped a one million pound fine and possible loss of its franchise, but remains under probation. ($ = 0.607 British Pounds)</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 4365</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I72102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
