<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="604696" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Brent up on paper market, physical.</title>
<headline>Brent up on paper market, physical.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brent rose on the paper market on Thursday with firm intermonth spreads and outright levels and the benchmark North Sea crude seemed stronger on the physical side also, traders said.</p>
<p>There was unconfirmed talk of an early June cargo of Brent sold at July Brent -2 cents, eight cents higher than a deal for a June 5-7 loader of the benchmark crude on Wednesday. On the cash market, July Brent was trading 18 cents a barrel higher at $20.31, just three cents off the day's high reached after New York's WTI contract opened higher than expected. A Brent August paper contract traded once at $20.31, compared with $20.11 a similar contract fetched on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In an active physical market in other North Sea grades, Norwegian grades were steady to a shade easier. A June 10-12 cargo of Statfjord was sold at Dated Brent +31 cents, the same level an end May cargo fetched a day earlier.</p>
<p>A trading house was also reported to have bought a June 6 Ekofisk, with talk of the price in the Dated Brent +10/+13 cents region, and there was unconfirmed talk of a June 5 loader sold at about the same level. &quot;It (Ekofisk) is coming off a bit, it is only Brent that is really strong, the rest of the grades are struggling a bit,&quot; the seller of the Statfjord said. He said Brent's strength was coming from shipments out of the area.</p>
<p>Brent's gains of some $2.50 a barrel since the start of May have caused refinery runs to worsen.</p>
<p>Traders said on Thursday afternoon that British Petroleum cut refinery runs at its Rotterdam refinery by 40 percent from midnight on Wednesday due to poor margins.</p>
<p>They said BP, which controls 65 percent of 400,000 bpd Rotterdam Nerefco refinery, had cut runs by the equivalent of 10 percent for the month of May, which translated into a 40 percent cut for the balance of May.</p>
<p>Last week, Texaco cut crude runs at the refinery by the equivalent of 20 percent for the second half of May.</p>
<p>But other ARA refiners were holding back from cutting runs on Thursday, traders said. Prompt Brent Contracts for Difference (CFDs) strengthened further with May 27-30 traded once at July Brent flat after earlier trades at a seven cents discount to July Brent.</p>
<p>But next week's CFD eased some seven cents to trade at July Brent -15 in the afternoon while Jun 9-13 was offered two cents weaker at July Brent -12 cents. Brent intermonth spreads rose in late talk with June July talked +7/+10 after trading at +6 cents in the afternoon, just one cent off an earlier trade. Jul/Sep traded four times at +3 cents.</p>
<p>Jul/Aug and A/S eached gained one to two cents in late talk to +1/+3 cents and 0/+2 cents. The single Brent cargo turning wet on Thursday was kept by Suko ahead of the five o'clock deadline, traders said. The cargo is due to load in the June 6-8 period. In the Mediterranean Russian Urals was still pressured, with late May barrels talked in the Dated Brent -$1.45 region and early June barrels some 10 cens firmer.</p>
<p>A cargo of Urals loading May 27-29 changed hands at Dated Brent -$1.42 on Wednesday, four cents adrift from the value achieved for a distressed parcel a day earlier. Traders were seeking information about the fate of a Urals offered on the water at around Dated Brent -$1.40.</p>
<p>&quot;We see potential buyer interest for early June barrels at (Dated Brent) - $1.35 but seller are not there at that price so nothing is happening. It is a quiet day,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Traders earlier said they had no word on the status of the loading on May 25 of a one million barrel cargo of Iraqi Kirkuk at Turkey's Ceyhan port. Some traders said they doubted there would be any cancellations of Kirkuk liftings under Baghdad's $2 billion &quot;oil-for-food&quot; deal with the United Nations but said there could be some delays.</p>
<p>&quot;There could be some delay, resulting from administrative reasons but I don't see any big problems, probably no cancellations (of liftings),&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>A senior U.N. official said on Thursday that a rollover of the oil-for-food plan for Iraq is a &quot;foregone conclusion&quot; presumably at the current $2 billion level.</p>
<p>Yasushi Akashi, undersecretary-general for humanitarian affairs, told reporters that renewal of the plan was virtually assured at current sales levels.</p>
<p>A senior U.N. official told Reuters on Wednesday that U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan was expected to recommend by the end of the month that the deal be renewed in June on the same terms as the present six-month plan. The West African market was quiet, still absorbing Nigeria's Official Selling Price issued late on Tuesday, with traders saying that the higher numbers have disappointed some market players. --Haitham Haddadin, London newsroom +44 171 542 8145</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
