<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="604616" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: FOCUS-HUNGARY STRATEGY EYES GDP AND CPI TOGETHER.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-HUNGARY STRATEGY EYES GDP AND CPI TOGETHER.</headline>
<byline>Sandor Peto</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A strategic plan approved by Hungary on Thursday to cut inflation to 13 to 14 percent in 1998 was the less radical of alternatives as Hungary eyes EU membership and economic growth, the government said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government had to reconcile its ideas about inflation with the ideas about economic growth,&quot; Finance Minister Peter Medgyessy told a news conference following the government's meeting which approved economic priorities for the period reaching to 2000.</p>
<p>Medgyessy said the decision on inflation followed a sharp debate although the economic cabinet -- an inter-ministerial body preparing economic decisions -- had put only one formal proposal on the table.</p>
<p>&quot;The discussion was about economic policy directions, not figures,&quot; Medgyessy told a news conference following the government meeting.</p>
<p>The programme approved does not represent a significant change in the previous inflation forecast figures, which projected a cut of about five percent for 1997 and 1998.</p>
<p>Under the plan, Hungary would reduce average inflation to 13 to 14 percent in 1998 from a forecast 18 percent this year and December year-on-year CPI would fall to 11 to 12 percent in 1998 from a projected 16 to 17 percent in 1997, Medgyessy said.</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) earlier this year urged Hungary for a more radical cut in inflation in 1998.</p>
<p>Medgyessy said the government had to consider that for the short term a radical cut could cool Hungary's increasing economic growth, which is a main priority of the government's strategy along with preserving economic stability.</p>
<p>Hungary targets two to three percent gross domestic product (GDP) growth for 1997, up from some one percent in 1996.</p>
<p>According to the three-year economic priorities, the GDP would rise by three to four percent in 1998, and the growth rate would stabilise at about four percent in 1999 and 2000.</p>
<p>Economic growth is important for Hungary, as the country plans to join the European Union after 2000 and it must take efforts to catch up with the developed countries of the West, the minister said.</p>
<p>Growth would also ensure living standards improvement for Hungarians who suffered a slump in real wages following the introduction of a strict austerity programme in 1995, which reduced the soaring current account and budget deficit.</p>
<p>Real incomes are likely to rise by one to two percent in 1997, and by two to three percent in the subsequent three years, at a rising pace, while household savings are expected to preserve the current level in real terms, Medgyessy said.</p>
<p>However, Hungary does not plan to propel economic activity mainly by boosting household consumption, which would increase at an annual rate of two to three percent from 1998, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Growth would be oriented mainly by rising exports and investments,&quot; he said, adding that investments were seen rising by 10 to 12 percent in real terms annually in the next three years.</p>
<p>Total corporate resources for investments would rise to 900 billion forints in 1997 from 640 billion in 1996, and to 1,750 to 1,800 billion forints by 2000, Medgyessy said.</p>
<p>Along with increasing economic performance, the unemployment rate should fall to below 10 percent by 2000 from 11.4 percent.</p>
<p>Monetary policies should allow interest rates to drop in case of substantial money oversupply in the market, but caution will remain justified in protection of savings and capital inflow, he said.</p>
<p>Medgyessy added that according to the anti-inflation plan, Hungary is likely to consider if its current energy price formula, which generates inflation, could be revised.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
