<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="604984" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: INSTANT VIEW - Bulgaria Q1 industrial output.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - Bulgaria Q1 industrial output.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are analysts' comments on the 15.4 percent fall in Bulgarian first quarter industrial output.</p>
<p>GALINA DIMITROVA, ECONOMIST, BULGARIAN INVESTMENT BANK - This is not surprising as the first three months were crucial due to the political uncertainty, plummeting currency, soaring inflation and high rates. Contraction of the economy is a natural reaction, the downturn will continue by inertia. We can expect some stabilisation by year-end. @</p>
<p>CHARLES ROBERTSON, EAST EUROPEAN ANALYST, HILFE INDEPENDENT ECONOMIC AND POLITICAL ANALYSIS COMPANY - The factors of restructuring and closing loss-making firms will ensure that industrial output over the year will show a decline, which we estimated at five percent. Towards the end of the year there might be some scope for improvement in year-on-year terms. The lev stability over the last two months would support exports which would lead to improvement in some sectors of industry. @</p>
<p>ALEXANDER BEBOV, EAST EUROPEAN STRATEGIST, JP MORGAN - I think industrial decline has reached its bottom. This is certainly the result of continuing depressiion in 1996 and the UDF victory would not have helped improve the results yet. The very high interest rates precluded crediting possibilities to any industrial enterprises. We should expect industrial output to continue falling at a slower pace and gradualy recover in 1998. -- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-981-4145</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
