<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="605048" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Speculators renew battle with Czech cbank on crown.</title>
<headline>Speculators renew battle with Czech cbank on crown.</headline>
<byline>Alan Crosby</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Speculators renewed their battle with the Czech central bank (CNB) on Thursday, pushing the crown to an all-time low before a wave of CNB market intervention came to the currency's rescue.</p>
<p>The crown, which has been under pressure for over a week, opened steady at about 2.7 percent on the depreication side of its dollar/mark basket midpoint.</p>
<p>But speculators in London moved in soon afterward, pushing the crown to a record low of -6.4 against basket parity, forcing the central bank to step into the market directly for the third time in a week.</p>
<p>&quot;They're in the market, and they are using large volumes,&quot; said Petr Korous of Ceskosolvenska Obchodni Banka.</p>
<p>Other dealers said the CNB had also been intervening in London by dealing directly with some foreign banks there.</p>
<p>&quot;It's (the intervention) unsustainable and...I think that they (speculators) will really now at these levels push it over the band,&quot; said Petr Kuklis, a dealer of Girocredit in Prague.</p>
<p>The market steadied after the intervention at about -4.5 percent below parity, and the central bank followed up with a one-week repo tender to drain funds from the market at 75 percent, after Wednesday's rate of 56.63 percent.</p>
<p>The CNB has been waging a war against investors to keep the crown from crashing since last week when a wave of short-selling pushed the currency to more than five percent below the mid-point of the dollar/mark basket, which the central bank uses to fix the crown's exchange rate daily.</p>
<p>Central bank and government officials to date have adamantly ruled out a devaluation of the currency.</p>
<p>Last Friday the CNB raised the Lombard rate from 14 percent to 50 percent in a move bolster the crown, once regarded as the most stable currency in post-communist central Europe.</p>
<p>The CNB through the course of the week has gradually restricted access to the Lombard facility, the last resort lending facility for banks, squeezing market liquidity and further boosting the crown.</p>
<p>CNB officials have not revealed the limits it has set, but CNB board member Ludek Niedermeyer said on Wednesday: &quot;We will react in order to stabilise the currency, so we are willing to cut it (access) to...zero.&quot;</p>
<p>The Czech Republic under economist Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus used to be praised in the West as a model for post-communist reform.</p>
<p>While the CNB has kept inflation in single figures, a soaring current account deficit raised concerns about the Czech economy and the government has slashed earlier forecasts of robust GDP growth.</p>
<p>The central bank fixed the crown at 30.359 to the dollar and 17.971 to the mark on Wednesday, implying a deviation against basket parity of - 2.27 percent after a fixing of 2.78 percent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 420-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
