<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="605284" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: NBT says don't know why stock active.</title>
<headline>NBT says don't know why stock active.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Borneo Timbers Bhd (NBT) said on Thursday it was not aware of any market rumour which has caused recent heavy trading in its stock.</p>
<p>In a letter to the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange, NBT said, &quot;the directors wish to inform the exchange that they are not aware of any rumours that might have caused the recent increase in the company's share price and heavy turnover.&quot;</p>
<p>NBT stock on Thursday jumped 8.50 ringgit to hit a 12-month high of 34.0 on heavy volume of 12.2 million shares traded.</p>
<p>It had surged 2.80 on Tuesday. The market was closed on Wednesday for a religious holiday.</p>
<p>NBT said it believed that the market is reacting to the improvement in company prospects following its recent public announcements.</p>
<p>The commodities and timber firm said there was no material development in its business and affairs to affect the stock's price except a proposal to sell its stake in a timber firm.</p>
<p>NBT said on Tuesday it was proposing not to proceed with an earlier plan to list Sabah Softwoods Sdn Bhd, and will instead sell its stake in the timber firm for 150 million ringgit.</p>
<p>It said the proposal to sell 40-percent-owned Softwoods would result in an extraordinary gain of 87.44 million ringgit &quot;upon completion of the proposal&quot;.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
