<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="605390" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: MOF agrees with BOJ low interest rate policy - Ogawa.</title>
<headline>MOF agrees with BOJ low interest rate policy - Ogawa.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Ministry of Finance (MOF) agrees with the Bank of Japan's (BOJ) low interest rate policy, Vice Finance Minister Tadashi Ogawa said on Thursday.  </p>
<p>Ogawa said he agrees with BOJ Governor Yasuo Matsushita's repeated remarks that the central bank's monetary policy is aimed at strengthening the basis for Japan's economic recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;We think that (the BOJ policy) is exactly right,&quot; Ogawa said.</p>
<p>Ogawa said it was important to the Japanese economy for exchange rates to be stable, adding that concerns since the beginning of April over an excessively weak yen had completely disappeared.</p>
<p>He declined to comment when asked what he thought about the present exchange rate. The yen stood at around 116 yen per dollar in late Tokyo trade.</p>
<p>Asked whether he thought recent movements in exchange rates were triggered by comments from ministry officials, Ogawa said the ministry and its officials would continue to make statements on their understanding of the situation surrounding the foreign exchange market.  </p>
<p>Ogawa said he could not comment on suspected illegal activities by Dai-Ichi Kangyo Bank Ltd (DKB), as the bank was still being investigated by authorities.</p>
<p>But he said: &quot;It is extremely regrettable when a bank, which serves the public and has responsibilities to society, becomes a problem.&quot;</p>
<p>He declined comment on media reports that Yamaichi Securities Co Ltd had stopped providing support to ailing Ogawa Securities Co, one of its affiliates.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
