<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="605324" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Asia needs political commitment to fight AIDS.</title>
<headline>Asia needs political commitment to fight AIDS.</headline>
<byline>Sutin Wannabovorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Delegates from Asian countries on Thursday called on their governments to give priority to the prevention of AIDS and the virus that causes it before the deadly disease reaches epidemic proportions.</p>
<p>Representatives from China, Cambodia, Indonesia, Malaysia, Burma, Thailand and Vietnam who participated in a United Nations workshop here urged their governments to give priority and pay more attention to preventing the disease.</p>
<p>&quot;What we accomplished is for the countries in Asia to know about the successes of Thailand,&quot; Werasit Sittitrai, coordinator of policy strategy and research for UNAIDS, told reporters after the workshop. &quot;We (want) to have each country go back and mobilise more political support.&quot;</p>
<p>He said there were about three million people with HIV -- the virus that causes AIDS -- in Asia, and that should increase by one to two million by the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;But if there was no prevention effort going then the figure could be two to five million more,&quot; he said, urging governments to join in a political commitment to fight against AIDS.</p>
<p>UNAIDS officials pointed to Thailand as a success story in terms of trying to prevent the further spread of AIDS, because many people have changed sexual habits and now use condoms.</p>
<p>Statistics compiled from a group of 600,000 people in Thailand show condom usage has grown to nearly 100 percent this year, from about 30 percent in 1993. Data also shows the number of Thais visiting brothels has dropped by 50 percent since 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;The change of the sex behaviour in Thailand has made it a great sucesses,&quot; said Dr Peter Way of the International Programs Centre of the U.S. Bureau of the Census.</p>
<p>He said that in 1991, when he joined a team to promote condom usage in Thailand, he had projected that by the year 2000, between two and four million people in Thailand would be infected with HIV.</p>
<p>&quot;The success of the campaign made my projection wrong. Currently the estimation of HIV cases in Thailand is about 800,000 and by the year 2000 it will be around 900,000 to one million,&quot; Way said.</p>
<p>But in mainly Moslem Indonesia, the word condom is a sensitive term, and experts predicted an AIDS/HIV epidemic by the turn of the century if the prevention program was not improved.</p>
<p>Dr Irwanto (one name) said although there are only about 300 HIV cases officially recorded in Indonesia, his estimates show more than 100,000 people are infected with the virus. If prevention programmes are not successful the number could leap to 2.5 million by the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;Comdom is a sensitive word for our country. Our government does not totally prohibit using condoms but we allow people at risk to buy condoms on their own,&quot; he said. &quot;Commercial sex is common in Indonesia, like other countries.&quot;</p>
<p>Experts from other countries such as Burma, Cambodia and Vietnam said their governments had begun condom distribution programs but they were aimed mainly at the high-risk population.</p>
<p>HIV is spread through the exchange of bodily fluids. In most parts of Asia the disease is passed on through heterosexual contact, or through intravenous drug use with infected needles.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
