<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="605306" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Wharf restates 1996 net to HK$2.24 bln.</title>
<headline>Wharf restates 1996 net to HK$2.24 bln.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wharf Holdings Ltd said on Thursday it had restated its 1996 net profit to HK$2.24 billion from the HK$2.74 billion figure announced on March 21.</p>
<p>Wharf said in a statement it was making a general provision of HK$500 million &quot;in respect of the relevant contingencies as well as legal fees incurred which may not be recoverable&quot; from two court cases the company is planning to appeal.  </p>
<p>Wharf said that there had been significant developments in two court cases in which the group was involved since the March 21 announcement of results for the year ended December 31, 1996.</p>
<p>Former subsidiary Wheelock Marden and Co Ltd would appeal against a Hong Kong court decision against it on the basis of positive legal advice, Wharf said. The decision awarded about HK$225 million plus interest to Danish finance institution ADS.</p>
<p>Wharf also said it intended to contest a US$125.5 million Denver federal district court verdict against it in favour of United International Holdings Inc, once the judgement order was issued.</p>
<p>&quot;Having carefully considered the implications and legal advice and, in respect of the case in the U.S.A., without admitting any ultimate liability, the directors now consider it prudent to make in the accounts of the group for the year ended 31st December 1996 a general provision in the sum of HK$500 million in respect of the relevant contingencies as well as legal fees incurred which may not be recoverable,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;The making of such a provision has resulted in a restatement of the group's profit figures as originally announced on 21st March 1997,&quot; the company said.  </p>
<p>The results are restated as follows:</p>
<p>Year ended December 31 (in million HK$ unless stated)</p>
<p>    Shr (H.K. cents)	   100.0*	 vs   166.0</p>
<p>    Dividend (H.K. cents)     84.0	  vs    81.0</p>
<p>    Exceptional items	  342.2** loss vs 1,510.2 gain</p>
<p>    Net			  2,238.5***     vs 3,604.8</p>
<p>    Turnover		   8,404.5	  vs 6,769.6</p>
<p>    Company name	     Wharf (Holdings) Ltd</p>
<p>NOTE - Wharf is a holding company for property, hotel, transport and warehouse businesses.</p>
<p>Total dividend for year is 110 H.K. cents (including interim dividend of 26 cents) vs 105 cents.</p>
<p>The exceptional item represents gain of HK$157.8 million from from the sale of subsidiaries and certain investment properties and loss of HK$500 million from provision for litigation cases.</p>
<p>* Share earnings were originally stated as 123.0 H.K. cents in the March results announcement.</p>
<p>** Exeptional item was originally stated as gain of HK$157.8 million in the March results announcement.</p>
<p>*** Net was was originally stated as HK$2,738.5 million gain in the March results announcement.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6368</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
