<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="605393" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: FORECAST - Japan Apr output seen rising slightly.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Japan Apr output seen rising slightly.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's industrial output for April is expected to be flat or slightly higher than March, remaining firm as the effects of the April 1 tax rise would not yet to be reflected, economists said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters forecast rises ranging from 0.3 percent to 1.5 percent in April output, compared with a month-on-month drop of 0.3 percent in March.</p>
<p>The Trade Ministry expects major manufacturers' output to show a 0.3 percent rise in April.</p>
<p>Industrial output data for April and forecasts for May and June will be released on May 29 at 1.30 p.m. (0430 GMT).</p>
<p>&quot;The (output) figure will show that production continues to be firm. There are some left-over orders for car production from the period before the tax rise, so that will give support,&quot; said Osamu Katano, an economist at Nikko Research Center.</p>
<p>Japan raised its national consumption tax to five percent from three percent on April 1, and consumption is widely expected to have dropped following the move.</p>
<p>But economists also said the weak yen led to strong exports and supported production.</p>
<p>&quot;In April, the yen was still relatively weak and exports were strong. All in all, production is firm so we can expect it to be flat for April,&quot; said Yasuo Yamamoto, an economist with Sanwa Research Institute.</p>
<p>An economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell also said strong car exports in April lifted production.</p>
<p>But economists said the outlook for production may not be as rosy as the tax rise begins to take its toll.</p>
<p>&quot;From May onward, there may be a decrease in production due to the effects of the rise in the consumption tax,&quot; said Nikko Research's Katano.</p>
<p>The following is a breakdown of economists' forecasts for April:</p>
<p>				   mth/mth	     yr/yr</p>
<p> NIKKO RESEARCH CENTER     +0.3 pct	    +5.6 pct</p>
<p> HSBC JAMES CAPEL	    +0.3 pct	    +5.7 pct</p>
<p> DEUTSCHE MORGAN GRENFELL  +0.4 pct	    +5.7 pct</p>
<p> SANWA RESEARCH		+0.5 pct	    +5.8 pct</p>
<p> MERRILL LYNCH		 +0.5 pct	    n/a</p>
<p> LEHMAN BROTHERS	     +0.7 pct	    +6.0 pct</p>
<p> DAIWA BANK RESEARCH	 +1.0 pct	    +6.3 pct</p>
<p> INDUSTRIAL BANK OF JAPAN  +1.5 pct	    +6.3 pct</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Policy Desk +81-3-5473-3710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
