<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="605550" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BankAmerica says Hawaii is problem area.</title>
<headline>BankAmerica says Hawaii is problem area.</headline>
<byline>Sue Zeidler</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>BankAmerica Corp chief executive David Coulter, who has sold several underperforming units this past year, said Hawaiian operations are a problem.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking at all our major businesses. If they're not earning the hurdle rate, our first knee-jerk reaction is to try to fix it,&quot; Coulter said in a briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a few fixes going on and they've been pretty successful. Hawaii's been a problem we've tried to fix. We've resisted putting a sign (out) saying we're selling the units, but we have to do something about the units on this list.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman said BankAmerica has about 40 branches in Hawaii.</p>
<p>BankAmerica has previously said it expects to sell its consumer finance unit by the third quarter, 68 retail branches in Texas, 120 retail branches in California.</p>
<p>It is eliminating about 3,700 positions out of 92,000 employees companywide. It is also overhauling several overseas operations.</p>
<p>Coulter cited strong performance due to a focus on fundamentals and top-line revenue growth in businesses that return more than their cost of capital.  </p>
<p>Coulter reiterated that BankAmerica's exposure to lawsuits filed by San Francisco and the California, alleging misconduct in municipal bond dealings, are immaterial.</p>
<p>The state is seeking hundreds of millions of dollars and San Francisco is seeking over $12 million.</p>
<p>Coulter said the bank discovered errors on its own and made refunds and tried to get the state and city to agree to a third party audit and to pay each any additional claims.</p>
<p>&quot;But the city will not agree and insisted it wanted to proceed with litigation. We're still hopeful we can proceed with a third party audit with the state,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Coulter said he did not know whether other municipalities would participate in the lawsuit.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't tell you there. The state has taken over the suit for all municipalities other than the city of San Francisco and other municipalities will be happy to have the state representing them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He cited concerns about BankAmerica's image. &quot;It strikes at the reputation of BankAmerica. We've been in communciaiton with our municipal customers in the past few weeks. If I'm concerned personally about any aspect of the litigation...it strikes at the reputation and that concerns me.&quot;  </p>
<p>Looking ahead, Coulter said one area of interest to BankAmerica is information technology.</p>
<p>&quot;We might decide to form a new company or a whole range of things but right now its very speculative,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
