<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="605669" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Georgia to gain from economic diversification.</title>
<headline>Georgia to gain from economic diversification.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Georgia's economy is among the healthiest in the nation and will benefit from diversification over the next decade, according to a DRI/McGraw-Hill report Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The South has attracted a diverse set of industries and its economy is evolving from an agrarian-based one of the not-so-distant past. As a result, Georgia's economy is less volatile than other states and is outperforming national economic growth since the recovery began six years ago,&quot; said Sara Johnson, chief regional economist for the forecasting and consulting service.</p>
<p>Payroll employment in Georgia should see modest gains in 1997 with 81,000 new jobs created, particularly among business and professional services, the report said.</p>
<p>The Olympics provided a tourism boost across Georgia that should continue, it said.</p>
<p>Although construction will not regain its pre-Olympics payroll levels any time soon, the infrastructure improvements stemming from Atlanta's hosting of the games left a positive residual effect, the report said.</p>
<p>Employment in Georgia's manufacturing sector posted a 0.04 percent decline in 1996, most of which is attributed to the nondurables sector, especially apparel.</p>
<p>But the outlook for the state's textile industry is not all bad, the report said. Shaw Industries, headquartered in Dalton, Ga., plans to open a new manufacturing and distribution facility this year, which should add about 800 jobs, the report said.</p>
<p>Georgia's employment total is expected to rise by 2.3 percent in 1997, moderate by year-ago standards.</p>
<p>&quot;Georgia's service sector, which accounts for more than 25 percent of the state's employment base, experienced the biggest job gains last year with exceptionally strong growth in the state's amusements and recreation sectors,&quot; Johnson said.</p>
<p>Two other developments should boost the state's economy in 1997, the report said. One of the nation's largest credit-card processors is expected to build a $100 million corporate campus in Columbus and Atlanta-based ValuJet Inc is expected to rebuild its airline operations, which should add 1,250 new jobs, the report said.</p>
<p>((--Jane Sutton, 305-374-5013))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
