<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="605714" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Conn. seen hurt by electric uncertainties.</title>
<headline>Conn. seen hurt by electric uncertainties.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Lewis</byline>
<dateline>HARTFORD 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Connecticut's failure to pass an electric industry restructuring bill this year is bad news for the state's near-term economic future, analysts said Thursday.</p>
<p>It is also bad news for the share prices of the state's two main power suppliers, Northeast Utilities and United Illuminating Co, which are likely to remain depressed until the uncertainty over deregulation is put to rest, they added.</p>
<p>Connecticut, whose power prices are among the highest in the nation, has grappled with deregulation for two years.</p>
<p>House bill 6774, which called for a 10 percent rate cut and opening of the electric industry beginning in 1999, died on Wednesday with the Senate's surprise decision to drop it.</p>
<p>One of the bill's main backers, Sen. Melodie Peters, a Democrat, said she was worried that the proposal was becoming too complicated and might end up hurting consumers.</p>
<p>She has vowed to reintroduce the measure at next year's legislative session which starts in February.</p>
<p>Connecticut Attorney General Richard Blumenthal told Reuters he was surprised and disappointed that the bill was dropped. He said he is concerned because other New England states are moving ahead with deregulation, which might make it harder for Connecticut to attract new industry.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a serious setback, because it simply puts Connecticut at a competitive disadvantage compared to other states that are proceeding actively and aggressively, and will be lowering costs even as ours are rising,&quot; Blumenthal said.</p>
<p>He is hopeful that the original time frame of full deregulation by 2000 can still be met if the legislation is pushed harder next year.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to organize and push hard for it again,&quot; Blumenthal said. &quot;I am absolutely convinced that the bill can be framed so that it is a win-win for everyone.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think any stumbling block was insuperable, but certainly securitization, stranded costs, rate reduction -- all were perceived as difficult.&quot;</p>
<p>The legislation collapsed partly because of controversy over the issues of recovery of stranded costs and securitization.</p>
<p>Stranded costs refer to a utility's outstanding debt on investments in plants, equipment and programs that were made while the industry was a regulated monopoly. Securitization involves issuing bonds to cover the debt or stranded costs.</p>
<p>Northeast Utilities, weighed down by heavy debt tied to its three idled Millstone nuclear power units in Waterford, Conn., estimates its stranded costs at about $3 billion.</p>
<p>United Illuminating's stranded costs have been estimated at about $1 billion.</p>
<p>Some critics had feared that the bill amounted to a bailout for troubled Northeast Utilities.</p>
<p>United Illuminating Chief Executive Richard Grossi told Reuters he had no major objections to the bill's treatment of stranded costs and securitization.</p>
<p>&quot;I was looking forward to this bill being passed, because I felt it would at least reduce the uncertainty that presently exists,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been a lot of uncertainty within the company... and of course in the marketplace, and our stock has suffered because of that, and other reasons. I was hopeful that this would at least mitigate some of that uncertainty.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;But we will go on, cutting our costs and doing things which essentially will be preparing us for a more competitive future, which I'm sure will develop in any case,&quot; Grossi said.</p>
<p>&quot;The provisions (of the bill) were favorable from an investor's point of view,&quot; said Dan Scotto, analyst at Bear, Stearns &amp; Co.</p>
<p>He said the collapse of the legislation was bad news for Northeast Utilities, &quot;simply because it dealt with all of the major issues, primarily the valuation of stranded generating assets, and securitization.&quot;</p>
<p>At 1423 EDT, Northeast Utilities shares were off 1/8 at 8-3/4, and United Illuminating shares were up 1/8 at 28.</p>
<p>--Hartford newsroom (860) 727-0224</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARTFORD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
