<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="605712" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX Hub natgas mixed late, June holds gain.</title>
<headline>NYMEX Hub natgas mixed late, June holds gain.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures turned mixed late Thursday in moderate trade, with spot-June still underpinned by reports of steady-to-firmer physical prices despite fairly mild weather for most of the nation.</p>
<p>At 1430 EDT, June was up 2.4 cents at $2.23 per million British thermal units, while July slipped 0.2 cent to $2.245. Other deferreds were trading on either side of unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;The values on the screen have been sustained with no real weather. You have to expect higher numbers when it really gets hot,&quot; said one Texas-based trader, noting cash has been well-supported recently.  </p>
<p>While forecasts next week for normal to slightly below-normal temperatures for most of the nation promised only minimal load, traders said steady injection demand and some heat in the West and parts of the South may be enough to keep cash firm heading into bidweek later in the week.</p>
<p>Technical traders saw little reason for the market to break out of its recent range. June support and resistance were still pegged at $2.15 and $2.30, respectively. Major buying was likely at the $2.05 double bottom, with good selling expected at the $2.43 contract high.</p>
<p>In the cash, Gulf Coast swing prices were steady to up slightly Thursday to the high-teens. Midcon pipes were little changed in the low-$2s. New York city gate gas also held relatively steady in the mid-$2.40s.</p>
<p>Transco said 400 mmcfd of gas capacity on its Texas mainline, still cut this week due to planned maintenance, should be fully restored by tomorrow. The line has a capacity of 600 mmcfd.</p>
<p>Planned work on Mobil's Mary Ann gas processing plant in Coden, Ala., has cut the plant's total processing capacity of 380-390 mmcfd. About 120 mmcfd should be back by early next week, with the balance due back in three weeks.</p>
<p>NYMEX said 35,954 contracts traded at 1355 EDT.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, June eased one-half cent to $2.065, while deferreds were mixed. The East/West spread widened by 2.9 cents to 16.5 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>((J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
