<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="605910" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany probing sect leader Schaefer in Chile.</title>
<headline>Germany probing sect leader Schaefer in Chile.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Fleck</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prosecutors in Germany said on Thursday they were investigating the leader of a secretive German settlement in Chile, Paul Schaefer, who is wanted by Chilean authorities on suspicion of sexually assaulting boys.</p>
<p>Peter Iwand, a spokesman for prosecutors in Bonn, said Schaefer, a former Nazi army officer now believed to be about 80, was suspected of murder, kidnapping and causing injury in Chile.</p>
<p>Chilean police have searched the Colonia Dignidad settlement in vain for the fugitive sect leader, who has been wanted there since November 1996 on charges including child abuse and obstruction of justice.</p>
<p>The opposition Social Democrats (SPD) said the German government had a responsibility to do its best to stop Schaefer's &quot;shameful dealings&quot; and asked Bonn what it proposed to do.</p>
<p>Iwand said the German authorities were assessing material they had requested from Chile about Schaefer which might provide enough evidence to issue an arrest warrant. But at present he said they did not have enough to press charges against him.</p>
<p>It is possible for German justice authorities to prosecute a German citizen, even if the alleged offences were committed abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Chilean authorities catch him, they may want to prosecute him themselves&quot; Iwand said.</p>
<p>He said investigations first began into Schaefer -- who also founded a sect just outside Bonn in the 1960s -- in 1986 after he was suspected of keeping sect members in Chile confined inside the settlement.</p>
<p>In 1991 another case was launched after a German lawyer informed German authorities two Chilean dissidents had been brought to Colonia Dignidad and had disappeared. Schaefer was suspected of complicity in their murder.</p>
<p>The Chilean colony was set up in the early 1960s by Schaefer, who fled Germany after being accused of sexually molesting children at an orphanage he ran after World War Two.</p>
<p>His settlement was protected by the former military regime of General Augusto Pinochet and human rights groups say the military used it as a secret detention and torture centre.</p>
<p>Last month German prosecutors launched their third probe into Schaefer on suspion of sexually assaulting children at the Chilean settlement, Iwand said.</p>
<p>The opposition SPD said it was too little too late.</p>
<p>&quot;It is incomprehensible that the German government has not done all it can to put an end to the shameful dealings of this German sect,&quot; said Renate Rennebach, an SPD deputy who sits on a parliamentary inquiry committee into religious sects.</p>
<p>&quot;The victims and the German public have a right to know...what the German government proposes to do to dissolve this organisation -- something that should have been done long ago -- and punish the ringleader,&quot; Rennebach said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
