<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="605903" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: INTERVIEW - Pena beefs up U.S. oil security.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Pena beefs up U.S. oil security.</headline>
<byline>Richard Mably</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Energy Secretary Federico Pena says he cannot rule out the possibility of imposing a minimum requirement on company petroleum product stocks as part of his strategy for defending national oil supplies.</p>
<p>Pena told Reuters that rebuilding the U.S. Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) of crude oil or creating a petroleum product reserve also were options for an administration determined not to be caught out by an unexpected disruption in oil supplies.</p>
<p>&quot;We've not reached that point yet but that's one of the issues we're going to look at,&quot; Pena said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything is on the table at this point,&quot; said Department of Energy (DOE) senior advisor Kyle Simpson.</p>
<p>Pena, in Paris for a meeting on Friday of the International Energy Agency (IEA), said the DOE was scheduled to complete plans for a national energy strategy this autumn.</p>
<p>Renewed fears about energy security were sparked in the U.S. last year by a shortage on international oil markets which saw U.S. heating oil and gasoline prices hit six-year highs.</p>
<p>The situation was exacerbated by oil companies which had reduced inventory holdings to 20-year lows to save money.</p>
<p>&quot;The question that arose out of the gasoline crisis has now been raised in a serious way to see if the markets have changed,&quot; said Simpson. &quot;We haven't reached conclusions yet.&quot;</p>
<p>Pena said rising U.S. dependence on imported oil supplies meant sales from what remains of the SPR following sales in recent years had been ruled out.</p>
<p>U.S. dependence on imported oil was expected to reach 60 percent of consumption by 2010 from about 50 percent at the moment, he said.</p>
<p>A budget deal thrashed out last week between the White House and Congress excluded a previously proposed $1.145 billion crude sale from the SPR in 2002.</p>
<p>Pena said he was confident the SPR sale would not make its way back in to the budget.</p>
<p>&quot;No more sales from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve is one of my priorities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there is growing interest on the part of (Congress) members to avoid sales. I think that agreement will stick. Our challenge now is to make sure that every year we don't go back and revisit it.&quot;</p>
<p>The energy secretary said discussions had been held with at least three countries -- Mexico, Japan and Korea -- on the possibility of leasing 110 million barrels of vacant SPR space.</p>
<p>Pena said he expected to see a further rise in U.S. oil imports from neighbouring suppliers at the expense of Middle East nations.</p>
<p>&quot;We think imports from, for example, Canada, Venezuela and Mexico and other countries we have close relations with is our part of our energy security strategy so that we are not over-reliant on the Persian Gulf.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Saudi Arabia's role as the leading world supplier won't be diminished because our purchases get reduced,&quot; added Simpson.</p>
<p>Pena said he would examine the possibility of opening new areas for domestic oil exploration.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to explore whether or not we can make some additional areas available for exploration in the United States.&quot;</p>
<p>Regions such as the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge and offshore California and Florida would remain off-limits, he said.</p>
<p>Pena said he did not consider U.S. sanctions on three of the world's leading oil suppliers -- Iraq, Libya and Iran -- as posing a threat to U.S. oil supplies.</p>
<p>&quot;Thus far not,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the U.S. administration did not approve of French oil company Total SA's moves to secure a $3.5 billion gas deal with Iran.</p>
<p>&quot;We certainly are discouraging that and we hope that's not the case,&quot; he said of the deal Total is expected to strike with Iran to develop its South Pars gasfield.</p>
<p>The U.S. in 1996 passed legislation designed to stop non-U.S. companies from doing business with Iran.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
