<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="606265" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: STARCKJOHANN TO INVEST FIM 80-90 MLN IN 97.</title>
<headline>STARCKJOHANN TO INVEST FIM 80-90 MLN IN 97.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish hardware wholesaler Starckjohann plans to invest some 80-90 million markka this year gross of depreciation, mainly in its Starkki chain, CEO Taisto Riski said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The group said earlier it had sold its 51 percent stake in wood machinery wholesaler Penope for an undisclosed sum and Riski told Reuters by telephone Starckjohann would now focus on its core businesses -- building materials sales (Starkki), steel and metal goods sales (Rauta Starckjohann), plumbing, heating and air-conditioning equiment sales (Suome LVI Tukku) and car dealing (Auto Starckjohann).</p>
<p>&quot;We have an investment programme, the bulk of which is for the Starkki chain,&quot; Riski told Reuters by telephone. &quot;It is about 80 to 90 billion, gross.&quot;</p>
<p>Riski said the sale of Penope did not mark any change in strategy although Starckjohann had increased its Penope holding to a majority less than a month ago.</p>
<p>&quot;We then simply had some expiring options and we decided to use them, it is not related to this sale,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Penope is one of the smallest listed companies in Finland with a market capitalisation of about 16.4 million markka. Starkjohann's market capitalisation is 1.15 billion markka.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +358-9-680 50 242, news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
