<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="606249" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares, hurt by Bunds, end bourse lower.</title>
<headline>German shares, hurt by Bunds, end bourse lower.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares gave up early gains and ended bourse trade lower on Thursday, hurt by ongoing weakness in German debt markets.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index ended down 16.67 points at 3,579.42 points after earlier reaching a new record high at 3,616.54 points in morning dealings.</p>
<p>But weak German debt prices, which have fallen in recent days, capped the advance and prompted the share market sell-off, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The losses are due to the debt market,&quot; said one trader. &quot;It's hard to understand why both markets are falling.&quot;</p>
<p>Bund market traders have said squabbling over plans to plug the expected 1997 deficit hole was giving both international and domestic investors an uncomfortable feeling about the German market since no clear strategy has emerged.</p>
<p>The losses came despite a report by the Ifo economic research institute that fueled hopes of stronger German growth without inflation. The institute's April west German business climate index rose to 94.07 from 92.6 in March.</p>
<p>&quot;This is of course a really good number,&quot; said Gernot Nerb, senior economist at Salomon Brothers. &quot;I would expect that mainly the export sector has boosted the index because construction and retailing remains sluggish.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank also announced M3 money supply grew an annualised 6.7 percent in April versus the average for the fourth quarter of 1996, lower than market expectations.</p>
<p>But the German debt market failed to get a boost from the M3 data and traded lower, putting a cap on share market gains.</p>
<p>Among specific shares, construction group Philipp Holzmann AG surged 33 marks to 505 marks after reporting it returned to profit last year with a one million mark profit, rebounding from a 443 million mark loss in 1995.</p>
<p>Utilities group Bewag AG rose 30 pfennigs to 41.50 marks after reporting that nine-month pre-tax profit climbed to 359 million marks from 372 million marks during the same period a year earlier.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
