<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="606293" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Storehouse reassures on current sales.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Storehouse reassures on current sales.</headline>
<byline>Jane Merriman</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>British retailer Storehouse reported a nine percent increase in annual profits on Thursday and announced a 120 million pound ($197.4 million) expansion, including 1,000 new jobs.</p>
<p>The results, which included a disappointing  performance from the group's Mothercare chain, were much as expected, but an upbeat report on sales in the past eight weeks boosted the shares.</p>
<p>The company, also owner of Bhs clothing and housewares chain, said in the eight weeks to May 17, including Easter, total sales were 15.5 percent ahead of the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>UK Sales at Bhs were up by 6.7 percent and Mothercare sales, excluding Childrens World bought from Boots Co Plc last year, rose by 5.7 p percent.</p>
<p>The shares hit a session high of 238 1/2 pence, up 22 pence on the day.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the statement that's really pushed them ahead,&quot; said one retail analyst.</p>
<p>Chief executive Keith Edelman said the results were satisfactory overall, but Mothercare had had a difficult year.</p>
<p>Worries about Mothercare had overshadowed Storehouse in the run up to the results, but its UK sales since the end of March were ahead.</p>
<p>Edelman said the group did not usually comment on trading so early in the year. &quot;We have been aware that there have been scurrilous comments about our sales performance over the last number of weeks - so we thought we'd put some facts down so people knew where we were trading.&quot;</p>
<p>The retailer, whose outlets are Bhs and children's wear chain Mothercare, said profits before tax and exceptional charges rose to 118.3 million pounds, from 108.7 million in the previous year. Sales were up 15.3 percent to 1.25 billion.</p>
<p>Edelman said Mothercare, the UK market leader in childrenswear, had probably lost some market share because of the current craze for branded sportswear for children.</p>
<p>He said this had led to a shift in the childrenswear market from traditional retailers to sportswear shops.</p>
<p>He estimated that the overall childrenswear, market, excluding the sportswear sector, had fallen by about three percent on a like-for-like basis over the past year.</p>
<p>Edelman told Reuters in an interview Storehouse planned to introduce sports fashion into its own- brand products to try and capture some of the demand for sports fashion.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got some...ideas in some of our Childrens World stores about how we can capture some of that marketplace,&quot; he said by telephone.</p>
<p>Edelman said Mothercare had lost share in the two to five age group, but had held share in the nought to two year old range. Bhs had also held its share in childrens clothing, he said.</p>
<p>Mothercare's sales fell 3.3 percent on a like-for-like basis in the year to March 30 1997, but gross margins improved and profits were up 10.7 percent to 26.8 million stg.</p>
<p>Edelman said the integration of Childrens World stores, bought from Boots Co Plc last year, was going well. He said six had been converted to the Mothercare format and another 30 would follow in the current year.</p>
<p>Finance director Chris Martin said about 30 million pounds of the group's 120 million investment would be spent on adding four new Bhs stores this year.</p>
<p>Redesigning Bhs to the new &quot;Millenium&quot; format would cost between 25 and 30 million pounds and investment in new systems another 25 to 30 million. Edelman said the Bhs Millenium format was doing well, and was driving sales gains.</p>
<p>The company plans to finish refurbishing almost the entire 283 store chain by the end of the current financial year.</p>
<p>Bhs increased operating profit by 14.1 percent to 88.3 million stg. Like-for-like sales were up 3.1 percent.</p>
<p>Asked about the new Labour government's plans for a minimum wage, Edelman said this was not a worry. But he said since the minimum wage was unlikely to take account of additional benefits -- such as pensions -- this might mean some adjustments.</p>
<p>The group's rapidly expanding international franchise business performed well. Mothercare now has 138 franchises overseas, and Bhs 72. New markets included Russia, Hong Kong, Thailand, Philippines, Israel and Lebanon.</p>
<p>($ = 0.607 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
