<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="606347" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent steady, tests of resistance bounced.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent steady, tests of resistance bounced.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE Brent crude futures tracked sideways on Thursday but trade was choppy as tests of resistance were bounced back leaving the market to trade just above unchanged, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are stuck between a rock and a hard place at the moment and there's not enough volume in the buying or selling to push the market either way,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>At 1228 GMT July Brent was six cents up at $20.19 a barrel, struggling to brake resistance around $20.20 and with good support at just above $20.</p>
<p>June gas oil stood $2.25 firmer at $178.50 a tonne.  </p>
<p>Despite the low volume some players were taking a more bullish stance.</p>
<p>Nicholas Wilson, analyst at MeesPierson said the target $20.50 remains intact even though the market has pulled back a little recently.</p>
<p>He saw good support in a band between $19.25 and $19.50 which represents a period of congestion on the July chart between May 12-15.</p>
<p>&quot;Ultimately the next target is $20.20 with a further upside target at $21.35 and then taking out contract highs of $21.90,&quot; Wilson said.</p>
<p>He saw a similar pattern of trade for gas oil with the markets recent pull back having been very modest and its failure to fill a recent gap up and pull away from the highs and indication the market still has plenty of room to improve.</p>
<p>Reports that Turkish troops pushed deeper than ever into northern Iraq on Thursday, the ninth day of a drive against Kurdish separatist guerrillas which Baghdad has dismissed as a pointless pursuit of &quot;ghosts&quot;, had little impact.</p>
<p>Iraqi Kurdish officials said Turkish troops had pushed 200 km (125 miles) into northern Iraq, a far deeper penetration of Iraqi territory than past incursions.</p>
<p>This follows Turkish reports that Iraq, Syria and Iran have all built up forces in the region.</p>
<p>The operation has been criticised by Turkey's Western allies and the United Nations.</p>
<p>--Colin Wooster, London Newsroom, +44 171 542 7456</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
