<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="606478" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Prudential admits errors in pension sales - paper.</title>
<headline>Prudential admits errors in pension sales - paper.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Insurance group Prudential Corp Plc admitted it had mis-sold pensions to the public, The Daily Telegraph reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>The newspaper said Prudential owned up to the mistakes in its direct sales of pensions products after a draft report by the Securities &amp; Investment Board (SIB), expressing worries that staff had wrongly advised clients, was leaked.</p>
<p>&quot;We have made some mistakes and we are sorting them out,&quot; a spokesman told the newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;There are some issues in the SIB document that we need to address but we cannot comment on those specifically until a final report if produced,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The SIB report, which followed a two-month investigation, concerned clients who were advised to invest in a high selling product rather than more suitable investments.</p>
<p>&quot;The product is linked to Pru's life fund and so is believed to suffer from the underlying taxation applied to the fund,&quot; the newspaper said, adding that some people could have been disadvantaged by it.</p>
<p>The report also looked into procedures where clients may have incurred new charges by salesmen for selling second pensions instead of topping up their initial pension.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150214">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
