<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="606435" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSTANT VIEW - UK retail sales, GDP data.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - UK retail sales, GDP data.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following is a list of analysts' reactions to UK April retail sales and UK first quarter gross domestic product data released at 0830 GMT.</p>
<p>* UK APRIL RETAIL SALES +0.1% MM,+4.7% YY IN VOLUME TERMS</p>
<p>(vs expectations +0.3 m/m, +4.1 y/y)</p>
<p>* UK Q1 GDP UP 0.9% QQ, +3.0% YY (vs expectations +1.0 q/q, +3.0 y/y)</p>
<p>ANDREW SNOWBALL, TREASURY ECONOMIST CO-OPERATIVE BANK -</p>
<p>&quot;Net/net the picture is still that the consumer sector is very strong.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's always important to look at the three month trend figures.&quot;</p>
<p>He noted that there was a sharp revision to the March retail sales data with the monthly change now standing at 0.7 percent compared with the originally reported figure of 0.3. The annual growth rate was revised to 4.4 percent from 4.0 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The GDP numbers show a very strong consumer sector and a strong economy. It's the usual suspects that are growing most strongly - the consumer sector not the manufacturing sector,&quot; Snowball added.  </p>
<p>ALEX GARRARD, UBS UK ECONOMIST - &quot;On the retail sales figures while it looks weaker over the month, there's obviously been a lot of backward revisions and 4.7 percent year-on-year is likely to be viewed as uncomfortably strong by the Bank of England.&quot;  </p>
<p>JEREMY HAWKINS/ROB HAYWARD, BANK AMERICA:  &quot;Although April retail sales were on the soft side of expectations, revisions have boosted annual growth to a very robust 4.7 pct. This should be seen as increasing the likelihood that the Bank of England will hike rates soon unless the budget is very tight.&quot;</p>
<p>--London newsroom +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
