<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="606461" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT -Bunds in poor shape,more losses to 100.83.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT -Bunds in poor shape,more losses to 100.83.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The technical outlook for June Bund futures has deteriorated sharply and the market is looking to slide to 100.83 ahead of a possible break below trendline support at 100.00, technical analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>They said any spike up towards 101.30 resistance should be used as a selling opportunity ahead of further potential losses.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook for Bunds is pretty bad,&quot; said Guenter Redeker, technical analyst at Chase here.</p>
<p>&quot;We broke the uptend on weekly charts at 101.06 yesterday, so the next objective for the market is 100.83.&quot;</p>
<p>By 0656 GMT, the June Bund on LIFFE was down 0.19 at 101.04.  </p>
<p>Below 100.83, Redeker put the next target at 100.28, followed by trendline support at 100.00.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will determine medium term direction around those levels,&quot; he said. &quot;So if it breaks 100.00 then it would mean a retest of 99.05, which is a low tested a few months ago.&quot;</p>
<p>Charts show the market hit a daily low of 99.05 on April 3.</p>
<p>Redeker said any upside potential would be limited to trendline resistance at 101.30. &quot;An uptick into that area should be regarded as a shortening opportunity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said only a break of 101.38 would give the market the potential to move higher up to trendline resistance at 101.65.  </p>
<p>&quot;But even that possible level should be used as a selling opportunity,&quot; said Redeker.</p>
<p>Francoise Skelley, head of global trading technical analysis at Credit Suisse First Boston in London, said in the very near term the market would bounce before a further move down.</p>
<p>&quot;Very short term, the sell-off has left the market oversold on an hourly basis, so ahead of more declines it will bounce back to 101.25,38 -- and that will cap the market,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Skelley said she was then looking for a test of 100.81 ahead of stronger support at 100.54,48.</p>
<p>By 0726 GMT, September Euromarks were down 0.01 at 96.72.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
