<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60673" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: SOCCER-YUGOSLAVS FACE PERENNIAL PROBLEM OF EXILE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-YUGOSLAVS FACE PERENNIAL PROBLEM OF EXILE.</headline>
<byline>Rex Gowar</byline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslavia, back in World Cup contention after suspension for political reasons, are more affected than ever by their perennial problem of top players in soccer exile.</p>
<p>Coach Slobodan Santrac has 14 players in Spain, five in Italy, three in England, two each in Portugal and Scotland plus captain Dragan Stojkovic in the J.League, where he was voted Japanese player of the year in 1994 and 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem with them not playing in Yugoslavia is that we can never be sure when they might be injured,&quot; he said. &quot;They are all fighting in super leagues.</p>
<p>&quot;It's normal to expect some to be injured but we don't have enough time to work with them,&quot; he told reporters at UEFA's National Coaches Convention.</p>
<p>&quot;Another problem is moulding a side with players coming from clubs with such different styles. In Italy, not all the coaches are even Italian. The players have too much influence from other schools of football,&quot; said the former Yugoslav international.</p>
<p>&quot;For a long time in the ex-Yugoslavia we had the Yugoslav school. We will try to retain the Yugoslav style while taking some finer points from others.</p>
<p>&quot;Yugoslavia have always had extraordinary individual talent, like the Brazilians, but have suffered from weaknesses as a team. Our problem is not scoring but in defence.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the convention was helpful in sharing problems faced by national team coaches and was happy they had agreed they would have their players at least seven times a year, five times for five days ahead of World Cup qualifiers.</p>
<p>Santrac left the three-day convention a day early on Tuesday to fly to the Czech Republic to watch the Euro 96 runners-up play Malta in a qualifier in World Cup group six in which his team, Spain, Slovakia and the Faroe Islands are also competing.</p>
<p>Santrac, a former OFK Belgrade, Partizan and Grasshopper Zurich centre-forward, said Spain and the Czechs were the favourites, but Yugoslavia and Slovakia were also in with a good chance.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a good team but we have had no international competition for a long time -- four years in the dark,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Whoever is in best form (of the four main contenders) and has the luck in their matches against each other will qualify.</p>
<p>&quot;For me Spain are the favourites. They have been together the longest, they have made so few changes in the last years, they are compact, they have quality and a great understanding among each other.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
