<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60682" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Olivetti board meets, shake-up seen.</title>
<headline>Olivetti board meets, shake-up seen.</headline>
<byline>Charlotte Cooper</byline>
<dateline>MILAN, Italy</dateline>
<text>
<p>The board of Italy's Olivetti group was expected to oust Chief Executive Francesco Caio in a meeting on Wednesday, with market analysts tipping an aide of former Chairman Carlo De Benedetti as his likely replacement.</p>
<p>Olivetti said in a statement it had called the board meeting for Wednesday afternoon, giving no details of what was on the agenda.</p>
<p>But analysts said they understood Roberto Colaninno, managing director of auto components firm Sogefi and a close associate of De Benedetti, had agreed to take over from Caio, who has only held the post since July.</p>
<p>Newspapers reported on Wednesday Caio was likely either to resign or to be ousted only two weeks after winning a boardroom power struggle which led to the sudden resignation of Chairman De Benedetti on Sept. 3.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Olivetti declined comment on the reports.</p>
<p>De Benedetti, the biggest shareholder in the company, is widely believed to be still in control, with his son Rodolfo and other allies flanking Caio on the board.</p>
<p>Colaninno also comes from a company which is controlled by De Benedetti's industrial holding CIR.</p>
<p>The former chairman was reported by daily Il Sole to be the prime mover behind a plan to eject Caio, his former assistant, and is now widely reported to be thirsting for revenge.</p>
<p>The upheavals have seen Olivetti shares plunge to record lows as investors dumped the stock in concern over who was running the loss-making group and its real financial position.</p>
<p>The company side-stepped key questions about its business put by market regulators by issuing a statement early Wednesday giving details of some of its affairs but leaving out others.</p>
<p>It said it could not divulge information about talks under way on future divestments or strategic accords nor could it state its consolidated financial situation for the end of August 1996 until the first week of October.</p>
<p>It set a value on its stock of computer hardware without detailing -- as the market had wanted -- whether the equipment was outdated and unsellable or state-of-the-art.</p>
<p>In the marketplace, authorities delayed the start of trading in Olivetti shares for two hours on Wednesday to allow the market time to assess the information supplied by the group.</p>
<p>Once the stock opened, it rebounded from record lows of 465 lire (30 cents) set on Tuesday and triggered automatic suspension by touching a 10 percent trading ceiling and forging a day's high of 511.5 lire (33 cents) . It then failed to resume trade.</p>
<p>Olivetti, an entrepreneurial success stories of the 1980s, has been caught in a snowballing crisis over doubts about the accuracy of its first-half accounts.</p>
<p>Caio, 39, new Chairman Antonio Tesone and De Benedetti himself are being investigated by magistrates in Olivetti's home town of Ivrea who suspect the company may have issued misleading statements about its affairs, judicial sources say.</p>
<p>That inquiry and Consob's questions were all prompted by the resignation of Olivetti director general Renzo Francesconi the day after De Benedetti stood down. Francesconi said he disagreed with figures in the half-year results.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
