<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="606824" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Taiwan fails to show up at tourism conference.</title>
<headline>Taiwan fails to show up at tourism conference.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan failed to show up at an international tourism meeting in the Philippines on Thursday following complaints from China that they should not have been invited in the first place.</p>
<p>&quot;Actually, we never got to tell them not to attend,&quot; Philippine Secretary of Tourism Mina Gabor told Reuters.</p>
<p>Some 60 countries are taking part in the two-day meeting of the World Tourism Organisation, which is looking at some of the darker sides of mass travel, including drugs, prostitution and child abuse.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, China protested against Manila's decision to invite a delegation from Taiwan -- which it considers a renegade province -- saying this violated the one-China policy that Manila embraces.</p>
<p>The invitation had been made by the Philippine tourism department without checking with the foreign ministry.</p>
<p>The Taiwan delegation had been due to arrive for the conference on Wednesday night but did not show up, although organisers said it would be all right if they came as ordinary guests.</p>
<p>However, a delegation of Taiwanese tour operators has agreed to visit the Philippines in two weeks, Gabor added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
