<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="606904" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: LME copper seen correcting in near term - Asia trade.</title>
<headline>LME copper seen correcting in near term - Asia trade.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange (LME) were seen edging up in quiet Asian trade on Thursday, but facing a technical correction in the short term, Far East traders said.</p>
<p>Three-month copper was quoted at $2,501/$2,506 a tonne at 0400 GMT, compared with the LME close of $2,500/$2,505 late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The copper market appears overbought with the 14-day relative strength index (RSI) at 78.02,&quot; said a trader with Samsung Futures in Seoul.  </p>
<p>The Samsung trader said current copper prices were likely to meet a technical correction in the near term to ease the market's overbought situation.</p>
<p>The market generally considers an RSI of 70 or more as overbought and 30 or less as oversold.</p>
<p>Copper prices also made a gap between $2,495 and $2,499 on Wednesday and set new one-year high of $2,518 before falling back to $2,506 at the end of the PM kerb.</p>
<p>The cash to threes backwardation also widened to $81/$85 by the end of the kerb from around $70 at the end of business on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>LME metal broker Brandeis said in its daily report that the appearance of an island reversal, signalling that prices were over-extended, coupled with the overbought RSI suggested that moves on the upside from this level would be difficult unless prices correct lower first.</p>
<p>Brandeis pegged a support at $2,490/$2,500 and then $2,470.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, with another poor close on the aluminium charts on Wednesday, three-month aluminium prices appeared headed lower and a down channel was becoming established, Brandeis said.</p>
<p>The broker pegged a support for three-month aluminium prices at $1,645/$1,650 and then $,1,625/$1,630.  </p>
<p>Borrowing of the nearby dates resulted in the cash/threes spread narrowing to $13/$10 contango at the end of Wednesday's LME kerb, against $19 on the previous day.</p>
<p>Japanese yen-denominated aluminium contracts on the Tokyo Commodity Exchange (TOCOM) rose on Thursday in line with the yen's weakness against the dollar.</p>
<p>TOCOM's active April aluminium contract rose in thin trading to 196.0 yen per kg at 0530 GMT, up 4.6 yen from Wednesday's close of 191.4 yen.  </p>
<p>&quot;The aluminium prices rose today on TOCOM mainly due to the weak yen against the dollar,&quot; said a trader at Japanese broker Ace Koeki Co Ltd in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Three-month zinc prices were barely changed in Asian trade and are expected to decline on a technical correction.</p>
<p>The zinc market also stood in overbought territory with the 14-day RSI at 70.21.</p>
<p>A regional trader said LME stocks for copper and aluminium are expected to decline further on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Jae Hur, Seoul Newsroom (822) 727 5651</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
