<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="607186" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: INTERVIEW - Singson sees lower Philippines rates.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Singson sees lower Philippines rates.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rates in the Philippines are returning to normal after last week's Asian currency turmoil, with further declines in the key overnight rate possible next week, central bank governor Gabriel Singson told Reuters on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is down to 18 (percent) and we can bring it back down to normal next week. It depends on the market, how the market behaves,&quot; Singson said.</p>
<p>The overnight rate, raised from 13 percent to 20 percent when speculators attacked the Thai baht last week, dropped back to 18 percent on Thursday morning.</p>
<p>Speculators betting on a sudden devalution of the Thai baht precipitated widespread currency turmoil throughout southeast Asia last week, with hedge funds taking positions on the Malaysian ringgit, Philippines peso and Indonesian rupiah.</p>
<p>Coordinated central bank intervention appeared to foil the hedge funds, and Singson said that if market conditions warrant, the overnight rate will be dropped back to normal next week.</p>
<p>Singson also put forward a firm defense of the Philippines' peso, ruling out any immediate devalution.</p>
<p>&quot;Devaluation won't work. A sharp devaluation won't solve our problems,&quot; he said. &quot;Our exchange rate policy is to let the market decide the exchange rate and we intend to continue. My statement is unqualified.&quot;</p>
<p>Although he conceded that interest rates were high and credit growth was strong, Singson rejected any comparison with Thailand or Malaysia, where he said credit continue to grow at rates of about 90 percent.</p>
<p>In the Philippines, private sector credit growth dropped to 37 percent in the first quarter from 57 percent in all of 1996.</p>
<p>Bank indebtedness to the property sector is restricted to less than 20 percent of outstanding loans, with two recent surveys confirming total exposure of less than 11 percent.</p>
<p>If credit growth were a problem, the inflation rate in the Philippines would be higher than the 4.6 percent recorded in April, Singson added.</p>
<p>The central bank governor gave no clues on the timing of the launch of its controversial US$1.25 billion yankee bond, which was delayed in April.</p>
<p>Market conditions would determine the new date of the launch, and everything was in place to allow the Philippines to move swiftly, he said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission registration remains valid for nine months and the roadshow has been completed, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is really a judgement call and we have to decide on a daily basis. Ultimately, I have the luxury of time. I'm not in any hurry,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sarah Davison (852) 2843 6470</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
