<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60712" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: SLOVAK C.BANK STILL REVIEWING VSZ'S BANK EQUITY.</title>
<headline>SLOVAK C.BANK STILL REVIEWING VSZ'S BANK EQUITY.</headline>
<dateline>BANSKA BYSTRICA, Slovakia 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Bank of Slovakia (NBS) on Wednesday said it was still reviewing a request by steel maker VSZ a.s. to increase its holdings in bank IRB a.s. to over 20 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The NBS is still waiting for Central Securities Registry (SCP) information on VSZ's holdings in IRB,&quot; Tibor Kasiak, head of the NBS banking supervision board, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Last August VSZ asked for central bank permission to increase its stake in IRB, the third largest Slovak commercial bank, to over 20 percent.</p>
<p>But, Kasiak warned, the move will not be approved until it is ascertained that VSZ's current holdings in the bank do not exceed the legal limit of 15 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Regardless of what the SCP says, in the NBS's opinion no one can breach the current law and if VSZ has over 15 percent, it will have to return it as if the deal had not happened,&quot; Kasiak said in an interview while attending the Finex banking fari in the central Slovak city of Banska Bystrica.</p>
<p>According to Slovak law, any acquisition of over 15 percent stake in a commercial bank has to be approved by the NBS.</p>
<p>In August, the SCP published figures showing VSZ held some 20 percent of IRB, but later denied the figures without further explanation.</p>
<p>&quot;If VSZ shows full quality of a shareholder, why should not it be allowed?,&quot; Kasiak said adding: &quot;But it would certainly not be immediately to such an extent as VSZ imagined it would be.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that the issue should be completed within a month.</p>
<p>VSZ is a major client of IRB, accounting for an estimated 1.5 percent of the bank's total loan portfolio.</p>
<p>-- Tatiana Vacova, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANSKA BYSTRICA, Slovakia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
