<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="607389" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thailand to support Hopewell project.</title>
<headline>Thailand to support Hopewell project.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai government said on Thursday it will provide support to Hopewell Holdings Ltd's mass transit project in Bangkok, including some financing to ensure its partial completion ahead of the 1998 Asian Games.</p>
<p>The support was approved on the condition that Hopewell's Thai unit, Bangkok Elevated Rail Train System (BERT), must double its paid-up capital to 30 billion baht ($1.15 billion), government spokesman Warathep Rattanakorn told Reuters.</p>
<p>BERT currently has paid-up capital of 15 billion baht, he said.</p>
<p>The government will also fine the company 7.5 million baht per day for its delay in completing the project, he said.</p>
<p>Thailand wants BERT to finish its elevated toll roads and community trains ahead of the 1998 Asian Games to be held in Bangkok next December.</p>
<p>The much-delayed BERT projects included a toll road and community train system as well as retail developments.</p>
<p>The government's support will also include the transfer and clearance of land for construction from the State Railway of Thailand and loans worth 2.5 billion baht.  </p>
<p>&quot;The loan is insignificant relative to the project's total investment cost. But it will express the government's commitment to the project,&quot; Warathep said.</p>
<p>The government's commitment to the project will make foreign and local commercial banks more willing to grant loans for the project, he said.</p>
<p>The finance ministry is still considering the details of the loan, he said.</p>
<p>Hopewell said in a statement it welcomed the Thai support and said it would help clear major concerns of potential lenders to the project and allow the financing arrangements with banks to move ahead.</p>
<p>($1 = 26 baht)</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020028">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
