<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="607407" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: PRESS DIGEST - Vietnam - May 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Vietnam - May 22.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the official Vietnamese press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>VIETNAM NEWS</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Vo Van Kiet was given a red carpet welcome in Warsaw on Tuesday by Polish Prime Minister at the beginning of his two-day official visit.</p>
<p>-- Deputy Prime Minister Phan Van Khai said Vietnam must establish controls on the growing amount of money borrowed from foreign banks and governments.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SAIGON TIMES DAILY</p>
<p>-- The area of summer-autumn paddy in the southern Mekong Delta has decreased at least by 19,000 hectares compared with last year's level because of difficulties and delay of the previous crop.</p>
<p>-- The Planning and Investment Ministry released a list of 23 projects calling for investment under form of build-operate-transfer and offers of exemption of land rentals and import tax for foreign investors taking part in those projects.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>NHAN DAN</p>
<p>-- Communist Party Secretary General Do Muoi leaves Hanoi on Thursday for an friendship visit to Myanmar.</p>
<p>-- Vietnamese embassy in Phnom Penh has sent a letter to Cambodian officials and U.N Human Right protection center accusing Khmer Rouge of the recent killing of 12 Vietnamese in Rattanakiri province.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HANOI MOI</p>
<p>-- Vietnam's National Assembly issued resolution calling the entire people and sodiers to bring into play their mastership, to heighten the spirit of self-reliance and to practise thrift to build the country.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SAIGON GIAI PHONG</p>
<p>-- More than 3,000 monks attended a ceremony in Ho Chi Minh City on Wednesday to mark Buddha's birthday.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
