<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="607422" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila B shares up despite lack of foreign buyers.</title>
<headline>Manila B shares up despite lack of foreign buyers.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine blue chip B shares were firmer by midsession despite the absence of heavy foreign institutional buying, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems that some local investors are buying up the B shares for trading purposes. It's a quiet market today,&quot; Astro del Castillo, research analyst of A &amp; A Securities, said.</p>
<p>Among the most traded B shares were power distributor Manila Electric Co B which went up three pesos to 123 pesos, food and beer giant San Miguel Corp B up 2.50 pesos to 69.50 pesos, and Ayala Corp B which nudged up 25 centavos to 17 pesos.</p>
<p>Ayala Land Inc B, which is also one of the top ten traded stocks, was steady at 18 pesos.</p>
<p>B shares are stocks open to both local and foreign investors.</p>
<p>De Castillo said foreign investors were still shying away from the Philippine equities market awaiting for the first quarter economic growth figures to come out next week to validate government's claim that the Philippine economy is not slowing down. -- Manila Newsroom (63 2) 841-8938 Fax 817-6267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
