<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="607629" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli, Egyptian presidents set peace meeting.</title>
<headline>Israeli, Egyptian presidents set peace meeting.</headline>
<byline>Howard Goller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's President Ezer Weizman and Egypt's President Hosni Mubarak plan to meet soon to try to salvage Israeli-PLO peace talks deadlocked for two months, an Israeli official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The planned meeting sparked what Israel Radio called a &quot;mini-crisis&quot; in Israel between the blunt-spoken Weizman, an architect of Israel's landmark 1979 peace treaty with Egypt, and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>
<p>&quot;The proposal by Mubarak was for a meeting to advance the peace process. The date and time have yet to be set,&quot; Arye Shumer, director-general of Weizman's office, told Israel Radio. &quot;I imagine we are speaking of the coming days.&quot;</p>
<p>Weizman's job as president is largely ceremonial and his contacts with Arab leaders, including meetings with Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat, underscore the crisis Netanyahu's 11-month-old right-wing government faces in peacemaking.</p>
<p>Asked on Thursday if it was healthy for Weizman to have diplomatic contacts with Middle East leaders when Netanyahu was not meeting them, Shumer told the radio: &quot;What do you want me to say -- that we are to blame for this?&quot;</p>
<p>Shumer said the Egyptian leader proposed the meeting during a phone call on Wednesday and Weizman informed Netanyahu of the initiative immediately after the call.</p>
<p>Differences over Netanyahu's Jewish settlements policy have stalled negotiations with the PLO. Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat on Wednesday urged the United States to put pressure on Israel to save the process.</p>
<p>Weizman, an architect of the treaty with Egypt when he was a cabinet minister in 1979, was quoted last week by an Israeli newspaper as saying he had cut off contact with Netanyahu over the prime minister's attitude towards the peace crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;If there's a situation where there's a process of a sort of freeze, or various hardships, when it comes to the president of Israel, the things speak for themselves,&quot; Shumer said on Thursday.</p>
<p>But asked if it was his impression Mubarak was refusing to meet Netanyahu, Shumer said: &quot;Absolutely not.&quot;</p>
<p>Government spokesman Moshe Fogel told Reuters on Thursday that Netanyahu's office had been informed of the planned Mubarak-Weizman meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister's office is aware of the proposal and it's aware of the potential initiative and it's aware of what's on the table,&quot; Fogel said without elaborating.</p>
<p>The Israeli newspaper Yedioth Ahronoth last week quoted Weizman as having assailed Netanyahu, using his nickname &quot;Bibi&quot;, by saying: &quot;I have cut all contact with him. Bibi isn't ready to listen. He knows everything.&quot;</p>
<p>Weizman met Arafat earlier this month to try to break the impasse and the newspaper quoted him as saying: &quot;When I returned from the meeting with Arafat, I thought he (Netanyahu) would want to hear what happened there. Not at all.&quot;</p>
<p>On May 12, Weizman told Israel Television: &quot;I see myself as the icebreaker. I opened the channel and the convoy needed to follow it...but the convoy did not follow it.&quot;</p>
<p>Peacemaking ground to a halt when Netanyahu ordered work to begin on a new Jewish settlement in East Jerusalem on March 18.</p>
<p>Netanyahu has said he is proud of the decision to build the 6,500-unit settlement. Israel occupied East Jerusalem in 1967 and claimed the whole city as its capital. The claim is not recognised internationally.</p>
<p>Palestinians want East Jerusalem as capital of a future state. They say settlement-building pre-empts final peace talks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
