<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="607745" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ex-railroad official sentenced in Alaska oil case.</title>
<headline>Ex-railroad official sentenced in Alaska oil case.</headline>
<dateline>ANCHORAGE, Alaska 1997-05-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former supervisor for Alaska's White Pass &amp; Yukon Railroad was sentenced in federal court on Wednesday to a year in confinement for his role in a 1994 oil spill from a company pipeline.</p>
<p>Edward Hanousek was ordered by U.S. District Court Judge James Fitzgerald to spend six months in prison and six months in a halfway house for a violation of the federal Clean Water Act, the U.S. Attorney's office said.</p>
<p>He was also ordered to pay a $5,000 fine, officials said.</p>
<p>Hanousek was convicted in December of negligent discharge of oil, a charge related to a spill of oil from a company pipeline into southeast Alaska's Skagway River.</p>
<p>He was in charge of a rock quarrying project that caused the pipeline rupture, officials said.</p>
<p>The former president of the railroad's owner, Pacific and Arctic Navigation Co., Paul Taylor, was also convicted of pollution violations. Taylor has not yet been sentenced.</p>
<p>Prosecutors said Taylor and Hanousek conspired to conceal the pipeline rupture and resulting oil spill.</p>
<p>Pacific and Arctic Navigation Co. and a sister company, Pacific and Arctic Pipelines Inc., last year pleaded guilty to pollution charges and agreed to pay fines and restitution of $1.5 million for the damages.</p>
<p>The White Pass &amp; Yukon Railroad, a relic of the Klondike gold rush, runs from Skagway, Alaska, to the Yukon Territory. The narrow-gauge railway is a major tourist attraction.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANCHORAGE, Alaska"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
