<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="607766" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France expresses hopes for democracy in ex-Zaire.</title>
<headline>France expresses hopes for democracy in ex-Zaire.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Jacques Chirac told South African head of state Nelson Mandela on Thursday that France hoped the former Zaire would move towards democracy under new leader Laurent Kabila.</p>
<p>Chirac told Mandela during a 20-minute telephone conversation that France wanted the newly renamed Democratic Republic of Congo &quot;to move towards democracy and organise elections&quot;, the Elysee presidential palace said.</p>
<p>Paris also sought commitments from the Kabila government that it would protect foreigners, including French residents, following the shooting to death of two Frenchmen in Kinshasa on Tuesday evening.</p>
<p>Defence Ministry spokesman Pierre Servent told reporters that 300 Foreign Legion paratroopers stationed in Brazzaville, across the Congo river from Kinshasa, would remain in case they were needed to protect French nationals.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no plan to evacuate anyone now but our units will nonetheless remain ready,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>French officials have urged French nationals in Kinshasa not to panic, saying there was no evidence that businessmen Michel Tournaire and Herve Rigaud were killed by troops from Kabila's Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire.</p>
<p>The foreign ministry however called on the nearly 500 French nationals still in Kinshasa to &quot;exercise the greatest caution&quot;.</p>
<p>The ministry, which described the situation in the city as &quot;still somewhat confused and changing&quot;, said it was sending senior official Jean-Pierre Lafon to Kinshasa to meet French citizens and local security authorities.</p>
<p>Paris also ordered its ambassador to Kinshasa to demand that Kabila protect French nationals and refugees.</p>
<p>France was a close ally of deposed president Mobutu Sese Seko, who fled to Togo last weekend as Kabila's forces marched into the capital after a seven-month rebellion.</p>
<p>The Alliance makes no secret of its dislike for France's post-colonial policy in Africa and anti-French sentiment is pronounced on the streets of Kinshasa.</p>
<p>Army officers in Paris said French aircraft were patrolling the border between Zaire and the Central African Republic, a Paris ally, to spot stragglers from the defeated Zairean army or their Rwandan Hutu allies crossing the border with weapons.</p>
<p>France fears such armed groups could destabilise small countries adjacent to Zaire by their presence, especially if they took to banditry in poorly-policed rural areas.</p>
<p>Chirac also told Mandela France hoped Kabila would help remedy the humanitarian situation in east Zaire, where thousands of refugees are stranded and threatened with starvation and disease, the Elysee said.</p>
<p>Mandela had telephoned Chirac to seek his views on the current situation in the vast central African nation, the Elysee said. Mandela led international efforts to bring about a democratic transition but the campaign ended in failure.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
