<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="607827" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: UDF leader says Italy needs to meet EMU criteria.</title>
<headline>UDF leader says Italy needs to meet EMU criteria.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Francois Leotard, leader of French ruling coalition member UDF, said on Thursday he did not agree with the opposition Socialists that Italy should take part in the start of a European single currency come what may.</p>
<p>In an interview with French afternoon daily Le Monde, Leotard said he hoped Italy would be part of the euro from the start but only on the condition that it respected the Maastricht criteria.</p>
<p>He also distinguished the UDF position on European economic and monetary union (EMU) from the Socialist stance by saying the euro should be &quot;solid&quot; and a future European central bank (ECB) should be independent.</p>
<p>&quot;I would strongly wish that Italy (participated) in the euro, but on the condition that it respects the criteria,&quot; Leotard was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Leotard said the level of the euro would largely be set by the markets and &quot;besides, I am not for a weak euro but for a solid euro. The Germans are right to hope that the euro has the same qualities as their currency.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he was concerned that the Socialists' &quot;extraodinarily subjective&quot; condition that the euro not be overvalued against the dollar could be a pretext for an EMU delay or a breaking of existing agreements.</p>
<p>Leotard also said he was &quot;very attached to the independence of the European central bank&quot; and that the Socialists' call for an economic government to counterbalance the ECB needed to be defined more clearly.</p>
<p>Socialist leader Lionel Jospin has laid down four conditions for France joining EMU: Italy and Spain must be in EMU from the start, the euro must not be overvalued against the dollar and the yen, there should be an economic government alongside the ECB and the stability pact should be reviewed.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5542</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
