<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="607800" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU leaders meet to force pace of treaty reforms.</title>
<headline>EU leaders meet to force pace of treaty reforms.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Gaunt</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union leaders gather in the Dutch coastal resort of Noordwijk on Friday to try to force the pace of negotiations on a new EU treaty so that it can be signed on time next month.</p>
<p>While no decisions are expected from the half-day summit, the leaders plan to sound each other out and see what each can live with ahead of the June 16-17 summit in Amsterdam.</p>
<p>&quot;Leaders will go home from Noordwijk knowing what they'll have to do at Amsterdam. Lots of things still have to be sorted out,&quot; Luxembourg premier Jean-Claude Juncker told Reuters.</p>
<p>The inter-governmental conference (IGC) talks, aimed at revising the Maastricht Treaty, began in Turin, Italy, in March 1996. They are designed to prepare the EU for enlargement into eastern Europe and to be the latest step in the bloc's slow march towards political and economic integration.</p>
<p>But to date the 15 countries have shown little fervour for adopting the kind of radical new projects thrown up by previous treaty talks, notably the single currency and the single market.</p>
<p>Reflecting this, German Chancellor Helmut Kohl urged his colleagues in the mainly Christian Democrat European People's Party on Wednesday to be realistic about what they could get.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't overload the wagon but get enough on the wagon to reach the next stage,&quot; Irish Prime Minister John Bruton said, categorising the mood.</p>
<p>To prepare for enlargement, the EU wants to overhaul the way it takes decisions, adding more majority voting, streamlining the European Commission and perhaps returning to larger countries some of the voting clout lost by previous expansions.</p>
<p>But the leaders also want to make the bloc more meaningful to its citizens. To do this, some are urging the creation of a freedom and security zone in which internal borders would be completly lifted with shared crime-fighting among the EU states.</p>
<p>They also want to show their citizens they are serious about job creation by making the fight against unemployment legally binding in the treaty.</p>
<p>Optimism has grown in recent weeks that a treaty can be agreed at Amsterdam, primarily because of the defeat of Britain's largely euro-sceptic Conservative government.</p>
<p>The Conservatives had threatened to veto the treaty over a number of issues if they did not get their way and had refused to countenance any move toward further integration.</p>
<p>Friday's meeting in Noordwijk will be the first opportunity since the election for Britain's new prime minister, Tony Blair, to meet his counterparts.</p>
<p>Blair has pledged to work closely with the rest of Europe and has already invigorated the treaty talks with promises to agree some new majority voting, a new employment chapter and a number of other items spurned by his predecessor.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
