<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60796" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French bourse ends weaker, shrugs off budget.</title>
<headline>French bourse ends weaker, shrugs off budget.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The French stockmarket showed little reaction to the French 1997 budget unveiled on Wednesday and closed slightly lower as it digested recent gains.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is consolidating calmly. The budget conformed to expectations,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed down 8.13 points or 0.39 percent at 2,072.73, while the CAC-40 September futures contract fell 11.5 points to 2,075.50. Volume was 4.1 billion francs.</p>
<p>Shares in Renault slumped 3.57 percent to close at 116.10 francs after a big sell order was issued in the last minutes of trading. The carmaker on Wednesday unveiled two new models in the Megane family, the innovative Scenic and the Classic sedan, aimed at improving its product-mix and recapturing market share.</p>
<p>Michelin stock fell 2.98 percent to 257.30 francs, giving back its gains made on Tuesday after reporting strong pre-exceptional profit growth. Brokerage CS First Boston lowered its rating to hold from buy, citing the rise in Michelin's first-half working capital requirements.</p>
<p>Alcatel Alsthom was the top gainer in the CAC index, closing up 2.93 percent at 386.40 francs after outlining its plans for Thomson SA if its bid for the group succeeds.</p>
<p>Chairman Serge Tchuruk told a news conference he would look for a European defence partner and an Asian partner for Thomson's consumer electronics operations. Brokers said his approach suggested the deal would not be too costly for Alcatel.</p>
<p>The French government is expected to announce the winner in the bidding for Thomson in early October.</p>
<p>Both Alcatel and rival Lagardere, which ended 1.81 percent lower at 119.50, said on Wednesday that they would offer to buy out minority shareholders. Thomson's listed unit, Thomson-CSF, closed up 1.91 percent at 154.40 francs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
