<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60955" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SA Druggists sells 6 drugs to U.S. firm.</title>
<headline>SA Druggists sells 6 drugs to U.S. firm.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African Druggists Ltd (SAD) said on Wednesday it had agreed to sell six drugs to U.S. pharmaceuticals group Wyeth-Ayerst/Whitehall International for an undisclosed sum.</p>
<p>SAD had originally bought the licenses for the drugs from Wyeth and the reacquisition by their first owners will see Wyeth re-enter the South African market for the first time since 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;(The deal) facilitates Wyeth-Ayerst/Whitehall's return to South Africa, while securing and extending SAD's relationship with that company well beyond its origiunal horizon,&quot; said Peter Beningfield, SAD's chief executive.</p>
<p>SAD will continue to manufacture the drugs on behalf of Wyeth, a unit of giant U.S. firm American Home Products Inc.</p>
<p>The drugs' licensing agreement would have lapsed in 1999. The deal also provides for an extension of manufacturing and marketing rights to 2006 for Wyeth drugs retained by SAD.</p>
<p>The drugs reacquired by Wyeth are female hormone replacement therapies Premarin and Prempak, anti-depressant Efexor and self-medications Anadin, Advil and Preparation H.</p>
<p>SAD will retain oral contraceptives Minulet, Tri-Minulet, Triphasil, Nordette and Biphasil. The firm will also keep Ativan, Dristan, Mucaine, Normison, Isordil, Serepax, Postoval, Denorex and child nutritional products SMA, S26 and Infasoy.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom + 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
