<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61016" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish Gdansk refinery Jan-Aug net plunges 46 pct.</title>
<headline>Polish Gdansk refinery Jan-Aug net plunges 46 pct.</headline>
<dateline>GDANSK, Poland 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Net profit for Gdansk refinery, Poland's second biggest, fell 46 percent in Jan-Aug against the same period last year to 51.4 million zlotys, the head of the refinery's finance department said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Stanislaw Pokojski told Reuters that the company's gross profit in that period was 65.9 million zlotys, also 46 percent lower than in the same period last year.</p>
<p>He said the refinery's costs grew 21 percent to 1.978 billion zlotys.</p>
<p>&quot;The refinery's profit plunged because prices of oil on world markets have soared while the government's policy of keeping domestic prices flat have reduced the refinery's profits,&quot; Pokojski said.</p>
<p>Pokojski said however, the firm's smaller earnings would not affect Gdansk's financing arragement with Merrill Lynch, which is the organiser of a fully-guaranteed $100 million five-year loan for the refinery's modernisation.</p>
<p>The whole modernisation programme, to be completed until 1999, will cost $400 million.</p>
<p>Pokojski said the Merrill Lynch loan accounted for 25 percent of funds needed for the programme and that another 25 percent the refinery would seek to raise from a consortium of Polish banks.</p>
<p>He said the firm asked the state-owned commercial Bank Handlowy SA, Bank Pekao SA, PKO BP and the private Bank Gdanski to organise such a consortium, hoping the agreement could be signed by the end of November.</p>
<p>Pokojski said the refinery would raise the remaining funds by issuing three-year commercial papers late next year.</p>
<p>-- Jan Kreft +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GDANSK, Poland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
