<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61133" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Sept 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Sept 18.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Wednesday morning's Albanian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>KOHA JONE</p>
<p>- A woman died and another woman was wounded when two people exchanged fire in a main street in Tirana on Tuesday.</p>
<p>- The European Commission said in a letter to two opposition parties that it would closely watch the upcoming local elections in Albania.</p>
<p>- In a letter to OSCE chairman Flavio Cotti, four opposition parties denounce a request of President Sali Berisha not to welcome OSCE observers to the local elections.</p>
<p>- Vegetable prices have doubled since last week.</p>
<p>- Heavy rain over the last days has caused many traffic problems in northern Albania.</p>
<p>- A 20-year old man has been detained in the western city of Durres for attempting to sexually abuse an 11-year old girl.</p>
<p>- Omonia, the ethnic Greek minority association in southern Albania, will elect its new leaders this month.</p>
<p>GAZETA SHQIPTARE</p>
<p>- Polio outbreak in Albania claims sixth victim.</p>
<p>RILINDJA DEMOKRATIKE</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Aleksander Meksi said the government had taken all the necessary measures to ensure free and fair local elections.</p>
<p>- The Democratic Party to start its electoral campaign on September 22 for the October 20 local poll.</p>
<p>- Tirana has officially invited OSCE observers for the local elections, parliament's presidency said, denying opposition reports it did not want them to monitor Albania.</p>
<p>ZERI I POPULLIT</p>
<p>- Agim Fagu, famous former basketball player, was chosen by the Socialist Party to run for mayor in the local elections in the capital Tirana.</p>
<p>- Jailed Socialist leader Fatos Nano tells his party to be more actively engaged ahead of the October 20 elections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
