<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61147" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: FEATURE - Russia sees Baikonur as space Eldorado.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Russia sees Baikonur as space Eldorado.</headline>
<byline>Viktor Anoshkin</byline>
<dateline>BAIKONUR COSMODROME, Kazakhstan 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>For Russian space officials, the cosmodrome at Baikonur on the bleak steppes of southern Kazakhstan is an Eldorado in a crisis-ridden industry.</p>
<p>But the people who endure searing winds from the Gobi desert 300 days a year to work at the cosmodrome, which covers an area bigger than Kuwait, see few of the benefits.</p>
<p>Russia has already launched two Western communications satellites from Baikonur this year, earning a total of $96 million.</p>
<p>Another $65 million launch is also planned, said a senior official from the military space forces, speaking from his office in Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the only cosmodrome with sites for launching heavy Proton boosters and other money-making rockets,&quot; said the official, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>An official at the cosmodrome was more direct. &quot;Baikonur has begun to make money and we think it will be big money,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In theory $115 million of the earnings should go each year towards paying the 20-year lease on Baikonur, agreed with the former Soviet republic of Kazakhstan in 1994.</p>
<p>But old inter-state debts mean Russia uses the cosmodrome without paying. &quot;Kazakhstan owes Russia $1 trillion and we use the cosmodrome to help cover this debt,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>While the millions flow to Moscow, the local authorities do not even have enough cash to pay electricity bills.</p>
<p>This, together with the lack of a fresh water supply, makes life hard to bear for much of the year, during which temperatures swing from minus 40 to plus 40 degrees Centigrade (minus 40 degrees Fahrenheit to 104 degrees Fahrenheit).</p>
<p>Most of the staff put up with it, not because they are well paid but because they have neither the means nor the bureaucratic muscle to move to Russia, flooded with refugees from former republics after the Soviet Union collapsed in 1991.</p>
<p>A lieutenant-colonel for the military space forces said the officers who make up the bulk of the cosmodrome's employees have a salary of about 1.5 million roubles ($280) a month.</p>
<p>&quot;But we have not seen this money since June,&quot; said the officer, who declined to be named. &quot;People do not want to stay here any longer...They cannot even go on holiday due to a lack of money,&quot; he said, adding that morale was very low.</p>
<p>The officers and their families live in the small town of Leninsk, named after the Soviet Union's founding father.</p>
<p>The Kazakh goverment recently renamed the town Baikonyr, but street names are still written in Russian and the town bears all the hallmarks of the shabby, communist-era construction spread across the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Here, though, some of the windows in the grey, faceless blocks are still broken from clashes in the town between the local Kazakh inhabitants and the Russians they drove out in 1994 after Kazakhstan claimed ownership of the cosmodrome.</p>
<p>The Russians subsequently moved back but the streets are virtually deserted apart from the few cars and camels whose owners are prepared to brave the extreme temperatures and sandstorms.</p>
<p>Mayor Gennady Dmitrienko said the population had dropped to 50,000 from 80,000 over the past three years. About 10 percent are civilians and the rest are officers. Some 10,000 conscripts are based in nearby barracks.</p>
<p>Dmitrienko was appointed personally by the Russian and Kazakh presidents under an agreement which put an end to the row over control of the cosmodrome through the lease deal which allowed the Russians back.</p>
<p>The first Russians came to Baikonur in 1955 and launched the Soviet Union's first rocket two years later.</p>
<p>Since then there have been two tragedies. In 1960 a rocket exploded on the pad during ground tests killing 120 people, including the artillery marshal Mitrofan Nedelin. Three years later a similar incident killed seven specialists.</p>
<p>The cosmodrome now has three launch zones with 11 pads for the launch of Proton, Soyuz, Zenit, Tsiklon and Rokot boosters.</p>
<p>Two more giant launch pads for the Energia-Buran Soviet shuttle system are obsolete because the Russian space shuttle programme was closed after the Soviet Union collapsed.</p>
<p>Despite a prolonged budgetary crisis, Russia continues to launch manned spacecraft and satellites. In November, it plans to lift a probe to Mars from Baikonur.</p>
<p>Next year the first block of a new Alpha international orbital space station is scheduled to be launched from the cosmodrome.</p>
<p>But monetary problems mean that launches from Baikonur, although the cheapest in the world, can be nail-biting for international satellite owners such as London-based Immarsat.</p>
<p>On the eve of the $36 million launch of the Immarsat satellite on September 6, there was a power cut at the cosmodrome, raising fears, which later proved unfounded, that the launch might simply not take place. ($1=5391 Rouble)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAIKONUR COSMODROME, Kazakhstan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
