<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61199" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexican rebels say to continue guerrilla attacks.</title>
<headline>Mexican rebels say to continue guerrilla attacks.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's Popular Revolutionary Army (EPR) rebels said on Wednesday they would continue to wage &quot;guerrilla war&quot; on government forces and denied they had any intention of demobilizing.</p>
<p>In a statement published in the Mexican press, the group, which emerged in southern Mexico at the end of June, sought to clear up confusion caused by recent reports that it planned a &quot;tactical dispersion&quot; to avoid head-on combat with the army.</p>
<p>&quot;The dispersion and concentration of our forces is (for) preparing and carrying out military offensives. In no way does it mean demobilizing our units, ceasing to fight and even less, watering down (the struggle),&quot; the communique said.</p>
<p>Some Mexican newspapers ran front-page stories on Sunday saying the &quot;dispersion&quot; suggested a scaling-down of the low-level conflict initiated by the EPR in its Marxist struggle for a workers' state.</p>
<p>The confusion emerged after a rebel commander gave a news conference on Friday in the southern state of Oaxaca in which he spoke both of tactical dispersion and of stepping up attacks if military repression increased.</p>
<p>The EPR in late August carried out a series of strikes against military and police units in several southern states and the official death toll was at least 20. But it has not declared full-scale war on the government and says its military actions are part of a &quot;self-defence campaign.&quot;</p>
<p>In Wednesday's communique, the EPR acknowledged its forces were poorly armed compared to the army units combing southern Mexico and it said it would avoid head-on combat if it could. It said its strategy instead was &quot;adapting to our conditions of weaker capacity and firepower, striking with surprise and impact at the time and the place that we choose.&quot;</p>
<p>In a statement issued late on Tuesday, the government said actions by the leftist EPR had diminished in recent days because of operations by security forces. There were fears of attacks ahead of Monday's Independence Day celebrations.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear that even though the activity of the EPR has diminished or has been inhibited by security operations and the general rejection society has shown them, actions of propaganda and intimidation have become their characteristic profile,&quot; the Interior Ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>Reliable assessment of the number of EPR attacks has been made extremely difficult in recent weeks by a government clampdown on information from more remote parts of Mexico where the guerrilla group has been active.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
