<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61195" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>MONTSERRAT: Montserrat volcano spews ash, hot rocks.</title>
<headline>Montserrat volcano spews ash, hot rocks.</headline>
<dateline>OLVESTON, Montserrat 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Montserrat's volcano has rumbled back to life with one of its most powerful eruptions, spewing hot rocks that torched houses and sending a blanket of ash over the capital, its governor said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>For a period of about 12 hours on Tuesday the volatile mountain in the Soufriere Hills sent streams of hot gases and rock down its sides until it went into an &quot;explosive phase&quot; before midnight, Gov. Frank Savage said.</p>
<p>Hot boulders set fire to six homes and damaged six others in the town of Long Ground on the volcano's eastern flank.</p>
<p>&quot;We've gotten quite used to having ash clouds but last night was the first time we've had projectiles thrown out by the volcano,&quot; said Savage, who added that there had been no reports of casualties.</p>
<p>The eruption forced the evacuation of up to 2,000 people from the villages of Richmond Hill and Cork Hill.</p>
<p>The volcano, dormant for more than a century, came to life on July 18, 1995 and has waxed and waned since. Authorities have ordered the evacuation of the capital Plymouth and the southern end of the tiny British colony three times.</p>
<p>The last evacuation, in April, was still in effect. More than 4,000 residents of Plymouth and southern towns remain in crowded public shelters and the homes of family and friends in &quot;safe zones&quot; in the north of the island. The population of the tiny eastern Caribbean island dropped from nearly 11,000 before the first eruption to about 7,000 as residents left.</p>
<p>The eruption on Tuesday left about two inches (5 cm) of ashy mud in the capital and roads coated with pebble-sized pieces of rock, Savage said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there's any doubt that the 12-hour period ... was the most intensive period of volcanic activity since the crisis started,&quot; he said. &quot;The scientists say it's akin to the volcano clearing its throat.&quot;</p>
<p>He said scientists who are monitoring the volcano's activity were not able to predict whether Tueday's activity foreshadowed a climactic eruption.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MONT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OLVESTON, Montserrat"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MONTSERRAT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
