<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61202" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Bonn, Brazil, S.Africa to push global eco policy.</title>
<headline>Bonn, Brazil, S.Africa to push global eco policy.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chancellor Helmut Kohl said on Wednesday that Germany, Brazil and South Africa would push at the United Nations for agreement on a global environmental policy to protect rain forests and ecosystems.</p>
<p>Kohl, passing through Brasilia on a 24-hour visit, said the three would join forces to place the issue on the agenda of a special U.N. general assembly next year.</p>
<p>&quot;Cooperation on environmental policy is of the highest priority,&quot; Kohl told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The three of us together, including South African President Nelson Mandela, and perhaps with Asian countries, will work to push for a global environmental policy at a special U.N. General Assembly next year.&quot;</p>
<p>The veteran German leader, who was on a three-nation Latin American tour accompanied by high-powered German businessmen, earlier lashed out at other Group of Seven countries for not doing enough to help protect the Amazon rain forest.</p>
<p>Bonn's ties with Brazil are essentially economic. But the environment plays a large role and Bonn is the single greatest contributor to a G7-backed pilot programme for the Amazon.</p>
<p>&quot;For us it's important to give the (pilot program) a new boost, a new dynamism,&quot; Kohl said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am extremely pleased to find here that (Brazilian) President (Fernando Henrique) Cardoso regards this problem like I do, that he knows that the preservation of the forests is one of the key issues for the future.&quot;</p>
<p>Cardoso was due to visit South Africa in November. Kohl said he expected one of the key items on the agenda would be a global environmental policy.</p>
<p>The German chancellor was due to leave Brazil later on Wednesday for Mexico.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
