<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="612280" id="root" date="1997-05-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOZAMBIQUE: Mozambique's Chissano re-elected ruling party head.</title>
<headline>Mozambique's Chissano re-elected ruling party head.</headline>
<byline>Iain Christie</byline>
<dateline>MAPUTO 1997-05-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mozambique's ruling Frelimo Party has re-elected head of state Joaquim Chissano as president of the party, a Frelimo spokesman said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The election of the president and other members of the Frelimo Central Committee took place on Friday night at the end of a one-week party congress.</p>
<p>The election ended Mozambican press speculation during the congress that Chissano would step down as party leader, to cultivate the image of a state president above party politics.</p>
<p>This proved unfounded and Chissano stood unopposed.</p>
<p>Of the 653 votes cast, 641 were for Chissano. Three ballot papers were spoiled and nine were blank.</p>
<p>Chissano, 58, was a founder member of Frelimo, created in 1962 to fight for independence from Portugal.</p>
<p>He became foreign minister at independence in 1975 and president of the republic and the party in 1986 when Mozambique was a one-party state, on the death in a plane crash of his predecessor Samora Machel.</p>
<p>After leading the country into a multi-party system, he won a first-round victory in presidential elections in 1994, after a long civil war.</p>
<p>This week's party congress, the seventh since 1962, was held in a huge tent at Matola, an industrial town on the outskirts of the capital Maputo.</p>
<p>The election of Chissano as party leader increases the likelihood of his selection as Frelimo candidate for the next state presidential elections, scheduled for 1999.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAPUTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOZAMBIQUE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
