<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="612364" id="root" date="1997-05-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK's Dragonair suspends A330-300 operations.</title>
<headline>HK's Dragonair suspends A330-300 operations.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong Dragonair Airlines (Dragonair) said on Saturday it has suspended operations of its four Airbus Industrie A330-300 aircraft due to concerns about the reliability of their Rolls-Royce Trent 700 engines.  </p>
<p>&quot;Dragonair has chosen to take the precautionary measure of suspending A330-300 operation until the engine manufacturer can provide sufficient assurance that the reliability problems of the engine are resolved,&quot; the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>It said the decision followed a series of Trent 700 engine failures on A330 aircraft of Dragonair and Cathay Pacific Airways Ltd over the past few weeks, with the latest being on a Dragonair A330 aircraft on Friday.</p>
<p>Flight KA-MH061 from Hong Kong made an emergency landing at Subic Bay in the Philippines on Friday after developing engine trouble en route to Kota Kinabalu in Malaysia.  </p>
<p>&quot;The most recent failure occured on a brand new component of the engine and the possibility of some form of assembly or quality problem cannot be ruled out until a full inspection has taken place,&quot; Dragonair said.</p>
<p>Cathay Pacific also said earlier on Saturday it had suspended operations of its A330-300 fleet of 11 aircraft.</p>
<p>Problems in the Trent 700 engines have forced a series of unscheduled single-engine landings recently.</p>
<p>Dragonair said the problem with an engine part in the Rolls-Royce Trent 700 engine had been &quot;clearly identified and understood&quot; and a long-term design solution had been found.  </p>
<p>&quot;However, as standard procedure, this design will have to be endurance tested before it can be released for service,&quot; it said. &quot;As a result, Dragonair has decided to avoid exposing its passengers and staff to any level of risk however small.&quot;</p>
<p>The carrier said the suspension, with immediate effect, did not affect Dragonair's fleet of seven A320 aircraft powered by IAE V2500 engines.</p>
<p>Swire Pacific Ltd and Cathay Pacific together hold about 26 percent of Dragonair, whose major shareholder is China National Aviation Corp.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6590</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
