<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="612367" id="root" date="1997-05-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Moderate Khatami new Iran president after landslide.</title>
<headline>Moderate Khatami new Iran president after landslide.</headline>
<byline>Barry May</byline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-05-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran's moderate former culture minister Mohammad Khatami was elected president on Saturday in a stunning upset victory over the Islamic republic's conservative establishment.</p>
<p>Final results showed Khatami winning 69 percent of the 29.1 million votes cast in Friday's nationwide ballot, seen by many as a referendum on 18 years of revolution.</p>
<p>His main rival conservative parliamentary speaker Ali Akbar Nateq-Nouri conceded defeat after more than 17 million votes had been counted showing a Khatami landslide and pledged to work with the president-elect.</p>
<p>Supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, whose position commands more authority than the presidency, congratulated Khatami and called on the other candidates and their supporters to back the new president.</p>
<p>Khatami will take over in August from President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani, who must step down after completing the maximum two four-year terms permitted by law.</p>
<p>The result was a major shock to the religious establishment which has ruled Iran since fundamentalist clerics toppled the pro-American Shah in 1979.</p>
<p>Nateq-Nouri had been widely predicted to take the presidency despite what many Iranian analysts and Western diplomats had forecast would be a close contest.</p>
<p>In the event he was relegated to second place with 25 percent of the vote while two lesser-known other candidates were far behind with relatively insignificant numbers of votes. Some 33 million people aged 15 and over were eligible to vote.</p>
<p>Both leading candidates are 54-year-old middle-ranking Shi'ite Moslem clerics. But while Khatami is an outspoken proponent of reforms, Nateq-Nouri is a traditionalist close to influential groups of conservative clerics and merchants.</p>
<p>During the 12-day election campaign Khatami attracted a broad coalition of centrists close to Rafsanjani, Islamist left-wingers and women, youths and intellectuals seeking a more relaxed application of Islamic mores.</p>
<p>The coalition was formed to counter conservatives accused by Khatami's supporters of trying to monopolise state power by adding the presidency to their control of the 270-seat parliament, where Nateq-Nouri holds sway.</p>
<p>Khatami, an ayatollah's son, is considered an open-minded religious intellectual and tolerant politician.</p>
<p>He advocates more personal freedom, democracy and the rule of law in a country of 60 million where many complain that state bodies act arbitrarily and rules are changed according to the whim of officials.</p>
<p>He also appeals to devout Shi'ites because he holds the title Seyyed and wears a black turban -- signs that he is believed to be a descendant of Islam's Prophet Mohammad.</p>
<p>The result was a also blow to Khamenei, who tacitly supported Nateq-Nouri.</p>
<p>Suporters of Khatami were jubilant after he clinched his shock victory with some shop owners handing out boxes of sweet cakes to friends and customers. But celebrations were muted as many Iranians observed a Shi'ite mourning month.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm shocked. I really thought it would go to a second round...The winner is freedom,&quot; said Behrooz, a 45-year-old housing agent, relaxing with friends.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very happy. It was very important that Nateq-Nouri did not become president. For the first time the people have rejected what the establishment wanted,&quot; said Mitra, a 20-year- old woman student in a main Tehran shopping street.</p>
<p>Iran's state security apparatus stepped up its profile on key Tehran highways and intersections early as daylight ended.</p>
<p>The government's Guidance Patrol stopped cars to enforce strict Islamic dress codes on drivers and passengers while police and plainclothes security were also evident.</p>
<p>One woman driver wearing the compulsory hejab (headscarf) was rebuked by a female member of the Guidance Patrol outside her car for wearing make-up which is not officially tolerated.</p>
<p>At least one other young woman was put into a white coach with red windows by the patrol. The patrol usually detains violators of dress codes overnight.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
