<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="612418" id="root" date="1997-05-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tongass plan reduces allowable timber cut.</title>
<headline>Tongass plan reduces allowable timber cut.</headline>
<byline>Yereth Rosen</byline>
<dateline>ANCHORAGE, Alaska 1997-05-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Logging in the largest U.S. national forest will be allowed at only half the level of past years under a final 10-year plan issued Friday by the U.S. Forest Service.</p>
<p>The Forest Service's Tongass Land Management Plan called for an average logging cap of 220 million to 267 million board feet a year for the next decade in the Alaskan forest.</p>
<p>That compared to the 450 million board foot annual cap set by the previous 10-year plan.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a balanced plan. I am confident it will sustain all forest resources over the long haul,&quot; Alaska Regional Forester Phil Janik said in a teleconferenced news briefing from his Juneau office.</p>
<p>Logging supporters claimed the Tongass National Forest plan will starve the southeast Alaska timber industry. Environmentalists said it neglected fish and wildife protections needed to repair damages of past over-logging.</p>
<p>The head of an Alaska timber industry group disputed Forest Service claims that more logging would damage the Tongass.</p>
<p>&quot;It's all pseudo-science. What they've done is they've beefed up the so-called habitat protections for a problem that doesn't exist. It's to solve a perception that's obviously pervasive along the Potomac and in New York,&quot; said Jack Phelps, executive director of the Alaska Forest Association.</p>
<p>His group and two local governments have entered an agreement to appeal the plan and may sue to overturn it.</p>
<p>But Greg Petrich of the Alaska Rainforest Campaign said the new Tongass plan still accomodated high-volume operations, even though both of the regions pulp mills -- fueled by low-priced, contract-supplied timber -- have closed.</p>
<p>With the region's tourism and fishing industries booming, &quot;The trees are worth more standing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The new Tongass plan calls for increased protection of fish and wildlife, such as 1,000-foot no-logging buffer zones along streams and beaches. It also includes protections for the forest's fragile limestome caves, which hold newly discovered archaelogical and paleontological relics.</p>
<p>Janik said he hoped the environmental protections would make it unnecessary for the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to list two Tongass subspecies -- the Alexander Archipelago wolf and the Queen Charlotte goshawk -- as threatened.</p>
<p>Alaska's all-Republican congressional delegation -- strong backers of the timber industry -- vowed a review of the plan.</p>
<p>&quot;This huge reduction (in logging) means no real benefit for the animals and plants, but it does mean lost potential for Alaskans who work for a living in the wood products industry,&quot; Rep. Don Young, chairman of the House Resources Committee, said in a statement.</p>
<p>But Democratic Gov. Tony Knowles praised the plan as balanced, and said its release would help southeast Alaska communities plan their economic futures.</p>
<p>Tongass is a 17-million acre forest that sprawls over steep mountains, vast glaciers and thousands of thickly wooded islands in southeast Alaska.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANCHORAGE, Alaska"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
