<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="612528" id="root" date="1997-05-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Peru's Fujimori arrives in Bangladesh.</title>
<headline>Peru's Fujimori arrives in Bangladesh.</headline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1997-05-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peruvian President Alberto Fujimori on Saturday arrived in Bangladesh to a warm welcome from his hosts but noisy protests by left-wing political and student groups.</p>
<p>Bangladesh President Shahabuddin Ahmed and Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina received Fujimori at Dhaka airport as military guards fired a traditional salute.</p>
<p>As Fujimori drove into the capital city in a motorcade, left-wing students demonstrated outside Dhaka University.</p>
<p>&quot;Go back Fujimori, you are not welcome here,&quot; chanted the students as riot police struggled to keep them from the streets, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Several political groups demonstrated in Dhaka on Friday against Fujimori's visit and vowed more protests during his stay.</p>
<p>&quot;We denounce the visit of Peru's hated President Fujimori who has dealt inhumanely with anti-fascist revolutionaries, including communist leader Abimael Guzman,&quot; said a leader of the Democratic Revolutionary Council during Friday's protest.</p>
<p>Guzman, leader of Peru's Maoist Shining Path rebels, was captured in 1992, which his followers called a severe blow to human rights and principles of freedom.</p>
<p>Dhaka protesters called Fujimori, the first South American head of state to visit Bangladesh, an &quot;agent of U.S. imperialism,&quot; and criticised the Bangladesh government for inviting him.</p>
<p>Government officials said Hasina and Fujimori would hold formal talks on Sunday aimed at fostering economic relations and trade.</p>
<p>&quot;The trade between the two countries has been negligible,&quot; one official said without giving details.</p>
<p>He said the talks would be followed by the signing of two agreements on trade promotion and technical cooperation.</p>
<p>Fujimori, who flew to Dhaka from Vietnam, will go to India from Bangladesh on Sunday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
