<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="612667" id="root" date="1997-05-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER-AT LAST &quot;KAISER&quot; FRANZ CAN ENJOY HIS KINGDOM.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-AT LAST &quot;KAISER&quot; FRANZ CAN ENJOY HIS KINGDOM.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-05-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chairman Franz Beckenbauer was so caught up in the moment that he chose to hug a fellow Bayern Munich board member before turning to kiss his wife sitting next to him.</p>
<p>The two second-half goals which clinched Bayern a 4-2 victory over VfB Stuttgart and a record 14th German championship on Saturday had ended a turbulent time at the Bundesliga's most glamorous club.</p>
<p>After a season packed with so many scandals that the German media nicknamed the club &quot;Hollywood F.C.&quot;, the relief on the faces of Beckenbauer and vice-chairman Fritz Scherer was clear to see as they celebrated the triumph in the VIP box.</p>
<p>After largely dominating German football in the 1970s and 1980s, Bayern have found life hard in the 1990s with the emergence of European Cup finalists Borussia Dortmund as a major force and a much more competitive Bundesliga.</p>
<p>Before Saturday Bayern had just two titles to their name in the current decade -- in 1990 and 1994.</p>
<p>The Bavarians have been desperate for another taste of the glory days when Beckenbauer and business manager Uli Hoeness led the team to three European Cup triumphs in consecutive years in the mid-1970s during their playing days.</p>
<p>Beckenbauer admits he would rather spend his days playing golf, concentrating on his business and media interests and enjoying life with his wife.</p>
<p>But in the past few seasons the former World Cup-winning coach and captain has done everything possible to get Bayern back into the top echelons of European football, including taking the chairman's job and at times coaching the team.</p>
<p>It is ironic that Bayern's triumph has come in a season when, for the first time, second place would have been good enough for a place in the lucrative Champions' League. But that was irrelevant to Bayern. They had to win the championship.</p>
<p>Beckenbauer has faced a season when the team have produced some calamitous performances at times and there has been bickering and back-stabbing in the dressing rooms. Striker Juergen Klinsmann is leaving the club because of the strife.</p>
<p>&quot;Bayern is a bit of a kitchen of gossip but it has been like that in the past, &quot; Beckenbauer said. &quot;We have done something special this season. It has not always run smoothly. But German football can be satisfied.&quot;</p>
<p>Hoeness added: &quot;The Hollywood tag came from the media. We didn't want it. But it's true that we have had too many arguments in the past at this club. Disputes that are part of every team managed to get out into public.&quot;</p>
<p>Munich's Olympic stadium has witnessed some wild celebrations over the years. But this was special.</p>
<p>Gerd Mueller, the brilliant striker who inspired Bayern in the 1970s before the club helped him overcome a long battle against alcoholism, was hugging players and officials on the bench at the end of the match.</p>
<p>Former Wimbledon champion Boris Becker, the club's most prominent fan who knows many of the players well, stood for several minutes at the end of the match just soaking up the jubilant atmosphere.</p>
<p>Yet Hoeness was soon talking about the future and bringing people down to earth. In addition to Klinsmann, who is joining Italy's Sampdoria, Bayern will lose German international wing-back Christian Ziege to AC Milan next season.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not possible for any club to win three European trophies like we did in three (consecutive) years (in the 1970s),&quot; Hoeness said. &quot;The economic power of too many European clubs is took big for that now.</p>
<p>&quot;Then there were three or four clubs capable of doing that. Now there are at least 10.&quot;</p>
<p>Nevertheless when Dortmund come to the Olympic stadium to take on Juventus in the European Cup final on Wednesday, Beckenbauer and Hoeness will sit in the stadium dreaming of seeing Bayern in the same position next season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
