<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="612636" id="root" date="1997-05-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: TENNIS-GRAF WORRIES MORE ABOUT FITNESS THAN RANKING.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-GRAF WORRIES MORE ABOUT FITNESS THAN RANKING.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>For the first time in years Steffi Graf will not start the French Open as the top seed but the German, fighting her way back after a long injury break, says she has other things to worry about.</p>
<p>&quot;I wish I could only worry about that,&quot; Graf, second to Swiss teenager Martina Hingis in the world rankings, told a news conference on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;My ranking is not even on my mind. I have to concentrate on how I've been playing lately and on how I will be playing in the next few weeks.&quot;</p>
<p>Graf's fitness is one of the big question marks before the Paris tournament starting on Monday even though her confidence has been boosted by victory in Saturday's Strasbourg tournament final.</p>
<p>The German made her comeback in the German Open in Berlin the previous week after a three-month lay-off with a knee injury but her run ended in the quarter-finals when she was bundled out by Amanda Coetzer of South Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm slowly getting into the rhythm again but I certainly would have needed more time to be fully fit,&quot; she said. &quot;There are certain periods during which I play really well, then I have some lapses in between, which means my concentration is not there all the time.</p>
<p>&quot;Another problem is that I need to strengthen my muscles. There's still quite a big difference in the way the muscles are defined between the right and the left leg &quot;</p>
<p>Hingis is also coming back after a knee injury but hers was not quite as bad.</p>
<p>&quot;I know she had to stop playing for a few weeks but she will still be a major threat,&quot; Graf, who has won the French Open five times, said.</p>
<p>Everybody will be looking for a final showdown between Graf and Hingis, who ousted her from the top of the rankings in March. But Graf said others could win.</p>
<p>&quot;There's Arantxa (Sanchez-Vicario), who's always good here, and Mary Pierce, who has been playing very well lately&quot;, she said.</p>
<p>Graf said women's tennis was far more competitive nowadays than when she started her career.</p>
<p>&quot;It was the reign of Chris (Evert) and Martina (Navratilova),&quot; she said. &quot;There was little room for other players. Now it's different.</p>
<p>&quot;You see quite a few players with a chance of winning a tournament like this one. It's a change and it's a good thing for women's tennis, no question.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
