<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="612769" id="root" date="1997-05-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Plugged In: Souping up the Pay Phone.</title>
<headline>Plugged In: Souping up the Pay Phone.</headline>
<byline>Russell Blinch</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>What is your definition of a kiosk?</p>
<p>Is it a terminal you stop by at any given moment and retrieve useful and entertaining information, seemingly invaluable for everyday living whilst you are out shopping or before boarding a plane?</p>
<p>Or is it something you pass by in an airport or a mall which contains useless tidbits and is invariably adorned with a hand-written &quot;out of order&quot; sign?</p>
<p>Perhaps, of late, the latter definition is most apt. But look out: the venerable electronic kiosk could be making a comeback, aided by multimedia technology and Internet connectivity.</p>
<p>A small Canadian concern, King Products Inc., announced last week a plan to team up with a much larger Hong Kong telecommunications concern to produce an Internet-ready, multimedia unit called the PowerPhone.</p>
<p>King (www.kingproducts.com) has an initial $2.2 million order to supply the phones to INFA Telecom Asia Ltd., which in turn plans to install them in Hong Kong and throughout China.</p>
<p>For a little extra media splash, INFA Telecom plans to have the souped up payphones installed in the Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Center in time for the hand over ceremony marking the transfer of the British colony to China. The wall-mounted unit is a combination pay phone and networked computer with a touch-sensitive color screen.</p>
<p>One could just imangine that the late Great Helmsman -- Mao Tse-Tung -- enthusiastically surfing the Net on the PowerPhone during the some of the slower parts of the hand over ceremony.</p>
<p>But back to reality. Users of the PowerPhone will have access to such things as an electronic telephone directory, advertising and hotel and restaurant information. As well, the phones will soon have access to the Internet and e-mail.</p>
<p>The research firm Frost &amp; Sullivan (in a study graciously supplied by King Products) sees the demand for Kiosks rising from 64,000 units in 1997 with a value of $562 million to 445,000 units with a value of $2.9 billion by 2003. &quot;Strong growth is projected as Internet use, financial applications, and retail applications for kiosks spur demand,&quot; the report stated.</p>
<p>King also wants to take this concept to North America but could not say when it might happen. U S West, however, announced in April it has begun setting up its own Internet-capable pay phones at airports, supermarkets, restaurants and in other areas in Seattle and Denver. Internet connection will be made over the speedier ISDN (Integrated Services Digital Network) line.</p>
<p>&quot;We see this as a growth center for the payphone business,&quot; says Steve Dennis, a general manager for U S West. &quot;As wireless phones have proliferated, the pay phone business has not exactly been a center of growth for carriers.</p>
<p>Not everyone is convinced that the new vending machines of the 1990s will be so popular. Rick Broadhead, co-author of the Canadian Internet Handbook, wonders if Internet-ready kiosks, especially the pay phone type, might prove to be little more than a fad.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they might serve a niche market but they might also go the way of the Internet coffee house,&quot; said Broadhead. Internet coffee houses seem to rise up and fold within a few short months and one of the reasons may be that Internet browsing is not a public activity.</p>
<p>He also notes that a phone booth is not the most comfortable place to surf the net, especially if you got someone tapping you on the shoulder while some honking graphic comes dripping into focus.</p>
<p>But he acknowledges specific Internet applications could prove useful, including mapping or reservation services. An electronic directory with quick searching capabilities might also be popular, especially to replace those phone books that contain all the pages except the one you need. - - - -</p>
<p>For ideas or comments on the weekly Plugged In column contact: russell.blinch@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
