<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="612783" id="root" date="1997-05-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - May 26.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - May 26.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE DOMINION</p>
<p>Peters unimpressed by Henare comment: NZ First leader Winston Peters found &quot;not helpful&quot; comments by his deputy Tau Henare floating the idea of a Maori party, a spokesman for Peters said on Sunday. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Gresham joins fight against fast super vote: The referendum on superannuation should be delayed, former social welfare minister Peter Gresham said on Sunday night. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Shipley points to ACC changes: ACC Minister Jenny Shipley promised on Sunday to get tough with doctors who abused the ACC system. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>MAS heads for listing on Nasdaq: Lower Hutt electronics firm MAS technology, formerly Marine Air Systems, has decided to bypass the New Zealand Stock Exchange and has applied to list on the Nasdaq market in the United States. Page 11.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Kiwi expected to fall against US, Aussie: The New Zealand dollar should fall against the American and Australian dollars in the next few months, but exporters should not expect too much easing, according to the ANZ Bank. Page 11.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Power plant to cut Mercury's costs: Mercury Energy's cost of electricity is expected to drop when it fires up its Poihipi geothermal power plant in about three weeks. Page 12.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE NEW ZEALAND HERALD</p>
<p>Weekend of blood stains city: Answers lacking to rising tide of crime and violence: Two murders, one policeman in hospital, four shootings over the weekend raise questions about Auckland.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>TransAlta lines up Wairarapa: Wairarapa Electricity, owned by South Easterms Utilities, is being tipped as a takeover target for neighbouring power company TransAlta.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Anchor spreads funds in British market: Traditional Anchor butter is to get a promotional push in Britain with the money which was due to be spent on its spreadable equivalent.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Software set for US explosion: Sales of IBM's NZ-developed telephone company customer and billing software are poised for a growth explosion due to the deregulation of the United States telecommunications market, IBM says.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE PRESS</p>
<p>Man's acquittal ends a nightmare: An American acquitted in an Arkansas court three days ago of the murder of his former girlfriend, wants to return to his Christchurch home as soon as possible.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Kiwi above A90c: Manufacturing exporters will be watching the currency market today after the New Zealand dollar's spurt against the Australian dollar on Friday.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
