<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="612792" id="root" date="1997-05-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Fall in NZ trade balance trend continues in April.</title>
<headline>Fall in NZ trade balance trend continues in April.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand's merchandise trade balance trend continued to decline in April, Statistics New Zealand (SNZ) said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The imports trend has risen from a low point in October 1996 by an average of 1.2 percent per month. The exports trend has recorded an average monthly decline of 0.9 percent from a high point in September 1996,&quot; SNZ said.</p>
<p>The trade balance for April showed a surplus of NZ$55.3 million, down $67.3 million on the April 1996 surplus. Comparing against the year-ago figures, unadjusted imports (worth NZ$1.91 billion) were up 13.7 percent while exports (worth $1.96  </p>
<p>billion) rose nine percent.</p>
<p>For the year ended April, the trade deficit was valued at NZ$541.1 million, compared with a $997.7 million deficit in the year ended April 1996.</p>
<p>Unadjusted exports for the year ended April were valued at $20.93 billion, up 1.9 percent on the previous April year. The major export commodities were milk powder, butter and cheese valued at $3.51 billion, meat valued at $2.72 billion and wood valued at $1.54 billion.  </p>
<p>Unadjusted imports for the year ended April were valued at $21.47 billion, down 0.3 percent from the previous year. The major import commodities were mechanical machinery (valued at $3.37 billion), vehicles ($2.86 billion) and electrical machinery ($2.2 billion).</p>
<p>SNZ said that excluding large irregular items, such as aircraft and ships, the deficit for the April 1997 year would have been reduced to $436 million.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom (64 4) 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
