<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="613050" id="root" date="1997-05-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French interest rate futures seen down on election.</title>
<headline>French interest rate futures seen down on election.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>French PIBOR interest rate futures were expected to open sharply lower on Monday after the left outpolled the right in first round of France's parliamentary election, analysts said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The spread between the yield on French and German government bonds was also expected to narrow, but much less dramatically.</p>
<p>&quot;The 10-year (bond) spread (over Germany) could be knocked into single digits (from minus 14), but I'm not convinced it will be hit too badly,&quot; said Iain Lindsay, senior bond strategist at Credit Lyonnais.  </p>
<p>&quot;(June) PIBOR could lose 20 centimes or maybe more. The franc will depend on the will and the purchasing power of the Bank of France to hold it in check,&quot; Lindsay added.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly if it got above 3.38 and targetted 3.40, PIBOR would get hit badly. PIBOR moves will probably be ahead of the currency if (the franc) is being articficially supported.&quot;</p>
<p>The franc slipped as low as 3.3755 per mark from 3.3714 after first election predictions came out with the selling pressure coming from non-resident institutions trading in New York, foreign exchange traders said.  </p>
<p>A futures trader at a French bank was shocked by the results and said the fact the centre-right coaltion appeared to have polled less than 38 percent would be key.</p>
<p>&quot;From my from point of view anything below 38 percent was going to be a sell short, just because it seemed to us anything below that would mean an unworkable majority,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If these results are any indication it's going to be a big, big change. I would say if it's near the Sofres percentages, 25 basis points (off June PIBOR) is very realistic,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>June PIBOR settled on Friday at 96.47, implying three month interest rates of 3.53 percent, 14 basis points above three-month cash market rates.</p>
<p>The June contract slumped as low as 96.26 after the snap election was called on April 21 but recovered during the campaign as opinion polls suggested the centre-right coaltion would win, albeit with a smaller majority.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we'll see it tomorrow. I think it will take final results - but if it continues in this trend I certainly see it down there next week. The short-term jolt should be 10-15 basis points,&quot; the trader said.  </p>
<p>He said the French June bond future had looked poised for a break after trading in a fairly narrow range last Friday and the election predictions ensured it would be a break lower.</p>
<p>It will open a gap lower &quot;which technically fits in with what saw on Friday...without the election we were looking for breakout and now it's obviously going to break to the bottom&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Specifically, we're getting remarkably close to very strong trend line back to March 1995 which sits about 127.65. I would not be surprised to see it get back to that, possibly this week,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The June bond future closed at 129.00 on Friday. It fell as low as 127.06 after the election was called but, like PIBOR, gained ground as more and more people bet on a return to power for the centre-right coaltion.</p>
<p>Philippe Brossard, head of research at ABN Amro Finance said, &quot;I see PIBOR (June interest rate future) off 10 basis points at least. 96.38 would be a good level but it may be a touch lower.</p>
<p>&quot;The 10-year spread (between the French OAT and German Bund) could be minus eight or minus six basis points (from minus 14 now) and the two-year spread could widen by about eight basis points,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5542</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
