<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="613023" id="root" date="1997-05-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: EU talks over cheap Australia, NZ dairy imports.</title>
<headline>EU talks over cheap Australia, NZ dairy imports.</headline>
<byline>Peter Blackburn</byline>
<dateline>MIDDELBURG, Netherlands 1997-05-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union farm ministers gathered on Sunday in the southern Dutch town of Middelburg for three days of informal talks on the future for more than one million dairy farmers.</p>
<p>In Middelburg, Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler is due to present an analysis showing that high EU dairy prices will result in further erosion of its 45 percent world market share to cheaper New Zealand and Australian competitors.</p>
<p>The Netherlands, which presides over EU meetings until the end of June, had pushed the issue to the top of the agenda because as a major exporter of cheese and other dairy products it wants to compete for expanding world markets.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be the first time that we discuss it,&quot; Dutch Farm Minister Jozias Van Aartsen told Reuters, referring to a round-table discussion on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The aim is to start the discussion, not more. No solution is possible here,&quot; added EU Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler.</p>
<p>Van Aartsen said a a study by the EU's executive commission showed that radical changes were not needed in the short term because the EU would still be able to export its surplus milk.</p>
<p>But he stressed that it was vital the EU should remain a major exporter, noting the special importance of the dairy sector in the Netherlands.</p>
<p>The Dutch want to press on with a review of national production quotas and subsidised prices in preparation for the next round of World Trade Organisation (WTO) negotiations starting in 1999 and for the EU's expansion eastwards.</p>
<p>Most of the 15 EU member countries, led by Germany, want to extend the quota system, which is due to expire at the end of March 2000, saying it has stabilised the dairy market and helped to keep thousands of smaller farmers in poor areas in business.</p>
<p>But EU Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler noted that several countries were pressing for reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a clear blocking minority in favour of bigger changes,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Sweden, Britain, Denmark, Italy and Spain are demanding either the dismantling or modification of production quotas.</p>
<p>Milk quotas and prices are explosive issues as shown by protests in France last week by angry farmers who blocked deliveries to hypermarkets and poured thousands of litres of milk onto the road to protest against falling prices.</p>
<p>The EU is by far the world's largest dairy producer, with an annual output of 120 million tonnes, or just over 20 percent of world production.</p>
<p>Although the report makes no proposals, it signals that prices will have to be cut if the EU is to continue to export its annual surplus of around nine million tonnes of milk despite stricter curbs on export subsidies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIDDELBURG, Netherlands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
