<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="613148" id="root" date="1997-05-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-Election seen hitting Paris bourse hard.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Election seen hitting Paris bourse hard.</headline>
<byline>Christine Tierney</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>French stocks are likely to fall hard on Monday, traders said on Sunday after projections of the first round of a parliamentary election put the left well ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;Few people were expecting results like this,&quot; said chief trader Olivier Blitz at IFF Bourse. &quot;I expect it (the stockmarket) to open down at least two percent.&quot;</p>
<p>Bourse investors had bet on a good showing by the conservative RPR-UDF coalition and drove the blue-chip CAC-40 up 0.78 percent to close at 2,762.90 points on Friday.</p>
<p>But projections broadcast after voting ended at 1800 GMT on Sunday gave the opposition Socialists, Communists, extreme-left and other left candidates between 40.6 and 41.6 percent of the vote, with the ruling RPR-UDF and other moderate-right candidates scoring between 36.1 and 37.1 percent.</p>
<p>Polling firms forecast the RPR-UDF coalition would win fewer than the 289 parliamentary seats required for a majority in the runoff vote next Sunday, while the Socialists were projected to win as many as 270 seats and their Communist allies 30.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just the opposite of what the polls were showing. We can easily expect a two percent fall tomorrow,&quot; said equities salesman Laurent Careno at brokerage Kleinwort Benson.</p>
<p>Some bourse operators said the market could easily lose five percent in the week ahead of next Sunday's runoff election.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect people to take cover tomorrow. I wouldn't be surprised to see the market fall three to four percent, even with Wall Street's (1.2 percent) rise&quot; on Friday, said Jacques Chahine, head of his consulting firm Jacques Chahine Finance.</p>
<p>He said he expected the CAC index, which has risen nearly 20 percent this year, to fall to 2,400-2,450 if the left wins the runoff, leading to an uneasy &quot;co-habitation&quot; between Gaullist President Jacques Chirac and a parliament dominated by the left.</p>
<p>Although the U.S. and British markets will be closed for holidays on Monday, traders said they expect the big foreign brokerage houses to react on Monday to Sunday's vote results.</p>
<p>U.S. and British investors bought French stocks on expectations of a conservative win, said GAN analyst Pascal Nigen. &quot;A lot of them will be disappointed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nigen said he expected the market to fall five percent next week after its recent gains to near records.</p>
<p>&quot;We could see a downside correction in the area of five percent next week,&quot; concurred Credit Lyonnais equities strategist Michelle Jardin.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though the decisive results will be after next week's poll, the market will be nervous,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The franc and French bonds are also expected to fall on the first-round results, but economist Marie Owen-Thomsen at Banque Internationale de Placements said she expected the stockmarket to react more sharply.</p>
<p>&quot;The bourse risks to see more selling than the bond market, which had pulled back on Thursday and Friday,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Jean-Pierre Filbien, director of Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in Paris, said the CAC could fall to 2,600-2,650 points this week and to as low as 2,350 if the left wins the runoff.</p>
<p>Traders were divided as to whether big blue chips such as luxury goods group LVMH and retailer Carrefour would be seen as safehavens or attract profit-taking.</p>
<p>Blitz at IFF said he expected oil majors Elf Aquitaine and Total to get hit after recent rallies.</p>
<p>Traders said stocks in the banking and auto industries would be vulnerable to investor concerns that the Socialists would frown on painful restructurings entailing job losses.</p>
<p>Careno at Kleinwort Benson said stocks involved in privatisations such as Thomson-CSF and rival bidders Alcatel Alsthom and Lagardere would be affected. &quot;If the Left wins, they could block the privatisation of (the state's 58 percent stake) in Thomson-CSF,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Traders said the market will be watching for signs this week that the conservatives may try to improve their chances by dropping unpopular Prime Minister Alain Juppe.</p>
<p>They said the market will also welcome &quot;centrist-sounding&quot; remarks by the Socialists.</p>
<p>Any effort by the Communists to obtain pledges from the Socialists for ministries in exchange for their cooperation will make the bourse nervous, as will attacks by the National Front on the conservatives, traders say.</p>
<p>Traditionally, voters for the National Front have tended to tilt toward the conservatives in the runoff vote.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
