<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="613365" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NSea crudes steady on holiday, Urals still pressed.</title>
<headline>NSea crudes steady on holiday, Urals still pressed.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Physical North Sea crudes were notionally unchanged on Monday with many market players absent due to a bank holiday in Britain, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very quiet, we did not have that many customers in the office today and all those were waiting for the others to come into the market,&quot; a trader at a Norwegian producer said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very quiet with the holiday in Britain and the United States. I am doing paper work,&quot; a second trader said. The United States markets were closed for Memorial Day holiday.</p>
<p>A June 9-11 Brent traded on Friday at a high July Brent +17 cents, a price which some traders have said would unlikely to be matched this week due to weaker demand.</p>
<p>The rise of the price of Brent, the North Sea benchmark grade, since the start of May by some $2.50 per barrel has hurt refiners' margins and some have already cut runs to curtail their losses.</p>
<p>The Norwegian trader said most of the Norwegian grades were steady, drawing strength from the fact that there are no May cargoes left unsold.</p>
<p>But other traders have noted that the Norwegian crudes may have hit their peak, adding that the bad refining margins would cut demand for them.</p>
<p>A number of deals for Statfjord, Oseberg and Draugen were reported done late on Friday but no details were available immediately.</p>
<p>London's International Petroleum Exchange was also closed on Monday. July Brent had settled at 18 cents lower on Friday at $20.00 a barrel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
