<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="613378" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: World durum prices should continue to rise - CWB.</title>
<headline>World durum prices should continue to rise - CWB.</headline>
<dateline>WINNIPEG 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>World durum wheat prices should continue their rise due to drought stressed durum crops in North Africa, a Canadian Wheat Board market analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;The key factor there continues to be the drought in North Africa. The demand outlook remains very positive for durum and of course what happens in North America is going to be key too because the U.S. and Canada typically account for 75 percent of durum exports,&quot; CWB market analyst Larry Sawatzky said.</p>
<p>The CWB increased its world price estimate Thursday by C$12 a tonne for No1 Canada Western Amber Durum wheat to C$208.00-C$238.00 a tonne in-store Vancouver or St. Lawrence.</p>
<p>That's a 6.1 percent increase from April's world price estimate for No1 CWAD at C$196.00-C$226.00 for crop year 1997/98 (Aug/July).</p>
<p>The drought in Algeria, Morocco and Tunisia was comparable to those of crop years 1994/95 and 1995/96 when durum saw its last price peaks, Sawatzky said.</p>
<p>Agriculture Canada on May 7 forecast 1997/98 (Aug/July) Canadian durum supplies at 6.365 million tonnes and exports at 3.8 million tonnes with ending stocks at 1.6 million tonnes after supplying domestic markets - the lowest carry out since the 1994/95 crop year.</p>
<p>&quot;Generally, the supply-demand situation looks quite tight, the dryness in southern Europe is going to have a negative impact on the European durum crop so that's going to be a positive factor too,&quot; Sawatzky said.</p>
<p>Southern Alberta and southeast Saskatchewan, where 80 percent of Canada's durum wheat crop is traditionally grown, was almost completely seeded by last week.</p>
<p>Soil moisture conditions were dry and expected to become a concern in early June unless the region received a significant rainfall, the CWB has said.</p>
<p>((Gilbert Le Gras, Winnipeg Reuters bureau 204 947 3548))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINNIPEG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
