<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="613343" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: PRESS DIGEST - HUNGARY - MAY 26.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - HUNGARY - MAY 26.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories reported by Hungary's press, based on information by Nepszabadsag's Hungary Around the Clock service. For further details on how to subscribe to Hungary Around the Clock, please contact Monica Kovacs at (361) 351 7142 or fax your request to (361) 351 7141.</p>
<p>ALL PAPERS</p>
<p>-- Gabor Kuncze, acting president of the junior government coalition member party Free Democrats (SZDSZ) easily captured the post of party president at Saturday's congress of the party, taking 490 votes against 13.</p>
<p>-- A heated debate arose at Saturday's meeting of the netional board of the senior government coalition member party Socialists (MSZP), with some members calling on Prime Minister Gyula Horn to resign from the post of party president.</p>
<p>-- Janos Latorcai, chairman of the opposition Christian Democrats (KDNP) national board said he would not run for the post of party president and was ready to convene a session of the national board to elect new executives.</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Gyula Horn ruled out cooperation the far- left Workers' Party and the far-right Hungarian Justice and Life Party.</p>
<p>-- The opposition Smallholders Party (FKgP) urged speedingh up Hungary's preparations for joining the NATO and the European Union.</p>
<p>-- The parliament expects to begin debating bills related to a reform of the pension system this week, despite the opposition having voiced its reservations by walking out of the house committee's meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- President Arpad Goncz, thye first Hungarian head of state this century to visit Romania, held talks with President Emil Constantinescu after arriving in Bucharest on Sunday on a three-day official visit.</p>
<p>-- Defense Minister Gyorgy Keleti said on Sunday that a one billion forint tender for fighter aircraft will be launched after the Madrid NATO summit in July, where it is expected to be revealed which countries will be invited to join NATO.</p>
<p>-- Hungary's credit rating may improve further as the institute IBCA announced it is to revise its reting to the National Bank of Hungary, president of the central bank Gyorgy Suranyi said.</p>
<p>NAPI GAZDASAG</p>
<p>-- The National Bank of Hungary (NBH) may decide in June top allow foreigners to conduct futures foreign exchange deals in Hungary, NBH vice president Zoltan Bodnar told journalists on Friday.</p>
<p>-- PanTel Rt, the telecommunications company set to bring thet monopoly of Matav to en end, will be set up without the use of state funds, a government body decided on Friday.</p>
<p>VILAGGAZDASAG</p>
<p>-- The bradcaster Antenna Hungaria generated pre-tax profit of 610 million forints in 1996, exceedingg projections of breaking even.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
