<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="613505" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania parliament votes in new chief spy.</title>
<headline>Romania parliament votes in new chief spy.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's parliament endorsed on Monday a proposal by President Emil Constantinescu to appoint a political ally to head the country's intelligence service, whose former chief quit amid allegations of illegalities.</p>
<p>A joint session of parliament's two chambers passed with 381 votes for and 11 against the nomination of Costin Georgescu as director of the Romanian Intelligence Service (SRI).</p>
<p>&quot;I will take the most serious action against those willing to involve the SRI in politics,&quot; Georgescu told parliament after the vote.</p>
<p>Georgescu, 55, was Constantinescu's chief fund-raiser in the presidential election that brought him to power last November and main political strategist in the 1992 campaign in which Constantinescu finished a distant second.</p>
<p>He was elected to parliament last year for the Democratic Convention, the electoral bloc forming the backbone of the centrist coalition backing the president.</p>
<p>Under the rules, Georgescu will have to give up his seat in the lower house of parliament.</p>
<p>Virgil Magureanu was the first head of the SRI, which emerged as the successor to the all-pervasive communist-era Securitate in 1990, months after the bloody upheaval which toppled dictator Nicolae Ceausescu.</p>
<p>Magureanu left the job last month but had indicated his intention to resign before Constantinescu's election victory last November over ex-communist Ion Iliescu. He often came under attack from liberals who accused him of meddling in politics to block reforms.</p>
<p>Many Romanians believe the former Securitate still influences public life.</p>
<p>Last month, Magureanu's spokesman had made plain that he was leaving his job after the new government had come under pressure from diplomats for him to go.</p>
<p>Magureanu was one of several witnesses filmed attending the summary trial of Ceausescu and his wife Elena after they fled Bucharest during the December 1989 uprising against communist rule. Both were executed on Christmas Day.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
