<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61355" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai opposition blames economic slowdown on PM.</title>
<headline>Thai opposition blames economic slowdown on PM.</headline>
<byline>Vithoon Amorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Thai opposition on Wednesday blamed Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa for the country's economic problems and said he risked further damaging exports and the stock market by resisting calls to quit.</p>
<p>Opposition leaders, headed by former premiers Chuan Leekpai and Chatichai Choonhavan, focused on economic issues in their blistering attack on Banharn in the first part of a confidence debate against him in parliament.</p>
<p>The Thai economy in 1996 is projected by private economists to grow at its slowest pace in a decade.</p>
<p>They see gross domestic product growing as little as 6.2 percent in 1996 against 8.6 percent in 1995. The government expects it to dip below a target of 7.8 percent.</p>
<p>Exports rose 3.8 percent in the first seven months of the year against 26.2 percent a year ago. Overall, 1996 exports are forecast to rise by about six percent against 23.6 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>Chuan and senior opposition members of parliament said Banharn had not sustained fiscal discipline.</p>
<p>They also said Banharn's choice of unqualified people to fill economic portfolios had led to a serious loss of confidence among Thai and foreign investors.</p>
<p>The debate on the opposition-launched no-confidence motion against Banharn was expected to last three days.</p>
<p>&quot;We have said from the outset that the people you chose for your economic portfolios were not suitable for the job,&quot; Chuan said in a speech in parliament.</p>
<p>Banharn's two finance ministers during his 14 months in office, Surakiart Sathirathai and Bodi Chunnananda, and commerce minister Chucheep Hansawat, have been under fire for the prolonged slide in the Thai stock market and high food prices.</p>
<p>The exchange's composite SET Index has under-performed most regional Asian markets, losing about 20 percent this year.</p>
<p>Banharn, resisting pressure to step down, has said the slowing economic trends started during Chuan's previous government and his coalition should not be blamed alone.</p>
<p>He has also denied accusations of incompetence and economic mismanagement.</p>
<p>Chuan accused Banharn of failing to sustain Thailand's long-standing conservative fiscal policy by approving supplementary national budgets for fiscal years 1996 and 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The extra budget fuelled inflation and widened the current account deficit. The issue is not how much was the supplementary budget. The issue is it reflected a disregard for fiscal disciplines that eroded public confidence in prudent Thai economic policies...,&quot; Chuan said.</p>
<p>Supachai Panichpakdi, a former deputy premier, said some Thai finance firms with cashflow problems had turned to the Bank of Thailand for help in the past month to meet funding needs, while many Thai companies would post growing losses for the third and fourth quarters.</p>
<p>&quot;The spectre of bankruptcies is looming for the private sector...it would not be soft or hard landing. It would be a crash landing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Supachai said rising oil prices and an 8.3 percent Thai minimum wage hike in October would make the government miss its adjusted 5.5 percent inflation target this year.</p>
<p>He projected the Thai consumer price index to rise 6.3 percent for 1996 against 5.8 last year. The central bank earlier projected 1996 inflation at only 4.9 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
