<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61367" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong's Hang Lung seen reporting flat profit.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong's Hang Lung seen reporting flat profit.</headline>
<byline>Kathleen Kearney</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Residential property developer Hang Lung Development Ltd is expected to announce sluggish earnings for the year ended June 30, slowed by a thin land bank and a dependence on sites with less demand, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Hong Kong developer is expected to announce zero to single-digit percentage growth in earnings for the year ended June 30, analysts said.</p>
<p>Hang Lung will release its results on Friday alongside its 57.6 percent held subsidiary Amoy Properties Ltd and 60.62 percent held Grand Hotel Holdings Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;The company failed to replenish its landbank during the downturn in the market,&quot; says Adrian Ngan, property analyst at Peregrine Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The projects (and sites) that it has on hand are not sufficient to sustain earnings growth in the long-term.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said the company's concentration of residential development projects outside Hong Kong's urban core in the New Territories district, where an oversupply is forecast, was another negative.</p>
<p>Carol Lai, research manager at Amsteel Securities Research Ltd, said Hang Lung's projects were located in Tuen Mun, Tai Po and Maanshan, where other large developers have major projects.</p>
<p>Because of its small landbank and limited number of projects, Hang Lung is the only residential property developer to book profits on a percentage of completion basis in stages before a project are fully completed.</p>
<p>&quot;Hang Lung is the hardest (developer) to gauge because it uses the percentage of completion basis, said Lai. Most other developers book profits after a project is completed and a government occupation permit is received.</p>
<p>Hang Lung reported net profit of HK$2.16 billion (US$279 million) in the year ended June 1995, up 6.88 percent from the previous year.</p>
<p>Amsteel is forecasting earnings growth of 5.2 percent for Hang Lung for 1996 and a pick up to 13 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>Peregrine's Ngan is forecasting flat earnings growth to HK$2.167 billion for the company in 1996.</p>
<p>For 1997, Ngan said he expected the company to show a 16.7 percent decline in earnings, subject to upward revision if 1996 prices for flats look firmer than forecast, he said.</p>
<p>Given the 1997 forecast and despite the share's low valuation of only 8.96 times historic, Ngan said the share was fairly valued and recommended a sell.</p>
<p>Since the bulk of Hang Lung's assets are in subsidiary Amoy, the company's shares always trade at a deeper discount to the market than other developers, Ngan said.</p>
<p>&quot;Only when we see a greater discrepancy (in valuations) open up between Amoy and Hang Lung will we see Hang Lung move up,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Hang Lung shares fell HK$0.05 to HK$15.10 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>(US$1=HK$7.73)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
