<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61362" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong to issue gold coins to mark 1997 handover.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong to issue gold coins to mark 1997 handover.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong said on Wednesday it would issue a limited edition of commemorative gold coins next July to mark the British colony's return to Chinese rule.</p>
<p>The 1997 commemoratives would bear Hong Kong's floral emblem, the ubiquitous tree orchid, or purple bauhinia flower, on the obverse, with a design of the territory's skyline on the reverse, the government said in a statement.</p>
<p>The 22-carat gold coins would have a face value of HK$1,000 (US$128) and would be sold by inviting public applications, and, if too many orders came in, by drawing lots, the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;Making it legal tender adds appreciably to its attractiveness and value in the eyes of the collectors,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The government did not say how many coins would be minted.</p>
<p>Hong Kong becomes an autonomous Special Administrative Region of China on July 1, 1997, under a &quot;one country two systems&quot; policy aimed at reintegrating lost Chinese territories.</p>
<p>China's central bank intends to issue its third set of Hong Kong-related commemorative coins on the date of the handover.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I49100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
