<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="613836" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: BT Fund Managers sees HK's Hang Seng at 15,500 pts.</title>
<headline>BT Fund Managers sees HK's Hang Seng at 15,500 pts.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>BT Fund Managers Ltd said on Monday it had set a year-end target for Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index of 15,500 points but positive liquidity flow could push the blue chip index to 16,000 or beyond.</p>
<p>&quot;Short-term we might get close to 15,000,&quot; BT Fund Managers vice president Dio Wong told a news conference.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index shot into new record territory on Monday, surging 242.96 points, or 1.70 percent, to an all-time closing high of 14,574.64.</p>
<p>The index hit an intra-day record high of 14,581.35.</p>
<p>Wong said earnings growth of close to 20 percent this year, a healthy property market, stable interest rates, and continued smooth economic growth in China should underpin share price rises.</p>
<p>Even if the U.S. Federal Reserve did decide to raise interest rates later in the year, &quot;the downside in Hong Kong is not going to be too large,&quot; said Wong.</p>
<p>He said red chips should continue to dominate the market but investors should be cautious, particularly since Chinese authorities were likely to introduce measures on asset injections over coming months.</p>
<p>&quot;It is my belief that they are promulgating a set of rules at the moment...Some of these assets are being sold too cheaply,&quot; said Wong. &quot;I would not be surprised if in the next two or three months we see a set of rules come out.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Mature&quot; red chips should continue to perform well, but he said there were some &quot;developing&quot; or &quot;dark horse&quot; categories whose market capitalisations were &quot;ridiculously out of proportion to their assets and earnings&quot;. In the long run, the mania for red chips was not healthy, Wong added.</p>
<p>He said there was likely to be a period during the second half of the year when the overall market would stagnate. But he said prices should then rally into the year end.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on a conducive liquidity environment, we think that banking and particularly property stocks can continue to perform well for the rest of the year,&quot; said Wong. &quot;Our view is that we will see another small uptick in the property market of around 10 percent from the recent bottom.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
