<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61385" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia regrets Australian union shipping ban.</title>
<headline>Indonesia regrets Australian union shipping ban.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia said on Wednesday it regretted a rolling ban by Australia's powerful Maritime Union on Indonesian shipping as a protest against the recent arrest of two independent labour leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;Such kind of incidents are regretted and will harm the efforts to build up relations between the two countries,&quot; Foreign Minstry spokesman Ghaffar Fadyl told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the two countries had being trying to strengthen ties with the three-day official visit of Australian Prime Minister John Howard which ended on Wednesday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;Probably this kind of thing will have the strongest reaction from the business sector who are most affected,&quot; Fadyl said, declining to make any further comments until the nature of the rolling bans was made clearer.</p>
<p>The union said in a statement on Wednesday the rolling bans were to protest against the recent arrests of independent labour leaders Muchtar Pakpahan and Dita Sari and what it said was continuing repression following the July riots in Jakarta.</p>
<p>The bans were also a response to Howard's failure in Jakarta this week to press Indonesia on the issue of human rights and democracy, the union said.</p>
<p>The first ship to be hit by the rolling bans will be the Bogasari Empat, due to arrive in Fremantle on the Western Australia coast late on Wednesday to load wheat, it said.</p>
<p>The ship will load wheat as scheduled but will not be allowed to leave right away after loading. Instead it will be delayed 24 hours,</p>
<p>Sari was detained in early July in Indonesia's second city of Surabaya after a labour protest. Pakpahan was arrested following the July 27 riots in Jakarta on subversion charges, which carry a possible death sentence.</p>
<p>The riots followed a police raid on the headquarters of the minority Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI) to evict supporters of Megawati Sukarnoputri, who had been ousted as party leader by a government-backed faction the previous month.</p>
<p>Pakpahan is a prominent government labour critic.</p>
<p>The Australian union bans on Indonesian shipping threaten to hit A$2.4 billion worth of Australian commodity exports covering wheat, refined petroleum, cotton, livestock, aluminium and iron and steel.</p>
<p>The first commodities to be held up by the 24-hour bans will be wheat and livestock, while cotton will also be especially hard-hit, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Australia's biggest single disclosed export to Indonesia is refined petroleum and oils, worth A$282 million in 1995.</p>
<p>Petroleum ranks second to a confidential catch-all category for Australian exports, worth more than A$300 million last year and, analysts say, dominated by wheat.</p>
<p>But cotton will be a clear casualty of protracted bans.</p>
<p>Indonesia, now Australia's largest customer for cotton after overtaking Japan in recent years, last year imported A$205 million worth of the Australian product.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
