<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="613830" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: FOCUS-HK stocks seen surging on liquidity wave.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-HK stocks seen surging on liquidity wave.</headline>
<byline>Alison Leung</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks are likely to soar further before the May index futures' expiry on Thursday, supported by hefty cash inflows, red hot red-chips and a turnaround in the property market, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>Fresh liquidity surging into the market in search of red-chips and derivatives-linked stocks sent the Hang Seng Index to close Monday above the psychological barrier of 14,500.</p>
<p>The blue-chip barometer rose 242.96 points, or 1.70 percent, to close at record of 14,574.64, a touch below an all-time high of 14,581.35 hit earlier.</p>
<p>Turnover was a record HK$20.59 billion, surpassing the previous high of HK$18.04 billion set on May 12.</p>
<p>Considering the strength of the cash inflows and derivatives traders' interest in push up the futures market before Thursday's settlement date, the Hang Seng should move higher in the short term, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's quite possible that the strength could be sustained until Thursday before major profit-taking sets in,&quot; said Percy Au-Young, research director at DBS Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;In the longer-term on Relative Strength Indicator (RSI), there is still some room to move before reaching the overbought level of 80,&quot; he said. This meant the index could move up to 15,000 before reaching the long-term overbought level, he added.</p>
<p>Money was seen flowing in from overseas -- particularly from China after Beijing took measures to curb speculation on its own stock markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Overseas investors believe Hong Kong is still cheap,&quot; Henry Lui an analyst at Mansion House Research, adding that investors also liked Hong Kong's higher liquidity.</p>
<p>Brokers said the latest market rise also reflected optimism that property prices were rebounding.</p>
<p>Developers released very little supply onto the market in April and May, and banks had been willing to finance purchases, said Michael Green, property analyst at Salomon Brothers.</p>
<p>&quot;This has pushed residential property prices back up,&quot; he said. &quot;We should see a strong response to sales programmes in June,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>However, brokers said investors would still focus on red chips which accounted for six of the 10 most traded stocks on Monday.</p>
<p>The Yamaichi index monitoring 49 red chips, surged 152 points or 5.8 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The rise of the red-chips is beyond fundamentals, and players are purely speculating on the asset injection hopes,&quot; one broker said. Investors hoped the red chips' influential Chinese parents would sell lucrative Chinese projects to their listed arms in Hong Kong at attractive prices.</p>
<p>This drove Beijing Enterprises Holdings Ltd's initial public offering subscription multiple to a record of between 1,250 and 1,300 times. Dealing in the shares was scheduled to start on Thursday.</p>
<p>But the market was also vulnerable to profit-taking following the recent steep market surge. &quot;I am not confident in buying at the current high price level anyway,&quot; said Michael Ng, dealing director, at Sassoon Securities.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6369</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
