<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="613996" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany remains committed to euro, Waigel says.</title>
<headline>Germany remains committed to euro, Waigel says.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Busvine</byline>
<dateline>DUESSELDORF, Germany 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel vowed on Monday that Germany would press ahead with efforts to qualify for Europe's single currency even as political fighting over tough budget decisions erupted in Bonn.</p>
<p>Speaking at a conference on European economic and monetary union (EMU) organised by Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democratic party, Waigel sought to reassure Germans that the country was on course to qualify.</p>
<p>Waigel also said Bonn's plan to revalue its gold and currency reserves will not undermine the solidity of the Bundesbank and said Germany was committed to a strict interpretation of Maastricht criteria on monetary union.</p>
<p>&quot;The reorganisation of the accounts of the Bundesbank will be undertaken with the required caution,&quot; said Waigel. &quot;The financial solidity of the Bundesbank will be maintained.&quot;</p>
<p>Waigel has come under intense criticism for the proposal to revalue the Bundesbank's vast holdings. He said that Germany will insist on strict adherence to budget deficit limits spelled out in the Maastricht treaty.</p>
<p>&quot;For the government, a narrow and strict application of the treaty rules when examining convergence is vital. Markets and citizens expect that,&quot; he said. &quot;Both houses of parliament and the constitutional court have demanded strict and narrow&quot; interpretation.</p>
<p>Separately, the leader of Germany's main opposition party, Oskar Lafontaine, warned that the basis of the single European currency would be undermined if tax systems across the continent were not harmonised.</p>
<p>Lafontaine said it was unacceptable for European Union countries to compete against one another for jobs and investment by cutting taxes and social contributions for employers, leaving workers to pick up the tab.</p>
<p>&quot;If a harmonisation of tax systems does not take place, then European economic and monetary union will be based on weak foundations,&quot; he told a meeting of his Social Democrats (SPD).</p>
<p>The new currency, the euro, would help put an end to the currency market fluctuations which had damaged all European economies in the past, Lafontaine said.</p>
<p>&quot;We want the currency union because we expect long-term benefits for the labour market all over Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>Speaking in the northwestern city of Duesseldorf, Waigel also warned against the idea of weakening the Maastricht treaty target requiring public deficits totalling no more than three percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>&quot;I warn against such a discussion which would lead to a reaction not only in Germany,&quot; he said. He also said no countries would be given special consideration.</p>
<p>&quot;A chain is only as strong as its weakest link. Therefore only equally strong stability-based (countries) can join in at the start of currency union,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Waigel added that it would be possible for countries to join EMU later through the revised exchange rate mechanism while pressing on with efforts to converge with the euro-countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody will be discriminated against or left behind, but the euro-countries will offer all the others an anchor of stability.&quot;</p>
<p>In order to meet the Maastricht borrowing requirement, Waigel said he would press ahead with privatisation of state property holdings and shares in Deutsche Telekom AG.</p>
<p>He would also maintain tight control on departmental spending, and said he did not rule out the option of a budget freeze.</p>
<p>The pressure on Germany to qualify for EMU prompted an unusually public rift between Waigel and Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt over the weekend was led Kohl on Monday to tell them to stop bickering in public.</p>
<p>Kohl, himself taking no position on whether Germany would need to raise taxes to ensure it meets Maastricht criteria for European economic and monetary union, said calm discussion rather than public rowing was in order.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's talk to each other first before we start talking about each other,&quot; Kohl told journalists at a meeting of executives of his CDU in Bonn.</p>
<p>Rexrodt abandoned all show of ministerial solidarity to condemn recent critical comments from Waigel as a &quot;transparent manoeuvre to distract from his own faults&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUESSELDORF, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
