<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="613942" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Albright to send senior U.S. envoy to Congo.</title>
<headline>Albright to send senior U.S. envoy to Congo.</headline>
<byline>Carol Giacomo</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Secretary of State Madeleine Albright is to send U.N. Ambassador Bill Richardson for the first senior-level U.S. talks with Laurent Kabila since the former rebel took power in the Democratic Republic of Congo, U.S. officials said on Monday.</p>
<p>Richardson, who established a relationship with Kabila on an earlier trip to the region, would push the new leader of the former Zaire to establish a broad-based government that would pursue economic and political reforms, the officials told Reuters.</p>
<p>Albright &quot;decided to send Richardson to the Congo with a U.S. delegation to begin some senior-level discussions on what we would like to see happen&quot; in that key central African nation after Kabila's rebel alliance ousted President Mobutu Sese Seko after three decades in power, one official said.</p>
<p>The U.S. team was expected to leave Washington very soon, he added.</p>
<p>France has a political-business delegation at present in the mineral-rich former Zaire and French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette told Albright during talks on Monday that the early effort to lay down ties with Kabila was proving worthwhile, officials said.</p>
<p>U.N. envoy Richardson, who has often been a trouble-shooter for the Clinton administration, was in the region several weeks ago as rebel troops advanced on Kinshasa and has since been in contact with Kabila by telephone.</p>
<p>For some weeks, as it became evident Kabila's forces would soon gain control of Zaire, the United States urged Kabila to include other members of the country's political opposition in a broad-based post-Mobutu government and to hold early elections.</p>
<p>Initial signs are, however, that Kabila is ignoring Washington's viewpoint or reacting in a confusing way to it. Kabila's alliance has told political parties in the former Zaire to suspend activity and there has been talk of not holding elections for two years.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns acknowledged Monday that &quot;with Kabila we don't know which way he is going to go&quot; but the United States still believes &quot;we can work with him&quot;.</p>
<p>Because Kabila is now the main powerbroker in the former Zaire, Washington seems to have little choice but to make the best of the situation. It has warned Kabila that U.S. support for bilateral and international assistance to his country depends on his commitment to economic and political reforms.</p>
<p>But U.S. officials so far have refused to say if a decision by Kabila to defer elections for as long as two years would be cause for blocking that aid.</p>
<p>Albright and de Charette discussed the former Zaire at length on Monday during talks at the French Foreign Ministry and afterwards both told reporters their two countries were cooperating well there, contrary to media reports.</p>
<p>Burns told reporters that during the meeting, de Charette had raised the &quot;shocking treatment&quot; of refugees in and around the Kisangani region, many of whom were found massacred.</p>
<p>&quot;Both of us believe that there ought to be actions taken by Mr. Kabila to make sure that these terrible indignities to the refugee population are not committed in the future and that some accounting must be made for those atrocities,&quot; Burns said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
