<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61407" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Morocco reduces jail term for French drug smuggler.</title>
<headline>Morocco reduces jail term for French drug smuggler.</headline>
<dateline>TANGIER, Morocco 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Moroccan court on Wednesday cut to 18 months a jail term imposed on a Frenchman for drug trafficking, the official MAP news agency said.</p>
<p>Charles Gerard Schmitt, 28, was arrested in July at the northern port of Tangier while loading his vehicle for Spain. Police found 500 kg (1,100 lbs) of cannabis resin hidden in his vehicle, MAP said.</p>
<p>Schmitt was sentenced the same month by the court of first instance to two and a half years imprisonment, it said</p>
<p>His arrest helped the authorities to dismantle a drug traffickers network in which foreigners were involved, the agency said but gave no details.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, a court in Tangier cut to six months a jail sentence imposed on an 68-year-old French woman, sentenced with her husband for smuggling drugs.</p>
<p>It quashed the original three year term imposed on Jeanne-Marie Gagneux because of her health. But it confirmed the four-year sentence on her husband, Andre aged 69.</p>
<p>Police last week arrested two British nationals and a Frenchman on drugs charges and accused the Britons of being part of an international drug network run from Spain.</p>
<p>Earlier this year Morocco launched a crackdown on drugs smuggling in which a dozen international drug trafficking networks were dismantled, the interior ministry said.</p>
<p>Dozens of German, French, Spanish, British, Italian and Hungarian drug traffickers were arrested.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TANGIER, Morocco"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
