<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="614187" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: WALL ST WEEK AHEAD/Puzzled Wall Street may stall.</title>
<headline>WALL ST WEEK AHEAD/Puzzled Wall Street may stall.</headline>
<byline>Mary Kelleher</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street is in a quandary about U.S. economic growth: is it too strong, is it starting to slow or is it just right?</p>
<p>The Federal Reserve's decision last week to leave interest rates alone instead of raising them, put against a background of ambiguous economic data, has unsettled equities.</p>
<p>Analysts said they expect stocks to shift in a narrow and uninspiring range this week until they get a better sense of which is the bigger concern: inflation or growth.</p>
<p>&quot;There's still a lot of uncertainty in the market about the Fed's next move,&quot; Pierre Ellis, senior economist at Primark Decision Economics said. &quot;I think the market is going to be flat (this) week, trading within a 100 point range.&quot;</p>
<p>On Friday, the Dow Jones Industrial Average jumped 87.78 points to close at a record high of 7345.91. For the week it closed up 151.24 points.</p>
<p>The pre-Memorial Day rally Friday also pushed the Nasdaq composite up 17.12 points to a record closing peak of 1389.72.</p>
<p>John Cleland, chief investment strategist at Security Benefit Group of Cos, predicted the market will not show a clear trend this week.</p>
<p>&quot;The Fed's decision not to change rates has unsettled markets,&quot; he said. &quot;There is no clear direction on interest rates and it is hard for stocks to make headway in that environment.&quot;</p>
<p>The Fed could attack inflation at its next meeting in July, raising interest rates. Or, analysts said, if the Fed were to feel the economy was slowing by itself, this might signal Wall Street that corporate profits will suffer.</p>
<p>&quot;The market now thinks Greenspan did not do anything with interest rates because he was worried the economy was slowing down,&quot; Peggy Farley, managing director of Amas Securities.</p>
<p>Wall Street &quot;will look closely at economic data for signs of slowdown, more than is desirable,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Durable goods orders for April, due out on Wednesday, would receive a fair amount of attention, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Durable goods could show if demand is really slow going into the second quarter, as some recent data has suggested,&quot; Ellis said. &quot;If it is very strong, that could add to the case of the Fed tightening.&quot;</p>
<p>The Commerce Department will also issue its second estimate for first quarter gross domestic product on Friday, after an initial estimate of 5.6 percent, but this was not seen as factor that will move shares.</p>
<p>&quot;There could be technical revisions with small changes in its various components,&quot; Ellis said. &quot;But it would have to be a pretty big revision to really shake a market.&quot;</p>
<p>As with last week, data-sensitive bonds could direct and also compete with stocks this week, analysts said.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year benchmark has been flirting with a key seven percent level. Rising yields could prompt money managers to shift money from stocks to bonds and cash.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be okay as long as we stay under the seven percent yield,&quot; Peter Canelo, chief investment strategist at Dean Witter, said.</p>
<p>The 30-year Treasury bond closed Friday with a 6.99 percent yield.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
