<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="614184" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian bonds open little changed in quiet market.</title>
<headline>Canadian bonds open little changed in quiet market.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian bonds opened little changed in very quiet trade on Monday, with the closing of the U.S. market for Memorial Day keeping flows almost non-existent, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's nothing really to talk about today. We're closed,&quot; said one long bond trader with a bank-owned brokerage.</p>
<p>Canada's 30-year benchmark bond traded unchanged at C$111.10 to yield 7.062 percent. The U.S. 30-year bond last traded with a yield of 6.99 percent on Friday. The spread between the bonds was unchanged at seven basis points.  </p>
<p>While there was no official close planned for the Canadian bond market, dealers said activity was expected to trail off with the U.S. market closed for Memorial Day and London observing a banking holiday.</p>
<p>Trading volumes have also remained low because several brokerages are sponsoring golf tournaments on Monday, which will keep many traders from the market.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, dealers said the focus for the week was likely to be new supply in Canada and the United States. Canada has a five-year bond auction on Wednesday, while the United States has bond auctions on Wednesday and Thursday.  </p>
<p>&quot;We've got supply to deal with on Wednesday, and there's a possibility that polls could rattle the market one way or another through the week as we get closer to the big event. But I think people feel pretty comfortable the way the whole process has unfolded,&quot; the bond trader said.</p>
<p>Recent polls show the ruling Liberal party appears set to be re-elected with a majority government when the Canadian election is held on June 2.</p>
<p>In other prices, Canada's 10-year benchmark bond traded unchanged at C$103.30 to yield 6.529 percent. The U.S. 10-year bond traded with a yield 6.75 percent at Friday's close.  </p>
<p>The negative spread between the two bonds was 22 basis points.</p>
<p>The three-month cash T-bill traded with a yield of 2.87 percent against its U.S. equivalent, which yielded 5.15 percent.</p>
<p>((Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
