<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="614240" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Lebanon growth down in first quarter - Banque Audi.</title>
<headline>Lebanon growth down in first quarter - Banque Audi.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leading Beirut bank signalled on Monday that Lebanon's economic growth fell in the first quarter of 1997 to its lowest level since billionaire Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri took office nearly five years ago.</p>
<p>Banque Audi said in its quarterly economic report that growth fell not only below the four percent annual rate recorded last year but also below the three percent registered in the first quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Growth in the first quarter of 1997 slowed down significantly. In terms of annual rates, it fell from the four percent reported in 1996,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;Internal sources of growth appeared to have run dry. Consumption was sluggish and investment fell,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>In a break with its usual practice, Banque Audi did not give a figure for first quarter growth. However, it referred to &quot;relative stagnation&quot; in comparison with the first quarter of 1996 when it reported growth at three percent.</p>
<p>A rate of less than three percent would be the lowest Lebanon has experienced since Hariri took over in October 1992 with a mandate to rebuild the country after the 1975-90 civil war.</p>
<p>It would compare with a growth target of 10 percent a year set in Hariri's multi-billion dollar reconstruction programme.</p>
<p>According to Banque Audi, estimated GDP growth was eight percent in 1994, seven percent in 1995 and four percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Banque Audi said sluggish consumption and disappointing demand in the first quarter resulted from &quot;depression in the political and business environments&quot; and the cumulative effects of the government's adjustment policies.</p>
<p>Industry continued to sell off stocks and investment fell, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Compared to the first quarter of 1996, both public and private investment decreased, according to our estimates, by almost 14 percent in nominal value, thus negatively affecting growth and confirming the slowing down of activity.&quot;</p>
<p>Other negative indicators included a continued decline in the growth of bank loans to the private sector and deterioration of the state's debt ratios.</p>
<p>Banque Audi also cited a 59.67 percent budget deficit in the first quarter compared with a planned shortfall of 36 percent.</p>
<p>- Beirut editorial (9611) 345723 345740 602057</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
