<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="614206" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE oil products flat, gasoline softer on UK budge.</title>
<headline>NWE oil products flat, gasoline softer on UK budge.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>NWE oil products were largely unchanged on Monday and little business was done with markets in the U.S. and the U.K. shut for public holidays, traders said.</p>
<p>Eurograde gasoline barges were valued by one trader as being a shade weaker than the $212 paid late on Friday, although numbers were very notional. &quot;Make of that number what you will,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>British newspapers said over the weekend their new Labour government's first budget, which is expected to include a duty increase on gasoline, may be delayed from June 10 to June 25 or even July 2.</p>
<p>Traders said this delay would exert a downwards pressure on prompt gasoline barge prices and ease the front-month backwardation in the swaps markets as a number of players had already started to hoard duty-paid gasoline in anticipation of the budget.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no point stockpiling it now and paying for tankage if it is going to sit there for a few more weeks,&quot; one player said. &quot;So I expect to see a bit more selling in the short term.&quot;</p>
<p>Heating oil was lacklustre, and flat.</p>
<p>High sulphur fuel oil barges were also little changed and valued at around $80/$82 fob ARA. Dealers fear increasing exports of Russian barrels may soon exert a downwards pressure on prices.</p>
<p>-- Nicholas Shaxson, London newsroom +44 171 542 8167</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
