<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="614330" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French bank shares hit hard by election worries.</title>
<headline>French bank shares hit hard by election worries.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in French banks were badly hit on Monday by fears about the future of reforms in the sector following the left's upset win in the first legislative election round, traders said.</p>
<p>Among the decliners, BNP was off 5.63 percent at 248.20 francs on 798,987 shares traded at 1450 GMT, Societe Generale was down 5.17 percent at 660 francs on 381,888 shares traded and Credit Commercial de France was 4.20 percent lower at 253.0 francs on 154,589 shares.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC 40 index of 40 leading stocks was off 3.73 percent.</p>
<p>BNP was hardest hit because it had risen most in the past week, traders said, and would benefit greatly from reforms to the sector.</p>
<p>Shares in Credit Lyonnais tumbled 5.41 percent to 220.50 on 63,000 shares traded after having gained sharply amid hopes of early privatisation. The Socialists have said they will put privatisations on hold.</p>
<p>Pascal Decque of CDC Bourse said that traders had been expecting a victory by the right and believed this would bring swift much-needed reform to the banking sector.</p>
<p>The reforms included ending competitive distortions in the banking sector involving state-backed savings schemes and allowing longer bank opening hours.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was expecting a lot of reforms in the sector but now there's a big question mark,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
