<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="614383" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: San Paolo share offer confounds doubters.</title>
<headline>San Paolo share offer confounds doubters.</headline>
<byline>David Jones</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>San Paolo's successful share offering illustrates there is good interest in Italian banking stock when management makes a good presentation and promises an improving trend in results, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>Italy's biggest bank completed its week-long share offering last Friday with an offer price fixed higher than many analysts had forecast given the poor past performance of Italy's banking sector with a surprising strong level of investor interest.</p>
<p>San Paolo di Torino announced on Saturday the final price to the public of its share offer would be a 2.5 percent discount to Friday's closing share price at 10,435 lire ($6.26) a share while for institutional investors the price would be 10,630 lire.</p>
<p>Many analysts had expected price to be a critical element in the offer, and had suggested that it needed to be close to 10,000 lire a share to attract strong investor demand.</p>
<p>But good presentations from San Paolo, improvements it has made over the last 18 months and promises of more to come convinced many investors that this was a stock with plenty of potential for the future as Italy's banking sector restructures.</p>
<p>&quot;The price was certainly better than expected at the beginning of the week with investors impressed by the objectives that the management had set,&quot; said Marco Nascimbeni, Italian equity specialist at Merrill Lynch in Milan.</p>
<p>But others thought the shares were good value, and now the bank was in effect fully privatised the management could continue to make changes and transform itself into a banking group in the northern European model.</p>
<p>&quot;At the end of the day, the price represents good value and the big positive is that San Paolo is now finally privatised,&quot; said banking analyst Francesco Ricciulli at brokers Pasfin.</p>
<p>The share prices reacted favourable on Monday rising 0.82 percent to 10,790 lire despite a lower overall Milan market.</p>
<p>San Paolo's global offer was for 220 million shares, or a 26.96 percent stake, sold by the bank's controlling foundation bringing its own stake below 20 percent. The share issue raised around 2.3 trillion lire.</p>
<p>A green shoe over-allotment of 33 million extra shares is now likely to be triggered with the offer more than three times oversubscribed with demand seen for around 760 million lire.</p>
<p>But the success is not likely to lead to an avalanche of new share issues in the banking sector with prime privatisation candidate, Italy's largest savings bank Cariplo, now a talks with Ambroveneto.</p>
<p>($ = 1664 Italian Lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
