<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="614447" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: China to keep dollar after 1997 - Chinese official.</title>
<headline>China to keep dollar after 1997 - Chinese official.</headline>
<dateline>ST GALLEN, Switzerland 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Chinese official denied on Monday that Beijing would ban the Hong Kong dollar and replace it with the renminbi after it takes over the British colony later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people suspect that the Chinese government will not allow the circulation of two currencies in Hong Kong after 1997,&quot; Shangquan Gao, a university professor and member of the Beijing committee preparing for the handover, told the International Managment Symposium.</p>
<p>&quot;They speculate that the Hong Kong dollar will be replaced by the renminbi and the relationship of the Hong Kong dollar to the U.S. dollar will be cut off. This is a misunderstanding,&quot; the Beijing University professor said.</p>
<p>He said the Basic Law stipulated that Hong Kong will enjoy autonomy in monetary and financial policy.</p>
<p>It also established a fundamental financial relationship between Hong Kong and the mainland that foresees &quot;two currencies, two currency systems and two currency authorities within a single country&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore the Hong Kong dollar will not dissolve and the renminbi will not replace the Hong Kong dollar. The Hong Kong dollar in the mainland and the renminbi in Hong Kong will each be regarded as a foreign currency.&quot;</p>
<p>Gao said Hong Kong would also maintain its fixed exchange rate of 7.8 Hong Kong dollars to the U.S. dollar -- a mechanism adopted in 1983 -- beyond 1997 as well.</p>
<p>&quot;After 1997, the Special Administrative Region of Hong Kong will stick to this linked exchange rate mechanism because it fits with Hong Kong's reality,&quot; the former Bank of China board member said.</p>
<p>&quot;As an economy with foreign trade as a mainstay, Hong Kong's monetary policy must make the stabiity of the exchange rate its most important target,&quot; he said, adding the link to the dollar had supported the Hong Kong dollar's stability and promoted economic development.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST GALLEN, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
