<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="614565" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia's Wills sues Philip Morris over new brand.</title>
<headline>Australia's Wills sues Philip Morris over new brand.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian cigarette maker W.D. &amp; H.O. Wills Ltd said on Monday it had launched legal action against U.S. tobacco giant Philip Morris for misleading and deceptive conduct over a key Wills cigarette brand, Horizon.</p>
<p>Wills said it discovered last week that Philip Morris planned to launch a cigarette brand packaged almost identically to Horizon in terms of colour, lettering and imagery and accused it of trying to 'pass off' the new brand as Horizon.</p>
<p>Wills said Horizon had been the fastest growing cigarette brand in the Australian market and had achieved a 14 percent market share since its launch in 1991.</p>
<p>&quot;We will use every available means to protect Horizon from attack by this me-too product,&quot; Wills corporate communications manager Catherine Byrne said in a statement.</p>
<p>The two companies will first meet in court on Wednesday, a Philip Morris Australia Ltd spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have considered the material provided (by Wills) and have briefed our lawyers,&quot; Philip Morris Australia's corporate affairs manager, Nerida White, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Wills, 67 percent owned by Britain's B.A.T. Industries Plc, made a A$13.27 million ($US10.1 million) profit in calendar 1996 in a turnaround from a loss of A$5.16 million in 1995 caused by a price war.</p>
<p>The head of Philip Morris's Australian subsidiary, Henry Goldberg, said in April that he expected another cigarette price war to erupt in Australia by June that could cost the sector A$100 million in earnings in 1997.</p>
<p>Rothmans Australia Ltd is the other main cigarette maker in Australia.</p>
<p>(A$1 = US$0.76)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
