<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="614558" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia says China no threat, seeks trade boost.</title>
<headline>Australia says China no threat, seeks trade boost.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia on Monday sought to reassure China it did not regard Beijing as a military threat, rejecting claims Canberra was involved in a strategy to contain China as its military and economic power grows.</p>
<p>Ahead of talks on Tuesday with Chinese Vice-Premier Zhu Rongji, Foreign Minister Alexander Downer told parliament the government was keen to strengthen its relations with China and boost trade and investment.</p>
<p>&quot;For Australia's part it is quite untrue that we see China as a threat,&quot; Downer said.</p>
<p>&quot;We see nothing of the sort. We totally repudiate the suggestion by those who argue that Australia is part of some containment strategy of China.&quot;</p>
<p>Beijing has previously expressed concern that Canberra's newly-strengthened defence ties with the United States were part of a strategy to contain China, using Japan as the northern anchor and Australia as the southern.</p>
<p>The government-run China Daily revived those concerns on Monday in a lengthy opinion piece attacking the 14-month-old conservative government's moves to strengthen defence links with the United States.</p>
<p>Australia and Japan last year sealed separate pacts with the United States to boost defence defence co-operation.</p>
<p>&quot;Through the joining of the two alliances, the two pincers become more powerful and it is reasonable to believe they're pointed against China,&quot; the China Daily said in an article reported by Australian media.</p>
<p>Downer said that while trade and investment were the centrepiece of Zhu's Australian visit, Canberra would also discuss the start of planned bilateral talks on human rights, and Australia's push to boost ties with its Asian neighbours.</p>
<p>Zhu was scheduled to arrive in Canberra from Adelaide later on Monday for a dinner with Treasurer Peter Costello before talks on Tuesday with other political leaders. He arrived in Australia on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's also very importantly a great opportunity for us to reinforce the view we hold in this country ... that we have a very deep partnership with countries such as China in the Asia-Pacific region,&quot; Downer said.</p>
<p>&quot;The visit by Zhu Rongji is yet another step forward in developing Australia's very broad and deep relationship not just with China but with Asia generally.&quot;</p>
<p>The Liberal-National government, while continuing the previous Labor administration's push for a greater role in Asia, has also moved to strengthen ties with Australia's traditional allies in Europe and the United States.</p>
<p>Canberra and Washington agreed last year to dramatically increase defence cooperation, with increased military exercises aimed partly at improving the two nations' ability to fight together overseas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
