<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="614700" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam, U.S. experts to examine lessons of war.</title>
<headline>Vietnam, U.S. experts to examine lessons of war.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>America's Vietnam War Defence Secretary, Robert McNamara, and Vietnamese officials are due to meet next month in Hanoi to examine possible lessons from the conflict, a foreign ministry official said on Monday.</p>
<p>McNamara, the most senior member of a non-government U.S. delegation comprising some 54 researchers and historians, will attend a &quot;Missed Opportunities&quot; conference between June 19 and 22 with Vietnamese government ministers and academics.</p>
<p>But the official said General Vo Nguyen Giap, Vietnam's foremost military strategist and mastermind of victories over both the French and Americans, was not expected to attend. No reasons were given.</p>
<p>Robert McNamara resigned as U.S. Defence Secretary in 1968 after overseeing the U.S. military buildup in Indochina in a conflict which became known as McNamara's War.</p>
<p>In memoirs published in 1995 he sparked debate in the United States by detailing wrong decisions under the Kennedy and Johnson administrations which he said had led Washington to stumbling into an unwinnable war.</p>
<p>The war finally ended in 1975 with the fall of U.S.-backed Saigon to the forces of communist North Vietnam.</p>
<p>In terms of human lives the cost was 58,000 American dead and around four million Vietnamese either killed or injured.</p>
<p>McNamara visited Vietnam in 1995 a few months after the two countries normalised diplomatic ties.</p>
<p>His forthcoming visit follows the first exchange of envoys between the former foes.</p>
<p>Former fighter pilot and prisoner-of-war Douglas &quot;Pete&quot; Peterson arrived in Vietnam on May 9 to take up a post as the first U.S. ambassador to Vietnam since the war. His Vietnamese counterpart, Le Van Bang, arrived in Washington at around the same time.</p>
<p>Asked last week if he viewed the conflict as a mistake, Peterson told reporters he was not qualified to decide on what was still &quot;instant history.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
