<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="615006" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs end virtually unchanged after paring losses.</title>
<headline>JGBs end virtually unchanged after paring losses.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key June 10-year Japanese government bond futures contract ended virtually unchanged on Monday, as most of its early losses were pared due to short-covering, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The June fell in the morning, as it retained weakness from (Friday's) London trade... But buy backs emerged in the afternoon once it became apparent that selling by investors was lacking,&quot; said a trader for a city bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>The June fell in London on Friday after a senior Japanese Finance Ministry official was quoted as telling Le Monde that a rise in Japan's discount rate is expected in the coming year.  </p>
<p>A 0.5 percentage point rise would still leave Japan's discount rate at a low level and such a move should be expected from the Bank of Japan in the coming year, the official, Eisuke Sakakibara, said in an interview with Le Monde.</p>
<p>But he said he did not think the Bank of Japan would raise the discount rate before being confident of economic upturn.</p>
<p>The impact of Sakakibara's comments was limited, as the market does not believe the BOJ will raise interest rates immediately, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;He (Sakakibara) is not saying interest rates will be raised immediately. Also, the comments came at a time when the market was already weak. If the market had been on an rising trend, JGBs would have been more sensitive to the remarks,&quot; said the trader at the city bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>Investors were mostly quiet during the day, traders said.</p>
<p>Some investors were detected buying cash JGBs on dips, the city bank trader said.</p>
<p>There was some selling of low-coupon JGBs by investors, a trend which has been in place for about a week or so, a brokerage house trader said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Cash bonds with low coupon rates, such as 10-year JGBs with coupon rates of 2.4 percent or 2.5 percent, were sold today,&quot; the brokerage house trader said.</p>
<p>Investors such as agricultural financial institutions may have been behind the selling of 10-year JGBs such as the 194th and 195th issues, the trader said.</p>
<p>The selling seemed limited to long-term JGBs, however, and there was little evidence of selling in the short to medium end of the JGB yield curve, the trader added.</p>
<p>The June ended at 123.66, down slightly from Friday's close of 123.67. Turnover was 35,106 contracts.  </p>
<p>The benchmark 182nd JGB yield stood at 2.585 percent as of 0706 GMT, up slightly from Friday's close of 2.580 percent.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry is planning to offer four-year government notes through a price-competitive auction on Tuesday, a MOF official said on Monday.</p>
<p>Traders said the issue amount is likely to be 500 billion yen, unchanged from the previous auction for four-year government notes.</p>
<p>Judging from current market conditions, the coupon rate is likely to be set at 1.6 percent or 1.7 percent, up from 1.1 percent at the previous auction, the first trader said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
