<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61510" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tambrands sees savings from restructuring.</title>
<headline>Tambrands sees savings from restructuring.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tambrands Inc told analysts it expects its restructuring to translate into savings of about $0.35 per share next year, improved margins and cost savings that will help it reinvest in its feminine hygiene product line.</p>
<p>Tambrands, earlier Wednesday, said it would take a pre-tax charge of $46 million, or $1.00 per share in the third quarter, and that it would close four plants and cut its workforce by about 17 percent.  </p>
<p>Analysts who attended a meeting in New York with company executives also said Tambrands is committed to build up its existing product line and does not expect to diversify.</p>
<p>Tambrands also outlined how a reduction in manufacturing costs will make the company more profitable by improving margins.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question the restructuring will make the company more profitable,&quot; Constance Maneaty, an analyst at Bear Stearns, said. &quot;It was the next obvious step to take in the process of making the company stronger.&quot;</p>
<p>Tambrands shares rose 1-1/8 to close at 42-7/8.  </p>
<p>The company posted second-quarter earnings of $0.35 per share compared to $0.36 per share the same period last year.</p>
<p>Tambrands said the restructuring will result in pre-tax annual savings of about $20 million, which will be realized by the beginning of 1998.</p>
<p>But analysts said the company, at its meeting, did not elaborate on how much of the savings would be put into product development and how much would go to the bottom line.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like (the savings) won't all fall down to the bottom line,&quot; said Michael Grant, an analyst at JP Morgan.</p>
<p>Grant said Edward Fogarty, president and chief executive, who was also named to the post of chairman today, told analysts the company would not be diversifying but rather building up the existing tampon and feminine hygiene lines.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't think we are going to be seeing major new products from them in the latter half of the year,&quot; Grant said.</p>
<p>-- Patricia Willens, 212-859-1727</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
