<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="615104" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan says third man jumps aboard patrol boats.</title>
<headline>Japan says third man jumps aboard patrol boats.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>An activist on a Taiwanese fishing boat challenging Japan's claim to islands in the East China Sea jumped from his ship on to a Japanese coastguard boat on Monday, a coastguard spokesman said.</p>
<p>The spokesman told Reuters the incident was separate from an earlier boarding in which two demonstrators jumped from a Hong Kong protest ship on to another Japanese coastguard vessel.  </p>
<p>In the first incident, the two activists jumped from a boat called the &quot;Protect-the-Diaoyus&quot;, flagship of a Taiwan-Hong Kong flotilla challenging Japan's claim to an island chain called the Senkakus in Japanese and the Diaoyus in Chinese.</p>
<p>The coastguard has mobilised about 60 patrol boats to prevent the flotilla from approaching the disputed island chain.</p>
<p>&quot;In the latest incident, a man jumped on to one of our coastguard ships from a Taiwanese fishing boat,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The coastguard spokesman said Japanese authorities had not arrested the three men and wanted to return them to their ships.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
