<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61527" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - ends 1/8 to 1/4 point lower.</title>
<headline>U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - ends 1/8 to 1/4 point lower.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. municipal prices ended 1/8 to 1/4 point lower at the close Wednesday, continuing to lose ground after Tuesday's report that several regional Fed officials were urging an interest rate hike, traders said.</p>
<p>The Treasury market, in contrast, managed to stop its downturn Wednesday, with the 30-year bond heading into the New York close unchanged at a 7.03 percent yield.</p>
<p>In the muni secondary, yields were up three basis points to 5.81 percent on the bid side for Texas Turnpike Authority FGIC 5-1/4s of 2023.  </p>
<p>Colorado Springs, Colo.'s 5-3/4s of 2025 held their ground slightly better, with bids rising just one basis point on the day to 5.84 percent.</p>
<p>In afternoon negotiated action, Illinois State Toll Highway Authority sold $150 million refunding bonds through PaineWebber Inc, which priced the deal at a top yield of 5.55 percent in 2009.  </p>
<p>Several of Wednesday's other new issues were repriced, including a $50 million Kentucky Housing Corp deal senior managed by Merrill Lynch &amp; Co, which lowered yields in several maturities at the repricing. To see the repricing, double</p>
<p>On the competitive side, Merrill Lynch &amp; Co said it had a $20.3 million on Massachusetts $200 million general obligation offering, which the firm won earlier in the day. To see Merrill's reoffering scale, double click on  nN18113570. To see the remaining balances, double blick on  nN18148074.  </p>
<p>Thursday's new issue action features six expected negotiated offerings totaling $155 million and six competitive issues totaling $34.5 million, according to Reuters Municipal Bond Information Group.</p>
<p>The largest deal for the day is expected to be a negotiated $100 million Honolulu, Hawaii, general obligation offering through Smith Barney Inc.</p>
<p>Thursday's data releases include housing starts for August at 0830 EDT. Economists polled by Reuters expect the figure to be 1.445 million. Jobless claims for the week ended Sept 14, also set for an 0830 EDT release, are expected to be 335,000.</p>
<p>The Philadelphia Federal Reserve Board index, scheduled for a 1000 EDT release, is expected to show a reading of 21.</p>
<p>--Steven Dickson, 212-859-1652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
