<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="615287" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: An Feng confirms Kingstream merger finding.</title>
<headline>An Feng confirms Kingstream merger finding.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan An Feng Steel Co said it welcomed Monday's positive independent evaluation of its plan to merge with Australia's Kingstream Resources NL, saying the deal was mutually beneficial.</p>
<p>&quot;The report further comfirms that the merger is good for Kingstream as well as for An Feng,&quot; An Feng vice-president Sun Kuang-tsan told Reuters.</p>
<p>Kingstream said on Monday that an independent expert, Grant Samuel and Associates Pty Ltd, found that the strategic logic of the merger was compelling, enhancing the prospects for projects jointly undertaken by the merged companies.</p>
<p>The merger would help Taiwan's number two steelmaker to secure iron mine resources for an A$1.4 billion steelmaking project in Western Australia to be undertaken in 1997 by the merged company, Sun said.</p>
<p>&quot;An Feng will have stable iron and steel supplies after we merge with Kingstream,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>After the merger, An Feng would hold over 80 percent of the newly merged Perth-based firm, which would become an Australian listed company called An Feng Kingstream, Sun said.</p>
<p>He added that the new steelmaking project would be supplied by Kingstream's three large iron mines.</p>
<p>The new project's iron and steel production would be retailed in Australia or reprocessed by An Feng facilities in Taiwan, he said.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (2-508-0815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
