<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61530" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FBI agent says Gulf Cartel built on bribes, murder.</title>
<headline>FBI agent says Gulf Cartel built on bribes, murder.</headline>
<byline>James Pierpoint</byline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reputed drug kingpin Juan Garcia Abrego relied on bribery and murder to eliminate competitors and build a massive Mexican drug organisation, a former FBI agent testified on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Retired FBI agent Claudio de la O said payoffs to government officials in Mexico helped Garcia Abrego avoid prosecution as he built a cartel that shipped billions of dollars in cocaine across the U.S.-Mexico border.</p>
<p>De la O told jurors a close friend of Garcia Abrego had said the reputed kingpin was aware of pressure on the mayor of Matamoros and the governor of the region &quot;to intercede, to do something about Garcia Abrego,&quot; who was then operating his drug smuggling operation out of Matamoros.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, but with money they fix it,&quot; De la O said he was told in a secretly recorded conversation with a now deceased Brownsville, Texas, opthamologist and Garcia Abrego confidant.</p>
<p>Garcia Abrego has pleaded not guilty to 22 counts of drug trafficking and money laundering in a 28-count indictment against him and several alleged members of his so-called Gulf Cartel. If convicted, he faces up to life in prison and forefeiture of millions of dollars in drug proceeds.</p>
<p>After once working as a labourer in a Nabisco cookie plant in Mexico, Garcia Abrego allegedly went on to build an organisation that smuggled tons of cocaine and marijuana into the United States over the past 15 years.</p>
<p>Prosecutors allege his organisation was the shipping arm of Colombia's Cali cartel, taking a 50 percent cut of cocaine it shipped into the United States and laundering millions in drug proceeds to fund the operation.</p>
<p>By bribing police and government officials and providing information on activities of rival cartels, Garcia Abrego built a massive international drug smuggling ring, Assistant U.S. Attorney Melissa Annis said in opening arguments.</p>
<p>In 1986, De la O opened the U.S. investigation into Garcia Abrego and his cartel. Posing as a corrupt agent, he accepted three bribes totalling $170,000 from Garcia Abrego lieutenants in exchange for information he provided -- all of it false, he said -- on the progress of drug investigations.</p>
<p>After receiving an initial $100,000 payoff, De la O said, Garcia Abrego in handwritten notes and recorded telephone conversations began providing him with details of the activities of rival drug smugglers. &quot;He's trying to vindicate himself, that he's being blamed for some of the violence, trafficking in the region,&quot; De la O said of Garcia Abrego's reasons for providing information on the rival cartels.</p>
<p>He said intermediaries from the Gulf Cartel sent by Garcia Abrego to meet with him talked of the murders of two rival traffickers and the mysterious death of a pilot who had been ferrying cocaine into the United States for another cartel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
