<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="615316" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan stocks end up despite late profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Taiwan stocks end up despite late profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-05-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan share prices closed slightly higher on Monday despite late profit-taking that eroded early-session gains that were fuelled by a resurgent electronics sector, brokers said.</p>
<p>The weighted index wavered in a narrow range throughout Monday's session to finish a scant 15.96 points or 0.20 percent higher at 8,194.66. Turnover was modest at T$84 billion.</p>
<p>Share prices rose to an intra-day high of 8,248.48 on active buying of electronic shares, which have rebounded from the heavy profit-taking they endured in a recent market correction.</p>
<p>Electronics gained 1.06 percent as a sector.  </p>
<p>Asustek Computer Inc jumped the daily seven percent limit, or T$24, to T$373 -- the highest price of any listed share -- on reports that its recent issue of global depository receipts had been well received overseas.</p>
<p>Winbond rose T$1.5 or 4.13 percent to T$37.8.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt electronics will outperform others and become the market's leading sector, but views are divided on how the market's current consolidation will be,&quot; National Securities' analyst Alex Yang said.</p>
<p>Investors were cautious as the index neared the technical resistance of 8,250 points, brokers said.  </p>
<p>Overall sentiment has improved in part because of the Taiwan government's plan to allow local and foreign institutions to issue warrants on big-capital blue chips in June, brokers said.</p>
<p>As a result, many foreign and domestic funds were buying up warrant-related issues, mostly in big-capital firms, they said.</p>
<p>Under the liberalisation, local and foreign institutions will be allowed to issue warrants on local firms having market value above T$30 billion and having 25 percent or more of their shares circulating in the market. To be eligible, listed firms must have more than 7,500 shareholders.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
