<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="615657" id="root" date="1997-05-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FRENCH ELECTION - Key constituencies - Latest.</title>
<headline>FRENCH ELECTION - Key constituencies - Latest.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Results of Sunday's first round of the parliamentary election in 31 constituencies.</p>
<p>Where no candidate polled 50 percent in the first round, a second run-off ballot will be held on June 1.</p>
<p>DOMINIQUE STRAUSS-KAHN, former Socialist minister, won 36.62 percent of votes in Val d'Oise constituency, beating RPR rival who polled 20.94 percent. National Front knocked out.</p>
<p>JEAN TIBERI, member of RPR party and Paris mayor goes to second round ballot, with 33.46 percent ot votes, beating Socialist opponent who polled 27.94 percent.</p>
<p>PIERRE LELLOUCHE, RPR party member won 31.51 percent of votes cast in paris constituency, ahead of Socialist opponent with 22 percent.</p>
<p>LIONEL JOSPIN, first secretary of Socialist party, won 42.71 percent of votes in Haute-Garonne constitutency, easily beating UDF rival who polled 15.79 percent.</p>
<p>Former Prime Minister EDOUARD BALLADUR, member of RPR party, won 49.34 percent of votes cast in Paris constituency and goes onto second ballot. Socialist Anne Le Moal won 21.79 percent.</p>
<p>Ecologist GUY HASCOET, supported by Socialists, won 30.27 percent of votes in Nord constituency, beating RPR candidate who won 24.59 percent.</p>
<p>National Front candidate CLAUDE DERESNES won 25.90 percent of votes in Maubeuge constituency, ahead of UDF opponent, mayor of Maubeuge, who won 22.16 percent.</p>
<p>RPR gaullist party secretary general JEAN-FRANCOIS MANCEL, won 27.92 percent of votes in Oise constituency, ahead of socialist candidate Beatrice Marre, who polled 24.77 percent.</p>
<p>Ecologist NOEL MAMERE, supported by the Socialists, topped the ballot in Gironde constituency with 34 percent of votes while incumbent RPR candidate won 24.97 percent.</p>
<p>BRUNO GOLLNISCH, secretary general of the National Front came second in the Rhone with 28.65 percent while incumbent Socialist Martine David, won 30.85 percent. The UDF candidat captured 22.10 percent.</p>
<p>Socialist mayor of Strasbourg CATHERINE TRAUTMANN won 39.30 percent in the Bas-Rhin constituency, ahead of UDF outgoing member of parliament Harry Lapp, who polled 31.40 percent. The National Front candidate was knocked out.</p>
<p>National Front extreme-right deputy BRUNO MEGRET, led in the Bouches-du-Rhone constituency with 35.45 percent, in front of Socialist outgoing member of parliament Henri d'Attilio, who polled 31.01 percent.</p>
<p>PHILIPPE DE VILLIERS, head of rightwing Movement For France (MPF), came top in fourth constituency of Vendee, with 47.44 percent. Runner-up was ecologist candidate supported by the Socialists who won 20.58 percent of the vote.</p>
<p>ALAIN BOCQUET, head of the communists in the outgoing National Assembly won first round of voting in the 20th constituency of Nord, with 41.09 percent of the vote. Runner-up was National Front candidate who polled 20.21 percent.</p>
<p>Education Minister FRANCOIS BAYROU, deputy head of the UDF, won 39.63 percent in second constituency of Pyrenees- Atlantiques. Socialist candidate second with 32.68 percent.</p>
<p>Orange National Front Mayor JACQUES BOMPARD came second in Vaucluse with 28.78 percent of votes, RPR incumbent Thierry Mariani won 29.41 percent. Socialist Jean-Pierre Lambertin collected 22.89 percent.</p>
<p>Former Socialist Prime Minister LAURENT FABIUS won massive 41.7 percent in the first round ballot, compared to the UDF runner-up who won just 13.8 percent, but still faces a run-off.</p>
<p>Gaullist Interior Minister JEAN-LOUIS DEBRE won 34.34 percent in Eure constituency. The radical-socialist candidate won 18.73 percent and National Front candidate 18.41 percent.</p>
<p>Toulon National Front Mayor JEAN-MARIE LE CHEVALLIER topped first round in Toulon, grabbing 32.39 percent of vote and faces Socialist Odette Casanova in runoff. Casanova captured 26.61 percent, beating UDF incumbent Daniel Colin with 19.69 percent.</p>
<p>Prime Minister ALAIN JUPPE faces a second-round decider next week after winning 38.57 percent of votes in the second Gironde constituency. Main rival, Socialist candidate Gilles Savary, polled 28 percent. National Front out of second round.</p>
<p>Gaullist (RPR) member of parliament MARIE-JOSEE ROIG, mayor of Avignon, polled 30.39 percent in Vaucluse constituency. Former Socialist minister for European Affairs ELISABETH GUIGOU came second.</p>
<p>FRANCOIS HOLLANDE, Socialist Party spokesman, has to go to a second-round after coming second with 35.4 percent. He will be pitted against Raymond-Max Aubert from RPR party in the goverment coalition. President Jacques Chirac has his personal power base in the Correze area. Aubert scored 38.2 percent.</p>
<p>MARTINE AUBRY, ex-Socialist Labour minister and favourite for prime minister in opinion polls, goes to second-round runoff after obtaining 34.69 percent in the Nord constituency. She faces Jacques Donnay, chairman of regional council in the North and member of RPR majority, who obtained 22.58 percent.</p>
<p>FRANCOIS LEOTARD, head of the UDF party in the centre-right coalition, has to go to a second-round run-off. The mayor of Frejus obtained 35.21 percent of votes, or 13 percentage points fewer than the partial parliamentary elections of 1995.</p>
<p>DOMINIQUE VOYNET, spokeswoman for the Greens party, has to go to a second-round run-off next Sunday. She is leading in the third Jura constituency 31.11 percent. Main rival, UDF centre-right parliamentarian Gilbert Barbier, won 27.87 percent.</p>
<p>Former president and outgoing UDF member of parliament VALERY GISCARD D'ESTAING faces second-round run-off in Puy-de-Dome constituency for the first time in parliamentary career. He polled 34.64 percent to 29.44 percent for the ecologist candidate Danielle Auroi, backed by Socialists.</p>
<p>PHILIPPE SEGUIN, speaker of the outgoing National Assembly and a member of the RPR party, topped the poll with 44.59 percent in Vosges constituency compared to 24.23 percent to the Socialist candidate.</p>
<p>JACK LANG, former socialist Culture Minister, is ahead in the Loir-et-Cher first constituency. He polled 33.9 percent against UDF candidate Jacqueline Gourault who 28.4 percent.</p>
<p>ALAIN MADELIN, ultra-liberal former finance minister, won 46.7 percent in the Ille-et-Villaine fourth constituency. His Socialist rival obtained 24.6 percent.</p>
<p>SEGOLENE ROYAL, a key Socialist parliamentarian, won 49.1 percent of votes, while UDF main rival won 30.3 percent in her Deux-Sevres second constituency.</p>
<p>JEAN-PIERRE CHEVENEMENT, a left-wing former defence minister and anti-Maastricht campaigner, topped poll with 40.47 percent for the second Belfort constituency to 6,228 votes (20.42 percent) for National Front candidate.</p>
<p>Source: Interior Ministry</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
