<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="615693" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Hollinger would mull change to Southam bid.</title>
<headline>Hollinger would mull change to Southam bid.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hollinger Inc Chief Executive Conrad Black said on Tuesday he would consider increasing the cash portion of Hollinger's bid for the remaining shares of Southam Inc, but would not raise the overall value of the C$923 million offer.</p>
<p>&quot;We'd certainly be reluctant to change the offer. But if we got right to the edge and we're just a very small bit short of what we needed, then maybe a minor adjustment of that kind that didn't change the total, something like that we could probably think about,&quot; Black told reporters after the company's annual meeting.  </p>
<p>But Black dismissed suggestions that the C$23.50 a share price did not reflect the increasingly rosy outlook for Canadian newspaper publishers.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the offer is likely to succeed as it is...there have been a few shareholders and anonymous spokespeople that we don't deal with, holding hands and claiming that we should be turning our pockets inside out, but the fact is it's a fair offer,&quot; Black said.</p>
<p>Hollinger in April offered to buy the 49 percent of newspaper publisher Southam that it did not already control.  </p>
<p>Hollinger's offer involved C$13.50 a share in cash and a C$10 non-voting special share in Hollinger Canadian, a unit of New York-based Hollinger International Inc.</p>
<p>Black repeated to shareholders that Hollinger could live without the remaining shares if the bid failed to be accepted by at least two-thirds of minority shareholders.</p>
<p>&quot;Those disposed to wait for a higher offer should remember that there will be no competing offer. We are the last train leaving the station,&quot; Black said.</p>
<p>Toronto-based Southam is Canada's biggest daily newspaper publisher.  </p>
<p>It publishes 32 dailies, including the Ottawa Citizen, Vancouver Sun and Montreal Gazette, and 58 free and paid circulation newspapers.</p>
<p>Demonstrators picketed outside the Hollinger meeting to protest increased media concentration brought about by Hollinger's bid to take Southam private.</p>
<p>But Black said that Hollinger's holdings increased Canadian media diversity and offered an alternative to Canada's two largest newspapers, Torstar Corp's Toronto Star and Thomson Corp's Globe and Mail, both based in Toronto.  </p>
<p>He said Hollinger continues to study the possibility of establishing a fifth Toronto newspaper. The idea came up earlier this year after a near-agreement between Black and Sun Media Corp's management for Black to increase his 20-percent stake in the Toronto-based The Financial Post fell through.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't doubt our ability to produce at least as viable a product as the Financial Post relatively easily and this project will be explored and decided upon in the balance of this year,&quot; Black said.</p>
<p>Hollinger's holdings include several high-profile international papers such as London's Daily Telegraph, the Chicago Sun-Times and Jerusalem Post.</p>
<p>((Andrea Hopkins at Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8102 or e-mail andrea.hopkins@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
