<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="615810" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida sees cigarette-deal framework in 2-3 weeks.</title>
<headline>Florida sees cigarette-deal framework in 2-3 weeks.</headline>
<dateline>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Significant progress has been made in negotiations between tobacco companies and state governments, and a detailed proposal to settle lawsuits against the tobacco industry could be fleshed out in two to three weeks, Florida's attorney general said Tuesday.</p>
<p>A key negotiator for state officials, Florida Attorney General Bob Butterworth, told reporters that both sides had reached tentative agreements covering sharp advertising restrictions on tobacco products and Food and Drug Administration oversight of the tobacco industry.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think a structure could be in place that we could bring back to the attorneys general in the country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Later, he added, a detailed proposal could be presented within three weeks to the dozens of other attorneys general who are suing cigarette makers to recover billions of dollars of piublic funds spent treating smoking-related illnesses.</p>
<p>But a tentative pact is unlikely to postpone the August 4 start of Florida's civil suit against the tobacco industry, or a similar suit scheduled to go to trial next month in Mississippi, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I do not believe that there will be anything finished that would postpone the Florida trial,&quot; Butterworth said.</p>
<p>He said any pact would require congressional approval, which could possibly be obtained by year-end.</p>
<p>He said the two sides had agreed -- subject to negotiation of a complete pact -- that cigarette companies would end all outdoor advertising, such as billboards, and put in place a campaign aimed at reducing cigarette use by teenagers.</p>
<p>&quot;They are going to have to reduce teen smoking. We'll give them a challenge. Reduce it by 30 percent in five years and 50 percent in seven years .... Each year you don't meet your goal, you'll have to pay,&quot; Butterworth said.  </p>
<p>He said the negotiators were still working out major issues such as whether injured smokers would be allowed to sue tobacco companies for punitive, as well as compensatory, damages.</p>
<p>Other proposals under negotiation were possibly capping the money awards in civil lawsuits, and granting the industry sweeping insulation against lawsuits from people who take up smoking years after a pact is in place, Butterworth said.</p>
<p>If implemented, the unprecedented deal would radically change how U.S. cigarette makers operate, he said.  </p>
<p>Under the proposal, print advertisements would be toned down, and animated characters and other symbolic figures used in cigarette advertising would be eliminated, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;When an agreement is reached, the Marlboro man is dead. Joe Camel is gone. All the pictures portraying people on billboards will be gone. In fact, all the billboards will be gone,&quot; Butterworth said.</p>
<p>Face-to-face bargaining among the negotiators was to resume Thursday and likely continue through the weekend, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're pretty much getting closer,&quot; he said. &quot;There are some points which are a no-go for us or a no-go for the (tobacco) industry.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLAHASSEE, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
