<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="615982" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: ROMANIA PRESIDENT TO VISIT GERMANY FOR NATO SUPPORT.</title>
<headline>ROMANIA PRESIDENT TO VISIT GERMANY FOR NATO SUPPORT.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romanian President Emil Constantinescu will visit Germany in July, in a last-ditch attempt to boost his country's chances to get an early admission in NATO, a senior official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The president's official visit to Germany on July 2 will have a special significance in the context of Romania's real chances to join NATO in the first group,&quot; Prime Minister Victor Ciorbea told a news conference.</p>
<p>Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic are seen as favorites in a NATO expansion. Slovenia and Romania are trailing behind.</p>
<p>Constantinescu's visit to Bonn is scheduled ahead of the NATO summit in Madrid where the Alliance is expected to announce its new members.</p>
<p>France, Italy, Spain, Portugal, Greece and Turkey have expressed public support for Romania's bid to win early admission. But the United States, Britain and Germany have so far remain cool on the issue.</p>
<p>Romania's centrist coalition government, which ousted the former ruling leftists in elections last November, has made NATO membership its main political goal.</p>
<p>Over the past months, Bucharest sent ambassadors, including Romania's former King Michael, to all 16 NATO member countries in a bid to persuade them consider Romania's NATO candidacy.</p>
<p>&quot;In countries which have not yet decided on whom to back -- mainly the United States and Germany -- the degree of support is on the rise,&quot; Ciorbea said on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
