<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61592" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Penn State shooter may have planned shooting spree.</title>
<headline>Penn State shooter may have planned shooting spree.</headline>
<dateline>STATE COLLEGE, Pa 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A young woman suspected of a shooting spree that left one person dead and another wounded may have told friends last month about plans to commit the crimes, officials said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Police said Jillian Robbins, 19, fired five shots from a high-powered rifle, killing a 19-year-old woman and critically wounding a 22-year-old man on the Penn State campus. Robbins, who lived in a nearby community, was not a student at the school and did not know the people she shot, police said.</p>
<p>&quot;She had spoken to acquaintances (a month ago) about 'doing it',&quot; said Dave Stormer, assistant vice president for university safety, at a news conference. &quot;We are speculating that 'it' may be (the shooting).&quot;</p>
<p>Stormer said charges of first-degree murder, attempted homicide and associated homicide would be filed against Robbins Wednesday. Robbins was listed in fair condition at Centre Community Hospital, where she underwent surgery on Tuesday for a self-inflicted stab wound.</p>
<p>The shooting threw the rural central Pennsylvania campus community into shock, but students said they were trying to get life back to normal a day later.</p>
<p>&quot;I think people are just trying to get things back to normal,&quot; said James Reeser, 22. &quot;You try to forget it ... but you can't.</p>
<p>&quot;People are walking by the spot where it happened and some won't look at it. It's like they stare straight ahead, trying not to look,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Stormer said the suspect had been in the Army reserve and that dog tags were strapped to the 7 mm Mauser rifle she used in the shooting. A background search produced no criminal record and a search of her apartment produced &quot;nothing significant,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Stormer said several people saw Robbins sitting outside near the school's student centre reading a newspaper early Tuesday. She was then seen hiding beneath a tree before opening fire.</p>
<p>Melanie Spalla, a communications major, was killed at the scene, and Nicholas Mensah, also an undergraduate student, was wounded when a bullet struck him in the abdominal area.</p>
<p>Another student's life was saved when one of the bullets struck the student's backpack, Stormer said.</p>
<p>Mensah and was listed in fair condition at Centre Community Hospital.</p>
<p>Police said that after shooting the two students the suspect stopped to reload the rifle and was tackled by another student.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STATE COLLEGE, Pa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
