<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="615957" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: OPINION-RHETORIC VS REALITY IN SOUTHERN AFRICA.</title>
<headline>OPINION-RHETORIC VS REALITY IN SOUTHERN AFRICA.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Tony Hawkins, Professor of Business Studies at The University of Zimbabwe</p>
<p>Invariably high profile business-govenment regional summits fall short of expectations. While optimism predominated at last week's World Economic Forum Southern African summit in Harare, the closing session left the impression that for some of the leading participants rhetoric came easier than grappling with the hard realities of regional economic development.</p>
<p>For all the commitment to a &quot;regional vision&quot; member governments are all too well aware that they are competing against one another for the tiny proportion of global foreign direct investment - no more than one percent - targetting southern Africa.</p>
<p>So when Zambia's President Frederick Chiluba was hailed by many as the star of the show because of his performance in outlining Zambia's successes, especially on the privatisation front, there was no shortage of businessmen and politicians from competing economies, such as Zimbabwe, all too keen to pour cold water on Zambia's achievements.</p>
<p>As one businessman put it: &quot;His pitch was excellent, but wait until potential investors get to Zambia and see the situation on the ground, especially the rundown infrastructure and the shortage of skills.&quot;</p>
<p>Furthermore, plain speaking is taboo on such occasions. Political correctness is everything. Business leaders pull their punches and bite their tongues rather than be seen to disagree publicly with the party line espoused by their government's spokesmen.</p>
<p>And when it came to looking forward at the final session of the Harare summit when a regional business task force put forward its vision for the future of the 12-country Southern African Development Community (SADC), the self-same business leaders who pride themselves on being hard-headed pragmatists, were seen to have asked more questions than they answered.</p>
<p>Nor was this confined to the southern Africans themselves.</p>
<p>Professor Klaus Schwab, president of the Geneva-based World Economic Forum, argued that regional integration should be seen a step on the road to globalisation but much of the evidence, especially from Asia, suggests otherwise.</p>
<p>The leading globalisers - the Asian Tigers - liberalised unilaterally rather than regionally. That there was a very powerful regional impetus is acknowledged, but this was not the result of regional trade preference, but of trade and payments liberalisation with the world at large.</p>
<p>More to the point perhaps, some southern African firms - mainly South African companies or multinationals using South Africa as a platform to penetrate sub-Saharan Africa, are globalising as well in advance of the progress of regional integration.</p>
<p>Far from being driven by the regional process, such firms are themselves pioneering it with cross-border investments and the rapid growth of South Africa's trade surplus with the rest of Africa.</p>
<p>The reality is the very opposite of what Schwab argues - namely that business cannot afford to wait for the politicians to get their act together. Like the Asians before them, they are acting unilaterally - they have to.</p>
<p>If a vision is to be credible it must tackle real issues rather than sidestep them, but three themes from the closing session underscored the task force's failure to do that.</p>
<p>The business task force concluded that the growth path for SADC should be one that optimises regional industrial and infrastructure development. Easy to say, but how is to going to be achieved?</p>
<p>Will it be market-driven, on the basis of open economies and privatised utilities and infrastructure, or will governments or some supranational regional body, decide what is &quot;optimal&quot;?</p>
<p>This question was not answered but the former South African Finance Minister Chris Liebenberg, a member of the task force, was quick to insist that there was no intention to recommend any form of central planning.</p>
<p>Others speaking after him left a rather different, if still distinctly fuzzy, impression.</p>
<p>A second, largely non-controversial, theme was that of setting up a regional business organisation to match the governmental structures within SADC.</p>
<p>But this is hardly new.</p>
<p>The SADC Business Council idea was tried - and failed - in the 1980s. With South Africa as a member, the idea looks a good deal more promising, but given the weakness of national private sector business organisation, the danger - indeed the probability - is that of domination by Pretoria, which is not in anyone's interests.</p>
<p>More important though is the role of such a body. The task force sees it working alongside governments and a regional labour organisation to foster regional integration. This raises a number of problems, not the least of which is the central planning aspect.</p>
<p>Is a regional &quot;golden triangle&quot; encompassing business, government and labour, going to be just a debating society or will it have teeth, power, influence? The suggestion is deeply ironic.</p>
<p>It was made in a week in which the World Economic Forum published its Global Competitiveness Report highlighting the fall from grace of a corporatist economy such as Germany, ranked 25, and the revitalisation of the British economy, up eight places in seventh spot, under a conservative administration that rejected corporatist solutions.</p>
<p>Ironic too because the Forum's organisers can hardly have been happy with such a recommendation that they know to be out of tune with the mood of most of their members.</p>
<p>What can SADC's business leaders be thinking of? In southern Africa, poverty is greatest amongst the unemployed and underemployed and amongst those in the informal sector.</p>
<p>Organised labour with its demands for higher wages, for improved working conditions and for a national minimum wage does nothing for those marginalised in the development process.</p>
<p>Higher labour costs - one area where SADC ought to have competitive advantage - further marginalise those already disadvantaged.</p>
<p>Add to that the weakness of the trade union movement in SADC (excluding South Africa) and the corporatist solution seems wholly irrelevant to the region's needs.</p>
<p>Business leaders know that but when it comes to the crunch, they opt for political correctness, even if it flies in the face of logic and history. That way, they avoid hard choices and tough decisions.</p>
<p>Sadly, though, that is not leadership, or if it is, it is leading the regional economy down the wrong road away from the enhanced global competitiveness needed to solve unemployment and poverty in southern Africa.</p>
<p>			     / / / / / / / / / /</p>
<p>(The opinions expressed in this article represent those of the author only. They should not be seen to represent the views of Reuters.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SADCC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
