<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="616169" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GHANA: Ghana's inflation, currency worry top local broker.</title>
<headline>Ghana's inflation, currency worry top local broker.</headline>
<dateline>ACCRA 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ghana's leading stockbroker, Databank Ltd, said it was pessimistic about the government's ability to control inflation and stem the decline of the local currency, the cedi, against the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;Given its reputation for fiscal indiscipline, there is widespread pessimism about the commitment to contain money supply to control inflation,&quot; Databank wrote in its Economic Review for the first quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;(Government) expenditure is expected to go up, since there has been no drastic change in the structure of the public sector,&quot; wrote Databank.</p>
<p>In March, year-on-year consumer price inflation stood at 29.2 percent, down from 64.8 percent in March 1996.</p>
<p>The government is trying to control inflation through maintaining a high rediscount rate, but this is stifling private investment, Databank said.</p>
<p>&quot;Industry is experiencing difficulties trying to cope with high interest rates. This makes the Government's forecast for a 4.9 percent growth in the sector quite optimistic,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>In 1996 money supply grew by 34 percent, way above the government's target of five percent.</p>
<p>The target this year is 15 percent. The Central Bank has not yet published money supply figures for the first quarter.</p>
<p>At the beginning of January, one US dollar was worth 1,740 cedis. That was up from 1,446 at the beginning of 1996, and the cedi has since fallen further to 2,020 per dollar. &quot;The decline in the value of the cedi during the first quarter has been attributed to continuing demand for imported goods as against slow growth in export earnings, the inability of the local industrial sector to meet domestic demand and the lack of intervention by the Central Bank,&quot; Databank said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ACCRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GHANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
