<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="616187" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African Coke bottlers' shares fizz on Pepsi woes.</title>
<headline>S.African Coke bottlers' shares fizz on Pepsi woes.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Coca-Cola Corp's South African bottlers frothed up on Tuesday as investors toasted the demise of Pepsi bottler New Age Beverages which filed for liquidation last Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;You saw New Age Beverages go into liquidiation and with Coke bringing in more capital, I think certainly Suncrush and ABI could benefit,&quot; said Societe Generale Frankel Pollack dealer James Scott.</p>
<p>&quot;Coca-Cola is just going to become the dominant player in the country again. Pepsi tried, didn't succeed and those who were buying Pepsi will just go back to Coke,&quot; said another dealer, who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>Suncrush Ltd shares were up 10 cents to 910 cents on volumes of 231,300 shares while Amalgamated Beverage Industries Ltd had climbed 110 cents to 27.70 rand on turnover of 10,300 shares.</p>
<p>Kilimanjaro Investments Ltd, the third listed Coke bottler, edged up two cents to 242 cents on a modest 11,500 shares.</p>
<p>Pepsi kicked off a South African division of the global cola wars three years ago, entering the market via NAB with its eyes fixed initially on black townships, such as Soweto outside Johannesburg.</p>
<p>More recently the battle has been widened to a countrywide showdown between Pepsi and arch-rival Coke.</p>
<p>Coke and its seven bottlers upped the stakes earlier this year with ambitious plans to invest 1.25 billion rand in South Africa over the next five years, prompting earlier run on local bottlers' shares.</p>
<p>Societe Generale's Scott said merger rumours also might be helping the Coca-Cola bottlers.</p>
<p>&quot;There's talk of Suncrush possibly heading up an African bottling merger. All these things are fuelling a bit of speculation that is going on in these shares at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Justin McCamish, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
