<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="616265" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GEORGIA: Georgia signs military agreement with Ukraine.</title>
<headline>Georgia signs military agreement with Ukraine.</headline>
<dateline>TBILISI 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The former Soviet republics of Ukraine and Georgia signed agreements on Tuesday aimed at deepening cooperation between their armed forces.</p>
<p>Georgian Defence Minister Vardiko Nadibaidze and his Ukrainian counterpart Alexander Kuzmuk signed six documents on deepening cooperation between their air forces and air defence systems.</p>
<p>&quot;Relations are already developing between the branches of our (Ukraine and Georgian) armed services,&quot; Kuzmuk told a news conference.</p>
<p>Georgia, with a population of just six million compared to Ukraine's 50 million, needs help in building a military damaged after independence by ethnic and civil conflicts. Russia has provided it with some assistance.</p>
<p>Kuzmuk was completing a two-day visit to the Georgian capital Tbilisi.</p>
<p>Ukraine has developed close relations with Georgia and its neighbour Azerbaijan in the aftermath of the collapse of the Soviet Union, in which all three were constituent republics.</p>
<p>All three countries have had troubled relations with Russia since independence.</p>
<p>Kuzmuk said Ukraine was preparing to sign an agreement with NATO. &quot;A document is being prepared for signing between NATO and Ukraine. We are actively taking part in the Partnership for Peace programme and are always ready to establish friendly, peaceful ties with neighbours.&quot;</p>
<p>Kuzmuk did not elaborate on the specifics of the agreement. Russia signed an agreement with the western alliance on Tuesday in Paris.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GRGIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TBILISI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GEORGIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
