<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61628" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY Gov agrees deal for $300 mln Times Square hotel.</title>
<headline>NY Gov agrees deal for $300 mln Times Square hotel.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York State Gov. George Pataki on Wednesday said a state agency had approved lease terms with the Tishman Urban Development Corp for a $300 million hotel and entertainment complex in New York City's Times Square.</p>
<p>During construction, the project is expected to create about 3,680 jobs, and produce approximately $29 million in city and state tax revenues.</p>
<p>After the complex opens, it is projected to generate non-real estate tax revenues of more than $14 million, while producing 1,620 jobs.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the state agency, Empire State Development Corp, said he had no information immediately available on when the complex, which will be located on the northeast corner of 42nd Street and Eighth Avenue, was expected to open.</p>
<p>Construction on the project, which first was announced last year, is expected to begin this autumn.</p>
<p>Saying this was a prime example of the public and private sectors working together, Pataki added, &quot;In a little more than a year, we have seen the revitalization of 42nd Street take off like a rocket,&quot; in prepared remarks.</p>
<p>The three anchor tenants for the entertainment part of the complex will be Sony Theatres, Vegas, which plans a large center for live entertainment, and Transportation Displays Inc, which will have the lease on 20,000 square feet of &quot;super signage.&quot;</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
