<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="616353" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: Poland, Ukraine, Balts hail NATO-Russia accord.</title>
<headline>Poland, Ukraine, Balts hail NATO-Russia accord.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Lannin</byline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The presidents of Poland, Ukraine and the Baltic states met at a special regional summit on Tuesday and hailed the historic pact between NATO and Russia as a boost to European security and stability.</p>
<p>Polish President Aleksander Kwasniewski, whose country is the only one of the five likely to enter NATO in a first round of expansion, said the accord between the two old Cold War foes would set the stage for further growth of the alliance.</p>
<p>Kwasniewski was invited to the summit along with Ukraine's Leonid Kuchma by Estonian President Lennart Meri. Latvian President Guntis Ulmanis and Lithuanian leader Algirdas Brazauskas also took part in the meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;The presidents expressed their satisfaction with the signing on the same day in Paris of the Founding Act on bilateral cooperation and security between NATO and Russia,&quot; the five men said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>&quot;In their view, the Founding Act enhances mutual confidence, security and stability in the Euro-Atlantic area,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The pact between NATO and Russia  is aimed at defining Russia's relations with the alliance and establishing a new security order in Europe that formally consigns the Cold War to history.</p>
<p>It is also aimed at easing tensions as NATO plans to expand eastwards, taking in some of Russia's former Warsaw Pact allies.</p>
<p>The Estonian hosts of the meeting had stressed that the timing of the summit was a coincidence and was not a demonstration of solidarity against Russia.</p>
<p>Poland, the Czech Republic and Hungary are all expected to be invited to join the alliance at a July summit in Madrid.</p>
<p>Ukraine does not wish to join the alliance but wants a special cooperation treaty with NATO. The Balts are desperate for membership but their entry is seen as highly unlikely given very strong Russian objections.</p>
<p>Kwasniewski had some words of comfort for the Balts, saying the NATO-Russia pact set the groundwork for more new members.</p>
<p>&quot;This document is the formula to open the process of NATO enlargement,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sure NATO enlargement will have next stages, it depends on the internal decision of member countries,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In their communique, The five leaders also insisted that NATO's door should stay open for unsuccessful candidate states.</p>
<p>&quot;The presidents reiterated their common position that NATO should remain open for all countries aspiring for membership in this organisation and that these countries will be invited to join the alliance upon their readiness to fulfill the requirements of membership,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Western diplomats say  Russia's objections to Baltic inclusion in NATO have been too strong to contemplate letting them join without upsetting the delicate balance of relations that has been established with Moscow.</p>
<p>The five presidents also said they wanted good relations with their neighbours and shared the goal of integration into Europe with the same goal of European Union membership.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BALTST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
