<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="616476" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Work begins on Escondida expansion.</title>
<headline>Work begins on Escondida expansion.</headline>
<byline>Roger Atwood</byline>
<dateline>MINA ESCONDIDA, Chile 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Escondida has begun work on a long-planned $450 million plant that will turn copper oxides into cathodes and expand the mine's capacity -- already the world's largest -- by 15 percent, officials said.</p>
<p>Workers broke ground on the plant immediately after the regional environmental authority Corema gave final approval to the project on May 12, company officials said.</p>
<p>Heaps of dull green oxides waiting to be processed in the new plant are already piled on the edge of the sprawling Escondida complex in Chile's Atacama desert, about 170 km southeast of Antofagasta. The mine is majority owned by Broken Hill Proprietary Co Ltd and has RTZ Corp-CRA Ltd as minority partners.</p>
<p>With a capacity of 125,000 tonnes of copper in cathodes a year, the oxides plant will come onstream in late 1998, said Jorge Zeballos, corporate affairs manager at Minera Escondida Limitada.</p>
<p>The mine's design capacity of about 800,000 tonnes of copper a year will grow by about 15 percent with the new cathodes plant and put Escondida a step closer to becoming the world's first million-tonne-a-year copper mine.</p>
<p>Output at the whole mine and an existing cathodes plant was a combined 841,000 tonnes last year, about five percent over design capacity thanks to good grades and soft mineral, said Zeballos. The soft ore made milling in the concentrator go faster and controlled explosions in the pit more efficient, he said.</p>
<p>The oxides are concentrated on the open pit's western face starting at about 180 meters below the original surface and with a grade of about 0.68 percent, said Zeballos. Some also come from an area known as Escondida Norte straddling the property line between Escondida and the Zaldivar copper mine.</p>
<p>&quot;As we go mining the sulphides (in the open pit), we come across a layer of oxides, and then another layer and so on,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The circular pit is about 1.5 km wide and 300 meters deep and will eventually reach a width of four km and a depth of 600 meters, officials said.</p>
<p>The mine, majority owned by Australia's, has expanded so quickly since opening in 1991 that one of the three mountains depicted on Escondida's logo has disappeared and another will be wiped from the map in the next decade as the pit widens and deepens.</p>
<p>The oxides plant will use a solvent extraction and electrowinning process similar to those in leaching operations throughout northern Chile's metals industry.</p>
<p>The technique, no longer the cutting edge of copper it was a few years ago, is much cleaner than the old refining process but it takes a lot of water -- something in very short in the Atacama.</p>
<p>Escondida's current water supply from the Punta Negra salt flats won't be enough for the oxides plant so the mine is building an 80-km underground pipeline to bring water from an area known as Monturaqui.</p>
<p>Engineering studies and environmental approvals for the Monturaqui pipeline had to be finished before the oxides project could go ahead, said Zeballos. Expansion of the concentrator, which runs on a traditional flotation system, will also depend on a steady water supply from Monturaqui.</p>
<p>Sulphides in the open pit have a mineral grade of about 2.5 percent, &quot;which is of course fantastic,&quot; said Zeballos. Other big copper mines in Chile make do with less than one percent.</p>
<p>Sulphide grade will probably decline to 1.2-1.5 percent by the year 2010 or 2015, he said.</p>
<p>((--In Antofagasta, 56-55-268259, ext.522))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINA ESCONDIDA, Chile"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
