<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="616502" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile's Pelambres negotiating $935 mln credit.</title>
<headline>Chile's Pelambres negotiating $935 mln credit.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile's Los Pelambres copper mine began negotiating a $935 million loan to finance a $1.3 billion expansion from a banking syndicate about a month ago, a top official of the mine's Chilean partners said in a newspaper interview Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have received offers from a small group of banks which would lead the syndicated loan,&quot; Anaconda Chile general manager Jean-Paul Luksic told the Estrategia financial daily.</p>
<p>The banks are the Industrial Bank of Japan, Bank of Tokyo and Mitsubishi, ABM AMRO, Union Bank Suisse, Credit Lyonnaise, and also there is the German agency KFW and Japan's Eximbank.</p>
<p>Luksic said that if all goes well, the finance package could be agreed by October. The rest of the funding for the project will be provided by Los Pelambres' owners.</p>
<p>He added that the project's environmental impact study should be ready in June.</p>
<p>No Anaconda spokesman was immediately available to comment on the Estrategia report.</p>
<p>Anaconda is the mining arm of London-listed Antofagasta Holdings Plc, which is controlled by Chile's Luksic family.</p>
<p>Antofagasta Holdings said May 16 that it agreed to sell a 40 percent stake in Los Pelambres to two Japanese groups for about $256 million in cash.</p>
<p>The first consortium, which included Nippon Mining &amp; Metals Co Ltd, Marubeni Corp and Mitsui &amp; Co Ltd, planned to buy a 25 percent stake, while companies owned by the second group would hold a 15 percent equity interest.</p>
<p>The second Japanese group included Mitsubishi Materials Corp and Mitsubishi Corp.</p>
<p>In addition, Nippon Mining and Mitsubishi Materials conditionally agreed to buy 400,000 tonnes per year of copper concentrates from the project on a long-term basis of about 12 years.</p>
<p>Antofagasta Holdings said it would use proceeds from the deal to fund its equity financing obligations related to its 60 percent stake in the project.</p>
<p>Antofagasta projected planned production from Los Pelambres for the first 10 years at an average of 743,000 tonnes per year of copper concentrates, yielding about 246,000 tonnes per year of fine copper.</p>
<p>((--Jason Webb, Santiago Newsroom +562 672-5595))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
