<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="616670" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia Fuel Oil- Soft, 180-cst support at $103.50/T.</title>
<headline>Asia Fuel Oil- Soft, 180-cst support at $103.50/T.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Singapore high sulphur fuel oil market was a little soft on Tuesday after the 180-cst grade failed to break the $103.5-per-tonne barrier in the past few days, traders said.</p>
<p>The 180-cst was offered at $103.00 per tonne but there was no buyers. Traders said a major has been offering the 180-cst in the past few days, trying to get rid of its June stocks.</p>
<p>The market has largely discounted the impact of tight summer supplies from the Middle East.  </p>
<p>Two to three cargoes from the Mediterranean were heard to arrive in Singapore in the second half of June, adding supplies to this region, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Supply and demand look quite balanced at this moment,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The 180-cst grade has been capped by the $103.50-per-tonne level, with the last two cargoes traded at $103.50 per tonne last Tuesday.</p>
<p>Industry sources said the local trader who bought at least five cargoes in the past two weeks has stopped its purchase, reversing the previous uptrend momentum.  </p>
<p>National Iranian Oil Co (NIOC) has renewed its annual fuel oil term sale contracts with two Singapore companies, Hin Leong Trading and Kuo International for 1997/1998.</p>
<p>Under the contract for March 1997 to February 1998 liftings, Hin Leong will take four cargoes and Kuo two cargoes per month. Each cargo is between 75,000 and 90,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Taiwan's state Chinese Petroleum Corp (CPC) will announce on Wednesday the result for a tender to sell a third 30,000-tonne cargo of 3.0-percent sulphur fuel oil for June lifting.</p>
<p>Traders expected the awarded price at around $100.00 per tonne, compared with CPC's last awarded level at $101.00.  </p>
<p>Despite the relatively firm swaps market, &quot;the cargo market sentiment may become a little weak from now on if no additional demand comes out,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>June swaps were last quoted at $100.25/$101.00 against Monday's $101.75/$101.25.</p>
<p>In the LSWR market, the Korean Electric Power Company (KEPCO) has issued a tender to buy one 500,000-barrel cargo of 0.3-percent LSWR for July delivery, a KEPCO source said.</p>
<p>The tender, which seeks to buy the cargo for delivery July 18-22 to the ports of Ulsan or Pusan, will close on June 5 and is valid for a day, the source said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The tender is for July cargo, which won't help the current bearish sentiment,&quot; said one trader, noting the market was still waiting for Japan's summer demand to emerge to digest current ample supplies.</p>
<p>(Prices in dollars per tonne, unless stated)</p>
<p> MTH  FOB SIN		     BUY/SELL	  PREV BUY/SELL</p>
<p>MAY  LSWR *		    15.20/15.40	   15.20/15.40</p>
<p> MAY  FUEL OIL (180 CST)   102.00/104.00	 103.00/104.00</p>
<p> MAY  FUEL OIL (380 CST)    95.00/97.00	   96.00/97.00</p>
<p> JUN  FUEL OIL SWAPS	  99.75/100.50	 101.75/101.25</p>
<p> JUL  FUEL OIL SWAPS	  98.50/99.50	   99.00/99.50</p>
<p>*Dollars per barrel</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (+65-870 3571)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
