<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="616608" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Chinese boat seized after chase, Beijing protests.</title>
<headline>Chinese boat seized after chase, Beijing protests.</headline>
<dateline>SUBIC, Philippines 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A row between the Philippines and China over rival claims in the South China Sea intensified on Tuesday when Beijing protested at the seizure of 21 Chinese fishermen and their boat in the disputed area.</p>
<p>Chinese Consul-General Shi Bingyi demanded the release of the fishermen, who were apprehended off the Scarborough Shoal on May 20 following a dramatic boat chase. Both Beijing and Manila claim sovereignty over the barely-visible rocks.</p>
<p>In the chase, a Philippine Navy patrol ship fired warning shots across the Chinese bow to force the boat to stop, Coast Guard officials said.</p>
<p>Shi said the fishermen were in Chinese territory when they were seized.</p>
<p>The fishermen are being kept under guard on their boat, now anchored off Subic freeport, west of Manila, Coast Guard officials said.</p>
<p>The officials told Reuters the Chinese boat had tried to flee as the Navy ship approached, triggering a chase.</p>
<p>The Philippine ship fired two warning shots before the Chinese boat stopped. The Filipinos then took over the vessel, said the officials, who asking not to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese fishermen have every right to fish in Huang Yan island (Scarborough Shoal) because it's part of Chinese territory,&quot; a Filipino diplomat quoted Shi as saying.</p>
<p>The latest diplomatic clash between the two countries flared while their senior officials met in Beijing to try to defuse growing tension over their rival claims to tiny islands and rocky outcrops in the South China Sea.</p>
<p>Beijing insists all the islands, reefs and rocks in the area historically belong to China. Manila says the 16-km (10-mile) rock formation lies within its exclusive economic zone, giving it ownership.</p>
<p>The rocks, which almost disappear at high tide and are little more than a resting place for smugglers, lie 200 km (125 miles) west of the Philippines' mainland Zambales province.</p>
<p>It was the third time this month that the two countries have tangled over the rocks.</p>
<p>China earlier protested against the hoisting by Filipinos of their national flag over the rocks. It protested again when a group of Philippine congressmen sailed to the shoal to be photographed standing under the flag.</p>
<p>The Navy said charges of poaching were being prepared against the Chinese.</p>
<p>Two days after their arrest -- which Manila kept secret -- President Fidel Ramos adopted a conciliatory tone, telling financiers in Hong Kong that Manila was ready to settle disputes with China by peaceful negotiations.</p>
<p>News of the arrest was unknown until Shi strode into the Foreign Ministry on Tuesday and demanded their release.</p>
<p>&quot;It is in everyone's interest to lower the alarm levels and temperature level,&quot; Philippine Foreign Secretary Domingo Siazon told reporters after China's protest.</p>
<p>The shoal lies well north of the Spratly islands, a cluster of potentially oil-rich isles, reefs and atolls that the two countries are also arguing over. The Spratlys are also claimed wholly or in part by Vietnam, Taiwan, Malaysia and Brunei.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SUBIC, Philippines"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
