<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="616637" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Benguet hopes to see light with projects.</title>
<headline>Benguet hopes to see light with projects.</headline>
<byline>Dolly Aglay</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Benguet Corp is optimistic it will be able to reverse its losses in 1998 with new projects and after it secured a one-year moratorium on its debts, officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Once the Philippine's largest gold miner, Benguet received a one-year reprieve on principal payments on its 944 million pesos ($35.9 million) debts from 19 local and foreign banks early this year, a senior official said.</p>
<p>He said the firm requested relief from banks because of losses incurred last year.</p>
<p>Benguet swung to a net loss of 165.1 million pesos in 1996 from a profit of 40.2 million in 1995.</p>
<p>The company suffered from unfavourable metal prices and poor production due to natural disasters and opposition by small-scale miners, company president Dennis Belmonte told stockholders in their annual meeting.</p>
<p>This made it difficult for the firm to access its mines in northern Philippines last year, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;For this year, it will be another loss,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the short term outlook for your company's profit performance may not look encouraging at all, we remain optimistic about your company's medium to long-term outlook.&quot;</p>
<p>Other officials said they expected Benguet to rebound in 1998.</p>
<p>The company hopes form an additional $85 million next year to pay off its debts.</p>
<p>The money is expected to come from Echo Bay Mines and TVI Pacific Inc when they exercise their option to develop the Kingking copper and gold mine in Pantukan, Davao del Norte in southern Philippines.</p>
<p>Belmonte, in his report to stockholders, said the latest study by Echo Bay and TVI showed higher reserves.</p>
<p>&quot;Early results of the drilling show the ore reserves have increased at more than 529 million tonnes at a lower grade of 0.35 percent total copper and 0.41 grams of gold per tonne,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An earlier study done by Benguet indicated ore reserves of 315 million tonnes at a grade of 0.44 percent total copper and 0.52 grams of gold per tonne.</p>
<p>&quot;The Kingking project appears to be the brightest mining prospect for your company,&quot; Belmonte said. &quot;In the same horizon, your company's possible entry into real estate development could be the new impetus that will restore your company's preeminent position in Philippine business,&quot; Belmonte said.</p>
<p>Early this year, Benguet signed an agreement with affiliate Petrofields Exploration and Development Co Inc to develop a 240-hectare (592-acre) site near the mountain city of Baguio.</p>
<p>Belmonte said Benguet is also conducting its own studies on the development of other landholdings near Baguio City into similar real estate projects.</p>
<p>&quot;Should these activities turn out to be favourable, your company could also well be in the real estate business in the years to come,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Manila Newsroom (63 2) 841 8936</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
