<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="616770" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish MPs say scandal report not good enough.</title>
<headline>Turkish MPs say scandal report not good enough.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish MPs said on Tuesday a parliament report on state links with right-wing gangsters did not go far enough and called for further investigations to expose the biggest offenders.</p>
<p>&quot;The report is full of holes, it does not produce a result and is lacking in documentation and information,&quot; leftist MP Fikri Saglar told parliament during a debate on the &quot;Susurluk report&quot;, prepared by an MPs' commission after a crash in which a top policeman and a fugitive gangster died in the same car.</p>
<p>The report issued in April accused two MPs from Foreign Minister Tansu Ciller's True Path party -- former interior minister Mehmet Agar and Sedat Bucak -- of deep involvement in underworld dealings.</p>
<p>It painted a bleak picture of rightist gangsters using state privileges to kill, trade guns and traffic drugs. Bucak himself was injured in the road accident last November.</p>
<p>Conservative opposition MP Halit Dumankaya, from the Motherland Party, said the commission had not been able to produce a proper report for fear of hurting the government.</p>
<p>&quot;With this report, the gangs have taken the state prisoner. The state has been delivered to the gangs,&quot; Dumankaya said.</p>
<p>The real culprits were far more senior than the two MPs implicated, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;According to parliament rules, it is possible to form a new commission. So a new commission must be formed and the incidents followed up,&quot; Dumankaya said.</p>
<p>On Monday, a Turkish truck driver became the only person convicted so far in the scandal when he was found guilty of causing the car crash that unearthed the murky ties between the state and gangs.</p>
<p>He was made to pay 100 million lira ($720) in damages to relatives of those who died when his truck hit a car in the western town of Susurluk and was fined six million lira.</p>
<p>Esref Erdem, another leftist opposition MP, criticized the commission's failure to interview Ciller during the inquiry.</p>
<p>The commission decided at the last minute not to speak to Ciller and a leading general, sparking a row among its members.</p>
<p>Commission member Bedri Incetahtaci, of the government's Islamist wing, said a more conclusive investigation would not be possible without a mandate to delve deep into state affairs over the past few decades.</p>
<p>&quot;Let us form a permanent specialist commission,&quot; Incetahtaci told parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;A specialist commission would not be limited to certain events. It must look into every aspect of such vital issues and regularly inform parliament and the public,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>($1=139,640 lira)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
