<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="616883" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. investors warm to Brazil bond swap roadshow.</title>
<headline>U.S. investors warm to Brazil bond swap roadshow.</headline>
<byline>George Lerner</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil will likely succeed with its upcoming Brady bond swap as long as it offers room for capital gains, according to U.S. investors who attended the country's road show on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Brazil kicked off its three-leg road show here on its offer to swap Brady bonds for a 30-year global bond, or to allow outright purchase of the global bond.</p>
<p>A high clearing price that allows for price appreciation will be essential to generate interest in the global bond and U.S. investors sounded upbeat that Brazil would comply.  </p>
<p>&quot;The consensus is that the risks going into the exchange will be worth it because Brazil would like to make it successful,&quot; said one U.S. investor.</p>
<p>The deal would allow investors to tender their Par bonds, Discount Z-L bonds or &quot;C&quot; bonds for the global bond issue.</p>
<p>Market talk has pegged the issue at 350-400 basis points above U.S. Treasuries, but U.S. investors expected the deal to price at the upper end of that range.  </p>
<p>&quot;Most people I talked to are more comfortable with the upper end,&quot; said another U.S. investor. &quot;If it's priced to tight, I don't think there would be a lot of upside. 375 basis points is a bare minimum.&quot;</p>
<p>Since the tender prices for the old Brady instruments are below market prices, investors need to be compensated with strong gains when the issue hits secondary trade.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the clearing price will not be lower than 380 because people are going to to be making bids on the cheaper side to compensate for selling the bonds at a lower price,&quot; one attendee said.</p>
<p>One investor said many attendees seemed to be short-term players, but institutional investors were also present. Talk circulated that the issue would also attract strong interest from Brazilian banks.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Brazilian Brady bonds fell on overall market weakness. Brazil's &quot;C&quot; bonds slipped 3/4 to 78-7/8 bid, Discounts lost 1/2 to 83 and Pars were down 3/4 to 65-3/8.</p>
<p>Brazil's road show will move on to Boston on Wednesday and London on Thursday. Goldman Sachs and JP Morgan are acting as joint lead managers on the deal.</p>
<p>-- Emerging Markets Desk, 212-859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
