<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="616810" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Last Aberdeen Proving Ground rape charge dropped.</title>
<headline>Last Aberdeen Proving Ground rape charge dropped.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Funk</byline>
<dateline>ABERDEEN, Md. 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Army prosecutors on Tuesday dropped the final rape charge in a wide-ranging investigation into sexual misconduct at the Aberdeen Proving Ground.</p>
<p>Without elaboration, prosecutors dropped one count each of rape, forcible sodomy and extortion against Staff Sgt. Vernell Robinson Jr., Army officials said. The action was announced just before the start of Robinson's scheduled court-martial trial.</p>
<p>Robinson, a drill sergeant at the proving ground's Ordnance Centre and School, continues to face charges on 20 other counts including indecent assault, adultery and communicating a threat.</p>
<p>A seven-member military jury in the case was chosen on Tuesday afternoon. Attorneys from both sides were barred under a court order from discussing the case.</p>
<p>Robinson was one of four trainers at the Proving Ground who had been charged with rape. Eight other soldiers were charged with lesser sexual misconduct in a controversial investigation that was first revealed in November 1996 and led to an Army-wide probe of sexual harassment.</p>
<p>Only one of those at Aberdeen charged with rape, Staff Sgt. Delmar Simpson, was convicted. He was sentenced this month to 25 years on convictions of raping six female trainees.</p>
<p>Military law expert Eugene Fidell said the decision to drop the rape charge against Robinson probably reflected individual circumstances, but may also demonstrate more caution by prosecutors after Simpson's controversial trial and conviction.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that the management there (at the base) has learned some lessons from, A, prosecuting the Simpson case and, B, from the dismay that at least some members of the public had at the charge of rape being used in the circumstances that were presented,&quot; said Fidell, an attorney and president of the National Institute of Military Justice.</p>
<p>A key issue in Simpson's case was the prosecution's contention that his authority as a drill instructor gave him such power that he could be considered to have raped female trainees under his command even though some made no overt resistance to his sexual overtures.</p>
<p>Simpson was convicted on 18 of 19 rape counts he faced, although several counts were dropped before trial. Robinson's jury included three jurors who also sat on the jury which convicted Simpson.</p>
<p>Of the two other Aberdeen trainers initially charged with rape, Capt. Derrick Robertson pleaded guilty in March to adultery and consensual sodomy but was found innocent of rape and forcible sodomy, and two rape charges against Staff Sgt. Herman Gunter were dropped in an investigative proceeding that ended earlier this month.</p>
<p>Five female trainees at the base had charged in March that investigators tried to coerce them into saying they were raped, but they said they refused to characterise their sexual encounters that way.</p>
<p>Black congressional and civil rights leaders also said the investigation may have unfairly targeted black soldiers -- all those charged at Aberdeen were black.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABERDEEN, Md."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
