<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="616926" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Coffee price soars, oil and grains fall sharply.</title>
<headline>Coffee price soars, oil and grains fall sharply.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Avidan</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coffee futures soared on Tuesday as continuing worries about short supplies of high quality arabica coffee beans threatened to push the market to new 20-year highs, traders said.</p>
<p>At the Coffee Sugar and Cocoa Exchange in New York, coffee for July delivery rose 17.45 cents a pound to close at 274.30 cents, just below the 20-year high of 280 cents a pound set by the expired May coffee contract two weeks ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The perception is that supply is tight and will remain tight into the December contract,&quot; said Refco analyst Ann Prendergast. &quot;I don't expect to see any enormous amount of coffee coming onto the market between now and October, and that's going to support prices.&quot;</p>
<p>Coffee prices have risen more than 150 percent since December as stockpiles in both consuming and producing countries hover near 20-year lows.</p>
<p>Supply worries for the coming year have been fed by forecasts for smaller-than-expected crops in many Latin American countries, labor unrest in top producers Brazil and Colombia and fears of a smaller crop in Brazil next year.</p>
<p>Worries about a possible frost in June and July in Brazil, a top grower of mild arabica beans, are also keeping nerves on edge.</p>
<p>Supply concerns were reignited by news from a meeting of the Association of Coffee Producing Countries in London last week that 14-nation group agreed to continue to limit members' exports to 52.75 million bags for 12 months from July 1.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch analyst Judith Ganes said the accord, if honored, would keep roasters from rebuilding stocks this year.</p>
<p>&quot;If abided by, the impact will keep consumer stocks from rebuilding next season,&quot; Ganes said in a report to client.</p>
<p>The ACPC on Tuesday said world coffee production in the year beginning in June would fall to 97.65 million 132-pound bags from 98.40 million a year earlier, with a likely supply shortfall of at least 1.5 million bags.</p>
<p>Large coffee roasters have already hiked retail prices of coffee by nearly 50 percent since February and traders said another round of retail price hikes -- the fifth -- could be in store for coffee drinkers in the next few weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I would expect it to have an impact on consumption,&quot; said Prendergast. &quot;The limit in this market is when people want to stop buying coffee at those prices -- or when there's more coffee.&quot;</p>
<p>At the New York Mercantile Exchange, oil prices fell sharply as talk of sufficient supply of both crude oil and unleaded gasoline put an end to the market's recent strength.</p>
<p>Crude oil for July delivery closed 84 cents lower at $20.79 a barrel, with June unleaded gasoline ending 1.54 cents a gallon lower at 65.38 cents and June heating oil ending 2.25 cents a gallon lower at 55.27 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot depends on what products do, and right now the products are coming off. Unless gasoline can take the ball and run with it, over time the fundamentals are less favorable,&quot; said Smith Barney analyst John Saucer.</p>
<p>Crude oil markets typically look for demand in the unleaded gasoline market during the peak summer driving period. Although unleaded gasoline inventories are about 7 million barrels below last year's levels, crude stocks and refinery usage rates remain high.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Board of Trade, beneficial rains in the Midwest and Plains over the weekend produced a sharp fall in grain and soybean prices as production prospects improved.</p>
<p>Wheat for July delivery closed 11-1/2 cents a bushel lower at $3.63-1/2 cents, while July corn closed 6-1/4 cents a bushel lower at $2.64-1/4 and July soybeans closed 4-3/4 cents a bushel lower at $8.31-1/4.</p>
<p>&quot;It was largely a fund-led selloff today,&quot; said Mark Weidner, oilseeds analyst with Cargill Investor Services, referring to sales of futures contracts by speculative commodity funds exiting the markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Weather had a lot to do with it and plantings progress kept the support away from the market,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In a weekly update after the market closed, the Agriculture Department said that as of Sunday, 95 percent of U.S. corn and 70 percent of soybeans were planted, both far ahead of the five-year averages and last year's pace.</p>
<p>Conditions of the U.S. wheat crop also continued to improve after a rough winter and spring which saw a sudden frost in the High Plains as well as flooding in the Dakotas, a leading production area for spring wheat.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
