<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61708" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALTA: Share index maintains rally on Malta Exchange.</title>
<headline>Share index maintains rally on Malta Exchange.</headline>
<dateline>VALLETTA 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Malta Stock Exchange share index continued to rise on Wednesday, climbing 1.85 points to break 1,000 at 1,001.18, the highest since July.</p>
<p>The rise was fuelled mostly by a continuing increase in the average price of Mid-Med Bank shares, but it was dampened by the price of soft drinks manufacturer, Farsons, ordinary shares. Farsons shares continued to lose ground, reaching 55 cents in Wednesday's once-weekly session after having had an average price of 62 cents a month ago.</p>
<p>Turnover on Wednesday reached Lm948,000 ($2.6 million), from the previous week's Lm1,067,300 ($2.97 million).  </p>
<p>There were 125 deals, of which 67 were in equities and 58 in fixed income securities.</p>
<p>Business in equities amounted to Lm79,383, with 52,984 shares being traded. Of these, 32,618 were Bank of Valletta shares, which were sold in 33 deals for an average of 130 cents, up from 129.3 cents.</p>
<p>There were six deals in Mid-Med Bank, with 3,340 shares selling for an average of 150.6 cents, up from 147.9 cents. These shares also rose by almost two cents last week.  </p>
<p>There were no deals in Lombard Bank Malta, but three deals were effected in Middle Sea Insurance shares at an average price of 120.6 cents, up six mils.</p>
<p>Trading picked up in Farsons ordinary shares, with 10,580 being traded, but the average price continued to fall reaching 55 cents from last week's 57.8.</p>
<p>Farsons' six percent preference shares with a nominal value of Lm10 also traded on Wednesday, with 1,956 shares changing hands at an average of Lm10.59. These shares were last traded on July 24 at an average Lm10.60.</p>
<p>Most of the activity on the trading floor on Wednesday was in the government bond market where 18 issues were dealt in, turnover reached Lm860,700.</p>
<p>Business was mainly in the 7.25 percent MGS 2006 (III) and the 6.3 percent MGS 1999 (III).</p>
<p>In corporate bonds, six deals were struck, four in Mid-Med Bank 7.25 percent unsecured loan stock 2005 amounting to Lm2,475 and two in the 6.5 percent GFC bond amounting to just over Lm5,400.</p>
<p>(1Maltese lira = $2.79)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALTA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALLETTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALTA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
