<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="617035" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: San Francisco area home prices surge 8.8 pct.</title>
<headline>San Francisco area home prices surge 8.8 pct.</headline>
<dateline>LA JOLLA, Calif. 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Home prices in the San Francisco Bay area rose 8.8 percent in April to levels not seen since their 1989-1991 peaks, according to a survey released on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The median price paid for a resale house in the nine-county Bay area was $260,000 last month, up 8.8 percent from $239,000 in March and up 11.6 percent from $233,000 for April last year, the DataQuick survey said.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's Bay area home market is stronger than it was six years ago,&quot; said Mike Ela, DataQuick's president.  </p>
<p>Ela said Bay area home prices have now regained virtually all the lost ground of the recession.</p>
<p>A total of 5,891 resale houses were sold in the nine-county Bay area last month, up 18.3 percent from 4,979 in March and up 8.7 percent from 4,642 for April last year, the survey said.</p>
<p>The Bay area has recorded year-over-year increases in sales volume for the last year-and-a-half.  If current trends stayed in place, 1997 would see the highest number of homes sold since 1989, the survey said.  </p>
<p>A total of 1,441 Bay area resale condominiums were sold in April, up 27.2 percent from 1,133 a year ago.  The median price was $179,000, up 3.5 percent from $173,000 a year ago, the survey said.</p>
<p>A total of 1,148 newly-built homes were sold last month, up 29.3 percent from 888 a year ago.  The median price was $251,000, up 3.7 percent from $242,000 in 1996, DataQuick reported.</p>
<p>DataQuick monitors real estate purchasing and financing nationwide.</p>
<p>The nine-county Bay area includes Alameda, Contra Costa, Marin, Napa, San Francisco, San Mateo, Santa Clara, Solano and Sonoma counties.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8500031">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LA JOLLA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
