<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="617171" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Sierra Leone asks for intervention, sanctions.</title>
<headline>Sierra Leone asks for intervention, sanctions.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sierra Leone's ousted president has asked West African states to restore his government and for sanctions to be imposed against army corporals who engineered a weekend coup, the country's U.N. ambassador announced on Tuesday.</p>
<p>James Jonah, a former U.N. undersecretary-general, said President Ahmad Tejan Kabbah had &quot;made an appeal (to West African countries) to help restore democracy,&quot; which could include the use of troops.</p>
<p>Jonah also said he had been authorised to go to the forthcoming Organisation of African Unity summit in the Zimbabwean capital of Harare to ask for sanctions against the coup leaders. These would include non-recognition of their regime and a travel ban on those who organised the revolt.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to make it difficult for any military leaders to make a coup,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>Jonah said Kabbah wanted immediate action &quot;because we have no time&quot; or the coup, which still faces widespread opposition, would be consolidated. He emphasised that Nigerian troops were part of a West African coalition and were not acting alone.</p>
<p>But in a confusing turn of events, U.N. sources said the rebels had now taken over the airport, which had been guarded by Nigerian and other West African troops, and had timed their coup during a rotation of African troops.</p>
<p>At the same time Kieran Prendergast, U.N. undersecretary-general for political affairs, told reporters Nigerian troops had landed in Sierra Leone &quot;in cooperation with the coup leaders&quot; in order to help &quot;bring the situation under control and restore law and order.&quot;</p>
<p>Jonah said the coup leaders were 20 non-commissioned officers who were encouraged by the lack of opposition to Laurent Kabila's rebel forces in Zaire, now the Democratic Republic of Congo. &quot;But Kabbah is not Mobutu,&quot; he said, referring to Zaire's ousted autocratic president Mobutu Sese Seko.</p>
<p>Asked if Kabbah, now in Guinea, had asked for troops to overthrow the coup plotters, Jonah said: &quot;If possible yes.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;What else do we have in the country? We have a bunch of corporals who opened the prisons wide open and 600 people came out, criminals, and they are roaming the streets right now.&quot;</p>
<p>He said there had been a &quot;firm commitment&quot; from the West African group ECOWAS to &quot;restore the legitimate government of Sierra Leone. How they are going to do it I do not know.&quot;</p>
<p>But Jonah said he was not going to the U.N. Security Council to ask for sanctions or endorsement of any intervention, saying the council moved too slowly and African nations had a right to intervene.</p>
<p>Jonah, 63, was responsible for organising successful elections in Sierra Leone a year ago over the objections of army officers who had seized power earlier and sought to back out of elections by intimidating voters.</p>
<p>He said Sierra Leone now had two armies, the regular one and that from the former National Provisional Ruling Council (NPRC), which once ruled the country by force. Many NPRC officers were sent to Britain on scholarships and others were dispersed in separate units but managed to organise anyway.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, he said, all soldiers were undisciplined and embarked on widespread destruction and looting, including the treasury building and the national bank. He said the rebels had put uniforms on prisoners to bolster their forces.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECOWAS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OAU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SILEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
