<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="617106" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FDA okays sites for PLC Systems Heart Laser.</title>
<headline>FDA okays sites for PLC Systems Heart Laser.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKLIN, Mass. 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>PLC Systems Inc said Tuesday the U.S. Food and Drug Administration has approved its request to add fifteen new clinical testing sites for the company's Heart Laser Transmyocardial Revascularization (TMR) System.</p>
<p>With the expansion approval, the company said thirty-five clinical sites in the United States are now allowed to enroll end-stage coronary artery disease patients.</p>
<p>PLC Systems, which had been granted expedited review of its PreMarket Approval (PMA) application for the heart laser system, is testing it on patients with medically refractory angina who are not candidates for angioplasty or bypass surgery.</p>
<p>The company said the FDA recently notified it the PMA application is expected to be reviewed by the agency's circulatory systems advisory panel during a meeting scheduled for July 28 and 29.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the FDA's decision to authorize the company's request to increase the number of clinical sites is a positive indication for The Heart Laser TMR System,&quot; said company chairman Robert Rudko.</p>
<p>((- New York Newsdesk, 212 859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKLIN, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
