<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="617241" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bonds/futures closing report.</title>
<headline>Italian bonds/futures closing report.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian debt markets recovered at the close after nervousness over a strong showing for France's Socialists in the first round of elections had a delayed impact on London and U.S. traders back from a long weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;After the initial nervousness the market calmed,&quot; one broker said noting Bunds had recovered, helping Btps and futures to close near the day's highs.</p>
<p>Now, brokers said, the market would probably wait and see how voting progressed in the second round next weekend.</p>
<p>The June future on LIFFE ended five basis points up on positive turf at 129.95 after dipping to 128.90.  </p>
<p>The cash February 2007 Btp ended 70 basis points up at 97.27, having already suffered the French election effect on Monday when London and U.S. markets were closed.</p>
<p>The Btp was yielding 7.26 percent and at one point the spread over the benchmark 10-year Bund closed in to a record level of 133 basis points before ending at 135 basis points.</p>
<p>On the domestic front, the market was awaiting more details on the government's three-year economic plan which is expected to be unveiled by the end of the week. In addition it is waiting for a possible Italian discount rate cut and wondering what will be the ultimate factor which will prompt it.  </p>
<p>Some see a 50 to 75 basis point cut by Friday evening once the government's three-year plan (Dpef) is unveiled and others expect the Bank of Italy to wait until next week once the final French vote is out of the way.</p>
<p>As far as details on the Dpef go, Treasury undersecretary Laura Pennacchi said the 1998 budget would need to contain 25 to 28 trillion lire of deficit cutting measures, with the bias on the high side.</p>
<p>Budget Ministry undersecretary Giorgio Macciotta said Italy would take further measures if the 1997 deficit turned out to be more than three percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +392 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
