<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61726" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: EU says no special terms for Egypt wheat contract.</title>
<headline>EU says no special terms for Egypt wheat contract.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A top European Commission official on Wednesday ruled out a specially targeted refund to smoothe a major recent wheat sale to Egypt and said a decision on whether and how to cover the sale with general subsidies would depend on short-term prices in the United States.</p>
<p>Guy Legras, director general for agriculture, also stressed in an interview there had been no advance agreement between exporters and the Commission regarding the weekend sale of 450,000 tonnes of French wheat at $163.90-167.00, FOB.  </p>
<p>He was responding to trade speculation of a &quot;pre-cooked&quot; deal between Brussels and a batch of exporters who lined up the wheat sales at the weekend, rumours which implied that the European Commission had agreed in advance to cover the deals with the necessary export subsidies.</p>
<p>Egypt said on Sunday it had bought 450,000 tonnes of French wheat for October-November shipment, causing U.S. wheat futures markets to skid lower on Monday.</p>
<p>Legras said his first reaction was that the sales price was low, although the European Union would only decide its response when it saw traders' bids as well as the level of U.S. prices.  </p>
<p>&quot;My first reaction: the selling price seems low to me,&quot; Legras told Reuters during a trip to Paris to brief a French parliamentary committee on mad cow disease.</p>
<p>Legras, who is seen as holding authoritative sway over EU grain decisions, cautioned however that he had not studied the market closely in recent days because of full-time commitments in discussing the European crisis over cattle disease.</p>
<p>But the EU had a general practice of watching trade bids and aligning itself with U.S. prices and would do so again now. He recalled that whereas the EU had sold some wheat to Egypt in the past, Cairo was not one of its mainstay markets.  </p>
<p>The next chance for European grain exporters to bid for subsidies to close the $15 a tonne or so gap between the Egyptian price and higher French wheat costs is on Thursday.</p>
<p>The EU earlier on Wednesday cleared the way for traders to seek export subsidies for wheat exports by cancelling an export tax mechanism in place since last December.</p>
<p>Export refunds have been justified on paper by world markets for some weeks but the Commission was unable to grant them while also accepting export taxes at tenders each Thursday. Exceptions have been for sales to African, Caribbean and Pacific countries assisted by the EU through trade accords.  </p>
<p>Ahead of Thursday's tender, U.S. wheat export prices were seen around $166 per tonne compared with French September wheat at some $180 per tonne, fob.</p>
<p>In EU subsidy terms, and discounting any adjustment for freight differentials between Europe and the United States, this would imply an EU refund of some eight Ecus, traders said.</p>
<p>It remained unclear whether the EU would jump from taxes to this kind of subsidy at the first possible tender on Thursday.</p>
<p>Legras did however flatly rule out following world markets as low as Argentine prices of barely more than $140 per tonne.</p>
<p>-- Paule Bonjean, Tim Hepher, Paris newsroom +331 4221 5146</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
