<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61728" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Aerolineas Argentinas expects to breakeven in 1996.</title>
<headline>Aerolineas Argentinas expects to breakeven in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aerolineas Argentinas SA expects to breakeven this calendar year and make a moderate net profit in 1997, its first in many years, economic manager Edgardo Jorge Cabrera said.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1996 we should reach breakeven and next year we hope to produce a profit,&quot; he told Reuters during a conference in Madrid.</p>
<p>&quot;We have made tremendous cost savings and hoped to breakeven earlier but just then fares fell,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The airline, still managed by Iberia although the Spanish flag carrier has reduced its stake to 10 percent, made a net loss of $135 million in the second six months of 1995. It has switched its financial year end to December instead of June from this year so does not have a full-year figure for 1995.</p>
<p>The net loss in the first half of this year was $14 million but Aerolineas produced profits in July and August. Iberia said last month the Argentine carrier had recorded a seven-month profit of $3.6 million net.</p>
<p>Aerolineas has abandoned some unprofitable Latin American destinations and increased frequencies to more profitable ones such as Rio de Janeiro and Sao Paulo.</p>
<p>It flies daily to Madrid, continuing to London, and twice a week to Rome via Sao Paolo. Cargo business on the first route is minimal because most of the movement is from Madrid to Buenos Aires and not vice versa, but business from Sao Paulo to Rome is substantial, Cabrera said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
