<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="617317" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India clears ONGC, IOC LNG deal.</title>
<headline>India clears ONGC, IOC LNG deal.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral's cabinet on Tuesday approved a liquefied natural gas (LNG) import venture linking four state-controlled firms.</p>
<p>The companies are Oil and Natural Gas Corp (ONGC), Indian Oil Corp (IOC), Bharat Petroleum Corp Ltd (BPCL) and Gas Authority of India Ltd (GAIL).  </p>
<p>The new firm would have an equity base of 12 billion rupees ($335 million), half of which would be held by state-run firms, the government said in a statement.</p>
<p>The cabinet also approved a proposal to build facilities to import LNG.</p>
<p>&quot;The proposed approach will encourage the development of the LNG sector, thus providing access to a clean and competitive fuel which is specially required for power generation,&quot; the statement said.  </p>
<p>A government spokesman told reporters it had been left to the joint venture to decide how to mobilise the remaining 50 percent of the equity.</p>
<p>The LNG sector required establishing LNG links with gas fields, liquefication of gas, shipping, regassification and end-uses such as power generation.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the joint venture would have a strong presence in the energy market in India with a good credit rating, a nationwide marketing infrastructure and expertise to develop LNG chain links. ($1=35.8 rupees)</p>
<p>-- New Delhi newsroom +91 11 301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
