<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="617666" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Khatami says U.S. holds key to relations with Iran.</title>
<headline>Khatami says U.S. holds key to relations with Iran.</headline>
<byline>Barry May</byline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran's incoming president Mohammad Khatami on Tuesday blamed the United States for two decades of animosity and said Washington held the key to any thaw in ties.</p>
<p>Khatami, due to take over from President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani in August, said relations with the United States would depend on observing changes in its attitude towards Iran. &quot;But unfortunately we have not seen anything.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore, the key to the problem is in their hands and not ours,&quot; Khatami, a moderate Shi'ite cleric, said at his first news conference since a landslide election victory on Friday.</p>
<p>Khatami, whose election was Iran's biggest political upset since Shi'ite Moslem fundamentalists ousted the pro-American Shah in 1979, said: &quot;We are sorry to see that the United States' policy has always been hostile to our revolution.&quot;</p>
<p>Iran and the United States have had no diplomatic relations since Washington severed them in 1980 during the U.S. embassy crisis when radical students held 52 Americans captive for 444 days.</p>
<p>The comments by Khatami, seen as a tolerant politician compared with the conservative clerics who control the Iranian establishment, reiterated those of other Iranian officials.</p>
<p>Analysts said Khatami's stance was close to that of Rafsanjani and not as uncompromising as some of the positions taken by Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, who has final say in major state policies and has rejected the possibility of improving ties with Washington.</p>
<p>Khatami said the United States was the source of the problem and there would be no ground for any ties as long as it wanted to harm Iran's independence or national interest.</p>
<p>U.S. analysts in Washington on Monday described Khatami's election as a turning point in the revolution and said the Clinton administration -- which has imposed sanctions on Iran -- should rethink its policy of isolating the Islamic republic.</p>
<p>The United States accuses Iran of sponsoring international &quot;terrorism&quot;, seeking nuclear arms and trying to wreck Middle East peace efforts -- charges which Iran denies.</p>
<p>Khatami dismissed charges of Iranian involvement in international &quot;terrorism&quot;, saying: &quot;We have always been against terrorism and especially state terrorism.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Iran opposed the Middle East peace process, but made it clear Tehran would not take any action to disrupt peace.</p>
<p>&quot;We are interested in peace and tranquillity...under the condition that the rights of all sides to the matter would be observed,&quot; he said. &quot;Of course, we are not going to have any intervention in this matter and we are going to leave it to the people of Palestine and the governments and the people of the region.</p>
<p>&quot;But we do keep the right to express our views regarding the matter...and with a scientific, realistic approach we do think that the current process will not come to any conclusion.&quot;</p>
<p>Khatami -- speaking through an interpreter -- said Iran was &quot;interested in all-out cooperation with all Arab and Islamic countries&quot; and would exert all efforts towards this goal.</p>
<p>He said Iran disagreed with some of Egypt's policies but still respected &quot;the great nation of Egypt&quot;.</p>
<p>He said it would be in the interest of both states to put their differences aside and work &quot;hand in hand&quot; against Israel, which he accused of sponsoring state terrorism.</p>
<p>Egypt has said Iran's alleged support of political violence stands in the way of a thaw in relations between the two countries. It has accused Iran and Sudan of backing an attempt by Egyptian militants to kill President Hosni Mubarak in 1995. Both countries denied the charges.</p>
<p>Khatami said Tehran opposed Turkey's cross-border offensive against Kurdish rebels in northern Iraq and said a military offensive would not help settle differences.</p>
<p>He said Iran supported the territorial integrity of all countries, including Iraq -- the enemy Iran fought an eight-year war with in the 1980s.</p>
<p>Khatami said he had begun consultations on the formation of his cabinet. Asked if he would appoint a woman as a minister, he said the government had a duty to provide equal opportunities to women and &quot;I see no impediment to their presence in the highest possible positions in the country. Therefore opportunities are left with their capabilities and not their gender&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
