<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="617668" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordanian pleads not guilty in schoolgirl killings.</title>
<headline>Jordanian pleads not guilty in schoolgirl killings.</headline>
<byline>Suleiman al-Khalidi</byline>
<dateline>MARJ AL-HAMAM, Jordan 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Jordanian soldier charged with premeditated murder of seven Israeli schoolgirls in March pleaded not guilty at the opening session of his military trial on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Ahmed al-Daqamsa, cheered on by his wife and mother, stood in a black cage as four charges including premeditated murder and military disobedience were read out in the courtroom at a military base a few miles (km) south of Amman.</p>
<p>&quot;Do you understand the charges?&quot; asked Brigadier Mamoun al-Khasawneh, head of a five-man tribunal of military judges.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes. Not guilty,&quot; said Daqamsa, who faces the death penalty if convicted. The case was adjourned until Monday.</p>
<p>Daqamsa, wearing an olive green military uniform, was brought by soldiers to the cage, prompting his elderly mother, wearing traditional Jordanian costume with a bedouin headscarf, to recite Moslem prayers.</p>
<p>&quot;Hold your head up high, don't be afraid...God is with you,&quot; the woman from the northern village of Ibdr, close to the Israeli border, told her son. &quot;God is above all, defend yourself ...what they say about you are lies.&quot;</p>
<p>His veiled wife told Daqamsa across the court that his three-year-old daughter Noor sent her love and they were proud of him. Khasawneh warned Daqamsa's mother to keep quiet or be evicted from the courtroom.</p>
<p>Daqamsa lost his composure only once when he shouted &quot;lies&quot; and shook the iron bars after the prosecution said he told an army comrade to get out of their car just before the shooting, so he (Daqamsa) could masturbate while watching the girls.</p>
<p>Defence counsel Ahmed Nijdawi told the court earlier that he objected to &quot;wounding words&quot; in the charge list which he said were inserted to discredit Daqamsa.</p>
<p>&quot;These words have no purpose but to discredit my client, whom we regard from our point of view as a devout soldier who did what he did for his nation and to protect his military honour,&quot; Nijdawi said.</p>
<p>The prosecution said Daqamsa got out of the car, switched his rifle to rapid fire, and fired at the girls from a distance of just five metres (yards).</p>
<p>Nijdawi has said Daqamsa shot the teenage girls, on a school trip to the border region of Baqoura, on the spur of the moment because they were teasing him while he prayed.</p>
<p>But the prosecution said Daqamsa had killed the girls, part of a group of 50 students aged between 11 and 14, in cold blood. They said he had seven ammunition clips and would have shot more if his rifle had not jammed after he finished the third clip.</p>
<p>After he was finally captured by colleagues, Daqamsa managed to give them the slip, jump into an army car, and tried to run over another Israeli, the prosecution said.</p>
<p>They said Daqamsa had planned for years to kill Israelis and had volunteered extra guard duties on the day of the attack so he would have an opportunity to strike.</p>
<p>The prosecution also said Daqamsa planned to cross into Israeli-occupied West Bank in 1993 to attack Israeli patrols.</p>
<p>&quot;He decided against executing it because...sophisticated electronic equipment on the barbed wire in that area would have killed him before he implemented his plan,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>A team of 95 lawyers from Jordan and the Arab world have put their names to join an expanded defence counsel, said Jordanian lawyer Riyad Nawayseh.</p>
<p>The chief judge also postponed considering a request by the defence team to bar 11 Israeli witnesses from testifying.</p>
<p>The shooting, on Jordanian border land leased to Israel under a 1994 peace accord, rattled an already tense Middle East and highlighted deep unease in Jordan over the treaty. It also revived charges in Jordan that, by leasing the land to Israel, Jordan had surrendered territory to its former enemy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARJ AL-HAMAM, Jordan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
