<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="617773" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mich. needs more time to assess renaissance zones.</title>
<headline>Mich. needs more time to assess renaissance zones.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Michigan will need more time to judge the success of tax-free renaissance zones intended to spur economic development in isolated areas of the state, Standard &amp; Poor's said in its CreditWeek Municipal publication this week.</p>
<p>&quot;Although several projects have been proposed and development interest has increased in the months since the program was established, more time is required to judge the plan's success,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>Michigan established the program earlier this year at 11 sites statewide, including Detroit, Flint, Grand Rapids, Saginaw and Lansing, S&amp;P said. Properties and economic activity within the districts are exempt from state income, single business and property taxes, as well as local property, income and utility use taxes, S&amp;P noted.</p>
<p>Detroit officials have estimated that the 1,345-acre zone would general 14,000 new jobs and the Michigan Jobs Commission has reported a large number of inquiries about relocations and expansions in the last few months, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>In Grand Rapids, an investment group has announced a planned $5 million factory-to-office and retail space renovation, S&amp;P noted. A manufacturer currently leasing a building in the Grand Rapids rennaisance zones also plans to buy it and invest $10 million for renovations, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>&quot;From a credit perspective, the impact on the municipalities that house these zones is unclear,&quot; S&amp;P said. &quot;Obviously, any development encouraged by the creation of the zones, which would not have occurred without zones themselves, would have a positive impact on the local economy.</p>
<p>&quot;It is unclear, however, whether the costs of providing increased services within a municipality's developing sector will be completely offset by the generation of indirect revenues,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>Stabilizing influences within certain areas could have a positive influence on surrounding areas, resulting in some tax revenue increases over the longterm, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>Michigan Gov. John Engler announced last week that private firms had invested $66.85 million in 17 projects since the program started, creating 938 to 1,139 new jobs.</p>
<p>((--David Bailey, 312-408-8647))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
