<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="617845" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SVCD-BC-UN-ISRAEL-RIGHTS.</title>
<headline>SVCD-BC-UN-ISRAEL-RIGHTS.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.N. committee will leave for the Middle East on Friday to investigate Israeli human rights practices affecting Palestinians and other Arabs in the occupied territories, a United Nations statement said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The three-member committee will visit Egypt, Jordan and Syria from May 30 to June 9, the statement added. The committee will hold a preparatory meeting in Geneva on Wednesday and Thursday.</p>
<p>The committee is headed by Sri Lanka's ambassador to the United Nations in New York, Herman Leonard de Silva. The other members are from Senegal and Malaysia.</p>
<p>It monitors Israeli practices in the occupied Golan Heights, the Gaza Strip and West Bank (including East Jerusalem) and regularly reports to the U.N. General Assembly.</p>
<p>&quot;Since its establishment in 1968, the special committee has repeatedly tried to obtain the cooperation of the government of Israel but has consistently been denied such cooperation and access to the occupied territories,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Lacking direct access, the committee bases its report on testimony gathered during visits to neighbouring states from people with first-hand and recent experience of the rights situation in the occupied territories. They also use articles in the Israeli press and in the Arab press in the territories.</p>
<p>&quot;During its stay in Jordan, the committee plans to interview persons from the West Bank at the King Hussein Bridge,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Another U.N. human rights organ, the U.N. Committee against Torture called this month on Israel to stop interrogating Palestinian detainees with methods including violent shaking which it said constituted torture and broke international law.</p>
<p>Its 10 independent experts also expressed concern that a decision by the Israeli Supreme Court last November had the</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SYRIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
