<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61793" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian OLOs end volatile day little changed.</title>
<headline>Belgian OLOs end volatile day little changed.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian 10-year bonds ended unchanged after an active day in the OLO market which saw the long end of the yield curve first well bid then later in the day well offered, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been up and down all day,&quot; said one dealer, adding there were curently two trains of thought dividing the market.</p>
<p>Some believed there was still value in Europe compared to Japan and U.S.. But others were concerned that the yield gap between Bunds and U.S. Treasuries was growing too wide for comfort. T-bonds have been weakened by worries the Federal Reserve will raise its Fed funds rate.  </p>
<p>The Fed's policy-making FOMC meets next week.</p>
<p>Treasuries managed to recover by Wednesday afternoon in Europe, after news the U.S. trade gap widened to $11.68 billion lead to expectations economists may revise downwards slightly their third quarter GDP estimates.</p>
<p>The 2006 OLO closed yielding 6.38 percent, unchanged from the previous day's finish, its premium over Bunds narrowing one basis point to 22 bp. The spread had widened to 23 bp on Tuesday, under pressure from an exchange auction, and is seen edging out two or three basis points again at the prospect of next Monday's monthly linear bond auction.  </p>
<p>Interest in the new March 2007 OLO was sustained for the second day after the Treasury announced late on Monday the new line would be offered at next week's auction.</p>
<p>Trading in the grey market on a &quot;when issued&quot; basis, the March 2007 OLO was yielding around five basis points over the current 10-year benchmark which it is expected to replace in January. &quot;Some people are buying it for OLO nines (due October 2007), but others are shorting it because they think it is too expensive,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>September bond futures closed just two bp higher at 118.46, after touching a fresh contract high of 118.60  </p>
<p>In the money markets, three-month T-bills closed yielding 3.03/06 percent, slightly less than the previous close of 3.06/07 percent.</p>
<p>One week market repo rates held steady at 3.01/03 percent, close to the Belgian National Bank's central rate - currently 3.00 percent - which they anticipate.</p>
<p>The franc weakened fractionally to the mark, quoting at 20.5835/45 compared to 20.5810/30 late Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Lorrayne Smith, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6812, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
