<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="617903" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: EU favours modest dairy reform not revolution.</title>
<headline>EU favours modest dairy reform not revolution.</headline>
<byline>David Evans</byline>
<dateline>MIDDELBURG, Netherlands 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union farm ministers wrapped up three days of informal talks on Tuesday, favouring fine-tuning its complex system of milk quotas rather than a radical shake-up of the 13-year-old regime.</p>
<p>&quot;You should not be talking about a radical reform but more of an evolution,&quot; Dutch Farm Minister Jozias van Aartsen told a news conference in the southern Dutch town of Middelburg.</p>
<p>The sentiment was re-inforced by Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler who called for &quot;reform not revolution&quot; of the sector that involves one million dairy farmers and sets national quotas on milk production and subsidised exports to world markets.</p>
<p>Fischler stressed that discussions had only just begun and promised proposals in the autumn when the Commission will also detail its more radical plans for the beef and cereals sectors.</p>
<p>But the negotiations will not be plain sailing.</p>
<p>A majority of countries, led by Germany, wants to extend the milk quota system when it expires at the end of March 2000. They say it has stabilised prices at profitable levels and helped to keep thousands of small farmers in poor areas in business.</p>
<p>&quot;I repeated that we don't want any change in quotas,&quot; German Farm Minister Jochen Borschert said as he left the talks.</p>
<p>But World Trade Organisation talks scheduled for 1999 and the planned expansion of the EU eastwards are two looming factors that have heightened the pressure for change.</p>
<p>&quot;Where today there is high price support, there is a risk that this policy will not suit the situation in these (new member) countries,&quot; Fischler said in a speech to ministers.</p>
<p>The EU is the largest milk producer in the world with around 20 percent of the global market. But this share is coming under threat from lower cost producers in Australia and New Zealand.</p>
<p>Denmark wants reforms to be able to compete for key Asian markets and sees the need for measures sooner rather than later.</p>
<p>Britain is known to favour a more free-market approach and is demanding the gradual abolition of the milk quota system.</p>
<p>&quot;We got our message across but that's not to say we are going to win the final act,&quot; British Farm Minister Jack Cunningham told Reuters, adding that Denmark, Sweden and Italy supported the British position.</p>
<p>Italy, along with  Spain and Greece want to be allowed to produce more milk to satisfy domestic demand.</p>
<p>Italy has demanded a 600,000 tonnes increase in its quota to 10.5 million tonnes in order to pacify angry farmers who blocked roads across the country earlier this year.</p>
<p>Spain, which only covers 75 percent of domestic milk demand, had been heavily penalised for exceeding its quota.</p>
<p>The French floated a dual quota system, under which internal prices are supported but exports are subsidy-free. French Farm Minister Philippe Vasseur said the proposal had received support from Denmark and Luxembourg.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIDDELBURG, Netherlands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
