<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="617911" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: FOCUS-Philips sells Bang &amp; Olufsen stake.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Philips sells Bang &amp; Olufsen stake.</headline>
<byline>Keiron Henderson</byline>
<dateline>EINDHOVEN, Netherlands 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philips Electronics NV said on Tuesday it had agreed to sell its 25 percent stake in Denmark's Bang &amp; Olufsen A/S to Bang &amp; Olufsen Holding for about 160 million guilders ($84 million).</p>
<p>A Philips spokesman said it had bought its stake in the chic Danish audio and television maker in 1990 for about 100 million guilders as part of a deal to cement a cooperation pact.</p>
<p>&quot;When we took the 25 percent shareholding in 1990 it was attached to an agreement to work closely together. Now seven years later the companies are satisfied with this cooperation,&quot; said Philips spokesman Ben Geerts.</p>
<p>&quot;The contract will be extended for another five years and Philips maintains the status of preferred supplier. We feel and Bang &amp; Olufsen feels that it's not necessary per se to maintain the participation because B&amp;O's financial situation has improved,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Philips and B&amp;O said that a substantial economic recovery in recent years had enabled B&amp;O to buy back the stake and become the sole shareholder in its audio and video subsidiary.</p>
<p>&quot;We have substantial excess cash and it is in the interest of both the group and its shareholders to use part of that liquidity for this purpose, as long as this does not affect our successful cooperation with Philips,&quot; B&amp;O chairman Anders Knutsen said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>The Dutch company said that B&amp;O had steadily increased its purchase of components from Philips since the agreement started in 1990 and added the cooperation had functioned satisfactorily for both parties.</p>
<p>&quot;Our investment has made a significant contribution to the further development of the cooperation between the two companies, a cooperation which both parties firmly believe should continue,&quot; chairman Doug Dunn of Philips' Sound and Vision division said in the statement.</p>
<p>Bang &amp; Olufsen makes audio equipment for the exclusive luxury goods market, as well as making telephones and medical equipment. In January it reported half year pre-tax and minorities profits of 174 million crowns ($27.6 million) and forecast a 20 percent rise in 1996/97 full year results.</p>
<p>Analysts welcomed the deal as fitting in with Philips' strategy of streamlining the organisation and wringing cash flow from the business, as well as promoting the Philips brand.</p>
<p>&quot;For Philips I think it is more important to concentrate on its own brand name than on the brand names of other companies that have in the past have contributed,&quot; said Peter Wortel of Delta Lloyd Bank.</p>
<p>Arjen Dibbets of MeesPierson said it was clear that the holding was not core to Philips' activities.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been a minority for so long and it wasn't even (a shareholding) in the B&amp;O holding company. Given the strategic reorganisation at Philips and the shift towards high growth consumer markets...it's not really a surprise. It was a minority stake that was ready for sale,&quot; said Dibbets.</p>
<p>Steven Vrolijk of ING Barings said the move was a sensible way to generate cash from a minority shareholding. &quot;The consumer electronics business is difficult enough as it is, it's just something which is taking up cash from Philips and not making any money, by selling it they can make some money,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Philips shares were down 0.50 guilders to 108.60 guilders following the news in a mostly lower Amsterdam share market.</p>
<p>-- Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EINDHOVEN, Netherlands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
