<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="617991" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Barry Callebaut eyes new investment in Ivory Coast.</title>
<headline>Barry Callebaut eyes new investment in Ivory Coast.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Barry Callebaut AG said on Tuesday it planned to increase its cocoa processing capacity in the Ivory Coast.</p>
<p>&quot;We are planning to invest in the Ivory Coast. We believe there is still room to increase capacity,&quot; board vice chairman Charles Gebhard told a news conference.</p>
<p>A group of company officials was travelling to the Ivory Coast to discuss the plan with local authorities, he added.</p>
<p>Barry Callebaut, formed by the merger of France's Cacao Barry and Swiss Callebaut AG, currently processes some 90,000 tonnes of cocoa beans in its three Ivorian plants.  </p>
<p>It processes between 200,000 and 250,000 tonnes of cocoa beans worldwide and should reach a processing capacity of 300,000 tonnes this year, or 12 percent of world capacity.</p>
<p>Asked if the group planned to increase the capacity of existing plants or build a new factory in the Ivory Coast, Gebhard said, &quot;We have not decided yet. It is possible that we will build a new site next to our existing site in Abidjan.&quot;</p>
<p>But he did not say what capacity the group had in mind.</p>
<p>Barry Callebaut has 19 production sites around the world. It will open a new production unit in Singapore in June with an initial capacity of 8,000 tonnes of chocolate. Capacity may later be raised to 20,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>--Paris newsroom +331 4221 5432</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100144">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
