<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="617928" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy unions baulk at welfare cuts - union official.</title>
<headline>Italy unions baulk at welfare cuts - union official.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's labour movement would have trouble accepting cuts of eight to nine trillion lire in pensions and health spending in 1998 as reported in Italian newspapers, a trade union official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Gugliemo Epifani, number two at the CGIL trade union confederation, said the government should not reduce the ratio of welfare spending to gross domestic product between now and the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;I would find the figure of eight to nine trillion lire a bit high. It has only been reported in the press but if these figures are true it would be hard for the trade unions to agree to them and support them,&quot; he said at a conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We can make sacrifices but there is a limit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The government is due to meet trade union leaders and representatives of industrial employers on Thursday to discuss its three-year economic plan, which is expected to outline the government's tax and spending plans for 1998.</p>
<p>Prime minister Romano Prodi's centre-left government wants to approve the plan at a cabinet meeting on Friday.</p>
<p>Fausto Bertinotti, leader of the hard-left Communist Refoundation party on which the government relies for support in the lower house of parliament, said a meeting of the government's political allies on Monday night had failed to resolve differences over the three year plan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
