<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61797" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Negative campaigning sweeps Greece's close election.</title>
<headline>Negative campaigning sweeps Greece's close election.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Weeks</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greece's socialist Prime Minister Costas Simitis, in a tough election race, has given up on a &quot;keep it clean&quot; pledge and has launched a string of hostile television  advertisements in the last week of the campaign.</p>
<p>Simitis, 60, who called elections a year early confident of an easy win, is now struggling in a neck-and-neck race and has switched tactics to breathe life into his lacklustre campaign.</p>
<p>His new ads, launched at the start of the week, try to show conservative opposition leader Miltiades Evert as a buffoon in foreign policy, confusing world leaders' names, and repeating the same promises in campaigns over the past 10 years.</p>
<p>Along with these hostile ads, Simitis has started to put some political bite in his usually weary academic speeches and even to move his arms a bit while delivering them.</p>
<p>For weeks he has avoided nitty-gritty campaign promises and focused instead on vaguer and more painful notions such as the need for Greece to sacrifice more to become a normal EU member.</p>
<p>But with no big change in poll numbers, he held a jubilant mass rally in the agricultural heartland of Thessaly this week and pledged cotton price supports for the region's disgruntled farmers.</p>
<p>He has also trained his fire on smaller left-wing parties, dismissing them as fringe groups, refusing to debate with their leaders and warning their voters that their wasted ballots were strengthening the right.</p>
<p>The switch in tactics has come in the closing days of the campaign, with official polls showing Simitis's gaining a bit but still in an election which is too close to call.</p>
<p>The rating of Simitis and Evert is so low that the election may be decided by which one loses more votes to smaller parties, with apathy at record levels and more than 50 percent of voters saying they have little interest in the outcome.</p>
<p>From the outset for Sunday's vote, Simitis had called for a low-key campaign, ordering socialists to abandon fireworks, mass rallies and wild populist harangues that have been standard fare for years.</p>
<p>&quot;We say no to cock-fights, to false promises, to meaningless rallies and plastic flags. We are against negative propaganda and blows below the belt,&quot; Simitis said at the start.</p>
<p>But he was quickly criticised for a lack of passion and an apparently smug belief he could win without running a vigorous, populist campaign.</p>
<p>His deadpan style, delivered in flat tones and with fingers neatly intertwined on the podium, has been in dramatic contrast to socialist premier Andreas Papandreou, who died in June.</p>
<p>Papandreou was renowned for his ardant populism, flights of oratorical fancy and ability to sweet talk just about everybody in the course of a single speech.</p>
<p>&quot;Papandreou had a wonderful gift of spreading his message to many segments of the population at the same time: the poor, the rich, the working class, middle class, the countryside and the city,&quot; said polling expert Christina Badouna.</p>
<p>His socialist faithful expected wild rallies with flares, banners, blasting horns and thousands of people streaming in to town squares to applaud a Papandreou harangue against &quot;foreign centres of intrigue&quot;.</p>
<p>But he often mixed foreign policy with domestic populism and left Greece isolated from EU partners and weakened where its main interests, such as relations with Turkey, were concerned.</p>
<p>Simitis clearly believed his dispassionate approach would help Greece shed its Balkan image and move the country towards a more modern, EU approach to campaigning.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
