<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="618069" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: NATO, RUSSIA SIGN HISTORIC SECURITY PACT.</title>
<headline>NATO, RUSSIA SIGN HISTORIC SECURITY PACT.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>NATO leaders and Russian President Boris Yeltsin signed an historic treaty on Tuesday consigning the Cold War to history and opening up the prospect of uniting Europe in peace after more than half a century of division.</p>
<p>&quot;The Paris accord does not shift the divisions created in Yalta. It does away with them once and for all,&quot; French President Jacques Chirac told a Paris summit held to sign the accord.</p>
<p>Supported strongly by the United States, NATO's most powerful member, the West says the accord formally ends the post-World War Two carve-up of Europe at the 1945 Yalta summit when eastern Europe was left in Josef Stalin's &quot;zone of influence&quot;.</p>
<p>The Founding Act on Mutual Relations is designed to bind Russia into efforts to create a new European security order and ease tensions over the 16-nation alliance's eastward expansion by admitting some of Moscow's former communist allies.</p>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin hailed the new security accord between Russia and NATO on Tuesday, but criticised the alliance's expansion plans just minutes before signing it.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia has a negative view of NATO's expansion plans, &quot; Yeltsin said in his speech, but in line with the celebratory mood of the summit kept the criticism to a minimum, adding:</p>
<p>&quot;This is an historic agreement and our mutual achievement.&quot;</p>
<p>In a surprise gesture, Yeltsin told the assembled leaders that Russia would disarm all missiles targeted on NATO states.</p>
<p>NATO Secretary-General Javier Solana, who negotiated the &quot;Founding Act&quot; in six tough sessions with Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov, hailed Yeltsin's vision in agreeing the pact.</p>
<p>&quot;The vision and leadership of President Yeltsin have been truly instrumental to the success of this process,&quot; he told the gathering.</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton, a strong advocate of enlargement, arrived in Paris early on Tuesday for the signing ceremony.</p>
<p>He and the other leaders of the West's military shield say the deal will allow the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation to take in new members from former communist Europe at a special summit in Madrid in July.</p>
<p>Czech-born U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright, herself a child of a divided Europe, said on Monday the accord was &quot;truly historic&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We will all be able to participate in putting a divided Europe back together,&quot; she told reporters after meeting French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
