<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="618063" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Pain follows euphoria for companies in East Europe.</title>
<headline>Pain follows euphoria for companies in East Europe.</headline>
<byline>Kathleen Callo</byline>
<text>
<p>LONDON, May 27 (Reuter)  The collapse of communism in Central and Eastern Europe sent Western-based multinationals stampeding into the region, but experts say many have been burned by Europe's emerging consumer markets.</p>
<p>Multinationals expected the rise of democracy in the early 1990s to bring them a business bonanza from a region long starved of international-quality consumer goods.</p>
<p>Companies manufacturing everything from toothpaste to cars to music CDs rushed into Poland, Hungary, the Czech Republic and neighbouring countries in hopes of boosting sales.</p>
<p>But a lot has changed in the last seven or eight years. Some companies that rushed into the region have made money, while others have found doing business in Central and Eastern Europe a sobering if not painful experience.</p>
<p>Its easy to understand the initial hysteria. Companies making consumer-related goods like breakfast cereal or cosmetics or beer have been struggling for years to cope with little or no growth in their traditional markets in the United States and Western Europe.</p>
<p>Increasingly tough competition means there are too many companies fighting for the attention of too few shoppers.</p>
<p>Some companies, like tobacco manufacturers, are caught in a worse situation, with traditional markets in the West shrinking rapidly.</p>
<p>For many consumer-related multinationals, the only way forward is to find new markets.</p>
<p>There was a rush into the market by European and U.S. multinationals. There was a new dawn in the consumer age in Eastern Europe, says Chris Gentle, from the Henley Centre research group in London.</p>
<p>There was pent-up demand and consumers in countries like Poland, the Czech Republic, Slovakia and Hungary were not very sophisticated. They werent used to choice. Anything that was Western was 'good Gentle, a senior consultant at Henley, told Reuters.</p>
<p>That's what Gentle describes as &quot;Phase One&quot; of the rush into Central and Eastern Europe - a euphoric period from 1989 to 1991. But reality set in with &quot;Phase Two&quot; - from 1993 to 1996 - when many companies learned painful lessons.</p>
<p>One problem was that, with an economic squeeze in countries like Hungary or Poland, many consumers couldn't afford internationally-branded products.</p>
<p>Piracy made it tough for companies in the music industry and other sectors to gain market share, while delapidated infrastructure, unstable currencies and volatile tariff barriers also dampened foreign investors' enthusiasm.</p>
<p>Countries like Russia and Ukraine offer tantalisingly big populations for Western multinationals, but many companies have also found themselves blocked by mafia that control local distribution of consumer goods.</p>
<p>Finally, there's growing local competition. Manufacturers in Central and Eastern Europe have woken up to the new business opportunities and are snatching customers away from big foreign companies by improving quality and offering less expensive products.</p>
<p>But its not all doom and gloom. Gentle from the Henley Centre, which is owned by WPP Group Plc, the worlds biggest advertising and marketing services group, says Phase 3 in Central and Eastern Europe holds new promise for the Western-based multinationals that have hung on.</p>
<p>He says a vibrant labour market of people under 30 years old, some of whom work for foreign companies and who represent the regions modern consumer, has grown in the last couple of years. Multinationals are busy wooing these new consumers.</p>
<p>For some companies a determined, yet gradual entry into Central and Eastern Europe has reaped benefits.</p>
<p>The worlds five biggest music companies - BMG, EMI, Polygram, Sony and Warner - have moved swiftly into the region and established full local affiliates in the Czech Republic and Hungary.</p>
<p>Market Tracking International Ltd (MTI), a London-based market consultancy group, says the regions biggest music markets - in Russia, Poland, the Czech Republic, Hungary, Lithuania, Latvia, Romania, Slovenia, the Slovak Republic and Bulgaria - account for a mere 1.5 percent of the global market, but theyre growing fast.</p>
<p>The region is becoming increasingly important, with its rapidly growing music sector making up for stagnant sales in Western Europe, says a report MTI will publish in a few weeks about the music industry in Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Chris Groner, who wrote the report, told Reuters none of the big music companies lost much money in the region because they built up local presence step by step in a way that allowed them to fix mistakes along the way.</p>
<p>Piracy has hurt the ability of Western music groups to build up market share rapidly, but Groner said the move into Eastern Europe was a clear necessity.</p>
<p>For the music industry, they have to be there. Sales in Western Europe have been stagnant for several years, so they have to move to emerging marketsCompanies have got to experiment.</p>
<p>For the tobacco industry, hounded by court cases and growing restrictions on marketing in the West, the emerging markets of Central and Eastern Europe offer a win-win situation.</p>
<p>Companies like B.A.T, Phillip Morris, RJ Reynolds, Germany's Reemtsma, Rothmans International and Seita have all made significant investments in Central and Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Its worked quite well for the tobacco industry and still is...They (big Western tobacco companies) have had and they will have a very significant impact on cigarette consumption there, says Don Hedley, a director of MTI.</p>
<p>Central and Eastern Europe represent the worlds second largest cigarette consumption region according to volume, after the Asia-Pacific region, MTI says in a different report.</p>
<p>The report, called World Tobacco File: Emerging Markets in Central and Eastern Europe 1997, says the region represents over 13 percent of the world market for white stick cigarettes, with more than 690 billion cigarettes sold there each year.</p>
<p>Hedley said big Western tobacco companies initially entered the region by promoting international brands, but later shifted to an emphasis on local brands.</p>
<p>In some markets, there was a backlash against foreign brands, so they bought up local brands. Thats enabled the multinationals to increase the share, he told Reuters.</p>
<p>As Western consumer-related companies rushed into Central and Eastern Europe, the global advertising agencies that they hire to promote their brands and market their goods followed closely behind.</p>
<p>Local newspapers and trade magazines in Poland, Hungary, the Czech Republic and Bulgaria, for instance, carry articles about virtually all the global ad agency networks, including Bates, Saatchi &amp; Saatchi, BBDO, Euro RSCG, Grey, McCann Erickson, Ammirati Puris Lintas, Young &amp; Rubicam, Publicis and FCB.</p>
<p>Willott Kingston Smith, an accountancy firm specialising in communications companies, says several global ad agency networks and public relations firms put lots of money into Central and Eastern Europe, but some have found it a tough market.</p>
<p>There was quite a considerable commitment by ad agencies, but there is a lingering concern whether it really is going to work that quickly in the region, he says. I dont expect them (global agency networks) to do a wholesale retreat, but I think some went in too quickly.</p>
<p>Willott says some clients dragged their ad agencies into Central and Eastern Europe too soon.</p>
<p>There was a very strong encouragement brought to bear by clients on their ad agencies to get there and deliver.</p>
<p>He says global agencies have to maintain at least a foothold in Eastern European markets that could boom later on. Whether it's about advertising or selling cars or marketing toothpaste, experts say the winners will be companies who adopt a patient, gradual approach.</p>
<p>Gentle at the Henley Centre says, Its about long-term gain. There are opportunities. Its no use just jumping into Eastern Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>-- London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2792 kat.callo@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
