<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="618039" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Balladur, Seguin jockey to succeed France's Juppe.</title>
<headline>Balladur, Seguin jockey to succeed France's Juppe.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Intense jockeying broke out on the French right on Tuesday in a race to succeed humiliated Prime Minister Alain Juppe as President Jacques Chirac prepared a plan to lure back angry voters in Sunday's parliamentary runoff vote.</p>
<p>Chirac was looking at Philippe Seguin, popular speaker of the outgoing National Assembly, and Edouard Balladur, an urbane former premier, as candidates to succeed Juppe if the right won the runoff, the daily Le Monde said in an unsourced report.</p>
<p>It was also possible that Chirac could choose to appoint a premier from the business sector, the newspaper said. Should the left claim victory on Sunday, however, Chirac would have to name -- and share power with -- Socialist leader Lionel Jospin.</p>
<p>Juppe announced on Monday that he would step down as premier, taking the blame for the ruling coalition's disastrous showing in Sunday's first round of the snap assembly election in which it was outscored by the combined left.</p>
<p>Juppe, stunned by the left-wing upset, said his departure would give Chirac new last-minute arguments to convince voters to return the conservatives to power.</p>
<p>The left's surprise first-round victory unsettled bond markets across Europe due to worries over the future of European monetary union, although Socialist former European Commission chief Jacques Delors said the left would make EMU its priority.</p>
<p>French shares traded higher, however, after Monday's sharp declines. In mid afternoon the blue-chip CAC 40 index was up 0.55 percent at 2,669.40.</p>
<p>Chirac, described by Juppe as &quot;the only man able to embody renewal&quot;, was scheduled to deliver a live television address at eight p.m. (1800 GMT) on Tuesday, his third intervention in the campaign to try to save his majority.</p>
<p>He was not expected to divulge his choice for next prime minister but rather to outline new priorities should the government win a new lease on life.</p>
<p>Le Monde said he would emphasise the need for economic growth through a sharp reduction in payroll taxes, and for less economic regulation though with no weakening of the social safety net -- the same priorities he has espoused throughout the long campaign.</p>
<p>Analysts said only a dramatic gesture could now succeed in swaying enough votes to his side to avert a leftist triumph.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything will depend on this evening,&quot; said one analyst, who said Chirac must choose between the free-market liberalism embodied by sacked finance minister Alain Madelin and the populism embodied by Seguin, &quot;now that it is clear that a cautious middle path does not work&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;In 24 hours, the president must invent another policy. Mission impossible,&quot; the centre-left daily Liberation wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;The sacrifice of Alain Juppe comes too late, as the symbol of an enormous mess,&quot; Liberation editorialist Serge July wrote.</p>
<p>Chirac could also lay his own job on the line, threatening to resign if voters disavow him, as his mentor, president Charles de Gaulle, did regularly during his time in office.</p>
<p>However, the last time de Gaulle tried the ploy was in 1969, in a referendum over decentralisation. He lost and left office the next morning.</p>
<p>Balladur affirmed his availability for Juppe's job with a lengthy interview in Le Monde in which he said France had to invent its own style of economic liberalism rather than turn to &quot;Anglo-Saxon models&quot;.</p>
<p>He said voters had shown in the first-round ballot that they wanted a more dynamic society in order to bring down France's record 12.8 percent unemployment but that they were also attached to a strong French identity.</p>
<p>Seguin, a jovial and rotund politician who led the unsuccessful campaign against ratification of the Maastricht treaty on greater European integration in a 1992 referendum, has consistently topped the list of favourite potential rightist prime ministers in voter surveys.</p>
<p>Seguin, holed up at his home in the eastern city of Epinal, told France 2 television: &quot;Whether it's a big victory or a small victory, or no victory at all, it will be very difficult for whoever heads the government.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
