<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="618193" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Ford Australia to review investment if tariffs cut.</title>
<headline>Ford Australia to review investment if tariffs cut.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ford Motor Co's Australian subsidiary said on Tuesday it would review its investment plans in Australia if a government industry review recommended that car import tariffs be cut below their current 15 percent level.</p>
<p>&quot;All we have said so far is we would have to look at our investment plans if the tariff goes below 15 percent,&quot; Ford Australia's managing director David Morgan said in a speech.</p>
<p>Morgan said Australia's vehicle industry needed to achieve a pause in the process of reducing tariffs and needed the continuation of the export facilitation scheme to provide the critical mass the industry required to survive.</p>
<p>The car industry is lobbying against a draft proposal by the government's Productivity Commission to lower tariffs to five percent by 2004. Tariffs are scheduled already to fall from the current 22.5 percent to 15 percent by 2000.</p>
<p>Japanese car makers Mitsubishi Motors Australia and Toyota Motor Corp Australia both recently reported losses for their Australian operations in 1996.</p>
<p>Morgan expressed concern about the local car industry's profitability and declining volume base, saying foreign-made vehicles were &quot;coming over the wharves in frightening numbers&quot;.</p>
<p>Growth in new vehicle demand in Australia had been flat for nearly 20 years, yet imports had made major gains, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Six years ago imported cars accounted for barely 20 percent of new car sales. For the first quarter of this year, that figure had soared to a massive 55 percent,&quot; Morgan said.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact, more (are imported) every week than Korea imports in a year based on last year's figures,&quot; he added, in a reference to surging imports of South Korean makes such as Hyundai, Daewoo and Kia.</p>
<p>In Canberra, Prime Minister John Howard told parliament that he expected the final report of the Productivity Commission on the motor industry would be received by the government quite soon but he did not know the exact day.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
