<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="618154" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian PM apology to Aborigines &quot;not enough&quot;.</title>
<headline>Australian PM apology to Aborigines &quot;not enough&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Terry Friel</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard's apology to tens of thousands of Aborigines taken from their families was welcomed on Tuesday as a start to healing wounds, but criticised for not going far enough.</p>
<p>Criticism of Howard's move came as race row politician Pauline Hanson and Governor-General Sir William Deane, the representative of Britain's Queen Elizabeth, also apologised for past injustices to native Australians.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to say how profoundly sorry I personally am that things like that were ever done,&quot; Deane told a reconciliation convention in Melbourne, receiving a standing ovation.</p>
<p>The injustices that spawned the Aboriginal civil rights movement 30 years ago remained today, he added.</p>
<p>Hanson, accused of racism over her criticism of Aboriginal welfare, also apologised for wrongs suffered by Aborigines and called for unity among all Australians.</p>
<p>&quot;Some terrible things were done in the past and I, like many Australians am sorry for the fact that they occurred,&quot; Hanson told parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;This does not mean, however, that I am in some way responsible for what has happened and I resent being made to feel guilty for something I did not do,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>As the apologies continued, politicians and newspapers said Howard must make a full apology, personally and on behalf of all Australians, if Aborigines and white Australians were to reconcile their differences.</p>
<p>The vice-chairman of South Africa's Truth and Reconciliation Commission, Alex Boraine, said Howard &quot;has balls but he hasn't got a hell of a lot of heart&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not going to speculate about the size of other parts of his anatomy, but his heart is the size of a split pea,&quot; added Gareth Evans, deputy leader of the Labor opposition.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a lot for us to be ashamed of, we have to be sorry about what happened and we have to say so.&quot;</p>
<p>Howard made an unexpected personal apology on Monday to the tens of thousands of Aborigines who were taken from their families between the 1880s and 1960s under welfare laws now condemned as racist.</p>
<p>But he stopped short of the official apology urged by the Human Rights Commission in a landmark report on the &quot;Stolen Generation&quot; Aborigines released on Monday.</p>
<p>The Sydney Morning Herald newspaper said the Australian authorities' treatment of Aborigines ranked with Japanese atrocities during World War Two and required a national apology.</p>
<p>&quot;Any attempt to insist that Australian behaviour towards Aborigines is not in the same category as Japanese behaviour towards Australian prisoners of war simply does not withstand scrutiny,&quot; its editorial said.</p>
<p>A poll in the same newspaper said 65 percent of Australians supported the report's recommendation that the government should officially apologise to the &quot;stolen generation&quot; of Aborigines.</p>
<p>Aboriginal and Torres Strait Island Commission chief Gatjil Djerrkura urged all governments, state, territory and national, to apologise.</p>
<p>&quot;By expressing his personal sorrow for the hurt suffered by the indigenous families separated by the policies of past governments, the prime minister made an important first step in acknowledging the seriousness of the issues,&quot; Djerrkura said.</p>
<p>Boraine welcomed Howard's words but said more was needed.</p>
<p>&quot;It was tragic for me that he wasn't able to take the next step because he is, after all, the prime minister, he does wield considerable power,&quot; Boraine said in a radio interview.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
