<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="61863" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: New crop set to dampen India rice export prices.</title>
<headline>New crop set to dampen India rice export prices.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian rice export prices are expected to fall by an average of $20-25 a tonne with the harvest of the new crop in early October, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>This would make Indian higher grade rice competitive.</p>
<p>But the 25 percent broken variety, in demand in African countries, would still be higher than similar varieties grown in Vietnam and Thailand, they said.</p>
<p>India's five percent broken long grain non-Basmati rice was currently quoted at $310 per tonne FOB, 10 percent at $300, 15 percent at $280 and 25 percent at $250.</p>
<p>&quot;Export prices will fall by around $20-25 when the new crop comes in,&quot; said Ravi Kumar of Space Group, a leading foodgrains exporter. &quot;Exports will take place but not to last year's levels.&quot;</p>
<p>He said major exporters like Vietnam and Thailand had good crops this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore the exports this year will be split between India, Thailand and Vietnam,&quot; Kumar said.</p>
<p>India exported a record five million tonnes of rice in the year that ended in March. It was the world's largest exporter of rice after Thailand.</p>
<p>Analysts expected India to export a maximum of three million tonnes in 1996/97 due to a fall in world demand and uncompetitive Indian export prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The export demand this year is mainly for higher grades of rice,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>He said the state-run Food Corporation of India (FCI), the largest foodgrains trading agency, dealt with only the lower grades of rice, demand for which was sluggish.</p>
<p>Vietnam and Thailand lower grades were more competitive than Indian, he said.</p>
<p>He said demand for the upper grades of five percent, 10 percent and 15 percent broken was mainly from the Phillipines, Malaysia and some east European countries.</p>
<p>--Sambit Mohanty, New Delhi newsroom +91 11 301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
