<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="618603" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: LG Semicon to raise non-memory sales.</title>
<headline>LG Semicon to raise non-memory sales.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>LG Semicon Co, a unit of South Korea's LG Group, said on Tuesday it planned to raise its non-memory chip sales in the domestic market to 50 percent of its total local sales by the year 2000 from 32 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>LG Semicon's domestic semiconductor sales totalled 220 billion won in 1996, with 70 billion won coming from non-memory chips, the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>The company said its domestic semiconductor sales would reach one trillion won in the year 2000, about 10 percent of its total target sales, including exports.  </p>
<p>In 1996, LG Semicon's semiconductor sales totalled 2.1 trillion won, of which 90 percent came from exports.</p>
<p>To strengthen the non-memory sector, LG Semicon signed strategic alliances with seven specialist firms in the fields of application specific integrated circuits (ASIC) and micro components, the company said.</p>
<p>The ASIC specialist companies include Core System Co, Yujin Technology and MITECH in micro control unit and I &amp; C Technology and Simon Co, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
