<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="618755" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Airbus unlikely to reconsider business with Rolls.</title>
<headline>Airbus unlikely to reconsider business with Rolls.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Airbus Industrie is not likely to reconsider its business dealings with Rolls-Royce Plc despite recent problems with Rolls-Royce jet engines on Airbus aircraft, said Adam Brown, an Airbus vice president in charge of market forecasts. </p>
<p>Hong Kong's two airlines suspended a total of 15 Airbus Industrie A330-300 aircraft on Saturday, leading to the cancellation of 23 flights, due to concerns about the reliability of their Rolls-Royce Trent 700 engines.</p>
<p>A Hong Kong Dragon Airlines Ltd A330 made an emergency landing on Friday on one of its two engines at Subic Bay in the Philippines after developing engine trouble.</p>
<p>It was the latest in a series of single-engine landings by Dragonair and Cathay Pacific Airways Ltd Airbus A330-300 planes.</p>
<p>&quot;We're very sympathetic to the problem that Cathay Pacific had,&quot; Adams told a news conference on Tuesday.</p>
<p>He said Airbus offers a choice of jet engines from Rolls-Royce, General Electric and United Technologies Corp unit Pratt &amp; Whitney, and it is up to the individual airlines to select the engine they want.</p>
<p>Asked if Airbus would reconsider doing business with Rolls-Royce as a result of the two Hong Kong airlines' problems, Adams said that the possibility of such a reconsideration was slight.</p>
<p>He also stressed that Rolls-Royce, like Airbus, was a European company, and that political polarisation was a factor in the global airline and aircraft industries.</p>
<p>&quot;We must recognise the fact that Rolls-Royce is a European company,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
