<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="618979" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - May 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - May 27.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights of stories in the Danish press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>BERLINGSKE TIDENDE</p>
<p>--A.P. Moeller has taken over J.Lauritzen's stake in Danish Steelworks, Denmark's only steel producer, increasing its share in the company to over 25 percent. The company could now be eyeing a further 30 percent share which the state says it is willing to sell.</p>
<p>POLITIKEN</p>
<p>--Shareholders at SAS' annual general meeting on Monday were worried that the carrier might be unable to live up to its own forecast.</p>
<p>JYLLANDS-POSTEN</p>
<p>--The public sector budget will show a surplus in 1997 for the first time in 10 years.</p>
<p>--Danish holdings of foreign shares look set in 1997 to beat the 1996 record of 7.5 billion crowns. In the first quarter of 1997 they had already reached 4.1 billion crowns.</p>
<p>BORSEN</p>
<p>--Institutional investors allege that the East Asiatic Company broke Copenhagen Stock Exchange rules by not distributing its audit of a factory in Thailand through the bourse.</p>
<p>--Novo Nordisk is to begin insulin production in Russia, where Ferane will manufacture the substance under license.</p>
<p>--The tax ministry is preparing to double the allowance on shareholdings of married couples.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
