<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="619053" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore share index blips up at close, may slip.</title>
<headline>Singapore share index blips up at close, may slip.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore's benchmark Straits Times Industrials share index (STII) blipped up just before the close of business on Tuesday amid signs of concerted buying by a small number of investors.</p>
<p>Dealers said buying may have been linked to unofficial over-the-counter (OTC) options or to other derivatives based on the index, which can move dramatically on relatively low volumes because it is not weighted by market capitalisation.</p>
<p>&quot;If this buying is driven by derivatives, the index could easily slip back again tomorrow,&quot; said one local dealer.</p>
<p>The STII closed at 2,076.01, up 19.69 points.</p>
<p>Total market volume was a low 94.3 million shares -- around half an average day's activity -- with 209 falls and 122 gains.</p>
<p>Much of the day's volume was in a handful of Malaysian shares traded over-the-counter. The UOB OTC index, which tracks the sector, was down 8.91 points at 1,155.73.</p>
<p>Top of the volume was Malaysia's MBf Capital, which rose six cents to Singapore $2.99 on 7.7 million shares after rumours of merger talks with another financial group.</p>
<p>Communications firm Datacraft saw its shares rise seven percent, or 21 cents, to S$3.10 on rumours of a U.S. buy tip.</p>
<p>US$1 = S$1.43 REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
