<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="619260" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries boosted by technical buying at noon.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries boosted by technical buying at noon.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasury prices were mostly higher at midday, gaining ground as dealers and commercial buyers jumped on the back of a late-morning surge in the June bond contract, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's hard to tell whether it's just somebody getting long here or covering shorts. (It is) very technical in that 108-30 went and that triggered some stops,&quot; said Josh Stiles, a senior bond analyst at I.D.E.A. Inc.</p>
<p>But Treasuries languished for most of the morning after an early lift on the back of data on durable goods orders faded, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;There has been some buying off the low but with the data coming out somewhat stronger than expected, there is a little bit of concern the slowdown people were looking for may not materialize,&quot; said one trader at a primary dealer.</p>
<p>But, the dealer added, it is a little too early to cast a vote either way with respect to the future rate of growth.</p>
<p>Short-covering after the numbers boosted the back end, flattening the curve in the coupon sector, analysts said.</p>
<p>The 30-year bond was up 10/32 around midday, trading at 95-9/32. The yield eased back to 7.00 percent, from 7.04 percent earlier.  </p>
<p>The 10-year was also lifted 4/32, with market experts citing strong support from Middle East players. At noon the 10-year stood at 98-30/32, yielding 6.77 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The Middle East accounts were on a mission, they have a certain program and when the 10-year note sector gets to certain levels they buy it,&quot; said Roseanne Briggen, a bond analyst at MCM MoneyWatch.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the Commerce Department reported that durables rose 1.4 percent in April and March orders were revised upwards to show a 2.2 percent decline, from a 2.6 percent fall originally.  </p>
<p>The number was a tad stronger than the 1.3 percent which had been forecast. But analysts noted the data was not uniformly strong, citing a 4.5-percent rise in transportation equipment and a 28-percent surge in defense capital orders.</p>
<p>&quot;This report is peppered with all kinds of conflicting signs,&quot; said David Resler, chief economist at Nomura Securities International Inc. &quot;On the one hand, there is fairly discouraging news on the non-defense capital goods side, but the overall picture of orders looks pretty good.</p>
<p>The data certainly does not indicate the economy is growing out of control, he added.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, the two-year note was struggling just to tread water ahead of the Treasury's $16.5 billion auction on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The two-year was flat at 100-05/32, yielding 6.28 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no arbitrage bid for the two year note that I'm aware of, because neither twos nor fives have gotten hot in retail recently,&quot; Briggen said.</p>
<p>The Treasury is scheduled to sell $12 billion of new five-year paper on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Federal Reserve refrained from open market operations on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>The five-year note was up 2/32, also garnering support from talk of Middle East interest and rumored central bank demand. Around midday, it stood at 100-1/32, with a yield of 6.62 percent.</p>
<p>The bill market was firm, with the three-month and six-month each down three basis points, at 5.01 percent and 5.23 percent respectively.</p>
<p>((--Alden Bentley, 212 859 1667))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
