<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="619648" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Sun Resorts behind Mauritius stock index easing.</title>
<headline>Sun Resorts behind Mauritius stock index easing.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hotel-based blue chip Sun Resorts was largely behind the Stock Exchange of Mauritius SEMDEX index easing by 1.35 points to 379.60 on Wednesday, bourse officials said.</p>
<p>Volume rose to 8.82 million rupees on 321,144 shares from 4.75 million rupees on 166,234 shares on Monday.</p>
<p>Sun Resorts shed 70 cents to 48.80 rupees on 7,400 shares while New Mauritius Hotels gained 10 cents to 36.30 rupees on 1,770 shares and Grand Baie Hotel was unchanged at 47.20 rupees but not quoted.</p>
<p>Brokers said the SEMDEX would persist on a downward trend because of a lack of interest from local and foreign investors.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Vasant Bunwaree will present his maiden budget on June 9.</p>
<p>In the banking sector, Mauritius Commercial Bank was stable at 89.00 rupees on 48,227 shares and State Bank of Mauritius was unchanged to 11.40 rupees on 82,300 shares.</p>
<p>Commerce congolomerate Rogers was 1.50 rupee higher to 98.00 rupees on 480 shares and Ireland Blyth Ltd fell 10 cents to 15.50 rupees on 6,400 shares. Shell lost 10 cents to 20.50 rupees on 200 shares and Happy World Foods was unchanged at 14.80 rupees on 2,000 shares.</p>
<p>Sugar-based Mon Tresor Mon Desert climbed 50 cents to 39.90 rupees on 16,325 shares, Mount fell 10 cents to 22.90 rupees but was not quoted and Harel Freres remained to 57.00 rupees, also unquoted.</p>
<p>In the investment sector, Fincorp was stable at 70.00 rupees on 3,900 shares and Policy eased five cents to 4.20 rupees on 96,639 shares.</p>
<p>Industry stocks Gamma Civic fell 50 cents to 18.00 rupees on 5,000 shares, United Basalt Products lost 10 cents to 33.90 rupees on 4,075 shares and Mauritius Oil Refineries gained 10 cents to 11.60 rupees on 3,092 shares.</p>
<p>National carrier Air Mauritius lost 50 cents to 40.00 rupees on 1,750 shares.</p>
<p>--Clifford Vellien ++230 211-9555</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
