<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="619714" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary BUX share index drops on MOL, TVK losses.</title>
<headline>Hungary BUX share index drops on MOL, TVK losses.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian shares drifted slightly lower on Wednesday on profit-takings and mainly due to the losses of chemicals maker TVK and oil and gas company MOL, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;At the current price levels the bourse (Budapest Stock Exchange) seems to have reached a balance,&quot; said Peter Lencs of MKB Securities. &quot;Prices are likely to stagnate until news increases the appetite for buying.</p>
<p>According to preliminary figures, the BUX index closed down 0.21 percent or 12.46 points at 5,978.86 points.</p>
<p>Half of the 38 stocks which traded on Wednesday dropped. This dealers attributed to the slack interest of foreign investors.</p>
<p>Traders said that profit-taking came as a correction of a bull-run earlier this week, which raised the BUX to a new intra-day trading high of 6,012.20 points on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Some traders said the Czech government's fight for stabilising the crown made some investors, who are looking at the region, cautious, while other traders played down the significance of this impact.</p>
<p>The BUX index was pulled down mainly by MOL's and TVK's losses, which were slight, but both of these heavyweight stocks traded in high turnover.</p>
<p>MOL dropped 10 forints to finish at 3,380.</p>
<p>Traders said investors locked in profits following the domestic and international offerings of MOL earlier this month.</p>
<p>&quot;Many investors still have shares which were bought at a discount of some 10 percent,&quot; Lencs said.</p>
<p>New York Brokers Attila Gazdik said news about gas price rises expected for later this year would push MOL up, but some investors did not see the stock rising for the short term and they may have replaced their MOL shares with other stocks.</p>
<p>TVK closed at 2,695 forints, down 30. Traders attributed that to profit-takings following a sharp rise in the past few months.</p>
<p>Despite the price falls on the Hungarian bourse, the index changed little, mainly thanks to drug maker Richter, which closed at 15,280 forints, up 205, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Back in December, Richter stood at 8,0008 forints,&quot; Gazdik said. &quot;But the company is good, its results are good and it has outstanding prospects... Everybody recommends it to buy.&quot;</p>
<p>Some traders said the Hungarian market needed some good news to rise again, while others believed the BUX may firm already this week.</p>
<p>-- Sandor Peto, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
