<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="619948" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico Cetes rate ends down on stable peso.</title>
<headline>Mexico Cetes rate ends down on stable peso.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican overnight Cetes rates closed down 100 basis points on Wednesday to 17.50 percent from a sudden spike at the end of trade Tuesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said overnight rates had closed unchanged from their opening level after a session that was quiet due to a relatively stable peso in the wake of primary rate hikes.</p>
<p>&quot;It held very steady at 17.50 percent. The peso came under pressure at the beginning of the week as 28-day Cetes rates looked like falling,&quot; a fixed-income analyst said.  </p>
<p>Nonetheless, the analyst added, when primary rates increased across the board at Tuesday night's central bank auction, &quot;the exchange rate stabilized and demand for paper increased.&quot;</p>
<p>Bellwether 28-day Cetes rates increased by 24 basis points to 18.31 percent on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>Dealers said month-end demand for liquidity had yet to make an impact on the market, but could well do so at the end of the week. </p>
<p>Banco de Mexico did, however, find it necessary to offset a liquidity shortfall in the market and injected 363 million pesos through an overnight credit which it assigned at 19.30 percent. The central bank has mostly drained liquidity from the market so far this year.</p>
<p>Overnight rates on bank paper closed unchanged at 19 percent.</p>
<p>Liquidity of 3.297 billion pesos was due to return to the system from prior central bank participation.</p>
<p>((--Elena Vega, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9554))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
