<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="619957" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian presidential candidate targets impunity.</title>
<headline>Colombian presidential candidate targets impunity.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Interior Minister Horacio Serpa, who has resigned to run for president, on Wednesday described Colombia as a lawless land where virtually all crimes go unpunished.</p>
<p>Serpa, a former judge, told a news conference that Colombia -- which has Latin America's highest kidnapping and murder rates -- had grave problems with its judicial system.</p>
<p>If elected, he said, his administration would put a premimum on &quot;very important judicial activity&quot; aimed at ending &quot;the terrible rate of impunity in Colombia.&quot;</p>
<p>Serpa did not elaborate on his promise of a crackdown on crime. But he said &quot;99.5 percent&quot; of all the crimes currently committed in Colombia went unpunished. &quot;That's shameful and it's sad,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Police say they lack the resources and manpower to impose law-and-order on a country of nearly 40 million people torn by leftist guerrillas and criminal drug gangs.</p>
<p>Last year, authorities registered 26,642 murders, or an average of 73 per day. Colombia's military-run police force was just 92,000 strong, including cadets and civilian personnel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
