<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620032" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico's Cetes rates rise across the yield curve.</title>
<headline>Mexico's Cetes rates rise across the yield curve.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kozak</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's primary Cetes rates rose across the yield curve on Tuesday for the first time in two weeks on early jitters in the peso and rising U.S. long-bond yields.</p>
<p>The bellwether 28-day Cetes rate rose 24 basis points to 18.31 percent at Banco de Mexico's primary auction on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Analysts said they were not concerned about the slight increase in the Cetes yields, though.  </p>
<p>&quot;On the 28-day paper, we are not worried about it, since we believed that last week the rates were close to their short-term floor,&quot; said Santander economist Enrique Ramirez.</p>
<p>Analysts said the upcoming mid-term elections in Mexico on July 6 could be an additional factor adding pressure on rates.</p>
<p>In the secondary market on Tuesday, overnight Cetes rates rose a sharp 140 basis points to close at 18.50 percent.</p>
<p>Secondary rates came under pressure from an early weakness in the peso and the U.S. 30-year Treasury bond. That bond ended the day to yield 7.03 percent.  </p>
<p>The peso recovered later in the day to end firm, but the markets had already sent a signal to investors to push rates up slightly.</p>
<p>The increase in the 28-day Cetes rate was more or less in line with analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>A Reuters' survey of nine Cetes dealers found expectations of an increase of 12 basis points to 18.19 percent on the one-month paper, and small increases across the yield curve.</p>
<p>The range was unusually wide on the forecasts, however, ranging from a decline of 27 basis points to a rise of 50 basis points.  </p>
<p>A survey by MMS International also found a wide range of expectations, with the one-month paper coming in between 17.80 percent and 18.25 percent.</p>
<p>The one-month paper rates had fallen at the last two actions as the U.S. Federal Reserve kept its key federal funds rate unchanged.</p>
<p>Inflation is widely seen as coming in under one percent in May, after posting a 0.48 percent increase in the first two weeks of the month. And that may help rates to fall in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;The results suggest further declines in nominal Cetes rates in the weeks ahead as real rates remain a relatively high 7.0 percent,&quot; market analysis firm IDEA said in a recent report.</p>
<p>((--Mexico City newsroom +525 728 9559))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
