<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620169" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Wall Street high-tech jolt to Asia seen fleeting.</title>
<headline>Wall Street high-tech jolt to Asia seen fleeting.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Chen</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prices of Asian high-tech shares rose on Wednesday, tracking an overnight surge of electronic shares on Wall Street, but analysts said the jolt was unlikely to spur a longer-term rise.</p>
<p>If history is a guide, they said, Asia's key high-tech markets in Taiwan, South Korea and Japan likely would pay more heed to various local factors while also remaining hampered by a current slump in global computer memory chip prices.</p>
<p>Widespread gains by technology shares, including an all-time high for International Business Machines Corp and a surge by chip giant Intel Corp, pushed the Dow Jones industrial average to a record finish of 7,383.41 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The jump spurred correlative gains by major Asian firms.</p>
<p>South Korea's largest chipmaker, Samsung Electronics Co, rose 2,100 won ($2.35) to 63,500 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In Taiwan, the electronics sector rose 0.78 percent while the overall index lost 0.80 percent to 8,058.46 points.</p>
<p>Taiwan's top chipmaker, Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co, gained T$5 (18 cents) to T$116 while another major chipmaker, Mosel Vitelic Inc rose T$3 to close at T$63.50.</p>
<p>&quot;The timing was just right. Wall Street made a jump and those (Taiwan) shares that had seen some previous profit-taking had room for a corresponding rise,&quot; said David Yu, vice president of Taipei's International Investment Trust.</p>
<p>&quot;But the boost is probably only temporary, and most of the electronic shares remain somewhat overvalued,&quot; Yu added.</p>
<p>High-tech shares in Japan also rode the wave of the Dow rise. Fujitsu Ltd added 10 yen (nine cents) to stand at 1,390 by the end of morning trade.</p>
<p>Pioneer Electronic Corp, benefitting from a rebounding profit outlook, gained 140 yen to 2,720 by midday.</p>
<p>&quot;Until now, the shares were considered to be a loser,&quot; one broker said. &quot;However, the firm is expected to come back into the black, and investors are appreciating the forecast.&quot;</p>
<p>Pioneer said last week that it expected a parent current profit of 4.8 billion yen in fiscal 1997/98, compared to a loss of 4.10 billion yen the previous year.</p>
<p>In South Korea, analysts said the chip industry remained plagued by sluggish global prices despite Wednesday's gains by Samsung, Hyundai Electronics and LG Semicon.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot see any reason to revise our forecast upward for (Korean) semiconductor companies,&quot; said Ssangyong Securities analyst Bahn Young-one.</p>
<p>Hong Jong-hyun of Coryo Securities said: &quot;New York's rally helped semiconductor shares gain further momentum, but it would be a temporary boost.&quot;</p>
<p>Bahn said the unit price for 16-megabit dynamic random access memory chips on the spot market will average a low $8-$9 in 1997.</p>
<p>In Taiwan, analysts warned that electronics' index-defying rise may hurt the market by drawing too much money into one single sector at the expense of the market's overall health.</p>
<p>&quot;All the funds were concentrated too heavily in electronic stocks, especially integrated-circuit shares,&quot; said Yu of International Investment Trust.</p>
<p>&quot;Such a disparity meant that confidence in the market was weak other than in just the one sector,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The electronic sector fielded the lukewarm session's five most heavily traded shares. Chipmaker Winbond Electronics Corp, which notched the session's highest trade volume at 84.7 million shares, dropped T$0.90 to T$38.</p>
<p>(US$1= 116 yen, T$27.8, 892 won)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
