<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620280" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Major stock movements overnight - May 29.</title>
<headline>Major stock movements overnight - May 29.</headline>
<text>
<p>NEW YORK  - The Dow Jones industrial average lost 31 points as buyers retreated and profit-takers emerged after the previous day's jump to a record high.</p>
<p>Just after 7.45 a.m. (1945 GMT), the Dow was off 31 points at 7,352 and the drop activated the New York Stock Exchange's limits on programme trading. On Tuesday, the Dow rose 37.50 points to a record 7,383.41.</p>
<p>LONDON - The UK's FTSE 100 index suffered its first setback in the last five sessions as weaker European bourses and concerns about rising yields kept buyers sidelined. The blue chip index slipped 4.1 points to close at 4,677.5, as decliners  </p>
<p>narrowly outpaced advancers 48 to 45.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Shares peaked and troughed over the course of electronic trade, hitting record highs before tumbling to end over one percent lower after a jittery session before a German regional holiday. The IBIS DAX index, which measures electronic trade in 30 German blue-chips, ended down 38.83 points, or 1.06 percent, at 3,626.60 points. Its bourse counterpart, the DAX index, ended down 37.94 points, or 1.03 percent, at 3,536.42.  </p>
<p>PARIS - Stocks plunged on rumours of private opinion polls which traders said showed the left well placed for the second round of the parliamentary election on Sunday. The blue-chip CAC-40 index finished down 97.17 points, or 3.63 percent, to 2,583.17 points.</p>
<p>ZURICH - Shares slipped more than one percent but ended off the day's lows as profit-taking in blue chips and derivatives-linked transactions wiped out initial gains. The blue-chip SMI slid 56.9 points, or 1.1 percent, to 5,133.1. The broad SPI was down 30.89 points at 3,250.39. Turnover was high at 3.26 billion Swiss francs.  </p>
<p>TOKYO - The stock market's key index closed more than two percent higher, as stable currencies encouraged buying of high-tech exporters. A rally in Wall Street stocks overnight and keen interest in Japanese telecommunication shares also supported the market. The 225-share Nikkei average surged 461.45 points or 2.32 percent to finish at 20,351.34, just below the day's high of 20,351.64.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Stocks retreated from an all-time high to close just slightly higher following late profit-taking in blue chips, particularly Hong Kong Telecommunications. The Hang Seng Index closed 16.32 points, or 0.11 percent, higher at 14,556.48 after  </p>
<p>setting a new intra-day high at 14,688.47 late in the morning session.</p>
<p>SYDNEY - The share market kept a firm grip on early gains to close firmer, capturing record highs along the way. The All Ordinaries index closed 6.3 points up at a record closing high of 2,585.2, having touched a record high of 2,590.4, surpassing the previous mark of 2,585.8 set on Tuesday.</p>
<p>JOHANNESBURG - The all gold index ended at a four year low as bullion's slight rally on a surge in palladium and platinum prices failed. Golds refused to follow bullion, remaining flat to negative in morning trade before slipping to new lows.  </p>
<p>Industrial shares ended weak in negative sentiment compounded by a higher-than-expected April consumer price index figure of 9.9 percent year-on-year. The gold index ended 8.1 points down at 1,178.5 points, the industrial index lost 37.4 points to 8,281.9 points and the all-share index was off 24.5 points to 7,040.8.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
