<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620268" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Building a company from a home-business - one man's odyssey.</title>
<headline>Building a company from a home-business - one man's odyssey.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Fromartz</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Many people who start businesses at home often keep it simple, content with the small office in the spare bedroom or basement and gradually earning enough money to make it all work.</p>
<p>There are some, however, with the scent of a market opportunity, an invention or just impatience, who gather up the gumption to take yet another leap and form a company.</p>
<p>It happens every day in America. Count Doug Poretz among them.</p>
<p>Poretz's speciality is investor relations, acting as a source of information for the investment community. The young companies he represents were started by entrepreneurs like himself who need to spread the word about their business.</p>
<p>He first set up his home business in 1991, having left a high-paying job at a major corporation and signing up his former employer as his first client. He steadily built the business and by 1995 was handling about 10 clients out of his McLean, Va., home.</p>
<p>Realising that there was a greater opportunity for his expertise in the region, he recently joined forces with three partners and formed the Poretz Group.</p>
<p>In essence, Poretz's story is a microcosm of what is happening in the American economy in the 1990s at a quickening pace: skilled professional employees are leaving the corporate workplace, either out of choice or through layoffs, going into business on their own or forming full-fledged start-ups.</p>
<p>In part, necessity breeds the transition. In Poretz's case, his former employee was about to enter bankruptcy. But he also saw the opportunity to take a risk and seek a greater income stream than would have been possible as an employee.</p>
<p>Now Poretz, in his early 50s, has taken the next step and formed a company to build equity and enlarge his business.</p>
<p>&quot;I've swapped my anxieties,&quot; he said. &quot;As a one-person business, you're always worrying about what happens if you get sick, or how will you build equity for retirement or how can you afford to take a vacation.</p>
<p>&quot;Now I don't have to worry about taking a day off, but I do worry about overhead. You swap to a new set of concerns.&quot;</p>
<p>Essentially, he is capitalising on the same entrepreneurial movement that put him in business. In the Washington area, the number of young companies focusing on technology, the Internet, multimedia and telecommunications has been rising at a rapid rate. But many of them are cut off from investors, who don't understand their business.</p>
<p>&quot;It's really just happening now, but the vibrancy of the area is really becoming quite dramatic,&quot; said Poretz. &quot;I want to position myself to become dominant in this market and in that way contribute to its growth.&quot;</p>
<p>Although many growing companies usually go to New York or Chicago for investor relations experts, Poretz is virtually alone in servicing the local market.</p>
<p>&quot;Most investor relations firms service clients long distance with junior people,&quot; he said. &quot;We service firms locally with senior people.&quot;</p>
<p>Aside from the local focus, Poretz is attempting to shift the model somewhat in how he disseminates information to investors, relying heavily on technology that his company is in the midst of developing.</p>
<p>Instead of focusing solely on institutional investors, who have recently shied away from small and micro-cap stocks, he is identifying rich investors -- many who made fortunes in the high-tech field -- and are looking for investment opportunities.</p>
<p>All of that spells differentiation for the Poretz Group, offering something the bigger guys don't in a way that could benefit the customer.</p>
<p>Poretz, like most entrepreneurs, is also a dreamer. Not quite finished with setting up his company in the Washington area, he easily goes off on a tangent to talk about greater opportunities down the road, in other regions.</p>
<p>&quot;There's an opportunity to change the model and then apply it to other markets too,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>(Samuel Fromartz is a Washington-based writer who focuses on entrepreneurs and emerging companies. Any opinions in the column are solely those of Mr. Fromartz. He can be reached by e-mail at sam1on1 (at) aol.com)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
