<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="62035" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Allied Waste to buy Laidlaw waste business.</title>
<headline>Allied Waste to buy Laidlaw waste business.</headline>
<dateline>SCOTTSDALE, Ariz. 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Allied Waste Industries Inc said on Wednesday it had signed a definitive agreement to buy Laidlaw Inc's solid waste management operations for about $1.5 billion in cash, stock and notes.  </p>
<p>Laidlaw will receive $1.2 billion cash, a seven percent, 12-year subordinated debenture with a face amount of $150 million, and a 12-year zero-coupon subordinated note with a face amount of $168 million, Allied said.</p>
<p>The Toronto-based company will also receive 14.6 million shares of Allied Waste common stock and 20.4 million warrants.</p>
<p>Allied Waste shares closed at 9-1/8 on Tuesday, while Laidlaw Class B shares ended at C$14.30.</p>
<p>On completion of the transaction, Laidlaw will hold about 20 percent of Allied Waste's common shares outstanding, Allied said.  </p>
<p>Laidlaw will name two directors to Allied's board, expanding it to 12 members, Allied said.</p>
<p>Allied said it expects the transaction to be accretive to earnings per share in 1997 and beyond.</p>
<p>It also said it expects the combination to generate more than $60 million in pre-tax cost savings.</p>
<p>&quot;The acquisition of Laidlaw's North American solid waste management operations will, in one step, place Allied Waste among the industry's leading companies,&quot; Allied said.  </p>
<p>As a result of the acquisition, Allied expects to have combined 1996 revenues of $1 billion and a leading market presence in 23 U.S. states and seven Canadian provinces.</p>
<p>Allied reported 1995 revenues of $169.9 million.</p>
<p>&quot;In those markets where existing Allied and Laidlaw operations offer compelling growth prospects, we will seek to enhance efficiencies by making additional acquisitions and taking related steps to integrate additional waste volumes into current processing and transfer facilities and landfills,&quot; the company said.  </p>
<p>The transaction has been approved by the boards of both companies and is expected to be consummated by early 1997.</p>
<p>It is subject to a vote of Allied shareholders and standard regulatory approvals.</p>
<p>The 20.4 million warrants paid to Laidlaw are not exercisable by Laidlaw except upon a change of control at Allied. However, Laidlaw may transfer the warrants to other parties, who may exercise them, Allied said.</p>
<p>It said it had received commitments from Goldman, Sachs, Credit Suisse and Citibank for a $1.2 billion bank credit facility.</p>
<p>Allied said it had also received a &quot;highly confident&quot; letter from Goldman and Citibank for a $475 million senior subordinated debt offering to finance the cash consideration paid to Laidlaw and refinance existing Allied debt, among other things.</p>
<p>Goldman served as adviser to Allied on the transaction.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I92110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SCOTTSDALE, Ariz."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
