<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620484" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Couple sues supermarket chain over finger sandwich.</title>
<headline>Couple sues supermarket chain over finger sandwich.</headline>
<dateline>TAMPA, Fla. 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Tampa couple is suing Publix Supermarkets after they found a part of a finger in ham they had bought at the chain.</p>
<p>David and Katie Dean told a court Wednesday they had suffered great distress after finding the finger in ham sandwiches they had made for a boating trip. They are seeking $15,000 in damages.</p>
<p>Publix admits there was a human finger in with the ham but says the Deans are not as upset as they claim to be.</p>
<p>The Deans bought one pound (0.45 kg) of sliced ham in July 1995 at a Publix store in Tampa. Their lawsuit says that two days later, after eating most of the meat, they found part of it contained &quot;the top portion of a human finger pad, in addition to a substance in the ham that appeared to be blood&quot;.</p>
<p>They are suing for mental anguish, medical expenses for AIDS and hepatitis tests, loss of earning capacity, loss of comfort and attention of each other, and loss of &quot;the joy of living.&quot;</p>
<p>The Deans and the Publix worker who cut her fingertip off have tested negative for AIDS. The trail continues Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAMPA, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
