<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620417" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX natgas ends down, then reacts little to AGAs.</title>
<headline>NYMEX natgas ends down, then reacts little to AGAs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures, pressured by reports of softer basis differentials at bidweek, ended lower on Wednesday in active trade, then reacted little to a weekly AGA stock build near the expected range.</p>
<p>June expired 1.7 cents lower at $2.346 per million British thermal units. July slipped 4.5 cents to close at $2.316, then traded on ACCESS between $2.29 and $2.315 after the AGA data. Other contracts ended down by 2.5 to 4.5 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the weekly AGA number) was right in the range. It's not a surprise either way,&quot; said one East Coast trader, noting June bidweek differentials softened today.  </p>
<p>AGA said on Wednesday that U.S. gas stocks rose last week by 76 bcf, in line with expectations, and were still 212 bcf, or 24 percent, over year-ago levels. Eastern storage, which gained 47 bcf last week, remained 107 bcf, or 26 percent, above last year.</p>
<p>Injections need to average 10.5 bcf per day through October to hit 2.8 tcf ahead of the peak demand winter heating season.</p>
<p>Technical traders noted July held near-support Wednesday at $2.28 and closed over the $2.30 level. They pegged next support along the up trendline in the $2.24 area, with resistance seen at $2.37-2.38 and then at the contract high of $2.44.</p>
<p>Normal to slightly below-normal weather is expected to cover much of the East and Midwest into next week. The only heat forecast is for the Southwest.</p>
<p>In the May cash, Gulf Coast prices firmed a few cents Wednesday to the high-$2.20s, with June gas on the same pipes in the low-$2.30s. May Midcon gas gained a similar amount to the low-teens, with June in the mid-teens. New York city gate gas for May was steady to up slightly near the $2.50 level.</p>
<p>The NYMEX 12-month Henry Hub strip slid 3.5 cents to $2.321. NYMEX said 76,365 contracts traded, up from Tuesday's revised tally of 68,933.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, July finished six cents lower at $2.145, while deferreds ended down by four to eight cents. The July East/West spread widened by 1.5 cents to 17.1 cents (NYMEX premium). KCBT said 243 lots traded, down sharply from Tuesday's total of 1,417.</p>
<p>((J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
