<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620416" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INGAA urges looser U.S. FERC natgas controls.</title>
<headline>INGAA urges looser U.S. FERC natgas controls.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>On the eve of a Federal Energy Regulatory Commission natural gas conference, interstate natural gas pipeline operators on Wednesday urged the regulators to speed up decontrol to increase competition.</p>
<p>&quot;Simply put, INGAA believes that FERC should continue to use regulation to increase competition rather than increase regulatory controls,&quot; Oliver Richard, second vice chairman of the Interstate Natural Gas Association of America, said at a briefing.</p>
<p>INGAA's said FERC should do the following:</p>
<p>-- Increase competition at the citygate by allowing market-based rates for short-term transportation, where appropriate.</p>
<p>-- Allow as many shippers as possible including marketers, producers, end users, eligible pipelines and unbundled local distribution companies to trade capacity at market rates to increase the market's liquidity.</p>
<p>-- LDCs that agree to unbundle services should qualify for uncapped rates at all their interstate points, including secondary delivery points at citygates of LDCs that do not agree to unbundle.</p>
<p>-- Increase competition in services by allowing negotiated terms and conditions of service.</p>
<p>INGAA said pipelines should be able to negotiate contracts with rates, terms and conditions of service that vary from the generally available tariffs as long as shippers also have recourse to pipeline service under a commission-approved tariff.</p>
<p>-- Streamline construction and certification processes, including considering alternatives to traditional rulemaking.</p>
<p>-- Encourage open markets behind the citygate.</p>
<p>INGAA said FERC should remove LDCs' right-of-first-refusal, which it said shields existing capacity holders from competition by other bidders and gives existing shippers the right to service without having to make long term contractual commitments.</p>
<p>-- Require open access for all Outer Continental Shelf transporters.</p>
<p>INGAA said 130 pipelines currently in the OCS perform essentially the same function, but operate in dual markets of regulated and unregulated offshore pipelines.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
