<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620503" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs, pork bellies end lower to limit down.</title>
<headline>CME hogs, pork bellies end lower to limit down.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME lean hog and pork belly futures closed sharply lower to down their respective daily limits, pressured by evidence there is an ample supply of market-ready hogs, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think a lot of it comes back to the hog slaughter. The revision puts last week's slaughter above a year ago,&quot; said Dan Vaught, analyst with A.G. Edwards and Sons,Inc. &quot;Three weeks ago we were eight to nine percent below a year ago.&quot;</p>
<p>USDA late Tuesday revised last week's slaughter to 1.613 million head versus 1.611 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Also, traders may have sold hog futures in anticipation of a large hog slaughter Wednesday. After the close, USDA reported Wednesday's hog slaughter at 347,000 head, which exceeded many trade estimates.  </p>
<p>Trading turned fast in hogs near midsession when chart-based sell orders were triggered near 80.50 cents per lb in the July and 78.70 in the August, traders said.</p>
<p>Pork bellies were off the 3.00 cent limit in three of the four traded months and down 2.50 cents in the fourth, also in reaction to evidence of an increasing hog supply.</p>
<p>However, after the close the CME released its weekly storage report that showed a bullish reduction in frozen belly supplies. Traders had expected an increase. The CME reported supplies decreased 366,000 lbs.</p>
<p>&quot;It will probably be limit up before the day is out,&quot; said Vaught of Thursday's pork belly futures in reaction to the CME storage report.</p>
<p>At the close Wednesday about 300 July contracts and 250 August contracts were offered limit down.</p>
<p>Hogs closed down 2.00 to 0.300 cent with June off 1.350 at 79.850 cents per lb. Pork bellies were off 3.00 to 2.500 with July off the limit at 88.900.</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
