<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620662" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French centre-right floats &quot;dream-team&quot; before vote.</title>
<headline>French centre-right floats &quot;dream-team&quot; before vote.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's ruling centre-right on Wednesday floated an unlikely-sounding &quot;dream team&quot; to salvage its chances in Sunday's parliamentary election runoff as the opposition Socialists savoured the prospect of victory.</p>
<p>French financial markets plunged on worries that the Socialist-led opposition, planning to create 700,000 jobs and cut working hours, would win Sunday's decisive ballot after taking a stunning first round lead.</p>
<p>Stocks plunged by 3.63 percent, the franc fell below a key level of 3.38 per mark and bonds also closed down.</p>
<p>Socially-minded Philippe Seguin, a former opponent of a single European currency, and militant free-marketeer Alain Madelin attended a rally together as the fractious centre-right thrust them into the limelight as seemingly improbable saviours.</p>
<p>&quot;The president has said that we must find how to reconcile liberty and solidarity,&quot; National Assembly speaker Seguin, with Madelin alongside, told the rally of about 1,500 supporters in the Alpine city of Chambery.</p>
<p>He said that his views that more should be done for the poor and unemployed were &quot;fully complementary&quot; with the harsh deregulation favoured by Madelin, sacked as finance minister in 1995 for attacking civil servants' &quot;privileges&quot;.</p>
<p>President Jacques Chirac telephoned both men to discuss the campaign in a veiled blessing of their alliance, bringing together opposite tendencies in the centre-right coalition.</p>
<p>Seguin has long been shown by opinion polls to be favourite as prime minister if the centre-right wins. Madelin could be finance minister.</p>
<p>Opposition Socialist leader Lionel Jospin, meanwhile, sounded increasingly confident. Chirac called the election 10 months early, wrongly believing the re-election of his coalition allies for another five years was a virtual formality.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, we are ready to govern,&quot; Jospin said in Cintegabelle, southwest France. And in a jab at Chirac's gamble gone awry, he said: &quot;One must never be fooled by who is in charge. And in democracy, there is only one sovereign -- the people.&quot;</p>
<p>At a final cabinet meeting in Paris before the election, Chirac warned voters that change brings risks.</p>
<p>&quot;France cannot afford to change direction all the time without taking serious risks,&quot; Chirac said.</p>
<p>To change horses now would lead to &quot;confusion and weakness&quot;, government spokesman Alain Lamassoure quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>Jospin urged Chirac to brace for a period of power sharing with the left but also warned his followers against overconfidence, &quot;even if victory seems more and more likely.&quot;</p>
<p>The left-wing opposition outpolled the centre-right coalition by more than four points in last Sunday's first round of voting. Polling firms said it was on course for a narrow majority if the pattern were repeated in next Sunday's runoff.</p>
<p>The sudden focus on Seguin and Madelin followed Prime Minister Alain Juppe's announcement on Monday that he was bowing out irrespective of Sunday's results, hoping to bolster the centre-right's chances in the final stretch.</p>
<p>Madelin took a swipe at the likely inclusion of Communists in any left-wing government.</p>
<p>&quot;I know that (Communist party leader) Robert Hue seems more like Groucho Marx than Stalin, but people mustn't underestimate the consequences of a return of Socialo-Communism for our country,&quot; he told the magazine Valeurs Actuelles.</p>
<p>Seeking to lure back disenchanted voters, Chirac said in a televised message on Tuesday that he had heard their message but urged them not to return to &quot;the socialist ideas of yesteryear&quot;.</p>
<p>Most analysts said his appeal fell short.</p>
<p>&quot;Is that all there is?&quot; headlined the daily France-Soir over a picture of Chirac in a Superman costume.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
