<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620688" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germans relieved at Buba's firm stand on gold plan.</title>
<headline>Germans relieved at Buba's firm stand on gold plan.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>German bankers and industrialists on Wednesday heaved a collective sigh of relief when the Bundesbank underscored its independence, rejecting Bonn's plans to pave over its debts by revaluing reserves.</p>
<p>Over 200 guests attending a 50th anniversary celebration at the Hesse state central bank burst into thunderous applause as Bundesbank council member Ernst Welteke read out the statement agreed at the council meeting held earlier in the day.</p>
<p>&quot;I am relieved,&quot; one jubilant guest said, clinking a glass of champagne with another banker.</p>
<p>Tension permeated the room as no less than 10 Bundesbank council members, in Frankfurt for the day's regularly scheduled meeting, were ringed by hordes of journalists awaiting a nudge or a wink about the day's decision.</p>
<p>Revealing only that the decision would be released at 1700 GMT, the normally talkative group of grey and dark-blue suited central bankers looked rather somber and indeed said nothing.</p>
<p>Some of the guests, representing a virtual who's who of the Frankfurt financial and industrial community, said they hoped the Bundesbank would send a strong signal to Bonn but were uncertain how the council would react to the desperate plan.</p>
<p>After Welteke read the statement, other officials took pains to elaborate the central bank's stance, leaving no doubt Bonn's plans would catapult Germany to creative accounting policy-makers had earlier so vehemently abhorred.</p>
<p>&quot;(Theo Waigel's plan) could be called creative accounting, in fact it would be even more creative&quot; than what some nations, like Italy and France, have done to secure entrance into the monetary union, Bundesbank chief economist Otmar Issing told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;This would impinge on our independence,&quot; Issing said, echoing almost every other council member's comments.</p>
<p>While sources had said the Bundesbank was by no means always of one opinion, the group presented an absolutely uniform front at the festivities.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's discussions were very serious but they were not strained,&quot; council member Ernst Welteke, who is also the president of the state central bank in Hesse told Reuters.</p>
<p>Even at the last meeting where Finance Minister Theo Waigel was a surprise guest flying in for part of the meeting from Bonn, Bundesbank officials said the atmosphere had been civil but critical.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course there were a lot of very direct questions after Waigel presented his plan two weeks ago, but the mood should not be called acrimonious, as some have said,&quot; a senior Bundesbank source, who declined to be indentified, said.</p>
<p>Now that the Bundesbank has reached a decision on the matter, council members said they would have to wait and see how the matter progressed. &quot;For us the first round is completed,&quot; Issing said.</p>
<p>No one however could be drawn out for comment after Bonn fired off its reaction to the Bundesbank's statement, saying it too was sticking with its plan.</p>
<p>&quot;That was to be expected, they will stick to their stance and we will stick by ours,&quot; an official said privately.</p>
<p>At the same time the Bundesbank also sought to shrug off any suggestions that a serious fight would now unfold between Bonn and Frankfurt, which could prompt resignations on either side.</p>
<p>Asked whether any members of the council might consider stepping down in protest if Bonn successfully overrules the Bundesbank's stance in parliament, Welteke said, &quot;I think that would only make it worse.&quot;</p>
<p>The Bundesbank had already denied market rumours that Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer had resigned.</p>
<p>Welteke suggested further that part of the Bundesbank's credibility rests with the current team and that any change in players could irritate markets.</p>
<p>But fiercely independent Bundesbank members, all no strangers to conflict with Bonn, could still surprise their colleagues, sources said, recalling former president Karl Otto Poehl's high-profile resignation in 1991.</p>
<p>Poehl stepped down to protest an earlier currency union when the east German mark was converted to the west German mark.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
