<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620601" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cosmic snowballs bombard upper atmosphere - NASA.</title>
<headline>Cosmic snowballs bombard upper atmosphere - NASA.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Zabarenko</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Giant cosmic snowballs are bombarding the upper atmosphere, then breaking up, adding water to Earth's oceans and possibly nurturing life on the planet, scientists reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The snowballs are actually small comets about 40 feet (about 12 metres) in diameter, which appear to be streaking toward Earth in a steady stream.</p>
<p>However, according to data provided by NASA's Polar satellite, the snowballs are no danger to people on Earth or to astronauts, spacecraft or airplanes because they break up at altitudes from 600 miles (965 km) to 15,000 miles (24,140 km).</p>
<p>At that height, the snowballs break up first into fragments and then exposure to sunlight vaporises the fragments into vast clouds which are in turn dispersed by winds.</p>
<p>These cometary clouds eventually blend with normal weather systems and cosmic rain mixes with the common variety, according to Louis Frank of the University of Iowa, who first theorised about the phenomenon in 1986.</p>
<p>&quot;This relatively gentle 'cosmic rain' -- which possibly contains simple organic compounds -- may well have nurtured the development of life on our planet,&quot; Frank said in a statement.</p>
<p>The cosmic rain from these small comets accounts for only about one ten-thousandth of an inch (0.00025 cm) of water on Earth each year, scientists from the National Aeronautics and Space Administration said.</p>
<p>The Polar satellite, which orbits high above the Arctic Circle, tracked the snowballs as they disintegrated, and using a filter that detects visible light emitted by water molecules, Frank determined that the snowballs consist mainly of water.</p>
<p>Scientists have long believed that regular-sized comets, such as this year's clearly visible Comet Hale-Bopp, are made up largely of water ice and cosmic dust.</p>
<p>The finding that these mini-comets also contain water and that they are headed for Earth at a furious rate -- possibly thousands each day -- bolster Frank's earlier theory about the cause of what appeared to be holes in the atmosphere.</p>
<p>Frank theorised in 1986 that these apparent holes were caused by the disintegration of small comets in the upper atmosphere, but many colleagues discounted the theory and attributed the apparent holes to an instrumental problem.</p>
<p>Frank's findings were presented on Wednesday at a meeting of the American Geophysical Union in Baltimore.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
