<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620704" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Europe's single currency plans enter crisis stage.</title>
<headline>Europe's single currency plans enter crisis stage.</headline>
<byline>Henry Engler</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's planned single currency may be in trouble.</p>
<p>The decision by Germany's Bundesbank on Wednesday to reject a government plan to revalue the bank's gold reserves in order to fill a budget revenue shortfall this year is being interpreted by some analysts as outright war.</p>
<p>&quot;It means a real war is going on,&quot; said one London-based economist. &quot;One of the two sides needs to give up at some point, but I think the Bundesbank has the upper hand.&quot;</p>
<p>In denying Bonn the option to use the controversial strategy to bring its deficit down to the Maastricht Treaty's requirement, the Bundesbank has introduced a degree of uncertainty into the EMU process that some say is almost impossible to gauge.</p>
<p>&quot;I just don't know what's going to happen,&quot; said another economist at a Frankfurt-based bank.</p>
<p>The language used by the Bundesbank in defending its decision was unequivocal and employed the kind of emotion one rarely sees among central bankers.</p>
<p>In its tersely worded statement the bank said: &quot;Such a measure would be in contradiction with the German tradition and with the Maastricht Treaty's view on the independence of the central banks.&quot;</p>
<p>In reply, Bonn said it would go ahead with its plan, arguing that &quot;the successful stability policies of the Bundesbank as well as its sole monetary political responsibility will not in any way be hampered by the planned adjustments of the currency reserves.&quot;</p>
<p>Some analysts noted that what was really at stake is the safeguarding of the Germany's economic future, a responsiblity the Bundesbank has carried out with unparalled success.</p>
<p>Given the country's ravaged financial past and the mistrust many have with politicians handling monetary matters, the Bundesbank would likely command the moral high ground, public loyalty that Bonn would find hard to fight against.</p>
<p>While comparisions with the costs of German reunification were numerous, an episode that saw Chancellor Helmut Kohl impose a one-for-one conversion rate between the deustchemark and the eastern half's currency, several said the current situation beared no resemblance.</p>
<p>German reunification was something that a large majority of the public wanted. But the exchange of their trusted currency for an untested unit, one that has increasingly become politicised, is something different.</p>
<p>&quot;People draw a parallel with German unification, but that was something the German people really wanted,&quot; said another analyst who requested anonymity.</p>
<p>German Finance Minister Theo Waigel's gambit to raid the Bundesbank's coffers was always seen as a desperate attempt to meet the demands of a single currency, and at best many interpreted it as a solid commitment to see that the euro is launched on schedule in 1999.</p>
<p>But to create a common currency on political grounds, devoid of the rigours that Bonn had always preached to other EU countries, smacked of a heightened sense of anxiety, one that put credibility behind everything else.</p>
<p>Complicating the outlook for EMU further was the growing fear that the French government might be ruled by a coalition of Socialist and Communists.</p>
<p>From a German perspective analysts said the new political uncertainty in France made the path towards a timely launch of the euro that much more uncertain.</p>
<p>If there was one confident prediction that most could make, it was that European financial markets would now be prepared more than ever to test the political will of EU leaders over their commitment to create a monetary union.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
