<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620726" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: INSTANT VIEW - German analysts on Buba statement.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - German analysts on Buba statement.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are analysts' comments on the Bundesbank's statement:</p>
<p>HOLGER FAHRENKRUG, UBS, FRANKFURT.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the answer one would have expected from the Bundesbank and it would have been surprising if the answer had been different.</p>
<p>&quot;It shows that the Bundesbank is against interference with its independence on policy-making. But the statement was naturally very careful. It says that the Bundesbank is against the plan, but doesn't say that the Finance Minister won't carry out his plans and leaves the final decision to him.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;A very important point which the Bundesbank makes is that the plans go against what Waigel has always been saying about the necessity of a strong euro, the need for an independent central bank, and that the government shouldn't interfere in fiscal policymaking.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;A market which doesn't like inflation and which likes the independence of the Bundesbank will view the Bundesbank statement as a positive thing.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The statement points out that the basic budgetary problem is still there, just as before -- Germany is going to find it difficult to meet the three percent criteria.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;The following scenario is possible -- the Bundesbank will take the gain from the revalued gold assets not as profit, but as a valuation reserve&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;But this would not flow into government coffers, which makes the whole attempt to stop up holes in the budget look a little absurd.&quot;</p>
<p>ARMIN KAYSER, SWISS BANK CORP, FRANKFURT</p>
<p>&quot;This was a punch in the jaw for the German government and what we are seeing is a showdown between the Bundesbank and the government.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;The build-up to the release of the statement led one to expect this. The way in which the Bundesbank council said it was unanimous on the decision -- they wouldn't have said this if it wasn't going to be controversial.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Also when they said it was going to be short and worth reading also sounded like they were preparing for a show-down.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank said very clearly that the (move to revalue the gold assets) was an attack on the Bundesbank's sovereignty.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;Legally, the government has the law on its side. From a political point of view, it is going to be very difficult to introduce the plan for the assets against the will of the Bundesbank, against the will of the experts and definitely against public opinion.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If the government continues with the plans, they will look as if they lack solidity.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a precedent for the advice of the Bundesbank being ignored and that time the Bundesbank President announced his resignation.&quot;</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
