<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620713" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Buba-Bonn standoff could pressure Spanish markets.</title>
<headline>Buba-Bonn standoff could pressure Spanish markets.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spanish markets could weaken on Thursday, pressured by hostilities between the Bundesbank and the German government over a plan to drum up extra profit by revaluing central bank gold reserves, analysts said.</p>
<p>Earlier, bonos experienced a sharp selloff amid rumors of such Bundesbank disapproval of Bonn's move, but later recovered a bit, ending above lows.</p>
<p>But the 10-year spread over Bunds climbed to 75 basis points from 65 basis points earlier, while the peseta weakened to 84.87/90 per mark versus 84.40/41 on Tuesday despite intervention from the central bank.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this will affect badly the markets,&quot; said Felix Gonzalez Marin, chief economist at Beta Capital in Madrid.  </p>
<p>&quot;Longer-term this is going to be bad for all (European) markets,&quot; added Henrik Lumholdt, chief economist at Bank of America in Madrid.</p>
<p>&quot;To me it's an open war between the Bundesbank and the central government,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Earlier, the Bundesbank issued a statement rejecting Bonn's plan to revalue its gold assets. The Bundesbank warned the plan ran the risk to undermining stability of the planned European single currency.</p>
<p>But right after the Bundesbank released its statement, the Bonn coalition said it would stick to its plan.</p>
<p>And economists said such strong opposition would be disliked by markets, because it could raise doubts about the overall European economic and Monetary Union (EMU) project.</p>
<p>&quot;This is going to have a bad effect on public opinion in Germany. Gold is a thing everybody understands. It's more than creative contability, which no-one understands,&quot; said Lumholdt in Madrid.</p>
<p>Although remote, the possibility of early elections in Germany was scaring markets, which are convinced that German public opinion is against early entrance of certain countries especially Italy, in EMU's first wave, analysts added.</p>
<p>In addition, the Bundesbank might turn to interest rate policy -- raising rates-- to defend the euro's credibility.</p>
<p>&quot;It's possible that the Bundesbank would raise interest rates before previously thought in order to reinforce the single currency's credibility,&quot; said Gonzalez.</p>
<p>But other economists were more cautious.</p>
<p>&quot;The market had already priced in the possibility that the Bundesbank would be against such a move,&quot; said Alfredo Urrutia, economist at Societe Generale in Madrid.</p>
<p>&quot;At the end it is as if they would decide to print money in relation with the amount of gold they have -- this is a thing of the past,&quot; Urrutia added.</p>
<p>But Bonn's stance in implementing its decision, could be seen also as a positive factor, others added.</p>
<p>&quot;Bonn is very keen in doing it (EMU), and in doing it on time in 1999. Because of this it is defying the Bundesbank's traditional rigour,&quot; said Marco Pianelli, economist at Nomura Research in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course there is a credibility problem, but it is also confirmation that they really want to do EMU, and as large as possible, and this is going to help peripheral markets,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Madrid Newsroom, + 341 585 8340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
