<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620860" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's ITC to expand investment in cigarettes.</title>
<headline>India's ITC to expand investment in cigarettes.</headline>
<byline>Sabyasachi Mitra</byline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA, India 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's tobacco and hotel conglomerate ITC Ltd will invest eight billion rupees in expansion and modernisation of its units over the next five years, company officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The company recently announced an investment plan of 19 billion rupees ($530 million) over the next five years.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a part of that plan,&quot; company spokeswoman Aditi Syam told Reuters.</p>
<p>Britain's BAT Industries Plc holds a 31.7 percent stake in ITC.</p>
<p>ITC will spend 3.5 billion rupees to set up a new cigarette manufacturing unit near the southern city of Bangalore.</p>
<p>The new unit which will produce 100 million cigarettes every day in the first phase was expected to be begin production in the latter half of 1999, the company officials said.</p>
<p>After its completion the unit was expected to produce 300 million sticks per day, the officials said.</p>
<p>ITC which currently produces 46.1 billion sticks a year at its four factories hoped to double its output over the next six years, they said.</p>
<p>The company which has 15 brands is a market leader. But officials did not divulge the firm's market share.</p>
<p>In the whole industry growth last year was picked up by ITC, officials said. They refused to give any further details.</p>
<p>&quot;The industry grew by seven percent while ITC grew by 11 percent,&quot; company chairman Y.C. Deveshwar said last week.</p>
<p>ITC, which posted net profit of 3.4 billion rupees in 1996/97 (April-March) compared with 2.6 billion a year earlier, will focus on its core competent areas -- tobacco, hotels, speciality papers and packaging -- the officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are rationalising. The intention is to consolidate,&quot; said one company official who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;We are concentrating on our core business and want to be leaders where we operate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The company would invest five billion rupees in its existing and planned hotels to double its room capacity to 5,000 in the next five years and open hotels in Bombay and Calcutta, they said.</p>
<p>ITC Hotels, in which ITC holds 71.2 percent, operates 15 hotels across the country. Three of these hotels are owned by ITC while the rest are managed by the company.</p>
<p>The company has two units producing speciality papers and boards.</p>
<p>In addition, it also has two units in the eastern state of Bihar and the southern state of Tamil Nadu which specialise in packaging.</p>
<p>The company planned to specialise in cigarette packaging and export much of that output, the officials said. ($1 = 35.8 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
