<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620884" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Bangladesh urged to privatise aggressively.</title>
<headline>Bangladesh urged to privatise aggressively.</headline>
<byline>Serajul Islam Quadir</byline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bangladesh has suffered nearly $1.86 billion in losses over five years due to inefficient public enterprises and must aggressively privatise, the chief of the Bangladesh Privatisation Board said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no option but to go for aggressive privatisation. The slow and uneasy process of privatisation has caused a total loss amounting to some 80 billion taka (nearly $1.86 billion) from fiscal 1991-92 to 1995-96 (July-June),&quot; said Kazi Zafarullah.</p>
<p>He told a meeting with leading businessmen that the government had given 420 billion taka ($9.76 bln) in subsidies to state-owned enterprises (SOEs) over the past 21 years.</p>
<p>&quot;The SOEs were also given huge loans, but 90 percent of it, nearly 130 billion taka ($3.02 bln), has not been repaid,&quot; Zafarullah said.</p>
<p>&quot;This has resulted in a severe liquidity crisis in the lending banks.&quot;</p>
<p>He called the loss-making public enterprises -- which were overstaffed and mismanaged -- a &quot;cancer of the economy&quot; that cost the government 25 billion taka ($580 million) each year, or an equivalent of two percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>The World Bank said in a recent report 225 non-financial SOEs under 39 corporations incurred losses equivalent to 27 percent of Bangladesh's annual development programmes.</p>
<p>The privatisation board listed 95 state-owned enterprises in jute, textile, engineering, sugar, food and chemicals sectors that Zafarullah said should be disposed of immediately.</p>
<p>&quot;We could make little progress so far...only one jute mill is now in the final stage of privatisation,&quot; Zafarullah said.</p>
<p>The government would sell out its shares in 18 enterprises, said Zafarullah, who took office only a month ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Privatisation is an important element of the government's overall economic adjustment strategy. The process will soon gain momentum,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina has assigned top priority to the privatisation process in its economic reform programme.&quot;</p>
<p>Zafarullah blamed the &quot;dismal condition&quot; of the public sector largely on the failures of the previous government.</p>
<p>Ailing industrial units should have been swiftly transferred to private ownership to prune their management, inject fresh capital and create jobs, he said.</p>
<p>He also said the privatisation programme faced stiff opposition from restive labour unions and political groups, helping to delay the process.</p>
<p>&quot;I am now trying seriously to implement the government's policy in this regard as fast as possible,&quot; Zafarullah said.</p>
<p>He said the board had proposed to the government that it would not ask prospective buyers of state-owned enterprises to disclose their source of funding.</p>
<p>&quot;This (proposal) is under consideration,&quot; he said, without elaborating.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
