<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="621042" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: N.J. Senate to vote on $2.75 bln bond plan June 5.</title>
<headline>N.J. Senate to vote on $2.75 bln bond plan June 5.</headline>
<dateline>TRENTON, N.J. 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Jersey Senate will vote on Gov. Christine Whitman's $2.75 billion pension bond plan June 5, a senior aide said Wednesday.</p>
<p>State Senate President Donald DiFrancesco announced that next week's session would be converted from a committee day into a voting session.</p>
<p>&quot;The calendar dictates that there be a vote on the pension bonds,&quot; said Rae Hutton of the Senate majority staff. &quot;We can't do the budget until we know whether we have the pension bonds.&quot;</p>
<p>The state faces a June 30 constitutional deadline for enacting a balanced budget into law, but the controversial pension bond proposal has been a key sticking point in moving forward on the budget.</p>
<p>Every Democrat and several of the governor's Republican allies have said they would oppose the deal, arguing it is irresponsible to borrow such a large amount for the pension system.</p>
<p>But Whitman again on Tuesday called on the Legislature to approve the deal, saying her plan is needed in part to meet the dictates of a May 14 state Supreme Court order demanding up to $250 million in additional spending for schools.</p>
<p>In 1990, the high court identified 28 districts it said had special needs, and in 1994 it ordered the state to equalize their per pupil spending with the average of the state's most affluent districts by September 1997. Its latest order held Whitman to that deadline, ruling that her reforms aimed at dealing with the disparity were helpful but not sufficient.</p>
<p>Whitman said no taxes need be raised to meet the $250 million target. Revenues on existing taxes are running at least $215 million ahead of budget projections, and the governor said her proposed pension bond sale will make the problem manageable.</p>
<p>Whitman's original pension bond plan was to borrow $3.4 billion to eliminate the pension system's unfunded liability and enable her to forgo $647 million in contributions to the state's four pension funds. The plan was stymied in the state Senate, which pared it and reduced its budget benefit to $590 million.</p>
<p>If approved, the state has already selected Merrill Lynch &amp; Co to underwrite the pension bonds.</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TRENTON, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
