<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="621187" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Sinn Fein pledges zest for N.Irish peace process.</title>
<headline>Sinn Fein pledges zest for N.Irish peace process.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sinn Fein, political wing of the Irish Republican Army, said on Wednesday it wanted to see progress in Northern Ireland's deadlocked peace process but it gave no indication that the IRA was about to call a new ceasefire.</p>
<p>British officials and Sinn Fein representatives began a second round of talks in Belfast a week after Britain's new Labour Party government ended a ban on contact with the Irish nationalist party.</p>
<p>&quot;We are seeking to ensure that a meaningful and inclusive process of peace negotiations is on offer. We are seeking to make progress on that today,&quot; Martin McGuinness, Sinn Fein's chief negotiator, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;It is our intention to go into this meeting absolutely committed, dedicated, to moving this entire situation forward,&quot; said McGuinness, who won a seat in the British parliament in the May 1 general election.</p>
<p>The United States has stepped up pressure on the IRA to declare a ceasefire, arguing that British Prime Minister Tony Blair's landslide election victory presented an opportunity to address the Northern ireland conflict.</p>
<p>But as Sinn Fein went into talks with the senior officials in Britain's Northern Ireland Office there were no indications that either side expected an early breakthrough that might lead to a truce by the outlawed IRA.</p>
<p>Britain is adamant that the IRA, which is fighting to end London's rule over Northern Ireland and unite it with predominantly Roman Catholic Ireland, must unequivocally abandon violence before Sinn Fein is given a seat in multi-party talks due to get under way next Tuesday.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein, which wants immediate unconditional entry to the talks, is looking for a guarantee that Britain will not subject it to a lengthy &quot;decontamination period&quot; if the IRA calls a truce.</p>
<p>London says the collapse of a 17-month IRA ceasefire in February last year means that it needs proof that any new truce will last.</p>
<p>Peace hopes clouded by the threat of IRA attacks are also overshadowed by violence from pro-British Loyalist guerrillas and fears that contentious parades by Protestants could spark a rerun of riots that plunged the province into chaos last year.</p>
<p>Britain's Northern Ireland secretary, Mo Mowlam, who travels to Dublin on Thursday for talks with Irish Foreign Minister Dick Spring, signalled her belief that a Loyalist bomb planted in Ireland last Sunday did not breach a fragile Loyalist truce.</p>
<p>&quot;My personal view is that the CLMC (Combined Loyalist Military Command) did not know of the action that was taken in Dundalk,&quot; she told reporters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The bomb, in the border town of Dundalk on Sunday, failed to explode. The renegade Protestant militia which left it, the Loyalist Volunteer Force, followed it up with a threat to set off more no-warning devices if Dublin did not stay out of Northern Ireland's internal affairs.</p>
<p>The LVF is outside CLMC, the controlling body for outlawed extremists with an unswerving loyalty to British rule.</p>
<p>A CLMC truce since October 1994 has been shaken recently by attacks on Catholics, some of which have been blamed on its activists. But Loyalist politicians insist that the ceasefire, which guarantees them places in Tuesday's talks, is intact.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein accuses London of double-standards by keeping it from the talks while its Loyalist foes are at the table.</p>
<p>The talks restart in Belfast under the chairmanship of former U.S. senator George Mitchell after a three-month break for the British election.</p>
<p>Mowlam on Wednesday met leaders of the Protestant Orange Order and Apprentice Boys organisations and spokesmen for a Protestant &quot;right to march&quot; group in a bid to ease tension about summer marches that go through Catholic zones.</p>
<p>The international civil liberties group Human Rights Watch/Helsinki in a report published in Belfast assailed the province's police force, and Britain, for giving in to threats of hardline Protestant violence during parades last year.</p>
<p>Catholics say the marches are sectarian and inflammatory. Protestants say they are traditional displays of pride in British citizenship which Catholics want to undermine.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
