<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="621327" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey says its troops to quit Iraq when job done.</title>
<headline>Turkey says its troops to quit Iraq when job done.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey on Wednesday rebuffed calls from Western and Middle Eastern capitals to withdraw its troops immediately from northern Iraq, where they have been fighting separatist Kurdish rebels for the past two weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;Turkish security forces, as with previous operations, will withdraw from northern Iraq when the operation ... has reached its targets,&quot; the Turkish foreign ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>More than 10,000 Turkish troops streamed into northern Iraq two weeks ago to pursue the Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK) rebels, who use the region as a base to launch raids into southeast Turkey.</p>
<p>The ministry statement said the cross-border raid was limited and its only target was to clear the region from &quot;terrorist activities&quot;, referring to the PKK.</p>
<p>NATO-member Turkey's Western allies and regional countries have expressed growing concern over the incursion into a Kurdish enclave protected by the West since the Gulf War ended in 1991.</p>
<p>Iranian president-elect Mohammad Khatami said on Tuesday that Tehran opposed the incursion and said it would not help settle differences. He said Tehran had officially lodged a protest with the Turkish authorities.</p>
<p>Iraqi Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz has accused the U.N. Security Council of failing to take any measures against the Turkish offensive. Jordan has urged Turkey to withdraw immediately.</p>
<p>Turkey's Western allies have also expressed worries and U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan has condemned the incursion and urged Ankara to pull out its troops.</p>
<p>Turkish officials have said Iran, Syria and Iraq were building up military forces on the borders of the Iraqi Kurdish region to help rebels escape.</p>
<p>The state-run Anatolian news agency said Turkish troops killed nine Kurdish rebels in the Sarisarilar border region of northern Iraq in clashes on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The agency gave the total PKK dead since the start of the operation as 1,750. Sources close to the PKK say the figures are exaggerated.</p>
<p>Iraqi sources, who declined to be identified, told Reuters that the PKK had killed 81 members of the Turkish security forces, including state-paid village guards, and 27 Iraqi Kurdish peshmerga guerrillas in fighting since May 23.</p>
<p>They said eight PKK had died in the clashes.</p>
<p>None of the figures could be independently confirmed because the operation is being conducted under a strict news blackout.</p>
<p>Turkish planes bombed on Tuesday Kurdish rebels fleeing northern Iraq into neighbouring  Syria and Iran.</p>
<p>Turkey mounted a six-week, 35,000-man operation into the Kurdish-held northern Iraqi regions two years ago but failed to achieve its stated aim of clearing the area of the PKK.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
