<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="621319" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Palestinian's claim highlights Hamas power struggle.</title>
<headline>Palestinian's claim highlights Hamas power struggle.</headline>
<byline>Wafa Amr</byline>
<dateline>GAZA 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Palestinian Hamas leader said he and two other freed prisoners now headed the Islamic movement, underscoring a power struggle in the guerrilla group best known for suicide attacks against Israel.</p>
<p>Hamas officials said the return to Hamas leadership of Abdel-Aziz Rantissi was weakening moderates in the group who had sought reconciliation with Yasser Arafat's Palestinian Authority in charge of self-ruled areas.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Hamas is stronger now than it has ever been. It is returning to its original firm beliefs. There is no suspension of military operations,&quot; he told Reuters on Monday. Other Hamas officials had said military attacks were suspended.</p>
<p>Since its creation about a decade ago, Hamas has campaigned for the destruction of Israel. Opposed to peace moves by Arafat's PLO, it has carried out bombings in Israel that have killed scores of people.</p>
<p>Rantissi, a hardliner freed from Israeli prisons this month, said the group had been leaderless while the three men were jailed -- and this had led to confusion among the grassroots membership.</p>
<p>&quot;In the absence of the leadership -- myself, Moussa Abu Marzook and Ibrahim Maqadmeh -- there was no leadership. There were only a few brothers who kept the movement's name alive but were not the leaders,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His remarks angered other Hamas leaders who insist the underground group is run not by a handful of persons but by group consultation called &quot;shoura&quot;.</p>
<p>Rantissi was released after completing a four-year prison term. Abu Marzook, head of Hamas' politbureau, was extradited from a U.S. prison to Jordan this month.</p>
<p>Maqadmeh, released from a PLO prison in Gaza last month, was accused by the PLO of having led secret Hamas cells that killed Palestinian policemen and Hamas members and of plotting to kill Arafat.</p>
<p>&quot;When the leadership of Hamas was absent, there was confusion and differences between (leaders) in exile and local (leaders). Now Moussa Abu Marzook will lead Hamas and things will return to their old ways and this is the right solution to end this confusion,&quot; Rantissi said.</p>
<p>Rantissi said he rejected competition between local and exiled leaders and attempts by some Hamas leaders to move the decision-making power from leaders in exile to the local leadership.</p>
<p>&quot;Now the Hamas movement will have one voice and one leadership, in exile, in the West Bank and in Gaza Strip,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Jamal Mansour, Hamas leader in the West Bank city of Nablus, said: &quot;Hamas's leadership is institutional and 'shoura' in the movement is obligatory. There isn't one personality that makes decisions especially on strategic issues.&quot;</p>
<p>Rantissi said Hamas was changing the way it functioned. He said it would not rebuild the cells destroyed by the PLO during a crackdown last year following the suicide attacks on buses and public places.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now working directly with the people and through the people,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GAZA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
