<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="621505" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish shares dip on French poll, more falls seen.</title>
<headline>Danish shares dip on French poll, more falls seen.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish shares closed lower on Wednesday, falling on rumours of an unpublished poll forecasting a left-wing victory in the French elections, with dealers seeing more falls ahead if buyer interest remained low.</p>
<p>&quot;The share market opened positively but the French poll pulled prices down. If we do not see any renewed buyer interest, we will fall again tomorrow,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The KFX top-20 index closed 0.17 point lower at 165.85 in overall bourse turnover of 747 million crowns. The KFX June future fell 0.75 point to 165.35 with 340 contracts each worth 100,000 crowns traded.  </p>
<p>The day's main movement was outside the KFX, where home electronics maker Bang &amp; Olufsen closed at 400.00 crowns, up 20 crowns from Tuesday's close, continuing to rise on news that it is to buy back Dutch electronics group Philips' 25 percent stake.</p>
<p>At one point the share, which rose 15 crowns on Tuesday, touched 420.00 crowns.</p>
<p>--Steve Weizman, Copenhagen newsroom +45 33969650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
