<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="621681" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Owens to buy Fibreboard in $600 million deal.</title>
<headline>Owens to buy Fibreboard in $600 million deal.</headline>
<dateline>TOLEDO, Ohio 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Owens Corning, seeking to broaden its building materials product line, said Wednesday was acquiring Fibreboard Corp., which produces vinyl siding and windows, for $600 million, including $85 million in debt.</p>
<p>Owens Corning, a leading producer of high-performance glass fiber composites and building materials, said it had a definitive agreement to acquire all outstanding shares of Fibreboard for $55 a share plus the assumption of debt.</p>
<p>Fibreboard, based in Walnut Creek, Calif., will become a wholly owned subsidiary of Toledo-based Owens Corning when the deal is completed this summer.</p>
<p>Wall Street welcomed the announcement, sending Fibreboard's stock soaring $6.8125 to $54.3125 on the American Stock Exchange, where it was the most heavily traded issue with 3.7 million shares changing hands. Owens Corning added 50 cents to $41.625 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The deal -- Owens Corning's 16th acquisition in the past three years and the largest to date -- will make the company a major producer and marketer of vinyl siding, one of the fastest growing products in the building materials market.</p>
<p>The combination will also provide Fibreboard with resources for continued growth, the announcement said.</p>
<p>&quot;During the last three years Fibreboard has become one of the top producers of vinyl siding and accessories in North America,&quot; Owens Corning Chairman Glen H. Hiner said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The company is among the industry's low-cost producers and it has an extensive network of distribution centres for both vinyl siding and windows. These products will become an integral part of our low-maintenance exterior system for the home.&quot;</p>
<p>Fibreboard, which also makes other residential and industrial building materials, had sales in 1996 of $469 million. It said that on a pro-forma basis -- assuming its 1997 acquisitions had been completed on Jan.1 -- Fibreboard's sales this year would be expected to be close to $800 million.</p>
<p>Owens Corning, which had 1996 sales of $3.8 billion, said that the acquisition, which is expected to close in July, will add to its earnings starting this year.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, Owens Corning will make a tender offer for all outstanding Fibreboard shares and certain options by June 3, subject to customary conditions, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>Owens Corning said it would finance the transaction using a long-term bank credit facility underwritten by a major financial institution.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24794">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I46000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOLEDO, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
