<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="62163" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Iraqi Kurd leader in talks with Turkey's Ciller.</title>
<headline>Iraqi Kurd leader in talks with Turkey's Ciller.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Baghdad-backed Iraqi Kurdish leader Massoud Barzani met Turkish Prime Minister Tansu Ciller on Wednesday ahead of his first talks with U.S. officials since seizing control of northern Iraq.</p>
<p>Witnesses said Barzani arrived at Ciller's residence wearing a dark suit instead of his usual Kurdish traditional costume for talks on security on the Turkish-Iraqi border.</p>
<p>Barzani, head of the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP), was to hold talks later in Ankara with Robert Pelletreau, the U.S. assistant secretary of state for near eastern affairs.</p>
<p>Washington was expected to press Barzani to end further cooperation with Iraqi President Saddam Hussein in a bid to pick up the pieces of its shattered policy on north Iraq.</p>
<p>Barzani's forces, backed by Iraqi troops and tanks, captured the Kurdish city of Arbil from a rival militia last month, prompting U.S. missile strikes on southern Iraq.</p>
<p>Washington pulled back its military, aid and intelligence operations from Iraq, fearing that Barzani's new ties to Baghdad would endanger U.S. personnel and their local staffs.</p>
<p>The evacuation of hundreds of Kurdish families linked to U.S. efforts in the predominantly Kurdish north undercut Washington's ability to influence events in the remote region.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
