<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="621717" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India soymeal exports seen dipping on low supplies.</title>
<headline>India soymeal exports seen dipping on low supplies.</headline>
<byline>Sambit Mohanty</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Low domestic supplies are expected to cause a drop in Indian soymeal exports in the 1996/97 (Nov-Oct) season despite a demand surge from Far East countries, industry officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Ample overseas' demand is there, but our supplies are limited,&quot; Davish Jain, chairman of the Soybean Processors Association of India (SOPA), told Reuters by telephone from the central city of Indore. &quot;There is no dearth of market.&quot;</p>
<p>Indore in the central Madhya Pradesh state is the hub of India's soybean processing industry. Madhya Pradesh contributes about 80 percent to the country's soybean output.</p>
<p>Jain said soymeal exports in 1996/97 were expected to dip to 2.2 million tonnes from 2.6 million in the previous year.</p>
<p>&quot;The fall in exports is expected due to a dip in output in the current season,&quot; Jain said. He said soybean output in the 1996/97 season was likely to fall to about four million tonnes from 4.45 million in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Analysts and industry officials said high Indian prices and competition from the United States would also contribute to the fall in India's soymeal exports.</p>
<p>&quot;We have some competition from the United States because the timing of our crop is same as that of the United States,&quot; Jain said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the United States is not a major factor as the demand for soymeal from the Far East countries is rising,&quot; said a Bombay-based commodity analyst.</p>
<p>Jain said India's export market mainly consists of the Far East and the Middle East, with India meeting 25 percent of their demand. The United States, Argentina and Brazil are the other major supply sources.</p>
<p>Analysts said Argentina and Brazil were also expecting a good soybean crop but those countries did not pose a competitive threat to India since their crop arrives in April.</p>
<p>By that time when most of India's marketing season, which runs from November to March, has finished.</p>
<p>&quot;Soybean arrivals are also less as farmers are holding back stocks for sowing operations in the coming season,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>He said farmers received high prices in the current season, and as a result were tempted to keep more seeds for sowing. &quot;This coupled with the forecast of a normal monsoon will induce more acreage under the soybean crop in the coming season.&quot;</p>
<p>The Meteorological Department on Sunday said that India's annual monsoon, crucial to farming and the health of the overall economy, is likely to yield a normal amount of rainfall for the tenth successive year in 1997.</p>
<p>In 1996, delay in the onset of monsoon rains in Madhya Pradesh had affected sowing operations and later heavy rains at the time of harvesting contributed to a fall in output.</p>
<p>Analysts and industry officials expect acreage under the soybean crop to increase to more than five million hectares in the 1997/98 season, from about 4.8 million in the current season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
