<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="621892" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ's Clear to launch local call business service.</title>
<headline>NZ's Clear to launch local call business service.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Clear Communications will announce its move into the local call business market on Wednesday, a company spokesman said.</p>
<p>Ian Parkes told Reuters Clear had installed fibre-optic cables in the central business districts of Wellington, Auckland and Christchurch to service inner-city businesses. He said Clear had invested over NZ$20 million in the project.</p>
<p>&quot;In the main centres of Auckland, Wellington and Christchurch we spent $20 million putting a fibre-optic network through the streets so that businesses on those streets can connect directly through Clear,&quot; Parkes said.  </p>
<p>The new service would provide not just telephone calls, but also a full range of network services such as switched broadband data and video.</p>
<p>Parkes said over 100 buildings had been cabled so far but at present only &quot;a handful&quot; of businesses were using the network.</p>
<p>They included some parts of the old Department of Justice, the Department of Social Welfare, Eftpos New Zealand, Saturn Communications Ltd and Telstra New Zealand.</p>
<p>&quot;We've had some customers on trial for some time, but besides building the network we have to build all the systems at Clear that can cope with a whole new side of business,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;This is just the beginning. We will go wherever the numbers stack up right.&quot;</p>
<p>Parkes said while Clear was not likely to build a network up and down every street, it may eventually be able to compete with Telecom for residential calls via other networks.</p>
<p>Cable television companies were looking at installing residential networks and there was also the concept of putting communications signals over power lines, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;So we're not assuming right now that we're going to be building a duplicate network right up and down the country. The economics for that are way out of the ball park.  </p>
<p>&quot;But we could still provide service to residential customers at some time in the future over other networks that will appear.&quot;</p>
<p>Until now Clear has competed only in the toll call market.</p>
<p>The company has signalled plans to be in the cellular telephone market by the end of the year. Although it has not announced details, it is expected it will join forces with another company.</p>
<p>Clear is owned by the Todd Corporation, Television New Zealand, British Telecommunications Plc and American company MCI.  </p>
<p>--Matthew Brockett, Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
