<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="62180" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey to unveil second resource package on Thurs.</title>
<headline>Turkey to unveil second resource package on Thurs.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan said on Wednesday a second revenue-raising package prepared by the government to close huge fiscal deficits would be revealed on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will examine how the first (resource) package is progressing in today's meeting. Preparations for the second package are complete. It will be presented to the public tomorrow after a final review,&quot; Erbakan told reporters before a meeting with senior economy officials.</p>
<p>The package on Thursday is expected to contain measures detailing short-term privatisation plans, securitisation of state real estate and a central cash management system to collect public revenues under a single account to support poorer state firms.</p>
<p>Erbakan also said the government planned additional pay rises for senior bureaucrats, security forces, academicians and judges.</p>
<p>The government had awarded a more-than-expected 50-percent pay rise to some seven million civil servants for the second half of 1996 soon after it won a parliamentary vote of confidence on July 8.</p>
<p>Analysts saw the pay rises as a populist move likely to fuel annual inflation already running at around 80 percent.</p>
<p>The government aims to raise $10 billion from each of the two packages in the next three years. But the first package has failed to fuel optimism in the business community and markets, which saw the package as unrealistic and unpractical.</p>
<p>The first package, disclosed on July 31, included speedy privatisation, issuing foreign-currency denominated bonds, sale of state property, incentives and tax exemptions for Turkish workers abroad to channel their savings into the country and a six-percent charge on the financing of some imports. -- Aydan Eksin, Istanbul newsroom +90-212-2750875.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
