<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="621941" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia may shorten detention under security act.</title>
<headline>Malaysia may shorten detention under security act.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia may shorten a two-year detention period for violations of its Internal Security Act (ISA) to six months for less serious offences, the national Bernama news agency reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Deputy Home Minister Megat Junid Megat Ayob was quoted by Bernama as saying the shorter detention period could be applied if the ministry felt the offence committed by an ISA detainee was not that serious and the period of rehabilitation adequate.</p>
<p>The ministry was still studying the matter and would discuss it with the attorney-general before any decision was taken, Megat Junid told reporters after opening a crime prevention meeting.</p>
<p>The ISA actually allows virtually indefinite imprisonment without trial by permitting the government to jail someone for up to two years, then conduct a review of the case after two years and every two years after that.</p>
<p>It was enacted under British colonial rule to deal with a communist insurgency in the late 1940s and 1950s. Opposition leaders have been jailed under the act for fanning racial hatred and religious figures for preaching deviant creeds.</p>
<p>The government has been reviewing the ISA for the past several years to consider amendments.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad said last February that the internal security law was still needed to control certain groups including those which triggered racial riots and staged general strikes as political weapons.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
