<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="622393" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: OPINION-German yield curve-How steep,how long?-DMG.</title>
<headline>OPINION-German yield curve-How steep,how long?-DMG.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Dr. Helmut Kaiser and Werner Kraemer, DMG Global Markets Germany, Deutsche Bank AG, Frankfurt</p>
<p>The fact that &quot;Fed relief trades&quot; stayed away after the May 20 FOMC meeting makes clear that the market quickly moved its attention to the next FOMC meeting in July. Our view is that the still booming economy, the tight labour market, rising wages and labour costs will finally oblige the Fed to tighten monetary policy in a pre-emptive strike even if the actual inflation rate is still not menacing.</p>
<p>This won't leave U.S. bonds unimpressed. We think that the US bond market is in the early stages of a bear market. The increasing risk of rising interest rates in Japan - although we don't go for a hike this year - will add to the gloom on the bond markets later this year.</p>
<p>However, although we expect surging US bond yields in H2 1997 and well into 1998 we see a clear outperformance of Bund yields against Treasuries and therefore a more limited loss potential on the German bond market compared to the US. Arguments for that are a continued loose monetary policy of the Bundesbank until EMU starts in 1999, excellent fundamentals and the steepness of the German yield curve.</p>
<p>The export-led, non-inflationary, jobless recovery of the German economy has been confirmed by the recent economic figures. Output figures for Ql (+0.5 percent qoq) and a six-month annualised seasonally-adjusted inflation below one percent tell a corresponding story. Since wages are rising as slowly as never before since the 5Os, the overall capacity utilisation is just approaching its long-term average (we assess the output gap to be around 1.5 percent) and as further U.S. dollar strength should be limited price stability is not jeopardised at all over the foreseeable future. Moreover, money supply is not a problem this year.</p>
<p>The current 230 bp difference of the 2-year/10-year spread is large by historical standards. It is nearly the highest spread since the 8Os. Only in 1988, when the discount rate was also at 2-1/2 percent, was the curve so steep. If investors trust the theory that long-term yields are the sum of expected short term rates, a liquidity premium and inflation expectations, the latter factor must currently be the most important one as short term rates are expected to be on hold and liquidity is not a problem for benchmark bonds.</p>
<p>Hence, the steepness of the yield curve implies too pessimistic inflation expectations given the fundamentals mentioned above - even if one takes into account setbacks triggered by possible losses coming from U.S. Treasuries.</p>
<p>The only negative influence factor from the domestic side is still fiscal policy and its political implication for the ruling coalition in Bonn and the approaching Euro. The continued high rate of unemployment and disappointing tax revenues put an increased burden on the Federal budget.</p>
<p>German fiscal policy still has not given the impression of clear decisions but of trying window dressing methods to solve its budget deficits problems ahead of EMU.</p>
<p>Possible selling of the government's 75 percent stake in Deutsche Telekom (market value DEM 80 billion), increased privatisation efforts, revaluation of the gold and currency reserves of the Bundesbank (current market prices rather than lowest value; this would bring DEM 40 billion for gold stakes and DEM 30 billion for forex stakes) are not a problem from the side of pure economic argumentation, but the timing was unfortunate, confidence in Germany's preparedness to solve its problems has been put in question, and the market is increasingly discounting a broad EMU with a Euro starting in 1999 which might be weaker than hitherto expected.</p>
<p>It is becoming more and more difficult for Germany to argue that the former &quot;high yielders&quot; should wait some more time before they will become members of EMU now that Germany itself is obliged to use the interpretation scope of the Maastricht Treaty.</p>
<p>What does that mean for the German yield curve? In the mid term the expected Fed and possible BoJ tightening should lead to higher yields at the long end. Uncertainty on the fiscal stance of the German government, on the degree of stability of the approaching Euro and the expectation of stronger growth in H2 1997 now that fiscal tightening will be weaker than expected fits in this view.</p>
<p>The short end remains anchored as there is no reason to expect a policy change of the Bundesbank at least on a one year horizon. The fact that monetary union is going to start in 1999 and that the Bundesbank will in fact be obliged to follow a more European monetary policy stance after the decisions will have taken place in May 1998 will it make very difficult to increase rates in the course of 1998. Therefore, the German curve is expected to steepen after the flattening in April and in the first three weeks of May.</p>
<p>However, the above mentioned bullish fundamentals especially the steepness of the curve will allow Bunds to outperform the US and we see the spread between 10-year Treasuries and l0-year Bunds to widen to the 130-140 bp area in the next months. 10-year Bunds should rise to only six percent in three months, 6.20 percent in six months and 6.50 percent in 12 months.</p>
<p>In this environment of still historically steep yield curve, carry trades out of the very short end still provide value. A total return analysis (including coupon income, cash losses due to rising rates and roll-down effects) shows that the segments three to five years offer the best risk-return-value on the German yield curve on a three-month horizon.&quot;</p>
<p>/////By Dr. Helmut Kaiser, Head of Fixed Income Research, and Werner Kraemer, Senior Fixed Income Analyst, DMG Global Markets Germany, Deutsche Bank AG, Frankfurt. The views expressed in this item are those of the authors alone. They do not necessarily represent the view of Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
