<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="622378" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bundesbank meets to discuss gold proposals.</title>
<headline>Bundesbank meets to discuss gold proposals.</headline>
<byline>Janet Northcote</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Bundesbank council met for its regular policy-meeting on Wednesday with its agenda topped by a plan to revalue its assets and no market expectations of any move to change interest rates.</p>
<p>German finance minister Theo Waigel two weeks ago announced his aim of revaluing the central bank's gold and foreign exchange holdings in a bid to raise money for cash-strapped Bonn budgets.</p>
<p>No details of the plan have yet been formally published, although a German newspaper reported in broad terms on the plans on Wednesday morning.</p>
<p>The Boersen-Zeitung reported that the paper to be discussed by the Bundesbank's central council contained proposals for a revaluation of central bank reserves which will result in a payment to Bonn in two tranches, one in 1997 and one in 1998.</p>
<p>It said the paper also included draft wording for a corresponding amendment to Bundesbank legislation.</p>
<p>The newspaper, which did not name its sources, said Bonn had proposed an interim balance sheet which will allow a payment of more than 10 billion marks in 1997.</p>
<p>Coalition sources told Reuters on Tuesday that a revaluation towards market prices could boost federal finances by an extra 10 billion to 12 billion marks in 1997 and by a similar amount in 1998.</p>
<p>The sources also said neither Finance Minister Theo Waigel nor Juergen Stark, secretary of state at the finance ministry, will attend Wednesday's council meeting, at which the Bundesbank is expected to reluctantly approve the revaluation.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank declined to comment on whether a statement would be issued after its meeting. Yet financial markets will be looking closely at any statement to assess the level of support the central bank is giving to the Bonn plan.</p>
<p>Waigel's scheme has already unsettled some who say the move will pave the way for a weak single European currency.</p>
<p>The revaluation plan is part of proposals by Waigel to shore up Germany's 1997 budget, straining to meet Maastricht criteria for European monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>Waigel himself told journalists in Frankfurt on Tuesday that a special interim Bundesbank balance sheet had been drawn up and that as a result Bonn could receive a payout from such reserve revaluations this year.</p>
<p>But his comments came as Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer was reported in an unconfirmed newspaper article as having warned Bonn two months ago that any such revaluation in the run-up to EMU risked damaging Germany's credibility.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank has some 95 million ounces of gold in reserve valued at well below current market levels. The central bank adopts a lowest price principle in its accounts.</p>
<p>Confusion still remains about whether Bonn can find a way to use the measure to cut back its 1997 budget deficit to the three percent of gross domestic product (GDP) required for entry into the single European currency.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank's council meeting on Wednesday is one of its regular fortnightly meetings. It has been brought forward by one day because Thursday is a regional holiday in Germany.</p>
<p>-- Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
