<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="622425" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks indicated higher on Wednesday.</title>
<headline>French stocks indicated higher on Wednesday.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>French shares were indicated higher on Wednesday, building on Tuesday's solid gain.</p>
<p>A statement on Tuesday night by French President Jacques Chirac left French markets unmoved and the stock market appeared relatively free of worries linked to a possible win by the left in Sunday's parliamentary runoff.</p>
<p>In pre-session electronic trading, blue-chip CAC-40 May futures were up 11 at 2,689.00 compared to an afterhours session settle price of 2,678.00 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the stock market gained 0.96 percent after serious foreign selling failed to materialise.  </p>
<p>Gains in the dollar and bond prices were also expected to help the bourse on Wednesday.</p>
<p>U.S. durable goods orders for April due at 1230 GMT.</p>
<p>* LVMH, which opposes the planned Guinness-Grand Met merger, says it will exercise its rights to repurchase Guinness's interests in their existing joint ventures.</p>
<p>It says it still holds open its proposal that Guinness-Grand Met split the brewing and spirits businesses and create the world's leading spirits group with LVMH.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
