<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="622527" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NASD unit eyes bias case aribitration procedures.</title>
<headline>NASD unit eyes bias case aribitration procedures.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Association of Securities Dealers' top regulator, Mary Schapiro, said on Thursday her group is considering ways to improve how employees of securities firms can bring discrimination cases.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got to make some decision about this issue. We think in the next two months,&quot; Mary Schapiro, head of NASD Regulation, told Reuters. Schapiro said NASD Regulation is considering several options which may include modifying the standard form, called U-4, which employees must sign agreeing that all cases be arbitrated rather than taken to court. That also includes discrimination cases.  </p>
<p>&quot;There are a wide range of options. One is not to do anything,&quot; Schapiro said, adding that the NASD has already taken many steps to improve the arbitration process.</p>
<p>But Schapiro maintained that NASD will continue to improve its arbitration process, particularly when it comes to discrimination cases.</p>
<p>The issue has become a top priority for the securities industry's self-regulator, even though in 1996 discrimination cases accounted for less than two percent of the total cases arbitrated at the NASD.  </p>
<p>According to a spokeswoman, there were 5,631 cases arbitrated at NASD, of which only 109 were discrimination cases.</p>
<p>But arbitrators involved in discrimination cases are generally more versed in securities laws than discrimination issues.</p>
<p>&quot;I think no matter what we decide to do there are improvements to the arbitration program for employment discrimination claims that we want to make no matter what,&quot; Schapiro said.</p>
<p>The regulator's plans would at least include greater diversity in the arbitrator pool and better training, Schapiro said.</p>
<p>To help make a decision over the next two months, NASD Regulation has created a special group to act as a &quot;sounding board,&quot; a spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>That group includes: Ellen Brown, Maryland's former state securities regulator; Gertrude Michelson, a labor attorney and governor of the American Stock Exchange; Pauline Schneider, a Washington attorney; Alfred Osborne, a professor at UCLA's Graduate School of Management; Mark Sargent, dean of Villanova University's school of law; and Theodore Levine, PaineWebber Inc's general counsel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
