<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="622722" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. sees WTO Japan film case setting precedent.</title>
<headline>U.S. sees WTO Japan film case setting precedent.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. trade complaint about Japan's photo film and paper markets has broader implications than whether Eastman Kodak Co. will be able to enjoy more market access, U.S. officials said Thursday.</p>
<p>The trade officials said a World Trade Organization ruling against ruling against the U.S. complaint that the Japanese government took steps to offset competition from tariff reductions and thwart foreign entry into its photo film and papers markets would send the wrong signal to other countries.</p>
<p>&quot;If what Japan did in this film case is acceptable, then it's an open invitation for other countries to make tariff commitments and then offset them or undermine them as systematically as possible, as creatively as possible, as long as it is done in a non-transparent way so that it takes years to figure out what happened,&quot; a U.S. official, who asked not to be identified, told reporters in a telephone conference.</p>
<p>&quot;That can't be the right lesson from this case and that can't be an acceptable result for the trading system,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>U.S. and Japanese officials are set to make a second round of oral arguments before three-member WTO panel that is charged with resolving the dispute over access to Japan markets. The U.S. official said oral arguments would be made &quot;shortly&quot; and declined to say what date had been set.</p>
<p>The European Union has sided with the United States in the case arguing that Tokyo has taken steps to limit foreign producers' access to Japan's distribution channels.</p>
<p>A U.S. official said he expects a preliminary decision on the case in early autumn.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37330">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
