<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="62287" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Sept 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Sept 18.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Service Corp International offered to buy Loewen Group for $2.8 billion in stock, plus the assumption of debt, the Wall Street Journal reported Wednesday.</p>
<p>Other top stories included:</p>
<p>* Santa Fe Energy will announce Wednesday plans to split into two separate publicly trade companies.</p>
<p>* The terms of Ford Motor Co's contract with the United Auto Workers union, keeping hourly employment at 95 percent of the current level for three years, has implications for the rest of the industry, especially General Motors Corp.</p>
<p>* Chrysler Corp and the Canadian Auto Workers reached a tentative contract agreement that includes a pay hike but none of the concessions sought by Chrysler.</p>
<p>* The Federal Trade Commission adopted new rules intended to limit how long it takes to challenge mergers and acquisitions.</p>
<p>* U.S. industrial production rose 0.5 percent in August.</p>
<p>* Bond prices dropped almost a full point on renewed fears of an interest rate hike by the Federal Reserve. Stock prices dipped about four-tenths of a point.</p>
<p>* A court filing in Minnesota's lawsuit against the tobacco industry suggests Philip Morris Cos Inc had a method of allegedly hiding or destroying sensitive research documents.</p>
<p>* A Florida state-court judge sharply cut the scope of the state's lawsuit against the tobacco industry.</p>
<p>* Chateau Properties rejected two merger proposals and sweetened its proposed merger with ROC Communities.</p>
<p>* Japan's trade surplus narrowed 31 percent in August when measured in yen, but most of the reduction was a result of weaker currency.</p>
<p>* Suez's SGB  agreed to acquire the stakes of Belgian and Canadian financiers Albert Frere and Paul Desmarais in Belgian utility and engineering company Tractebel for $1.58 billion.</p>
<p>* Provident Cos Inc delayed its $1.2 billion purchase of Paul Revere Corp.</p>
<p>* FoxMeyer Health Corp's bankruptcy filing has created disputes between several securities firms and some of the world's largest pharmaceutical companies. - Heard on the Street.</p>
<p>* Bond prices tumbled after the market changed its mind yet again about monetary policy prospects. - Credit Markets</p>
<p>--New York Newsdesk  (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
