<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="622861" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-GROIN STRAIN PUTS BAGGIO IN DOUBT FOR FRANCE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-GROIN STRAIN PUTS BAGGIO IN DOUBT FOR FRANCE.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Milan's Roberto Baggio picked up a groin injury in a friendly match on Thursday, putting him in doubt for a four-nation soccer tournament in France next week.</p>
<p>Baggio's Milan club had no immediate details of the extent of his injury, which happened in a tackle, but he was expected to be out for Sunday's serie A match against Cagliari.</p>
<p>The tournament involving Italy, Brazil, France and England starts runs from June 3 to 10.</p>
<p>Italy are to announce their squad on Friday.</p>
<p>Baggio, nicknamed the &quot;Diving Ponytail&quot;, made a stunning return to the Italian national team against Poland a month ago.</p>
<p>Called up as an afterthought, he came on as a second-half substitute and scored a superb goal, helping take Italy closer to the 1998 World Cup finals.</p>
<p>Baggio, 30, had frosty relations with former Italy coach Arrigo Sacchi and had been off the team since September 1995, his only appearance since missing a penalty in the World Cup final against Brazil in Los Angeles in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
