<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="622808" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-JACQUET UNHAPPY AT MEAGRE TURNOUT.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-JACQUET UNHAPPY AT MEAGRE TURNOUT.</headline>
<byline>Pierre Serisier</byline>
<dateline>CLAIREFONTAINE, France 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>French coach Aime Jacquet was angered on Thursday when only half the national squad turned up for the first day of training ahead of the four-nation World Cup warm-up tournament starting in France next week.</p>
<p>France, World Cup hosts next year, meet holders Brazil in the opening match of the Tournoi de France in Lyon on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm really anxious because if I lose two or three players on Sunday, everything I've put in place to face the world champions becomes useless,&quot; Jacquet told a news conference.</p>
<p>Nine of France's Italian exiles -- all except Roma's Vincent Candela -- were absent on Thursday, having stayed with their clubs until after Sunday's round of matches in Italy's serie A championship.</p>
<p>Paris St Germain defender Bruno N'Gotty and striker Patrice Loko had permission to play for their club in a friendly against Real Madrid on Thursday and join the squad on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to start on a false note for this first match and that's never good for the remainder of a tournament,&quot; said Jacquet, particularly irritated by the Italian football federation's refusal to release the French players.</p>
<p>Key defenders Marcel Desailly of AC Milan and Lilian Thuram of Internazionale, as well as Inter forward Youri Djorkaeff and Sampdoria midfielder Christian Karembeu will have had a break of only 48 hours before meeting Brazil.</p>
<p>&quot;Those 48 hours are the minimum duration imposed by FIFA and the Italian federation has decided to make the most (of that rule) by making them play in the last match of the season on Sunday afternoon.&quot;</p>
<p>Zinedine Zidane and Didier Deschamps, losers with Juventus in the European Cup final on Wednesday, will be able to join Jacquet on Saturday as their club have already won the Italian league title.</p>
<p>Karlsruhe striker Marc Keller is also due to arrive at France's Clairefontaine retreat south of Paris on Saturday.</p>
<p>The Spain-based players, Laurent Blanc of Barcelona, Athletic Bilbao's Bixente Lizarazu and Espanyol striker Nicolas Ouedec, were released in good time for Jacquet although there are still several games to go in the Spanish championship.</p>
<p>&quot;This Tournoi de France will not have been preapred as we would have wished. That is going to oblige us to adapt because you can't do just anything against Brazil,&quot; Jacquet said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CLAIREFONTAINE, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
