<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="622909" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICA'S TUTU SEEKS 9 MLN RAND FOR TRC PAYOFFS.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICA'S TUTU SEEKS 9 MLN RAND FOR TRC PAYOFFS.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Archbishop Desmond Tutu said on Thursday he had asked South African Finance Minister Trevor Manuel to approve a nine million rand severance plan for the 300 staff of his Truth and Reconciliation Commission (TRC).</p>
<p>Tutu told a news conference he understood the concerns of staff who stopped work briefly in East London last week to press for some form of payoff when their contracts expire.</p>
<p>The TRC, appointed by the government to probe the human rights record of the war over apartheid, was originally scheduled to stop work in July, but was granted a six-month extension to December 14.</p>
<p>Tutu said that though recruits had known when they joined the commission that their contracts were limited, it was &quot;only human&quot; at the time to ignore the prospects of unemployment until it became imminent.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not surprised...if there is agitation, and unhappiness in the ranks of the staff of the commission,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tutu said the Finance Ministry had scrapped a budget provision for severance packages for commission staff, but that he had written to Manuel to ask him to reconsider the deal.</p>
<p>The National Unity and Reconciliation Act determines that Tutu and the 16 commissioners should be paid at the same rate as judges and that each should get an additional four months' salary after their work stops.</p>
<p>Staff are hired on public service contracts which do not include any severance package. The first contracts expire at the end of July. The remaining staff will leave either on December 14 or, after helping to complete a report, on March 14 next year.</p>
<p>--- Parliament newsroom +27 21 4032502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
