<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="622973" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: EUROPEAN COURT OPPOSES CODITEL CARTOON NETWORK BAN.</title>
<headline>EUROPEAN COURT OPPOSES CODITEL CARTOON NETWORK BAN.</headline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Court of Justice said on Thursday that member states may not block television broadcast retransmission from other states, even if the programming does not meet European based programming quotas.</p>
<p>Confirming an earlier ruling between the Commission and the United Kingdom, the court found jurisdiction over television content rests with the member state where a broadcaster is legally established, not where a programme is retransmitted.</p>
<p>The broadcast at issue is the Turner Network Television Cartoon Network. Turner International Sales are established in London, and the Cartoon Network is broadcast over the Astra Satellite under British authorization.</p>
<p>Belgium brought criminal proceedings against Paul Denuit, the managing director of Coditel, for infringing domestic Belgian broadcasting legislation when he allowed the Cartoon Network to be broadcast in Belgium.</p>
<p>The Belgian Minister for Communications prohibited the TNT Cartoon Network because it consists &quot;essentially of programmes produced outside the European Community and of commercial advertising,&quot; according to court documents.</p>
<p>The court found that quota rules under the Television without Frontiers directive have no effect on the issue of establishment and jurisdiction for programme approval.</p>
<p>Noting that the purpose of the TV directive is to abolish all restrictions on the freedom to provide broadcasting services, the court said &quot;it is solely for the member state from which television broadcasts emanate to...ensure compliance with the directive and the receiving state is not authorized to exercise its own control in that regard.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;A member state cannot unilaterally adopt, on its own authority, corrective or protective measures designed to obviate any breach by another member state of rules of Community law.&quot;</p>
<p>The court directed member states that relief may be sought under article 170 of the treaty, which allows states to challenge each other for failure to fulfil obligations under directives, or by asking the Commission to pursue the action under article 169.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
