<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623012" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE fuel oil markets steady to slightly higher.</title>
<headline>NWE fuel oil markets steady to slightly higher.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>European fuel markets were steady to slightly higher on Thursday as barges were boosted by bunker demand while low sulphur was steady with traders saying it was a little better supplied.</p>
<p>High sulphur fuel barges traded at a high of $82 and $83 a tonne fob in the ARA area after earlier trades at $79 and $80 a tonne, slightly better than Wednesday.</p>
<p>One trader said bunker demand was &quot;not bad&quot; at about 25,000 tonnes by mid-day. Another said that high sulphur was talked in the $81/$82 region later in the day.</p>
<p>Traders said an Italian trader and a Portugese refiner won bids on Wednesday to each supply 25,000 tonnes of high sulphur fuel oil to state-run Electricidade de Portugal, which took up an option for a third similar cargo to be supplied by the local refiner. No low sulphur fuel oil cargoes were heard moved. Traders said the market was a little better supplied, with offers and bids steady in the $96 and $94 fob area. &quot;It was a very dead market, nothing happening,&quot; one seller said, adding he would not show new cargoes before the end of June.  </p>
<p>One trader said lesser Russian material was on offer with some berths at the country's main Black Sea oil port of Novorossiisk shut due an oil spill last week. &quot;Novorossiisk is shut because of the pollution incident so there is delay down there. There are some pieces on the water but I think they will go fairly easy, especially if there are delays to the programme now out of Novo,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there will be delays because it is a sizeable spillage they had there. Three berths are closed at Novorossiisk after some 400 tonnes of oil spilled at a terminal when a pipeline burst open on Tuesday night. -Haitham Haddadin, London newsroom +44 171 542 8145</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
