<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="62310" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. West Coast crudes creep over previous levels.</title>
<headline>U.S. West Coast crudes creep over previous levels.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast light crude prices on Tuesday crept over Monday's levels in late trade, reacting to a choppy market for West Texas Intermediate crude and an absence of deals.</p>
<p>October WTI traded late at $23.35/23.45 a barrel, up 10 cents from early levels, as U.S. refiners avoided the market until Mideast tensions stopped roiling prices.</p>
<p>Outright prices for Alaska North Slope (ANS) crude climbed 10 cents to $20.95/21.25, with buyers and sellers failing to strike deals. Discounts for ANS remained at $2.30 under WTI, the level of a deal done late last week.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, West Coast refining capacity climbed 0.7 percent to 89.6 percent last week, according to data from the American Petroleum Institute. The rise continued an uptrend from low utilisation levels seen mid-August after a series of refinery disruptions.</p>
<p>Arco announced it will restart a coker at its Carson, Calif., refinery on September 21 following a roughly two-week shutdown for repairs.</p>
<p>Deltas for Line 63 widened by about 50 cents to $3.20/3.00 a barrel under WTI following a purported deal late last week.</p>
<p>Discounts were previously seen around $2.60/2.40.  </p>
<p>California heavy grades were seen flat, but some traders claimed deltas had risen above the current range of 50 to 25 cents under posted prices.</p>
<p>They said the Kern River crude gained strength after a major refiner reportedly bought 15,000 bpd of Kern River on a term basis starting in October.</p>
<p>Values for Wilmington were steady at $17.40/17.50.</p>
<p>-- David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau, +1 213 380 2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
