<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623106" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC OF CONGO: Congo's Kabila gives himself sweeping powers.</title>
<headline>Congo's Kabila gives himself sweeping powers.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Phythian</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Self-proclaimed president Laurent Kabila has given himself sweeping powers to run the Democratic Republic of Congo until the adoption of a new transitional constitution.</p>
<p>The decree was read out on state television late on Wednesday on the eve of Kabila's inauguration as president of the former Zaire.</p>
<p>Earlier, Kabila's soldiers broke up a third opposition protest since his Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo won the civil war on May 17, sweeping veteran dictator Mobutu Sese Seko from power.</p>
<p>Kabila's finance minister, Mawapanga Mwanananga, meanwhile, announced plans to change the country's currency from the new zaire to the congolese franc and to launch an audit of its debts with a view to negotiations on easing the burden.</p>
<p>Wednesday's decree said the nation's three institutions were the president, the government and the judiciary, which would remain independent.</p>
<p>Individual liberties would be guaranteed subject to respect of the law, public order and morals, it added.</p>
<p>&quot;The government conducts the policies of the nation as defined by the president, it executes the laws of the republic and the decrees of the head of state,&quot; the decree said.</p>
<p>The president has the power to hire and fire members of the government and after consultation also do the same with other holders of state posts, including those in the judiciary and the armed forces.</p>
<p>The decree will remain in force until a planned constituent assembly has approved a new constitution.</p>
<p>Mobutu ruled mineral-rich Zaire for more than three decades, during which rampant corruption and administrative chaos drained what is potentially one of Africa's richest nations.</p>
<p>Foreign and domestic pressure forced him to abandon his near absolute powers in 1990 and agree to a democratic transition but implementation dragged.</p>
<p>Several thousand supporters of Etienne Tshisekedi, a veteran Mobutu opponent, took part in Wednesday's march in Kinshasa, denouncing the presence of Rwandans among Kabila's forces and seeking power-sharing.</p>
<p>Kabila has set up a 13-member government. Aides say he plans to name seven more ministers.</p>
<p>Tshisekedi enjoys support in the capital's poor districts. His Union for Democracy and Social Progress (UDPS) has called another march for Friday.</p>
<p>Soldiers from Kabila's Alliance allowed Wednesday's march to go ahead but dispersed the protesters later, firing in the air and beating them with batons and rifle butts.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue until there is an army in the service of the people,&quot; Tshisekedi ally Joseph Olenghankoy said, but he expressed the hope that Tshisekedi and Kabila would meet.</p>
<p>Olenghankoy said at least 30 protesters were arrested.</p>
<p>Opposition activists marched in Kinshasa on Friday and Saturday. Soldiers broke up those marches.</p>
<p>Kabila's Alliance, which fought seven months of civil war, later banned political activity and public demonstrations.</p>
<p>At the United Nations, diplomats said envoys from at least a dozen countries planned to tell Kabila face-to-face he must do something about human rights and the treatment of Rwandan refugees in his country.</p>
<p>A group of 21 ambassadors, including those from the United States, European states, Canada, Japan, Egypt and South Africa, met after senior U.N. officials asked them to consider what they could do to express their concerns.</p>
<p>Many said their governments would probably send their Kinshasa ambassadors in one large group to see Kabila before he leaves for the Organisation of African Unity summit in the Zimbabwean capital Harare this weekend.</p>
<p>Kieran Prendergast, U.N. undersecretary-general for political affairs, said the ambassadors were asked what they could do quickly &quot;to get across to Mr. Kabila the very deep concerns there are in the international community on the humanitarian and human rights fronts&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC OF CONGO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
