<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623288" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia, Ukraine move to improve relations.</title>
<headline>Russia, Ukraine move to improve relations.</headline>
<byline>Oleg Shchedrov</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin, who is shaping Moscow's relations with the West, will visit Ukraine on Friday and Saturday to fix uneasy ties with his Slav neighbour and fit them into Russia's new foreign policy.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's first state visit to Kiev, postponed at least six times in the last few years, also appears to be a part of his commitment to remove some of Russia's biggest headaches before he quits the post in 2000.</p>
<p>The Kremlin leader is expected to sign a friendsip treaty with Ukrainian President Leonid Kuchma setting a long-term framework for bilateral relations.</p>
<p>Moscow and Kiev, which played crucial roles in ending the Soviet Union in late 1991, have since found themselves caught up in a web of mutual recriminations over the heritage of the defunct communist empire.</p>
<p>The row over the disputed Black Sea Fleet, Ukraine's energy debt and the fate of Soviet nuclear missiles as well as other problems soured bilateral relations, stoking emotions on both sides of the newly-established border.</p>
<p>Ukraine, with a population of 51 million, nervously watched the policies of Russia, with nearly 150 million, suspecting it of imperialistic plans.</p>
<p>Russia, for its part, greeted Ukraine's bid to find a new identity with alarm, asking itself how far Kiev would go in distancing itself from Moscow.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, who has been involved for years in a bitter power struggle with conservative opponents, could do little to improve relations with Kiev without making himself vulnerable to attacks from influential nationalist forces.</p>
<p>That situation changed after Yeltsin won his second and final term in office last summer.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, who seems to have tamed the opposition-dominated parliament and who is barred by the constitution from running again, has lately made a series of major steps aimed at putting his house in order irrespective of opposition criticism.</p>
<p>He struck a peace deal with rebel Chechnya, formed what was effectively a new government dominated by liberal reformers and signed a cautious integration deal with Belarus, led by authoritarian President Alexander Lukashenko.</p>
<p>On Tuesday he headed off an impending confrontation with NATO by striking a deal which gave Moscow some say in the Western alliance in exchange for an unspoken assent its plans to grant membership to some Eastern European countries.</p>
<p>Political experts have said that fixing relations with Ukraine looks like a natural next step in Yeltsin's programme, both from a symbolic and practical point of view.</p>
<p>Russian officials have said that good relations with Ukraine could keep it from joining the Baltic republics of Latvia, Lithuania and Estonia in actively seeking NATO membership, something Moscow sees as a big threat to its national interests.</p>
<p>Moscow is unruffled by Kiev's plan to strike a separate deal on special relations with the Western alliance as long as Ukraine does not seek full NATO membership.</p>
<p>Russian officials have also said that improving the climate for bilateral trade was a practical way of maintaining traditionally preferential economic relations between the two countries.</p>
<p>They said ending old squabbles was also a good way to protect the interests Ukraine's 12 million ethnic Russians, most of whom live in the east bordering Russia.</p>
<p>Kuchma, though likely to face attacks from nationalists over rapprochement with Russia, is also clearly committed to the new mood, as shown during a trip to Kiev by Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin this week.</p>
<p>It took Chernomyrdin and Kuchma just three hours of face-to-face talks on Wednesday to come out with the announcement that all problems in relations, including the Black Sea fleet row, had been solved.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin and Ukrainian Prime Minister Pavlo Lazarenko, clearly intending to demonstrate special ties, made an unplanned visit to the monument of Kievan prince Yaroslav the Wise, 12th century ruler of the then-united Slav kingdom.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a good idea to come and find some inspiration from our common ancestor who united people rather than dividing them,&quot; Chernomyrdin told reporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
