<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623224" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: IMF says more work needed to curb Bulgaria deficit.</title>
<headline>IMF says more work needed to curb Bulgaria deficit.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the Bulgarian government have so far failed to agree the size of 1997 budget deficit and the Fund will extend its mission to Sofia to keep working with the authorities on the budget draft.</p>
<p>&quot;The overall problem is that the estimated deficit is larger than we would like and we need to find the way to narrow it,&quot; IMF team leader Anne McGuirk told a news briefing.</p>
<p>Deputy Finance Minister Svetoslav Gavriiski, also present, said that work on the budget would be over soon.</p>
<p>&quot;This year's budget bill is expected to be completed shortly and introduced to parliament for approval in the next few days,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Preparations on this year's budget were expected to be completed by Friday under preliminary plans.</p>
<p>McGuirk said the IMF was concerned with fast-rising wages in some sectors.</p>
<p>&quot;We are discussing the income policy. The most recent data we have received indicated that some (state) enterprises have been raising their wages more rapidly than we think is justified,&quot; said McGuirk.</p>
<p>After adjustments to inflation and depreciation of the local currency, average state wages have risen from $30 per month to between $100 and $400 monthly in the past several months.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's labour and social welfare ministry aims for $200 across the board monthly wage in public enterprises, fearing recurrence of street protests, which in January toppled the Socialist government for failure to cope with a grave economic crisis.</p>
<p>Most of the pay-rises are concentrated in loss-making sectors like power-engineering, the national airline and few state banks.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not a general problem, it seems to be large in a few sectors and we need to get to the bottom of that problem,&quot; said McGuirk.</p>
<p>A $657 million reform and funding deal with the IMF envisages reducing budget deficit in 1997 to 3.8 percent from 10.9 percent last year by eliminating the need for central bank credit to the government and rationalising expenditures.</p>
<p>This year's  budget is assumed at a lev/dollar exchange rate of 1,600 or 1,000 levs to the German mark.</p>
<p>The IMF mission arrived in Sofia in mid-May to help prepare introduction of a currency board in July.</p>
<p>This is a self-regulating mechanism where the lev is pegged to an anchor currency at a fixed rate and the amount of levs in circulation must be fully covered by the foreign exchange reserves.</p>
<p>-- Elisaveta Konstantinova, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-981-4145</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
