<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623356" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>PANAMA: Panama police seize 1.5 tons of cocaine.</title>
<headline>Panama police seize 1.5 tons of cocaine.</headline>
<dateline>PANAMA CITY 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Panama's anti-narcotics police seized nearly 1.5 tons of cocaine, in the largest drug haul this year, authorities said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The police arrested five Panamanians when they seized most of the drugs late on Wednesday in a van parked outside the free-trade zone in Colon, 50 miles (80 km) from Panama City on the Atlantic Coast. The rest was found on Thursday in a car parked outside a home in Panama City.</p>
<p>&quot;This was the biggest drug bust of the year,&quot; a spokeswoman for the Technical Judicial Police (PTJ) said.</p>
<p>PTJ chief Alejandro Moncada told a news conference the detained people likely belonged to an international drug ring that shipped drugs from Panama's Atlantic Coast to a Caribbean island, and then on to the United States.</p>
<p>He said cocaine busts were expected to rise in Panama this year. &quot;So far this year we've seized some 4 tons of cocaine. In all of last year, we seized more than 8 tons of cocaine.&quot;</p>
<p>He attributed the increase in busts to closer cooperation among customs, police anti-drug units and maritime officials.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PANAMA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PANAMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
