<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623362" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexican left accuses army of conducting dirty war.</title>
<headline>Mexican left accuses army of conducting dirty war.</headline>
<byline>David Luhnow</byline>
<dateline>ATOYAC DE ALVAREZ, Mexico 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Renewed fighting between Marxist guerrillas and the Mexican army in a poor southwestern state sparked accusations on Thursday of a dirty war and cast a cloud over upcoming national elections.</p>
<p>Army troops and rebels of the Popular Revolutionary Army (EPR) have fought several times in the past few days in Guerrero state -- their first clashes this year.</p>
<p>The army said on Thursday at least nine soldiers and rebels were killed in the fighting. The rebels claim at least 60 people have been killed or wounded. Hundreds of troops, backed up by helicopter gunships, are now sweeping the state.</p>
<p>The army said in each clash that they were attacked by rebels, while the guerrillas allege they reacted when they were hunted down in a counter-insurgency sweep.</p>
<p>A rebel statement issued late on Wednesday said some guerrillas had been surrounded by army troops and others may have been captured and tortured by the military. They called on the Red Cross to monitor human rights abuse in the region.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Ninth Military Region, which covers Guerrero, said he had no comment on the allegations.</p>
<p>Mexico's main leftist party charged the army with illegally arresting and holding nine of its members in Guerrero since the fighting erupted last weekend. No formal charges had yet been filed against them.</p>
<p>&quot;Mexico's army and federal police are carrying out a very large anti-guerrilla operation throughout this state. There are illegal searches of homes and arbitrary arrests every hour,&quot; said Guillermo Sanchez Nava, a senior member of the leftist Party of the Democratic Revolution (PRD) in Guerrero.</p>
<p>He told Reuters the arrests began on Sunday, a day after the first battle between rebels and troops in the central part of the state some 150 miles (220 km) southwest of Mexico City.</p>
<p>Villagers in the municipality, 40 miles (62 km) northwest of the Pacific tourist resort of Acapulco, were not allowed by the army to return to their homes for at least a day after fighting in the area by rebels and troops.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not allowed to go to our homes or return to our fields, they are full of soldiers,&quot; a local peasant told Reuters. He was too afraid to give his name.</p>
<p>In the nearby hamlet of El Guanabano, where rebels and soldiers exchanged gunfire for several hours on Tuesday, residents said they were questioned extensively by army troops but their homes were not searched. Reporters were not allowed into the area by the army for several hours.</p>
<p>Further down the coast in Acapulco, tourists enjoyed their vacations apparently unaware of the huge military operation against the rebels only an hour's drive away. The only sign of unusual activity was military helicopters buzzing over the resort as they took off and landed at army headquarters.</p>
<p>Fighting erupted after months of relative quiet from the Marxist EPR, which sprang up in Guerrero last June calling for the overthrow of President Ernesto Zedillo's government. The rebels had announced a series of cease-fires to concentrate on what they termed &quot;armed propaganda&quot; activities.</p>
<p>Political analysts feared the outbreak of violence would raise tensions ahead of mid-term elections on July 6, when Mexicans elect most of Congress, six state governors and the first elected Mexico City mayor.</p>
<p>&quot;It is essential to establish peace and a state of law in the areas affected by the military's presence and stop persecution and repression against civilians in order to guarantee the upcoming elections will be peaceful....&quot; Mexican daily La Jornada wrote in an editorial on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The federal government has played down the incidents, hoping news of violence will not scare away badly needed foreign investment just as the country is recovering from a massive economic crisis.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATOYAC DE ALVAREZ, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
