<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623381" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian debt futures firm on U.S., rate talk.</title>
<headline>Australian debt futures firm on U.S., rate talk.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>----------(Snapshot at 9.00 A.M./2300 GMT)------------------</p>
<p>FUTURES					  CASH YIELD</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS  (JUN) 94.48  (+ 0.01)    5.56    (UNCH)</p>
<p>3-YR T-BONDS  (JUN) 93.66  (+ 0.05)    6.29    (- 0.06)</p>
<p>10-YR T-BONDS (JUN) 92.465 (+0.030)    7.54    (- 0.03)</p>
<p>AUD/USD  0.7665 (PREV 0.7625) US 30-YR  6.98   (- 0.05)</p>
<p>---------------------(May 30)-------------------------------</p>
<p>*Australian debt futures were firm across the curve at the start of trading following a rally in U.S. Treasuries and amid talk that the RBA could ease policy again.</p>
<p>*April retail trade due at 11.30 a.m. (0130 GMT).  </p>
<p>Australian debt futures were firm across the curve at the start of trading following a rally in U.S. Treasuries on Thursday and as the market debated the possibility of a further official rate cut.</p>
<p>Three-year bond futures contract hit their highest level since mid-December 1996 at 93.69, continuing the advance seen since last Friday's unexpected policy easing to 5.5 percent.</p>
<p>The bill futures curve also firmed as the market priced out the chances of a tightening looking forward, and the September contract went to small discount to the cash rate.  </p>
<p>The market was taken completely off guard when the Reserve Bank eased policy last week, and as the central bank appears to be going all out for growth, few analysts would totally rule out another easing.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a fair probability that the next move in interest rates is going to be down, and I reckon in the next two to three months,&quot; one short-end trader said. &quot;In the meantime, I think every time the September (bill) goes below 10 (basis points) under cash it's going to be sell.&quot;</p>
<p>Adding to the rate cut speculation were comments by Prime Minister John Howard late on Thursday.  </p>
<p>Speaking at a mining industry dinner Howard said that while Australia had seen significant reductions in interest rates, real interest rates were still too high.</p>
<p>The market awaits April retail trade at 11.30 a.m. (0130 GMT) for an indication of current demand. Forecasts centre on a 0.5 percent rise after the 0.3 percent fall in March, according to a Reuters survey of economists.</p>
<p>Also due are April motor registrations and first quarter balance of payments data.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, U.S. Treasuries firmed on Thursday amid foreign buying and a positive response to a five-year note sale.  </p>
<p>----------------------(SPREADS)---------------------------------</p>
<p> AUD VS   3-YR	   10-YR	* AUD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p> USD	-13 (UNCH)    79 (+ 01) * FUTURES   119   (+ 01.5)</p>
<p> CAD	114 (+ 03)    99 (+ 04) * CASH	123   (+ 01)</p>
<p> NZD	-92 (+ 02)   +03 (+ 02) *</p>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The market gave up a little ground to the dollar bloc after this week's strong outperformance, particularly at the short end. Canadian debt rallied on a firm local currency, having recently been down in the dumps this week on fears of a Fed tightening in July and in front of next week's election.  </p>
<p>------------------------(TECHNICALS)-------------------------</p>
<p>FUTURES	*SUP/RES     *SUP/RES 2ND *RSI    *MA-10 *MA-20</p>
<p>10-YEAR (JUN)*92.43-92.50 *92.35-92.55 *62 PCT *92.38 *92.32</p>
<p>3-YEAR  (JUN)*93.65-93.72 *93.58-93.80 *73 PCT *93.43 *93.30</p>
<p>90-DAY  (JUN)*94.45-94.48 *94.41-94.52 *79 PCT *94.30 *94.17</p>
<p>-------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>-- Colin Brinsden 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
