<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623412" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PNG offers peace plan to Bougainville rebels.</title>
<headline>PNG offers peace plan to Bougainville rebels.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Papua New Guinea on Thursday unveiled a surprise plan aimed at peacefully ending a long-running secessionist rebellion on Bougainville island in which thousands have died.</p>
<p>Acting Prime Minister John Giheno said the South Pacific nation, rocked by an army rebellion two months ago against plans to use mercenaries to quell the Bougainville war, now believed there could be no military solution.</p>
<p>&quot;The strategy states clearly the government's belief that there can be no military solution to the conflict,&quot; Giheno said in a statement released in Canberra.</p>
<p>&quot;Rather, the main objective of the strategy is stated as to find a peaceful and lasting resolution of the Bougainville conflict, without reliance on military force.&quot;</p>
<p>Giheno said the plan was developed under the direction of Prime Minister Sir Julius Chan, in a process which began before Chan was forced to stand aside by an army mutiny.</p>
<p>The strategy includes negotiations with the rebel Bougainville Revolutionary Army (BRA), increased control of their own affairs by Bougainvilleans and a move towards peacekeeping operations for the Papua New Guinea military on the resource-rich island, 800 kilometres (500 miles) northeast of Port Moresby.</p>
<p>Giheno appealed to rebel leaders to work with his government to help end the nine-year conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been too much suffering caused by the Bougainville conflict,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Together we can set Bougainville on the path to peace and normalcy. We must not waste this unique, God-given opportunity.&quot;</p>
<p>Australia, Port Moresby's biggest aid donor and a fierce critic of Chan's failed US$36 million mercenary plan, immediately welcomed Giheno's move.</p>
<p>&quot;It is my sincere hope that this strategy will initiate a process that will lead to lasting peace,&quot; Foreign Minister Alexander Downer said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that the resolution of the Bougainville conflict can best be achieved through peaceful negotiation.&quot;</p>
<p>Downer urged the rebels to release immediately, as a gesture of goodwill, five soldiers being held hostage.</p>
<p>Chan and two senior ministers were forced by the army mutiny and civilian protests to stand aside in March, pending completion of an official inquiry into the mercenary contract.</p>
<p>Giheno said earlier on Thursday the inquiry's findings were unlikely to be released until after national elections due next month.</p>
<p>The mercenary deal, aimed at also reopening Bougainville's rich Panguna copper mine, was opposed by then military chief Brigadier General Jerry Singirok, who was promptly sacked by Chan, sparking the mutiny in which soldiers besieged parliament house.</p>
<p>The Panguna mine, owned by Bougainville Copper Ltd, was forced to close in May 1989 by secessionist violence.</p>
<p>Many past rounds of peace talks between Port Moresby and the rebel army and military offensives have failed to resolve the conflict.</p>
<p>Giheno said the peace strategy had been drawn up in consultation with church and other community groups.</p>
<p>Rebel officials based in Australia were not immediately available for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
