<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="62341" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: FOCUS - SBC restructures to boost profits.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - SBC restructures to boost profits.</headline>
<byline>Peter Nielsen</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss Bank Corp (SBC) on Wednesday announced sweeping changes to its domestic operations, including the shedding of some 1,700 jobs, that would lead to an expected loss of 1.9 billion Swiss francs ($1.5 billion) for 1996.</p>
<p>The bank expects the moves to improve the health of its ailing domestic operations, especially business with corporate clients, and boost overall profitability.</p>
<p>SBC, which has undergone a dramatic transformation in recent years, said it would take extraordinary charges of some 3.3 billion francs this year, but this would be offset by an expected profit of 1.4 billion in 1996 compared with 1995's net profit of 1.05 billion francs.</p>
<p>In addition to reorganising its domestic operations, SBC will radically change the way it calculates possible losses on customer loans and revalue its own real estate portfolio.</p>
<p>&quot;All these initiatives will already have a further positive impact in 1997,&quot; SBC said.</p>
<p>SBC, Switzerland's third largest banking group, expects the restructuring of its domestic division -- including the closure or integration of 80 of 325 branches -- to lead to a boost to earnings of around 400 million francs in the next three years.</p>
<p>To mark the bank's 125th anniversary, the board of directors will propose to shareholders on May 13, 1997 that instead of a dividend, a capital repayment of 10 francs in nominal capital per share be made, without any tax deduction. This will cut the nominal value of SBC's share to 40 francs from 50 francs.</p>
<p>SBC is taking a three-pronged approach to improve the profitability of its domestic operations: Redirecting Corporate Clients Business, streamlining the distribution network and new organisational and management structures.</p>
<p>One of the most important goals of the new domestic division is to make the business with corporate clients profitable and central to the new strategy is to have a sharper focus on those customer relationships where there is an opportunity for building a broad-based, long-term partnership.</p>
<p>&quot;In future, a corporate client with a high risk profile will have to pay significantly more than a customer who is deemed to be low risk,&quot; SBC said.</p>
<p>SBC has around 14,000 highly differentiated clients that require costly and time-consuming servicing. In fact, some two-thirds of these customers have retail-type requirements.</p>
<p>A 400 million charge will be taken to cover the risks from repositioning of bank's corporate clients business.</p>
<p>Most of the 1,700 jobs that will be eliminated over the next three years will be absorbed by natural attrition, retirements, internal transfers and retraining and flexible working hours.</p>
<p>Only 100 of the job losses will be due to the closing of branches, most of which only employ two to six people.</p>
<p>SBC will also radically change the method of calculating loss provisions to a new system under which default by a loan customer is a predictable risk with a certain probability.</p>
<p>&quot;Losses in the lending business should not be treated as extraordinary, unexpected events but as a cost of doing business which must be anticipated and quantified to the greates extent possible,&quot; SBC said in a statement.</p>
<p>As a consequence, SBC will take annual recurring charges of around 600 million Swiss francs annually starting in 1997. This equals the expected annual loss on the existing loan book.</p>
<p>It will also create a one-time general loss reserve -- the ACRA reserve -- of about two billion francs.</p>
<p>The ACRA reserve will act as a cushion in the balance sheet, making it possible to absorb unexpectedly high loan losses, for example during times of recession.</p>
<p>In the past loan losses were confined to a few unexpected instances and the fundamental problem that a bank's loan customers might find themselves unable to meet obligations was not given any particular importance by banks. ($1=1.2403 Swiss Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
