<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623409" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian real rates high, reform needed - Howard.</title>
<headline>Australian real rates high, reform needed - Howard.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard on Thursday repeated his government's view that Australian real interest rates were too high.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very proud of the fact that Australia continues to boast very low levels of inflation,&quot; he said in a speech to a mining industry dinner.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen significant reductions in interest rates, although it would be fair to remark that real interest rates in Australia are still quite high by the standards of the industrialised world.&quot;</p>
<p>The government has long argued that the structural condition of the Australian economy, such as the budget deficit, keeps its real interest rates too high.</p>
<p>It has justified its policies by saying that in the long run its economic reforms will help keep interest rates lower.</p>
<p>Howard pointed to the reforms that the conservative Liberal-National government had implemented since it gained office last year, including tighter fiscal policy and a more flexible system of industrial relations.</p>
<p>&quot;In many other areas of reform the process of reform is proceeding at a very considerable pace,&quot; the prime minister said, citing improvements in energy distribution.</p>
<p>More reform was needed, however, especially in the taxation system, he added.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank of Australia eased monetary policy last week, dropping its overnight cash-rate target to 5.5 percent, the lowest since 1994. It was the fourth monetary easing since July.</p>
<p>But Australian real interest rates -- nominal rates less inflation -- remain high, as they have historically. Australian consumer prices rose just 1.3 percent in the year to the March quarter.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
