<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623498" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China stocks end down on new curb rumours.</title>
<headline>China stocks end down on new curb rumours.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>China shares closed slightly lower in slow trade on Thursday on renewed rumours about government measures to curb the market, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Shanghai B index fell 0.292 points, or 0.34 percent, to 86.340 on volume of 16.687 million shares worth $11.842 million.</p>
<p>The Shenzhen B index shed 0.18 points, or 0.12 percent, to 151.16 as turnover shrank to HK$67.6 million from Wednesday's HK$126.9 million.</p>
<p>State media said on Thursday that China's central bank had set up two special phone lines for investors to report irregularities and illegal trading on the financial markets.</p>
<p>It followed a similar announcement by the China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC) on Wednesday.</p>
<p>According to new rumours, specific measures on how to bar state-owned enterprises from &quot;speculative&quot; stock trading would be worked out in the short term, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Rumours of further clampdown measures prevailed in the market again late in the session, which triggered a little selling to unwind positions and pushed down the index,&quot; said one broker.</p>
<p>&quot;So many rumours are true, some are false and still more are hanging in the air... People are just worn out,&quot; an analyst at a foreign investment bank said.</p>
<p>Brokers said the new issue of Jinan Qingqi Motocycle also sucked some capital from the Shanghai secondary market.</p>
<p>Jinan Qingqi Motorcycle began issuing 230 million B shares today at a price of $0.482 per share for listing on the Shanghai Stock Exchange, a company statement in Thursday's Shanghai Securities News said.</p>
<p>Shanghai Jinjiang Tower was the biggest loser on unpromising prospects, plunging $0.032, or 9.19 percent, to $0.316 on volume of 108,000 shares.</p>
<p>Pudong real estate firm Shanghai Jinqiao Export Processing Zone Development was the most actively traded with some institutions seen liquidating their positions after prices rose in the morning on news that a major micro-chip project located in the area had been signed in Beijing.</p>
<p>It ended down $0.006, or 0.83 percent, at $0.714 on volume of 3.4 million shares.</p>
<p>Changchai Co Ltd was the worst performer in the Shenzhen B share market, losing HK$0.48, or 6.26 percent, to HK$7.19.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Shenzhen B index would likely hover in a tight range in the short term as investors wait for new government cues.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been so many rumours (about government moves to cool the markets) in the last month, people do not know what to believe any more,&quot; an analyst at PBI Securities said.</p>
<p>The Shanghai A index fell 7.390 points, or 0.56 percent, to 1,318.645 on volume of 435.0 million shares worth 6.3 billion yuan. The SSE30 blue chip index dipped 26.501 points, or 0.67 percent, to 3,913.154 points.</p>
<p>The Shenzhen A share index sagged 3.50 points, or 0.80 percent, to 433.34 on turnover of 5.7 billion yuan.</p>
<p>($1=8.3 yuan, $1=HK$7.8)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
