<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623509" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila raises heat in island dispute with China.</title>
<headline>Manila raises heat in island dispute with China.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippines on Thursday raised the heat in its dispute with China over tiny islands in the South China Sea but the United States warned against using force to settle the issue.</p>
<p>Brushing aside protests from China, Philippine police filed charges of illegal entry against 21 Chinese fishermen arrested nine days ago after a dramatic boat chase off a rocky outcrop called Scarborough Shoal which Manila and Beijing both claim.</p>
<p>China demands the fishermen's immediate release, saying they were in Chinese waters. Two are now in jail and the rest have been languishing in their boat off the Philippine coast for nine days.</p>
<p>China on Thursday again called on the Philippines to release the men, saying Manila had seriously infringed on Chinese sovereignty.</p>
<p>&quot;The Philippines side ... has seriously infringed on Chinese sovereignty,&quot; Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Cui Tiankai told a news briefing in Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;We request the Philippines side to quickly release the people and the boats,&quot; Cui said, adding the fishermen had been engaging in routine fishing activities.</p>
<p>The row is the latest incident involving ownership of disputed islands in the South China Sea, with the Philippines accusing China of repeatedly intruding on its territory.</p>
<p>As relations between the two Asian neighbours have turned increasingly testy, Philippine officials and politicians have called for a strengthening of Manila's defence pact with Washington.</p>
<p>They are keenly aware that the Philippines, which five years ago closed the last of two huge U.S. military bases on its soil, is no match for the Chinese armed forces.</p>
<p>But U.S. Ambassador Thomas Hubbard rejected any revision of the defence treaty and warned claimants to the obscure islands against using force to settle their quarrels.</p>
<p>&quot;We would strongly oppose any effort to solve this problem by using force and we have made known to all parties of the region that we encourage their efforts to solve the problem,&quot; Hubbard told reporters after meeting President Fidel Ramos.</p>
<p>Hubbard said the United States was not keen in revising its defence treaty with the Philippines, calling it &quot;a good document that serves our mutual interest.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We're happy where it now stands,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The 1951 treaty calls on both countries to come to each other's aid if one is attacked but some Filipino officials are unhappy with one of its provisions which require any aid by either party to first be approved by its Congress.</p>
<p>Philippine Senate minority leader Francisco Tatad on Tuesday said the treaty should be renegotiated to provide for &quot;an automatic retaliation clause ... to repel aggression instantly in case the Philippines is attacked in the South China Sea.&quot;</p>
<p>Besides quarrelling over Scarborough Shoal, Manila and Beijing are also contesting the Spratly Islands, a potentially oil-rich cluster of islets, reefs and atolls in the South China Sea.</p>
<p>Beijing says everything in the sea historically belongs to China. The Spratlys are also claimed wholly or in part by Vietnam, the Philippines, Taiwan, Malaysia and Brunei.</p>
<p>Manila last month accused Beijing of sending armed naval vessels near two islands it claims in the Spratlys. Beijing says they were on a scientific research mission.</p>
<p>Days later, a Philippine Navy vessel drove away a Chinese-organised expedition of radio hams from Scarborough Shoal and allowed Filipino fishermen to raise the country's flag over the rock. Beijing protested, saying it was a serious violation of its sovereignty.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
