<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623580" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: MMC sees golden future outside Malaysia. [CORRECTED 10:55 GMT]</title>
<headline>MMC sees golden future outside Malaysia. [CORRECTED 10:55 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia Mining Corp Bhd (MMC), disillusioned with the domestic mining industry, said on Thursday it was prospecting in the gold fields of the former Soviet Union and Africa in its aim to become Asia's top miner.</p>
<p>&quot;Malaysia is not a mining country anymore,&quot; MMC chief executive Ibrahim Menudin said. &quot;That's why we're looking for opportunities in Russian states such as Kyrgyzstan and Kazakhstan.&quot;</p>
<p>Ibrahim said MMC has a 52 percent stake in Krygyzstan's Taldybulak Mining Corp, which has found recoverable deposits of 80,000 ounces of gold a year for the next eight years.</p>
<p>The company was also involved in a Kazakhstan gold venture, which promised reserves of 20 to 30 million ounces of gold.</p>
<p>&quot;Entry into the Russian states is difficult but cheap,&quot; Ibrahim told reporters after MMC's annual meeting with shareholders on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The current gold price of $342 is not very encouraging, but if the economic recovery ability is good, then you can still mine,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said MMC had also ventured into Botswana and Malawi after being inspired by studies for gold and base-metal deposits in the African states.</p>
<p>Ibrahim said although MMC was originally a home-grown company before becoming Southeast Asia's largest mining firm, only about 40 percent of its revenue was now locally-derived.</p>
<p>The Malaysian firm has a strong gold mining base in Australia through Plutonic Resources Ltd, Ashton Mining Ltd and Hillgrove Gold NL. It also operates mines in Canada and Indonesia.</p>
<p>&quot;We're already Southeast Asia's largest mining company, but now we want to be Asia's largest,&quot; Ibrahim said. &quot;We produce about 23,000 kg (corrects from 23,000 tonnes) of gold in all the world, but unfortunately not even an ounce in Malaysia,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>MMC officials said the company's activities in Malaysia were basically infrastructure development, engineering and oil and gas exploration.</p>
<p>The Malaysian Chamber of Mines, at its recent yearly general meeting, said the country's mining industry will continue to lag behind and remained uncompetitive and unattractive to investors.</p>
<p>It singled out tin, saying that while Malaysia once accounted for one-third of world production, it was now in seventh position.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230-7509)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
