<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623677" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Women thrive on technology in workplace - survey.</title>
<headline>Women thrive on technology in workplace - survey.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Zabarenko</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Modern technology -- from beepers to cellphones to computers -- has leveled the playing field for women in the American workplace, according to a new survey.</p>
<p>Contrary to popular perceptions that working women fear technology, the survey found they embraced technology as a business ally, pollster Joel Benenson said on Thursday in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Women view technology as the leveler,&quot; Benenson said. &quot;They see it as an integral tool in the workplace and for entry into fields they felt might not have been available to them.&quot;</p>
<p>On-the-job use of technology was also seen as a battering ram on the so-called glass ceiling, according to the survey.</p>
<p>Among the more than 400 women surveyed, 80 percent saw technology as a way to get into traditionally male-dominated fields, and 75 percent attributed recent advancement at work to how well they used technology.</p>
<p>Nearly three out of four women surveyed -- 73 percent -- said workplace technology, including but not limited to the use of computers and the Internet, helped them achieve professional goals they would not have reached otherwise.</p>
<p>The more women used technology at work, the more likely they were to earn salaries above $25,000, the survey found.</p>
<p>Women without college education can earn as much as college graduates if they are heavy technology users at work, and in fact may have the edge over college-educated women who do not use technology or use it only sparingly.</p>
<p>Computer use alone did not determine women's success at work, the survey found; women who use three other kinds of technology in addition to computers are more likely to earn more than $25,000 a year than those who just use computers.</p>
<p>Benenson said one salient finding of the survey was the overwhelming confidence women had in technology, with fewer than one-third expressing intimidation and 85 percent saying they were confident about technology as opposed to worried about it.</p>
<p>&quot;The message for employers (in this survey) is that they should make every effort to treat women equally, particularly when it comes to technology, and work diligently to set aside any stereotypical notions that they may have,&quot; Benenson said. &quot;Women like technology...they see it as a tool of advancement.&quot;</p>
<p>The survey, which has a margin of error of 4.7 percent, was commissioned by Avon Products Inc., after women entrepreneurs who had been honoured by the company overwhelmingly said one key to their success had been technology.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
