<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623609" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar rises vs. yen on low Japanese rates.</title>
<headline>Dollar rises vs. yen on low Japanese rates.</headline>
<byline>Donna Sells</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar rose against the yen Thursday after a report pointed to weakness in Japan's economy and remarks from a Bank of Japan official diminished concern that Japanese interest rates will soon head higher.</p>
<p>The dollar rose in Asian trading after the Ministry of International Trade and Industry reported that Japan's industrial output fell 0.4 percent in April, though private economists had expected it to rise.</p>
<p>Japanese interest rates have been at record low levels since September 1995 to help stimulate economic growth. But some investors have grown concerned the Bank of Japan may raise rates soon because the economy was recovering. Higher rates would make the yen more attractive to foreign investors.</p>
<p>The report on industrial production, however, diminished speculation that a rate increase was right around the corner.</p>
<p>&quot;Personally, I think, the Bank of Japan is not going to be tightening rates as quickly as first thought,&quot; said Edith Wolf, head of corporate sales at Credit Commerciale de France in New York.</p>
<p>Wolf said the industrial production data helped push the dollar above 116 yen.</p>
<p>The gains continued into European and U.S. trading, and the dollar stood at 116.18 yen late in New York, up from 115.85 yen late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The dollar also rose to 1.6965 German marks from 1.6956 marks. But it edged down to 1.4105 Swiss francs from 1.4111 and to Canadian $1.3805 from C$1.3828.</p>
<p>The British pound climbed to $1.6403 from $1.6393.</p>
<p>The dollar got a second boost during New York trading after Bridge News reported an unidentified Bank of Japan official said the Japanese economic recovery was not strong enough for the central bank to raise rates.</p>
<p>The Japanese government raised its consumption tax in April. The central bank official emphasised that uncertainty about consumer spending was a major factor that made the Bank of Japan reluctant to raise rates.</p>
<p>&quot;This comment here is obviously helping the dollar gain some ground against the yen, and it's also softening the yen&quot; against other currencies, said Steven Walker, a senior foreign exchange trader at Skandinaviska Enskilda Banken in New York.</p>
<p>The dollar's rally against the yen in New York helped it trim losses against other currencies.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, doubts about plans for a single European currency bolstered the Swiss franc. Switzerland does not plan to join European Economic and Monetary Union.</p>
<p>The Swiss franc is benefiting from the view that it is a safe-haven currency in Europe, said Hillel Waxman, vice president of foreign exchange at Bank Leumi Trust Co. in New York.</p>
<p>Uncertainty about the proposed single European currency intensified on Wednesday when the German central bank and government clashed over the government's plans to revalue the bank's gold reserves.</p>
<p>German Finance Minister Theo Waigel told reporters Thursday his proposal to revalue the central bank's gold reserves was needed despite the central bank's strong objection to the plan.</p>
<p>He said &quot;not a single mark&quot; from revaluation would be funnelled into the government's budget, which some critics said would have helped Germany qualify for inclusion in the single European currency.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
