<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623666" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New documents found on Nazi looting from Jews.</title>
<headline>New documents found on Nazi looting from Jews.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Billions of dollars of looted Jewish assets were acquired during the Second World War by the neutral nations of Europe and by countries under Nazi occupation, according to documents to be released next week.</p>
<p>The documents, to be released at a meeting of the Jewish group negotiating the return of Holocaust-era assets, break new ground on the extent of Nazi theft in such countries as the Netherlands, Belgium and France, World Jewish Congress (WJC) sources said on Thursday.</p>
<p>They added that the recently uncovered documents also shed new light on the failure of liberated European countries and neutral nations like Switzerland to return the bulk of the assets to its rightful owners or Jewish groups after the war.</p>
<p>The documents will be released at a meeting in Jerusalem on Monday of the World Jewish Restitution Organisation (WJRO), the WJC branch that negotiated with Switzerland on whether Swiss banks were hoarding Holocaust-era Jewish bank accounts.</p>
<p>The joint Swiss-Jewish commission headed by former U.S. Federal Reserve Board Chairman Paul Volcker will also be meeting in Jerusalem on Monday. The commission was set up by the WJRO and Swiss banks to investigate the fate of Jewish accounts in Swiss banks.</p>
<p>Among the documents to be released at the WJRO meeting is one that alleges Dutch Nazis between 1940 and 1942 seized assets then worth about $750 million from the 100,000-member Jewish community of the Netherlands. The value of the assets would be about 10 times greater today, the WJC sources said.</p>
<p>The document, from the U.S. National Archives, said only 10 percent of the looted Dutch assets were returned after the war.</p>
<p>France, which recently admitted that 2,000 looted works of art were hanging in its museums, is cited in a number of documents. One says the number of unrecovered paintings and art works taken mostly from Jewish owners totals 40,000.</p>
<p>The documents also show the plunder from Jews in the Alsace Lorraine region of France under Nazi occupation even included their furniture.</p>
<p>One U.S. military document said the United States authorised the return to the Czechoslovak government after the war of valuables and possessions of concentration camp victims found in that country. The items were kept by the Czechoslovak government and not returned to the Jewish community, it said.</p>
<p>Diamonds worth tens of millions of dollars were looted by the Nazis from the famous diamond district of Antwerp, mainly from Jewish owners, and sold by Nazi leader Hermann Goering's personal agent to dealers in Switzerland, Sweden, Spain and even the United States before its entry into the war.</p>
<p>Switzerland, already under fire for allegedly hoarding unclaimed Jewish bank accounts, is named as the location for a German smuggling operation for the exchange of &quot;Jewish jewelry&quot; for hard currency needed for the German war effort.</p>
<p>&quot;These shocking documents show that plunder of Jewish wealth was not a rougue operation but a systematic massive effort aimed at fuelling the German war machine and enriching the murderers of millions,&quot; a WJC source said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
