<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623681" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sierra Leone envoy urges U.S. troop intervention.</title>
<headline>Sierra Leone envoy urges U.S. troop intervention.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sierra Leone's ambassador to Washington called on the United States on Thursday to send troops to help oust military officers who seized power from an elected government in his country last Sunday.</p>
<p>Envoy John Leigh told a rally that he was handing a petition to the State Department urging Washington &quot;to work with other nations and international organisations to act decisively to end the crisis, by force of arms if necessary.&quot;</p>
<p>Leigh spoke to about 50 banner-waving Sierra Leonean demonstrators across the street from the State Department as marines and helicopters from the U.S. Navy ship Kearsarge landed in Sierra Leone to evacuate Americans.</p>
<p>&quot;Fifty Marines from USS Kearsarge can boot the bandits out,&quot; one banner read.</p>
<p>Leigh said he wanted the 1,200 Marines aboard the ship to support West African peace forces &quot;to bring in law and order&quot; and end a &quot;reign of terror&quot; by the coup leaders, whom he described as &quot;wild savages&quot;.</p>
<p>Nigeria has sent troops to bolster a contingent of the ECOMOG peace-keeping force already in Sierra Leone, but no move to end the coup is expected until foreigners have been evacuated, according to West African military sources.</p>
<p>Leigh said he expected that even without U.S. help, West African forces would still move in and &quot;do the job,&quot; but it would be &quot;faster and less bloody&quot; with American support.</p>
<p>The United States has condemned the coup and on Wednesday instructed non-essential staff and dependents at its embassy in Freetown to leave the country. About 400 other Americans are reported to be in Sierra Leone.</p>
<p>Leigh said he had already spoken to U.S. assistant secretary of state George Moose about the situation in his country and planned to hold further talks later Thursday.</p>
<p>The Americans &quot;are very supportive, but American policy right now is to first of all secure the safety of American citizens in Freetown,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But, recalling past pledges by the U.S. Congress to support democracy in Africa and elsewhere, he added: &quot;American policy will fail in Africa if it doesn't have a deterrent to criminals.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SILEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
