<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623686" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. yield curve shows mkt doubts Fed - Dean Witter.</title>
<headline>U.S. yield curve shows mkt doubts Fed - Dean Witter.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The steepening of the U.S. Treasury yield curve since the Federal Reserve left interest rates unchanged on May 20 reflects market concern the Fed may be softening its anti-inflation stance, Dean Witter Reynolds Inc said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The spread between the bond-equivalent three-month bill and the 30-year bond had dropped to a low of 162 basis points on the day before the recently concluded Federal Open Market Committee meeting,&quot; said Dean Witter senior economist and first vice president Kevin Flanagan, who noted that spread now is &quot;coming in at 190 basis points.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;This current level represents the widest reading for this measure since June of last year,&quot; Flanagan noted. &quot;This renewed steepening of the Treasury yield curve appears to be the direct result of the Fed's decision to leave monetary policy on hold at the May 20th convocation.&quot;</p>
<p>The Dean Witter economist said such steepening reflected investors' doubts about &quot;the credibility of the Fed's fight against inflation.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This negative reaction from bond holders reflects the concern that the credit authorities are no longer being proactive but rather reactive in nature,&quot; Flanagan added. &quot;The fear is that the Fed could be falling behind the curve.&quot;</p>
<p>Flanagan said if the expected slowdown does not materialize and May economic data -- mainly the payrolls -- come in strong, &quot;the Fed's resolve and credibility will be questioned even further with higher open-market yields most likely being the direct result.&quot;</p>
<p>(( Isabelle Clary, 212-859-1666))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
