<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623706" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: EMU worries push Swedish shares to lower close.</title>
<headline>EMU worries push Swedish shares to lower close.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Worries about Europe's economic and monetary union (EMU) depressed Swedish shares on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is confusion about EMU both locally and internationally so nobody wants to bet much on the upside,&quot; a trader said. &quot;The downside is also limited as the U.S. shows it has a very strong bourse.</p>
<p>The Stockholm bourse's general index fell 0.96 percent to close at 2,812.89 in turnover of 4.16 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Construction company Skanska was among losers and fell eight crowns to 311.  </p>
<p>The share was hurt by a tax committee ruling Skanska would have to pay capital gains tax on its sale of shares in engineer Sandvik, a deal worth about 10 billion crowns. Skanska said, however, that it would appeal.</p>
<p>But automotive group Volvo withstood negative trends and ended flat at 216, supported by a strong order intake on trucks, strong car sales and its share redemption.</p>
<p>Cyclical steel and forestry shares were hurt as investors turned away from them for the second consecutive day after favouring them for a couple of weeks. The forestry sector fell 1.62 percent.  </p>
<p>ABB Sweden edged down marginally on news Kazakhstan annulled its 1.4 billion framework agreement with Swiss-Swedish ABB AG Power Consortium Ltd. The share was already trading down two crowns and it closed the session 2.5 lower at 106.5.</p>
<p>Drug company Astra fell two crowns to 127.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1008</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
