<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623712" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's Jospin says leftist win will cheer Europe.</title>
<headline>France's Jospin says leftist win will cheer Europe.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Socialist Leader Lionel Jospin, sounding confident of victory in Sunday's parliamentary election, said a leftist win would stun but also cheer Europe as it would follow Labour's victory in Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;We are on the brink of an event that is going to astound Europe, but it will also raise a magnificient hope in Europe after the victory of the leftist Labour party in Great Britain,&quot; Jospin told a rally in the northern city of Lille late on Thursday night.</p>
<p>&quot;This evening, I am telling you, we can win on Sunday,&quot; Jospin told a cheering crowd of backers.</p>
<p>But in a sign of renewed stress within the leftist alliance, France's Communist Party -- perhaps feeling uneasy about being the junior partner in a coalition that did not share much of its ideology -- said it might not join a leftist government.</p>
<p>Alain Bocquet, president of the Communist group in the outgoing National Assembly, told the Lille rally that the Communists would be loyal &quot;whether we participate in a government or whether we support it without participating&quot;.</p>
<p>That raised the prospect of the Communists seeking no ministers in a leftist cabinet. Bocquet said a decision would be made at a mass party meeting on Monday.</p>
<p>The two campaign allies have bickered before over European monetary union, which the Communists oppose but the Socialists generally favour.</p>
<p>The Communist threat did not prevent joyous Socialists from debating draft lists of cabinet officers and weighing legislative strategy should they take power.</p>
<p>The campaign was to formally end at midnight on Friday. Candidates are barred from scouring for votes on the final day before Sunday's vote.</p>
<p>The parliamentary election was called nearly 10 months early by conservative President Jacques Chirac, who sought a friendly parliament with a new five-year lease on life and a &quot;new elan&quot; for France as it prepared for the shift to a single European currency.</p>
<p>But Chirac badly misjudged voters' dismay at record 12.8 percent unemployment and government austerity programmes adopted to help France qualify for the euro and monetary union.</p>
<p>The left scored an upset win over the governing centre-right in last Sunday's first-round vote, forcing Chirac to contemplate the prospect of a leftist majority sharing power with him in an arrangement known in France as &quot;cohabitation&quot;.</p>
<p>The humiliating upset forced unpopular conservative Prime Minister Alain Juppe to take the blame and announce he would step down after Sunday's vote, no matter who won.</p>
<p>In a last-ditch effort to lure back disenchanted voters, centre-right leaders joined forces at an emotional rally in Paris on Thursday night.</p>
<p>Voters at the meeting heard an unlikely duo of socially-minded National Assembly speaker Philippe Seguin and free-marketeer Alain Madelin bidding them to return to the fold.</p>
<p>Voters &quot;want a road map which explains to them what we expect of them, where we want to lead them,&quot; Seguin said. &quot;If we do not do so now, their anger will continue to grow and will end up engulfing us all, both the majority and the opposition.&quot;</p>
<p>He pledged an all-out effort to create jobs should the coalition be returned to power. But the glum faces on the stage and in the audience belied their dwindling hope.</p>
<p>Centre-right leaders also sought to soften the government's tone on the euro, in an effort to reassure voters that not much more austerity would be needed for France to qualify for monetary union.</p>
<p>Gaullist Nicolas Sarkozy, a likely contender for a cabinet post should the right win, said the coalition now believed that the criteria for European monetary union should be viewed flexibly rather than rigidly, making further public spending cuts less likely.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
