<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623779" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Eurotunnel sees profit in 2005, risks remain.</title>
<headline>Eurotunnel sees profit in 2005, risks remain.</headline>
<byline>Pierre Tran</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Channel Tunnel operator Eurotunnel, laden with debt, said on Thursday it expected to show a net profit in 2005 and pay a first dividend in the following year.</p>
<p>The Anglo-French firm, holding out the prospect of future rewards, urged shareholders to back a complex debt deal with its lending banks.</p>
<p>French executive chairman Patrick Ponsolle made clear the risks as he presented Eurotunnel's debt restructuring prospectus, which is vital for winning shareholder and bank approvals to rejig its 70 billion francs ($12.2 billion) of bank debt.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel faces bankruptcy if the prospectus fails to win the necessary approvals, Ponsolle told a news conference.</p>
<p>The document sets out three-year and longer-term projections, including the &quot;base&quot; and &quot;downside cases&quot; -- both with and without an extension to its 65-year operating concession.</p>
<p>In the base case, Eurotunnel will make a net profit in 2005 and pay dividends in the following year, Ponsolle said.</p>
<p>That compares to a previous forecast dividend payment in 2003 and net profit of 320 million francs in a much-criticised prospectus for its 1994 share rights issue.</p>
<p>Ponsolle was careful to stress that the prospectus contained &quot;illustrative projections&quot; and not forecasts.</p>
<p>Some small shareholders blame Eurotunnel and its advisers for misleading them into subscribing in the 1994 issue, which contained what later proved to be grossly inflated forecasts.</p>
<p>Under a &quot;downside case&quot;, the Anglo-French company would return to profit in 2006 and pay a dividend in 2010. But if its performance improved faster than the base scenario, it could pay a dividend before 2006, Ponsolle said.</p>
<p>Under the base scenario and without an extension of the concession, Eurotunnel expects losses of 2.84 billion francs ($493.6 million) for 1997, 2.36 billion for 1998 and 1.82 billion for 1999.</p>
<p>It reported a 6.1 billion franc loss for 1996.</p>
<p>In a warning to investors, it said an outcome below the more pessimistic scenario could lead to a breach of covenants in the new credit agreement with lenders.</p>
<p>Despite the guarded tone of the prospectus, Ponsolle urged the shareholders to adopt the restructuring terms. &quot;This plan is not perfect but it is, nevertheless, the best possible one in the circumstances. It is the only solution possible,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A more drastic plan with an earlier dividend payment would have meant &quot;an infinitely greater dilution for the shareholders&quot; leaving them with between 10-15 percent of the capital, he said. Also, the banks were not ready to accept such a deal.</p>
<p>The plan allows shareholders to own 54 percent of the equity after a capital increase to issue stock to banks in exchange for eight billion francs of loans. Shareholders may also subscribe to the issue, depending on the market price.</p>
<p>Two thirds of Eurotunnel's French shareholders and 75 percent of British investors must approve the debt deal and lenders must give unanimous consent.</p>
<p>British co-chairman Robert Malpas said last month's official sales of Eurotunnel's loans held by by banks had boosted the chances of getting the lenders' approval. &quot;Yes it has, absolutely, no question,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Ponsolle said U.S. investment banks were among its main lenders after buying from a number of Japanese lenders who sold in the secondary debt market</p>
<p>Lazard Freres bought 700 million pounds of the bank debt and holds 8.71 percent of the loans, Eurotunnel group treasurer Mike Grant said. Other buyers were Bankers Trust which holds 4.27 percent and Merrill Lynch with 3.82 percent.</p>
<p>Other big debt holders are the European Investment Bank with 4.28 percent and the four agent banks, National Westminster Bank Plc with 3.12 percent, Credit Lyonnais 2.95 percent, Banque National de Paris 2.95 percent, and Midland Bank 2.84 percent.</p>
<p>After those are the Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi with 2.49 percent and Bank of America, 2.37 percent. The Japanese banks now hold eight percent of the stock of debt, compared to 19 percent initally, Ponsolle said.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel's concession to operate the Channel Tunnel expires in 2052. Ponsolle rated its chances of getting a concession at one in two. ($ = 5.749 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
