<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623922" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian call money up on bond outflows.</title>
<headline>Indian call money up on bond outflows.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian call money was quoted in the 7.0-7.5 percent range in early trade Thursday, up from Wednesday's close of 5.0-5.25 on funds outflows towards a bond auction, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India auctioned 30 billion rupees of three-year federal government bonds on Wednesday and received bids for 57.45 billion. It acccepted bids for 30 billion.</p>
<p>Payment by successful bidders in on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The outflows (towards the bond) take place today,&quot; said a dealer at a foreign bank. &quot;This has slightly squeezed funds supply in the market and pushed rates up.&quot;</p>
<p>Other dealers said liquidity had not been affected much and that lenders were driving rates up.</p>
<p>&quot;Supply of funds is still good,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;The bond auction received bids far in excess of the notified amount. This shows that enough money is floating around. Rates are being driven up by lenders.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he expected rates to start drifting down and to end below 7.0 percent by close of trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Call money should be around 6.0-6.5 percent by tomorrow,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
