<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="624013" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Light U.S corporate issuance to feature trust pfds.</title>
<headline>Light U.S corporate issuance to feature trust pfds.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Light U.S. corporate debt issuance on Thursday will feature another in a long string of trust preferred deals as those issuers capture positive investor sentiment, dealers said.</p>
<p>Paling next to Wednesday's $1.0 billion capital security deal from Zurich Insurance's Zurich Capital, Centura Banks Inc will price $100 million in 30-year capital securities on Thursday afternoon, said a source close to the deal.</p>
<p>Unofficial price talk on the deal is 180 basis points over the long bond, the source said. Goldman Sachs, which led the Zurich deal, is also lead manager for Centura Banks.  </p>
<p>Despite the rush of capital security deals, syndicates noted the demand has yet to be satiated. Still, deals that had traditionally come on the &quot;rich&quot; side were seen more attractively priced to ensure better secondary performance.</p>
<p>Zurich's $1.0 billion 40-year deal, rated Aa2/AA, was priced to yield 133 basis points over Treasuries.</p>
<p>Capital security deals are not just a hot product for investors, however. Underwriting the deals commonly results in higher commissions for syndicates than a subordinated offering, according to one official at a New York bank.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
