<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="624210" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Mark slips after Buba opposes asset revaluation.</title>
<headline>Mark slips after Buba opposes asset revaluation.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The mark drifted down from yesterday's highs on its European crosses amid a row between the Bundesbank and the German government over plans to revalue the central bank's assets.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank's objections to the plan, a bid to ensure Germany qualifies for European economic and monetary union from the outset, initially supported the mark against other European currencies.</p>
<p>Expectations the planned European single currency will be launched on schedule in 1999 despite the row have, however, led the mark to retrace some of its gains.</p>
<p>Traders expect the German government's determination to carry out the plan in the face of Bundesbank's opposition will pave the way for a broad EMU which includes Italy and Spain.</p>
<p>&quot;The mark is a bit softer on the crosses as people believe Kohl will push something through and won't stand for a delay to EMU,&quot; said Rob Hayward, the economic adviser at Bank of America.</p>
<p>Mark/Paris was quoted at 3.3797/99 at 1045 GMT from 3.3817/22 late Wednesday in Europe. The mark was at 990.40/62 lire and 84.70/73 pesetas from its 994.45 and 85 highs late yesterday.</p>
<p>Nor has the turmoil benefited the Swiss franc, the usual safe haven in Europe. Traders have been wary of taking on the SNB which has been pumping liquidity into the money market on a regular basis in the past week as a sign of its commitment to combating franc strength.</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing holding the Swissie back is the liquidity injections from the SNB,&quot; said Hayward at Bank of America.</p>
<p>There was also speculation that the SNB could cut its discount rate from one percent, already the lowest in Europe, in the coming months. Traders don't expect it to use up its ammunition by cutting rates at its meeting later today, though.</p>
<p>Mark/Swiss franc was last at 83.25/27 from 83.75/80 late yesterday.</p>
<p>Instead, traders are seeking refuge in the dollar and sterling, both seen to be immune to EMU jitters.</p>
<p>&quot;People will go for more straightforward currencies like the dollar and the pound until the situation is clarified,&quot; said Tony Norfield, the treasury economist at ABN Amro.</p>
<p>Nervousness in the run up to the second round of the French parliamentary elections Sunday should underpin the mark against the French franc before the weekend.</p>
<p>Traders expect the opposition Socialist party to wrest control from the right-wing coalition, but said the franc would weaken on any rumours of private polls which suggest the Socialists are widening their lead.</p>
<p>Meantime, in Italy, traders will also be looking for direction to the cabinet discussion Friday of the three-year economic programme which will outline how Italy intends to meet the Maastricht treaty's EMU criteria.</p>
<p>Olviero Diliberto, the leader of Italy's Communist Refoundation party, said today he still has objections to cutting welfare provisions.</p>
<p>--Swaha Pattanaik, London Forex Desk +44 171 542 6284</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
