<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="624236" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: U.Utilities on track for merger benefits.</title>
<headline>U.Utilities on track for merger benefits.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>British multi-utility United Utilities is on track to produce financial benefits of 104 million stg this year from the merger of its electricity and water activities, chief executive Brian Staples told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;This year I think the figure is 104 million stg (target for benefits) and it's effectively secured by the actions we took last year...all on course,&quot; Staples said.</p>
<p>United Utilities was formed when North West Water took over regional electricity company Norweb in 1995.</p>
<p>He said the company's performance was &quot;still good,&quot; despite lower than expected pretax profits for the year of 444 million before exceptionals, compared with 389.2 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Staples said the 83 million stg provision which the company made over operations in Bangkok was &quot;a serious disappointment,&quot; and that the company continued to work to try to recover the amount.</p>
<p>United's Vertex services unit had had &quot;a superb first year,&quot; Staples said, and the company was &quot;extremely pleased with it.&quot;</p>
<p>He said further deals for Vertex along the lines of one agreed last month with Northern Ireland Electricity for a joint venture business outsourcing unit, were likely. -- London Newsroom +44171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
