<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="624459" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Passive German cocoa buyers target lower prices.</title>
<headline>Passive German cocoa buyers target lower prices.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>German cash cocoa buyers are looking for lower prices before committing themselves to raw materials purchases, traders said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Markets would stay lifeless as long as futures remained range-bound and sterling at historically high levels.</p>
<p>&quot;It's no secret that multinational firms have good long term cover while small and medium sized companies in Europe need to buy more spot beans,&quot; one said. &quot;But flat futures markets won't offer the necessary inspiration and chocolate sales are depressing.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said cocoa could potentially benefit from sympathy with rallying coffee prices or specific fund interest.</p>
<p>The industry would welcome bullish factors because it would like to present consumers with plausible reasons to raise chocolate prices -- as had been possible in coffee -- to improve its weak margins.</p>
<p>June bean price offers for West African cif material were pegged at 2.80 marks, up from 2.77 marks last week, with buyers' ideas at 2.60-2.65.</p>
<p>June cocoa butter cost 6.96 marks per kg liquid, ex-works, on the basis of a 2.43 butter ratio over futures.</p>
<p>Spot butter buyers' ideas were pegged at 6.65 marks.</p>
<p>West African third quarter beans were quoted at 2.84 marks (2.79 previously).</p>
<p>The cocoa butter ratio was at 2.43 (2.44) for the third and at 2.50 (2.51) for the fourth quarter, with mark prices at 7.02 (7.01) and 7.10 (7.08) respectively.</p>
<p>-Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100144">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
