<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="62456" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Santer says treaty stalemate threatens enlargement.</title>
<headline>Santer says treaty stalemate threatens enlargement.</headline>
<dateline>STRASBOURG, France 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Commission President Jacques Santer warned the European Union on Wednesday that a stalemate in EU treaty talks threatened prospects for bringing new members from eastern Europe into the bloc.</p>
<p>Reflecting concerns that negotiations on a new EU treaty would not properly prepare the bloc for enlargement, Santer said no country should assume that a second set of talks could be undertaken while the EU also negotiated with potential members.</p>
<p>&quot;I am in favour of enlargement,&quot; Santer told the European Parliament. &quot;But I must make clear that the scenario will come to nothing if the (new treaty) does not provide a solution to the institutional challenges posed by enlargement.&quot;</p>
<p>The EU has told 12 eastern European and Mediterranean countries they can eventually join the bloc, but said that EU institutions must first be reformed to pave the way.</p>
<p>That is being done in the so-called inter-governmental conference (IGC), due to be completed in mid-1997. A number of critics, however, have charged that the pace and scope of the negotiations are not robust enough to get the job done.</p>
<p>Some have privately suggested a second IGC may be needed to clear up what the current talks cannot agree.</p>
<p>&quot;The mind boggles at the idea of holding a second IGC, a play-off as it were, before the end of the century,&quot; Santer said.</p>
<p>&quot;I must emphatically discourage any such notion. Do we really want to carry on external accession (membership) negotiations and discussions on internal institutional reform at the same time?&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STRASBOURG, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
