<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="624650" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Blair, Clinton plan G7 unemployment initiative.</title>
<headline>Blair, Clinton plan G7 unemployment initiative.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton and British Prime Minister Tony Blair are planning a joint initiative under the umbrella of the Group of Seven to tackle unemployment, British officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>They said they would ask other members of the G7 at next month's summit in Denver, Colorado, to launch a two-year plan aimed at creating jobs in the industrial world by increasing labour market flexibility and reducing the burdens on business.</p>
<p>Officials said Clinton and Blair wanted to take advantage of the fact that the United States and Britain, whose records on jobs are probably the best in the G7, are chairing the powerful forum this year and next.</p>
<p>Britain, which will take over chairmanship of the group next year from the United States, is planning a special jobs mini-summit in London next January ahead of the group's main summit in Birmingham in the summer.</p>
<p>Blair and Clinton were expected to announce details of their initiative at a news conference on Thursday following talks at the prime minister's Downing Street residence.</p>
<p>Britain and the United States believe the other members of the Group of Seven industrialised nations -- Japan, France, Germany, Italy and Canada -- can learn from their success in creating jobs by keeping labour costs low and cutting through red tape to encourage small firms.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear whether the planned January summit would be attended by heads of government or by ministers.</p>
<p>G7 employment ministers have held two job summits in recent years, one in Detroit, Michigan and the other in Lille, northern France.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
