<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="624658" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: ERICSSON SEES BROADBAND MOBILE SYSTEM SOON.</title>
<headline>ERICSSON SEES BROADBAND MOBILE SYSTEM SOON.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish telecommunications giant Ericsson CEO Lars Ramqvist said on Thursday he expected a breakthrough soon in broadband mobile telecommunications systems, enabling video transmission.</p>
<p>He said Ericsson was cooperating strategically with other companies on standardisation, and that it was up to nations to decide which standards to implement.</p>
<p>&quot;This will be a breakthrough very soon,&quot; Ramqvist told a news conference here. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Ericsson said in April it had agreed with Japan's NTT DoCoMo to jointly develop the first experimental third generation wireless communications system, and Ramqvist said it will be a broadband solution based on Code Division Multiple Access (CDMA) technology.</p>
<p>But he repetead that Ericsson did not plan to enter the market for old CDMA systems.</p>
<p>Commenting on when Ericsson may present a PDA (personal digital assistant) product, Ramqvist said the company had many potential PDA products but did not feel there was a market yet.</p>
<p>&quot;We like to be in the leading edge, not in the bleeding edge,&quot; he said. &quot;It is still not a real market.&quot;</p>
<p>Finnish rival Nokia last year launched the world's first digital handset, the Communicator which integrates a palmtop computer for the PDA market.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +358-9-680 50 242, news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
