<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="624785" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: NSW says Kembla Copper to benefit from law change.</title>
<headline>NSW says Kembla Copper to benefit from law change.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New South Wales (NSW) state government said on Thursday it had introduced legislation aimed in part at restarting Port Kembla Copper's copper smelter.</p>
<p>The smelter, south of Sydney, has been under care and maintenance since 1995 and a planned upgrade has since been stalled by five months of legal debate culminating in a current action in the NSW Land and Environment Court.  </p>
<p>New South Wales urban affairs and planning minister Craig Knowles said legislation he introduced in state parliament would provide certainty for development projects and secure jobs for the Illawarra region south of Sydney.</p>
<p>&quot;The Port Kembla upgrade represents a major boost to the Illawarra's economy -- delivering investment and improved environmental performance,&quot; Knowles said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;However the project is under threat of collapse due to five months of protracted legal debate and manoeuvring on technical issues.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Land and Environment Court was told on Thursday by lawyers representing Port Kembla residents that the upgrade would expose residents to large amounts of lead and sulphur dioxide pollution.</p>
<p>Knowles however said current legal challenges could see the project &quot;put off for years or cancelled altogether&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The upgrade represents a massive economic injection of A$230 million, with more than A$170 million spent on environmental improvements,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>RTZ-CRA, now Rio Tinto Plc/Ltd, last December sold the land, buildings, plant and equipment owned by its subsidiary Southern Copper to the Port Kembla Copper group for an undisclosed sum.</p>
<p>Kembla Copper is a joint venture between Japanese copper smelter Furukawa Co Ltd, Nisho Iwai Corp, Itochu Corp and Nittetsu Mining Co Ltd.</p>
<p>As part of the deal Kembla Copper planned to renovate the plant so it could meet pollution regulations and boost production capacity to 120,000 tonnes a year by the second half of 1998 from its previous level of 80,000 tonnes.  </p>
<p>Tim Robertson, acting for Port Kembla resident Helen Hamilton, told the Land and Environment Court the upgrade would result in the smelter becoming the largest emitter of lead and sulphur dioxide pollution in the state.</p>
<p>Kembla Copper's lawyer Bret Walker applied to have the hearing adjourned until the fate of Knowles' bill was known. Justice Neal Bignold later agreed to adjourn until June 30.</p>
<p>The Environmental Planning and Assessment Amendment Bill passed the lower house on Thursday after receiving a second reading on Wednesday night.  </p>
<p>Knowles said it would give the Land and Environment Court power to issue remedies on technical breaches instead of invalidating entire projects.</p>
<p>&quot;Legal challenges on technicalities have been used to delay and frustrate environmentlally sound development, creating uncertainty for potential investors,&quot; Knowles said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is currently A$1.7 billion worth of investment being assessed in NSW, with the potential to create 2,000 jobs. Development proposals for another A$365 million generating more than 1,888 jobs are expected over the next six months,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
