<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="624767" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia may ease media rules-Howard.</title>
<headline>Australia may ease media rules-Howard.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard on Thursday confirmed the government was looking at allowing television proprietors to own one newspaper each in major capital city markets.</p>
<p>&quot;A whole lot of things including that is being looked at, a whole lot of things,&quot; Howard told radio 2UE.</p>
<p>Newspapers reported on Thursday that the Liberal-National government, reviewing media ownership laws, was planning to ease cross-ownership and foreign ownership laws.</p>
<p>Currently, television owners are banned from owning more than 15 percent of a newspaper in the same major market and vice versa.</p>
<p>Foreigners are limited to 15 percent of television stations and 25 percent of newspapers. But reports on Thursday said the government planned to raise foreign limits, possibly to 35 percent industry-wide.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the reports in the paper this morning were hairy, but others were a little closer to the mark in terms of options,&quot; Howard said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is still something that is being talked through and being talked through very carefully.&quot;</p>
<p>The government ordered a closed review of ownership limits after winning power in March, 1996.</p>
<p>Most papers said the easing of cross media rules would allow Kerry Packer, who owns the national Nine Network television group, to fulfill his family's long time ambition to take control of the John Fairfax Holdings Ltd newspaper group.</p>
<p>But the rule changes, the papers said, would probably mean that Packer would have to sell the Fairfax business daily, The Australian Financial Review. Executives from Pearson Plc and The Economist magazine have held talks with the government in recent weeks and are believed to be keen potential buyers of the business daily.</p>
<p>The break-up or sale of Fairfax is opposed by its largest shareholder, Brierley Investments Ltd of New Zealand, which has a 20 percent stake and has publicly said it wants more. Brierley acquired its stake from Canadian and U.K. publisher Conrad Black who bailed out due to frustration at the government's failure to resolve its media policy.</p>
<p>The rule changes would also allow Rupert Murdoch to increase his stake in the Seven Network Ltd whose national operations are the second largest behind Packer's Nine Network.</p>
<p>Murdoch's News Corp Ltd currently has a 15 percent stake in Seven and has also discussed media rule changes recently with the government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
