<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="624704" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Siebe shares up as profits break forecasts.</title>
<headline>Siebe shares up as profits break forecasts.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in British engineering group Siebe Plc rose 3p to 951-1/2p on Thursday, with many market-makers puzzled by the muted reaction after the company reported a larger than expected increase in its full year profits.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm surprised the price isn't better is my initial reaction. It's a strong pbt (profit before tax) figure and the dividend is good. I suppose there are still some worries about the currency with 90 percent of its business overseas,&quot; said a market maker.</p>
<p>Siebe executives were due to present the figures to analysts at 0800 GMT and traders said the stock was likely to remain on hold until research teams got back to their desks.</p>
<p>&quot;We like the figures which are much better than expected, and supported by an up tempo statement. In fact as a house we have moved from a hold to a buy,&quot; said one market maker.</p>
<p>&quot;It maybe that there is a bit of stock in the market to be absorbed and we are waiting for the analysts to get back from the meeting,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The company posted a 28.1 percent rise in pretax profits to 424.1 million for the year to April 5, 1997 as against the highest expected by analysts of 422.1 million.</p>
<p>In a statement, the group said it sees no signs of recession in any of its main markets and is &quot;very confident of continuing the underlying growth in Siebe's business operations.&quot;</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
