<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="625308" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: PRESS DIGEST - Norway - May 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Norway - May 29.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in Norwegian newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>AFTENPOSTEN</p>
<p>-The public prosecutor of Nordland county, Geir Fornebo, has given up hope of having anti-whaling activist Paul Watson extradited from the Netherlands. Watson, leader of the Sea Shepherd anti-whaling group, has been sentenced in his absence to 120 days in prison for sinking a Norwegian whaling boat in 1992. But he has been in custody in a Dutch jail since April 3 and has soon in effect served his sentence while his extradition order is being considered by the Netherlands.</p>
<p>-Airlines accuse travel agencies of selling jackpot and other cheap-fare tickets beyond the deadline for such sales, leading to losses for the carriers.</p>
<p>-Most members of parliament are in favour of investing billions of crowns of wealth accumulated in the State Petroleum Fund in overseas stock markets and not just in overseas bonds.</p>
<p>-Nice summer weather is expected in southern Norway in the next few days after weeks of rain, but next week the weather is expected to get colder again.</p>
<p>-While some people wish to avoid the taxman, citizens in Longyear in the remote Arctic archipelago of Spitzbergen want a tax office to be established in their tiny town for the sake of local democracy.</p>
<p>DAGENS NAERINGSLIV</p>
<p>-Branded-goods conglomerate Orkla is increasing its investments in the United States through Holberg Industries, in which Orkla controls 33 percent.</p>
<p>-Norway and the EU commission have apparently agreed on a compromise on the issue of possible European Union anti-dumping duty on imports of Norwegian salmon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
