<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="625485" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - Quality Food sees expansion.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Quality Food sees expansion.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Quality Food Inc would like to double the number of stores it operates in the Los Angeles area in the &quot;not too distant&quot; future, a company executive said Friday.</p>
<p>At the same, the grocery store company plans to continue expanding in its Pacific Northwest base and to seek new acquisitions elsewhere in the country, Marc Evanger, senior vice president, said in an interview.  </p>
<p>Evanger, formerly chief financial officer, was named to run the company's Northwest operations along with Mike Huse, both of whom will be senior vice presidents.</p>
<p>Evanger said his top priority would be to expand into the Portland, Oregon, area, where the company is building its first two stores to open in early 1998 and hopes to have 10 to 15 stores open within a few years.</p>
<p>The vast majority of the company's stores in the Pacific Northwest are in the Seattle area, where it is the second-biggest operator behind Safeway, and it sees more room for growth.  </p>
<p>&quot;Clearly, expanding the ring around the Seattle area is a big part of our future growth,&quot; Evanger said.</p>
<p>The company took a step in that direction earlier this year by acquiring the 25 stores operated by regional rival Keith Uddenberg Inc. for $65 million.</p>
<p>And last month, the company acquired Hughes Family Markets in Irwindale, Calif., with its 57 stores in the Los Angeles area, triggering Friday's management changes.  </p>
<p>Dan Kourkoumelis, who had been president and chief executive officer of the company's Quality Food Centers Inc. operating division, will move to California and take the same titles at Hughes.</p>
<p>Evanger said Kourkoumelis' goal will be to improve profit margins at the California chain, which are only about half those achieved in the Washington state stores, mainly due to &quot;underdeveloped&quot; deli and bakery departments.</p>
<p>He said expansion opportunities were huge in California, noting that some 18 million people live in the the Los Angeles area, compared with about four million in western Washington and Portland.</p>
<p>&quot;I could easily see doubling their number of locations as a not too distant goal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the goal could be achieved through both acquisitions of independent grocery store companies and through new store development.</p>
<p>Evanger said Kourkoumelis would remain in California for at least two years to oversee integration of the chain. His position in Washington state will be left open as the company continues &quot;building the bench for future acquisitions,&quot; Evanger said.</p>
<p>((-- Reuters Seattle bureau 206-386-4848))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
