<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="625432" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Congress set to vote on bolstering Cuba law.</title>
<headline>U.S. Congress set to vote on bolstering Cuba law.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The House of Representatives is scheduled to vote next week on amendments designed to bolster the Helms-Burton law, which last year tightened the U.S. embargo against Cuba, congressional aides said on Friday.</p>
<p>The aides said the amendments attached this month to the Foreign Policy Reform Act, a major bill on restructuring of the State Department, are due to come to a vote on the House floor on Tuesday or Wednesday.</p>
<p>The amendments were introduced by Rep. Ileana Ros-Lehtinen, a Cuban-born Florida Republican, and approved in the House International Relations Committee on May 6. The Senate currently has no equivalent amendments to its version of the foreign policy bill, aides said.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton signed the Helms-Burton law last year after Cuban combat pilots shot down two small civilian U.S. aircraft off the island's coast, killing four Miami men. The law sought to punish foreign firms that invest in property seized from U.S. citizens and companies in Cuba after the 1959 revolution that brought President Fidel Castro to power.</p>
<p>Castro, a hardline communist, confiscated thousands of properties from Americans and nationalized the assets of hundreds of thousands of Cubans who fled to the United States.</p>
<p>So far, the U.S. government has only imposed sanctions on a Canadian mining concern and a Mexican industrial group.</p>
<p>The Helms-Burton law drew fire from some of Washington's closest allies and trade partners, such as Canada, Mexico and the European Union. The Europeans even challenged the validity of the law before the World Trade Organization, but this year chose to withdraw their case in order to negotiate a separate agreement with the United States to end their dispute.</p>
<p>One of Ros-Lehtinen's amendments would require the State Department to report every three months to Congress which foreign companies and individuals it is investigating under the Helms-Burton law. Under the State Department's regulations in force, those inquiries are confidential.</p>
<p>Another amendment would restrict U.S. aid to Russia unless Clinton certifies that the Russian government is not giving Cuba technical or financial help to build a nuclear plant. The third would deny U.S. aid to any country that engages in subsidized trade with Cuba.</p>
<p>The Cuban government, which has endured U.S. embargos and sanctions almost since Castro came to power, has denounced the amendments charging that Washington was not complying with its commitment with the European Union on the Helms-Burton law.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
