<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="625458" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. unveil plans for plane crash center.</title>
<headline>U.S. unveil plans for plane crash center.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) said on Friday it was planning to set up an operations center for airline disaster information that would help families of crash victims.</p>
<p>The center in New York City -- an outcome of the aftermath of last year's TWA Flight 800 disaster -- would work to quickly identify passengers in plane crashes in North America, NTSB chairman Jim Hall said.</p>
<p>It would also provide hotel and travel assistance, translation services and access to clergy and mental health counselors for victims' families.</p>
<p>The plan was unveiled at City Hall in the presence of Mayor Rudolph Giuliani, a harsh critic of authorities' treatment of the relatives of the passengers killed aboard TWA Flight 800 last July.</p>
<p>All 230 people aboard the Boeing 747 bound for Paris died when the plane crashed off Long Island. It took more than two weeks to retrieve all of the victims' bodies, largely because of bad weather.</p>
<p>&quot;Loved ones should never be treated in such a fashion again,&quot; said Giuliani. &quot;This center is a large step toward ensuring information and support flows to families.&quot;</p>
<p>The center will be activated within 25 minutes of a crash, Hall said.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the most important duties an airline has is to promptly and compassionately notify the victims' families,&quot; he added. &quot;While many large airlines are up to this task, there are a number of small and foreign carriers ... that may became overwhelmed.&quot;</p>
<p>Hall did not say when the new center would open.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
