<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="625470" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Shalala proposes US Medicare hospital payment freeze.</title>
<headline>Shalala proposes US Medicare hospital payment freeze.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Clinton administration proposed Friday no increases in payments to hospitals next year in the Medicare program for the elderly, to help meet the goal of balancing the federal budget.</p>
<p>Health and Human Services Secretary Donna Shalala recommended that hospitals receive no increase in Medicare payments in fiscal 1998, a statement from her agency said.</p>
<p>Congressional action would be required to implement the recommendation or a 2.8 percent increase in Medicare payment rates would go into effect Oct. 1 due to the current law, the agency said.</p>
<p>The balanced budget agreement was approved by the Senate and House last week after being put together by congressional leaders and President Clinton. It calls for cutting projected Medicare spending by $115 billion over five years.</p>
<p>About $100 billion of the proposed Medicare cuts will come from reducing federal payments to doctors, hospitals and other health care providers. Also, the 38 million senior citizens enrolled in Medicare will face higher monthly premiums.</p>
<p>&quot;Medicare must become an increasingly prudent purchaser of health care services, and those who provide services to Medicare beneficiaries must do their fair share toward a balanced federal budget by increasing their efficiency and effectiveness,&quot; Shalala said in the statement.</p>
<p>Medicare pays short-stay, acute-care hospitals a predetermined rate for inpatient hospital services for beneficiaries of the federal program for the elderly.</p>
<p>There are 5,200 short-stay, acute care hospitals participating in Medicare and the program paid $81.9 billion to inpatient hospitals in fiscal 1996, the agency said.</p>
<p>Even with no increase in the Medicare payment for a hospital procedure, hospital payments were expected to grow by 6.4 percent to $91.2 billion in fiscal 1998 from $85.7 billion in 1997 due to more patients and procedures, the agency said.</p>
<p>Changes in delivery of hospital inpatient care contributed to Shalala's recommendation, according to a letter she sent to Vice President Al Gore.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on the recent changes in delivery of hospital inpatient care, with an increasing reliance on hospital outpatient and postacute care services and a corresponding decrease in use of hospital inpatient services, we recommend an update for hospitals in both large urban and other areas of zero percent,&quot; she wrote.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
