<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="625610" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TransTexas sells Lobo unit for over $1 bln.</title>
<headline>TransTexas sells Lobo unit for over $1 bln.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>TransTexas Gas Corp said Friday it had completed the sale of TransTexas Transmission Corp to First Intercontinental Leasing Trust for net proceeds in excess of one billion dollars cash, after closing adjustments for interim production.</p>
<p>The trust advised TransTexas it is selling and/or leasing substantially all of the TransTexas Transmission assets to DuPont Co's Conoco Inc.</p>
<p>TransTexas Transmission's assets include the company's Lobo Trend natural gas producing properties and a 1,100 mile South Texas natural gas pipeline system, TransTexas Gas said.  </p>
<p>First Intercontinental Leasing Trust is a consortium of leasing and finance companies managed by GATX Corp's GATX Capital Corp.</p>
<p>TransTexas President Arnold Brackenridge said, &quot;We're very pleased to announce ... this sale at a very attractive 'in the ground' price. Included in the sale are proved natural gas reserves of 550 billion cubic feet equivalent and the pipeline system.  </p>
<p>&quot;This is a key agreement ... that will significantly reduce our net debt.  It will de-leverage our balance sheet and allow us to focus on the expansion of our development areas such as Bob West North, Fandango South and Lodgepole and accelerate the development pace in other discoveries.&quot;</p>
<p>Terms of the agreement allow TransTexas to use the sold pipeline system to transport its ongoing Bob West North natural gas production in South Texas to a gas processing plant or to the Agua Dulce marketing hub, the company said.</p>
<p>The agreement also contemplates that TransTexas' drilling services division will continue to provide services to the operator of the Lobo Trend properties for an undisclosed period, for additional consideration.</p>
<p>After giving effect to the sale, TransTexas said, it has proved reserves of about 400 billion cubic feet equivalent.</p>
<p>In its fourth quarter, ended January 31, 1997, the company's operations in areas outside of the Lobo Trend generated more than half of its natural gas and oil production and total cashflow.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I84804">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8480401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
