<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="625760" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-NEWCASTLE SIGN BLACKBURN GOALKEEPER GIVEN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-NEWCASTLE SIGN BLACKBURN GOALKEEPER GIVEN.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Newcastle United signed Blackburn Rovers goalkeeper Shay Given on Friday and will now test whether they have to pay their English premier league rivals a transfer fee.</p>
<p>Ireland international Given has accepted a four-year deal. His contract with Blackburn expires at the end of June.</p>
<p>An independent tribunal will settle the transfer fee as the two clubs failed to agree on a sum.</p>
<p>Newcastle plan to seek clarification on payment for out of contract players involved in domestic transfers.</p>
<p>&quot;Following the European Court of Justice ruling in the Bosman case, the requirement for the payment of a compensation fee at the end of a player's contract may be unlawful where the player moves between two British clubs,&quot; Newcastle said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;NUFC proposes to raise this issue before the independent tribunal,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>In a ruling in December 1995, the European Court of Justice upheld the right of players to move to other clubs within the European Union on free transfers once their contracts expire.</p>
<p>The legal implications for transfers between two British clubs have yet to be fully established.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
