<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="62596" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Soaring UK retail slam door on rate cut hopes.</title>
<headline>Soaring UK retail slam door on rate cut hopes.</headline>
<byline>Michael Peacock</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Soaring UK retail sales in August suggest hopes of interest rate cuts have disappeared over the horizon and monetary policy may now be too loose, economists said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But few expected interest rates to be tightened in the foreseeable future even though Bank of England Governor Eddie George said at the July 30 monetary meeting that he would prefer to see official interest rates at 6.00 percent, not 5.75.</p>
<p>&quot;The sales figures were pretty punchy and momentum will increase,&quot; said Kevin Gardiner, UK economist at Morgan Stanley.  </p>
<p>&quot;George is calling for a rate rise but I think he has got the big figure wrong.&quot;</p>
<p>UK retail sales rose a robust 1.0 percent in August, giving year-on-year growth of 4.4 percent, up from 2.4 in July.</p>
<p>On a three-monthly basis sales were up 1.6 percent, the largest increase since August 1988.</p>
<p>Gardiner said those sort of figures suggested rates should head higher. But unlike George, who called for a quarter-point rate rise at his July 30 monetary meeting with Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke, he thinks a more substantial hike may be necessary.  </p>
<p>Gardiner said Wednesday's sales numbers should be viewed in conjunction with evidence pointing to a buoyant housing market recovery and spiralling growth in credit and lending.</p>
<p>Furthermore, survey evidence from the Confederation of British Industry and British Retail Consortium has suggested for some while that consumer spending has been stronger than official sales figures have reflected.</p>
<p>In July, retail sales fell 0.6 percent, according to official data.</p>
<p>&quot;The simplest story is the correct one. Sales are buoyant,&quot; Gardiner said.  </p>
<p>Jonathan Loynes, UK economist at HSBC Markets, still holds out hope of another interest rate cut -- but not before the budget.</p>
<p>&quot;These (sales) data confirm that the trend in high street activity is still firmly upward,&quot; he said. &quot;Coupled with the slightly disappointing retail prices...they should ensure base rates are left on hold at next week's meeting.&quot;</p>
<p>UK underlying retail price inflation held stubbornly steady at 2.8 percent year-on-year in August, for the fourth month in a row. Clarke and George meet to discuss monetary policy again next Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Looking at the breakdown of the sales figures, Loynes said there was strength in all the key high street sectors.</p>
<p>Textiles, clothing and footwear sales were up 2.2 percent, while household goods sales rose 3.4 percent. &quot;They are clearly benefitting from the housing market recovery,&quot; Loynes said.</p>
<p>For those who still wonder if a 0.6 percent fall in sales in July offset by a 1.0 percent rise the next month represents a solid trend, a string of financial results from UK corporate retailers this week shows buoyant trading conditions.</p>
<p>Supermarket group Tesco Plc reported a 10.7 percent increase in first half pre-tax profits to 321 million stg.  </p>
<p>Clothes retailer Next Plc's six month profits rose six million to 56 million and the John Lewis Partnership said sales for the last six weeks were up 17.3 percent year-on-year.</p>
<p>But even an unequivocal picture of sales strength may not tip Clarke's hand. With his Conservative government lagging the Labour Party in the polls and desperate to lure back disaffected voters, a rate rise would be seen as political poison.</p>
<p>David Coleman, chief economist at CIBC Wood Gundy, said the markets would be sceptical of Clarke's stance on monetary policy ahead of the election. &quot;The tactics now seem clear -- to hold out against a rise in interest rates as long as possible.&quot;</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
