<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="625979" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent ends narrowly weaker, lacking momentum.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent ends narrowly weaker, lacking momentum.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE Brent crude closed narrowly weaker on Friday, sagging within a slim range in thin volumes amid a lack of fresh fundamental direction, dealers said.</p>
<p>July Brent crude ended 10 cents weaker at $19.38 a barrel, near the middle of the session's 21-cent range after briefly breaking below support at $19.30.</p>
<p>&quot;Brent did break down to $19.25 but there was nothing behind the move and it soon bounced back into range,&quot; said a broker.</p>
<p>In the absence of new fundamental developments to provide fresh momentum, the tone remained cautious after Tuesday's slide and inconclusive U.S. inventory data released earlier this week.</p>
<p>Even the expiry of NYMEX June product contracts, which left unleaded gasoline over a cent a gallon weaker and heating oil nearly 0.50 cents firmer generated only limited volatility, brokers said.</p>
<p>Earlier, IPE gas oil $1.75 lower at $172.50 a tonne, slipping further behind the July contract which finished at $173.50.</p>
<p>Traders said the wider prompt contango reflected softer sentiment on European spot markets, where diesel was reported to be in ample supply and several players absent from the key German market. -- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7930</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
