<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="626041" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Ofgas lets Transco recover 28 mln stg charges.</title>
<headline>UK's Ofgas lets Transco recover 28 mln stg charges.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>UK gas industry regulator Ofgas has given permission to pipeline operator Transco, part of BG plc, to recover 28 million stg which Transco spent on storing gas in the winter of 1995/1996.</p>
<p>Transco stored the gas, known as Balancing Margins, in order to maintain a supply cushion in case gas in the pipeline system became short over the winter. The Network Code, governing use of the pipeline system and setting out commercial relations between Transco and the shippers who used it, had been due to start in October 1995.</p>
<p>Transco felt that because of these new commercial arrangements, there was a chance that the system would go short and so arranged to keep 58 million stg in the form of Balancing Margins.</p>
<p>This was enough to allow for a complete collapse of the flexibility mechanism, the market instrument enabling shippers and Transco to balance their gas portfolios on a daily basis.</p>
<p>But the start-up of the Network Code was delayed until the following march, so Transco ended up with far more Balancing Margins gas than was needed.</p>
<p>In October 1995, Ofgas had decided that 30 million stg was an appropriate level, but Transco kept the full volume in reserve. It later asked to be allowed to recover the extra 28 million stg.</p>
<p>Ofgas concluded that Transco's consultation procedure for booking Balancing Margins were inadequate, but added: &quot;We are satisfied that the amount of Balancing Margins booked for that winter did not exceed the requirement for that winter&quot;.</p>
<p>Ofgas said that it was possible that Transco overused Balancing Margins during the winter in order to justify its own actions in booking them, but &quot;it is difficult to establish whether this happened and in the absence of clear evidence we consider it appropriate to give Transco the benefit of the doubt.&quot;</p>
<p>Transco will now be able to recover the outstanding 28 million stg through transportation charges, an Ofgas spokesman said.</p>
<p>-- Sebastian Alison, London Newsroom, +44 171 542 6412</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
