<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="626078" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dated Brent offers fall as slide maintains momentum.</title>
<headline>Dated Brent offers fall as slide maintains momentum.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dated Brent's week-long slide looked set to continue into Friday with a cargo on offer below the last deal done.</p>
<p>A European major was touting a Brent loading June 12-14 at July Brent -25 cents, after another cargo changed hands on Thursday at July -24 cents.</p>
<p>Thursday's deal was nearly 30 cents off the last reported deal, and over 40 cents off what may traders regarded as an artificial high traded late last week.</p>
<p>Dealers said that underlying fundamentals were sloppy with only an opening of the trans-Atlantic arbitrage likely to break wet Brent's fall.</p>
<p>&quot;There are at least two or three players offering Brent out there, and probably less buying interest than sellers believe,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The heavy drop in Dated Brent values on Thursday encouraged traders to look for buyers on the other side of the Atlantic.</p>
<p>Brent was offered on the Gulf Coast five cents lower on Thursday at 70 cents under West Texas Intermediate/Cushing for July delivery.</p>
<p>&quot;If the arb opened up again that would offer us a bit of a floor,&quot; said one North Sea trader.</p>
<p>Two Brents loading June 13-15 which were left unclaimed from the paper chains on Thursday were deferred and were passing through the chains on Friday with another three cargoes from the original programme. All were now due to load in the June 14-18 window.</p>
<p>On the paper market, Brent CFDs and intermonth spreads were a touch weaker. A CFD for next week was heard traded at August Brent -44 cents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
