<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="626299" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Embattled Czech PM Klaus says ready to fight on.</title>
<headline>Embattled Czech PM Klaus says ready to fight on.</headline>
<byline>John Mastrini</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus, whose government has been under severe pressure over its handling of the economy, said on Friday he would remain in his post to fight for his coalition's economic recovery programme.</p>
<p>Answering growing calls for his resignation and a possible parliamentary vote of no confidence, Klaus said that he would take his fight to the floor of parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;I am resolutely repeating that I am ready to take on the political fight over these steps to the floor of parliament, and that I am not ready to run away from the fight,&quot; Klaus said, reading a statement which was not followed by questions.</p>
<p>The Czech crown has been under intense pressure sparked by an economic downturn, forcing the central bank from Tuesday to float the currency.</p>
<p>The ruling three-party coalition led by Klaus announced an emergency austerity package on Wednesday along with a sweeping cabinet reshuffle, aiming to stabilise the currency.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's currency situation, and consequently the whole economic situation, has a solution. It requires an energetic and consistent stance and I am ready to proceed this way,&quot; Klaus said in the statement.</p>
<p>Earlier on Friday, opposition leader Milos Zeman of the Social Democrats said his party would seek a vote of no confidence in the centre-right government in a parliamentary session beginning on July 1, because the austerity package marked a major change in government policy.</p>
<p>&quot;The government diverted in a major way from its (original) programme declaration,&quot; Zeman, who is also chairman of the lower house, told a news conference.</p>
<p>The Czech crown lost roughly two percent of its value against the mark and dollar less than an hour after Zeman's announcement, but regained the lost ground after Klaus's statement.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a short-term positive that Klaus is not resigning, but the medium term problems are still there,&quot; said Matt Starr, head of capital markets at Creditanstalt in Prague.</p>
<p>Klaus also said that Interior Minister designate Petr Necas, nominated in the reshuffle earlier this week, had withdrawn his candidacy and that President Vaclav Havel had rejected the resignation of Interior Minister Jan Ruml. Ruml accepted the decision, Klaus said.</p>
<p>Klaus's three-party coalition, which holds 100 seats in the 200-seat lower house, agreed Wednesday to budget cuts, public sector wage freezes, and other measures while acknowledging mistakes were made in economic policy.</p>
<p>The finance, industry and trade, education and interior ministers were changed as part of the Wednesday shakeup.</p>
<p>Ivan Pilip, part of Klaus's inner circle, was named to replace Ivan Kocarnik as finance minister, whom many Czechs blamed for the economic problems.</p>
<p>Zeman said the vote of no confidence, which would be put to the lower house session beginning on July 1, was not aimed at forcing early elections but &quot;a real reconstruction, not comic swaps of portfolios.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;What more mistakes must this government make for it to leave voluntarily,&quot; Zeman told reporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
