<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="626371" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary radio tenders final despite price protests.</title>
<headline>Hungary radio tenders final despite price protests.</headline>
<byline>Denes Albert</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's radio and television body ORTT on Friday drafted the tender for seven-year concessions for two nationwide radio channels and rejected criticism that the asking price was too high.</p>
<p>&quot;In the present business climate we think this asking price is reasonable,&quot; ORTT spokesman Gyorgy Lovas told Reuters. &quot;It is natural that bidders would want to push the asking price down&quot;.</p>
<p>The price for each channel concession has been set at three billion forints plus 25 percent VAT, with 30 percent payable in advance and the rest in four annual installments beginning with the third year of the concession.</p>
<p>Several potential bidders have said that such terms could jeopardise profitability.</p>
<p>&quot;The initial price certainly looks to be high,&quot; said Charlie Cox, managing director of the UK's DMG Radio Ltd, part of Mirror Group Plc .</p>
<p>&quot;We do not want to end up with a poisoned chalice.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S.'s Metromedia International Group Inc, owner of Hungarian commercial radio station Juventus earlier described the price as the highest in the world and disproportionate with the equivalent fee for commercial televison licences.</p>
<p>Hungary's media law, passed in December 1995 after four years of bitter political dispute, opened the way for the privatisation of the country's state-controlled national television and radio market.</p>
<p>Media analysis company Mediagnozis said Hungary last year spent 6.3 billion ($34.5 million) on radio advertising, compared with 4.17 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>Two radio channels are on offer and bids can be submitted after the tender is published, probably around June 10.</p>
<p>Lovas said ORTT expects five to 12 bidders, but other sources indicated the price might scare away some of the foreign companies that have shown an early interest.</p>
<p>However, with tender rules different from the ones set up for the television tenders, where the price only accounts for fourty percent of the criteria, in case of the radio concessions the highest bid is almost certain to secure a win.</p>
<p>&quot;The amount offered would account for a possible 850 points with other judgement criteria making up for 150 points of the total 1,000-point tender evaluation,&quot; Lovas said.</p>
<p>Some bidders said that the two FM channels on offer are not of the same value and most of them regard Danubius, Hungary's oldest commercial station, as their prime target.</p>
<p>Danubius reaches 67 percent of Hungary's 10.5 million people while the other, as yet unused channel could be available to 81 percent of the population once the broadcasting infrastructure is in place.</p>
<p>The radio and television tenders have suffered several delays so far but ORTT said it will meet the latest deadlines.</p>
<p>The winners are supposed to be announced two months after the September 10 bidding deadline and will have a maximum ninety days to go on air but media sources say some of them already have everything in place for an early start.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
