<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="626465" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: FEATURE - Serb returns home after 21 months living in wild.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Serb returns home after 21 months living in wild.</headline>
<byline>Zoran Radosavljevic</byline>
<dateline>ORAOVAC, Croatia 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mirko Djakovic is back in his house after spending almost two years hiding in the woods above his village since its recapture by Croatian troops.</p>
<p>He is one of the few Serbs who returned to Oraovac, which lies in a former rebel Serb enclave of Croatia. His house has no electricity or running water but he does not seem to care.</p>
<p>&quot;Now I just want my wife to return. A home without a wife is not a home.&quot; he told Reuters, sitting in his living room, crammed with used clothes and electrical appliances.</p>
<p>Djakovic, 54, spent 633 days in the hills like a modern-day Robinson Crusoe, avoiding the Croatian army and police who retook the village in mid-1995.</p>
<p>&quot;On August 5 my whole village fled as Croatian troops were approaching. I didn't want to go with them because my wife is Moslem and they've always given us a hard time for that,&quot; he told Reuters in his house, surrounded by green hills and trees.</p>
<p>&quot;I went to the woods with my wife and grandson the next day, while warplanes were flying overhead and several shells hit the village.&quot;</p>
<p>He took with him some food, a tool kit, blankets and a machine gun he had never used before.</p>
<p>His wife took the child and surrendered to the police after a few days and they were sent to her home town of Bihac in northeast Bosnia. &quot;I was all alone with my sheep dog,&quot; said Djakovic.</p>
<p>After months of struggling against the elements the former TV mechanic heard in January on his makeshift radio that Croatia had agreed to amnesty all Serbs who took part in the 1991-95 rebellion.</p>
<p>&quot;In February this year, when winter started receding, I began mental preparations to go down, but bad weather held me in the woods until April. Then I shaved, put on my best suit and walked straight into the police station.&quot;</p>
<p>DJAKOVIC GLAD HE DIDN'T FLEE CROATIA</p>
<p>He was sunburnt and had lost 30 kg (67 lbs). Small wonder, considering he had eaten his last portion of meat six months earlier. &quot;In October (1996) I caught four hedgehogs and ate them. That was the last meat I had until I returned here.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;When I came in and said  'Hi, I've come to surrender, I've been in the woods all this time' the policemen wouldn't believe me,&quot; Djakovic said with a smile.</p>
<p>They found his name on the missing persons' list and the next day he was taken to a court in the coastal city of Zadar where a judge said he was amnestied in line with the law.</p>
<p>&quot;When they told me I was free to go home I wept with joy. My police escort, they were Croatians, drove me home in their car and stopped at every bar and restaurant on our way to treat me to some food or drink. They were really great to me.&quot;</p>
<p>Djakovic is glad he did not join his fellow villagers who fled to Bosnia or Serbia in 1995. Up to 200,000 Serbs fled the former Krajina enclave ahead of Croatian troops. &quot;This is where I belong. I don't want to live anywhere else&quot;.</p>
<p>His experiences contrasted with allegations by The United States and the United Nations that Croatia has not done enough to help Serbs return and to guarantee their safety.</p>
<p>DJAKOVIC DREAMT OF EATING IN BEST RESTAURANTS</p>
<p>The precarious condition of returning Serbs was underscored by a number of recent incidents, when elderly people were harassed and evicted from their houses by Croatian refugees unable to return to their own homes.</p>
<p>Djakovic said nothing of the kind occurred in his village where about 35, mostly elderly, Serbs have returned. &quot;No one has had any problems, or rather, we all have the same problem -- how to make the village live again.&quot;</p>
<p>While sitting idly in the house, waiting for his new Croatian documents, he often recalls his life in the woods.</p>
<p>&quot;After the first month I was almost dead of thirst and hunger. Then I said to myself that I was going to survive.&quot;</p>
<p>At night he started going down to the village, patrolled by Croatian troops, to get water, nails, wire and anything else he could find, mostly books.</p>
<p>&quot;The books saved me. I read over 1,000 while I was up there -- fiction, encyclopaedias, popular science, travelogues, so I as good as travelled around the world.&quot;</p>
<p>The next thing he did was make a bow and arrow to hunt sheep roaming on the slopes. &quot;I couldn't fire the gun for fear of being heard by the troops.&quot;</p>
<p>However, his first chance to get fresh meat was spoiled by his dog, whose barking scared away a grazing sheep.</p>
<p>&quot;The next time I knew better and tied the dog to a tree...I roasted the lamb and feasted on it for four days,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His nightly visits to the village produced a stove and a knife. He built a hut in the woods some three km (two miles) from his house and started preparing for a harsh winter.</p>
<p>&quot;I killed a huge pig in the village and carried it on my back all the way to the hut, where I carved it up and dried it.&quot; He also gathered some cabbage and potatoes from nearby unattended fields.</p>
<p>But his dearest achievement, he says with a grin, was a makeshift brandy distillery, composed from a pressure pot and a metal tube. &quot;It produced just about enough brandy for me.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;You know when I think back on it, I had some kind of peace and comfort up there. I would lie on my 'bed', read a book, sip at my brandy and smoke dried tobacco and herb leaves.&quot;</p>
<p>In winter he gnawed at his supplies. In spring he ran out of meat. &quot;So I started labouring the fields at night, sowing beans and potatoes. I also learned how to bake bread.&quot;</p>
<p>Meat became scant and his diet was reduced to basic vegetables and bread. &quot;I dreamt of eating in the best restaurants for months,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Medicinal herbs and wild honey kept him healthy throughout the event, which he refuses to call an ordeal. &quot;I just assimilated with nature and did what every animal is capable of&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ORAOVAC, Croatia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
