<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="626638" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia court finds reporter guilty of contempt.</title>
<headline>Malaysia court finds reporter guilty of contempt.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Malaysian High Court on Friday found a foreign journalist guilty of contempt of court over an article he wrote concerning a mother's lawsuit against her son's international school.</p>
<p>Murray Hiebert, 47, the Malaysian bureau chief for the Far Eastern Economic Review, was ordered by the court to surrender his passport and bail was fixed at 100,000 ringgit ($39,840).</p>
<p>The court said it will announce on July 14 what damages it would award in the civil suit, filed by the mother described in the article.</p>
<p>Witnesses said Hiebert appeared stunned by the verdict and was put in a police lock-up for three hours while his associates scrambled to come up with his bail money and passport.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm disappointed by the court verdict and will be discussing with our counsel what our next steps will be,&quot; Hiebert told Reuters.</p>
<p>The suit stemmed from an article Hiebert wrote on January 23 about a lawsuit brought by the mother of a 17-year-old high school student against the International School of Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>The mother, Chandra Sri Ram, was suing the school for dropping her son Govind from the debate team.</p>
<p>The suit was settled on March 10 after the school agreed to apologise openly in court.</p>
<p>Chandra said in her suit against Hiebert that his article entitled &quot;See You in Court&quot; amounted to an attack on the Malaysian judiciary.</p>
<p>The suit referred to a passage in the article, in which Hiebert noted that Govind was the son of Court of Appeals Judge, Gopal Sri Ram, and that the case appeared to have sped through Malaysia's judiciary.</p>
<p>The editor of the Far Eastern Economic Review in Hong Kong was not immediately available to comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
