<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="626656" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian markets firm in post-election relief.</title>
<headline>Indonesian markets firm in post-election relief.</headline>
<byline>Raju Gopalakrishnan</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian financial markets firmed on Friday, reflecting relief that general elections were relatively peaceful and the ruling Golkar party was heading for a forecast landslide victory, analysts said.</p>
<p>Equities analysts said foreign funds had entered the Jakarta stock market in a big way following the post-election wave of optimism and Thursday's 2.53 percent surge in the composite index.</p>
<p>The index closed up 0.95 percent on Friday at 696.03 points, with large gains coming in the afternoon as foreign investors bought up blue chips, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has reacted very positively to the election results,&quot; said William Keeling at Mashill Securities, a brokerage associated with Kleinwort Benson.</p>
<p>&quot;Yesterday's reaction, which was a much larger one, was principally local retail investors trying to get in ahead of foreign investors,&quot; he said. &quot;It was only in the second session today that we saw foreign investors actively buying the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Thursday's elections passed off relatively peacefully although violence erupted in the troubled territory of East Timor and in Aceh on Sumatra island. Analysts noted both areas were violence-prone and unrest there had little effect on markets.</p>
<p>Also cheering investors was Golkar's surge towards what could be its largest-ever share of the vote. With over 100 million votes counted from a potential 125 million, Golkar had a 73.61 percent share, up from 68 percent at the last elections in 1992.</p>
<p>Analysts said markets had seen the vote as reflecting continued stability in the country, belying bouts of nervousness during the four-week campaign which was marked by some of the worst political violence in the country for three decades.</p>
<p>The rupiah firmed some six points to 2,434.40/35.25 against the dollar by the close in Jakarta from a 2,441/43 open.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like confidence is back in the market,&quot; said a currency trader at a U.S. bank in Jakarta. &quot;Since investors read that Golkar is heading for a win, we saw some (dollar) selling outright from investors and local banks here at 2,440.&quot;</p>
<p>Other traders said the selling represented the unwinding of long dollar positions established during the campaign and reflected optimism that the rupiah would strengthen over the medium term.</p>
<p>They said anything between a 70 percent and a 75 percent win for Golkar in the elections would be positive for the rupiah.</p>
<p>But some traders advocated caution.</p>
<p>&quot;On the surface, things look very good, the government increased its share of the vote substantially,&quot; said Desmond Supple, an exotics specialist at BZW Barclays in Singapore. &quot;My concern is if you get a lot of protest votes in the form of spoiled ballots then any attempt by the government to trumpet the strength or popularity of the success of its policies could create a lot of tensions.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It's probably more safe to hold back until a more complete picture of the situation and the popular reaction to the results emerges,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Equities traders pointed to a brief spell of profit-taking on the stock market at midsession after news of clashes on the island of Madura where residents were angered by the margin of the Golkar victory there and alleged vote fraud.</p>
<p>But the nervousness soon passed, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
