<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="626655" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan's JAL lands in the red despite cost-cutting.</title>
<headline>Japan's JAL lands in the red despite cost-cutting.</headline>
<byline>Ayumi Moriyama</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's top international carrier Japan Airlines Co Ltd veered into the red last fiscal year but vowed on Friday to pull out of the dive by cutting costs and boosting efficiency.</p>
<p>Hit by high fuel costs and stiff competition, JAL posted a parent current loss of 16.97 billion yen ($146 million) for the year that ended on March 31, following a parent current profit of 4.40 billion yen ($37.9 million) a year earlier.</p>
<p>Parent current profit is pre-tax and includes gains and losses from investments.</p>
<p>JAL's 1996/97 operating profit was a meagre 4.56 billion yen ($39.3 million), down 70.4 percent from the previous year's 15.40 billion yen ($132 million).</p>
<p>The company has worked hard to cut costs, but soaring fuel prices and a fall in the value of the yen have pushed up overall costs, JAL said in a statement.</p>
<p>Lower fares due to increasingly intense competition with foreign airlines made it difficult for Japanese international carriers to boost profits, and the weak yen lowered the number of Japanese travelling abroad, industry analysts said.</p>
<p>JAL expects business to remain tough but predicted a parent current profit of one billion yen ($8.6 million) for the current business year that started on April 1.</p>
<p>The company said the future strength of the Japanese economy remained uncertain, and the air travel market would grow even more competitive.</p>
<p>&quot;We will try to improve our business as soon as possible by implementing even more drastic cost-cutting measures, improving efficiency and boosting sales,&quot; JAL said.</p>
<p>JAL said it would add new flights to and from Tokyo's Haneda Airport in the domestic sector, and open new Asian routes in its international service.</p>
<p>High fuel costs, the weak yen and stiff competition have also hit Japan's number one domestic carrier All Nippon Airways Co Ltd (ANA), although it has not suffered as severely as JAL.</p>
<p>On Thursday, ANA posted a parent current profit of 17.33 billion yen ($149 million) for 1996/97, up just 2.9 percent from the previous year. ANA's operating profit fell 34 percent from a year earlier to 18.02 billion yen ($155 million).</p>
<p>Japan's third largest airline, Japan Air System Co Ltd (JAS), which mostly operates domestic flights, announced earlier this week that its parent current profit rose 62.2 percent in 1996/97 to 276 million yen ($2.37 million), helped by intensive cost-cutting, such as sales of aircraft.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
