<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="626710" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: India cancels term LPG tender, reappraises needs.</title>
<headline>India cancels term LPG tender, reappraises needs.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>State-owned Indian Oil Corp (IOC) has cancelled a one-year term tender for 540,000 tonnes of liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) and is reappraising its import needs, a source close to the company said on Friday.</p>
<p>IOC had tendered to buy 18 cargoes, each consisting 25,000-tonnes of butane and 5,000-tonnes of propane, between July 1997 and June 1998.</p>
<p>The tender was due to close May 27.</p>
<p>&quot;It was cancelled because the requirement was not there,&quot; the source said. &quot;IOC has plans to issue a new one-year term tender but the details are still being worked out.&quot;  </p>
<p>India's oil industry has been thrown into uncertainty this month by junior Petroleum Minister T.R. Balu recommending a 15-20 percent hike in state-controlled prices of LPG and diesel, to pay money owed to oil companies accrued from selling subsidised petroleum products below market prices.</p>
<p>The debt or oil pool deficit, totalled 155 billion rupees ($4.33 billion) at the end of March and is expected to rise to 245 billion rupees by March 31 1998.  </p>
<p>To release the government from the financial burden of providing subsidies on LPG, the government in February 1993 liberalised imports and distribution of non-subsidised LPG by introducing a &quot;parallel marketing&quot; scheme.</p>
<p>But imports, and consequently consumption - at around 4.2 million tonnes-per-year - were being capped by inadequate port and terminalling facilities, which are mostly state-owned.</p>
<p>Public sector companies have an annual import capacity of 1.9 million tonnes, IOC official said.  </p>
<p>As a result, IOC still dominates the market as it imports LPG on behalf of public sector companies which then supply consumers at subsidised prices.</p>
<p>IOC imports LPG on both a spot and a term basis, but other than an outstanding term contract with Saudi Aramco for 13,000-tonnes between January and December, it has not imported any term cargoes since its last term contract expired in March, the source said.</p>
<p>-- Marguerita Choy, Singapore Newsroom (+65-8703086)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
