<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="626778" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. stocks erase steep decline as bulls triumph.</title>
<headline>U.S. stocks erase steep decline as bulls triumph.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Westhoven</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue chip stocks, sent into a tailspin earlier Friday after a profit warning from semiconductor giant Intel Corp., erased a sharp decline to close nearly unchanged.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average closed up 0.86 points to 7,331.04, reversing a sell-off that pushed the blue chip index down as much as 88 points in early trading. The Dow index fell 14.87 points for the week.</p>
<p>The technology-heavy Nasdaq composite index was unable to overcome the Intel hurdle, and slipped 2.72 points to 1,400.32. For the week, the Nasaq index rose 10.60 points.</p>
<p>&quot;The bulls are definitely in charge,&quot; said Hildegard Zagorski, a Prudential Securities market analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;The entire market is so strong, it was able to turn itself around in a broad-based rally. It's a little startling,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The 30-stock blue chip average drew strength from banks and financial companies, which rallied in tandem with bonds.</p>
<p>Stocks tumbled at the opening after news that Intel, the world's largest maker of computer chips and a technology bellwether, said it expected its second-quarter revenues and earnings to fall short of expectations.</p>
<p>The news was especially shocking because Intel is known for consistenly beating Wall Street's estimates and because it came just one  day after Nike Inc. said it also expected weak quarterly earnings.</p>
<p>After the initial scare, bargain hunters stepped in. By late trading, the Dow had crossed back into positive territory and rose about 40 points before settling back.</p>
<p>&quot;The circumstances have been ripe for whippy action, so when you get a news event it can give you a sharp push up or down. But without heavier volume or broader participation, the sustainability isn't there,&quot; said Gregory Nie, technical analyst at Everen Securities.</p>
<p>One analyst warned that the stock market has so much good news built into it, some earnings disappointments have to be expected.</p>
<p>&quot;We've had such a run. Over time, the market has to pause because the backdrop is that the economy is slowing. The incredible gains have to be tempered,&quot; said Chris Dickerson, analyst at Global Market Strategists Inc.</p>
<p>Intel, which fell as low as 140, closed down 12-17/64 to 151-1/2 on very heavy volume of 57.3 million shares, the second heaviest trading session in the company's history. It came in sixth place for the greatest volume in an individial stock in a single session. That record is held by Comparator Systems Corp. Some 177.7 million Comparator shares changed hands on May 7, 1996, according to the Nasdaq.</p>
<p>The bond market also gave a leg up to stocks, especially banks and other financial companies. The 30-year Treasury bond rose 26/32, or $8.13 on a $1,000 bond, knocking its yield well below the psychological level of 7 percent, to 6.91 percent.</p>
<p>A brightened outlook for interest rates also sent bank and financial stocks soaring. Citicorp rose 4-1/4 to 114-3/8; J.P. Morgan &amp; Co. added 3-1/8 to 107-1/2 and Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. firmed 2-1/2 to 67-1/2.</p>
<p>Compaq Computer Corp. surged 6-3/8 to 108-1/4 after an executive said it expects strong second quarter earnings and is having none of Intel's troubles in Europe.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks rose 4.20 to 848.28. The American Stock Exchange index rose 2.26 to 605.38.</p>
<p>The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks rose 2.92 to 441.78. The average share was up 29 cents.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 8,038.50 up 37.53 or 0.47 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
