<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="626726" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraq completes oil exports under U.N. deal.</title>
<headline>Iraq completes oil exports under U.N. deal.</headline>
<byline>Leon Barkho</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq completed on Friday the export of limited amounts of oil under its six-month deal with the U.N. and was waiting for an offer from the Security Council to renew the deal, Oil Minister Amir Muhammad Rasheed said.</p>
<p>&quot;Today Iraq has completed the export of the last barrel of crude oil amounting to 120 million barrels since the start of the implementation of the memorandum of understanding on December 10,&quot; Rasheed told a news conference in Baghdad.</p>
<p>Asked whether Iraq wanted to renew the plan, he said: &quot;Let first the Security Council propose to us, make the offer, and then we will make the right response at the time.&quot;</p>
<p>The deal comes under review on June 9. Iraq has complained frequently about the sluggish pace of approving contracts for food, medicine and other humanitarian goods purchased with the oil revenues, blaming Washington for the delays.</p>
<p>The United States has already expressed misgivings about the deal worth $2 billion over six months and aimed at helping Iraqis stricken by U.N. sanctions imposed for Iraq's 1990 invasion of kuwait.</p>
<p>Rasheed said Iraq exported 54 million barrels of oil in the first three months of the deal and another 66 million in the next three.</p>
<p>He said the increase in amount of exports in the last three months was due to a fall in oil prices.</p>
<p>Rasheed said 51 contracts were signed, 33 in the first three months and 18 others in the last three.</p>
<p>He said revenues amounted to $1.07 billion each three months. The extra amount was paid for Turkey to cover transit fees of the twin pipeline via its territory. Iraq shipped the largest portion of the limited exports through Turkey.</p>
<p>Rasheed said talks with foreign firms on oil development contracts were continuing and a Chinese technical delegation was in Baghdad to sign an oil deal.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope the contract with the Chinese will be signed very soon, sooner than expected,&quot; he added without elaborating.</p>
<p>China is reportedly interested in the development of the billion-barrel Ahdab field in southern Iraq. Officials at the oil ministry also said China was interested in the prized Halfaya field, also in the south.</p>
<p>Halfaya was discovered 20 years ago and is believed to hold commercial reserves of about five billion barrels, the official said. Iraq believes the field could produce some 250,000 barrels a day (bpd) at full capacity.</p>
<p>Rashid said Iraq hoped Syria would reopen a pipeline via its territory for Iraqi oil exports after the two Arab foes recently resumed commercial cooperation.</p>
<p>The Syrian government closed the pipeline in 1982 and has been shut since then.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
