<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="626736" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turk shares surge on hopes of political crisis end.</title>
<headline>Turk shares surge on hopes of political crisis end.</headline>
<byline>Daren Butler</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish shares surged on Friday in a late flurry of buying fuelled by tentative hopes of an end to a political crisis which has brought the Islamist-led government to the verge of collapse.</p>
<p>The IMKB National-100 index ended the day up 4.32 percent, or 66 points, to close at 1,595. Trade volume fell to 32.69 trillion lira ($233 million) from 49.42 trillion ($352 million) on Thursday.</p>
<p>Brokers said shares were lifted by speculative buying in a rebound from losses of over two percent on Thursday and then boosted by a break through key resistance at 1,580 points, which brought gains over the week to a total 8.7 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a liveliness and and dynamism about the market at the moment and this is keeping the market on its feet,&quot; said broker Koray Cervatoglu from Baran Securities. Trading was focused on blue-chip stocks such as the flat steel maker Eregli, oil refiner Tupras and utilities Cukurova, Kepez and Aktas.</p>
<p>But analysts were sceptical about the sustainability of the gains while the 11-month-old alliance between Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan and pro-Western Tansu Ciller was crumbling under pressure from the secularist establishment.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not believe there has been a substantial fundamental improvement and it is better to be cautious,&quot; said Oner Ayan, responsible for international capital markets at Ata Securities.</p>
<p>The attention of brokers was focused on the timing of a possible election after media reports that Erbakan, whose party is facing closure in an anti-Islamist crackdown, wants to go to the nation in October while Ciller favours next March.</p>
<p>&quot;What is important for the market now is an election date. This will have a powerful influence as far as the direction of the market is concerned,&quot; Delta Securities broker Cem Baycan said.</p>
<p>The impact of an early election on market sentiment was still open to question, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people believe an election will improve the stock exchange situation, but we do not believe the political crisis is coming to an end,&quot; Ayan said.</p>
<p>He said a further unsettling factor for the markets was a meeting on Saturday of the powerful National Security Council, whose calls for a crackdown on Islamist activism in February set the current political crisis in motion.</p>
<p>The government suffered the latest in a series of blows on Friday with the resignation of a senior MP from Ciller's conservative True Path Party, robbing the government of its absolute majority in parliament.</p>
<p>Brokers said the coalition would hence face increasing difficulty in surviving a fresh censure motion expected to be filed by the opposition early in June.</p>
<p>On the currency market, the political tension buoyed demand for dollars, prompting the Turkish central bank to buy lira for the U.S. currency shortly before the close, bankers said. The Turkish lira closed at 140,410 to the dollar, down from 140,300 a day earlier.</p>
<p>Brokers said the priority for financial markets was evidence that progress was being made on addressing the country's deep seated economic problems and accelerating an ambitious sell-off programme, championed by Erbakan since he came to power.</p>
<p>The combined picture of political instability and economic weakness has depressed foreign investor interest in the stock market over the first four months of 1997, analysts said.</p>
<p>The volume of foreign trading on the Istanbul stock exchange was down 71 percent in April from January, according to data released by the Turkish bourse.</p>
<p>($1=140,410 Turkish lira)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
