<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="626934" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Most emerging debt follows U.S. Treasuries rally.</title>
<headline>Most emerging debt follows U.S. Treasuries rally.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most Brady bonds rose higher on the coattails of a rally in the U.S. Treasury market on Friday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The momentum is pretty good across the board and we had a nice rally in the U.S. Treasury market,&quot; one trader said. &quot;Our market is lagging that rally.&quot;</p>
<p>Brazil &quot;C&quot; bonds gained 1/4 to stand at 79-1/4 bid, but higher price talk on its upcoming Eurobond prevented a more-significant rise, traders said.  </p>
<p>In other major Latin issues, Argentina FRBs were unchanged at 93-1/4 bid, and Mexico Pars were up 5/8 at 75-1/8.</p>
<p>Peru spreads narrowed substantially. FLRBs were about 18 basis points narrower, up 1-1/4 at 57-7/8 bid. PDIs narrowed about nine basis points, with their price up 1/2 at 63-1/4.</p>
<p>Anticipation of strong economic growth figures for April gave players a reason to get back into Peru paper, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Mainly, Peru was lagging the rest of the market,&quot; a Brady trader said. &quot;The spreads against the majors were too wide, and we thought that Peru could easily tighten 30 basis points. Today was the day Peru caught up.&quot;</p>
<p>Interest in the country came from small accounts in the United States and Latin America, the trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;The momentum is pretty good. I think Peru could continue tightening a little bit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Venezuela Brady debt widened amid profit taking, traders said. News of a new 10-year $315 million Eurobond had spurred buying of the country's Bradys on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Venezuela FLIRBs were off 1/4 at 91-1/4 bid, and Discounts were off 1/2 at 86-1/2 bid.</p>
<p>&quot;We tightened quite a bit yesterday and we just gave it all back today,&quot; a Venezuela Brady trader said.  &quot;There's no real fundamental news other than the launching of the global.&quot;</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Ecuador Pars climbed 5/8 to 45-3/8, Poland PDIs rose 7/8 to 84-1/8 and dollar-denominated Russian Vnesh loans were up 3/8 at 86-1/4.</p>
<p>U.S. Treasuries rose on technical factors and benign economic data releases, market analysts said. The benchmark 30-year bond was up 24/32 to yield 6.92 percent.</p>
<p>(( -- Scott Gerlach, 212-859-1868 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
