<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="627177" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ADM expansion continues with UGG stake.</title>
<headline>ADM expansion continues with UGG stake.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. food processing giant Archer Daniels Midland Co added another key global partner Thursday with its agreement to buy 45 percent of Canada's second largest grain handler, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Archer is very successfully expanding. Their ability to manage any type of grain-related facility is very good, so it looks like a win-win situation,&quot; said Leonard Teitelbaum, a Merrill Lynch food and agribusiness analyst.</p>
<p>United Grain Growers Ltd said earlier Thursday it agreed to a C$113 million deal under which ADM will acquire a 45 percent stake in the Canadian company.  </p>
<p>&quot;Archer gets a good solid partner, UGG gets some cash and some management should they need it,&quot; Teitelbaum said.</p>
<p>Earlier this month ADM agreed with Glencore Grain Holding to buy Glencore's grain facilities in Brazil and Paraguay, while last year ADM acquired Minneapolis based grain merchandising firm Benson-Quinn.</p>
<p>&quot;Their (ADM's) strength has always been to strategically locate grain sourcing, grain storage and grain processing facilities and this looks like that pattern being continued,&quot; Teitelbaum of Merrill Lynch said.  </p>
<p>Tim Ramey, an analyst with Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, also saw the move as a continuation of ADM's expansion strategy.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like a logical extension of their reach,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>ADM is one of the largest wheat millers in North America and already owns, leases or has a 50 percent or larger interest in 10 flour mills in Canada. UGG had 173 primarily grain elevators across Canada's Prairies as of July 31, 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a backyard type of alliance for them (ADM),&quot; Ramey said. &quot;It is a business they are already in, a business they understand.&quot;</p>
<p>((Nigel Hunt 312-408 8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
