<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="627270" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Afghan Taleban suffer as foes attack.</title>
<headline>Afghan Taleban suffer as foes attack.</headline>
<byline>Raja Asghar</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Afghanistan's Taleban militia suffered in new opposition attacks north of the capital Kabul on Friday, losing at least one strategic town, and said it was fighting for control of a northeastern provincial capital.</p>
<p>Opposition forces commanded by guerrilla leader Ahmad Shah Masood had on Friday morning seized Golbahar, at the mouth of his native Panjsher Valley in Kapisa province, and nearby Jabal os-Seraj in Parwan province, after heavy fighting, a Pakistan-based Afghan news service said.</p>
<p>But a Taleban spokesman, quoted by the Afghan Islamic Press (AIP), later said the purist militia had retaken Jabal-os-Seraj, a key town on the main highway from Kabul to the north.</p>
<p>AIP also reported earlier that Masood's forces were fighting further south of Jabal-os-Seraj aiming to take the Parwan provincial capital of Charikar.</p>
<p>Wakil Ahmad, speaking from the militia headquarters in the southern Afghan town of Kandahar, said a Taleban force that had advanced through the strategic Salang Pass earlier this week was fighting opposition forces near the Samangan provincial capital, Aibak.</p>
<p>Earlier in the day, the Taleban had claimed that it had taken Aibak on Wednesday night, and its latest report of fighting for the town seemed to indicate a setback to the militia there as well.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear how much of Samangan province was under Taleban control.</p>
<p>AIP said the Taleban, who captured Kabul last September and now control nearly 90 percent of the country, had sent thousands of fresh fighters from various provinces to reinforce its front lines, including that of Jabal os-Seraj, about 70 km (43 miles) to the north.</p>
<p>The Taleban's Kapisa province governor, Maulvi Khushal, was killed in the fighting for Golbahar, AIP said.</p>
<p>Masood's fighters began attacking Taleban positions in the area on Thursday after the purist movement was ousted from the newly captured Mazar-i-Sharif by local ethnic Uzbek and Shi'ite Moslem forces.</p>
<p>Witnesses said the Taleban on Friday were in full control of the strategic northeastern town of Pul-i-Khumri, although an anti-Taleban official said the opposition had taken it.</p>
<p>Ousted president Burhanuddin Rabbani's ambassador to India, Masood Khalili, said in New Delhi that Pul-i-Khumri, in Baghlan province, which the Taleban captured on Wednesday, had been retaken by opposition forces overnight.</p>
<p>A Reuters correspondent in Pul-i-Khumri, Tim Johnston, said the town was under Taleban control and peaceful, but travellers arriving there said there had been heavy fighting overnight in Kayan valley south of there.</p>
<p>Some truckloads of refugees were leaving Pul-i-Khumri heading south, apparently not knowing of the situation in Jabal-os-Seraj.</p>
<p>Witnesses said there was a large attendance at mosques in Pul-i-Khumri for the traditional Friday congregations.</p>
<p>Khalili told a news conference in New Delhi that opposition forces were firmly in control of the strategic Salang Pass, about 100 km (60 miles) north of Kabul, they had taken Pul-i-Khumri town overnight and were advancing towards Charikar, a main town south of the pass.</p>
<p>There was no immediate independent word about the status of the Salang Pass, which a Taleban force had crossed earlier this week before taking Pul-i-Khumri.</p>
<p>But Afghan sources said this Taleban force seemed to be isolated with surrounding areas being in opposition hands after the fall of Jabal os-Seraj to Masood's fighters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
