<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="627220" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Focus - Buba bares fists in fight with Bonn on gold.</title>
<headline>Focus - Buba bares fists in fight with Bonn on gold.</headline>
<byline>Catherine O'Mahony</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bundesbank on Friday shed its gloves in its increasingly acrimonious fight with Bonn over plans to revalue gold and currency reserves in the run-up to Europe's monetary union.</p>
<p>Bundesbank council member Reimut Jochimsen, bemoaning what he said was an unprecedented break with Germany's consensus-led tradition, warned of &quot;disastrous&quot; consequences if the German government failed to back down from its contentious plan to use the proceeds of the gold revaluation to ease its debt burden.</p>
<p>&quot;What we have here is a dramatic conflict that must be played out fully in public,&quot; Jochimsen, a member of the Bundesbank council, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel however said he was sticking by a plan which envisages revaluing the Bundesbank's vast gold and currency reserves to market prices and using the value gains to redeeem old debt. Waigel has said he could receive a transfer as soon as this year.</p>
<p>But with Germany embroiled in a tough battle to bring its public deficit and debt levels under control to make the grade for monetary union, the Bundesbank is adamant that the revaluation procedure will undermine faith in the euro and interfere with its own monetary policy.</p>
<p>The German central bank on Wednesday issued a careful but unambiguous statement rejecting the Waigel plan, making clear it considered the proposal to infringe on its vaunted independence.</p>
<p>But two days later, with Bonn still pushing ahead with the project, Jochimsen was in no mood to mince words.</p>
<p>&quot;In the past we always tried to achieve an agreed solution in disputes. In this regard, the government's present actions are a complete break in style,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bonn had chosen to ignore the &quot;massive reservations&quot; raised by Bundesbank council members when Waigel put forward his plans in mid-May, Jochimsen said.</p>
<p>Traditionally reticent to play out matters of policy in public, the Bundesbank was now determined to keep the matter at the forefront of public discussion Jochimsen said, noting that neither the public nor financial markets had fully grasped the significance of Waigel's plans.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank council has already made absolutely clear statements and it will continue to do so. The mood on the council is determined and resignations are out of the question,&quot; Jochimsen said.</p>
<p>Jochimsen said the currency revaluations were an unacceptable intrusion into Bundesbank policy at a time when tight monetary control was crucial as Europe moves toward a single currency, scheduled for January 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank needs complete freedom to manoeuvre in 1997 and 1998. It would be completely contradictory to try to limit this freedom though a request to revalue currency reserves and to distribute the profits from the new valuation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Jochimsen said the revaluation would actually end up causing overall interest rates to rise.</p>
<p>The government has said it hopes its interest payments would be lowered by the revaluation measure, since the profit from the revaluation could be used to retire old debt.</p>
<p>&quot;The lasting damage which the realisation of the gold plans would bring is far greater than the short-term financial benefit it is calculated to achieve,&quot; Jochimsen warned.</p>
<p>At the same time he added the Bundesbank might consider a partial currency revaluation in 1998 if it had become clear by then under what conditions central banks would transfer currency reserves to the future European Central Bank and if there were clear signals of a stable euro.</p>
<p>Jochimsen said Waigel's plans envisaged valuing gold reserves at their market price, minus 40 percent.</p>
<p>Currency reserves, on the other hand, would be revalued at their market price without any discount, he said, although there would be risk reserves.</p>
<p>Jochimsen said the fight between the Bundesbank and Bonn was likely to escalate and would have implications far beyond German.</p>
<p>&quot;An agreeable solution has to be found quickly or there will be disastrous consequences,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
