<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="62734" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Comalco NZ resigns from electricity market.</title>
<headline>Comalco NZ resigns from electricity market.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Comalco Power NZ Ltd, a unit of Comalco New Zealand, said on Wednesday it had resigned as a purchaser class participant from the electricity market.</p>
<p>Comalco said its resignation followed the Commerce Commission's decision on the application by the Electricity Market Company (EMCO) for authorisation of the electricity market rules.  </p>
<p>The anti-monopolies commission said that the rules for the new wholesale market, which is to become fully operational on October 1, would not lessen competition and that it had no authority to rule on them in any case.</p>
<p>&quot;All the evidence is that EMCO is putting in place arrangements that will be bureaucratic and costly rather than effective and efficient,&quot; Comalco Power executive director Kerry McDonald said in a statement.  </p>
<p>&quot;While the original principles for a wholesale electricity market in New Zealand had been reasonable there have now been so many compromises, to the deteriment of electricity consumers, that the likely result was simply an inefficient cost-plus activity, with the consumer bearing the consequences,&quot; McDonald said.  </p>
<p>He said there were no effective mechanisms in the market arrangements or rules which would encourage lower costs and more efficient operation.</p>
<p>&quot;It is also unfortunate that few of the government's objectives in setting up the market will be effectively achieved. The market has favourable implications for the generation and supply industry but has largely ignored the end cost to consumers,&quot; McDonald said.  </p>
<p>He said the market rules were structured so that electricity suppliers could dominate decisions.</p>
<p>McDonald said cited as evidence of this &quot;the recent vote on rules in which market participants with generator interests voting in the purchaser class outvoted purchaser interests to secure a narrow vote in favour of the new rules&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Regrettably, as the consitutional arrangements of the market provide no effective opportunity for the purchasing or consumer side to influence outcomes, Comalco has no other option but to resign.&quot;  </p>
<p>Colmalco is New Zealand's largest power consumer, using around 15 percent of the total power generated.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
