<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="627426" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French election could herald wane of Le Pen.</title>
<headline>French election could herald wane of Le Pen.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jean-Marie Le Pen, fiery leader of France's far-right National Front, sees himself as king-maker in Sunday's parliamentary election but the poll could also spell the beginning of the end of his leadership.</p>
<p>Under his brash direction, the xenophobic party won 14.94 percent in last Sunday's first round, its best yet in a National Assembly election. Analysts say its voters will play a crucial role in the outcome of Sunday's runoff.</p>
<p>But a new generation of National Front leaders is seeking seats in parliament, and their success could soon eclipse the 68-year-old Le Pen in national prominence.</p>
<p>Pollsters predict the party will win at least one seat and perhaps as many as three in the assembly, where it now has none.</p>
<p>Among those angling for seats are Le Pen deputies Bruno Megret and Bruno Gollnisch, who have made no secret of their eagerness to succeed Le Pen should he step down as party chief.</p>
<p>Le Pen called backers to a Paris rally on Thursday evening where he handed out endorsements to non-Front candidates he deemed worthy of support and black marks to those he called enemies of his movement.</p>
<p>His behaviour showed both why he has been so successful in publicising the party and why he remains a pariah in mainstream political circles.</p>
<p>At one point, a beaming Le Pen paraded around the stage carrying an oversized photograph of the head of Strasbourg mayor Catherine Trautmann, perched on a huge platter.</p>
<p>&quot;I offer the head of Madame Trautmann to Marie-France Stirbois,&quot; he said, bowing to the National Front candidate in Dreux, west of Paris.</p>
<p>&quot;I find that absolutely shocking,&quot; Socialist Leader Lionel Jospin said of the incident. The Socialist Trautmann had led an anti-Front mass march in her eastern city in March.</p>
<p>Le Pen also urged defeat for outgoing Gaullist Prime Minister Alain Juppe, Gaullist Paris mayor Jean Tiberi, Gaullist Justice Minister Jacques Toubon, centrist Culture Minister Philippe Douste-Blazy and Communist Party leader Robert Hue.</p>
<p>Juppe, who is seeking a National Assembly seat from a constituency in Bordeaux, the southwestern city where he also serves as mayor, &quot;is the archetype of the most unjust and ferocious enemy of the National Front&quot;, Le Pen said.</p>
<p>Juppe, who last year called le Pen &quot;deeply, almost viscerally racist, antisemitic and xenophobic&quot;, is to step down as premier following the governing centre-right's surprise defeat in last Sunday's first-round vote.</p>
<p>Le Pen's 21 recommendations were a climbdown from earlier calls to &quot;zap the right&quot; by voting for leftist candidates in the second round. Other Front leaders had protested that the party rank and file were bitterly opposed to the left.</p>
<p>A day after his Paris rally, Le Pen ran into an angry mob of protesters campaigning for his daughter Marie Caroline Le Pen in the outer Paris suburb of Mantes-La-Jolie.</p>
<p>Two people, including Socialist candidate Anette Peulvast-Bergeal, were hurt as anti-racist militants began hurling eggs and stones at Le Pen, who was shielded from injury by a ring of police officers and private bodyguards.</p>
<p>Le Pen, who had to take refuge in a cafe, was apparently unhurt but was heard to be shouting angrily: &quot;When I'm attacked, I've never been afraid of another man or even several at once.&quot;</p>
<p>He has boasted that the Front will play a decisive role in Sunday's parliamentary election, saying it will only support candidates who endorse its anti-European stance and its plan to reserve jobs, housing, education, health care and welfare for native-born French citizens.</p>
<p>But pollsters say his endorsements will have scant impact.</p>
<p>The Front will itself have candidates in 132 of France's 577 constituencies in the second round, a sign that the Front is now a major force in all French elections, analysts say.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
