<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="627464" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian Real Software IPO 12 times oversubscribed.</title>
<headline>Belgian Real Software IPO 12 times oversubscribed.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>An offer of 420,000 shares in Belgian information technology (IT) services firm Real Software, to be listed on the Brussels bourse on June 10, was oversubscribed 12 times, the company said on Friday.</p>
<p>The shares are priced at 1,500 francs each.  </p>
<p>The company said in a statement the price meant Real Software was valued at 1.85 billion francs.</p>
<p>&quot;Real Software growth stock, with annual growth in sales and profit of 10 to 20 percent, will be listed at a price/earnings ratio of 15, which is lower than the average of the Bel-20 (blue chip share index  .BFX ),&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Using discounted cash flow and similar pricing methods, the price represented a discount of 12 to 28 percent.</p>
<p>Institutional investors will receive 60 percent of the issue, private investors 35 percent and staff five percent.  </p>
<p>Real Software, currently management-owned, is offering 34 percent of its capital to the public in a deal managed by KB Securities and co-lead by Generale Bank and Bank Degroof.</p>
<p>The software development and implementation company has 400 staff, annual turnover of some 1.2 billion francs, of which one third is realised abroad, and net profit of 102 million francs.</p>
<p>KB Securities analyst Johan Pede said in a recent report on Real Software he expected net turnover to grow by 16.5 percent in 1997, 20.9 percent in 1998 and 18.8 percent in 1999.</p>
<p>The EPS growth rate was seen at 20.8 percent in 1997, 23.0 percent in 1998 and 20.6 percent in 1999.</p>
<p>Real Software is the second Belgian IT firm to come to the market in the first half of 1997. Systemat NV, founded in 1984, offers hardware, configuration, assembly, installation, training and support services.</p>
<p>-- Nieck Ammerlaan, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6816, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
