<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="627594" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Delors would be Jospin adviser not minister-source.</title>
<headline>Delors would be Jospin adviser not minister-source.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former European Commission president Jacques Delors could serve as a special adviser to Socialist leader Lionel Jospin if the well-placed left-wing opposition wins Sunday's parliamentary election but would not take a cabinet post, a source close to him said on Friday.</p>
<p>The left-wing Liberation daily, close to the Socialists, said Delors, a former Socialist finance minister in the 1980s, was favourite to take a superministry for foreign and European affairs if the left won.</p>
<p>Delors described the report as &quot;journalists' speculation&quot; and there was no immediate comment from the Socialist party.</p>
<p>A source close to Delors said he could play an important role, if asked, as an adviser to Jospin and a special envoy, for example in smoothing relations with Germany, without having to hold a ministerial post.</p>
<p>Delors, 71, has served as an elder statesman and moral reference for Jospin during the campaign, giving his blessing to the party's conditions for joining a single European currency.</p>
<p>Liberation said: &quot;(President) Jacques Chirac could hardly refuse him, and he would have the advantage of being able to talk on an equal footing with German Chancellor Helmut Kohl.&quot;</p>
<p>But the source said taking a cabinet job &quot;would not be coherent with everything he has done since December 1994&quot;, when he decided not to run for the presidency in 1995, citing his age and the difficulty of governing with a right-wing majority.</p>
<p>Chirac, a conservative Gaullist who won that election, criticised Delors' federalist approach to European integration during the campaign and has not consulted him since then.</p>
<p>Delors and Kohl are close friends and the former commission president is widely respected in Germany, where the prospect of an upset Socialist-Communist French election victory has been viewed with some alarm.</p>
<p>Delors headed the Brussels-based European executive for a decade from 1985 until the end of 1994, presiding over the completion of the single European market and playing a major role in drafting the 1991 Maastricht treaty on economic and monetary union.</p>
<p>Since 1995, he has concentrated his energy on a think-tank, Notre Europe (Our Europe), dedicated to research and policy proposals on European issues.</p>
<p>Liberation said other possible contenders for the foreign ministry were centre-left ex-prime minister Michel Rocard, a member of the European parliament, and former premier Laurent Fabius.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
