<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="627614" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida hypocritical in tobacco lawsuits - lawyers.</title>
<headline>Florida hypocritical in tobacco lawsuits - lawyers.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Rothman</byline>
<dateline>WEST PALM BEACH, Fla. 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Florida is being hypocritical on the issue of nicotine addiction as it contests two tobacco-related lawsuits, lawyers for tobacco companies say.</p>
<p>In its defence of a lawsuit filed by a Florida prison inmate, the state contends the prisoner made the choice to smoke. But it is fighting efforts by tobacco companies to use the same argument in its multimillion-dollar Medicaid lawsuit against the cigarette industry, the lawyers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's ludicrous that Florida should be using the same defence to a prisoner's lawsuit for tobacco-related injuries that it is denying to the cigarette companies,&quot; said Stephen Krigbaum, a West Palm Beach lawyer representing cigarette giant Philip Morris Cos. Inc.</p>
<p>In its lawsuit against 12 tobacco companies, which seeks to recover the costs of treating smokers, Florida has rejected cigarette company assertions that smoking is a matter of choice and intends to present evidence that addiction in a prime motivator for smokers.</p>
<p>But in a 1995 lawsuit filed by state prison inmate Thomas Waugh, who claims he was denied treatment for nicotine addiction caused by cigarettes he bought in prison, the state has argued that Waugh made the choice to smoke.</p>
<p>&quot;This is clearly one of the most hypocritical moves the state has engaged in,&quot; said West Palm Beach lawyer Justice Reid, representing Loews Corp.'s Lorillard Tobacco Co. Inc.</p>
<p>Should Waugh win the lawsuit, filed in U.S. District Court in Jacksonville, the state could face millions of dollars in health care costs to treat prisoners. No trial date has been set.</p>
<p>In an unsuccessful petition to dismiss Waugh's lawsuit, Florida Assistant Attorney General Donna La Plante argued it was Waugh's choice to purchase cigarettes and that he &quot;is in no way entitled to medical intervention to 'cure' a habit which (he) continues to indulge and over which (he) has ultimate control.&quot;</p>
<p>Krigbaum called the state's position a &quot;classic case of wanting to have your cake and eat it, too.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It's position is directly opposite from the position it is taking in the Medicaid case,' he said.</p>
<p>Asked if the state was being hypocritical, La Plante said, &quot;No. The best way to quit is cold turkey and we wouldn't want it any other way. The documents we filed (in the Waugh suit) showed there were only transitory physical symptoms when people quit smoking and they were not medically serious.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WEST PALM BEACH, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
