<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="627649" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Elf says ends Chevron UK merger talks.</title>
<headline>Elf says ends Chevron UK merger talks.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Elf Aquitaine Chairman Philippe Jaffre told his group's annual general meeting Friday that his company had ended negotiations with Chevron about merging their activities in Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;Following detailed studies, the two parties considered that the planned study would not provide sufficient savings in order to justify the project,&quot; an Elf statement said.</p>
<p>The talks were started on Nov. 6, 1996, it said.</p>
<p>Britain's refining industry, like most of Europe, has suffered in recent years from a surplus capacity for gasoline production. A price war among gasoline retailers, initiated at the start of last year by Esso UK in response to the rapid growth of supermarkets as gasoline retailers, has hit profit margins.</p>
<p>Three companies, Elf, Chevron and Murphy Corp.'s Murco unit, signed a memorandum of understanding in November 1996 to consolidate their refining interests in Milford Haven in south Wales, by ceasing crude processing at the 115,000 barrels per day Gulf refinery in Pembroke.</p>
<p>In March, Murco decided to exit the proposed merger in favour of going it alone. But Elf UK Oil and Chevron's Gulf Oil decided to continue their talks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
