<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="62779" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Property blues seen hitting Amoy net.</title>
<headline>Property blues seen hitting Amoy net.</headline>
<byline>Kathleen Kearney</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The doldrums afflicting Hong Kong's commercial property sector are likely to rein in earnings for Amoy Properties Ltd, prompting analysts to predict that the company will post only single-digit growth for 1995/96.</p>
<p>&quot;Amoy is trading at a large discount to its NAV (net asset value) and offers an attractive yield, but we are not seeing the core earnings growth that some listed companies are showing,&quot; said Michael Green, regional property analyst at Salomon Brothers.</p>
<p>Amoy, the 57.6 percent-held subsidiary of Hang Lung Development Ltd and the holding company for more than five million sq feet of commercial, residential and industrial properties, will release its earnings for the year ended June 30 on Friday.</p>
<p>Green forecast that Amoy would post net profits of HK$1.68 billion. Last year, the company announced profit before preference dividends for the year ended June 30, 1995 of HK$1.67 billion. Net attributable to shareholders was HK$1.55 billion.</p>
<p>The group reported a net before preference dividends of HK$849.9 million for the six months ended December 31 1995, a 1.1 percent increase over the year-earlier period.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Earnings growth from the company's core property portfolio could be flat, or negative if there are no property disposals to boost the bottom line,&quot; said Carol Lai, research manager at Amsteel Securities Research.</p>
<p>Lai also said core earnings would be flat, although she was looking for growth in attributable profit of around seven percent.</p>
<p>Negative rental reversions from some of the group's office and retail properties on Hong Kong island and in Kowloon will depress earnings, while gains from the disposal of non-core properties could boost them, Lai said.</p>
<p>In the company's 1995 annual report, the management said the office rental market would remain weak at least until 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The retail (property) market is more difficult to judge because the problem is one of sentiment,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The report said it would not be surprised to see a recovery in the retail market in the second half of 1995 or early 1996.</p>
<p>The latest available retail sales figures for the month of June show inflation-adjusted sales rising just one percent year-on-year and flat compared with May's sales figures.</p>
<p>Lai said a recovery in consumer confidence and retail sales has not yet materialised, and added that the company may look to sell some of its older holdings to boost earnings.</p>
<p>In 1995, the company netted an an additional HK$84 million from the sale of part of its Argyle Centre building in central Kowloon. Property disposals in the first half of financial year 1996 brought in HK$12.8 million in pre-tax profits.</p>
<p>No additional sales have been noted in the second half of the year.</p>
<p>Amoy shares were at HK$9.10 in late afternoon trading on Wednesday, down from Tuesday's closing price of HK$9.40.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
