<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="627719" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Evacuees say they feared for lives in Sierra Leone.</title>
<headline>Evacuees say they feared for lives in Sierra Leone.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nearly 400 Westerners arrived in London on Friday after being evacuated from Sierra Leone, and some spoke of fearing for their lives after Sunday's coup in the West African state, Britain's Press Association reported.</p>
<p>The news agency quoted a British woman, who did not want to be identified, as saying soldiers had stormed through her house as her three-and-a-half-month old baby lay sleeping in her bedroom.</p>
<p>&quot;They rammed our gates with their Land Rover and threatened to shoot us,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;They have taken everything. For the last five days we have had only the clothes we are standing up in. I have lived in Sierra Leone for 15 years and I am devastated.</p>
<p>&quot;We were absolutely terrified. I have a girl of three-and-a-half months and a five-year old son and I didn't think we were going to get out alive.&quot;</p>
<p>The Press Association quoted another British evacuee, Maureen Cummings, as saying: &quot;We have been advised to leave as dependants, but my husband has had to stay because of his business.</p>
<p>&quot;I am so frightened for him. On Sunday, soldiers tried to break into our compound five times. In the end they came back at night and just broke the gate down with their vehicle.</p>
<p>&quot;We sat in the house and opened the door. Seven of them just went through our home taking everything. It was really threatening.&quot;</p>
<p>The British Foreign Office chartered a Boeing 747 to transport the evacuees from the Sierra Leone capital of Freetown.</p>
<p>The Press Association said the aircraft carried 200 British aid workers, businessmen and missionaries as well as 196 people from European and Commonwealth countries.</p>
<p>The evacuation flight left Freetown's Lungi airport on Thursday after a confrontation between Nigerian and Sierra Leone troops contesting control of the runway.</p>
<p>The Nigerians have been controlling the airport as part of a regional accord on peacekeeping in Liberia.</p>
<p>The relationship between the Sierra Leone troops and the Nigerians since the coup has been described by diplomatic sources as &quot;correct but not cordial&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a confrontation between the two sides who control opposite ends of the runway. A shot was fired as the evacuees were queuing to board the plane and everyone took defensive positions on the tarmac,&quot; said a British diplomat.</p>
<p>He said the shot had been fired by a Sierra Leone soldier.</p>
<p>No one was hurt in the incident, which witnesses said was exacerbated by the refusal of the Sierra Leoneans to allow a Nigerian C-130 Hercules to land with troops and supplies. The Nigerians insisted on landing the plane.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SILEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
