<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="627770" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Polls show Canada's Liberal Party keeping majority.</title>
<headline>Polls show Canada's Liberal Party keeping majority.</headline>
<byline>Heather Scoffield</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's ruling Liberal Party should manage to retain a parliamentary majority in Monday's election despite a steady slide in support over the past month, two polls showed on Thursday.</p>
<p>The last of five daily tracking polls conducted for Reuters by Zogby International showed support for Prime Minister Jean Chretien's Liberals rising to 41.9 percent of decided voters from 39.7 percent in Wednesday's poll.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears the Liberal support has stopped its downward slide,&quot; pollster John Zogby said.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears that the Liberals are headed toward a majority (and) that Reform, on the basis of its strength in the West, should win the second greatest number of seats,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A Gallup Canada poll taken May 25-28 and released late on Thursday gave the Liberals 41 percent among decided voters, down from the 55 percent in mid-April and the 46 percent just before televised debates in mid-May.</p>
<p>However, Canadian voters have been volatile in recent elections, and one in four were still undecided in both polls.</p>
<p>&quot;Traditionally, undecided voters break against the incumbent and do so over the last couple of days,&quot; Zogby said.</p>
<p>One poll, however, showed the Liberals at substantially weaker levels than those indicated by the Reuters-Zogby and Gallup polls.</p>
<p>An Angus Reid Group/Southam News poll broadcast on the CTV television network late on Thursday night showed support for the Liberals among decided voters at 36 percent, compared with 24 percent for the Conservatives, and 19 percent for Reform.</p>
<p>&quot;The Liberals' chances of forming a majority government on election night next Monday now stand at 50-50,&quot; CTV News said.</p>
<p>Reuters-Zogby polls earlier this week also threw into question the Liberals' ability to win another outright majority.</p>
<p>Financial markets have been jittery on fears that the Liberals' deficit-reduction plans might be jeopardized if the Conservatives, who want immediate tax cuts, or the New Democrats, who want more spending, hold the balance of power.</p>
<p>In the 1993 election, the Liberals won 177 of the 295 seats in the House of Commons on 41 percent of the vote.</p>
<p>Thursday's Reuters poll showed support for the right-wing Reform Party slipping to 17.3 percent from 17.5 percent the previous day. Conservative Party support also weakened slightly to 21.3 percent from 21.5 percent previously.</p>
<p>Both polls agreed that Reform, which wants smaller government and a tough line on Quebec, appeared poised to displace the separatist Bloc Quebecois as the official opposition in Canada's Parliament.</p>
<p>Reform's strength is concentrated in the West, while Conservative backing is scattered in pockets across Quebec, Ontario and the Atlantic provinces.</p>
<p>In French-speaking Quebec, the latest Reuters poll showed Bloc Quebecois support jumping to 36 percent from 29 percent in Wednesday's poll. It is still a three-way race in the province, however, with the Liberals at 32 percent and the Conservatives at 30 percent.</p>
<p>Gallup put the Liberals four points ahead of the Bloc in Quebec at 37 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very close in Quebec,&quot; Zogby said. &quot;It's a dog fight.&quot;</p>
<p>Gallup put the Conservatives -- which ran Canada from 1984-93 but was reduced to two seats in the last election -- at 22 percent nationally and Reform at 16 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The Liberals' strength in vote-rich Ontario will likely lead them to another majority government,&quot; Gallup said.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength of the Reform Party in Western Canada, and the recent decline of the Bloc Quebecois in Quebec, suggests that Reform will represent the official opposition in the next Parliament.&quot;</p>
<p>The Reuters poll, taken from May 26-28, covered 1,056 Canadians and the margin of error was 3.1 percentage points. Gallup's survey covered 1,507 adults, giving a margin of error of 2.5 points. The Angus reid poll was conducted May 22-27 among 3,220 voters and had a margin of error of 2.4 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
