<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="627716" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT-Coffee chart outlook unclear.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT-Coffee chart outlook unclear.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>--------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p> JULY     Close  * Support * Resist * RSI14 *   MA10 *   MA30</p>
<p> COFFEE   2,600  * 2262-2360*  2800 *  92.0 *  2,138 *  1,839</p>
<p>---------------VIEWS FROM THE MARKET - May 30 ----------------</p>
<p>Thursday's sharp rally in London coffee futures has left technical analysts wondering if the market would continue its upward pattern or start reversing downwards.</p>
<p>Traders called the market to open $40 higher. The second-month July contract rose by nearly 20 percent or $412 per tonne to a high of $2,670 at one stage on Thursday in a frenzied buying led by roasters.  </p>
<p>Trevor Neil, senior technical analyst at Union CAL Futures, said Thursday's explosive run left a big chart gap at between $2,262 and $2,360 basis July.</p>
<p>The volume was twice the normal size, the price range was very wide and prices closed near their highs.</p>
<p>&quot;But the big gap was left. Technicians have to decide whether this is a continuation or a reversal pattern...can be either,&quot; Neil said.</p>
<p>&quot;The important thing is how the market behaves concerning this gap. If it is left open, it will be a 'measuring' gap indicating that this present run should extend to $2,800.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;However, the closing of the gap would tell us that the top has been seen and the market will suffer a severe sell-off,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Neew York's arabica coffee futures broke the $3.00 a lb mark on Thursday as the broad-based buying frenzy continued.</p>
<p>July arabicas shot up to a life-of-contract high of 318.00 cents, the highest price in two decades, before closing at 314.80 cents, up 19.25 cents -- or more than six percent -- on the day.</p>
<p>&quot;We are seeing history happen,&quot; said Christian Wolthers, vice president of Miami-based importer Blaser &amp; Wolthers Specialty Coffee Trading Co. &quot;We've not seen a market move like this without frost, drought or any other kind of tragedy. It is a clear situation of short supply for demand.&quot;</p>
<p>In other news, world consumer coffee stocks stood at 10 million bags in April, up from 8.80 million in March and 1.1 million bags higher than April 1996, UK trade house E D &amp; F Man said on Friday.</p>
<p>It said stocks, reflecting some of the impact of high coffee exports earlier this year, were now 2.4 million bags above the all-time-low in December 1996, Man said in its April/May coffee report. --Jalil Hamid, London newsroom +44 171 542 4985</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
