<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="62804" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan aluminium mill output up 11.2 pct in August.</title>
<headline>Japan aluminium mill output up 11.2 pct in August.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Output at Japan's seven leading aluminium processors in August rose 11.2 percent from the same month a year before to 124,704 tonnes, according to data submitted by the companies to the Japan Aluminium Federation and released on Wednesday.</p>
<p>On a month-on-month basis, however, mill output was down 8.5 percent, with declines in all major mill products.</p>
<p>Output of flat-rolled products at the seven firms, at 97,524 tonnes, was up 12.1 percent year-on-year but down 8.1 percent month-on-month.</p>
<p>Can sheet production showed particularly strong year-on-year growth of 27.5 percent, to 39,136 tonnes, although this was down 5.3 percent from July's record output. Industry sources said a hotter-than-average July helped boost sales of canned beverages.</p>
<p>The seven producers' August output of extruded products was up 8.0 percent year-on-year at 27,180 tonnes, a modest slowdown from July's 9.4 percent growth. Month on month, extruded output was down 9.8 percent.  </p>
<p>Industry sources said the recent rise in shipments of extruded products reflected solid demand from the housing sector, which is enjoying strong growth as consumers rush to make purchases ahead of the scheduled increase next April in Japan's consumption tax.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Commodities Desk (81-3 3432 6179)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
