<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628206" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Stop mourning Tiananmen victims--Tung to activists.</title>
<headline>Stop mourning Tiananmen victims--Tung to activists.</headline>
<byline>Diane Stormont</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's future leader Tung Chee-hwa told pro-democracy activists on Friday to forget mourning China's bloody 1989 Tiananmen crackdown and look to the future.</p>
<p>Beijing did not want Hong Kong turned into a base for &quot;subversion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Tung in press interviews said he would not ban the annual rallies and marches held in Hong Kong in memory of the victims when China sent tanks into central Beijing to crush a student democracy movement.</p>
<p>The massacre horrified the world, but particularly stunned neighbouring Hong Kong where a million people, nearly all Chinese, turned out to protest. Even pro-China newspapers denounced the killings as &quot;fascism.&quot;</p>
<p>Tung, whose remarks were published in local papers, is China's anointed leader for Hong Kong when it ceases to be a British colony and becomes a mainly-autonomous region of China.</p>
<p>He hit out at pro-democracy activist Martin Lee who has lobbied for London to sue China over what the democracy lobby call breaches of the treaty governing the handover of Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Hong Kong, a British colony for 156 years, reverts to China at midnight on June 30, a date now just 32 days away.</p>
<p>Organisers say they expect tens of thousands of people to rally this year, the last pre-handover commemoration of those who died when Chinese troops crushed their massed, unarmed young compatriots on June 4, 1989.</p>
<p>Tung warned Hong Kong that China was concerned the territory should not develop into what he called a base for subversion.</p>
<p>&quot;No one really wanted June 4 to happen. But over the past eight years, some people have continued to persist on the issue of June 4,&quot; he was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact is that China has achieve a lot in many areas ... politics, economy ... in the past eight years.&quot;</p>
<p>Tung has angered the pro-democracy lobby and heightened Western concern by his plans to water down Hong Kong's civil liberties laws.</p>
<p>He said his proposals were required to ensure the considerable autonomy promised by Beijing, keeping Hong Kong's liberal character different from the rest of communist-ruled China.</p>
<p>He said the changes -- effectively scrapping democratic reforms by last British governor Chris Patten -- were necessary to prevent foreign meddling in Hong Kong affairs when it becomes a part of China.</p>
<p>&quot;We must not become a base that will threaten the existence of our country,&quot; Tung said. &quot;That is why local political parties must not be controlled or influenced by foreign forces.&quot;</p>
<p>The 1984 handover treaty, or Joint Declaration, signed by Britain and China bound London to return its last Asian colony to China and tied Beijing to maintaining Hong Kong's freedoms and capitalist way of life unchanged for 50 years.</p>
<p>The policy of Hong Kong people running Hong Kong with a high degree of independence is central to a One Country, Two Systems concept drawn up by China's late paramount leader Deng Xiaoping and enshrined in the Joint Declaration.</p>
<p>&quot;China is very concerned that Hong Kong will not become a subversive base. We do not want to see that happen as well,&quot; Tung was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;The stronger our sense of 'one country', the greater the chance that the 'two systems' will succeed,&quot; Tung said.</p>
<p>Lee, leader of Hong Kong's Democracy Party, has spearheaded the campaign against Tung's plans to curb civil liberties and revamp the British-style electoral system.</p>
<p>Lee argues that a Provisional Legislature China plans to install in place of the elected chamber is unconstitutional.</p>
<p>He returned from London on Thursday where he lobbied the British to submit a case to the United Nations International Court of Justice.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm disappointed Mr Martin Lee went to London to try and incite legal challenges against the provisional legislature,&quot; Tung said and urged the Democrats to take a more constructive role in shaping the challenges lying ahead.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
