<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628242" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Finance One plunges on trade resumption.</title>
<headline>Finance One plunges on trade resumption.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ailing Thai finance firm, Finance One Plc, plunged when it resumed trading to six baht on heavy early trade on the Thai stock exchange on Friday after a three-month suspension and its abortive merger with Thai Danu Bank Plc last week.</p>
<p>The stock fell below six baht immediately after the opening hitting a low of 5.10 baht from its last traded price of 23.75 baht on February 28. But at 0308 GMT it wound back up marginally to 6.20 baht, down 17.55 baht.  </p>
<p>Cash-strapped Finance One's price movement on its first day of resumed trading will not be limited to a daily 10-percent limit high or low as for most listed stocks.</p>
<p>The stock's resumed trade did not pull down the overall market as some brokers had feared earlier. The composite SET index hardly moved, hovering just 0.49 point below its Thursday close at 557.68 at 0319 GMT in early dealings.</p>
<p>Finance One told market analysts on Wednesday that its book value stood at 12.14 baht a share.</p>
<p>The biggest finance company has been instructed by the Bank of Thailand to raise its capital by 8.28 billion baht within 30 days partly to cover its deteriorating assets.</p>
<p>The planned merger between Finance One and Thai Danu was billed as a model for further consolidations in the troubled Thai finance sector and was blessed by the authorities.</p>
<p>Although the two firms cited tax and legal complications as obstacles to the merger, analysts said Thai Danu may have backed down also because of Finance One's serious cash flow problems.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662)-6520642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
