<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628213" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Indonesian coffee farmers to benefit from rally.</title>
<headline>Indonesian coffee farmers to benefit from rally.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian coffee farmers and exporters are likely to make some money from the searing rally in world coffee markets, but worries over defaults by arabica producers are increasing, traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The Indonesians are going to make some money out of this,&quot; a veteran coffee dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;The farmers will reap a lot of money this year, but the crop is also down. I know of some farmers whose harvest will be 50 percent lower than what they had last year. That sort of evens out,&quot; a trader for a European dealing house said.  </p>
<p>One dealer said those Indonesian exporters will benefit who are fixing their prices for nearby months over the next few days in their contracts. But those who pre-sold their crop before the recent rally erupted will lose out.</p>
<p>July arabicas in New York shattered the US$3.00 a lb level on Thursday in frenzied buying to hit a 20-year high of 318.00 cents. The contract closed 19.25 cents up on the day at 314.80 cents/lb.</p>
<p>London's July robusta contract hit a peak of $2,670 yesterday before finishing at $2,600, a $342 gain on the day.  </p>
<p>Despite the sky-high prices, the local market in Indonesia is also an attractive option for local coffee farmers.</p>
<p>&quot;Local prices in Indonesia are pretty high,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>One cause for concern in the trade would be defaults by arabica exporters.</p>
<p>&quot;For those getting arabica from Indonesia, that may soon become a problem,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Traders estimate that about 60-80 percent of the Indonesian crop has already been harvested. The total exportable crop for this year will probably reach 240,000-260,000 tonnes, down sharply from the more than 300,000 tonnes last year.  </p>
<p>Coffee consumption in Asia may eventually suffer from the surge in prices, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Coffee consumption here is growing. But with this thing, it might suffer,&quot; one dealer said. &quot;It will affect consumption, but not immediately.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers predicted that local roasters around Asia will have to eventually pass on the increased cost of the beans to consumers.</p>
<p>&quot;You can't expect local roasters to absorb the increase,&quot; one said. </p>
<p>-- Rene Pastor, Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
<p>singapore.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
