<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628404" id="root" date="1997-05-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - May 30.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - May 30.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights of stories in the Danish press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>POLITIKEN</p>
<p>-- There are at least 2,000 unemployed in the Copenhagen region who, although obliged to take job training or further education, are doing nothing.</p>
<p>--Sophus Berendsen caught the stock market napping on Thursday with a surprise announcement that it intended to split into two listed companies.</p>
<p>--Some 900 hourly-paid workers at hi-fi maker Bang &amp; Olufsen stopped work on Thursday over a pay dispute. They are to meet on Saturday to discuss further action.</p>
<p>BERLINGSKE TIDENDE</p>
<p>--Publisher Egmont's picture magazine He r&amp; Nu (Here and Now) is doing well and posing stiff competition for Aller's Se &amp; Hoer (See and Hear).</p>
<p>--Copenhagen's year as European cultural capital has left the organisers with debts at least 15 million crowns and the threat of bankruptcy.</p>
<p>--The transport board believes that more taxes are needed in order to reduce air pollution from vehicles.</p>
<p>JYLLANDS-POSTEN</p>
<p>--The planned Berendsen split will bring hidden value to light and create a windfall of billions of crowns for shareholders.</p>
<p>--April unemployment of 7.9 percent was the lowest in a decade.</p>
<p>BORSEN</p>
<p>--Den Danske Bank and Unibank expect to win back some 100 billion crowns in lost loan business by extending their telephone banking hours through the evenings and weekends. For example a housebuyer could ring on Sunday after viewing property and get a mortgage offer to compete with that offered by the estate agent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
