<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628556" id="root" date="1997-05-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICA HURTING BUT NO EARLY RATE RELIEF IN SIGHT.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICA HURTING BUT NO EARLY RATE RELIEF IN SIGHT.</headline>
<byline>Ben Hirschler</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-05-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mounting evidence of a sharp slowdown in the South African economy is piling on the pressure for a cut in the country's punitively high interest rates.</p>
<p>But economists said on Friday Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals would not budge until the impact of the July 1 easing of exchange controls on individuals could be assessed, possibly towards the end of the third quarter.</p>
<p>The case for easing the monetary brakes appears strong. The rand has stabilised, money market liquidity is improving, privatisation receipts will boost precariously low reserves -- and the real economy is hurting.</p>
<p>But the conservative central banker insisted this week that there could be no early move until inflation, money supply and credit growth showed clear signs of coming under control.</p>
<p>Inflation hit a 22-month high of 9.9 percent in April while money supply and credit growth showed no significant slowdown, although analysts believe all three indicators are now peaking.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not going to come down (cut rates) soon, certainly. But we will watch it very carefully,&quot; Stals told Reuters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The next day South Africa's financial markets were jolted by news that the economy shrank 0.8 percent on a quarter-on-quarter annualised basis in the three months to March.</p>
<p>That sent economists back to the drawing-board on full-year forecasts with most now looking for meagre growth of between 1.5 and 2.0 percent, against a consesus of 2.4 percent two months ago.</p>
<p>That would put GDP expansion well short of the target of 2.9 percent for 1997 contained in the government's macroeconomic strategy of last June or even the 2.5 in the March 12 budget.</p>
<p>&quot;It confirms what one has picked up anecdotally, that businesses are suffering, that final consumer demand has slowed down and I think we are going to see more of this the year to come,&quot; said Rudolf Gouws of Rand Merchant Bank.</p>
<p>The increasing pain in the real economy -- also evidenced in rising bad debts at major banks -- puts Stals on the rack in deciding how soon it is safe to ease interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;His bind will continue for another few months, but we will see at least one cut in the fourth quarter, definitely,&quot; said Nedcor chief economist Dennis Dykes.</p>
<p>The shock of the first quarter GDP number triggered immediate hopes that an early rate cut was back on the cards. But by Friday those expectations were evaporating, triggering a retracement in both stocks and bonds.</p>
<p>Jac Laubscher, chief economist at mutual assurer Sanlam in Cape Town, said weak first quarter GDP cast a shadow over the rest of the year which Stals would have to take into account in setting monetary policy.</p>
<p>&quot;But I don't expect any change until there is a clear picture as to what exactly the implications are of the July 1 exchange control relaxation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>From the beginning of July individuals will be allowed to invest offshore or hold foreign currency bank accounts for the first time, although the authorities have yet to set the exact limits.</p>
<p>Stals and Finance Minister Trevor Manuel argue that in the long-term South Africa will gain by scrapping capital controls, thereby making the country a more attractive destination for investors.</p>
<p>But the risk of heavy short-term outflows is real and a cut in rates at a time when rates in the U.S. are turning up could further encourage any rush of capital for the door.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
