<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628669" id="root" date="1997-05-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia, Indonesia send island dispute to Hague.</title>
<headline>Malaysia, Indonesia send island dispute to Hague.</headline>
<byline>Bill Tarrant</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-05-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia and Indonesia signed a pact on Saturday formally submitting an island territorial dispute to the World Court, saying it could be a model for similar conflicts elsewhere.</p>
<p>Both countries claim the islands of Sipadan and Ligitan in the Celebes Sea off Borneo and have at times backed their claims with a show of naval force.</p>
<p>Last October, the two countries announced they would submit the long-standing sovereignty dispute to the International Court of Justice (ICJ), the main U.N. judicial body in The Hague.</p>
<p>&quot;I am strongly convinced that the decision to resolve the issue on the basis of international law could set a precedent for other countries in the region to follow,&quot; Malaysian Foreign Minister Abdullah Badawi said in a speech at the signing ceremony. &quot;Further, our decision to submit this issue to the ICJ for a final settlement also means that we will not be burdening future generations of both c ountries with an unresolved dispute.&quot; Indonesia's Foreign Minister Ali Alatas called the agreement an historic one. &quot;For it is the first time that our two countries have ever agreed modalities for a court settlement of a dispute between them.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if the settlement could be used as a model for settling conflicting claims to the Spratly islands, Alatas said: &quot;The Spratlys are different because six parties have overlapping claims.&quot;</p>
<p>Straddling vital sea lanes and sitting atop vast potential reserves of oil and natural gas, the Spratlys comprise about 200 islets, reefs and shoals which are claimed in whole or in part by China, Taiwan, the Philippines, Vietnam, Malaysia and Brunei. The latter four are members of the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN), which also includes Indonesia, Thailand and Singapore. Last month, ASEAN held talks about the Spratlys with China at a resort in southern China's Huangshan Mountain, the first time Beijing had ever agreed to discuss the dispute in a multilateral forum.</p>
<p>But the long-standing row flared anew earlier this month when Manila accused Beijing of sending armed naval ships into areas Filipinos occupy.</p>
<p>Days later, Philippine naval vessels drove away a Chinese expedition of radio hams from Scarborough Shoal, north of the Spratlys, and allowed fishermen to hoist the Philippine flag over the Chinese-claimed rocks.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, Alatas said, &quot;there is a growing trend among claimant countries that the dispute be resolved amicably. This is positive and contributes to confidence-building measures in the region.&quot;</p>
<p>While ASEAN could organise workshops to help find a solution, in the end the Spratlys issue &quot;can only be settled bilaterally among the claimant countries&quot;, he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
