<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628674" id="root" date="1997-05-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodian rival calls for prosecution over arms.</title>
<headline>Cambodian rival calls for prosecution over arms.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-05-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Political tension increased in Cambodia on Saturday with one of the country's two prime ministers calling for prosecution over what he says was an illegal importation of weapons by his rival.</p>
<p>The call by the office of co-Prime Minister Hun Sen came hours after the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) agreed to admit weapons Cambodia, Burma and Laos as full members of the group in July.</p>
<p>&quot;In order to avoid the disaster of war and the destruction of the nation, the cabinet of the Second Prime Minister (Hun Sen) demands that the military court prosecutor start investigating the illegal import of many weapons, immediately and thoroughly,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>A complaint should be filed in court and sentences passed according to the law, it said.</p>
<p>Hun Sen said earlier that a shipment of weapons found last Monday at Cambodia's main port was being illegally imported by First Prime Minister Prince Norodom Ranariddh.</p>
<p>Ranariddh said the shipment was not illegal and he was entitled to import weapons. He said he needed arms, including anti-tank weapons, to defend himself against Hun Sen, who commanded many tanks.</p>
<p>Ranariddh was not available for comment on Saturday.</p>
<p>Political tension has been high in Phnom Penh for several months. Diplomats say the animosity between the two prime ministers stems from disagreement over power-sharing in the run-up to elections due next year.</p>
<p>On Wednesday a shot was fired at Hun Sen's bullet-proof car as he travelled through the outskirts of the capital. He was unhurt but a motor cycle escort rider was slightly wounded. Police are hunting for two suspects.</p>
<p>Cambodia's fractured coalition was formed in 1993 after United Nations-supervised elections in which Ranariddh's party won 58 seats in the 120-member house, against 51 for Hun Sen's party.</p>
<p>Foreign ministers from the seven-member ASEAN decided in Kuala Lumpur on Saturday that Cambodia, Laos and Burma will become full members of the group in July.</p>
<p>The offices of both Cambodian premiers welcomed the decision.</p>
<p>There had been speculation among officials in the region that the admission of the three might be put off until December due to concern about Cambodia's political problems and human rights and the suppression of democracy in Burma.</p>
<p>Political analysts said membership of the regional association could contribute to political stability in Cambodia.</p>
<p>ASEAN currently groups Brunei, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LAOS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
