<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628608" id="root" date="1997-05-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - May 31.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - May 31.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-05-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are significant stories in the Nigerian press on Saturday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY TIMES</p>
<p>- Nigeria says holding sub-regional consultations on appropriate action to be taken over last Sunday's coup in Sierra Leone.</p>
<p>- British negotiators blame European airline competitors for deadlock in talks to end a mutual ban by Nigeria and Britain on each other's aircraft.</p>
<p>- Prices of perishable food items have fallen in Lagos markets, signalling plentiful harvest is around.</p>
<p>- Four persons aspiring to contest governorship election in Ondo state have been arrested by the police for erecting campaign billboards without permission.</p>
<p>- Board of directors of the $4 billion Nigerian Liquefied Natural Gas Company has been dissolved with immediate effect.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>- Central bank governor Paul Ogwuma predicts faster economic growth, saying days of Nigeria's economic nightmare were over.</p>
<p>- Electoral commission denies releasing list of constituences for elections, saying recent reports to that effect are speculative.</p>
<p>THISDAY</p>
<p>- Demand for foreign exchange at weekly auction falls further to $58.47 million from $63.7 million last week.</p>
<p>- The two warring factions in the National Centre Party of Nigeria say they have now resolved their differences.</p>
<p>- Exiled Nobel laureate Wole Soyinka, an oponent of the Nigerian military government, describes Nigeria's efforts to restore Sierra Leone's deposed president as a ploy by its military rulers to curry international support for themselves.</p>
<p>($1=85)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
