<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628715" id="root" date="1997-05-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai dissident's brother to submit protest.</title>
<headline>Shanghai dissident's brother to submit protest.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-05-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The older brother of two jailed Shanghai dissidents has gone to Beijing to protest to parliament about the continued deprivation of his siblings' rights, a human rights organisation said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Yao Zhenyi, brother of dissidents Yao Zhenxian and Yao Zhenxiang, was due to arrive in Beijing on Friday to submit a protest letter to the National People's Congress (NPC), the Hong Kong-based Information Centre of Human Rights and Democratic Movement in China said in a faxed statement.</p>
<p>The organisation could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>The brothers, long-time supporters of the democracy movement in China, were arrested in April 1996 and sent to a &quot;reform through labour&quot; camp in Jiangsu province, north of Shanghai.</p>
<p>They were accused of illegally leaving China and distributing pornographic materials.</p>
<p>Yao Zhenxian began a hunger strike in April this year to protest deprivation of his rights to correspondence, and it was not known if he was still alive, the faxed statement said.</p>
<p>Yao Zhenxiang's family had not been permitted to see him for more than a year, it said.</p>
<p>Yao Zhenxiang fled to Hong Kong in 1994 and was granted political asylum in France. He returned to Shanghai in February 1996 after the police had promised not to arrest him.</p>
<p>The wife of Yao Zhenxian wrote a letter to the NPC in March protesting his continued confinement and demanding to see him.</p>
<p>Zhang Yueyin said then that she had not been allowed to see her husband since last October and that both men were in poor health and were not receiving adequate medical attention.</p>
<p>Her letter called on the Chinese authorities to allow the brothers to appeal their detention.</p>
<p>Under the terms of &quot;reform through labour&quot;, people can be sent to labour camps for up to three years without having to be sentenced in a court of law, at the discretion of the Public Security Bureau.</p>
<p>Chinese officials could not be immediately contacted for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
