<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="62872" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan stocks close slightly higher amid caution.</title>
<headline>Taiwan stocks close slightly higher amid caution.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan share prices erased early losses to finish slightly higher on Wednesday, but sentiment was cautious as the index inched towards 6,600, a key technical and psychological resistance level, brokers said.</p>
<p>The weighted index ended 20.58 points or 0.32 percent higher at 6,499.02, having recovered from an opening low of 6,452.37. Turnover was T$45.13 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Profit-taking pressure is expected to intensify as the index inches higher,&quot; said Michael Chien of China Securities.</p>
<p>State efforts to boost Taiwan's economy and Wall Street's recent gains helped to prevent a sharp fall, they said.  </p>
<p>High-tech and electronics shares rose for a second day, buoyed by the sector's strong recent rebound on Wall Street.</p>
<p>The electronics and machinery sector was up 1.17 percent.</p>
<p>Most-active issue Acer Inc was up 90 cents or 2.3 percent to T$40.1 while its affiliate, Acer Sertek Co, soared the daily seven percent limit to T$37.4 on its listing debut. Brokers said the newcomer's &quot;honeymoon&quot; could last a few more days. Textiles also were strong on improving profit outlooks, up 1.44 percent. Hualon advanced 40 cents or 1.63 percent to T$25.  </p>
<p>Reports of a T$1.05 billion banknote fraud scandal involving two local securities brokerages had not had a significant impact on the market, brokers said.</p>
<p>Brokers saw a slowly firming trend for the market, but said the performance of the heavily weighted financials would determine whether the index could breach the key resistance.</p>
<p>A range of 6,400-6,500 was seen for Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Alice Hung (2-5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
