<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628827" id="root" date="1997-05-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's Ciampi says delay in launch would kill EMU.</title>
<headline>Italy's Ciampi says delay in launch would kill EMU.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-05-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian Treasury Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi was quoted on Saturday as saying that delaying the launch of a planned European single currency, the euro, would kill the entire project.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not at all pleased with what's happening in Germany,&quot; Ciampi said, referring to a rift between the German government and central bank over Bonn's plans to revalue gold reserves in a bid to help Germany qualify for the single currency.</p>
<p>&quot;None of us has ever spoken of delaying the euro: it would be the end of the project,&quot; Ciampi told Rome's La Repubblica daily in an interview.</p>
<p>His comments contrasted with those of Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer, who is reported to have asked whether Germany and France can consider delaying the start of European monetary union (EMU) set for January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>Germany's Der Spiegel magazine on Saturday quoted Tietmeyer in an article to be published this week as saying: &quot;Wouldn't it be a possibility, together with France, to agree to a delay in the start of the euro?&quot;</p>
<p>Ciampi said Italy was worried about growing pressure in Germany and France to delay the euro's launch, but added that Italy must not back down from its commitment to clean up its finances and qualify for the single currency.</p>
<p>&quot;If problems are increasing elsewhere, we in any case must not stop trying to solve ours,&quot; Ciampi said.</p>
<p>&quot;The difficulties of others could even help Italy. And thus, I insist: let's take advantage of this situation,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
