<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628822" id="root" date="1997-05-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's Chirac doomed to &quot;cohabit&quot; whoever wins.</title>
<headline>France's Chirac doomed to &quot;cohabit&quot; whoever wins.</headline>
<byline>Paul Taylor</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-05-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Whoever wins Sunday's cliffhanger French parliamentary election runoff, a weakened President Jacques Chirac is doomed to &quot;cohabit&quot; in power with a political rival with presidential ambitions of his own.</p>
<p>Indeed Chirac's best hope of preserving his authority may now be for the election to end in a virtual dead heat that might just enable him to call on an elder statesman or non-political figure to form a consensus government rather than either a left-wing or a centre-right victory.</p>
<p>If the left converts its lead in last Sunday's first round into a majority of seats, Chirac will have little choice but to name Socialist party leader Lionel Jospin, 59, his unsuccessful challenger for the presidency in 1995, as prime minister.</p>
<p>A left-wing victory would severely diminish Chirac's power, leaving him with a say in foreign affairs and defence but unable to make domestic policy, except by using the moral weight of the presidential bully-pulpit, as his Socialist predecessor, the late Francois Mitterrand, did so skilfully.</p>
<p>He might eventually recover his power by picking the right moment to dissolve parliament again and regain a conservative majority in another election, but such an opportunity would be unlikely to arise for a couple of years, if it ever did.</p>
<p>If the centre-right stages a comeback win on Sunday, the president will have to appoint Philippe Seguin, 54, as premier.</p>
<p>Seguin, a left-wing Gaullist who led a 1990 rebellion against Chirac in the party and campaigned against him for a &quot;no&quot; to the Maastricht treaty in 1992, makes little secret of his determination to seek the presidency, nor of his contempt for Chirac's judgment.</p>
<p>When Chirac dissolved parliament last month to call the snap poll which has turned out so risky for the right, he summoned Seguin for consultations, as the constitution requires.</p>
<p>The National Assembly speaker made clear he thought the dissolution 10 months early was a foolish move which could explode in the president's face. Events have proved him right.</p>
<p>In his first campaign speeches, Seguin railed as much against the European policy of Chirac and Prime Minister Alain Juppe, his generational rival in the Gaullist party, as against the Socialist opposition.</p>
<p>Within hours of being called in as last-minute salvage man for the right's campaign after Juppe took responsibility for last Sunday's debacle and agreed to resign, Seguin had dropped the outgoing premier's plan for a 40-day blitz of market-oriented reforms.</p>
<p>No one know what Seguin would do if he entered the prime minister's Matignon office on Monday because he has given little clue as to his economic policies, other than to say he would wage an all-out war on unemployment and that he opposes a strict interpretation of the conditions for a single European currency.</p>
<p>Both Jospin and Seguin would be much more difficult to work with than Juppe, the president's most loyal and longest-serving political associate, who began as a speechwriter when Chirac was prime minister for the first time in 1976.</p>
<p>Jospin's steady nerves and cool manner would be assets in fencing with the impulsive, hot-blooded president.</p>
<p>The chain-smoking Seguin's own volcanic temper, withering sarcasm and unpredictablility could be just as much of a handful for Chirac.</p>
<p>If Seguin proves to be the right's saviour, he can be relied on to remind the president regularly who saved him.</p>
<p>Either way, Chirac is in for a less comfortable ride, and his stature on the international stage, where he had hoped to emerge as Europe's strongest leader with a renewed majority for five years, seems bound to be diminished.</p>
<p>Whether Jospin or Seguin is premier, France is likely to be seen as a trickier, less reliable partner, both in the drive for European monetary union and in the reorganisation of European and Atlantic security.</p>
<p>Both Jospin and Seguin oppose France's full return to NATO's military wing unless the United States yields a substantially greater share of power to the European allies than Washington has shown any willingness to contemplate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
