<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628818" id="root" date="1997-05-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish ruling group trails ahead of election-poll.</title>
<headline>Irish ruling group trails ahead of election-poll.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-05-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish Prime Minister John Bruton's ruling coalition lags ten points behind its chief opponents in the run-up to national elections next Friday, according to a poll on Saturday.</p>
<p>The survey put support for the main opposition Fianna Fail and smaller Progressive Democratic party at a combined 49 percent, bringing them close to securing a majority in the Dail, the Irish parliament, The Irish Times newspaper reported.</p>
<p>The total support for Fine Gael, led by Bruton, and his partner Labour and Democratic Left parties was 39 perent. Fine Gael was largest with 26 per cent voter rating, unchanged since the previous poll on May 20.</p>
<p>As well as declaring support for individual parties, voters were asked which combination they wanted if a coalition were to form the next government.</p>
<p>The result showed no change. A centre-right Fianna Fail and Progressive Democrat alliance was preferred by 44 per cent, six points ahead of the ruling &quot;rainbow coalition&quot;.</p>
<p>With Bruton's ruling centre-left group unable to make a major dent in an opposition lead in recent weeks his hold on power seemed to be slipping, bolstering forecasts of a hung Dail or a centre-right win.</p>
<p>In the survey Fianna Fail got 42 per cent support, down one point. The Progressive Democrats were unchanged at seven percent.</p>
<p>&quot;With a combined strength of 39 per cent at this stage, and with less than a week to go, the Government parties would require a political miracle to be returned to power,&quot; commented Denis Coghlan, Irish Times Chief political correspondent.</p>
<p>The Irish Times/MRBI poll was conducted among a quota of 1000 electors at 100 sampling points in all constituencies last Wednesday.</p>
<p>Labour was up one point, to 11 per cent. Democratic Left was unchanged on two per cent. Green Party was up one per cent to four per cent. Other parties were on eight per cent. They include Sinn Fein, the IRA's political arm, on a single point, down one point, and the left-wing Workers Party who gained a point to a new one per cent rating.</p>
<p>In line with the minimal shift in public opinion, the level of undecided voters dipped by just two points to 14 per cent since the May 20 survey.</p>
<p>Commenting on the survey's finding that Bruton's administration has a 57 per cent &quot;satisfaction rate&quot; with voters, Coghlan wrote that &quot;the way things are going, the Rainbow Coalition will become the most popular government ever to lose a general election&quot;.</p>
<p>Coghlan said a jump in support for the Green Party in Dublin could leave it with four or five seats, holding a balance of power. Independents are expected to do well, he wrote.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein whose Irish Republican Army ally is waging a sporadic guerrilla war against British rule in neighbouring Northern Ireland says it can win a seat.</p>
<p>&quot;It doesn't look as if Fianna Fail and the Progressive Democratics will get the kind of Dail majority they were looking for, so neither of the coalition options might win this election, and the Greens may be taken in to make up the numbers,&quot; Coghlan said in an RTE radio interview.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Fianna Fail/Progressive Democrats) may do it on their own. What seems to be clear is that Bertie Ahern is probably going to be the next Taoiseach (prime minister). The Green party may be required in negotiations to fill that gap,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
