<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628932" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: HANDBALL-RUSSIA BEAT SWEDEN TO LIFT WORLD CROWN.</title>
<headline>HANDBALL-RUSSIA BEAT SWEDEN TO LIFT WORLD CROWN.</headline>
<dateline>KUMAMOTO, Japan 1997-06-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia defeated Sweden 23-21 to win the men's handball world championship on Sunday. The Russians were unbeaten in the 15-day tournament.</p>
<p>&quot;Our players were more relaxed today than in Saturday's match,&quot; said Russian head coach Vladimir Maximov, referring to their ill-tempered semifinal against France. &quot;They learned the lessons from yesterday and stayed calm and cool and made the right judgements at the right time,&quot; added Maximov, who praised goalkeeper Andrei Lavrov -- who made 12 saves in 33 attempts -- and defenders Igor Lavrov, Viatcheslav Atavan and Viatcheslav Gorpichine. Valery Gopine led the scoring for Russia with five goals in seven attempts. But Sweden made a great fight of the final and their coach Bengt Johansson praised his team and the Russians. But he was less generous to the referees, saying: &quot;The referee team was the loser in this tournament. The referees are, in a word, the problem in the development of handball.&quot; Sweden's attack was driven by Magnus Wislander with six goals in eight attempts, and Stefan Loevgren, who hit five out of seven. Sweden led until the last minute of the first half before Russi</p>
<p>Defending champions France took third place with a 28-27 win over Hungary, driven by Stephane Joulin's 10 goals and an eight-goal performance by Stephane Stoecklin.</p>
<p>South Korean Yoon Kyung-shin, who scored 62 goals in 110 tries was top goalscorer for the second consecutive world championship. Compatriot Lee Suk-hyung won top goalkeeper ranking by stopping 89 out of 301 shots.</p>
<p>Spain's Dujshebaev Talant was named most valuable player of the tournament.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUMAMOTO, Japan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
