<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="628904" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MOTOR RACING-MOORE WINS GAMBLE ON FUEL, BECOMES YOUNGEST WINNER.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-MOORE WINS GAMBLE ON FUEL, BECOMES YOUNGEST WINNER.</headline>
<dateline>WEST ALLIS, Wisconsin 1997-06-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian Greg Moore won a gamble on fuel economy and held off hard-charging Michael Andretti to become the youngest driver ever to win a CART series event by taking the Milwaukee 200 IndyCar race on Sunday.</p>
<p>Moore, driving a Reynard Mercedes-Benz had a .348 of a second margin over Andretti, a five-time winner at the one-mile oval, in a Swift Ford. Third place went to American Jimmy Vasser in a Reynard Honda, 10.66 seconds behind.</p>
<p>&quot;It's about time we've got one,&quot; said the 22-year-old Moore, who averaged 119.597 miles per hour (192.47 kph) for the 200-lap event.</p>
<p>The relief of getting his first win was evident for Moore, who finished second at Surfers Paradise Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;It does take a lot of pressure off,&quot; said Moore. &quot;For a while I was wondering what I had to do to win one of these things.&quot;</p>
<p>Said Andretti: &quot;I knew we had a good race car today and I ran the best I could do, driving it as hard as I could. But it just wasn't enough.&quot;</p>
<p>With his second-place finish, Andretti moved into second place in the series standings behind Canadian Paul Tracy (94 points to 70), who finished sixth.</p>
<p>Moore took the lead on lap 135 and stayed on the track, gambling he had enough fuel to last him. He won the gamble and led the last 66 laps after polesitter Tracy dove into the pits for fuel and tires.</p>
<p>A dejected Tracy said &quot;we decided on our pit strategy but it didn't work out for us today.&quot; Tracy had won the last three races thanks in large measure to successful pit-stop strategy.</p>
<p>Although Tracy was able to hold his lead early in the race his Penske Mercedes-Benz didn't run as well in traffic as Moore's. Twice Moore caught Tracy only to turn over the lead coming out of the pits.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew I was faster in traffic so I was comfortable running behind Tracy in traffic,&quot; said Moore, who led for 104 laps in all, while Tracy led the other 96.</p>
<p>There were four cautions due to crashes but none of the drivers were injured.</p>
<p>The series resumes next week in Detroit for the eighth event in the 17-race series.</p>
<p>In an Indy Lights event run at the track, Clint Mears, son of four-time Indy 500 winner Rick Mears, won his first professional race, driving a Lola Buick.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WEST ALLIS, Wisconsin"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
