<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629047" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Battle for UK Conservative leadership hots up.</title>
<headline>Battle for UK Conservative leadership hots up.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The battle for the future leadership of Britain's opposition Conservatives heated up on Sunday when the party's deputy leader Michael Heseltine backed former finance minister Kenneth Clarke and warned the party's Eurosceptic right not to rule out joining a single European currency.</p>
<p>He told them his centre-left wing of the party would be &quot;deeply dismayed&quot; if they ruled out as a matter of principle Britain ever joining a single European currency.</p>
<p>Then he said that if they ganged up to prevent Clarke, the most pro-European member of John Major's old cabinet, winning this month's leadership election, the party would lose even more popular esteem.</p>
<p>The Conservatives' May 1 election defeat after 18 years in office was partly attributed to party splits over Europe.</p>
<p>Leader John Major immediately stepped down, triggering an election fight among six former cabinet members for his job. Four of the candidates are on the right and centre right of the party, leaving only Clarke and outsider Stephen Dorrell as standard bearers for the centre-left. Heseltine, who is 64, has ruled himself out because of ill health.</p>
<p>But in an article in the Sunday Times newspaper endorsing Clarke's candidature, Heseltine gave a warning that if the right went too far, it would make party unity, the basic ingredient for a fight-back, impossible.</p>
<p>&quot;Unity requires mutual tolerance and respect. Keeping options open on Europe is part of that process,&quot; he wrote. Saying a move to rule out a single currency on principle would be &quot;unwise and unrealistic&quot;, he added: &quot;Those of us who remained loyal to John Major...would be deeply dismayed by any move in that direction&quot;.</p>
<p>Because of the gaggle of right-wing candidates, Clarke is reckoned likely to head the June 10 poll, but not to get backing from the required overall majority of the 164 Conservative MPs.</p>
<p>Runner-up could be William Hague, the 36-year-old former Welsh Secretary.</p>
<p>Hague said in a BBC television interview on Sunday that while he would not categorically rule out a single currency for all time, &quot;in the shape or form that is proposed today, in the Europe that we have today, we should not agree to it.</p>
<p>An article in the Sunday Times suggested that three of the right-wing candidates, Michael Howard, Peter Lilley and John Redwood were preparing to mount a stop-Clarke campaign after the result of the June 10 vote was known.</p>
<p>The two who fared worst on June 10 would drop out to allow their backers to concentrate support on the third in the second round of voting on June 17, it said.</p>
<p>Lilley and Redwood both denied they were plotting against Clarke in Sunday television interviews, although Redwood said: &quot;We will have to look at this situation when we see the first round ballot results.&quot;</p>
<p>But Heseltine said in a BBC radio interview: &quot;I hope the party is not going to say well, Ken is a long way ahead on the first ballot, now we have got to find a way of stopping him'.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Frankly that is not to way to win popular esteem. That is not the way to command the heights.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
