<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629092" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chances for US bond simplification growing - NAST.</title>
<headline>Chances for US bond simplification growing - NAST.</headline>
<dateline>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. 1997-06-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A National Association of State Treasurers official said Saturday that chances are improving that bond &quot;simplification&quot; measures will land in a major tax bill being drafted by U.S. House Ways and Means Committee Chairman Bill Archer, R-Texas.</p>
<p>Christopher Allen, director of federal relations for the treasurers group, made the statement during a workshop at the Government Finance Officers Association's annual meeting here.</p>
<p>&quot;I've had conversations with individuals working on ... elements of the President' proposal,&quot; Allen said.</p>
<p>&quot;They indicated that staff of the Ways and Means Committee look favorably toward including the President's simplification package in the chairman's mark,&quot; Allen said,</p>
<p>The Clinton Administration in mid-April asked Congress to adopt a variety of provisions to simplify the nation's tax code, including five proposals to ease the Internal Revenue Service's arbitrage rebate rules.</p>
<p>The White House plan would, for example, exempt from arbitrage rebate those governmental bond issues that have a weighted average maturity of at least 10 years and that meet certain minimum spending requirements.</p>
<p>((-- Vicky Stamas, 954-523-6511))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
