<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629198" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>Australia: TIMELINES-Today in History - June 2.</title>
<headline>TIMELINES-Today in History - June 2.</headline>
<text>
<p>**  BIRTHDAYS **</p>
<p>Australian pioneer WILLIAM LAWSON, who surveyed the route across the Blue Mountains of New South Wales and took the first stock west to establish grazing at Bathurst and Mudgee, was born in 1774.</p>
<p>Surgeon ALEXANDER COLLIE, who became a pioneer in Western Australia and discovered the Collie River (South of Perth) with his Aboriginal companion MAKKARE, was born in 1793.  </p>
<p>British geologist WILLIAM CLARKE, who was the first to find gold in Australia, was born in 1798.</p>
<p>British journalist CHARLES KEMP, who became the editor of the 'Sydney Herald', was born in 1813.</p>
<p>English novelist and poet THOMAS HARDY, whose tales were set in Wessex (&quot;Far From The Madding Crowd&quot; 1874, &quot;The Woodlanders&quot; 1887, &quot;Tess Of the D'Urbervilles&quot; 1891), was born in 1840.  </p>
<p>English composer SIR EDWARD ELGAR was born in 1857. German film animator LOTTE REINIGER, who made the first full-length animated film in 1920 (&quot;The Adventures Of Prince Achmed&quot;), was born in 1899.</p>
<p>American Olympic swimming champion and actor JOHNNY WEISMULLER, who attracted more fame for playing &quot;Tarzan&quot;, was born in 1904. He was the first man to swim 100-metres in less than a minute (recording 58-point-6 seconds on July the 9th, 1922), and died on the 20th of January 1984.  </p>
<p>Australian artist THOMAS GLEGHORN was born in 1925.</p>
<p>American actress SALLY KELLERMAN, best known for her role as &quot;Hotlips Houlihan&quot; in the film version of M*A*S*H, was born in 1938. (LORETTA SWIT played the part in the tv series).</p>
<p>British drummer CHARLIE WATTS, who began his career with &quot;Blues Incorporated&quot; in 1961 before becoming a founding member of &quot;The Rolling Stones&quot; the following year, was born in 1941.  </p>
<p>Australian journalist MICHAEL WILLESSEE, who is said to have pioneered the &quot;foot-in-the-door&quot; tv interview, was born in 1942. US bass player MICHAEL STEELE, singer and songwriter for the 'Bangles', was born in 1959.</p>
<p>British singer TONY HADLEY, who was a founding member of &quot;The Makers&quot; in 1976 (the group became &quot;Spandau Ballet&quot; in 1979), was born in 1960.</p>
<p>			  **  EVENTS **</p>
<p>1780: A new horse race was run at Epsom Downs in the South of England, called the &quot;Derby&quot; after EDWARD STANLEY, the 12th EARL OF DERBY.</p>
<p>1868: The British crushed the Marathas in India and annexed their lands.</p>
<p>1896: Italian-born physicist GUGLIELMO MARCONI took-out the first patent for his wireless telegraphy apparatus, that broadcast sound over long distances by means of radio waves.  </p>
<p>1946: Italy's monarchy was abolished, and the country became a republic.</p>
<p>1953:PRINCESS ELIZABETH ALEXANDRA MARY was crowned by the Archbishop of Canterbury, becoming QUEEN ELIZABETH II of Great Britain and Ireland. Married in 1947 to her distant cousin PRINCE PHILLIP OF GREECE (now the DUKE OF EDINBURGH), ELIZABETH had been representing the Royal Family since 1951 due to the ill health of her father, KING GEORGE VI.  </p>
<p>1964: The Palestinian Liberation Organistion (PLO) was formed in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>1966: The American automatic spacecraft &quot;Surveyor&quot; landed in the south-west part of the Moon's Oceanus Procellanum.</p>
<p>1985: English soccer clubs were banned from playing in Europe, because of incidents of hooliganism by football supporters.  </p>
<p>1990: British actor SIR REX (CAREY) HARRISON died at the age of 82. He was best remembered for his role of PROFESSOR HENRY HIGGINS in the hit musical &quot;My Fair Lady&quot;.</p>
<p>(Compiled from ABC ARCHIVES, ABC RADIO NATIONAL, &quot;On This Day&quot; published by REED INTERNATIONAL BOOKS LIMITED, &quot;The Chronicle Of The 20th Century&quot; published by PENGUIN BOOKS and &quot;Rock And Pop (Day By Day)&quot; published by BLANDFORD BOOKS.)</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
