<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629103" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada may pick fractious Parliament in tight vote.</title>
<headline>Canada may pick fractious Parliament in tight vote.</headline>
<byline>Randall Palmer</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-06-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>When Canadian Prime Minister Jean Chretien campaigned in Alberta and British Columbia last week, he recited all the benefits his Liberal government had brought to the western regions.</p>
<p>Yet no sooner had his Boeing 737 touched down in Ontario than he regaled an airport rally with how he had temporarily withheld cash from the two provinces during his mandate until they agreed to adhere to federal health and welfare standards.</p>
<p>The contrast served as a poignant signal of how regionalized Canadian politics has become as voters go to the polls on Monday, with different messages for different regions, one area often pitted against the other.</p>
<p>In fact, if polling trends are borne out, Canada could end up with four or five regional parties in a deadlocked Parliament, with even the Liberals possibly finding it tough to speak for the nation as a whole.</p>
<p>&quot;The way it looks to me now is you'll have this massive bloc of Liberal votes in Ontario and you won't have the kind of support for the Liberals across the country that you had in the last outcome (in 1993),&quot; University of Toronto political scientist David Cameron commented.</p>
<p>&quot;Their capacity to assert themselves as a national party, and more seriously perhaps their capacity to understand the country and have it reflected in their councils is going to be reduced.&quot;</p>
<p>Most projections see the Liberals getting close to two-thirds of their seats from Ontario, with the rest of their support concentrated in Quebec and Atlantic Canada. They could well win a reduced majority or maybe even a minority due to a lackluster campaign.</p>
<p>In a television interview on Sunday, Chretien brushed away the concerns: &quot;I had a good campaign and I am optimistic about tomorrow's results.&quot;</p>
<p>Yet the protest Reform Party -- angry with big government, crime and what it sees as kid-glove treatment of French-speaking Quebec -- has taken a lock on British Columbia and Alberta with a few seats in the prairie provinces.</p>
<p>The Bloc Quebecois -- the second largest party in the last election -- runs candidates only in Quebec, which it wants to separate from Canada.</p>
<p>And the Conservatives, reduced in 1993 from a governing majority to only two out of 295 seats, could be reduced mainly to a base in Atlantic Canada and Quebec.</p>
<p>Again and again in the final week of campaigning, as he saw his still-substantial support waning, Chretien appealed for a broad mandate.</p>
<p>&quot;I need a strong government, with very strong members of Parliament like the ones you gave me in the last Parliament, and strong ministers from every region of Canada,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some of the most bitter feelings came out when Reform put out an ad saying Canada had had prime ministers from Quebec for too long -- 28 of the last 29 years -- and it was time for a voice for all Canadians, &quot;not just Quebec politicians.&quot;</p>
<p>That resonated well in the West, and consolidated Reform's position as likely to become the official opposition.</p>
<p>But it drew anger from all the politicians named in the ad -- Chretien, the Conservatives' Jean Charest, the Bloc Quebecois' Gilles Duceppe and Quebec Premier Lucien Bouchard.</p>
<p>&quot;That's the worst thing that could happen, to have such an anti-Quebec party as the official opposition,&quot; said Bouchard, a leading separatist.</p>
<p>Bouchard has said he plans to call another referendum on Quebec sovereignty if he gets a new mandate in the next provincial elections. He narrowly lost a referendum in 1995, and the country will need to decide how to handle a possible new vote along with any new demands Quebec might make.</p>
<p>Canada has been compared to a fractious family of a rich man who wrote a confusing will and left his children squabbling over the proceeds.</p>
<p>In the process, other issues have often been overshadowed: whether there should be broad tax relief or renewed emphasis on social programmes, whether there should be expanded rights or a return to traditional values, whether jobs can be created, whether abortion should be restricted or encouraged, whether more should be done to protect the environment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
