<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629139" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenya rally starts after protest leaders arrested.</title>
<headline>Kenya rally starts after protest leaders arrested.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bigg</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-06-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenyan security forces placed four leading opposition parliamentarians under house arrest in an effort to curb planned protests on Sunday at an annual presidential speech.</p>
<p>Amid heavy security, President Daniel arap Moi and guest of honour Tanzania President Benjamin Mkapa arrived at the state Madaraka (Self Rule) Day rally at central Uhuru (Freedom) Park.</p>
<p>The rally came a day after severe riots in the centre of Nairobi that erupted when security forces broke up a march by opposition activists demanding constitutional reform.</p>
<p>National Development Party (NDP) leader Raila Odinga, FORD-Asili chairman Kenneth Matiba, FORD-Kenya chairman Michael Kijana Wamalwa and Paul Muite, of FORD-Kenya and an activist in the unregistered Safina party, were placed under house arrest overnight, NDP secretary-general Charles Maranga and other activists told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The police and paramilitary units have surrounded their houses and they cannot get out. They are now under house arrest. We are condemning this action in the strongest terms possible,&quot; Maranga said.</p>
<p>Wamalwa told Reuters by telephone from his house: &quot;I am very frustrated. I wanted to go out there and see what would happen next.&quot; He said more than 100 troops had surrounded the building.</p>
<p>More than 10,000 people gathered to watch a military parade, fly past, songs and traditional dances ahead of Moi's speech. Scores of heavily armed police and troops deployed around the park early on Sunday and there was no sign of protests.</p>
<p>Central Nairobi was brought to a standstill on Saturday when security forces battled protestors after breaking up a banned rally by opposition and church leaders demanding constitutional change before elections later this year.</p>
<p>According to the East African Standard newspaper one person died after being stabbed. Scores of shops and stalls were looted and dozens of cars stoned in six hours of rioting. Shopkeepers made temporary repairs on Sunday and counted the cost of goods looted by thousands of rioters.</p>
<p>During the night an explosion started a fire in a building on opposition leader Matiba's property, David Kabeberi, an advisor to Matiba told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Something came from outside and exploded and burned part of the servants quarters,&quot; Kabeberi said, adding no one was injured.</p>
<p>Opposition leaders and churchmen gave conflicting advice on dealing with Sunday's state rally, acknowledging they had little time to co-ordinate plans.</p>
<p>&quot;What we want is to call on people to stay away from Madaraka Day, but to continue to agitate through a peaceful demonstration,&quot; Maranga said.</p>
<p>Timothy Njoya, a moderator of the Presbyterian Church of East Africa, said protesters should whistle at Moi's speech and then walk out.</p>
<p>Moi must call elections later this year pitting the ruling Kenya African National Union (KANU) against an opposition divided on ethnic, political and personal lines.</p>
<p>The National Convention Assembly (NCA), a coalition of opposition and church groups, called Saturday's rally to press for constitutional reform prior to elections. The government, which in 1995 promised reform, now says change is impossible within the election timetable. The NCA says fair elections are impossible under a one-party system.</p>
<p>&quot;Granting constitutional change after the election is like giving medicine to a person already dead,&quot; Njoya told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
