<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629102" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada election notable for its gaffes.</title>
<headline>Canada election notable for its gaffes.</headline>
<byline>Heather Scoffield</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-06-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The lasting image from the 1997 Canadian federal election campaign will likely be Bloc Quebecois leader Gilles Duceppe sporting a plastic shower cap during a tour of a cheese factory in Quebec.</p>
<p>Duceppe showed up on television across the country wearing the bonnet during the first week of the 36-day campaign, sending his party's fortunes into a tailspin and inspiring editorial cartoonists for the rest of the campaign leading up to the June 2 election.</p>
<p>Duceppe's unfortunate choice in headgear was certainly not the only gaffe of the campaign as five major political leaders competed to become prime minister.</p>
<p>Liberal Prime Minister Jean Chretien used a speech advocating gun control to warn Canadians about the danger of keeping nuclear weapons at home in case children got hold of them.</p>
<p>The leader of the leftist New Democratic Party, Alexa McDonough, did not make any major slips in her speeches across the country. But then again, she was hard to hear. She had laryngitis for days on end.</p>
<p>When she recovered, she boldly cried out for the legalisation of marijuana.</p>
<p>Conservative leader Jean Charest, whose popularity exploded during the campaign, puzzled voters when he spoke openly about his close friendship and frequent contact with the former Conservative prime minister Brian Mulroney, one of the most unpopular politicians in Canada.</p>
<p>And Reform Party leader Preston Manning used his campaign stops to publicise the &quot;Red Book II&quot; platform of Chretien's Liberal party -- a copy of which somehow fell into his hands two days before the Liberals planned to release it.</p>
<p>But one of the biggest foul-ups of the election campaign did not involve the five leaders jostling for supremacy.</p>
<p>Indeed, the politicians were stunned during a televised debate last month when the moderator brought argument to a sudden halt by fainting, keeling over and landing with a thud on the ground.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
