<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629146" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>albania: Prodi says Albania curfew to ease.</title>
<headline>Prodi says Albania curfew to ease.</headline>
<byline>Benet Koleka</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-06-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi said on Sunday that Albanian President Sali Berisha told him a curfew would be eased soon, meeting a major opposition concern ahead of early elections.</p>
<p>Prodi also said troops of the multi-national force in Albania would provide &quot;broad protection&quot; on polling day on June 29, suggesting a more active role than previously thought during the elections deemed crucial to Albania's stability.</p>
<p>Prodi defended his government's decision to revoke the nomination of a new ambassador to Albania, Manfredo Incisa di Camerana, who would have replaced an envoy, Paolo Foresti, accused by an Albanian newspaper of a pro-Berisha bias.</p>
<p>He said the decision was made after a newspaper quoted di Camerana as saying Foresti had always been politically aligned and the Italian Foreign Ministry was going through a period of weakness.</p>
<p>The row over the naming of an ambassador had cast confusion over Italy's leading role in European efforts to check its eastern neighbour's slide into anarchy.</p>
<p>&quot;President Berisha told me everything that can be done without new laws, including the shortening of the curfew hours, will be done in the coming days,&quot; Prodi told a news conference at the headquarters of the Italian-led multinational force.</p>
<p>&quot;I pleaded with him to make possible the election campaign not only in a way that was transparent but also so that every freedom can be respected. I will be saying the same things to Prime Minister Bashkim Fino,&quot; Prodi said.</p>
<p>&quot;I found the points of disagreement have been reduced to a minimum,&quot; he added before returning to Italy. &quot;I think they can have a regular and transparent electoral campaign.&quot;</p>
<p>Fino and his Socialist Party, the country's next largest after Berisha's Democratic Party, say a 9 p.m. to 5 a.m. curfew and a state of emergency imposed since March riots must be lifted to reduce the likelihood of electoral fraud.</p>
<p>Prodi did not say what the new curfew hours would be. Asked about the role of the 6,000-strong multinational force, he said: &quot;Of course there is no need to be present in each of the 4,000 polling stations.</p>
<p>&quot;But with the OSCE (Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe) we are making an agreement in order to ensure broad protection throughout the country. We have to guarantee free elections.&quot;</p>
<p>Under a barrage of questions from Italian journalists, Prodi defended his government's handling of the ambassadorial appointment and said it was separate from Italy's role at the head of the multinational force.</p>
<p>&quot;These problems do not have any reflection at all on the mission. It is an Italian problem and there are no problems within the Italian government,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The decisions taken for the ambassador were decisions that were shared specfically and expressly by the Ministry of Defence and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the Presidency of the Council of Ministers and all ministers in complete accord. These decisions were shared by all the government.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
