<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629273" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Troops search East Timor after fatal ambush.</title>
<headline>Troops search East Timor after fatal ambush.</headline>
<byline>Jim Della-Giacoma</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-06-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian troops searched on Sunday through steep hill country for East Timorese separatists who killed 17 security force members in a weekend ambush in the former Portuguese colony, police said.</p>
<p>They said the attackers killed the 16 policemen and one soldier on Saturday morning when they threw a grenade at the truck carrying 28 members of the security forces. It was the worst attack against Indonesian forces in East Timor in many years.</p>
<p>&quot;No one has been detained. Troops are still searching,&quot; East Timor deputy police chief Colonel Atok Rismanto said by telephone from the provincial capital, Dili.</p>
<p>Another 17 people died last Wednesday and Thursday during attacks by separatists seeking to disrupt Indonesia's general elections, in which the ruling Golkar won a sweeping 74 percent of the vote.</p>
<p>The official Antara news agency said those killed on Saturday had been members of an election security unit.</p>
<p>Rismanto denied an Antara report on Sunday that 18 police were killed in Saturday's attack near Abafala village in Quelcai district, about 20 km (12 miles) southeast of the territory's second city of Baucau.</p>
<p>&quot;There were only 17 victims, including one soldier,&quot; he said, adding that six police and one soldier were still in hospital with serious wounds.</p>
<p>Antara said 13 policemen died instantly in the truck. The others died &quot;while they were trying to flee the scene of the ambush&quot;.</p>
<p>Rismanto said there had been no other security problems in East Timor since the ambush and life was normal in Dili.</p>
<p>&quot;Church services are going ahead, people are going to market and others are swimming at the beach,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The ambush was part of the worst upsurge of violence in years in the territory, which Indonesia occupied in 1975 and annexed as its 27th province the following year. The United Nations has refused to recognise Indonesian sovereignty.</p>
<p>East Timor police chief Colonel Yusuf Muharam said on Saturday that police had detained 22 suspects -- including 13 &quot;rebels&quot; and nine supporters -- in connection with an attack on a police station in Dili in which four rebels were killed on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>Twelve civilians and one soldier were shot in another three separate incidents.</p>
<p>One diplomatic source said it was unclear whether the latest ambush signalled a longer-term escalation of violence.</p>
<p>The Indonesian military, which maintains a strong presence in East Timor, says about 80 poorly armed guerrillas remain in the rugged hills in the territory. Other sources suggest there are around 200.</p>
<p>Jakarta officially has five full battalions of troops as well as other units in East Timor numbering around 5,000 men, far more than in neighbouring provinces with much larger populations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
