<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629473" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Chirac's haste trips him up yet again.</title>
<headline>Chirac's haste trips him up yet again.</headline>
<byline>Paul Taylor</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac, whose power will be greatly diminished after just two years in office by a left-wing parliamentary majority, shot himself in the foot by calling a snap election 10 months early.</p>
<p>For the umpteenth time in his see-saw career, the impulsive Gaullist president was in too much of a hurry and misjudged the mood of the electorate, analysts say.</p>
<p>Chirac's supporters have tried to blame the debacle on Prime Minister Alain Juppe and two key technocrats who run the president's and premier's offices, Dominique de Villepin and Maurice Gourdault-Montagne, accused of having stampeded the president into an unwise dissolution of the National Assembly.</p>
<p>But while he has often been swayed by back-room gurus, notably Gaullist advisers Pierre Juillet and Marie-France Garaud in the 1970s, Chirac ultimately takes his own decisions.</p>
<p>In the fable of the tortoise and the hare, Chirac is always the hare.</p>
<p>Socialist leader Lionel Jospin, his unsuccessful challenger in the 1995 presidential election, has turned out to be a plodding but remarkably steady tortoise.</p>
<p>Ill-judged haste was not Chirac's only mistake. Opinion polls showed his dissolution of parliament was not unpopular, although voters thought it a &quot;political manoeuvre&quot; rather than a necessity.</p>
<p>Indeed for the first three weeks of the campaign, every poll suggested the centre-right would win re-election comfortably, albeit with a reduced majority.</p>
<p>So what went wrong?</p>
<p>Analysts say the conservatives' strategy was flawed from the outset. They had the wrong campaign leader, the wrong slogan and the wrong platform.</p>
<p>&quot;For the right to campaign on the theme of change after four years in government was downright masochistic,&quot; said Alain Duhamel, a leading political commentator.</p>
<p>&quot;Voters who wanted change weren't going to re-elect the same men to pursue the same policies.&quot;</p>
<p>The idea that Juppe, who had implemented two years of unpopular, if unavoidable, austerity to prepare France for a single European currency, would suddenly provide the &quot;new elan&quot; which Chirac had promised stretched belief.</p>
<p>Juppe compounded that credibility gap by promising a 40-day blitz of reforms, prompting Jospin to ask why he was suddenly in such a hurry, and why he had not used his vast parliamentary majority to carry out those changes before.</p>
<p>Jospin's emphasis on gradual change over five years seemed less frantic than Juppe's dash for reform. And his slogan that &quot;to change future, France needs to change majority&quot; struck home.</p>
<p>Chirac's own attempts to intervene in the campaign were so fumbling as to seem at times counterproductive.</p>
<p>His television interventions fell flat. Few people were convinced by his warning that a left-wing win would weaken France's voice in Europe. And his last broadcast on Tuesday was seen by many commentators as showing he was already resigned to &quot;cohabitation&quot; with a Socialist-led government.</p>
<p>Analysts say Chirac's biggest error may have been to sacrifice Juppe the day after last Sunday's poor first round score, when the combined left outpolled the mainstream right by four percentage points.</p>
<p>Juppe's sudden departure left the right without a leader or a platform at the start of the crucial runoff week, until social Gaullist Philippe Seguin was hastily propelled into the ring on Wednesday, shackled to free-marketeer Alain Madelin representing the opposite, liberal wing of Chirac's heterodox coalition.</p>
<p>Exit the omnipresent first-round team captain, exit the 40-day programme, exit the &quot;new elan&quot;, replaced in Chirac's last tv appeal by &quot;another way&quot; -- the non-slogan of the decade.</p>
<p>Voters could be forgiven for feeling confused.</p>
<p>Chirac's biographers cite several past episodes that showed the same mixture of haste, improvisation and miscalculation.</p>
<p>His sudden resignation as prime minister under president Valery Giscard d'Estaing in 1976 was one. Chirac walked out in mid-August, when most voters were on the beaches rather than watching politics, reducing his dramatic gesture to a non-event.</p>
<p>Then in 1979, he issued a melodramatic appeal from hospital during the campaign for the first direct European Parliament elections, denouncing Giscard d'Estaing's centre-right UDF, with which his Gaullist movement was allied in government, as &quot;the foreign party&quot; bent on dissolving France in a federal Europe.</p>
<p>In 1986, as prime minister under Socialist president Francois Mitterrand, Chirac tried to muscle in on foreign policy by insisting on attending a Group of Seven summit, at which France is traditionally represented by its president.</p>
<p>Chirac embarrassed his Japanese hosts, who had trouble bending the protocol to accommodate him, and Mitterrand humiliated him by making him sit in the audience, smoking nervously, at the final news conference.</p>
<p>The old Socialist fox went on to comprehensively outwit the restless Gaullist in two years of &quot;cohabitation&quot; and beat him easily for the presidency in 1988.</p>
<p>In 1993, Chirac finally seemed to have shaken off the &quot;hothead&quot; tag which Giscard d'Estaing gave him. Rather than risk his credit in another period of power-sharing with Mitterrand, he put fellow Gaullist Edouard Balladur in the premier's office.</p>
<p>That gamble almost backfired, when Balladur decided to run for president himself in 1995, but Chirac, for once judging his timing right, came from behind to beat him.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
