<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629424" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Berlin opera to sack musician for &quot;Hitler&quot; joke.</title>
<headline>Berlin opera to sack musician for &quot;Hitler&quot; joke.</headline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1997-06-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leading German opera company issued a public apology on Sunday and said it would sack a musician who signed a hotel bill with the name of Adolf Hitler on a tour of Israel.</p>
<p>The Berlin Opera said the musician -- who used the Nazi leader's name as a joke -- had been ordered to return to Berlin.</p>
<p>&quot;We will take the necessary disciplinary measures,&quot; the company's general manager, Heinz-Dieter Sense, told Berlin broadcaster Inforadio. &quot;That means we will dismiss him immediately. The appropriate procedure will begin on Monday.&quot;</p>
<p>The incident provoked a storm of protest in Israel. Holocaust survivors demonstrated outside the Tel Aviv opera house on Saturday night when the company gave a performance.</p>
<p>&quot;I most deeply regret the irresponsible behaviour of one member of our complete ensemble,&quot; Berlin Opera director Goetz Friedrich said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;In the name of my entire ensemble, I apologise for this isolated incident, which diametrically opposes the spirit and intention of our tour of Israel.&quot;</p>
<p>The story was front-page news in Israel and Holocaust survivors went on radio talks shows to condemn the musician.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt embarrassed, angry. What are you able to feel when you hear something like this even after 50 years people will not learn, they'll never learn, this hate will never pass,&quot; one of the demonstrators outside the Tel Aviv opera house said.</p>
<p>A letter of apology was read at the start of the performance in Tel Aviv on Saturday night. The German Embassy in Israel also issued a statement expressing its regret over the incident.</p>
<p>Berlin officials said the musician, whom they did not name, was a double-bassist although Israeli media had identified him as a horn player.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
