<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629432" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French markets in for rough ride after left win.</title>
<headline>French markets in for rough ride after left win.</headline>
<byline>Brian Love</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>French financial markets are in for a rough ride on Monday after voters swept the left to power -- but without the absolute Socialist majority which the markets had hoped for as &quot;next best thing&quot; to a return of the right.</p>
<p>Analysts had predicted a fall if the Socialist party came to power with an absolute majority but saw further troubles after confirmation late on Sunday that the Communist Party, which opopses the euro single currency and privatisations, would hold the balance of power in France's National Assembly.</p>
<p>&quot;The need for Communist support was not priced into the market on Friday,&quot; said Paris-based UBS economist Eric Muller. &quot;It is the worst case scenario.&quot;</p>
<p>The franc lost ground through the evening after voting ended at 1800 GMT and projections showed a left-wing win, dipping to 3.3840/45 per mark at 2305 GMT from 3.3816 late on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;French markets are likely to come under pressure early on this week. On Mark/Paris (franc versus the mark) over the past few weeks we have had some pretty aggressive Bank of France action to try to limit the downside and I'll expect that to be intensified,&quot; said treasury economist Mark Geddes with ABN Amro.</p>
<p>Things could get worse if Socialist leader Lionel Jospin tried to push Germany too hard on early Italian particpation in monetary union or on renegotiating the &quot;stability pact&quot; on budget control after monetary union, he said.</p>
<p>Perhaps the biggest issue set to weigh on capital markets is uncertainty over France's future position on European monetary union, made worse by a political crisis in Germany over its own EMU-related budget woes.</p>
<p>While markets have been coming round to the idea of a left victory, analysts say the Socialist position of 'Yes, but' on EMU could be reinforced if they see Germany getting into deep water and believe reliance on Communist support at home, while likely to be slight, does not make things any easier.</p>
<p>&quot;The initial reaction may be to dump Europe altogether,&quot; said Sonja Gibbs, London-based bond analyst at Nomura bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Then in a few weeks if EMU is still in jeopardy and if the German governent continues to tear itself apart, I would buy the mark,&quot; she added, referring to the general tendency to resort to the strongest European currency in times of worry.</p>
<p>Even without the euro worries, stock analysts believe the CAC-40 leading share index will fall, because of the return of a left wing more hostile to privatisations and industrial restructuring, notably carmaker Renault's plant closure plans.</p>
<p>The stock market has been the worst hit of French financial markets during France's election campaign, falling 6.48 percent in the week since a first-round lead for the left.</p>
<p>All markets would be watching each and every policy announcement closely.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be considerable volatility as announcements come through on policy decisions,&quot; Elisabetta Castelli, head of international equities CDC Bourse in Paris, said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
