<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629469" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy stresses no need for EMU delay, Italy ready.</title>
<headline>Italy stresses no need for EMU delay, Italy ready.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-06-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's deputy prime minister Walter Veltroni stressed on Sunday that there should be no delays in the start-up of Europe's Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) and that Italy was ready to join from the start.</p>
<p>He said in a newspaper interview with Rome-based La Repubblica that despite the row between the German government and the Bundesbank over the revaluation of gold reserves, Europe's single currency should still start on time.</p>
<p>&quot;We are ready for Maastricht, to the parameters known and with the calendar fixed,&quot; he told the newspaper.  </p>
<p>Italy's foreign minister and former prime minister Lamberto Dini told Milan's Corriere della Sera that Germany had a big problem to reach the Maastricht parameters on EMU entry, but that all wanted to see a strong Germany in EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;Today, therefore, we cannot speak of delays. The mechanism of monetary union is by now complete, and one needs to examine it thoroughly,&quot; he told the newspaper.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank has objected to the Bonn government's plans to revalue the nation's gold reserves in a bid to help Germany qualify for the single currency set to start in 1999, and both sides have so far refused to back down in the public row.  </p>
<p>However, a statement from the German central bank on Sunday said that reports or suggestions that the Bundesbank or its president had asked for a postponement of the start of currency union were not accurate.</p>
<p>This followed on from an advance release from Monday's edition of German news weekly Der Speigel which had quoted Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer asking whether Bonn and Paris could not postpone the start of EMU.</p>
<p>In March this year, Dini had said it would be in Europe's interests to postpone the start of EMU, but added that he saw no chance of EU partners negotiating a delay. He stressed then that it would be impossible to re-write the Maastricht Treaty at this late stage and stressed that Italy was not looking to rock the boat and was not looking for a delay.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
