<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629505" id="root" date="1997-06-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German Bundesbank backs EMU, denies delay report.</title>
<headline>German Bundesbank backs EMU, denies delay report.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Gray</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-06-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hans Tietmeyer, the president of Germany's Bundesbank, on Sunday denied a report he had proposed a postponement of the 1999 start date for Europe's single currency and insisted he stood by the Maastricht Treaty.</p>
<p>But he reiterated the Bundesbank's opposition to Finance Minister Theo Waigel's plan to revalue the bank's vast gold and currency reserves this year. He said he hoped the government and parliament would take proper note of its objections.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer's statement aimed to dampen feverish speculation that the powerful bank would rather sacrifice EMU (Economic and Monetary Union) than agree to Waigel's plan, after Der Spiegel magazine quoted him as asking if Bonn and Paris could delay the start of the single currency.</p>
<p>Some members of Chancellor Helmut Kohl's coalition also voiced opposition to Waigel's plan, raising the possibility that Kohl may not be able to muster a majority to push the controversial measure through parliament.</p>
<p>A related row over how to fill projected shortfalls in government finances, where Waigel is on a collision course with the Free Democrat (FDP) coalition partners, added to Kohl's woes.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer, a former Kohl protege, dismissed the Spiegel story. &quot;Reports of suggestions by the Bundesbank or its president in favour of a postponment of the start of the monetary union are not accurate,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The Deutsche Bundesbank naturally stands by the Maastricht Treaty. The bank has already been working intensively for a long time on the preparation of monetary union with a stable euro.&quot;</p>
<p>The bank has condemned the gold plan as an attack on its fabled independence, but Waigel and other coalition leaders, turning the row into a battle between institutions, stressed that parliament was also an independent body.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect the Bundesbank to respect the legislative independence of politics just as politics always respects the independence of the Bundesbank in monetary policy,&quot; Waigel told journalists during a weekend bicycle tour in southern Germany.</p>
<p>Wolfgang Schaeuble, the parliamentary leader of Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU), was even more blunt.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision on the question we now face is to be taken by the legislature, whose independence is not less than that of the Bundesbank,&quot; Kohl's chief lieutenant wrote in a letter to his members of parliament to rally support for the plan.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer said the Bundesbank's main objection concerned the effect the revaluation would have on 1997 balance sheets.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank hopes that the German government and parliament will take appropriate consideration of these objections when they make their decisions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Grumbling from members of Kohl's coalition suggested several members of parliament were indeed taking heed.</p>
<p>FDP budget expert Juergen Koppelin urged Bonn to retreat from what is shaping up to be an unprecedented clash between the government and the central bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Waigel should now give up his plan. The psychological damage would be too great,&quot; he told the Bild daily.</p>
<p>Juergen Augustinowitz, a young Christian Democrat who has already announced he will not vote for legislation opposed by the Bundesbank, said he was sure he would not be alone.</p>
<p>Press reports suggested Waigel also faced a battle on another front -- taking on the FDP over how to plug holes in this year's and next year's budgets.</p>
<p>The Bild am Sonntag weekly said Waigel would try to force through a rise in fuel tax or the postponement of a planned cut in an income tax surcharge at a top-level coalition meeting chaired by Kohl on Sunday evening.</p>
<p>The FDP has said it will not approve tax hikes and made clear the future of the coalition would be at stake.</p>
<p>&quot;The CDU will have to look for another coalition partner for a decision like that,&quot; FDP economic spokesman Paul Friedhoff told Bild am Sonntag.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
