<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629659" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Reeves Industries Inc debt extends decline.</title>
<headline>Reeves Industries Inc debt extends decline.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reeves Industries Inc debt dropped 1-1/2 points on Monday, extending its decline to eight points since last week, traders said.</p>
<p>The 11 percent senior notes due 2002 were off its lows but still off at 75 bid, 77 offer, traders said.</p>
<p>Players said the company has been plagued by unconfirmed rumors it had to borrow money to cover debt interest and operations. Further talk that its Chief Financial Officer resigned exacerbated the debt's performance, they said.</p>
<p>Reeves Industries could not be reached for comment on the rumors.  </p>
<p>&quot;For a company who had been cash flow positive and all of a sudden had to borrow $20 million ahead of a coupon payment in July is cause for concern,&quot; said one market source.</p>
<p>Recently, Moody's cut Reeves debt to Caa from B3, keeping a negative outlook on the rating.</p>
<p>Moody's said the actions reflected the continued weakness of the company's earnings and uncertainty regarding timing and realizable value from the intended sale of all, or parts of the company.  </p>
<p>Reeves' management's decisison to put the company up for sale, prompted S&amp;P to keep the firm under review with &quot;developing&quot; implications following a cut to Reeves' senior unsecured debt in September.</p>
<p>S&amp;P cited poor financial performance and the apparent failure of last year's restructuring actions to reverse deterioration of apparel textile operations.</p>
<p>Reeves Industries, Inc, located in Spartanburg, South Carolina, manufactures textile and coated products through its wholly owned operating subsidiary, Reeves Brothers Inc.</p>
<p>Reeves is a wholly owned subsidiary of Hart Holding Company Inc, a privately held firm.</p>
<p>(( -- Nancy Leinfuss, 212-859-1675 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
