<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629634" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Seagate sees Q4 results below expectations.</title>
<headline>Seagate sees Q4 results below expectations.</headline>
<dateline>SCOTTS VALLEY, Calif. 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seagate Technology Inc on Monday said it expected its fourth-quarter results to come in lower than expected because of weak demand for its high-performance computer disk drive products.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected the company to earn $1.06 a share in its fiscal fourth quarter, according to a First Call survey.</p>
<p>The company said in a statement said earnings before any charges could fall short of its profits of $1.01 per share for the third quarter ended March.</p>
<p>Its gross margin in the fourth quarter is expected to be steady with the margin in the previous three months.  </p>
<p>The company said revenues for the fourth quarter, ending June 27, were expected to be between six and 10 percent less than the $2.5 billion of revenues reported in its third quarter.</p>
<p>Seagate said the long-term outlook for the storage business remains strong.</p>
<p>Shares of the Scotts Valley, California-based company have been under pressure in recent days amid concerns about possible oversupply in the global disk-drive market.</p>
<p>A Singapore paper, Business Times, reported last week that Seagate may have to cut its high-end output in Singapore and that May and June production could drop as much as 30 percent from March levels.</p>
<p>Seagate also said it would seek authorization from its board of directors to repurchase up to $600 million more of its stock. That is in addition to the almost $570 million of its stock already purchased during the current fiscal year. At the end of its third quarter, Seagate had about 255.3 million shares outstanding.</p>
<p>Shares of Seagate closed 1-3/4 higher at 42-3/8 on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SCOTTS VALLEY, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
