<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="62968" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: AmEx Egypt adding 100 mln pounds to bond issue.</title>
<headline>AmEx Egypt adding 100 mln pounds to bond issue.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>American Express Bank in Egypt said on Wednesday it was increasing to 300 million pounds from 200 million pounds the amount it is raising through an issue of five-year floating-rate bonds.</p>
<p>Subscriptions have already passed the 200 million pound level and the offer will close at the end of business on Thursday after opening on September 11, it said. The bank originally said the offer would be open for two months.</p>
<p>&quot;We've almost reached the 300 million pound level,&quot; said a bank executive who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>The interest on the bonds will be linked every three months to the average annualised yield on the most recent 91-day T-bills. The yield on the latest bills was 10.261 percent.</p>
<p>If the treasury stops issuing bills, the interest will be 3.5 percentage points below the central bank discount rate, which has been stable at 13.5 percent since November 1995.</p>
<p>A 90 million pound seven-year bond offer by the public-sector Arab Land Bank closed last week more than four times oversubscribed. That bond was at 1.5 percentage points below the Central Bank discount rate, in other words 12 percent at the current discount rate level.</p>
<p>The treasury is simultaneously raising four billion pounds in seven-year bonds at a fixed 11 percent.</p>
<p>-- Jonathan Wright +20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
