<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629740" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TransAmerican sets price talk on junk deal-source.</title>
<headline>TransAmerican sets price talk on junk deal-source.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>TransAmerican Energy Corp has set the preliminary price talk on its two-part private placement of $1.53 billion (principal amount) in high-yield bonds expected for later this week, a market source said.</p>
<p>Price talk on the $425 million of senior secured notes due 2002 is 11 percent to 11-1/2 percent, the source said. Price talk on the $1.105 billion in senior secured discount notes due 2002 will be 1-1/2 points higher than the yield on the senior secured notes, the source said.</p>
<p>These price talk levels are preliminary and still subject to change, the market source said.  </p>
<p>Jefferies &amp; Co Inc, the sole underwriter of the offering, declined to comment.</p>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's has rated both tranches of the deal B-plus.</p>
<p>TransAmerican Energy is a holding company which holds a majority stake in two operating subsidiaries: TransTexas Gas Corp, an oil and gas exploration company; and TransAmerican Refining Corp, a refinery company.</p>
<p>TransAmerican Energy is indirectly owned by oil and gas mogul, John Stanley.</p>
<p>Proceeds from the offering will be used to finance a recapitalization of the operating subsidiaries, according to a statement by TransAmerican Energy.</p>
<p>-Douglas Brown, U.S. Corporate Bond Unit, ((212-859-1662))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
