<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629845" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: SOCCER-ALBANIA SQUAD FORCED TO MEET IN PORTUGAL.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ALBANIA SQUAD FORCED TO MEET IN PORTUGAL.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's World Cup squad will assemble abroad ahead of Saturday's qualifier in Portugal because of continuing unrest in the Balkan country.</p>
<p>Team official Gjergj Thaka said on Monday that coach Astrit Hafizi and six home-based players would join 12 exiles in Oporto, Portugal.</p>
<p>&quot;The coach does not aim at achieving any result but to present the team with dignity, taking into consideration our difficult circumstances,&quot; said Thaka.</p>
<p>Albania has been in a turbulent state since riots sparked by the collapse of pyramid investment schemes forced President Sali Berisha to instal a government of national reconciliation and agree to early elections.</p>
<p>Thaka said the squad would be missing Germany-based forward Altin Rraklli because of injury.</p>
<p>&quot;Lack of training for the domestic players obliged Hafizi to call many players from Cyprus, Greece, Germany, Croatia, Malta and Portugal,&quot; Thaka said.</p>
<p>Albania's main soccer league has not beein in action since late January because of the internal problems.</p>
<p>The Albanian senior and under-21 teams played their last matches against Ukraine and Germany in Spain after political violence forced the games to be moved from home venues.</p>
<p>Squad:</p>
<p>Goalkeepers - Fotaq Strakosha, Blendi Nallbani.</p>
<p>Defenders - Ilir Shulku, Afrim Tole, Artan Vila, Rudi Vata, Arjan Xhumba, Zamir Shpuza, Fatos Daja.</p>
<p>Midfielders - Sokol Prenga, Salvador Kacaj, Bledar Kola, Altin Haxhi, Amarildo Zela.</p>
<p>Forwards - Alban Bushi, Igli Tare, Fatmir Vata, Eduard Abazi.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
