<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629986" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: SLOVAK CBANK WINNING BATTLE BUT SKK WAR CONTINUES.</title>
<headline>SLOVAK CBANK WINNING BATTLE BUT SKK WAR CONTINUES.</headline>
<byline>Peter Laca</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Slovak central bank's battle to hold the crown steady has been successful to date, but analysts warned on Monday that a investors appear poised for another attack on the weakened currency.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Slovakia (NBS) has been fighting downward pressure on the crown started by speculative short- sellings some two weeks ago.</p>
<p>Its strategy has been to squeeze liquidity on the local money market while maintaining a stable strong crown fixing to make short-selling of crowns expensive.</p>
<p>The policy appears to have worked with the crown's spot market value gradually moving towards NBS fixing levels after the bank fixed it above market over the past 10 days.</p>
<p>But analysts said that while inflation and economic growth data have been positive -- yearly inflation was a region low 6.3 percent in March and 1996 real GDP was 6.9 percent -- yawning trade and current accounts deficit make the crown susceptible to further attacks.</p>
<p>&quot;Slovakia has a small and open economy, and at the same time it is running a huge current account deficit, so its currency will remain very vulnerable in the near future unless something radically changes in its economic structure,&quot; said one Bratislava-based analyst.</p>
<p>The NBS fixed the crown on Friday at 33.251 to the dollar and at 19.571 to the mark. The rates imply a deviation from the midpoint of -0.67 percent, while at the time of the calculation the crown was trading on the interbank market at -1.56 percent.</p>
<p>Slovakia posted a current accout deficit of $221.9 million in January 1997, compared with a shortfall of $19.6 million in the same month last year.</p>
<p>Analysts also warned that the decision-makers should keep in mind that it was virtually impossible to refinance state budget deficit during the current market liquidity crunch.</p>
<p>&quot;They (NBS) will have to add some liquidity fairly soon since money market rates of above 40 percent, if you get any funds at all, can spark inflationary pressure and make budget refinancing very expensive,&quot; the foreign analyts said.</p>
<p>Most of the pressure on the Slovak crown has come as a result of an attack on the Czech crown, which fell to record lows before the central bank was forced to hike rates and let the currency float freely.</p>
<p>One London-based dealer said the Slovak crown would continue to be heavily influenced by its Czech cousin. &quot;If they cut rates and the Czech crown finds its equilibrium -- since the current rate is not an equilibrium -- then we can talk about the Slovak crown.&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Before that no, one can say where the crown will be moving, but it seems that artificially high exchange rate will be costly for the central bank regarding its currency reserves.&quot;</p>
<p>NBS hard currency reserves totalled $3.452 billion as of May 21, but the central bank is estimated to have spent about $500 million in indirect interventions through fixing.</p>
<p>Some traders said foreign investors considered the crown overvalued at close to its official rate, adding foreigners were willing to buy crowns close to the fluctuation band floor of -7.0 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not place any funds in Slovakia at the moment at levels close to crown's official rate, especially remembering how weak it was a few days ago,&quot; the London trade said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the weakening of the Slovak crown, more likely on the market within its fluctuation band rather than by direct administrative devaluation, has almost become inevitable, especially given the ocuntry's deep ties with the Czechs, its former federation partner.</p>
<p>&quot;We think they will have to take some administrative decision, maybe not as radical as the Czech's abolition of the band, but at least widening its current fluctuation barrier,&quot; said one local analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;And if they did this, the crown would ease since the move would indicate the central bank no longer thinks the crown's price should be so high,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 421-7-521-8402</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
