<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629919" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLAND PRICES HANDLOWY FOR LONG-TERM INVESTORS. [CORRECTED 17:00 GMT]</title>
<headline>POLAND PRICES HANDLOWY FOR LONG-TERM INVESTORS. [CORRECTED 17:00 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland priced Bank Handlowy SA shares for long-term investors at 20 zlotys paid on the day of the transaction plus 11.4 zlotys payable three years after the deal and a premium in the fourth year for a possible rise in Handlowy's market value, Handlowy said on Monday.</p>
<p>(Corrects details of payment conditions)</p>
<p>Handlowy said in a statement the three long-term investors JP Morgan, Swedbank and Zurich Group would be required to pay the second installment earlier, if they decided to sell their shares before the end of the three-year period.</p>
<p>Investors would choose the timing of the third payment within a year after the second payment. The conditional payment would represent an extra premium paid by investors on a possible increase in Handlowy's value over a set $1 billion reference level.</p>
<p>(Corrects details of payment conditions in above paragraph).</p>
<p>Handlowy said the sale should be concluded after the close of the public offering.</p>
<p>&quot;The transaction should be concluded after the close of the initial public offering but the sides of the contract will do their best to make it happen no later than three months from the close of the public offer,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The state treasury is offering the three stable investors up to 27,859,000 million shares, representing 30 percent of Handlowy's equity diluted by a 28-million convertible bond issue, but the offer allows for up to 11,472,500 of these shares to be transferred to retail investors.</p>
<p>The treasury ministry agreed to allow the investors to buy enough convertible bonds, now held by the state treasury, to reach jointly 24 percent of Handlowy's equity.</p>
<p>Handlowy also said the three investors agreed not to buy shares or convertible bonds of the bank that would give any them individually 15 percent or more of equity or would allow the whole group to exceed the 30 percent equity limit.</p>
<p>Poland is offering 29,250,000 shares of Handlowy in a public subscription initially priced in a range of 28 to 35 zlotys. The final price will be announced on June 17.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
