<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630063" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Engineers submit Brent Spar disposal plans to Shell.</title>
<headline>Engineers submit Brent Spar disposal plans to Shell.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Six engineering companies selected by Royal Dutch/Shell group to produce plans for disposing of the Brent Spar oil platform are to submit bids to the Anglo-Dutch oil giant by the end of Monday, a Shell spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Shell asked the contractors in January to draw up detailed proposals for a total of 11 different disposal ideas after a campaign by environmental group Greenpeace in 1995 scuppered its plans to dump the platform in the Atlantic Ocean.</p>
<p>&quot;The contractors will be delivering the details of their proposals to our Aberdeen office by the end of the day,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Norway's independent advisory body Det Norske Veritas (DNV) will evaluate the technical, safety and environmental content of proposals over the next few months.</p>
<p>&quot;Shell will make its choice on the basis of the DNV report and in consultation with a wide range of bodies,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>The eleven ideas that Shell chose for development range from simple scrapping to adapting the platform for use as a fish farm or a coastal defence system.</p>
<p>Shell hopes to present a single firm proposal for approval by Britain's Department of Trade and Industry (DTI) by the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;We're quite sure that by the end of the year we'll have a solution...and decommissioning can go ahead in 1998,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>It must persuade the British government that the chosen alternative is better than deep sea dumping.</p>
<p>The Brent Spar has been parked in a Norwegian fjord since the Greenpeace campaign, which included a consumer boycott of service stations, forced the company to back down on its original dumping plans.</p>
<p>Shell, which operates in the North Sea as Shell UK Exploration and Production (Shell Expro), a joint venture between Shell and Exxon, estimates it would have spent almost 20 million stg on the platform's disposal even before awarding a final contract.</p>
<p>Of the six bidders for the contract, Norway's Kvaerner Stolt Seaway Alliance (KSSA), Brown &amp; Root of the United States, and a joint venture between Germany's Thyssen and Norway's Aker NC all proposed onshore disposal at yards in Britain or Norway.</p>
<p>KSSA and Britain's Alfred McAlpine in a joint venture with France's Doris, suggested using Brent Spar for quay extension projects.</p>
<p>Britain's AMEC proposed using sections of the rig in a coastal defence scheme planned for the east coast of England.</p>
<p>KSSA and a joint venture between Britain's John D. Wood and Norway's GMC identified potential clients interested in using the top of the platform for offshore training facilities.</p>
<p>KSSA also proposed converting the Spar into a floating dry dock gate and for a fish farm development.</p>
<p>--Rosalind Russell, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5387</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
