<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630043" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LME closes mostly lower, late rallies half-hearted.</title>
<headline>LME closes mostly lower, late rallies half-hearted.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most base metal markets ended Monday LME trading easier, led by copper, with partial rallies not enough to restore prices to equilibrium, traders said.</p>
<p>There was some mid-afternoon stability at the lows throughout the complex, but the buying was largely covering in against early sales, and there was little fresh buying interest.</p>
<p>&quot;Copper took a bit of a pasting today, and that really set the tone for the day,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Copper prices retreated from early little-changed levels after a modest stock fall of 200 tonnes, with speculative selling and technical pressure driving prices down to $2,475 at one stage. The late covering cut losses slightly, but final business at $2,485 a tonne was still $44 down from last Friday.</p>
<p>Analysts said the approach of the seasonally slow quarter for demand and dwindling supply-side concerns perhaps signalled that sentiment may be on the turn. There was little heat in the spreads as well, with cash/threes at a slightly softer backwardation of $58.</p>
<p>In the short-term, prices may hold this level until a tricky June option declaration on Wednesday is over, some said.</p>
<p>Aluminium flip-flopped either side of $1,600 during the afternoon, with the market damaged by the early decline when chart levels at $1,610 were taken out.</p>
<p>Despite a stock fall of 3,825 tonnes, there is some concerns that inventories are building &quot;off-warrant&quot; and that consumer interest is not particularly strong. Prices closed at $1,596, down $23.</p>
<p>Nickel prices bounced back above $7,000 during aftenoon trading, but remained easier after a substantial sell-off earlier in the session. Losses then were induced by the tentative three-year labour agreement at Inco's Sudbury facilities over the weekend and the 1,350-tonne stock increase.</p>
<p>Despite the rally away from the lows, traders expect the market to come under pressure in the short-term, with stocks seen rising further as Russian metal is placed in warrant in Europe. Last business was at $7,025, down $175, but above the $6,910 five-month low hit earlier.</p>
<p>Zinc prices picked up reasonable trade support in the mid-$1,320s, but a partial rally still left the market in the minus column. Short-term technicals are moderately bearish, while softer copper prices were also an influence. Prices closed at $1,330, down $15.</p>
<p>Lead trading was unimpressive, with prices tailing lower from the outset. A modest rally in the afternoon merely reflected trends elsewhere, and final trade was at $626, still down $7.</p>
<p>The tin market staged a fairly robust rally from 14-1/2 month lows of $5,510 racked up this morning, and last business was at $5,640, up $75 from last Friday.</p>
<p>Traders said the market had become oversold in its recent sell-off, so bargain-hunting buying was enough to claw back some lost ground. But the bias remains lower, with $5,500 seen being tested on general technical weakness.</p>
<p>Alloy was quiet, and business was fractionally lower throughout. Three months closed at $1,480/85 a tonne.</p>
<p>--Martin Hayes, London newsroom 44 171 542 8080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
