<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630064" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BOE appointments give process credibility - analysts.</title>
<headline>BOE appointments give process credibility - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Rosemary Bennett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The British government's appointment of four respected economists to the Bank of England's monetary policy committee will give the new framework the credibility it requires, City analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;These are middle-of-the-road, sensible economists with plenty of institutional and committee experience,&quot; said Geoffrey Dicks, economist at Natwest Markets and a former professor at the London Business School.</p>
<p>&quot;The experience of these people will give the new committee the credibility it needs.&quot;  </p>
<p>The four outside appointments to the committee are Professor Charles Goodhart from the London School of Economics, Dr DeAnne Julius chief economist at British Airways, Sir Alan Budd, chief economic adviser to the Treasury and Professor Wilhelm Buiter, macroeconomics professor at Cambridge University.</p>
<p>Bill Martin, co-director of economic research at UBS, said the appointments are politically neutral.</p>
<p>&quot;They don't come from any particular school and are quite clearly independent of political consideration.&quot;</p>
<p>He said there had been fears that Chancellor of the Exchequer Gordon Brown might have loaded the committee with close political allies. &quot;This is clearly unjusfied,&quot; said Martin.  </p>
<p>Goodhart and Budd were singled out as particularly welcome appointments.</p>
<p>Goodhart has been called the best monetary economist in the country by his peers and, as a former senior adviser at the Bank of England, already has considerable experience of the workings of the institution.</p>
<p>And Budd is associated with the economic successes of the previous government.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a general feeling that if (former Chancellor of the Exchequer) Kenneth Clarke the only ministerial success of the last government, then Sir Alan Budd is closely associated with him,&quot; said Dicks.</p>
<p>&quot;He got there after Britain joined the ERM and was not blamed when we were forced out. The advice he has given over the last six years is as good as it gets.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;Both have superb experience. You couldn't get much better. What you're looking at here is competence,&quot; said Ruth Lea, head of the policy unit at the Institute of Directors.</p>
<p>Buiter was referred to as a &quot;brilliant&quot; economist by City figures and is known to have strong, if unorthadox, views on European Economic and Monetary Union.</p>
<p>While favouring the currency union, he has described the Maastricht critera on fiscal deficits as nonsense.</p>
<p>Julius is less well known in the City, but will bring to the committee the view point from industry.</p>
<p>City figures said the four appointees could not collectively be considered either hawkish or doveish.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no obvious 'inflation is the root of all evil' types here,&quot; said Martin of UBS.</p>
<p>&quot;The big debate at the moment is about the exchange rate. I'm sure the industrialist Julius will say they must take more notice of it while the more mainstream Budd and Goodhart will take on the Bank's existing view,&quot; said Dicks.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7715</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
