<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630022" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Euro low sulphur fuel softens, high sulphur gains.</title>
<headline>Euro low sulphur fuel softens, high sulphur gains.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>European low sulphur fuel prices softened on Monday with prompter supplies pressuring numbers, while high sulphur gained a little on a temporary thinness in Russian supply, traders said.</p>
<p>Swaps led the way down for one percent cracked, with numbers settling at $92/$93 for June.</p>
<p>Buying interest was thin but it has become clear that the big Italian buyer took at least two one percent cargoes and possibly three two percent cargoes last week, easing prompt pressure for the moment.</p>
<p>The one percent deals were believed done around the $106-$107 cif Med level.</p>
<p>However, prompt barrels were seen on Monday in northern Germany. Several other cargoes were believed loading in mid-June.</p>
<p>&quot;Its been quiet today,&quot; said one trader. &quot;I don't thing northern Europe is terribly long for one percent but there is stuff out there looking for homes. It's certainly not going to get firmer.&quot;</p>
<p>After the traditionally slow start to the week in the barge market business picked up a little with deals heard done at $83, $83.25, $83.50 and $83.75 a tonne.</p>
<p>Potential arb opportunities out of Europe for high sulphur to the Gulf Coast helped barge and cargo numbers, with a thin loading schedule in St. Petersburg in the first five days of June easing the pressure of Russian cracked fuel on the ARA market.</p>
<p>- London newsroom +44 171 542 8060</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
