<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630086" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ SPORT-RUGBY UNION-Sevens star to join touring Fijian squad.</title>
<headline>NZ SPORT-RUGBY UNION-Sevens star to join touring Fijian squad.</headline>
<text>
<p>PALMERSTON NORTH, June 3 - Fiji's spirits received an added boost after their fine 19-10 win over the Central Vikings on Monday with news that sevens rugby star Waisele Serevi will join the tour squad in Wanganui on Thursday.</p>
<p>Strangely however, Serevi replaces hooker Eminoni Batimala who returns home to Fiji with medial ligament knee damage, NZPA reported.</p>
<p>Epeli Naituivau, who started at prop yesterday, is expected to become tour captain Greg Smith's deputy at hooker as Fiji coach Brad Johnstone looks to Serevi to add more firepower to the backs.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're actually bringing Serevi down on Thursday,&quot; Johnstone said after watching his team's satisfying effort in their third tour match.</p>
<p>&quot;He's returning to Suva from the French Sevens (in Paris) and he will be joining the squad for Baitimala.&quot;</p>
<p>Serevi's presence adds to the puzzle of who will get test backline spots with virtually all positions up for grabs because of the tourists allround depth there. Fiji play the All Blacks in a one-off test on June 14.  </p>
<p>Queensland-based Jonetani Waqa, in his third season with Fiji, pushed his case for test contention with a strong showing at first five-eighth yesterday.</p>
<p>&quot;Jonetani generally plays fullback and is generally better with space, but the injury to Nicky Little has forced us to play Jone there,&quot; Johnstone said.</p>
<p>Little is recovering from a chest injury and Serevi's arrival gives Johnstone the cover he needs for his entire backline from first five-eighth to fullback. Little may be asked to prove his fitness in Friday night's game against Wanganui.  </p>
<p>&quot;We can play Serevi from hooker to fullback,&quot; Johnstone joked about the allround capabilities of the dashing sevens player.</p>
<p>&quot;We can play him in most positions, he's a brilliant little boy.</p>
<p>&quot;We played him on the wing, we played him at first five and at fullback last year.&quot;</p>
<p>Johnstone said Serevi's versatility made him the ideal impact player off the bench for Fiji, hinting that might well be the player's role in the test.  </p>
<p>&quot;He might be more like an impact player for us rather than a fulltime player,&quot; Johnstone said.</p>
<p>Serevi is likely to get a run at some stage in Fiji's final hitout before the test, against Counties-Manukau next Tuesday.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the Fijian backline didn't miss Serevi yesterday as they created pressure to force two errors from the Vikings' backline on which they capitalised.</p>
<p>They were also strong on defence and despite the bitter weather conditions showed greater control and concentration to take the match.  </p>
<p>The newly-formed Central Vikings -- a combined Hawke's Bay-Manawatu team -- struggled in their first outing together, failing to find their rhythm despite the presence of nine Super 12 Wellington Hurricanes and one Auckland Blues squad member.</p>
<p>&quot;A team can only play with as much intensity as they are allowed and I think our boys played pretty well, so you have to give them a bit of credit there,&quot; Johnstone said.</p>
<p>&quot;We knew what Bull (Mark Allen) does and what they were likely to do as a team so we worked on that.&quot;  </p>
<p>A superb try 27 seconds into the game to winger Manasa Bari and then a charged down kick late in the second half to Lawrence Little gave Fiji their first half points.</p>
<p>For the Central Vikings halfback Scott Waldergrave scored his team's first ever try and at halftime Fiji led 14-5.</p>
<p>Another charge down and a try to Waqa early in the second half completed Fiji's scoring while Vikings No 8 Dustin Watts plunged over from a five metre scrum for his team's second try.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we'll strike a team this strong in the second division,&quot; Vikings coach Frank Oliver said.  </p>
<p>The Vikings now have six weeks off before playing North Harbour, Wellington and Southland -- all first division sides -- ahead of the NPC second division competition.</p>
<p>Fiji today headed for Wanganui where they take on the newly promoted second division side on Friday night.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIJI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
