<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630038" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK dismisses lottery operator's concessions - RPT.</title>
<headline>UK dismisses lottery operator's concessions - RPT.</headline>
<byline>Alan Wheatley</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Camelot, the operator of Britain's lottery, on Monday offered concessions aimed at defusing controversy over hefty bonuses paid to the firm's directors, but the government swiftly dismissed the proposals as inadequate.</p>
<p>Sir George Russell, chairman of the consortium of five British and foreign firms, said after a tense meeting with National Heritage Secretary Chris Smith that he would examine ways of turning the lottery into a not-for-profit operation.</p>
<p>He said Camelot would also pay to charity a sum equivalent to the controversial bonuses and would waive six million pounds ($9.8 million) in interest it earns from unpaid prize money.</p>
<p>Russell told reporters he would discuss with his directors their future bonus schemes but was powerless to do anything about their past pay packets.</p>
<p>&quot;As chairman I'm not able to overturn contracts freely entered into prior to people starting in the company,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Smith, the cabinet minister responsible for the arts and culture, said Camelot's response was inadequate and showed it had failed to grasp why the public was so angry.</p>
<p>&quot;The directors' remuneration would remain completely untouched and I don't find that acceptable. I want to see some or all of the bonuses that they've received going to charity and I want a commitment that that will happen for future amounts as well,&quot; Smith said.</p>
<p>He said thousands of people had expressed their disquiet since Camelot revealed last week that its directors' pay bill had jumped 40 percent to 2.35 million pounds in the year to March even though sums raised for good causes had fallen.</p>
<p>Chief executive Tim Holley's total pay package rose 53 percent to 590,000 pounds.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say we have made a little bit of progress but we haven't made nearly enough. They are showing a bit of contrition but not nearly enough,&quot; Smith said.</p>
<p>He told Camelot to come back with a firm response to his complaints by the end of the week and said it was in the consortium's own interest to do so. &quot;It's the people who play the lottery who have ultimate judgment on them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The new Labour government plans to turn the lottery into a non-profit operation when Camelot's licence, awarded by the previous Conservative government, expires in 2001.</p>
<p>Terminating the licence before then would probably be be prohibitively expensive for the government, but Russell said Camelot was ready to explore in any case plans to turn the money-spinning venture into a not-for-profit organisation.</p>
<p>&quot;We understand there is obviously going to be a change in the shape of the lottery in the future. We have offered to provide the government within six weeks our views on the shape of a lottery that is without profit in the long term, and possible change in the short term,&quot; Russell said.</p>
<p>Launched in November 1994, the lottery is played regulaarly by some 30 million Britons and has already raised billions of pounds for charities, sports, the arts and other good causes.</p>
<p>Camelot, whose after-tax profit from running the lottery is less than one penny in the pound, said the steep rise in executive salaries was due to the part-payment of long-term bonuses earned for the lottery's successful launch. ($ = 0.611 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
