<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630162" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: INTERVIEW - RMB upbeat on second half profit.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - RMB upbeat on second half profit.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rand Merchant Bank was on track to log higher profits for the year to June 30 on the back of a strong second half, managing director Paul Harris said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We've done very well. We're ahead of budget. Will we exceed it (last year's profit)? Yes, definitely,&quot; Paul Harris told Reuters at the launch of the bank's personalised merchant banking division.  </p>
<p>Rand Merchant Bank's parent company, RMB Holdings Ltd, also would grow its full year bottom line, Harris said.</p>
<p>RMB Holdings' headline earnings per share for the half to December 31 rose 67 percent to 128 cents.</p>
<p>Harris said a the group's newer businesses, including its unit trusts and Aegis Insurance Co, had underpinned earnings growth for the second half.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got a lot of companies in the early stage of growth that picked up where some companies are topping out,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Harris said the group's insurance sector was mixed as its life business was maturing while growth in health premiums had surged.</p>
<p>&quot;With Momentum Health, the only thing that's limiting it is the capacity to handle the business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Momentum Health is part of RMB's unit Momentum Life Assurers Ltd.</p>
<p>Unit trust divisions also had achieved explosive earnings growth.</p>
<p>&quot;We've started a unit trust company and we started a linked unit trust company just last year. In one we're taking in 200 million rand a month. We're growing unbelievably,&quot; Harris said.</p>
<p>RMB's rules off the current year on June 30.</p>
<p>-- Justin McCamish, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
