<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630134" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Kabila stands up Mandela once too often.</title>
<headline>Kabila stands up Mandela once too often.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Laurent Kabila of the Democratic Republic of Congo kept South Africa's President Nelson Mandela waiting once too often on Monday.</p>
<p>Mandela, who has defended Kabila repeatedly against Western criticism of his human rights record, waited for over an hour for him to arrive at the Harare hotel in which the Organisation of African Unity (OAU) is holding its annual summit.</p>
<p>&quot;I saw him for a short time and we were supposed to meet again,&quot; Mandela told Reuters as he left shortly before 5 p.m. (1500 GMT).</p>
<p>Ten minutes after Mandela left, Kabila arrived in a large black limousine, saying he had come to see the South African leader. He shrugged when told that Mandela had left.</p>
<p>An aide said Mandela saw Kabila briefly in the morning when Africa's leaders gathered for a photograph and waited for him for more than an hour in the afternoon.</p>
<p>The aide said Mandela left to keep an appointment at home.</p>
<p>Mandela said he had met President Yoweri Museveni of Uganda and other African leaders to discuss a home for Mobutu Sese Seko, who ruled Zaire for 32 years, &quot;where he can rest&quot;.</p>
<p>Officials said Mandela had come to Harare mainly to discuss with Kabila possible South African assistance in his efforts to rebuild a nation shattered by 32 years of dictatorship.</p>
<p>The officials said a South African task group headed by Deputy Foreign Minister Aziz Pahad was on standby to visit Congo and assess the potential to help, but was waiting for word from Kabila.</p>
<p>Kabila has failed to keep appointments with Mandela regularly since the South African president started last year to try to negotiate a peaceful transfer of power in Zaire, now renamed the Democratic Republic of Congo.</p>
<p>Kabila kept him waiting for several hours before attending one round of talks aboard a South African naval ship off the African west coast and failed to arrive for a second round a week later.</p>
<p>Since Kabila pronounced himself president of the former Zaire, Mandela has been amongst his staunchest supporters, telling reporters last week &quot;we can trust him&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OAU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
