<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63018" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Euro-MPs want sports to stay on free TV.</title>
<headline>Euro-MPs want sports to stay on free TV.</headline>
<dateline>STRASBOURG 1996-09-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Major sporting, entertainment and scientific events should all be broadcast free of charge on European television, the European Parliament is due to say on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Worried that more and more events of major interest or particular value will be shown exclusively on pay TV, Euro-MPs are expected to urge the member states to introduce laws guaranteeing that the highlights at least will be broadcast on free terrestrial television.</p>
<p>The call comes in a report, due to be adopted on Wednesday, which makes a series of recommendations designed to guarantee a future in Europe for state-funded television, which Euro-MPs fear may not survive the increasing competition from commercial channels.</p>
<p>According to the report, drafted by British Socialist Carole Tongue, the state-funded channels' share of European Union audiences has plummeted from 82 percent in 1984 to 46 percent in 1994.</p>
<p>The report says public service broadcasting should continue to receive support from the EU and national governments, so that it can continue to fulfil its role as a promoter of European culture and new talent, and a provider of unbiased information.</p>
<p>During a debate on Tuesday on state-funded TV, Tongue told Euro-MPs, &quot;We are in danger of witnessing a trend towards a society of those who can afford the privilege of impartial information and those who can't, those who can afford to watch our national sporting treasures and those who can't&quot;.</p>
<p>Industry Commissioner Martin Bangemann told the EU assembly the public could be informed just as well by the new, private TV channels as by public TV.</p>
<p>&quot;If you have got a monopoly, you can't be serving the interests of democracy,&quot; he insisted, adding that if public service broadcasting was as good as Carole Tongue made out, then she need have no fears for its future.</p>
<p>The majority of Euro-MPs think otherwise and are likely to demand an increase in funding for public service channels with a pan-European remit, like ARTE and EURONEWS.</p>
<p>They are expected to ask the Commission to sanction public funding for state channels &quot;provided they strictly fulfil their public service obligations&quot;, and allow them to bid jointly for television rights without contravening new EU rules on media concentration.</p>
<p>For their part, public TV channels should make a commitment to improve their accountability to the public, become more independent from governments and strictly respect their obligation to broadcast a majority of European programmes, parliament is likely to say.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STRASBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
