<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630125" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: OAU to consider response to Sierra Leone coup.</title>
<headline>OAU to consider response to Sierra Leone coup.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>African leaders meet privately on Tuesday to consider what, if anything, to do about the Sierra Leone coup they denounced in ringing terms at the opening of their Organisation of African Unity (OAU) summit.</p>
<p>&quot;Democracy must be restored in that country as a matter of urgency,&quot; President Robert Mugabe of Zimbabwe told the 53-nation OAU as he assumed the chairmanship on Monday.</p>
<p>But like other African leaders who denounced the military grab for power in Freetown, Mugabe did not say how a popular government should be reinstated.</p>
<p>OAU spokesman Ibrahim Dagash said delegates would be briefed on Tuesday by the Economic Community for West African States (Ecowas) on efforts to force Major Johnny Paul Koromah to restore power to elected President Ahmad Tejan Kabbah.</p>
<p>&quot;Ecowas was mandated by the council of the OAU to take the appropriate action it deemed necessary to make the lives of this regime miserable, hellish - as uncomfortable as possible.</p>
<p>&quot;They will tell us tomorrow what they have done to implement that mandate,&quot; he said, adding that the OAU delegates would then decide what to do to help.</p>
<p>There was no direct comment from African leaders on the joint armed mission by Nigeria, Ghana and Guinea to reverse the Koromah coup.</p>
<p>But speakers echoed the growing support for an African peace-keeping capacity when they underlined the responsibility of neighbours to bolster the continent's fledgling democracies.</p>
<p>African governments have remained cool to a joint proposal by Britain, France and the United States for an African peacekeeping capacity partly financed by the West.</p>
<p>But an African diplomat told Reuters there was growing enthusiasm for an entirely African initiative to build on the Ecowas operation in Sierra Leone.</p>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan, a native of Ghana, said regional powers, neighbours and the international community had a duty to underpin vulnerable democracies.</p>
<p>&quot;Where democracy has been usurped, let us do whatever is in our power to restore it to its rightful owners, the people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>OAU Secretary General Salim Ahmed Salim, reelected on Monday for an unprecedented third four-year term, said the Sierra Leone coup defied the trend towards democracy and accountability in Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything must be done to restore constitutional legality in that country,&quot; he said to applause from OAU delegates.</p>
<p>There was applause, too, for Laurent Kabila, the new Democratic Republic of Congo's self-proclaimed president and Africa's newest leader. But comments on his overthrow last month of veteran dictator Mobutu Sese Seko did not include unconditional endorsement.</p>
<p>Annan demanded access for the United Nations to refugees trapped in the southeast of the former Zaire and insisted that the protection of human life and human rights should be Kabila's highest priority.</p>
<p>South African President Nelson Mandela, who helped persuade Mobutu to quit after 32 years of despotic rule, left the summit without speaking at length to Kabila.</p>
<p>Though he visited Harare largely to discuss a South African assistance package for the new Congo, Mandela left after waiting more than hour for Kabila.</p>
<p>Mandela did meet privately with Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat, who asked the OAU to condemn Israel for stalling the Middle East peace process and risking conflict by continuing to build settlements in territory his people claimed.</p>
<p>Palestinian relations with Israel and Libya's continuing row with the United States and Britain were also on the OAU leaders' agenda for Tuesday, Dagash said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OAU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SILEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
