<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630197" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Gold Fields says strike hits some mines.</title>
<headline>Gold Fields says strike hits some mines.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold Fields of South Africa Ltd said on Monday a one-day general strike call had resulted in widely varying levels of action at its mines.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the strike) seems to have had quite a mixed reception in our operations,&quot; Gold Fields spokesman Andrew Davidson told Reuters.</p>
<p>Davidson declined to speculate as to what level of production was likely to be lost as a result of the strike.  </p>
<p>Driefontein Consolidated Ltd west division's morning shift reported for work although it worked no Sunday night shift. Absenteeism from the day shift was 18 percent.</p>
<p>Dries' east division's morning shift had not reported for work. Last night's shift also failed to work.</p>
<p>Kloof Gold Mining Co Ltd's Kloof division was working normally after the night shift failed to report for work. The Leeudoorn division's morning and night shifts stayed away. Libanon's day shift was at work although its night shift stated away.</p>
<p>Deelkraal Gold Mining Co Ltd has 73 percent of its day shift at work. NOrtham Platinum Ltd was working as normal.</p>
<p>O'Okiep Copper Co Ltd and Black Mountain Mineral Development Co were working as normal.</p>
<p>Gold Fields said that there was a complete stay away at its Greenside Colliery.</p>
<p>The Congress of South African Trade Unions (Cosatu) has mobilised for a one-day strike to protest the Basic Conditions of Employment Bill which has already passed through Cabinet and is expected to be tabled before parliament soon.</p>
<p>It is demanding a 40-hour working week, six months maternity leave and double pay for Sunday work.</p>
<p>Goldfields' gold production for the quarter to March totalled 23,448 kilograms.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
