<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630228" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa Stock Exchange on track for bumper year.</title>
<headline>S.Africa Stock Exchange on track for bumper year.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Johannesburg Stock Exchange is on track for a bumper trading year as investor confidence in local shares returns on the back of currency stability and growing efficiency at the exchange.</p>
<p>JSE turnover, excluding arbitrage deals, to the end of April reached 58.6 billion rand, roughly half the total volume for calendar 1996, exchange president Russell Loubser told a South African Reserve Bank seminar.</p>
<p>&quot;We should, if things keep going the way they are now, exceed the turnover for last year,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Loubser said foreigners were exhibiting a growing appetite for local stock with net purchases to date at eight billion rand.</p>
<p>&quot;If things continue the way that they are going now we could see the net foreign inflow into the equities market this year exceeding the last three years, maybe the last four years combined,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Foreigners were net buyers of 5.2 billion rand worth of South African shares in 1996.</p>
<p>Loubser said rising foreign interest stemmed from relative stability in the rand after the speculative shocks of last year.</p>
<p>&quot;That confidence is being exhibited in our equity because they see the rand being fairly stable.&quot;</p>
<p>Rand stability combined with the promise of a gradual lifting of exchange controls was also prompting more foreign companies to take a fresh look at drawing from the South African pool of equity capital, Loubser said.</p>
<p>&quot;For the first time in a very long time I'm getting inquiries from very significant (offshore) players, in the financial markets specifically, who are saying, 'When will I be able to list on your stock exchange?'.&quot;</p>
<p>Currently, just 27 of the JSE's 620 listed companies are based outside South Africa.</p>
<p>Even in the absence of new foreign listings, funds raised on the exchange were on the way to eclipsing the 1996 total of 28.4 billion rand, Loubser said.</p>
<p>But despite the rosy outlook, the JSE was still working hard to repatriate the trade in shares of the 153 South African companies listed on offshore exchanges as well as at home.</p>
<p>In 1995, the value of offshore trading in those 153 companies represented 142.2 percent of the JSE's total turnover, an alarming figure, Loubser said.</p>
<p>The situation has since improved due to improving liquidity and price discovery, with the proportion of offshore to local trade falling to 82.3 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>The exchange president said the statistic would drop to 70 percent his year, adding he aimed to get it down to 50 percent in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;It will only come back if we get our act together...that is, the entire financial system,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Loubser said the exchange was well on the way to becoming fully internationally competitive by the end of the year but challenges which lay ahead included the establishment of an electronic scrip registry, T+5 settlement and the abolition of transaction taxes.</p>
<p>He urged all financial market participants to get behind a move toward scrip-free trading which would speed up settlement and alleviate the pressure on back offices which were creaking under the strain of paper-based processing.</p>
<p>The JSE, the South African Futures Exchange and the South African Bond Exchange were closely co-operating in their efforts to promote paperless trade as well as linking their information technology infrastructures, Loubser said.</p>
<p>-- Justin McCamish, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
