<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63026" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SBC sees losses in lending as normal cost.</title>
<headline>SBC sees losses in lending as normal cost.</headline>
<dateline>BASLE, Switzerland 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss Bank Corp. (SBC) said it was radically changing its method of calculating loss provisions under which credit default is a predictable risk with a certain probability, similar to the actuarial risks in the insurance industry.</p>
<p>&quot;Losses in the lending business should not be treated as extraordinary, unexpected events but as a cost of doing business which must be anticipated and quantified to the greatest extent possible,&quot; SBC said in a statement.</p>
<p>SBC has therefore adopted a new approach for creating provisions known as ACRA, Actuarial Credit Risk Accounting.</p>
<p>The advantages are that credit costs are transparent, the position of &quot;value adjustments, provisions and loan losses&quot; will become more predictable and profits are stabilised at a group level, SBC said.</p>
<p>As a consequence, SBC will take annual recurring charges of around 600 million Swiss francs ($482.2 million) annually starting in 1997. This equals the expected annual loss on the existing loan book.</p>
<p>It will also create a one-time general loss reserve -- the ACRA reserve -- of about two billion francs. This will be charged to the 1996 accounts.</p>
<p>The ACRA reserve will act as a cushion in the balance sheet, making it possible to absorb unexpectedly high loan losses, for example during times of recession.</p>
<p>The ACRA sum should be enough to contain unexpected loan loss cost in 39 of 40 years, SBC said.</p>
<p>In the past loan losses were confined to a few unexpected instances and the fundamental problem that a bank's loan customers might find themselves unable to meet obligations was not given any particular importance by banks.</p>
<p>Steady appreciation of real estate prices and the good condition of the Swiss economy contributed to this sound position of SBC's bank customers.</p>
<p>Precautionary provisions were therefore only built up when an early warning signalled that a credit position could go bad.</p>
<p>This explains why all financial institutions listed provisions and losses at the end of an income statement, as an extraordinary expense.</p>
<p>But in the early 1990s there was a veritable quantum leap in provisions for loan losses in the Swiss banking industry. A sluggish economy, structural problems in different industries and the collapse of the real estate market lead to defaults of many of SBC's borrowing customers.</p>
<p>SBC will now assemble credit portfolios consisting of loans that are comparable in terms of risk and credit rating.</p>
<p>The calculation of expected losses on a loan portfolio is based on statistical analysis and credit risks therefore no longer represent an unexpected risk, but a reduction in income, i.e. a narrowing of the interest margin.</p>
<p>As a rule, the actual default experience fluctuates around the statistically expected loss with variations produced by factors that are not known at the start of the year.</p>
<p>The volatility of these expected losses, represents unexpected losses and thus a genuine credit risk.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore it is not enough for the bank to calculate only the expected loss. Provisions must also be set aside for the unexpected costs so that the bank is not caught unprepared,&quot; SBC said.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340 ($ = 1.244 Swiss Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BASLE, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
