<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630300" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: NATO studies &quot;reserve&quot; force for Bosnia mission.</title>
<headline>NATO studies &quot;reserve&quot; force for Bosnia mission.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senior NATO officers are visiting Bosnia this week to prepare plans for a possible reserve force that could be deployed to back up peacekeeping troops in the country, an alliance spokesman said on Monday.</p>
<p>Officers from the United States, the Netherlands, Italy, Turkey and two countries outside NATO -- Poland and Romania -- are travelling to bases across the country used by the alliance-led Stabilisation Force (SFOR), spokesmen told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;This reconnaissance is designed to enable them to gain a clear picture of the requirements should NATO decide to deploy the SFOR strategic reserve,&quot; Major Chris Riley said.</p>
<p>&quot;The strategic reserve concept is designed to provide a strong reserve force outside Bosnia which can be called upon to rapidly reinforce SFOR in the event of any major crisis which may require a greater number of troops than are currently available on the ground,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The 31,000-strong peace force, charged with enforcing a 1995 peace treaty in Bosnia, is due to withdraw when its mandate expires in June 1998.</p>
<p>But speculation persists that the alliance will be forced to extend the NATO mission to prevent another war from erupting in Bosnia, which is divided into Serb and Moslem-Croat territories.</p>
<p>SFOR officers declined to offer many details about the proposed &quot;strategic reserve&quot; but described the seven-day visit as part of NATO's long-term planning.</p>
<p>Colonel Steven Rausch, another spokesman for SFOR, indicated that units which could comprise the strategic reserve force would conduct military exercises later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be some (military) exercises later in the year and onto into next year. We are talking about a long term process,&quot; Rausch said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've always had forces outside the country that could be called in if the place really went down fast...This is an effort to take a look at the long-term.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
