<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63054" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Finland - Sept 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Finland - Sept 18.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the leading stories in Finnish papers this morning.</p>
<p>HELSINGIN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Declining oxygen and high phosphorus levels pose risk to Gulf of Finland, environment officials say.</p>
<p>- President Martti Ahtisaari said in Lapland Finland must honour its international obligations towards indigenous people.</p>
<p>- Government expected to award nationwide commercial television licence next week. @</p>
<p>- One in every five school children in Helsinki is an immigrant.</p>
<p>- Women account for a quarter of all management level employees in Finland, survey shows. Equality ombudsman says she is not clapping yet.</p>
<p>KAUPPALEHTI</p>
<p>- Finance ministry preparing to ease value-added tax on small firms as of the beginning of 1998. @</p>
<p>- Nokia has &quot;cut the umbilical cord with Motorola,&quot; with the share rising 20 percent since early August while the American rival's share price has declined.</p>
<p>DEMARI</p>
<p>- Parliamentary foreign affairs committee says decision-makers should keep human rights in mind when awarding export permits to weapons manufacturers.</p>
<p>- Labour sports federation CSIT is moving its headquarters to Helsinki from Brussels. @</p>
<p>AAMULEHTI</p>
<p>- Baltic ferries plan to curb boisterous behaviour on cruises by imposing new minimum age limit of 23 years on pasengers.</p>
<p>- Justice ministry proposal would enable officials to release prisoners with life sentences after 11 years.</p>
<p>- Man who imported hundreds of kilos of gold bullion to Finland has left 7.3 million markka in taxes unpaid.</p>
<p>- Finland's big three forest industry firms watching anxiously to see whether fine paper price hikes will hold. @</p>
<p>- The northernmost factory in the EU -- a jigsaw puzzle plant -- will start operations at the beginning of next year in Finland's northernmost municipality, Utsjoki.</p>
<p>- Proposed Nordic natural gas network is on European Union's list of important energy projects for the near future.</p>
<p>TURUN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Brewers' federation demands lower tax on beer -- worried about Sweden's tax break for beer.</p>
<p>- Chernobyl nuclear reactor leak caused no increase in radiation levels in Finland, official says.</p>
<p>--Helsinki Newsroom +358-0-680 50 235</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
