<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630599" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK's future leader chides Britain on policy moves.</title>
<headline>HK's future leader chides Britain on policy moves.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's future leader Tung Chee-hwa chided Britain on Monday for its policies of recent years and urged Prime Minister Tony Blair to patch up relations with China.</p>
<p>In an interview with the British Broadcasting Corporation, extracts of which were released in advance to Reuters, Tung hit out at the changes Britain made in recent years to Hong Kong's political system, including a greater measures of democracy.</p>
<p>The reforms have been a major source of friction between Britain and China. Beijing has vowed to scrap Hong Kong's elected legislature and Tung plans to dilute existing political freedoms from July 1, when British rule ends after 156 years.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue is that to go ahead without the consent of the future sovereign should not happen, it shouldn't have happened,&quot; Tung told the BBC.</p>
<p>Tung, who was a university student in the British city of Liverpool in 1957-1960, said he found it &quot;particularly sad&quot; that Britain had acted the way it had.</p>
<p>He said he would feel proud when China takes back Hong Kong but he hoped the strong bonds with Britain would continue.</p>
<p>Asked what he thought of suggestions by departing colonial Governor Chris Patten that Britain might consider legal action against China to protect civil liberties, Tung replied:</p>
<p>&quot;I think Hong Kong is now dawning on a new era and Britain with the election of Tony Blair as the new leader is also beginning a new era. So I am very much looking forward to an improved Sino-British relationship.&quot;</p>
<p>Tung balanced his criticism with praise of Britain's contribution to Hong Kong's success.</p>
<p>The territory of 6.4 million people is the world's eighth largest trading economy and a place noted for its superlatives, such as the highest per capita ownership of Rolls Royce cars in the world.</p>
<p>&quot;There are many reasons why Hong Kong is successful. Certainly, one of the main reasons is the rule of law we enjoy today, the Western system of governance and the freedom we enjoy today and I think, from that point of view, Britain has indeed contributed greatly to the success of Hong Kong,&quot; Tung said.</p>
<p>The 60-year-old Tung, a former shipping tycoon chosen as post-colonial leader by a China-controlled Selection Committee last December, repeated recent reassurances there would be no persecution of dissidents after the handover.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not going to give all the people who demonstrate the pleasure of becoming martyrs,&quot; he said. So no crackdown? the interviewer asked. &quot;That's right,&quot; Tung replied.</p>
<p>Tung also said he hoped the main pro-democracy group in the territory, the Democratic Party, would join in next year's elections to a new Legislative Council.</p>
<p>The party is one of China's fiercest critics in Hong Kong, and has been sidelined from various handover bodies set up by China to craft the territory's future government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
