<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630535" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru says May consumer price inflation 0.76 pct.</title>
<headline>Peru says May consumer price inflation 0.76 pct.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peruvian consumer prices rose 0.76 percent in May, compared with a 0.7 percent rise in the same month last year and a 0.39 percent rise in April, the government's statistics agency said Monday.</p>
<p>Wholesale prices rose 0.99 percent in May, compared with a 1.0 percent rise in the same month last year and a 0.30 percent rise in April, the National Institute for Statistics and Information (INEI) announced in the official gazette, El Peruano.  </p>
<p>Consumer prices increased 3.02 percent in the period January to May, compared to 5.9 percent in the same period last year.</p>
<p>Wholesale inflation for the first five months of the year was 1.84 percent, compared to 4.6 percent in the January to May period last year, the INEI said.</p>
<p>Consumer prices in Peru rose 11.8 percent in 1996, compared with a 10.2 percent rise in 1995.</p>
<p>In 1996, accumulated inflation for wholesale prices was 11.4 percent, up from 8.80 percent the previous year.  </p>
<p>The government estimates accumulated consumer inflation will be nine percent this year and will drop to &quot;the level of industrialized countries&quot; by 2000.</p>
<p>((-- Saul Hudson, Lima newsroom, 511 221-2134))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
