<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="630763" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pepsico to reorganize U.S. bottling business.</title>
<headline>Pepsico to reorganize U.S. bottling business.</headline>
<byline>Jeff Mamera</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Snack food and beverage giant PepsiCo Inc. said Monday it would create a separate unit for its $6 billion-a-year bottling operations in what Wall Street analysts said was a prelude to a spinoff.</p>
<p>Analysts, who estimate the new PepsiCola Bottling Co. will generate up to $6.4 billion in 1997 revenues, hope to obtain more specific details at a special all-day meeting with company executives set for Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though Pepsi's denying it, there's no question they'll spin that off,&quot; said Skip Carpenter, an analyst at Donaldson Lufkin &amp; Jenrette. &quot;I expect it in early 1998.&quot;</p>
<p>PepsiCo -- which earlier this year said it would spin off its Taco Bell, Pizza Hut and KFC fast-food operations to focus on international beverages -- repeatedly denied Monday's restructuring set the groundwork for another spinoff.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just a new way to structure our business by bringing additional resources and managerial talent to each segment of the company,&quot; said PepsiCo spokesman Brad Shaw.</p>
<p>Wall Street applauded the restructuring by driving PepsiCo's stock up $1.125 to $37.875 in consolidated afternoon trading on the New York Stock Exchange, well above its low of $28.125 earlier this year. It was the most active issue on the NYSE.</p>
<p>Analysts said Monday's move might spell the end -- at least for now -- of PepsiCo's infamous management reshufflings. The company has never gotten &quot;in-sync&quot; because it too quickly moved top managers between assignments, leaving little time for any changes to have an impact, said Tony Brenner, an analyst at UBS Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The management changes there are probably over now,&quot; he said. &quot;I think it's a step in an ongoing corporate culture change at Pepsi.&quot;</p>
<p>Brenner said if PepsiCo does indeed spin off its new beverage operations, it wouldn't be this year.</p>
<p>&quot;That would interfere with the restaurant business spinoff in the fourth quarter,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
