<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63084" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SBC details financial implications of move.</title>
<headline>SBC details financial implications of move.</headline>
<dateline>BASLE, Switzerland 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss Bank Corp. (SBC) said a radical change in its method of provisioning, new structures in its domestic division and a revaluation of its Swiss real estate portfolio would lead to a one-time technical loss of around 1.9 billion Swiss francs in 1996.</p>
<p>SBC said in a statement that this one-time loss compares with an expected group net profit of around 1.4 billion francs for 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;All these initiatives will already have a further positive impact in 1997,&quot; SBC said.  </p>
<p>SBC also said the restructuring of its domestic division should lead to a substantial improvement in earnings of around 400 million francs in the next three years.</p>
<p>&quot;The future freeing up of capital in the domestic division and the low capital intensity of the further expansion projects at group level will permit a one-time reduction in share capital,&quot; SBC said.</p>
<p>To mark the bank's 125th anniversary, the board of directors would propose to the annual shareholders' meeting on May 13, 1997 that instead of a dividend, a capital repayment of 10 francs in nominal capital per share be made, without any tax deduction.</p>
<p>The nominal value of SBC's share will thus fall to 40 francs from 50 francs.</p>
<p>It noted that regulatory authorities, the federal banking commission and rating agencies had been notified of these plans.</p>
<p>SBC said that by a systematic implementation of its measures, it intends to achieve a return of equity (ROE) of around 15 percent after tax on a capital base of around 16 billion francs.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BASLE, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
