<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="631050" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rain dashes hopes for replanting some U.S. corn.</title>
<headline>Rain dashes hopes for replanting some U.S. corn.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Weekend storms that produced 1.5 to 3.0 inches of rain in Indiana and Ohio likely erased many chances farmers there had of replanting corn and will delay replanting of flooded soybean fields, crop sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is going to cause some major problems,&quot; said Joe Miller, an Indiana Farm Bureau market economist. &quot;I have had a bunch of farmers tell me they can't replant corn because of the lateness.&quot;</p>
<p>Indiana and Ohio fields had abundant moisture prior to the weekend and the latest rain put many fields under water.  </p>
<p>&quot;I know we are going to have damage. There will be ponding in western and northwest (Ohio) fields,&quot; said Steve Baertsche, Ohio State University extension director for agriculture. &quot;They had quite a bit of moisture from two weeks ago.&quot;</p>
<p>Ohio and Indiana have had abundant moisture this spring. Weather Services Corp reported in the past 30 days Indianapolis had 174 percent of normal rainfall at 6.24 inches and at Findlay, in northwest Ohio, rainfall was 272 percent of normal at 10.28 inches.  </p>
<p>Baertsche said statewide damage estimates would be assessed Monday by extension leaders and a report should be released late Monday.</p>
<p>The Farm Bureau's Miller said fields are so saturated in east central Indiana, that if the rain stopped now it would be mid-June before replanting could begin. Some of the most saturated counties included Bartholomew, Fayette, Hancock, Henry and Rush.</p>
<p>Meteorologists and crop sources said more rain was forecast through early Wednesday, but amounts should be less than what fell over the weekend.</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk 312-048-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
