<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="631013" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tobacco stocks slip after Miami court ruling.</title>
<headline>Tobacco stocks slip after Miami court ruling.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in U.S. tobacco companies dipped Monday after a Florida judge refused two motions sought by the tobacco industry in a second-hand smoke lawsuit brought by airline flight attendants.</p>
<p>Judge Robert Kaye refused tobacco industry requests to deny the plaintiffs punitive damages and to decertify the suit as a class action.</p>
<p>Philip Morris Cos Inc fell 1-1/8 to 42-7/8, RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp fell 3/4 to 31-5/8, and Lorillard parent Loews Corp fell 3/8 to 96-7/8.  </p>
<p>Chewing tobacco maker UST Inc, which was dropped as a defendant in the suit because its products have not been linked to any of the plaintiffs, fell 3/8 to 28-1/8.</p>
<p>The suit, known as Broin v Philip Morris et al., is one of many pending against the tobacco industry. Some tobacco analysts view the case as one where the industry has a solid chance for victory.</p>
<p>Kaye ruled on the tobacco industry motions Friday. His rulings were sealed until this morning.</p>
<p>Jury selection in the trial is to begin today.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think this is one case where the companies have a very good case,&quot; said John Maxwell, analyst at Wheat First Butcher Singer. &quot;If there's one case that bothers me it's the Mississippi case, because there's no jury, only a judge.&quot;</p>
<p>Maxwell was referring to a Medicaid reimbursement lawsuit to be tried in Mississippi. In a statement late Friday, Philip Morris said the Chancery Court of Jackson County (Miss.) had ruled the suit would not be tried before a jury.</p>
<p>Philip Morris expressed disappointment with the ruling and noted that trials in Florida, Texas and Minnesota would be arugued in front of juries.</p>
<p>((--Wall Street Desk, 212-859-1730))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
