<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63119" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Resources lead Australian stocks down at open.</title>
<headline>Resources lead Australian stocks down at open.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian share market slid lower at the open on Wednesday, a bleak view on miner's prospects and a lack of positive offshore guidance encouraging sellers into the market.</p>
<p>From the opening, the All Ordinaries index fell 11.3 points to 2,243.1. September share price index futures slipped 14 points to 2,248, a 4.9 point premium to the underlying index.</p>
<p>Brokers said that while the whole market was off, attention remained focussed on the resource leaders with increasingly negative sentiment towards the miners.</p>
<p>&quot;The pessimistic view on the miners is leading us down,&quot; said a Sydney broker.</p>
<p>&quot;Metals (prices) and profits are all painting a pretty bleak picture for the resources but there is little else to drive things.&quot;</p>
<p>Bellwether BHP and major miner CRA suffered among the miners, while Crown also lost ground following Tuesday's announcement of media tycoon Kerry Packer's part sale of his stake in the Victorian-based casino operator.</p>
<p>Falls outnumbered rises by a ratio of about three to two, while about 45 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
