<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="631117" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French markets weather poll result, seen volatile.</title>
<headline>French markets weather poll result, seen volatile.</headline>
<byline>Brian Love</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>French financial markets proved one thing on Monday following a left-wing parliamentary election win -- their unpredictability.</p>
<p>Stock and government bond markets took a dive at the open of business, momentarily doing justice to the gloomy predictions of mounting uncertainty on everything from the launch of a European single currency to corporate privatisations.</p>
<p>But they then confounded analysts and investors alike with a U-turn which pushed shares, government bonds, and interest rate futures back into positive territory, where they held out until the end of the day.</p>
<p>Despite a relatively robust show in the face of adversity, mounting concerns over European monetary union plans and the suspense ahead of policy pronouncements by a new Socialist-led government are likely to mean a rocky ride in the days to come.</p>
<p>After sliding by nearly three percent in opening trade, the CAC-40 blue-chip share index finished 0.68 percent higher than its closing level ahead of the election on Friday to finish at 2,601.45.</p>
<p>The franc too pulled through the day relatively unscathed, hovering around 3.3722/27 against the mark late on Monday after slipping as far as 3.3860, albeit a performance attributed more to mark weakness than to the resilience of the French currency.</p>
<p>The pattern was the same for government bonds, bond futures, and PIBOR interest rates futures which, with greater exposure to more nervous foreign investors, tend to bear the brunt of market jitters along with shares.</p>
<p>June PIBOR three-month interest rate contracts finished the day's pit-trading three basis points higher at 96.39, after a plunge in early business to as low as 96.20.</p>
<p>While the prospect of a left-wing victory had dragged stocks down more than six percent last week following a surprise first round election win for the left, market analysts had predicted further losses on Monday when the left won the runoff on Sunday but the Socialists were left short of an overall majority.</p>
<p>In the bond market, analysts said the early slump triggered a surge of buying by both domestic and foreign investors keen to cash in on cheaper prices.</p>
<p>The downside is that the gains by the end of the day, even if the market has come round somewhat to believe in that the Socialist-led government will not reverse the general trend of government financial discipline, leave the market exposed.</p>
<p>The risk, traders and analysts said, was more related to doubts about EMU -- fuelled not simply by the Socialists party's &quot;Yes, but&quot; position on the single currency, but also mounting budget and EMU worries in Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of people had taken bearish French positions,&quot; said BZW international economist Mark Capelton.</p>
<p>&quot;Now they're caught between strategies of EMU delay or a regrouping of core (EMU qualifier countries) around a softer interpretation (of the terms on which countries join).&quot;</p>
<p>In the stock market, the fallout which experts had forecast mainly hit the shares of companies involved in privatisations or in other sectors where a left-wing government is seen as less helpful than the outgoing centre-right coalition.</p>
<p>The overall CAC-40 index at one point rose two percent, which one analyst described as &quot;amazing&quot;.</p>
<p>Shares in defence electronics group Thomson-CSF, whose 58 percent government stake has been put up for sale by the centre-right, closed 6.99 percent lower. The shares of two rival bidders, Lagardere and Alcatel Alsthom also suffered, with the former losing 6.42 percent.</p>
<p>In the absence of clear signals ahead of the formation of a new government, perception of traditional left-wing opposition to privatisations and to restructuring also took its toll in the banking sector.</p>
<p>Investment certificates in state bank Credit Lyonnais, also a medium-term privatisation candidate, fell 4.17 percent to 207.0 francs. The uncertainty spilled over into other financial stocks too, knocking several percent off the price of major players such as BNP and Societe Generale.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
