<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="631262" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian rupee gains mildly vs spot, forward dlr.</title>
<headline>Indian rupee gains mildly vs spot, forward dlr.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indian rupee gained mildly against the spot and forward dollar on Monday, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar touched a low of 35.780 rupees,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;This was the level at which RBI (Reserve Bank of India) bought dollars last week,&quot; he said. The RBI was not active on Monday.</p>
<p>Spot rupee opened steady on Monday at 35.78/79.</p>
<p>There was little demand for dollars on the first working day of the new month amid good supply.</p>
<p>The forward premiums slipped, tracking an easing of call rates, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Exporters continue to sell dollars forward to avail of available premiums,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;Premiums may go down to 4.25 percent but that may be the bottom for now,&quot; said a dealer at a foreign bank.</p>
<p>He said the government may announce a bond auction next week and June 15 would see some tax outflow from banks.</p>
<p>&quot;After all is said and done, the upside is absolutely limited, and 4.8/4.9 percent (six month annualised premium) should be a safe cap,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
