<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="631227" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Delhi shares close higher on fund buying.</title>
<headline>Delhi shares close higher on fund buying.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sustained buying by foreign financial institutions (FIIs) and purchases by domestic mutual funds drove Delhi share prices to a higher close on Monday, brokers said.</p>
<p>The bourse's benchmark index closed 13.83 points higher at 790.38.  </p>
<p>Brokers said they expected the share prices to rise further.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's rally in stock prices was a technical correction since most of the stocks had been over-sold,&quot; said Harish Malhotra of brokerage Malhotra Financial Consultants.</p>
<p>Another broker said: &quot;Resumption of buying by Unit Trust of India (UTI) also aided the upward trend.&quot;</p>
<p>UTI is the country's largest financial institution.</p>
<p>ITC soared 39.75 rupees to 480.00 on heavy buying by foreign and domestic financial institutions and short covering by speculators, brokers said.</p>
<p>ACC gained 17.50 rupees to 1,085.00. Larsen and Toubro increased 3.50 rupees to 214.20.</p>
<p>Tractor and motorcycle maker Escorts Ltd rose 1.00 rupee to 81.75. Its annual results for 1996/97 (April-March) were announced on Monday after the end of trading.</p>
<p>The company's net profit for 1996/97 increased to 1.27 billion rupees from 1.00 billion for 1995/96. It set a dividend of 45 percent, up from 40 percent in the previous year.</p>
<p>Reliance Industries climbed 5.25 rupees to 304.25.</p>
<p>-- New Delhi newsroom +91-11 301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
