<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="631475" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Oil prices edge up but trend still sideways.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Oil prices edge up but trend still sideways.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>World oil prices edged slightly higher on Monday but dealers said the underlying trend was broadly sideways.</p>
<p>Benchmark Brent crude oil futures for July delivery were up 15 cents at $19.54 a barrel at 1525 GMT.</p>
<p>The nearest Brent futures contract has averaged just $19 over the past three months after falling sharply from a high of $24.78 at the beginning of the year.</p>
<p>Although prices peaked at well over $20 last month many dealers have stayed sceptical of fledgling rallies in recent weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no urge to move out of the current price range,&quot; said Nigel Saperia, managing director of the oil division at Bankers Trust International in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Fundamentally there's too much oil around but frankly there always is at this time of year,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said much still depended on the ability of U.S. gasoline demand to prop up the wider oil market this summer.</p>
<p>Western oil refiners may also lend support to the crude oil market in the coming weeks as healthy profit margins encourage higher throughputs.</p>
<p>A sharp drop in the value of physical Brent last week boosted margins by 45 cents a barrel for Rotterdam plants.</p>
<p>Tighter than expected supply of crude oil could also help prices. For the second year running analysts have cut their forecasts for non-OPEC supply growth because new North Sea fields have failed to come on stream when planned.</p>
<p>Market pundits reckon there will be a shortfall of 300,000 barrels per day, easing the downward price pressure on Organisation of the Petroleum Exporting Countries oil, which has been under threat because of the cartel's own over-production.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, as expected the United Nations Secretary General Kofi Annan recommended to the Security council that the six-month &quot;oil for food&quot; deal be renewed , a U.N. source said on Monday.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						  Jun 02   May 30</p>
<p>						 (1525 GMT)(close)</p>
<p> Dated Brent				 $19.24    $19.08</p>
<p> IPE July Brent			    $19.54    $19.38</p>
<p> NYMEX July light crude		  $21.03    $20.85</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
