<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="631432" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French Socialists want to renegotiate budget pact.</title>
<headline>French Socialists want to renegotiate budget pact.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's Socialist party reiterated on Monday that it wanted to renegotiate the European Union's &quot;stability pact&quot; meant to limit budget deficits after the launch of a single currency.</p>
<p>Spokesman Francois Hollande, asked in an interview with Reuters Financial Television whether his party was still seeking to renegotiate the pact, replied: &quot;Yes&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want to renegotiate the treaty, we want to renegotiate the application of the treaty and we want to discuss with our partners to see what they accept and what they don't accept,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to have assurances the stability pact does not signify new austerity in France,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He also told a news conference France hoped to discuss with its European partners the entry of Italy and Spain to monetary union.</p>
<p>&quot;We made it a condition (for backing monetary union) so obviously it is important to us and now negotiations will start with our partners, the government itself will be committed, and you will see in the course of the next few months how this issue develops,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
