<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="631478" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE crude oil futures rise on back of NYMEX comple.</title>
<headline>IPE crude oil futures rise on back of NYMEX comple.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE crude oil futures moved to trade at slightly higher ground on Monday afternoon after the NYMEX complex rose further than expected, traders said.</p>
<p>July Brent was trading 8 cents up at $19.48 a barrel by 1505 GMT, having hit a high of $19.55 a little while earlier, and June gas oil was $1.25 a tonne higher at $173.25, after trading earlier at about 50 cents down.</p>
<p>NYMEX's WTI July contract was 9 cents up at $20.97 and gasoline was $0.34 cents up at 63.15 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>&quot;NYMEX's TWI is better bid now,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>He thought July Brent would try to test its next resistance level of $19.63.</p>
<p>&quot;If it (July Brent) is going to turn around, it is because gasoline is doing something,&quot; a second trader said shortly before the rise, as Brent futures were still trading at lower positive numbers.</p>
<p>But he said that Brent was range-bound, not interested in testing drastically higher or lower ground, adding that an earlier short-lived rally before NYMEX opened did not hold as selling set into New York and spilled over to London.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
