<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63152" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP BUDGETARY CONTROL COMMITTEE AGENDA - SEPT 25-26.</title>
<headline>EP BUDGETARY CONTROL COMMITTEE AGENDA - SEPT 25-26.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Budgetary Control [[ Wednesday 25 September 1996 ]] ***The room number will be displayed on the notice board*** 0.1 ===] Wednesday, 25 September 1996 at 3 p.m. 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE219.150 ) 2. Approval of minutes of meeting of: (PE219.147 ) 3. Chairman's announcements 4. Decisions on procedure 5. Integrated administrative and control system for certain Community aid schem es (amendment of Regulation 3508/92) (T04839) CNS96122 COM(96)0174 C4-0313/96 + CONT Fond R GARRIGA POLLEDO S. (PPE) (PE218.055 ) - Consideration and adoption of a draft report 5.1 * * * ===] In the presence of Mr Jo t o PINHEIRO, Member of the COMMISSION 6. 1994 discharge - 6th and 7th EDF (T04171) (T04171) DEC0065 COM(95)0180 C4-0198/96 + CONT Fond R WYNN Terence. (PSE) (PE215.702/DEF) + CONT Fond WYNN Terence. (PSE) (PE215.702/DEF) - Exchange of views 6.1 * * * 7. On-the-spot checks and monitoring by the Commission for the detection of fra uds against EC financial interests (T04630) CNS95358 COM(95)0690 C4-0115/96 + CONT Fond R THEATO Diemut. (PPE) (PE218.052 ) - Consideration and adoption of a draft report 7.1 * * * ===] In the presence of Mr Jan O. KARLSSON, Member of the COURT OF AUDITORS 8. Presentation of the special report of the Court of Auditors, No 1/96, concer ning the MED programmes - Member responsible: Juan Manuel FABRA VALLES - Exchange of views 8.1 * * * 8.2 * * * * * * * * ===] Thursday, 26 September 1996 8.4 *** In private *** ===] In the presence of Mr Michael GEUENICH, chairman of the Budget Group and me mber of the Bureau of the ECONOMIC AND SOCIAL COMMITTEE 9. Transfer of appropriations 26/96 - NCE - Economic and Social Committee/ Comi tee of the Regions (GBD2696 ) - Member responsible: Joaquim MIRANDA 9.1 * * * 10. Sound and efficient financial management (SEM) in the approach to the year 2000 (T04942) INI0523 INI0523 + CONT Fond COLOM I N. (PSE) - Consideration of Working Documents Nos 3, 4 and 5 11. Control and implementation of the current budget (T04932) PE219.152 ATT1232 + CONT Fond ELLES James E. (PPE) - Exchange of views and - Adoption of motion for a resolution 12. 1997 budget - Section III (T04556) PE219.151 (T04556) BUD0074 COM(96)0300 C4-0350/96 + CONT Avis A ELLES James E. (PPE) F BUDG Fond R BRINKHORST Laurens J (ELD) (PE219.042 ) - Consideration and adoption of draft opinion - Consideration of amendments 13. Any other business 14. Date of next meeting (PE/XV/OJ/96-12 ) - FIN - END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
