<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="631841" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FRENCH ELECTION - SOCIALIST/COMMUNIST POLICIES.</title>
<headline>FRENCH ELECTION - SOCIALIST/COMMUNIST POLICIES.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the economic policies of the French Socialist party and Communist party as outlined during the campaign ahead of France's parliamentary election.</p>
<p>Socialist leader Lionel Jospin will become France's next prime minister after the vote brought the left to power, but he needs support from the Communist Party to have an absolute majority in parliament.</p>
<p>SOCIALIST PARTY:</p>
<p>- Backs European monetary union, but with conditions.</p>
<p>Wants Italy, Spain in at the start, EMU entry criteria read in terms of the trend, a euro which is not overvalued, European economic government and wants euro zone countries to be bound by solidarity and growth pact, instead of an &quot;austerity pact&quot;.</p>
<p>Party leader Jospin said in an interview in Le Monde he saw no reason to feel bound by &quot;stability pact&quot; after EMU start.</p>
<p>- Opposes new referendum on monetary union and says its line will be line of left-wing government, whoever it comprises.</p>
<p>- Jospin says opposes a new round of austerity just to fulfil a strict, arithmetic interpretation of Maastricht criteria and wants negotiations on a political solution with Germany but also says there will be no rise in public spending.</p>
<p>- 700,000 jobs to be created: 350,000 in public sector, with funds to come from scrapping of existing job subsidy schemes.</p>
<p>- aims to cut work week to 35 hours from 39 over three year period, with emphasis on negotiated solution, starting with a &quot;national conference&quot; of social partners.</p>
<p>- budget for research raised to 2.5 percent of GDP</p>
<p>- entrepreneurs, small businesses helped by developing tax system favourable to risk investment for young companies and simplifying administrative procedures</p>
<p>- payroll charges cut, cost shifted onto enlarged CSG levy, VAT on basic goods lowered, housing tax burden on lower income groups eased, wealth tax raised</p>
<p>- reform welfare system, via control of health spending in negotiated way and ensuring free care for low income households</p>
<p>- existing pensions system to be bolstered. Jospin says he opposes recently adopted law which would introduce private pension funds but final position on private funds unclear.</p>
<p>- education to be top budget priority</p>
<p>- French public service model to be preserved. Security, education, transport, health, post and telecoms are services which must be guaranteed to all French people.</p>
<p>- opposed to &quot;privatisation&quot; but apparently keeping options open on sales of stakes in state companies. Says would &quot;consult&quot; staff France Telecom on partial sale planned by centre-right.</p>
<p>- environmentally, public transport to be priority, tax on fuels to be adjusted to fit pollution criteria, moratorium on nuclear plant construction, closure of &quot;superphoenix&quot; fast- breeder reactor, Rhine-Rhone-Saone canal project to be scrapped</p>
<p>- administrative checks on company layoffs to be reestablished</p>
<p>COMMUNIST PARTY:</p>
<p>Party leader Robert Hue outlined main policy points in speech on April 25:</p>
<p>- opposes European single currency project, believes January 1, 1999 launch date cannot be met and wants referendum on issue. wants renegotiation of EMU, other forms of monetary cooperation</p>
<p>- wants to create 1.5 million jobs in two years, cut working week to 35 hours without salary loss, retirement at 60 but at 55 for women and people in tough jobs</p>
<p>scrap &quot;Juppe reforms&quot;, 14.6 percent social charge on company financial revenues and speculation earnings to raise 192 billion francs</p>
<p>- cut in VAT and fuel excise duties as well as in income tax on low incomes plus reduction in relief for capital income as well as reform of local business tax to generate 100 billion in extra revenue</p>
<p>- emergency plan against poverty and exclusion, funded by quadrupling of wealth tax, which says would bring in 30 billion francs</p>
<p>- raise minimum wage by 1,000 francs a month and later by 1,500 for all salaries below 15,000 francs a month and raise minimum unemployment benefit (RMI). (minimum wage at present is 37.91 francs per hour).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
