<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="631988" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Investors eagerly await German ProSieben shares.</title>
<headline>Investors eagerly await German ProSieben shares.</headline>
<byline>Nele Husmann</byline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>German television company ProSieben Media AG, poised to debut on the German stock market, on Monday said it had held its market share steady in May, making the upcoming share sale even more attractive.</p>
<p>In a statement ProSieben, which runs the ProSieben and Kabel 1 commercial television channels, said its market share in May was unchanged at 13.1 percent, with ProSieben raising its market share very slightly to 19.1 percent from 19.0.</p>
<p>On the other hand Kabel 1's market share slipped to 4.0 percent from 4.1 percent.</p>
<p>As the June 24 sale date for ProSieben shares approaches, equity traders predict the issue will be a run-away success.</p>
<p>&quot;For many private investors the question is no longer whether they should buy but rather when they can buy,&quot; said Bankgesellschaft Berlin analyst Sebastian Stein.</p>
<p>On the other hand, market analysts also warned investors against embarking on a blind buying spree for Germany's first ever listed television company, noting the industry entails a variety of risks.</p>
<p>BHF Bank, coordinating the issue of 17.5 million preference shares, suggested the shares should be priced between 70 and 80 marks ($46.7), but argued for an issuance price at the lower end of the spectrum. The shares will begin bourse trade on July 7.</p>
<p>ProSieben hopes to earn at least one billion marks with the new issue, which would translate into the shares costing at least 57 marks.</p>
<p>Pierre Drach, head of Independent Research in Frankfurt, said a price of 65 marks per share would reflect the company's worth adequately. He predicted the shares would be a real hit with investors under 50 years of age particularly since the station offers entertaining programming but has steered clear of the costly sports sector.</p>
<p>Analysts cautioned however the ProSieben listing would not be a repeat of telecommunications company Telekom AG's glitzy share market listing November.</p>
<p>&quot;ProSieben is not a second Telekom issue,&quot; said Petra Heist, analyst at Bayerische Vereinsbank, adding &quot;this is a typical high risk-high return share which trades off higher earnings potential with higher risks.&quot;</p>
<p>She cited possible changes in European Commission rules as well as new domestic legislation as potential risks for the industry as a whole.</p>
<p>Currently Germany's public television networks cannot air commercials after eight o'clock in the evening, leaving a huge opportunity for private stations, able to air advertisements throughout the night.</p>
<p>Additionally BHF Bank analysts warned ProSieben's 1997 results might be lower at 3.60 marks per share, down from last year's 5.60 marks.</p>
<p>Separately analysts also worried about a change in cost structures, which could potentially swing results dramatically in either direction.</p>
<p>Television companies pay 60 percent of all costs for movies, and if these become suddenly more expensive, then this would be quite evident in the results, Bankgesellschaft's Stein said.</p>
<p>On the other hand Stein also said that ProSieben had enough material on hand to last for three years and should therefore be less exposed to any such changes.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.713 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
