<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="631937" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-French jobless falls. Is left &quot;lucky winner&quot;?.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-French jobless falls. Is left &quot;lucky winner&quot;?.</headline>
<byline>Brian Love</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>French unemployment fell slightly in April, but the news on Monday of the third monthly fall in a row came too late to help the centre-right government, swept out of power in parliamentary elections on Sunday night.</p>
<p>The official jobless number fell 6,400 to 3,081,100, labour ministry data showed.</p>
<p>But the unemployment rate, still stuck at a post-war record 12.8 percent, provided a stark reminder to the left of the task that it faces after a stunning election victory on the back of promises to make the fight against joblessness its top priority.</p>
<p>Compared to the same stage last year, the number out of work and eligible for unemployment benefit was 2.1 percent higher at the end of April despite the drop, which came after declines of 4,800 in March and 7,500 in February.</p>
<p>The number of young jobless people fell again in April, with the portion of men aged 25 or less down 1.5 percent from a month earlier and the number of jobless young women down 0.5 percent.</p>
<p>When outgoing Prime Minister Alain Juppe took over the top post in mid-1995 the unemployment rate stood at 11.5 percent.</p>
<p>He promised to make jobs his absolute priority in line with campaign pledges which won Jacques Chirac the presidency in the same year.</p>
<p>Juppe asked at the time to be judged on his performance but had altered tack within months to focus on budget spending cuts and getting the public deficit into shape to qualify for the planned single european currency.</p>
<p>Voters issued a damning verdict in Sunday's election runoff vote, putting the left, led by Lionel Jospin's Socialist party, back in the driving seat in France's National Assembly</p>
<p>Monthly unemployment figures tend to be highly volatile, but if the trend persists it may make it easier for a Socialist-led government to live up to the promises of its election campaign.</p>
<p>Jospin, set to be France's prime minister, has set a goal of creating 700,000 jobs over the next couple of years, half of them to be generated in the public sector with funds raised by scrapping existing job subsidy schemes judged as ineffective.</p>
<p>He has also pledged to push for a shorter 35-hour working week to provide more recruitment opportunities than under the current legal 39-hour week.</p>
<p>It remains to be seen whether he will reap the benefits of his hapless predecessor Juppe, whose dogged determination to cut back on public spending and qualify France for the euro single currency failed to muster public support as the number out of work or only eligible for minimum state support kept rising.</p>
<p>It may turn out that Jospin reaps the benefit of an upturn in growth which the centre-right had long been promising as the remedy for France's jobless scourge.</p>
<p>&quot;They're (the left) the lucky winners,&quot; said ABN Philippe Brossard, economist at ABN Amro bank in Paris.</p>
<p>&quot;Growth is creating more jobs full stop and we have more growth than we thought.&quot;</p>
<p>An indication of the state in which the left will inherit the economy comes on Thursday when national statistics institute INSEE releases data on France's growth domestic product (GDP) for the first three months of the year.</p>
<p>The outgoing government had been predicting a pick-up in the economy to produce at least 2.3 percent GDP growth this year and had a forecast of 2.8 percent growth in 1998.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
