<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="632009" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan unions vow to oppose privatisation plans.</title>
<headline>Pakistan unions vow to oppose privatisation plans.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani trade unions are braced to resist government plans to sell state-owned utilities, banks and industrial units, union officials said on Monday.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif's government, which took power after February 3 elections, wants to press ahead with privatising state assets, pledging to use the proceeds towards retiring Pakistan's foreign debt of at least $30 billion.</p>
<p>Its programme calls for the privatisation of the Water and Power Development Authority (WAPDA), Karachi Electric Supply Corporation (KESC), Pakistan Telecommunication Co Ltd (PTCL), Sui Northern Gas Pipelines Ltd (SNGPL), Habib Credit and Exchange Bank, Habib Bank Ltd and 45 industrial units.</p>
<p>However, trade unions have vowed to resist the plans, which they fear may throw many of their members out of work.</p>
<p>The Pakistan Railways Employees Union (PREM), affiliated with the right-wing Jamaat-i-Islami party, is contacting trade unions in all the major state corporations to forge a united front.</p>
<p>PREM's information secretary, Tabraiz Abbasi, told Reuters trade unions in Rawalpindi, near the capital Islamabad, were planning a joint protest meeting on June 4.</p>
<p>&quot;We were against privatisation yesterday and we are against it today,&quot; said Rafique Butt, general secretary of People's Unity, the labour union in Pakistan International Airlines with links to Benazir Bhutto's Pakistan People's Party.</p>
<p>Left and right-wing unions seem prepared to drop their political rivalry to join hands against privatisation.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been contacted by PREM union and we are with them on the issue,&quot; said Jaleel Ahmed, an official of the left-of-centre People's Unity.</p>
<p>&quot;We are dead against it as privatisation has given the country nothing but unemployment.&quot;</p>
<p>Ahmed rejected a golden handshake scheme devised by the previous government to compensate workers laid off after the sale of public sector units, many of which are grossly overstaffed.</p>
<p>&quot;Go and see the hardship being faced by the people expelled from the privatised units,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Privatisation Commission said there were no plans to revise the scheme, hammered out in months of talks with trade unions when the Kot Addu power plant was sold.</p>
<p>Union protests delayed the sale of Kot Addu to Britain's National Power Plc for over a year before the compensation formula, seen as a model for future privatisations, was agreed with the Privatisation Commission in August 1995.</p>
<p>Pakistan launched its privatisation programme in 1990 during Sharif's first government and the programme continued, albeit at a slower pace, under Bhutto's 1993-1996 government.</p>
<p>So far more than 100 industrial units have been sold, raising 51.7 billion rupees ($1.277 billion).</p>
<p>($1 = 40.49 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
