<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="632098" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Emap sees continued profitable growth.</title>
<headline>Emap sees continued profitable growth.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>British media company EMAP Plc announced a 40 percent rise in pre-tax profit to 121.1 million pounds ($198.2 million) on Monday and forecast continued growth in earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;The UK economy remains strong while in France and in Germany, although the situation is less certain, there are reasonable grounds for expecting a modest upturn in the coming year. We expect next year to be one of continued profitable growth,&quot; chairman Sir John Hoskyns said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The company increased its dividend to 13 pence per share, a 16 percent rise.</p>
<p>EMAP has recently reshaped its media businesses, selling out of its original local newspaper operations and expanding in UK commercial radio and French consumer magazines.</p>
<p>&quot;These results demonstrate once again the strong growth and margin improvement which EMAP has been able to generate in both its acquisitions and underlying businesses,&quot; said Hoskyns.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength of the UK economy has been evident in all our major markets, but especially those oriented directly towards the consumer. In France, where our underlying revenue growth has been much more modest, we have delivered significant operating margin improvement.&quot;($ = 0.611 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
