<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="632197" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - June 2.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - June 2.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Chinese political and business stories in leading newspapers, prepared by Reuters in Beijing. Reuters has not checked the stories and does not guarantee their accuracy. Telephone: (8610) 6532-1921. Fax: (8610) 6532-4978.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA SECURITIES DAILY</p>
<p>- China government securities depository trust and clearing company prepares to launch nationwide custody and clearing system for treasury bills.</p>
<p>- China sets 33 percent tax on local currency business of foreign banks though China Daily notes that foreign exchange business of same banks will be taxed at 15 percent.</p>
<p>- Guangdong Overseas Chinese Trust and Investment Company takes over Guangdong Nanfang Financial Services General Company.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA DAILY</p>
<p>- Fuji Heavy Industries signs letter of intent to invest $36.87 million to take 51 percent stake in subcompact car joint venture with China Guizhou Aviation and China Guizhou Joint Automotive Industrial.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FINANCIAL NEWS</p>
<p>- State Economic and Foreign Trade Commission issues notice ordering regulation of chaotic liquor production and new bid to clamp down on smuggling.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MARKET DAILY</p>
<p>- Competition in mobile phone market heats up in Beijing as Unicom and Beijing Wireless Communication Bureau cut prices.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PEOPLE'S DAILY</p>
<p>- Communist Party newspaper gives front-page coverage to Politburo standing committee member Hu Jintao in making call for stepped up efforts in education. Hu made the remarks at a meeting with students and teachers for International Children's Day.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
