<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="632235" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: FOCUS-Bank of Thailand hit by finance merger woes.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Bank of Thailand hit by finance merger woes.</headline>
<byline>Vithoon Amorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Thailand faces a delicate, uphill task in helping the country's troubled non-bank finance sector ride out its current crisis through mergers and acquisitions, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>The central bank on Monday denied it would force about 30 small, mostly family-owned finance firms, to merge but said it would soon propose guidelines for consolidation of a sector hit by mounting non-performing property loans.</p>
<p>Some local newspapers have speculated that the central bank could take the stern measures.</p>
<p>The central bank's annoucement, carried in a statement, came a week after the failed merger between cash-strapped Finance One Plc and Thai Danu Bank, which had the authorities' blessing and was touted as a model for consolidation in the ailing finance sector. The two parties cited tax and legal constraints for the failure.</p>
<p>The central bank said it would promptly consider proposed finance mergers which could expect incentives such as new bank licences.</p>
<p>It has encouraged mergers to strengthen the financial sector in a bid to avert any potential meltdown.</p>
<p>&quot;The timing is not right for the central bank to use the stick while market sentiment is shaky. Any drastic measures to rectify finance company problems could aggravate their pains and produce a backlash,&quot; said Somchai Trairatpirom, senior vice-president of SITCA Investment and Securities Plc.</p>
<p>Industry estimates put non-performing loans in the 91-company finance sector between 20 and 25 percent of its total outstanding loans. Most deteriorating assets languish in the ailing property market.</p>
<p>Analysts said a central bank requirement for financial institutions to detail non-performing loans and sub-standard assets from mid-year could further erode market confidence in finance firms.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan said on Monday the authorities would make it easier for finance firms to merge but declined to spell out details.</p>
<p>The sector has been hit by the prolonged bearishness of Thai stocks. The collapse of the Finance One-Thai Danu merger refocused market attention on the sector's declining health.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody denies that something needs to be done to shore up the sector and the Bank of Thailand has a lot of clout to induce small companies to merge,&quot; said Supavat Saichua of Krungthai Thanikit Plc.</p>
<p>Supavat said the central bank, through its role as lender of the last resort to troubled finance firms, enjoyed the leverage of urging companies to consolidate.</p>
<p>He said a recent study of the sector showed the Thai economy should have only 15-25 non-bank finance companies.</p>
<p>Supavat was also undeterred by the abortive Finance One-Thai Danu merger.</p>
<p>&quot;Finance One and Thai Danu are different types of companies with different cultures. I think it would be easier for big finance firms like Phatra Thanakit or Dhana Siam to absorb or take in small finance firms,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts asked the central bank to exercise care in beefing up the sector and to avoid repeating its earlier move to announce names of 10 firms facing short-term cash-flow problems early this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank has the responsibility to protect public savings kept in finance companies while Thailand still does not have a deposit guarantee system,&quot; said Kultida Malakul of Chao Phaya Finance and Securities Co.</p>
<p>The central bank said on Sunday that public deposits and creditors would receive full protection in finance mergers encouraged by the government.</p>
<p>The Bank of Thailand has since February asked the public not to stage a run on deposits in finance companies, saying it would be prepared to guarantee promissory notes issued by these institutions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
