<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63221" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Justice Dept to review Maine nuclear plant.</title>
<headline>U.S. Justice Dept to review Maine nuclear plant.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Department of Justice was asked to review allegations over a problematic computer analysis developed to show the adequacy of safety systems at the Maine Yankee nuclear plant, Maine Yankee Atomic Power Co said Thursday.</p>
<p>The investigation stems from an anonymous letter to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) in December 1995 alleging Maine Yankee's emergency core cooling system was inadequate and that Maine Yankee deliberately failed to comply with federal regulations, the company said.  </p>
<p>The issue centers on Main Yankee's application of a computer code developed in the 1980s to test the emergency core cooling system under certain accident conditions.</p>
<p>The company said it was informed today of the request by the NRC, which has been investigating this issue.</p>
<p>Although a Maine Yankee review demonstrated its application of the code is sound, the company submitted a new analysis and code to the NRC, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not unusual for the NRC to seek a Justice Department review in high profile cases such as this one,&quot;  Mary Ann Lynch, vice president and general counsel for Maine Yankee, said in a statement. &quot;It is our understanding that it represents a continuation of the review process.&quot;</p>
<p>The 910 megawatt Maine Yankee plant in Wiscasset, Maine, is 39 percent owned by Central Maine Power Co, 20 percent by New England Electric System and Northeast Utilities and 22 percent by other New England utilities.</p>
<p>--New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1610109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
