<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63231" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW/General Magic sees rev growth.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW/General Magic sees rev growth.</headline>
<byline>Mark Egan</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Magic Inc's new chairman and chief executive said Thursday he expected revenues at the Internet software company to pick up quickly.</p>
<p>&quot;My expectation is that in the next fiscal year you'll see more growth in the top line,&quot; Steve Markman said in a telephone interview. &quot;The products are ready and starting to ship, so I think there will be opportunities to see revenue growth there.&quot;  </p>
<p>Markman, formerly with Novell Inc, was named chairman, chief executive and president of the Sunnyvale, Calif.-based company on Thursday.</p>
<p>In his role as chief executive, Markham replaces founder Marc Porat, who plans to remain as an adviser to the company.</p>
<p>In 1995 General Magic lost $0.84 a share. Analysts forecast the company will lose about $1.09 a share this year.</p>
<p>Among the new products the company is starting to ship is its Magic Cap operating system for handheld wireless communications systems. On the server side of the business, the company is rolling out its Tabriz line of products.  </p>
<p>&quot;There are things we can do with Novell that I think are particularly exciting as well,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;They're in the business of making smart networks, and we're in the business of making them smarter and leveraging them. It's a natural opportunity to leverage,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Porat said he hoped Markman can solidify General Magic's place as a software provider in the Internet and intranet markets.</p>
<p>&quot;His mandate here is to take our technology and just hammer them right into the middle of the Internet into a place that makes money,&quot; Porat said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Going from concept to big revenues is where the value is,&quot; Porat said.</p>
<p>&quot;I took the company to the point where we have the concept. We have the people, we have the money and Steve is going to take it from concept ... to hit the goldmine in the Internet,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
