<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="632470" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish coalition conservative says polls this year.</title>
<headline>Turkish coalition conservative says polls this year.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Turkish government's conservative coalition partners said on Monday early elections would be held this year under a deal with Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan.</p>
<p>&quot;This election will be carried out by the end of 1997,&quot; Hasan Ekinci, deputy chairman of the True Path Party, told a news conference.</p>
<p>Erbakan, Turkey's first Islamist leader, announced on Sunday he would step down in favour of True Path leader Tansu Ciller within a month.</p>
<p>He said Foreign Minister Ciller would then head a caretaker government to go to elections, but set no date. Istanbul stocks shrugged off the possibility of early polls, rising 4.51 percent in morning trade.</p>
<p>Pressure from the generals to carry out an anti-Islamist crackdown had brought the 11-month-old coalition to breaking point.</p>
<p>Ekinci said the two coalition parties had no specific date in mind for elections, normally due by the year 2000. Turkish press reports say Erbakan, 70, wants a quick poll, but U.S.-trained economist Ciller had wanted a date next spring.</p>
<p>Turkish newspapers said on Monday that President Suleyman Demirel, who would have a key role in any power handover, may throw a spanner in the works of a transition. He reportedly said there was no clear mechanism for handing the prime minister's office to a coalition partner.</p>
<p>Demirel departed for a four-day visit to the Baltic republics on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
