<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="632994" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAFRICA BUILDS ARMOURY OF FUNDS AHEAD OF FX EASING.</title>
<headline>SAFRICA BUILDS ARMOURY OF FUNDS AHEAD OF FX EASING.</headline>
<byline>Paul Richardson</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa has an armoury of funds at its disposal to counter possible capital flight but is still likely to set conservative limits when it eases exchange controls on individuals on July 1, economists said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>On Monday night the Reserve Bank released figures which showed South Africa's gross gold and foreign exchange reserves ballooned 7.4 billion rand to a record 21.8 billion rand in May.</p>
<p>And on Tuesday it launched a 40 billion yen bond which will boost reserves by a further 1.54 billion rand this month.</p>
<p>In addition the central bank has some 15 billion rand of foreign credit lines that it can access to defend the rand if a capital exodus does materialise, while commercial banks are also believed to hold between five and 10 billion rand in forex.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Trevor Manuel said in his March 12 that individuls would be allowed to invest offshore or hold foreign currency bank accounts for the first time from July 1 -- but the limits will only be announced later this month.</p>
<p>The latest jump in reserves prompted market talk that Pretoria might act boldly by allowing individuals to shift large amounts of currency offshore. Market players have suggested allowances of anything between 100,000 and 300,000 rand.</p>
<p>But Mathison and Hollidge economist Henry Flint said the authorities would be reluctant to make the limits too large.</p>
<p>&quot;Capital inflows are very volatile and can be reversed in a very short period of time. If they (the Bank) act on these reserve figures in the end it could cost them dearly because foreigners could take a negative view on the country and we could see a lot of capital flight,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nedcor chief economist Dennis Dykes agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;They just don't know at all what the response is going to be. I think they would rather announce relaxations every three months than go ahead once off and have to reimpose limits, which would be embarassing for them.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he expected limits to be at the lower end of the range.</p>
<p>&quot;One hundred thousand rand would be in line with the travel allowance, which is 80,000 (rand). Anything more than 160,000 I would think would be extremely unlikely,&quot; Dykes said.</p>
<p>While there has been talk of substantial capital flight when controls are lifted, Flint and Dykes said that given current circumstances, this was unlikely.</p>
<p>Flint said the fact that individuals had little cash on hand at the moment as well as a general lack of knowledge of foreign economies ruled against a major exodus of capital.</p>
<p>&quot;I think people will be relatively cautious,&quot; Nedcor's Dykes said. &quot;It won't be a function of how much can people take out, it is going to be a function of what are perceptions at the time controls are relaxed and thereafter.</p>
<p>&quot;Under current circumstances, providing they continue, I don't think we will see a huge outflow. Even if it is in the order of five billion rand, provided it is over two months, it is not going to be a major problem,&quot; Dykes added.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
