<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="632922" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER-DORTMUND SHOCKED AS PRESIDENT QUITS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-DORTMUND SHOCKED AS PRESIDENT QUITS.</headline>
<dateline>DORTMUND, Germany 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Borussia Dortmund president Gerd Niebaum stunned the European Cup winners on Tuesday by announcing he planned to step down.</p>
<p>Niebaum, 48, whose trophy-laden 11-year tenure has left him with hero status in this Ruhr Valley town, said he would not be seeking re-election at the club's annual meeting this autumn.</p>
<p>Niebaum, in charge of a large law office in Dortmund, put the move down to the growing quantity of work associated with the president's position.</p>
<p>&quot;I've put in between eight and 10 hours a day for the club, gladly and passionately, but with the growing burdens of the role I do not want to sacrifice my family and professional life for a further three years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dortmund players, including current European Player of the Year Matthias Sammer, were clearly dismayed by the news.</p>
<p>&quot;Niebaum was one of the reasons I came to Borussia in the first place,&quot; said Sammer, a key figure in Dortmund's 3-1 European Cup victory last week.</p>
<p>Niebaum said winning Europe's top competition was critical to the timing of his announcement. &quot;I wouldn't have arrived at this decision had we not won the final last Wednesday. But I'm leaving the house in order,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Niebaum, who said he would help the club find his replacement, presided over Dortmund's 1989 German Cup final victory and two German championship wins in 1995 and 1996.</p>
<p>Previously, he was part of the board management team who between 1984 and 1986 saved the club from mounting debts and possible bankruptcy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DORTMUND, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
