<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633083" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Consumers target tin, market mulls Russian talk.</title>
<headline>Consumers target tin, market mulls Russian talk.</headline>
<byline>Eric Onstad</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A slump in tin prices has triggered new physical buying, traders said, adding that rumours swirled in the market that shipments of former Russian stockpile material are arriving in Europe and the U.S.</p>
<p>Traders said fresh interest has been seen from consumers as three month LME prices lost more than $200 over the past few days, bottoming at a 14-1/2-month low of $5,510 on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Over the last three or four days we have seen good covering by consumers...but then it dried up. I expect they will go quiet over the next couple of days,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>A trader in continental Europe said: &quot;Yesterday we booked some parcels for August and September, but today it has gone quiet.&quot;</p>
<p>A recovery by three month tin to $5,640 in the official LME ring on Tuesday together with a stronger dollar against the mark dampened business, he added.</p>
<p>Premiums were little changed, but one trader said they had a softer bias since plenty of metal was around.</p>
<p>Chinese tin in Rotterdam was quoted around $30/$40 above LME cash and low-lead metal at $125/$130.</p>
<p>LME stocks have been rising since mid-April. Inventories increased on Tuesday by 95 tonnes to 12,450 tonnes, up from 9,925 tonnes on April 15. LME stocks may dip slightly sometime this week, but after that they are expected to continue rising, a trader said.</p>
<p>Talk has been going around that one reason for the build up in LME stocks is shipments of former Russian stockpile material are satisfying demand.</p>
<p>The Russian metal, which is said to total about 8,000 tonnes, is of Chinese quality but too old to be registered on the LME and is going directly to consumers, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been offered Russian material in the states and I hear there are 1,000 to 2,000 tonnes in Rotterdam,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>Other traders and analysts had also heard the talk, but were sceptical.</p>
<p>&quot;I know about 800 to 900 tonnes arrived in Rotterdam a fortnight ago, maybe that's where the rumour started,&quot; one said, adding that that was Russian production, not from a stockpile.</p>
<p>Analyst William Adams of broker Rudolf Wolff wondered why the Russians would sell when prices are depressed unless they were desperate for hard currency.</p>
<p>&quot;Why would they be coming to the fore now?,&quot; he asked.</p>
<p>Adams saw three month prices declining further with Chinese selling still overhanging the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese are itching to sell if prices move back to $6,000 to $6,200,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Refined Chinese output is set to rise to 60,000 tonnes this year from 56,114 tonnes in 1996 while refined exports are due to increase to 35,000 tonnes after 29,412 tonnes last year, a recent report by Macquarie Equities said.</p>
<p>&quot;Exports in January-April were already 13,100 tonnes, double last year's January-April levels. This changes our view on the second half price outlook to a more bearish stance,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Adams pegged next serious support in the three months market at the March 1995 low of $5,070 with a key floor at the 1993 low of $4,350.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542-8065</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
