<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633058" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain, Ireland warn IRA patience is running out.</title>
<headline>Britain, Ireland warn IRA patience is running out.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain and Ireland warned republicans on Tuesday that their patience was running out and they told the Irish Republican Army the onus was on it to call a ceasefire if its political wing, Sinn Fein, is to be allowed to join Northern Ireland peace talks.</p>
<p>&quot;The patience of the two governments must not be presumed to be inexhaustible,&quot; an aide to Irish Foreign Minister Dick Spring told reporters as the multi-party talks resumed in Belfast after a three-month hiatus for a British general election that was held on May 1.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein was still being kept out of the talks because the outlawed guerrilla IRA has resisted calls to renew a truce, broken in February, 1996 with bomb attacks in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Is there any possibility of even opening this gate so that we can have a civilised conversation?&quot; Sinn Fein president Gerry Adams asked officials outside a government centre in Belfast where the talks took place.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm afraid not,&quot; an official replied without emotion.</p>
<p>Adams then read out a protest statement calling for Sinn Fein's admission to the talks.</p>
<p>A six-week lull in IRA activity ended over the weekend in a bomb scare involving 500 kg (1,100 pounds) of explosives in Belfast. Police found the explosives, which did not go off, in a burnt-out van and accused the IRA of trying to lure them into a trap.</p>
<p>Britain's Northern Ireland secretary, Mo Mowlam, appointed after Labour's landslide win in the May 1 poll, also showed signs of impatience as she urged political leaders to agree on how to disarm guerrillas, so-called decommissioning, and not to squander a golden opportunity for peace.</p>
<p>&quot;If Sinn Fein want to join the talks, there must ben an unequivocal restoration of the IRA ceasefire in words and deeds...The ball is in their court,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the settlement train is to begin to move, we must reach an agreed position on decommissioning first, and if the talks do not move on to substantive issues in the near future, they will lose credibility and we will defer, and perhaps lose, the best opportunity for a generation of securing a widely acceptable political accommodation,&quot; she said in a statement.</p>
<p>The talks started a year ago but have become mired in the disarmament issue. The chances of success have been damaged by increasing violence by both Protestant and republican guerrillas over the past few weeks.</p>
<p>Talks chairman George Mitchell, a former U.S. senator, expressed optimism over the new round after talks with British Prime Minister Tony Blair on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that an opportunity exists to move forward in the process and we hope very much that there will be substantive progress in these talks in the near future,&quot; Mitchell said as the talks got under way.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is a fair statement...that progress in the past year has been little and has been slow and we hope that there will be more of it and faster now that we have returned,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tuesday's talks began with a short round-table session and then returned to a pattern of bilateral discussions between representatives of the Protestant and Catholic political parties and the two governments.</p>
<p>Mitchell suggested on Tuesday that he might bring forward his own initiative to try to get round the disarmament issue but he declined to give details.</p>
<p>Pro-British Protestant hardliners, in the runup to what is feared will be a turbulent period of summertime parades through Roman Catholic districts, were blamed on Sunday for the mob killing of a police officer, who was kicked to death.</p>
<p>&quot;Loyalist&quot; militias, pledged to thwart the IRA's aim of ending British rule and claiming to represent the Protestant majority, have shot dead two Catholic nationalists in the past year and injured others in booby-trap bomb attacks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
