<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633267" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Family ties link Nigeria to Sierra Leone.</title>
<headline>Family ties link Nigeria to Sierra Leone.</headline>
<byline>James Jukwey</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ties between Nigeria and Sierra Leone date back to the 19th century and may have encouraged Nigeria's decision to try to oust military officers who seized power from the elected government of Sierra Leone on May 25.</p>
<p>&quot;Nigerian-Sierra Leone relations transcend diplomacy and international posturing,&quot; says Wande Ajayi, a retired Nigerian doctor of Sierra Leone descent. &quot;It is a relationship rooted in blood that is thicker than water.&quot;</p>
<p>Nigerian gunboats bombarded Freetown on Monday to try to restore the civilian president of Sierra Leone, Ahmad Tejan Kabbah, who was ousted in a coup by junior army officers.</p>
<p>Freetown, the Sierra Leone capital, was founded in 1833 by Britain for the re-settlement of freed slaves, many of whom were taken from present day Nigeria.</p>
<p>Some of the ex-slaves later returned to Nigeria to re-settle, having acquired Western education and professional skills, subsequently playing a prominent role in the development of Western education in Nigeria.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the most prominent Nigerian families have their roots in Sierra Leone,&quot; says the independent Guardian newspaper, listing some of those who have given their names to major Lagos streets.</p>
<p>Fourah Bay College, Freetown, established in 1828, was the first Western higher educational institution in West Africa and attracted many students from Nigeria.</p>
<p>Samuel Ajayi Crowther, an ex-slave from Sierra Leone, who traced his origins back to Nigeria in the latter part of the 19th century, was the first African bishop of the Anglican Church in Nigeria and an old boy of Fourah Bay College.</p>
<p>So is Michael Ajasin, the 89-year-old leader of the opposition National Democratic Coalition (NADECO) and one of the first to condemn the Sierra Leone coup d'etat.</p>
<p>The Sierra Leonian Creole language, a mixture of English and indigenous languages - including Nigerian languages - is similar to Pidgin English, a corrupted version of English language widely spoken in Nigeria.</p>
<p>But apart from blood ties, analysts find clear political and diplomatic reasons for Nigerian military ruler General Sani Abacha's decision to intervene in Sierra Leone.</p>
<p>&quot;By quelling the coup the West will take his march towards democracy seriously,&quot; says Aderemi Oyewunmi, a reseacher at Nigeria's Institute of International Affairs in Lagos, Nigeria's foreign policy think tank.</p>
<p>&quot;It is one of the surest ways of getting back into good relations with the United States and other Western countries,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>So far the intervention appears to have fared badly for Nigeria. On Monday the International Committee of the Red Cross had to broker a ceasefire to allow an evacuation of more than 600 civilians trapped in a Nigerian-protected hotel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SILEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
