<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633262" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Randgold plans to lift Syama gold output.</title>
<headline>Randgold plans to lift Syama gold output.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Randgold and Exploration Co Ltd said on Tuesday that its Randgold Resources subsidiary planned a three-year project programme to increase production at its Syama gold mine in Mali to 270,000 ounces per year.  </p>
<p>Randgold said arrangements for funding the $68 million cost of the programme are currently being finalised and the first effects of the programme will be felt in the first quarter of 1998.</p>
<p>The programme also aims to reduce cash operating costs to $210 an ounce.  </p>
<p>Syama's March quarter production was 35,312 ounces and Randgold said it expected the mine to produce 40,500 ounces in the current June quarter.</p>
<p>Cash operating costs in the March quarter were $330 an ounce and costs for the June quarter are expected to be $305 an ounce.</p>
<p>Randgold said it planned to commission Syama's new crusher in the first quarter of 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;Also on the agenda are the expansion of the mining equipment fleet and the upgrading of the mineral processing operations as well as the infrastructure of the mine,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Randgold Resources acquired management control and 65 percent of the share capital of Syama as part of its acquisition of BHP Mali Inc in October 1996.</p>
<p>Randgold Resources chief executive Mark Bristow said that elsewhere in Mali the feasibility study at the Loulo/Yalea project was due for completion this month.</p>
<p>&quot;Indications thus far have confirmed the company's confidence in the project and allowed it to upgrade the model and the resource,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Randgold Resources has a 20 percent stake in the Loulo/Yalea project but has the option to increase this.</p>
<p>The company is also involved in Golden Ridge in Tanzania, a joint venture with Pangea Goldfields Inc  PG.TO.</p>
<p>&quot;Following the completion of advanced resource definition drilling, the resource estimate at the main Myaligongo deposit has been refined upwards. The total resource is now estimated at 1.6 million ounces at 1.46 grams/tonne,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>It said a feasibility study on the project was due this month.</p>
<p>Randgold Resources is currently in the process of seeking a London listing.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
