<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633268" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: INTERVIEW-Sage Group has strong start to H1.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Sage Group has strong start to H1.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Insurance and unit trust investment group Sage Group Ltd has begun its first half in top gear with a rebound in premium growth and continued explosive investments in its unit trusts, its executives said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no reason to say the present (earnings) trend wouldn't be maintained,&quot; chief executive Bruce Ilsley told Reuters after the company unveiled a 25.4 percent leap in headline earnings for the year.</p>
<p>The group posted diluted headline earnings per share of 132.7 cents for the year to March 31, up from 105.8 cents a year ago and exceeding the average analysts' forecast of 132 cents.  </p>
<p>The results took Sage's compound annual EPS growth to 23.3 percent over the last five years.</p>
<p>Sage Life managing director Janssen Davies said the division's insurance premium growth had perked up this year.</p>
<p>&quot;This calendar year there's been a pickup again in recurring premiums, whereas last year it was quite depressed. It feels good,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ilsley said the South African insurance market overall was looking rosy.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to be that...there's a little more money to invest in life insurance,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>New sales in the unit trust division, which roared up 284.5 percent in 1996/97, continued to boom.</p>
<p>&quot;Unit trust sales went from 187 million to 720 million rand and that trend is continuing as we're seeing very good inflows of new money every month,&quot; Davies said.  </p>
<p>Ilsley said the group was unlikely to come to the market for extra funds following its planned US$40 million to US$50 million preference share issue in Europe which will fund the expansion of its recently-acquired U.S. life insurance unit.</p>
<p>He added the company was focussing on the search for a partner to help expand the U.S. arm which aimed to open for business in the first quarter of 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;The next step overseas would be to take on a strategic partner and that partner would provide at least some of the money required as well.&quot;</p>
<p>Ilsley said the company was in discussions with potential partners but was yet to draw up a shortlist.</p>
<p>He said the ideal partner would have a strong rating, a solid image in the U.S. market and be able to add value to Sage's products, especially via distribution.</p>
<p>Sage USA chief executive Ron Scowby said candidates would need an 'A' rating or better from insurance rating agency A.M. Best.</p>
<p>-- Justin McCamish, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 481-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
