<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633290" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: PRESS DIGEST - Zambia - June 3.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Zambia - June 3.</headline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Zambian press on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TIMES OF ZAMBIA</p>
<p>- Lecturers testifying before a government commission of enquiry blame political interference for student unrest at the country's two universities.</p>
<p>- The farmers' union calls on government to work with the private sector in securing bilateral trade agreements in the agricultural sector.</p>
<p>- Zambia will soon host the first micro-credit open forum as a preparation for the planned Southern African regional summit to be held in August.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ZAMBIA DAILY MAIL</p>
<p>- Lecturers accuse deputy health ministr Nkandu Luo of moonlighting by continuing to lecture at the University of Zambia after resigning from the institution to join the government.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE POST</p>
<p>- Post editor Fred M'membe files an affadavit in a Lusaka court claiming that former legal affairs minister Rommy Mushota, who has sued the newspaper, is of unsound mind and should not be allowed to take court actions.</p>
<p>- The U.N. Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organisation pledges $750,000 to the cash-strapped Pan African news organisation to meet operational costs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
