<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633397" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria sees 1997 tobacco output at 65,000 tonnes.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria sees 1997 tobacco output at 65,000 tonnes.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's private tobacco growers said on Tuesday they forecast 1997 tobacco output of 65,000 tonnes, compared to 71,000 tonnes planned by the agriculture ministry and up from last year's output of 39,790 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;The ministry's figure would not be reached due to unfavourable weather conditions, and about 65,000 tonnes of tobacco will be produced this year,&quot; Georgi Petrov, chairman of the Tobacco Producers' Union, told a news conference.</p>
<p>He said that favourable purchase prices and incentives provided to farmers had boosted tobacco growing but the crop had been hit by the unseasonally cold weather last week.</p>
<p>The expected output of about 65,000 tonnes is still much higher compared to the record-low output of 25,000 tonnes in 1995, when apart from unfavourable weather conditions, low purchase prices forced the poverty-stricken population in tobacco growing areas to switch to other activities.</p>
<p>Under the current scheme, purchase prices of tobacco will be updated twice annually in line with the inflation -- in mid-July and mid-October.</p>
<p>Private growers also qualify for additional payments from the state Tobacco Fund.</p>
<p>Seven years ago, when tobacco output was between 100,000 and 150,000 tonnes annualy, the small Balkan country exported some 40,000 tonnes of tobacco to the former Soviet Union and only some 10,000 to western buyers.</p>
<p>Since the collapse of Eastern bloc trade links Bulgaria's tobacco exports have started going mainly to French, German and U.S. companies.</p>
<p>-- Galina Sabeva, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-91188</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100145">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
