<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633341" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbian doctors to continue strike until wages paid.</title>
<headline>Serbian doctors to continue strike until wages paid.</headline>
<byline>Amra Kevic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbia's doctors, nurses and social workers said on Tuesday they would continue their strike despite reaching agreement in principle with the government, which has promised to begin paying overdue wages.</p>
<p>Health and social sector employees have been on strike throughout Serbia since May 12 over unpaid wages and neglect of the sector, providing a minimum level of services.</p>
<p>Some 1,500 Belgrade doctors, nurses and social workers, joined by colleagues from other towns, blocked traffic outside the Serbian government building before marching to a central square to hear the outcome of talks between union and government officials.</p>
<p>The union accepted the government's promise to pay April wages and bonuses for last year in several instalments by the end of next week, but said it would not call off the strike until the final payment is made.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to assemble outside the Serbian government every morning until we are sure these promises are fulfilled,&quot; Stevan Djordjevic, president of Serbian health and social workers trade union, told the crowd.</p>
<p>Djordjevic said the strike in institutions would end on the condition the government kept its promise by June 13. He said the sum owed to the sector was huge and it would be difficult to secure funds in the stagnating cash-strapped economy in a short time.</p>
<p>&quot;But that is not our problem -- that is the government's problem,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Many in the crowd were unhappy with the outcome of the talks and distrustful of the latest promises.</p>
<p>&quot;After 20 years as a specialist I have been reduced from being fairly well off to near poverty,&quot; said Milena, a dermatologist.</p>
<p>&quot;Promises, promises and more promises. If we didn't have the 'grey market' in the health sector as well, I would not be able to survive,&quot; said a cardiologist, who works part time in one of the private clinics which have sprung up in recent years, besides his regular job in a state hospital.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
