<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633327" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia's island row with Japan &quot;tsar's business&quot;.</title>
<headline>Russia's island row with Japan &quot;tsar's business&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian First Deputy Prime Minister Boris Nemtsov said on Tuesday that he would not discuss a long-running territorial row with Japan when he visits Tokyo next week.</p>
<p>&quot;That's a question for the Father-Tsar, I would have thought that was obvious,&quot; Nemtsov told a news conference in a clear reference to President Boris Yeltsin when asked whether the issue of the four disputed islands would come up during the June 9-11 visit.</p>
<p>Tokyo and Moscow have argued for decades over the remote islands in the north Pacific, seized by the Red Army in 1945. But Russia is keen not to let the row overshadow relations.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia has its official position, we can now discuss only joint trade and economic projects, including joint development of the northern territories,&quot; Nemtsov said.</p>
<p>Nemtsov, who is also Russia's fuel and energy minister, said he would take a list of proposals to boost trade and economic cooperation which he said fell far short of their potential.</p>
<p>&quot;There is not a single investment by a Japanese company without a state guarantee. That means that Japanese business is not putting money into Russia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that this is a big mistake and as a result of my visit Japanese business's attitude towards Russia and investment possibilities in Russia will change...we have already received the first signals that the ice is melting,&quot; Nemtsov added.</p>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin, whose huge powers make him the &quot;Father-Tsar&quot; of Russian politics said last month he had agreed with Japan's foreign minister Yukihiko Ikeda to forge closer ties despite the islands issue.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
