<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633440" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish Handlowy big investor offer price seen fair.</title>
<headline>Polish Handlowy big investor offer price seen fair.</headline>
<byline>Malgorzata Rzepka</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The price for long-term investors in Poland's Bank Handlowy SA was set at a justified discount to its public offer price range, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Poland priced Bank Handlowy's 27,859,000 shares offered in the so-called stable investor tranche at 20 zlotys paid on the day of the transaction plus 11.4 zlotys payable three years after the deal and a conditional premium due in the fourth year and linked to the bank's possible rise in market value. @</p>
<p>The stable investors, JP Morgan, Swedbank and Zurich Group, would choose an exact moment at which they would be required to pay 10 percent of an increase in the bank's value over a reference level of $1 billion.</p>
<p>Analysts said the price structure translated into a present value of 26-28 zlotys, just below or at the bottom of the price range of between 28 and 35 zlotys set for institutional and individual investors. @</p>
<p>&quot;It is about 26-28 zlotys and that's what one could have expected..I don't think the discount (for stable investors) is big, I think it's a good price,&quot; said Andrzej Soldek, an analyst at ING BSK Asset Management.</p>
<p>They said the discount was justified, given limits set for the so-called stable investors in selling the shares and the expected know-how they would bring to the Polish bank. @</p>
<p>&quot;I think the discount is more or less reasonable, it reflects the fact that the investors will be lending some strategic expertise to Handlowy, they will be tying up their own capital for a period of three years,&quot; said James Mellersh of Societe Generale in Warsaw.</p>
<p>The stable investors are offered 42.9 percent of shares, which would represent 30 percent of its equity diluted by a 28-million-convertible bond issue, but the offer allows for up to 11,472,500 shares to be transferred to retail investors. @</p>
<p>The treasury ministry agreed to allow the investors to buy enough convertible bonds, now held by the state treasury, to reach jointly 24 percent in Handlowy.</p>
<p>Analysts said the pricing of the long-term investor tranche was likely to have little if any effect on the undergoing book-building process in the institutional investor tranche, which will determine the price also for individual investors.</p>
<p>They said many small players might feel confused by the complex nature of the transaction but it should not weigh significantly on the success of the offer. @</p>
<p>&quot;One can get really confused..., especially small investors. The bank will definitely be sold but setting the price and the whole sale seems much too complicated,&quot; said Pawel Tarnowski, an analyst at Raiffeisen Capital and Investment Polska. -- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
