<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633404" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: Unibanka leads Latvian shares higher.</title>
<headline>Unibanka leads Latvian shares higher.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prices were stable to moderately higher on Tuesday and Unibanka was seen to be in for more gains after shareholders approved a eurobond issue, dealers said.</p>
<p>Total turnover on Tuesday rose to 73,000 lats from 63,000 lats and the Rietumu index added 1.05 percent to 183.8.</p>
<p>Unibanka was most active on volume of 34,000 lats and it rose to 3.40 lats from 3.36 lats.</p>
<p>&quot;Unibanka's price could be seen gaining if the planned eurobond has a good rate,&quot; Leonid Ruderman, a dealer with the Parekss Bank, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Shareholders yesterday approved the issue of a eurobond, epected to be launched sometime in the summer. The size and maturity of the issue has not yet been decided.</p>
<p>Ruderman also saw a chance for higher profits for Unibanka if the long-term dollar resources are put to work cleverly.</p>
<p>&quot;The bank has abundant lat resources and now it will be able to have more balance in terms of additional dollar resources,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The decision of Unibanka's shareholders not to back a merger with Zemes Banka, which was expected, had little impact on the share but was seen as good news for Unibanka's price in the longer term, dealers said.</p>
<p>Elsewhere on the official list, stocks were mostly stable and the Riga Transport Fleet saw turnover of 11,300 lats but was stable at 1.22 lats.</p>
<p>Staburadze also remained stable at 1.22 lats amid increased demand as it saw a small 400 lats of shares traded.</p>
<p>&quot;Staburadze posted a very good Q1 results earlier, when the bourse was in the lows and the market response was subdued,&quot; Ruderman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now seeing the last phase of this reactian where the demand side dominates,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Riga Shipyard added two santimes to 1.40 lats on volume of 8,400 lats.</p>
<p>-- Martinsh Gravitis, Riga Newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
