<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633554" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: US's AMF in $100 mln Brazil/Argentine bowling deal.</title>
<headline>US's AMF in $100 mln Brazil/Argentine bowling deal.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S.-based AMF Bowling Worldwide and local firm Playcenter SA said Tuesday they have formed a joint venture to invest $100 million over five years to build and operate 39 bowling alleys in Brazil and Argentina.</p>
<p>The Sao Paulo-based venture, called AMF Playcenter, is AMF's first move into the emerging South American leisure and recreation market, the firms said in a statement.  </p>
<p>&quot;We believe that Playcenter's dominant position in the South American recreation market will contribute significantly to the expansion of bowling on the continent,&quot; AMF President Douglas Stanard was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>As part of the accord, AMF Playcenter will take over operation of six Playcenter bowling alleys in Brazil and two in Argentina, the statement said.</p>
<p>The firms plan by the end of the year to construct and inaugurate five modern bowling alleys in Brazil and one in Argentina.  They plan another 25 between 1998 and 2001.</p>
<p>The first two alleys, each with 16 lanes, will begin operating Wednesday in Santo Andre, outside Sao Paulo.</p>
<p>Also in June, AMF Playcenter plans to inaugurate in Buenos Aires a recreation center with 24 bowling lanes, theme bar and video games, it said.</p>
<p>Based in Richmond, Va., AMF is a leading global operator of bowling lanes and owns and administers 400 alleys in 11 countries in North America, Europe, Asia and Australia. It plans to open alleys in South America, India and Eastern Europe.  Goldman, Sachs &amp; Co is the main shareholder in AMF.</p>
<p>Playcenter is a pioneer in the automated bowling market in Brazil, where it has operated since 1982.</p>
<p>((-- James Craig, Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 2485413))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
