<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633562" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Fiat truck unit IVECO invests $63 mln in Argentina.</title>
<headline>Fiat truck unit IVECO invests $63 mln in Argentina.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fiat's Argentine unit said its truck arm IVECO has started building two new plants for a total of $63 million to make heavy and medium-heavy trucks and engines for the local and foreign markets.</p>
<p>Work started Monday and the plants are expected to be complete by January 1999, a Fiat spokesman told Reuters Tuesday.</p>
<p>The plants are under construction in Cordoba Province, 500 miles north of Buenos Aires where IVECO already has a plant.</p>
<p>Staff will be increased to 800 from 500.</p>
<p>IVECO expects to have installed capacity of 10,000 trucks a year in a first stage and increase it to 20,000 in a later stage, the spokesman said. More than half the truck output is earmarked for export, including a large part to Brazil.</p>
<p>IVECO had initially planned to invest $120 million together with Fiat to upgrade its Cordoba plant to produce the light truck Daily and the Fiat Ducato van.</p>
<p>But after union unrest and car incentives offered by Brazil earlier this year, it decided to trim the investment and install the truck plant in Argentina and make the Dailys and Ducatos in Brazil.</p>
<p>This year it will start building with Fiat a $120 million plant in the Brazilian state of Minas Gerais to make the Dailys and Ducatos.</p>
<p>The spokesman said that although the investment is smaller, trucks mean more added value than light vehicles.</p>
<p>((--Guillermo Haskel, Buenos Aires Nerwsroom, 541 318-0650))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
