<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633626" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile shrs seen heading higher despite flat start.</title>
<headline>Chile shrs seen heading higher despite flat start.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chilean shares opened trading in a narrow range, as profit-takers evened out buyers following a record-breaking rally since last week, but brokers said the bourse was still headed higher.</p>
<p>The blue-chip IPSA fell about 0.11 percent in the first few minutes of trade but then bounced back and was up 0.33 percent to 134.01 points after about 15 minutes of trade.</p>
<p>The all-share IGPA was up 0.14 percent to 5743.98 points.</p>
<p>&quot;There is going to be a certain amount of profit-taking today.  It's only logical,&quot; said one broker.  </p>
<p>The Santiago Stock Exchange has risen to record highs on heavy buying by foreign investors on expectations that interest rates are coming down this month or in July.</p>
<p>&quot;People are believing, are assuming that interest rates in Chile are coming down, and that that will bring a lot more liquidity to the market,&quot; said a broker.  &quot;Also, there's an image that Chile has been too undervalued.&quot;</p>
<p>The market was also awaiting official inflation and unemployment figures due to be issued at 1030 local (1430 GMT) by the National Statistics Institute.</p>
<p>((--Roger Atwood, Santiago newsroom +56-2-699-5595 x211))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
