<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633670" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - June 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - June 4.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE DOMINION</p>
<p>Second storm strikes: Coast battens down hatches: Mahia Peninsula residents battened down for their second night without power on Tuesday night as a storm lashed Hawke's Bay. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Labour would keep top finance job says Cullen: Labour would insist on the top finance job in any future coalition government with the Alliance, Labour deputy leader and finance spokesman Michael Cullen said on Tuesday. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Anglers want equality for fishing licences: The government should stop dithering and join a legal challenge to the rights of some Maoris to catch trout without a licence, the Freswater Anglers Federation said on Tuesday. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>PDL just manages target profit: Christchurch-based electrical and plastics manufacturer PDL Holdings has only just achieved its forecast profit, with a result of $12.53 million for the year to March 1997. Page 16.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Consumers forecast to lead economic growth: New Zealand's economy will grow slower than the rest of the Asia Pacific region in the next two years, but will benefit from a consumer-led recovery, according to a report carried out for the Pacific Economic Cooperation council. Page 16.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Big demand for Restaurant Brands shares: The float of 85 million Restaurant shares is understood to have been heavily oversubscribed by the time bidding by retail investors closed on Tuesday afternoon. Page 16.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE PRESS</p>
<p>Man shot dead in hold-up: A 22-year-old man was shot dead on Tuesday night during an armed hold-up at the Caledonian Hotel in St Albans, Christchurch. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Stirling Sports stake to Asia: The owners of New Zealand sports retail chain, Stirling Sports, have sold a 35 percent stake to three Singaporean brothers. Page 21.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Telecom contracts out phone line maintenance: Telecom has contracted an outside company to maintain 30 percent of its Christchurch telephone network. Page 25.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE NEW ZEALAND HERALD</p>
<p>Economists predict a loosening of reins: A further but modest loosening of the monetary reins is in prospect after the Reserve Bank's monetary policy statement on June 27.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Delegation comes with spicy message for NZ: A six-member delegation of Indian spice exporters arrived in Auckland on Tuesday to talk to local inporters keen to take advantage of a growing local interest in Indian cruisine.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
