<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633658" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: ARCO wins first bout of Venezuela's oil round.</title>
<headline>ARCO wins first bout of Venezuela's oil round.</headline>
<byline>Tom Ashby</byline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. oil company Atlantic Richfield Co (ARCO) won majority shares in two contracts to operate inactive Venezuelan oilfields on Monday, the first of five days of bidding.</p>
<p>ARCO snapped up the Kaki and Maulpa contracts for a total of $121.4 million. Three other contracts were awarded on Monday, for a total of $280.7 million.</p>
<p>&quot;When you look around the world, Venezuela is one of the places that has huge reserves and is open to foreign to investment. We're trying to go international and this is one of the places you need to be,&quot; ARCO president Jay Cheatham said afterwards.</p>
<p>Monday's offerings were reserved for Venezuelan operators with a minimum stake of 30 percent. ARCO took 56 percent in each of its two fields, joining Venezuela's Inelectra, with 30 percent, and Polar, with 14 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;There were two fields this consortium wanted to win,&quot; Cheatham said. &quot;We did a very rigorous evaluation of these two fields and set a value at which we would be happy to get them... there is much synergy between the two fields located next to each other,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Most winning bids of the day were within a few million dollars of their nearest rivals, indicating that these companies made similar appraisals of the fields' potential, delegates said.</p>
<p>Argentina's Perez Companc and Venezuela's Corepli, with a bid of $41,000,021 for the Acema field, beat their closest rival by just $22.</p>
<p>Companies that bid much below the winners misjudged the potential that others saw in the geology, or did not have sufficient technology to exploit it, delegates said.</p>
<p>In bidding for the Mata contract, the winning Venezuelan consortium upped its valuation after it saw what ARCO paid for the Kaki field. The consortium of PBE Trading and Pivensa bid the day's record of $90 million.</p>
<p>Pivensa consortium leader Antonio Pardo said he estimated that at $18 per barrel, Mata's proven, probable and possible reserves came to $5 billion. But he estimated the reserves in Kaki came to $1.9 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;We simply extrapolated the exercise that Polar did. What Polar paid per square kilometre and by the reserves we estimated,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Petroleos de Venezuela's exploration and production manager Vicenzo Paglione said some of the Venezuelan operators still had much to learn, but thought they could improve with good partners.</p>
<p>The 20 fields on offer in this, the third, operating round mark another step towards Venezuela's ambitious 10-year oil production program. By 2006, it wants to double production to 6.2 million barrels per day (bpd), and hopes private capital will participate in 35 percent of the total output by then.</p>
<p>From the 67,000 bpd in current production from the 20 areas on offer this week, Petroleos de Venezuela hopes to see 350,000 bpd in 10 years.</p>
<p>&quot;What we have seen this morning is a very clear indication of the country's capacity, which often remains unexploited because of the way the oil industry was conceived in the past. By going through this opening process we are tapping all the opportunities,&quot; Petroleos de Venezuela president Luis Giusti said.</p>
<p>((-- Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2611))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
