<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633759" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: MOF expected to speed up financial reforms-sources.</title>
<headline>MOF expected to speed up financial reforms-sources.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Ministry of Finance (MOF) is expected to speed up the implementation of the government's &quot;Big Bang&quot; financial reform plan, financial industry sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The ministry is expected to submit financial reform bills at the next ordinary session of parliament (scheduled to start next January),&quot; said an industry source. &quot;Based on the reform bills, the ministry is expected to implement the bulk of its financial deregulation measures in fiscal year 1999/2000,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>That schedule is up to two years ahead of Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto's plan to liberalise the nation's financial markets by 2001, the sources said.</p>
<p>They added, however, that the ministry is still mulling the right time to implement some changes such as the liberalisation of broking commissions on stock transactions.</p>
<p>A MOF official said that details of financial deregulation would be decided after advisory panels to the Finance Minister make final proposals sometime in the middle of June.</p>
<p>The Nihon Keizai Shimbun, a business daily, reported on Tuesday that MOF would allow financial institutions to set up holding companies in fiscal year 1998/99.</p>
<p>The ministry will submit bills to revise banking, securities and insurance laws at the next extraordinary session of parliament later this year to enable the firms to establish holding companies in the next financial year, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>The ministry will also completely deregulate the permissible range of business activities for securities firms' trust banking subsidiaries and banks' securities units in 1999/2000, it said.</p>
<p>Banks and brokerage firms began moving into each other's turf through wholly owned subsidiaries after financial reforms took effect in 1993. Their range of permissible business activities has been restricted, however, to avoid jeopardising existing firms.</p>
<p>The newspaper said that the ministry, beginning in fiscal 1999/2000, will also allow banks and brokers to enter the insurance business by setting up insurance subsidiaries, while insurers will be allowed to enter the banking and securities sectors through their subsidiaries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
