<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633802" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Minor Metals - Inco strike may boost cobalt prices.</title>
<headline>Minor Metals - Inco strike may boost cobalt prices.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A strike at Inco Ltd's Sudbury operations in Canada may boost cobalt prices, which have eased since the ending of the seven-month civil war in former Zaire, traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The strike's first impact would be psychological, but if it lasts for a while, it would have a real impact, particularly in the United States,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of its (Inco) cobalt goes to the United States where there has been healthy demand for super-alloy.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said Inco, a major producer of nickel and cobalt, sells most of its 1,500 tonnes of annual cobalt production to the United States, which has already been hit by the suspension of the government's cobalt stockpile sales since March.</p>
<p>Japan buys less than 100 tonnes of cobalt from Inco a year, out of total demand of some 6,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Inco Ltd's workers in Sudbury, Ontario, went on strike on Tuesday after rejecting a tentative contract agreement, a union spokesman said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The news pushed up nickel prices on the London Metal Exchange as much as $200 per tonne during early Asian trading hours on Tuesday from the London close on Monday.</p>
<p>Another cobalt trader in Tokyo said: &quot;The metal price might start rising again later this month. Stocks held by Japanese users are now running low as well.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said the price for high-grade cobalt has softened to $24 per pound, and Russian low-grade cobalt to $19-21 since the end of the civil war in former Zaire, which has been renamed the Democratic Republic of Congo.</p>
<p>Gecamines, former Zaire's state run mining company, has resumed spot sales of cobalt although the quantity remains limited, they said.</p>
<p>Zambia's cobalt production remained low at around 300 tonnes in May, although the country hoped to boost that by 50 tonnes per month, traders added.</p>
<p>In Hong Kong, bismuth continued to spark traders' interest, with one China-based source reporting a 20-lot tonne of the metal sold for June delivery at $4.20 per pound, CIF Rotterdam.</p>
<p>While the deal could not be confirmed, other traders said they would not be surprised as they had received firm bids from China at $4.20 per pound earlier this week.</p>
<p>&quot;Normally, 20 tonnes is not a big amount, but with the market so tight, it's a different matter,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>In the Tokyo indium market, traders expected prices to go down towards $250 this month before stabilising next month.</p>
<p>Prices have slid to below $300 a kilogram (kg) on long liquidation and profit-taking, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The price should stabilise or even recover slightly in July when a new plant for liquid crystal display (LCD) starts operations,&quot; said one trader at a foreign trading house.</p>
<p>Traders agreed Japanese demand for the metal remained strong as production of LCDs continued to expand by two-digits.</p>
<p>The metal's price was pushed up by more than $100 to a peak of $320-330 during the first quarter of this year.</p>
<p>One trader estimated Japan's indium demand would stand at around 95 tonnes this year, of which 60 tonnes would be used for LCD production.</p>
<p>Chinese antimony was quoted at $2,100 per tonne, FOB China, but with freight and other costs, the price would go up another $100 per tonne, sources said.</p>
<p>About 200 kgs of gallium were sold at $455 per kg, CIF Japan, and customers were heard paying $470 per kg for July delivery.</p>
<p>-- Mishi Saran in Hong Kong +852-2843-6358</p>
<p>-- Nao Nakanishi, Tokyo commodities desk +81-3-3432-7431</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
