<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634099" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar falls as German gold compromise helps mark.</title>
<headline>Dollar falls as German gold compromise helps mark.</headline>
<byline>Noah Barkin</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar edged lower on Tuesday after the German government and central bank neared a compromise over plans to revalue the country's gold reserves, restoring some confidence in the German mark.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank had objected to German Finance Minister Theo Waigel's plan to use proceeds from the gold revaluation to fill budget gaps and thereby help Germany qualify for European monetary union.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Bonn reached what Waigel called &quot;a good compromise&quot; with Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer, under which the transfer of gold profits to government coffers was postponed until 1998 -- too late to help Germany meet strict criteria for the single currency.</p>
<p>And although no official deal was made, the apparent resolution of the dispute, which had sapped investor confidence in Germany and led to active selling of marks last week, helped the German currency regain some of the luster it had lost in recent weeks.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, analysts said they expected the market to remain wary of the mark and other European currencies as long as uncertainties about monetary union persisted.</p>
<p>&quot;Waigel was willing to give a little on the gold revaluation and that might have helped restore a little credibility to the deutschemark,&quot; said Bob Lynch, currency strategist at Paribas in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;But there remains a great deal of uncertainty about what will happen in Europe and over the near-term and that should keep the dollar supported.&quot;</p>
<p>After rising a full two-and-a-half pfennigs to 1.7305 marks late Monday, the dollar edged down to 1.7275 late Tuesday. It also fell slightly to 116.05 Japanese yen from 116.59 at Monday's close.</p>
<p>Apart from Germany, dealers also remained focused on France, where Socialist leader Lionel Jospin took over as Prime Minister on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Jospin has argued for a loosening of the criteria for monetary union and an end to the austerity policies designed to prepare the country for adoption of the single currency, known as the euro.</p>
<p>However, Germany is expected to resist any watering down of the guidelines on the fear that a weak euro could result.</p>
<p>&quot;People are waiting to see whether the Germans will dig in their heels and say there is no way they will compromise on the criteria,&quot; said Alfonso Alejo, corporate foreign exchange manager at Sakura Bank Ltd.</p>
<p>The mark fell against a number of European currencies on Tuesday, including the Swedish crown after Sweden's Prime Minister Goran Persson said the country would not join in launching the single currency in 1999, but would keep the door open for membership in the future.</p>
<p>The dollar ended higher against the Swiss franc, closing at 1.4373 against 1.4340 on Monday. The British pound retreated to $1.6347 from $1.6357. The dollar ended little changed at Canadian $1.3755 against C$1.3752.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
