<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634020" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sears close to settlements on credit card flap.</title>
<headline>Sears close to settlements on credit card flap.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sears, Roebuck &amp; Co., seeking to put to rest a flap over its method of collecting credit card debt, said Tuesday it has reached preliminary settlements with consumers and state and federal regulators.</p>
<p>The agreements were still subject to negotiations and require the approval of the U.S. Bankruptcy Court in Massachusetts among others, Sears said in a court filing.</p>
<p>The agreements would resolve claims that the retailer's method of collecting debt from Sears credit card holders who had filed for bankruptcy protection was illegal.</p>
<p>The dispute came to light during proceedings in Massachusetts bankruptcy court this spring. It threatened to tarnish the retailer's credibility just five years after it was rocked by a scandal over its selling of auto parts to customers who didn't need them.</p>
<p>Sears, however, quickly acknowledged it had mishandled the so-called reaffirmation agreements with customers by failing to file them in bankruptcy court.</p>
<p>In April, the Hoffman Estates, Ill.-based retailer voluntarily offered to repay consumers who signed the mishandled agreements and to give them each a $100 gift certificate.</p>
<p>Sears, the nation's second-largest retailer, said the pending settlements would resolve legal proceedings with consumers in several civil lawsuits, representatives for the attorneys general in 39 states and the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.</p>
<p>The retailer said it was scheduled to meet Wednesday with federal prosecutors. The U.S. Justice Department was expected to file a status report with the Massachusetts bankruptcy court on a potential criminal investigation by Thursday.</p>
<p>But the U.S. attorney for Massachusetts, Donald Stern, has asked the bankruptcy court to delay any settlement Sears proposes.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, a spokeswoman for Stern said that if a settlement were approved, it could affect Stern's pending investigation of Sears.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a double jeopardy issue involved&quot; for the prosecution, said spokeswoman Amy Rindskopf.</p>
<p>Sears spokesman Ron Culp said the company has not determined how much a settlement will cost. Sears has been scouring records between 1992 and 1997 involving 500,000 repayment agreements with credit card customers to calculate its liability.</p>
<p>The company's court filing was designed to bring up to date a Massachusetts bankruptcy judge who is scheduled to hold a hearing Thursday at which Sears hoped to present an agreement for approval.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Sears said it reached an agreement in principle covering compensation, penalties and other issues with the Massachusetts attorney general, who has headed a group representing 39 states in the negotiations.</p>
<p>The pact was being presented to the 39 attorneys general for formal approval, Sears said in the filing.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Massachusetts Attorney General Scott Harshbarger said the deal had not been completed. &quot;There is not an official settlement with Sears,&quot; said spokesman John Lamontagne.</p>
<p>A consent order has been reached with the Federal Trade Commission, which could approve the deal Wednesday, Sears said.</p>
<p>In addition to settlement costs, the U.S. bankruptcy judge could order Sears to pay punitive damages. But in its filing, Sears said it may be protected against court-imposed fines by laws barring multiple government punishments for the same offence.</p>
<p>Sears' stock rose 50 cents to $49.25 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
