<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634093" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: German row, soft-euro talk push dlr higher in US.</title>
<headline>German row, soft-euro talk push dlr higher in US.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar pushed marginally higher in U.S. trade on Tuesday, as uncertainty over Germany's plan to revalue gold reserves and speculation about a weak euro weighed on the mark.</p>
<p>German Finance Minister Theo Waigel said on Tuesday that Bonn reached what Waigel called &quot;a good compromise&quot; with Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer under which the transfer of gold profits to government coffers would be postponed until 1998.</p>
<p>But Tietmeyer said later that no deal had been reached and that talks to resolve the contentious debate were ongoing.  </p>
<p>&quot;Waigel was willing to give a little on the gold revaluation and that might have helped restore a little credibility to the deutschemark,&quot; said Bob Lynch, currency strategist at Paribas in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;But there remains a great deal of uncertainty about what will happen in Europe and over the near-term and that should keep the dollar supported.&quot;</p>
<p>After sticking to a relatively narrow range for much of the U.S. session, the dollar ended the day at 1.7265/75 marks, up from 1.7258/63 at the open. It also rose modestly to 115.98/08 yen from 115.87/97.  </p>
<p>Traders said they expected the market to favor the dollar and remain wary of the mark and other European currencies as long as uncertainties about monetary union persisted.</p>
<p>Apart from Germany, dealers also remained focused on France, where Socialist leader Lionel Jospin took over as Prime Minister on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Jospin has argued for a loosening of the criteria for monetary union and an end to the austerity policies designed to prepare the country for entry into the single currency.</p>
<p>Germany, fearing a weak euro, is expected to resist any watering down of EMU guidelines.  </p>
<p>&quot;People are waiting to see whether the Germans will dig in their heels and say there is no way they will compromise on the criteria,&quot; said Alfonso Alejo, corporate foreign exchange manager at Sakura Bank Ltd.</p>
<p>The mark also fell against a number of European currencies on Tuesday, including the Swedish crown, which gained after Sweden's Prime Minister Goran Persson said the country would not join in launching the single currency in 1999, but would keep the door open for membership in the future.  </p>
<p>Sweden's decision not to join as a founding member came as no surprise, but the market was cheered by prospects for entry at a later date.</p>
<p>Analysts began looking ahead on Tuesday to key U.S. employment data due out later this week. The market expects a weak report, and the dollar could get a boost if payrolls outstrip estimates.</p>
<p>&quot;If you were to get strong figures from the employment figures on Friday, both in payrolls and hourly earnings, the prospects for higher rates could very well act as another support to the dollar,&quot; said Paribas' Lynch.  </p>
<p>In other trade on Tuesday, the dollar rose to 1.4365/75 Swiss francs from 1.4325/35 at the open.</p>
<p>Sterling edged lower to $1.6343/53 from $1.6360/70 and the Australian dollar rose to $0.7620/25 from $0.7575/80.</p>
<p>The dollar ended higher at Canadian $1.3762/67 against C$1.3724/29.</p>
<p>((-- Noah Barkin, N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1673))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
