<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634016" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Minn. gov vetoes $6.7 bln education funding bill.</title>
<headline>Minn. gov vetoes $6.7 bln education funding bill.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Minnesota Gov. Arne Carlson on Tuesday vetoed a $6.7 billion elementary and secondary education spending package that lacked tuition tax credits he had proposed.</p>
<p>Carlson, a Republican, called the credits a key ingredient for parents that would lead to increased competition and school reforms in a letter to Democratic House Speaker Phil Carruthers announcing the veto.</p>
<p>The governor's veto will require lawmakers to return for a special session to resolve the impasse. No date has been set for that special session and Carlson and lawmakers have not yet scheduled a meeting to discuss an agenda for it, spokesman Brian Dietz said.</p>
<p>Carlson said lawmakers included a number of &quot;commendable&quot; reforms in the bill forwarded to him, but without his $150 million tax credit plan &quot;it does not achieve this administration's fundamental goal of reforming the education system and allowing choices for all Minnesota families.&quot;</p>
<p>On Friday, Carruthers had urged Carlson to sign the bill, contending that failure to adopt a full budget by July 1 could jeopardize Minnesota's efforts to obtain a AAA bond rating.</p>
<p>In his response Tuesday, Carlson wrote that Minnesota has reached a $2.3 billion surplus largely due to vetoes he has cast, placing the state in position to completely restore its AAA bond rating.</p>
<p>((--David Bailey, 312-408-8647))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
