<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634196" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Key U.S. economic gauge fell in April, slowdown seen.</title>
<headline>Key U.S. economic gauge fell in April, slowdown seen.</headline>
<byline>Glenn Somerville</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The nation's main economic forecasting gauge fell in April for the first time in 15 months, a report said Tuesday, the latest sign that a slowdown was likely later this year.</p>
<p>The Conference Board said its Index of Leading Indicators, meant to forecast activity six to nine months ahead, fell 0.1 percent in April -- the first decline since a 0.7 percent decline in January 1996 -- after rising 0.2 percent in March.</p>
<p>Six of its 10 components weakened from March and only four rose, which meant the economy was losing steam after growing at a brisk 5.8 percent rate in the first quarter, a rate likely to spark higher inflation should it continue, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;This indicator is pointing toward less robust activity than what we saw in the first quarter,&quot; said economist Gary Thayer of A.G. Edwards and Sons Inc. in St. Louis. &quot;But it is not pointing to problems for the economy. Leading indicators are suggesting (slower) growth that is more sustainable.&quot;</p>
<p>Thayer said growth probably will slow to about 2.5 percent in the current quarter, strong enough to keep generating jobs but with less pressure on prices that can fan inflation.</p>
<p>A caution on inflation was sounded by the president of the San Francisco regional Federal Reserve bank, Robert Parry, who said that some of the forces holding prices down, such as workers' job insecurity and a strong dollar, may be temporary.</p>
<p>&quot;The longer-run concern about inflation remains a live issue,&quot; said Parry, who is generally known for taking a tough line on inflation risks. But he also said the economy was on a track for more moderate expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm reasonably optimistic that we will see some slowing to a more sustainable rate from the rapid growth in the first quarter,&quot; said Parry, a voting member of the central bank's policy-making committee.</p>
<p>Fed policy-makers held short-term rates steady last month after raising them a quarter point in March, the first increase in more than two years, in a bid to ward off inflation. They meet again early next month to weigh their next move on rates.</p>
<p>The Conference Board said the main reason for the weaker April reading was a rise in new jobless claims. Stock prices were lower and consumer confidence dropped from March levels.</p>
<p>In addition, vendors delivered goods more quickly, a sign that factories were not as busy, and orders for capital goods fell. There also were fewer new applications for building permits.</p>
<p>The overall report fit with other recent signs of slowing in the economy as spring began. Government reports have showed weaker retail sales in April and flat industrial output, as well as sluggish car sales.</p>
<p>Chrysler Corp. on Monday said domestic car sales tumbled 17 percent in May, the fourth straight month of lower car and truck sales, and said the spring market was &quot;significantly softer&quot; than a year ago.</p>
<p>The only recent contrary sign has come from the nation's purchasing managers, who said Monday their widely watched index of industrial activity unexpectedly jumped in May even as consumer spending showed signs of easing.</p>
<p>The Conference Board's leading index had only four indicators that were stronger in April than in March.</p>
<p>The average workweek lengthened, consumer goods orders rose, the money supply increased and the Treasury yield curve steepened as long-term investors sought higher returns, pushing long-term rates higher in the bond market.</p>
<p>Previously, the board said the leading index had risen 0.1 percent in March, but it revised that upward.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E71">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
