<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634108" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Unicom, AlliedSignal in generator alliance.</title>
<headline>Unicom, AlliedSignal in generator alliance.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Commins</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unicom Corp, parent of utility Commonwealth Edison, said Tuesday it will begin selling small power generators to commercial and industrial customers as part of a long-term alliance with AlliedSignal Inc.</p>
<p>Unicom said it will buy an undisclosed number of natural gas-fired TurboGenerators from AlliedSignal. Unicom has the exclusive right to sell them to industrial and commercial customers in 10 Midwestern states and Ontario, Canada.</p>
<p>The on-site generators will allow customers to produce their own power, cutting consumption during peak demand.  </p>
<p>The TurboGenerator agreement is part of Unicom's strategy to offer services to industrial and commercial customers in the face of deregulation of the U.S. electricity industry.</p>
<p>Under deregulation, large users will be able to obtain electricity from the open market.</p>
<p>&quot;With TurboGenerator technology in our product portfolio, Unicom will now be able to target niche energy marktes, including distributed generation, standby power, off-grid power generation, portable power, uninterruptible power supplies and cogeneration,&quot; William Downey, Unicom's vice president for customer operations, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The power generators will be offered not only to customers of Chicago-based Commonwealth Edison, but to industrial and commercial users throughout the Midwest and in Ontario.</p>
<p>&quot;Bear in mind our relationship is broader&quot; than Commonwealth Edison's service area, Christopher Mahoney, general manager of Unicom Resources Inc, said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>The generators will be marketed to small commercial businesses, institutions, light industry and organizations. AlliedSignal said the generators are lightweight, compact units that are low in cost and almost emission-free.  </p>
<p>For AlliedSignal, the multi-year agreement with Unicom is the first of what it hopes will be four exclusive agreements with utilities across the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;Our strategy is to develop parallel relationships in three other regions in the U.S. with utility partners...that have the stature of Unicom,&quot; Tony Prophet, president of AlliedSignal Power Systems Inc, a unit of AlliedSignal, said.</p>
<p>AlliedSignal also plans to market the TurboGenerator globally, such as in China and India.</p>
<p>Prophet added that the alliance with Unicom likely will lead to other power-generation technology, including other sizes of TurboGenerators and cogeneration modules.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
