<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634218" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rubin skeptical on equity limit for bank/commerce.</title>
<headline>Rubin skeptical on equity limit for bank/commerce.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin expressed skepticism on Tuesday about allowing banks to hold non-controlling investments in commercial entities.</p>
<p>Congress and the administration, working to overhaul antiquated U.S. banking laws, are struggling to decide how much mixing should be allowed between financial and commercial companies.</p>
<p>The Clinton administration did not take a firm position on banking and commerce in its reform plan announced by Rubin last month. Instead, Rubin said Congress should choose between limited mixing or no mixing.  </p>
<p>Under Rubin's limited approach, a bank's nonfinancial activity would be limited to a &quot;basket&quot; or percentage of total revenues. Further, banks could not be owned by the 1,000 largest commercial firms based on asset size.</p>
<p>During a House Banking Committee hearing on Tuesday, Rep Richard Baker, Republican of Louisiana and a strong advocate of unlimited mixing, asked Rubin about another possible compromise approach based on control.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a cleaner measure as opposed to gross revenues and monitoring folks,&quot; Baker said. Baker argued revenue and asset tests would be difficult to enforce.  </p>
<p>&quot;Is that measurement something that you do daily at the close of business, is that a quarterly test?,&quot; Baker asked Rubin. For some earlier bank regulations based on similiar tests, &quot;everybody would 'game' their books in the last week,&quot; Baker noted.</p>
<p>Rubin was not enthusiastic about the idea of limiting control. &quot;I think it can create a lot of the kinds of problems that we think we've avoided with this basket suggestion,&quot; Rubin said. &quot;You would have to deal with a lot of technical issues to make sure that (a basket) functioned effectively.&quot;  </p>
<p>One of the primary arguments of opponents of mixing banking and commerce is that unlimited mergers would lead to the creation of vast conglomerates with excessive economic power. Baker said his approach would eliminate that issue by prohibiting banks from controlling non-financial companies.</p>
<p>Rubin said the basket would also prevent massive conglomeration. &quot;I think that if you're going to talk about something less than full commerce and banking, my own view, for whatever it's worth, is that the basket approach we've taken deals with the issues of undue concentration, whether political or economic,&quot; Rubin said.</p>
<p>--Aaron Pressman ((202-898-8312))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
