<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634317" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian child sex inquiry enters decisive phase.</title>
<headline>Belgian child sex inquiry enters decisive phase.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Belgian parliamentary commission on Tuesday began the decisive phase of a probe into allegations that two convicted child abusers and suspected murders might have enjoyed high-level protection.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe we are (investigating) a very delicate matter--the protection leads,&quot; commission member Dany Vandenbosche told BRTN television after the hearing with leading public prosecutor Michel Bourlet.</p>
<p>The commission is investigating the possibility that Marc Dutroux and Patrick Derochette -- between them accused of abusing and murdering five young girls -- and their accomplices may have escaped earlier detection due to well-placed friends.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, behind closed doors, the members of the all-party commission heard evidence from Bourlet, the public prosecutor leading the investigations into a series of missing children, and two top magistrates.</p>
<p>But, even as the commission resumes work, its task remains the subject of bitter controversy. Some critics say it is trying to over-reach it brief and others accusing it of underperforming.</p>
<p>In its preliminary report in April, the commission identified a degree of bungling by police and magistrates in investigations into a series of missing children that shocked the nation.</p>
<p>But it also said it could not rule out the possibility that incompetence might have been exacerbated by high-level efforts to divert the inquiries, and it would therefore resume its hearings into possible protection until the end of September.</p>
<p>On Tuesday the commissioners told Bourlet they wanted to find out if the bungled police investigations were due to incompetence, conspiracy or blackmail -- or a combination.</p>
<p>The scandal came to light in mid-August with the discovery of the bodies of two eight-year old girls at a house owned by Dutroux in the town of Sars-La-Buisierre near the central Belgian city of Charleroi.</p>
<p>Less than three weeks later the bodies of two more teenage girls were unearthed on a property in Charleroi linked to Dutroux, who has been charged with the murder of all four.</p>
<p>In February police discovered the body of another eight-year-old girl stuffed in a steel trunk in the basement of a garage in Brussels. They arrested and charged Derochette.</p>
<p>To date no link has been established between the two men.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
