<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634315" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's Jospin set to unveil cabinet Wednesday.</title>
<headline>France's Jospin set to unveil cabinet Wednesday.</headline>
<byline>Alister Doyle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Socialist Prime Minister Lionel Jospin was expected to unveil a cabinet including Communist ministers on Wednesday as the right fought a bitter leadership battle after its mauling in France's parliamentary election.</p>
<p>Jospin, 59, will face the first major test of his awkward power-sharing with a conservative President Jacques Chirac when he proposes the cabinet -- the constitution gives the president a veto over appointees.</p>
<p>The new government is expected to be a &quot;Pink-Green-Red&quot; alliance of Socialists, other moderate leftists, Greens and Communists who secured a stunning majority in the 577-seat National Assembly in Sunday's election.</p>
<p>Sources close to Jospin said the cabinet was likely to be announced on Wednesday afternoon, a day after the ex-education minister succeeded Alain Juppe as premier. The Communists were expected to rubber-stamp their participation in the morning.</p>
<p>Out of office, Juppe struggled to cling to his job as Gaullist party boss as a chorus of his erstwhile allies got out the political knives.</p>
<p>Jospin's triumph derailed a centre-right deluded by Juppe and Chirac into believing it could easily win.</p>
<p>Most of the jockeying for cabinet posts in Jospin's cabinet went on behind the scenes, but Greens leader Dominique Voynet said she wanted her party to get the environment ministry and a junior ministry for social affairs or women's rights.</p>
<p>Aides to Jospin said the Communists could expect two ministries and a junior post as long as they toed Jospin's line and did not set pre-conditions. The Communists, for instance, oppose a single European currency broadly favoured by Jospin.</p>
<p>&quot;Communist ministers,&quot; the party daily L'Humanite trumpeted in a banner headline on Wednesday. It would be the first time the Communists, struggling to come to terms with the end of the Cold War, have been in government in France since 1984.</p>
<p>The Communists want wage increases for the low paid and want speedier implementation than planned of Socialist promises to create 700,000 youth jobs and cut the working week to 35 hours from 39 to attack a record unemployment rate of 12.8 percent of the workforce.</p>
<p>Since his appointment, Jospin has met several of the Socialist &quot;Musketeers&quot; he sent out across France last week to fight for votes -- Dominique Strauss-Kahn, Martine Aubry and Elisabeth Guigou -- all of whom could get senior posts.</p>
<p>Chirac formally appoints ministers, on the premier's recommendation, giving him a chance to signal either cooperation or conflict at the start of France's third &quot;cohabitation&quot;.</p>
<p>Late Socialist president Francois Mitterrand, who cohabitated with the centre-right from 1986 to 1988 and from 1993 to 1995, rejected nominees for foreign minister and defence minister in 1986 -- when Chirac was premier.</p>
<p>Chirac has kept a low profile since his decision to call the election 10 months early and win re-election for his right wing allies ran disastrously off the rails. His seven-year term runs until 2002 and he has said he will not resign.</p>
<p>But there were some signs of criticisms targeting Chirac. Former centrist prime minister Raymond Barre told the daily newspaper Progres de Lyon that Chirac &quot;is in a weakened position&quot; and that he must &quot;now pay the price of failure&quot;.</p>
<p>Under cohabitation, Mitterrand claimed pre-eminence in foreign affairs while leaving domestic policy to the government. But the 1958 constitution is unclear over a division of powers.</p>
<p>Juppe failed to disarm a barrage of critics within the Rally for the Republic party by calling a meeting of the party in September to elect a new leader. He did not spell out if he would be a candidate for the leadership but made clear he would not stand down immediately for arch-rival Philippe Seguin.</p>
<p>Former interior minister Charles Pasqua and parliamentary allies of former National Assembly speaker Seguin, who emerged as Chirac's favourite in the dying days of the campaign, branded Juppe's timetable unacceptable.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
