<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634388" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French Communists lean towards joining government.</title>
<headline>French Communists lean towards joining government.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's Communist Party, back from the cold after a left-wing victory in France's parliamentary election, met on Tuesday amid signs grassroots members wanted to join a Socialist-led government.</p>
<p>The party's policy-making national council, which has opposed a single European currency and wants wage hikes for the low-paid, was discussing conditions for taking part in any government led by new Socialist Prime Minister Lionel Jospin.</p>
<p>The party's 121-member national council also met on Monday after the party won 38 of the 577 National Assembly seats, giving it a balance of power. The non-Communist left won 274 seats -- short of the 289 needed for a majority.</p>
<p>In the Val-de-Marne area that was a bastion of former party leader Georges Marchais, a hardliner who approved the 1979 Soviet invasion of Afghanistan, 88 percent of grassroots Communists voted for participation in government.</p>
<p>Just six percent voted against and six abstained in the biggest Communist Party grouping in France.</p>
<p>Communist Party boss Robert Hue spoke to Jospin on Tuesday and reiterated demands for an immediate 500 franc ($100) hike in the minimum wage, a two percentage point cut in Value Added Tax and bigger cuts in VAT on basic products.</p>
<p>Hue said on Monday that the national council had agreed in principle that Communists should serve in the new government as long as policy questions could be resolved.</p>
<p>Jospin has repeatedly said that anyone wanting to take part in a Socialist-led government would have to bow to the line of the dominant party -- leading to charges by Hue during the campaign that Jospin was trying to impose &quot;hegemony&quot;.</p>
<p>The Socialists and Communists signed a pre-election declaration outlining plans to cut the working week to 35 hours from 39 and to create 700,000 youth jobs.</p>
<p>But the Communists want both measures implemented far faster than the Socialists.</p>
<p>Jack Ralite, a former health minister and junior minister for employment in 1981-84, urged the Communists to take part in government. &quot;People are drowning, the Communist Party should roll up its sleeves and do the dirty work,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The 1992 Maastricht Treaty set a course for deeper European political and monetary union, including strict terms for a country's qualification for the euro single currency, due to be launched in 1999.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
