<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63463" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Zell remains committed to Chateau bid.</title>
<headline>Zell remains committed to Chateau bid.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Samuel Zell, chairman of Manufactured Home Communities Inc, said on Thursday that he is committed to a $26 a share bid to acquire Chateau Properties Inc, which has already agreed to a merger with ROC Communities Inc.</p>
<p>Chateau had filed a lawsuit against Manufactured Homes, but Zell said in a statement that the lawsuit has no merit.  </p>
<p>Zell said Manufactured Home's $26 a share or $400 million offer provides superior value to Chateau Properties investors, compared with the stock swap merger with each Chateau share representing 1.0316 shares of the combined company.</p>
<p>Each ROC share would be 1.042 shares of the combined company, ROC and Chateau said in a statement yesterday.</p>
<p>Manufactured Home's bid is not subject to financing contingencies and a deal with Chateau would create a dominant force in the manufactured home industry with a strong balance sheet, Zell said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The revised Chateau and ROC transaction raises a number of troubling issues about the fiduciary responsibilities of Chateau's management and board of directors as well as tax liabilities transferred from operating unit holders to Chateau and ROC common shareholders,&quot; Zell said.</p>
<p>Operating units are non-voting shares held by Chateau's top management and directors that could be converted into six million common shares, Chateau has said. There are presently 6.1 million shares of Chateau outstanding.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Manufactured Home said this conversion could hurt Chateau's current holders of common stock.</p>
<p>Chateau chief executive Jeff Kellogg said yesterday that the companies' properties and management teams would merge well and the merged company would be expected to grow.</p>
<p>Chateau was not immediately available for further comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010022">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
