<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634778" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE cocoa loses further ground, eyes support.</title>
<headline>LIFFE cocoa loses further ground, eyes support.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>LIFFE cocoa futures lost further ground in thin trade by Tuesday midsession and traders said the market looked vulnerable to further losses after failing to match last week's high.</p>
<p>&quot;It doesn't look too good for cocoa at the moment,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>By midsession, benchmark July stood 11 stg down at 1,015 a tonne after a low of 1,013. September was also 10 stg down at 1,034.</p>
<p>Overall volume was 1,898 lots. Some 400 lots of AA trades were seen in July.</p>
<p>In the absence of fundamental news, the market is being driven by technical factors.</p>
<p>Chartwise, July looked set to challenge its key support at 1,000 stg if the funds, who are still long in both London and New York, decide to liquidate their positions.</p>
<p>New York is vulnerable to the $1,444 level on July.</p>
<p>London's July hit a high of 1,046 last week. &quot;But there's a chance London will test the bottom of its range which is 1,000,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Traders think that speculators were probably disappointed prices did not continue climbing after Thursday and Friday's gains. Speculative pressures are expected to surface in New York before first notice day in a couple of weeks to lead the way lower.</p>
<p>Origin sales into any rallies were also expected to curtail gains.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 4985</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
