<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634814" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Govett GlobalSmall to convert to unit trust.</title>
<headline>Govett GlobalSmall to convert to unit trust.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Govett Global Smaller Companies Investment Trust, which has recently traded at deep discounts to net asset value, said on Tuesday it would seek to convert to unit trust status.</p>
<p>The new unit trust will be managed by John Govett &amp; Co, but holders will be given the option of taking cash at conversion.</p>
<p>Investors reacted positively to the news, with bids of 90 pence per share, as opposed to 81.5 pence at Monday's close.</p>
<p>&quot;Our overweening aim is to provide good returns to shareholders, we are going to be pragmatic, rather than ideological about that,&quot; said Ian Taylor of fund manager.</p>
<p>Govett Global Smaller has traded as low as 18.5 percent below net asset value in recent months, as shareholders have dumped its shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Over the last six months, more and more funds have taken steps to narrow their discounts,&quot; said Stephen Keeling, analyst at HSBC James Capel, &quot;but the performance, on the face of it, looked poor.&quot;</p>
<p>Govett Global Smaller has outperformed similar funds, according to Taylor, but failed to keep pace with the market as a whole.</p>
<p>&quot;Though the trust has outperformed its benchmark, it only rose by 1.7 percent in the last year,&quot; said Taylor, &quot;As an asset class, smaller companies around the world have not performed terribly well.&quot;</p>
<p>Shareholders must vote on the plan of conversion. - James Saft, London newsroom +171 542 2734</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
