<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634969" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Lower Latam fish catches to cut fishmeal supply.</title>
<headline>Lower Latam fish catches to cut fishmeal supply.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poor fish catches in Chile and low overall fishmeal stocks in South America have contributed to meal export delays and global supplies should remain tight in 1997, the independent Oil World newsletter said.</p>
<p>Declining fish resources have lowered prospects for Latin American 1997 catches, with Chile's catches very small so far and Peru expected to exploit its April/September quota by July.</p>
<p>But both countries stepped up their exports by drawing down stocks in early 1997.</p>
<p>Chilean fishmeal output in Jan/April was 28 percent down from a year earlier at 489,000 tonnes while exports of 373,000 tonnes in the four months were up from 348,000 tonnes a year earlier.</p>
<p>Peru produced 381,000 tonnes of fishmeal in April only after seasonal bans lowered the Jan/March volume.</p>
<p>The Jan/April production total was 683,000 tonnes (620,000 tonnes in 1996) while Jan/April exports of 802,000 tonnes compared with 519,000 a year earlier.</p>
<p>Jan/April fishmeal output in the two countries plus Denmark, Iceland and Norway totalled 1.47 million tonnes (1.60 million). Exports by the five countries rose to 1.37 million tonnes (1.09 million) as producers cashed in on attractive prices.</p>
<p>-Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
