<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="635050" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian OLOs to hold firm despite appetite for U.S.</title>
<headline>Belgian OLOs to hold firm despite appetite for U.S.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian government bonds, largely domestically-held, are expected to weather current turmoil over Europe's economic and monetary union project as long as local investors hold on to the paper, dealers said.</p>
<p>Tuesday's market provided no indication domestics were about to ditch OLOs, although dealers said prices were mainly supported by a Treasuries-inspired rally in Bunds which managed to crack a resistance level and expand early gains.</p>
<p>Volumes were thin. Dealers said there were no signs bond holders were actually switching out of Europe and into the U.S.  </p>
<p>Uncertainty over EMU and the euro in the wake of the French Left's election victory and a row between the Bundesbank and Bonn over a government plan to tap into gold reserves to cut state debt has sparked safe-haven buying of the dollar.</p>
<p>Along similar lines Treasuries should be bought, dealers said. &quot;Everybody should be buying America to evade Europe... I cannot blame people who would do that,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;But on the other hand it would not be smart to sell Belgium...nobody is selling Belgium,&quot; he said. Players would have a hard time trying to cover such short positions.</p>
<p>&quot;The next days will be volatile,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Dealers said buying of Treasuries could push the U.S./Bund spread down to 75 or 82 basis points from current levels around 89, but not much beyond that. Similarly, the OLO/Bund spread would not break out its 5-15 basis point band. It was at eight bps at 1015 GMT, down from Monday's nine.</p>
<p>Market fears of a weak euro have grown and doubts about the future euro's strength remain despite the French Socialists saying they would stick to the EMU timetable. Concern, however, centres less on a delay to the planned start of EMU in 1999 and more on the impact of growing popular opposition to austerity measures needed to meet the Maastricht Treaty criteria.  </p>
<p>If the Maastricht terms are not met and in line with France's wishes Italy and Spain would be allowed to join EMU from the start, this is seen undermining the euro.</p>
<p>&quot;The only winner is the dollar...investors are more and more convinced that the chances of a broader EMU with a weaker euro are gradually rising...rather than delay,&quot; an analyst said, &quot;sell any tops (in bonds).&quot;</p>
<p>Volumes would stay low ahead of a speech before the Bundestag on Wednesday by Finance Minister Theo Waigel, battling with the Bundesbank over plans to revalue Germany's gold reserves to improve public finances before joining the euro.  </p>
<p>The German central bank opposes the plan, saying it undermines its independence.</p>
<p>Analysts say the idea illustrates Bonn's desperation over a shortfall in revenues which is keeping it from cutting state debt and meeting the Maastricht criteria. Since EMU without Germany would be unimaginable the alternative would be to soften the criteria to ensure Bonn's participation  DE-EMU. For a delay the political will in favour of EMU is too strong.</p>
<p>U.S. payroll data due on Friday are providing players with another reason to hug the sidelines. Forecasts are not yet available  US-ECI.</p>
<p>-- Nieck Ammerlaan, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6816, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
