<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63508" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: RUGBY UNION-ARGENTINA, CANADA TO FACE OFF FOR PANAM RUGBY TITLE.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-ARGENTINA, CANADA TO FACE OFF FOR PANAM RUGBY TITLE.</headline>
<dateline>HAMILTON, Ontario 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina and Canada won their second-round matches in the four-nation Pan American championships on Wednesday, ensuring that when they play each other next Saturday it will be the tournament decider.</p>
<p>Argentina trounced Uruguay 54-20 in the first match of the evening while Canada had a tougher battle in beating the United States 23-18.</p>
<p>Next Saturday, Argentina and the United States meet in the third match of the league-style tournament with the winner assured of the trophy.</p>
<p>Uruguay look doomed to taking last place with the United States almost guaranteed victory over a noticeably unfit South American team.</p>
<p>The Argentina-Uruguay match saw two tries from both Diego Giannantonio and Pueblo Carmerlinkx, plus tries from Gonzalo Queseda, Christian Barrea, Omar Hassan and Jose Orgengo.</p>
<p>The man of the match was undoubtedly Queseda who converted all of his side's tries -- bringing his personal score for the game, with his try, to 19 points.</p>
<p>For Uruguay, Mauricio Mosca and captain Diego Ormaechea scored a try each. Santiago Silva converted both of them and scored one penalty while Fredrico Sciarra kicked one penalty.</p>
<p>The meagre crowd of just 1,500 was treated to better competition in the Canada-United States half of the double-header.</p>
<p>The United States led at half-time, thanks to four penalties by Matt Alexander, who kicked another two penalties in the second half.</p>
<p>But that was the Americans' only scoring and the lack of tries by the Eagles proved the deciding factor.</p>
<p>Courtney Smith put the Canadians into the lead with two tries, both converted by Bob Ross who also kicked three penalties.</p>
<p>U.S. coach Jack Clark admitted to being disappointed saying: &quot;The game swung on a few movements and Canada took advantage of them.&quot;</p>
<p>But Canadian coach Pat Parfrey insisted it was a well-deserved win.</p>
<p>&quot;Our forwards rucked outstandingly and we tried to play open rugby and it worked.&quot;</p>
<p>Argentina and Canada now top the four-nation league with a maximum eight points, with the United States in third place with two consolation points and Uruguay at the bottom with just one consolation point.</p>
<p>Each team gets four points for a win and a consolation point if it loses by seven points or less.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="URU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMILTON, Ontario"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
