<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="635109" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Worldwide Advertising &amp; Media Digest - June 3.</title>
<headline>Worldwide Advertising &amp; Media Digest - June 3.</headline>
<text>
<p>------------------------- WAM ------------------------</p>
<p>....REUTERS WORLDWIDE ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA DIGEST.....</p>
<p>-------------------June 3, 1997 ------------------</p>
<p>Reuters news from around the world on Advertising, Marketing, Media, the Internet, Brand-name Products and Consumer Trends ***********************************************</p>
<p>ADVERTISING &amp; MARKETING:</p>
<p>LONDON - Lowe &amp; Partners Europe appoints John Englehart for its newly-created role as general manager for the European advertising network. Englehart joins Lowe, a part of U.S.-based Interpublic Group of Companies Inc., from Ogilvy &amp; Mather Worldwide.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - British Prime Minister Tony Blair, who led his Labour party to victory, is a classic example of how good marketing sells a brand, advertising executives say. Similar to the way consumer goods companies market cereal, the Labour Party researched what the public wanted and delivered the product demanded.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SUMMIT, New Jersey - Pharmaceutical giant Novartis AG says its Novartis Consumer Health Inc unit has restructured its advertising accounts, adding Ogilvy &amp; Mather to handle media buying.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>MEDIA &amp; THE INTERNET:</p>
<p>SANTA CLARA, California - Internet company PointCast Inc says it will focus on providing an advertising-based news and information service while making tools available to corporate users for free.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>MUNICH - Private television stations ProSieben and Kabel 1 increased their viewer share of German TV in May. ProSieben's share rose to 9.1 percent from 9.0 percent in April, while Kabel 1's share increased to 4.0 percent from 3.9 percent. German market leader RTL's share dropped to 17.0 percent in May from 17.8 the previous month. Private station Sat1 also fell in the ratings, to 14.4 percent in May from 14.1 percent in April. *********</p>
<p>LONDON - Britain's United News &amp; Media Plc says it and Warner Brothers will be seeking alternative sites for their Warner Bros. Movie World studios and theme park following undisclosed problems with its proposed site in west London. *********</p>
<p>MUNICH - ProSieben Media AG, the German television company poised to go public on the German stock market, says it has held its market share steady in May, making the upcoming share sale even more attractive. ProSieben, which runs the ProSieben and Kabel 1 commercial television channels, says the stations' combined market share in May was unchanged at 13.1 percent. *********</p>
<p>BERLIN - The German Cartel Office has begun an investigation against Deutsche Telekom on suspicion of anti-competitive practices in its cable television operations, a spokeswoman for the office says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SYDNEY - Australian government-owned telecoms group Telstra Corp is in talks with News Corp Ltdabout shortening Telstra's cable rollout for their jointly-owned Foxtel cable television joint venture, The Sydney Morning Herald newspaper reports.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>ATLANTA - Lotus Development Corp. President Jeff Papows says that the commercial future of the Internet lies in billion-dollar transactions between businesses, rather than in sales to consumers.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>BRAND-NAME PRODUCTS &amp; MARKETS:</p>
<p>DETROIT - Kellogg Co. says it plans to announce that it is seeking permission to make a new health claim that foods with wheat bran fibre can help reduce the risk of colon cancer. It has asked the Food and Drug Administration to approve the claim on packages of foods containing wheat bran fibre.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BONN - Intel Corp is feeling pressure in Europe because of economic uncertainty in the region as well as gains by rival microchip makers, computer industry analysts. Stagnant economies, austerity measures related to European monetary union and transitions to new Intel chips are dampening demand for personal computers, especially among consumers, the analysts say.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>CHICAGO - McDonald's Corp's 55 promotion under which sandwiches cost 55 cents, is not working according to analysts. &quot;Campaign 55, it's just not working,&quot; Natwest Securities analyst Damon Brundage says, adding he estimates McDonald's U.S. same store sales in May were off four to five percent.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>MEXICO CITY - Mexico's most famous liquor gets a boost as the European Union signs an agreement that limits the uses of the name &quot;tequila&quot; to products bottled in Mexico. &quot;Just as we can't make vodka here, they can't make tequila over there,&quot; says Jos Luis Rojo, director of Tequila Dictador, a producer of premium tequila.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - Shares in Cadbury Schweppes Plc fell after press reports saying Coca Cola Co is seeking to banish soft drinks produced by Dr Pepper/Seven Up Inc from thousands of McDonald's Corp restaurants.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>ATLANTA -  Toshiba Corp., the world's leading notebook computer maker, has introduced the first full-function notebook that weighs less than two pounds.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>MANILA - Philippines' Pure Foods Corp, a subsidiary of conglomerate Ayala Corp, is negotiating for the local franchise of leading fastfood chain Burger King, company officials say. *********</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Union tobacco manufacturers, retailers and workers vigorously reject criticism by the European Union's top health official, saying that price cutting is the only way to raise sales. On Friday, EU Health Commissioner Padraig Flynn condemned a new cigarette price war as a ploy to attract new smokers and get round advertising bans.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BUDAPEST - Automakers have steered most of their investments in former communist Europe into major economies such as Poland and Russia, but one of the region's most attractive car market's is the tiny country of Slovenia, according to a study by British auto consultancy Harbour Wade Brown.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>CONSUMER TRENDS:</p>
<p>CHICAGO- America's preoccupation with navel-staring is stronger than ever, if the thousands of books on self-improvement and alternative spirituality presented at BookExpo America, the U.S. publishing industry's annual convention are anything to go by. From alternative medicine to Zen meditation, publishers say sales are thriving.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>MOSCOW - Russian President Boris Yeltsin is following thousands of other consumers and is setting up his own home page on the Internet, the Kremlin says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - The U.S. is becoming increasingly popular as a tourist destination. The number of international tourists hit an all-time high of 46.3 million in 1996, the Commerce Department's Tourism Industries office says.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>-- London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2792</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>See full stories on Reuters Advertising &amp; Media Briefing. And why not visit our Internet site at http://www.bizinfo.reuters.com?</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
