<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="635261" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Price rise impact low on NZ's WH - analysts.</title>
<headline>Price rise impact low on NZ's WH - analysts.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Analysts on Tuesday said publisher Wilson and Horton could expect up to a $2 million increase in revenues from a weekend hike in the cover price of its flagship newspaper the New Zealand Herald.</p>
<p>An analyst who declined to be named told Reuters he saw an increase of little more than NZ$2 million in revenues.</p>
<p>&quot;At the best I would say no more than $2 million. Obviously it has a beneficial effect, but the increase would have been budgeted this year in any case,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>A Wellington-based analyst, who also asked not to be named, said the impact would not be great and could be less than $1 million if the paper's current circulation was maintained.</p>
<p>On Saturday the Auckland-based Herald announced it would lift the cover price of its five weekday papers from 70 cents to 90 cents but would maintain the Saturday price at $1 a copy.</p>
<p>New and existing subscribers would be offered discounts to partially offset the price rise, it added.</p>
<p>Herald general manager Phillip Crawley declined to discuss expected revenue increases, but said they would not be large.  </p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't get too excited about the difference, to be honest. It is not that significant in the greater scheme of things,&quot; Crawley told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the Herald, which sells 50 percent of its newspapers on subscription and 50 percent as casual sales, had a range of expectations and was not certain how the promotion would affect revenues.</p>
<p>SBC Warburg analyst Paul Richardson said he expected a significant rise in earnings before interest and tax from the cover price hike.  </p>
<p>He said the muted reaction of Wilson and Horton's share price, up five cents to $11.70 on Tuesday, reflected the lack of liquidity in the stock and also that expectations of higher prices had already being factored in.</p>
<p>The Wellington-based media analyst said the Herald could expect to lose some circulation as a result of the price rise.</p>
<p>&quot;The previous two times the Herald increased its cover price there was a loss of circulation,&quot; he said. &quot;That also affects your ability to charge advertisers more.&quot;  </p>
<p>Announcing the price rise, the Herald told its readers the increase followed major improvements to the product, including a 25 percent increase in editorial content in a year.</p>
<p>&quot;The costs associated with these changes and rises in other operating charges necessitate the price rise,&quot; the paper said.</p>
<p>Wilson and Horton is 85 percent owned by Tony O'Reilly's Independent Newspapers Ltd.</p>
<p>The Herald's circulation had been in the doldrums in recent years despite strong population growth in its main Auckland market.  </p>
<p>But in the six months to March the Herald lifted its circulation by 2,696 to 229,398 over the same year-ago period.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
