<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="635229" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: AWB sees Japan as still in mkt for Australia wheat.</title>
<headline>AWB sees Japan as still in mkt for Australia wheat.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian Wheat Board (AWB) expects Japan will continue to buy Australian wheat to fulfil an agreement for the purchase of about 900,000 tonnes this year, an AWB spokesman said.</p>
<p>This was despite calls by the Food Agency of Japan, one of the AWB's largest customers, for a reduction in Australian wheat export prices.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got a very good working relationship and are in daily contact with the Agency,&quot; an AWB spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome any feedback on our prices. We're obviously concerned about how our customers feel,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are in dialogue with them all the time. But we also try to get the best price for our growers, so we're also walking that tightrope,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;They're obviously letting the world know how they feel,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But the AWB was confident of achieving its agreement with Japan for the sale of about 900,000 tonnes of wheat, he said.</p>
<p>The AWB and Japan reach agreement each year which projects the approximate tonnage of wheat trade between the two countries. The agreement is not binding.</p>
<p>This year's agreement is for about 900,000 tonnes.  </p>
<p>Japan bought 1.15 million tonnes of wheat from Australia in 1995/96 from a total of 13.22 million tonnes exported by the AWB in that year.</p>
<p>This made it Australia's fourth-largest customer in that year, after China, Hong Kong and Indonesia.</p>
<p>The AWB in the past has described Japan as its most stable customer.</p>
<p>The Food Agency of Japan said on Tuesday it would reduce wheat imports from Australia if prices were not reduced.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're known as a stable importer and have in the past bought wheat and barley even if prices fluctuated wildly,&quot; a Food Agency of Japan official was quoted by Reuters as saying in Tokyo.</p>
<p>&quot;But we may be forced to become more market-oriented from now on,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the past two tenders, the agency did not buy Australian grain as it intended to because prices were too high, he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
