<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="635260" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia's Beazley calls for opposition unity.</title>
<headline>Australia's Beazley calls for opposition unity.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian opposition leader Kim Beazley called on Tuesday for Labor Party discipline and unity, saying it could mean the difference between winning or losing if an election was held now.</p>
<p>A Labor party spokesman said Beazley had told a party room meeting that recent opinion polls showed the opposition would win or lose narrowly if an election were held tomorrow.</p>
<p>&quot;If there'd been a poll conducted tomorrow on those results there would be either an ALP (Australian Labor Party) victory or a small defeat,&quot; the spokesman quoted Beazley as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;We are being seen now by some as a national alternate government and that brings with it the need for discipline and the need for unity,&quot; he was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>On May 28, a Sydney Morning Herald newspaper poll showed the number of voters who approved of Beazley had increased four points to 49 percent, putting him ahead of Prime Minister John Howard for the first time. The same poll found Howard's approval rating had fallen 11 points to 46 percent.</p>
<p>Some recent polls have put support for the Liberal-National government and the opposition level at 50 percent, after preferences are distributed under the complicated voting system.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
