<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="635675" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek shares extend rebound, approach 1,700pts.</title>
<headline>Greek shares extend rebound, approach 1,700pts.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Easing selling pressure in large private banks and momentum carried over from Monday's session helped Greek shares extend their rebound from the 1,600 level in early Tuesday trade.</p>
<p>The broader market was being pulled higher by Alpha Credit Bank and ErgoBank which were recovering from heavy selling pressure in the past couple of sessions.</p>
<p>Brokers said the market was bouncing back after a sizeable correction due to institutional selling.</p>
<p>&quot;The market completed its 150-point correction down to 1,600 which was largely the result of profit-taking by large domestic and mostly foreign portfolios,&quot; said Costas Feggos, managing director of Axon Securities.</p>
<p>The French election outcome and last week's interbank rate hike mostly unnerved institutional investors but they did not wrap up their positions.</p>
<p>&quot;They merely rebalanced their portfolios realising their large capital gains and purchased stock at lower price levels,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Technical analysts pointed out the validity of the 1,600 support level.</p>
<p>&quot;The support level at 1,600 points corresponds to a 33 percent correction of the rally from 1,440 to 1,750 points,&quot; said Commercial Securities in its technical analysis outlook.</p>
<p>Following Tuesday's performance, the market was expected to enter a trading range at higher levels.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices will consolidate in a trading range with 1,650 points being its floor level,&quot; Feggos said.</p>
<p>&quot;The index will most likely move towards the broader 1,700 level where prices will consolidate unless volume picks up,&quot; said Commercial Securities which also warranted caution.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has entered a phase of increased short-term volatility with no clear direction,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The Athens general index was up 2.45 percent or 40.53 points at 1,693.52 from Monday's 1,652.99 close after 25 minutes of trading.</p>
<p>It opened at 1,673.00 points and continued to move higher throughout the early stages of trade, reaching  an intra-day high of 1,697.52.</p>
<p>Advancers led decliners 119 to 35 with 22 shares unchanged on 176 traded.</p>
<p>The Merrill Lynch call spread warrant on OTE with a strike price of 3,800 drachmas was quoted at 1,121-1,151. Shares of OTE telecom, the underlying, were up 200 drachmas at 7,600 drachmas.</p>
<p>The Merrill Lynch American call warrant on a basket of 23 Greek equities that are part of the Athens general index was quoted at 714.95-760.59. The warrants expire January 9 1998.</p>
<p>The ING Baring Financial Products American style call warrant based on a basket of six bank stocks was quoted at $88.39-$90.08. The strike price is set at $99.60 and the warrants expire October 8, 1997.</p>
<p>The ING Baring Financial Products American-style call warrant on a basket of six blue-chips denominated in drachmas was quoted at 4,447-4,685 drachmas. The strike price is set at 10,000 drachmas and the warrants expire on February 2, 1998.</p>
<p>The ING Baring American-style second call warrant on a basket of six bank stocks was quoted at $19.24-N/O. The strike price is set at $110.0 and the warrants expire April 9 1998.</p>
<p>The recently launched ING Baring American-style, drachma- denominated call warrant on the bourse's benchmark index was quoted at 304-338 drachmas. The strike price is set at 1,639 points and the warrants expire May 14 1998.</p>
<p>--Angelos Kiosklis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
