<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="635605" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Toshiba launches business desktop PCs in Europe.</title>
<headline>Toshiba launches business desktop PCs in Europe.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toshiba Corp said on Tuesday it had started marketing desktop personal computers (PCs) for business use in Britain, Germany, and France.  </p>
<p>The move is part of the company's reinforcement of its worldwide PC business, it said in a statement.</p>
<p>Toshiba plans to ship four million units of PCs worldwide in the year to next March 31, up 2.7 million units from 1996/97.</p>
<p>&quot;The company is strengthening its capabilities as a global PC supplier,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;In this connection, it is promoting its international desktop business, still the largest segment of the global PC market, and further strengthening its leadership position in the worldwide notebook PC market,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Toshiba sells its Equium business PC series in Britain, Germany and France, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;The company will now build on its new presence in Europe's three largest markets for business computers,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>A Toshiba spokesman did not give any prices for the Equium models in the three countries.</p>
<p>He said Toshiba would introduce the business desktop PC series in other European markets in the future but he did not provide specific dates.</p>
<p>Toshiba expects to sell 90,000 of the computers in Europe by the end of March 1998, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The company introduced its home-use desktop Infinia PC series in France in March but it has no immediate plan to launch the series in other European markets, he said.</p>
<p>Toshiba also started selling the Equium series in the United States in March with an annual target of 400,000 to 500,000 units, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Toshiba also sells the Infinia in the United States.</p>
<p>Toshiba also announced that it had launched eight new portable PCs worldwide on Tuesday, and had started worldwide marketing of its mini-notebook Libretto50CT.</p>
<p>Previously, the Libretto50CT was available only in Japan.</p>
<p>Toshiba expects to sell 100,000 Librettos in the United States, 50,000 in Europe and 35,000 in Asia, excluding Japan, by the end of March 1998, the Toshiba spokesman said.</p>
<p>Toshiba also said that it would start marketing an upgraded multimedia desktop PC in Japan on June 10.</p>
<p>Toshiba has the largest share of the world laptop market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
