<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="635775" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Micron says chip prices edged higher in Q3.</title>
<headline>Micron says chip prices edged higher in Q3.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Micron Technology Inc on Wednesday said average selling prices for its computer memory chips had improved slightly in its fiscal third quarter compared with the previous three months.</p>
<p>&quot;For our third quarter we saw a very modest improvement in (average selling prices) as compared to second quarter,&quot; said Wilbur Stover, Micron's chief financial officer. The company's third quarter ended last week.</p>
<p>He said memory chip prices had also shown some stability during the first and second quarters.  </p>
<p>But he told a Paine Webber conference in New York that Micron had budgeted for a five to six percent decline annually in selling prices over the next year and a half.</p>
<p>&quot;We are anticipating a decline in price for the next several years,&quot; Stover said. &quot;But what we see on the horizon is a pretty strong picture for PC demand.&quot;</p>
<p>Spot prices for memory chips were five to 10 percent lower at the end of May than at the beginning of the month, he said.</p>
<p>Stover said Micron likely showed some modest increases in its units of finished goods in the third quarter, but he said he was not uncomfortable with the company's inventory level.  </p>
<p>&quot;Given our pricing sense today, there is less risk of downside pressure, so there is less reason to push our inventory out the door,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Micron also said it was not seeing signs of a slowdown in personal computer demand, a concern that has spooked the market recently.</p>
<p>&quot;We have listened with great interest to announcements this week which have suggested demand has slowed....This is inconsistent with our experience,&quot; Stover said.  </p>
<p>He said: &quot;We're still seeing strong increases in the amount of memory which is being taken by our key (customers), relative to their contractual agreements with us.&quot;</p>
<p>With prices up, Micron could show higher gross margins in the third quarter than in the second quarter, Stover said.</p>
<p>The company's semiconducctor operations recorded a gross margin of 32 percent in the second quarter, an improvement from 24 percent in the first quarter, Stover said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Micron has been and continues to be pleased by its position as it rides out this downcycle,&quot; Stover said. &quot;We've been able to push our costs down even lower than our competition, so once again we have been able to enjoy profitability even in this downcycle.&quot;</p>
<p>But the percentage increase in production during the third quarter would likely be only be half as large as they were in the second and first quarters, he said.</p>
<p>Production increased 55 percent from the first quarter to the second quarter, Stover said.</p>
<p>((--Mary Kelleher, Wall Street desk 212-859-1730))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
