<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="635701" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS - German CDU eager for deal with Bundesbank.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - German CDU eager for deal with Bundesbank.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leader of Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU) said on Tuesday the German government was confident it could reach a consensus agreement with the Bundesbank on the controversial plan to revalue its assets.</p>
<p>Peter Hintze, general secretary of the CDU, told ZDF television that the government was working to reach an agreement with the Bundesbank after the central bank objected to Finance Minister Theo Waigel's plan to revalue gold and currency assets.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in the middle of negotiations and very interested in coming to a consensus agreement with the Bundesbank on the revaluation of the gold reserves,&quot; Hintze said. &quot;We are striving to reach an agreement and I am confident we will reach one.&quot;</p>
<p>Hintze was speaking as leaders from Kohl's governing coalition were holding their second crisis meeting in three days in Bonn to search for ways to resolve the battle over budget holes and the gold revaluation.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank has repeatedly warned Bonn against resorting to tricks designed to squeeze Germany into currency union.</p>
<p>Still angered by Finance Minister Theo Waigel's plan to revalue national gold and currency reserves and use a part of those proceeds to fill budget holes this year, the Bundesbank compared Bonn's plans to practices Bonn itself had abhorred.</p>
<p>&quot;A transfer of funds from a revalution in 1997 could be seen as creative accouting,&quot; Bundesbank official Helmut Hesse said in Hanover, recalling Germany's disdain when Italy and France gained approval for one-off measures to meet EMU goals.</p>
<p>Waigel, eager to defuse the unusally public and bitter row, said he hoped to reach agreement with the central bank, but also said the government would not back off its plan.</p>
<p>For the Bundesbank however the more irritating point is Bonn's plan to grab unrealised profits this year, a move many council members likened to an infringement on central bank's hallowed independence.</p>
<p>Bundesbank officials, driving their point home to audiences across Germany, insisted the asset revaluation should only occur once currency union has begun.</p>
<p>For the Bundesbank, any concession on the date when profits might be paid out would be a small but potentially key concession, officials said at a reception in Mainz.</p>
<p>While sticking by its tough talk, the Bundesbank nonetheless appeared interested in finding a solution to the problems which have tarnished Germany's image abroad.</p>
<p>Asset revaluation in 1997 could help Germany meet the criteria to qualify for EMU.</p>
<p>Conciliatory sounds from Bonn came amid growing worries about plans for Europe's single currency project, which appeared to have been put in further danger by the swing to the left in Sunday's parliament election in France.</p>
<p>Hintze told ZDF television even though some CDU deputies in parliament have said they would not vote for a law on the gold revaluation against the will of the Bundesbank he was confident that there would be no defections once an agreement was reached.</p>
<p>&quot;If we reach a consensus with the Bundesbank, and the finance minister is trying with all his energy to reach such a consensus, there won't be any defectors because who is going to have something against a consensus between the Bundesbank and government,&quot; Hintze said.</p>
<p>Asked about CDU deputy Juergen Augustinowitz, who last week said, said he would not vote for the legislation against the Bundesbank's will, Hintze said he would back a consensus plan.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr. Augustinowitz says he would like to vote for an agreement that is based on consensus,&quot; Hintze said. &quot;He said he would not vote for a plan that wasn't based on consensus.&quot;</p>
<p>The weekly magazine Stern said on Tuesday the government, despite official denials, is planning to sell part of the Bundesbank's gold and foreign reserves after the startup of the European Central Bank.</p>
<p>Government officials were not immediately available for comment on the Stern report.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
