<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="635879" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Immunex says Flt 3 ligand shown safe.</title>
<headline>Immunex says Flt 3 ligand shown safe.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Immunex Corp said Wednesday Phase I trials found its Flt-3 ligand compound to be safe and showed preliminary signs it was also effective as an immune system booster.</p>
<p>In a study of 20 healthy volunteers, Immunex said patients who received daily injections of Flt-3 ligand showed an increase in the volume of stem cells and dendritic cells in their blood.  Stem cells, which originate in the bone marrow, are central to the immune system.  Dendritic cells are white blood cells that also play a role in the immune system.</p>
<p>Immunex is testing Flt-3 ligand as a compound to bolster the immune system to improve patients' defenses in fighting cancer and infections.  By stimulating the count of stem and dendritic cells in the blood, Flt-3 ligand could potentially  reduce the number of blood collections required for stem cell transplants, and possibly do away with the need for bone marrow transplants by deriving the stem cells from the blood itself, Immunex said.</p>
<p>Immunex is also studying the Flt-3 ligand compound as a direct cancer treatment.  Trials in mice have shown it to be effective in shrinking tumors, the company said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
