<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="635890" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BP gasoline delivery in NYH raises surplus concern.</title>
<headline>BP gasoline delivery in NYH raises surplus concern.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A large delivery of reformulated unleaded gasoline to British Petroleum on the June NYMEX contract has created a perception of supply overhang in the New York Harbor Wednesday, depressing spot values.</p>
<p>Prompt conventional unleaded gasoline was offered at two cents under the July NYMEX gasoline contract versus 1.75 cents under Tuesday. Reformulated 87 grade was offered at 0.40 to 0.50 cent over the July contract versus 0.75 cent over Tuesday. Dealers said a dearth of bidders appeared amid the prospect of new supply.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a surplus of gasoline supply in the Harbor with BP taking delivery and several cargoes hanging about with not many bidders,&quot; said a Harbor dealer.</p>
<p>NYMEX said a total of 1,669,000 barrels of gasoline are being delivered on the June contract. BP sources said they are taking between one and 1.5 million barrels of gasoline.</p>
<p>Officials at midcontinent refiner Koch Industries declined comment on talk by dealers that Koch was the primary deliverer.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not even tried to sell any of the barrels that have not already been arranged to be sold, and we don't see any problems doing so,&quot; said a BP source who requested anonymity.</p>
<p>The BP source said the lack of bidders in the market reflected strategizing by dealers in the face of the new supply and did not reflect a lack of demand.</p>
<p>-- Harry Milling, New York Energy Desk, 212-859-1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
