<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63620" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Kevin Maxwell says Serious Fraud Office &quot;fixated&quot;.</title>
<headline>Kevin Maxwell says Serious Fraud Office &quot;fixated&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kevin Maxwell, spared a second fraud charges trial, launched a scathing attack on Britain's Serious Fraud Office, saying it was &quot;fixated with the desire to secure a conviction.&quot;</p>
<p>The youngest son of media tycoon Robert Maxwell, whose death in 1991 led to the collapse of his business empire, said he had lived in fear of prison for five years.</p>
<p>Judge John Buckley ruled on Thursday that a further trial &quot;would be unfair, so unfair as to amount to an abuse of power of the court.&quot; He said verdicts of &quot;not guilty' should be recorded on all outstanding charges against Kevin and his three fellow defendants.</p>
<p>He ordered their costs to be paid from state funds. Costs were estimated at around 30 million pounds ($46 million), making it the most expensive criminal case in Britain this century.</p>
<p>The ruling ended five years of controversy over hundreds of millions of pounds found missing from Maxwell company pension funds after Robert Maxwell disappeared from his yacht in the Atlantic Ocean.</p>
<p>Kevin Maxwell, interviewed by the London Independent newspaper, said the Serious Fraud Office was an investigator and a prosecutor.</p>
<p>He said it had been determined &quot;to clean up the City, to use terror and every weapon at its disposal.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the SFO's annual report how do they measure themselves...It is solely (by) their conviction rate.&quot;</p>
<p>Maxwell said with the threat of prison now lifted from his shoulders for the first time in five years &quot;I can say to my children I will be coming home. I will be around which is marvellous.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
