<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636430" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Podravka leads Croatian trade, market seen rising.</title>
<headline>Podravka leads Croatian trade, market seen rising.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks were mixed to higher in slower trade on Wednesday, dominated by food processor Podravka, and traders expected short-term advances.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect a mild rise in the next few days because several companies have announced the signing of credit agreements with foreign banks,&quot; Igor Kos of the Taurus brokerage said.</p>
<p>He referred to fully-listed Zagrebacka Banka and leading chocolate maker Kras.</p>
<p>Another trader, Denis Fuduric of IB Austria, said Croatia's compliance with Western demands on human rights, could boost trade. He mentioned U.S. pressure on Croatia to allow the return of all displaced minority Serbs.</p>
<p>&quot;After our politicians bowed to United States pressure, things (on the market) could be put in order,&quot; Fuduric said. However, he did not expect a significant boom before the end of the summer.</p>
<p>The U.S. has said if Croatia does not honour commitments over the return of refugees among other issues it would consider blocking International Monetary Fund loans and Croatia's integration into Western institutions.</p>
<p>Podravka was the most active stock with 4,788 shares sold. It inched up one kuna (16 cents) to 263, despite rumours the annual results it is due to publish soon would be negative.</p>
<p>Fuduric said the rumoured negative results were ascribed to Podravka getting rid of its loss-making subsidiaries, after which the company was poised for growth.</p>
<p>&quot;Podravka is an interesting stock right now because its price has been down,&quot; Kos said. The company peaked at 305 kuna in late April. &quot;It's a long-term investment which will pay off in the end,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Seven of 12 active issues rose on Wednesday, two fell and three were flat. Volume was down to 7,825 units and turnover halved to 3.4 million kuna.</p>
<p>Leading issues, fully-listed Zagrebacka Banka and drugs firm Pliva, were mixed to lower.</p>
<p>Zagrebacka's ordinary stock lost 15 kuna to 2,125 on a modest volume of 71 unit and Pliva held its ground for the second straight day at 460 kuna, with 339 shares sold. Zagrebacka E-series preference stock added 26 kuna to 1,225 on volume of 946 units.</p>
<p>Another fully-listed issue, Varazdinska Banka, was the day's biggest decliner. Its A-series lost 15 kuna to 220, selling 290 units.</p>
<p>Fuduric said its decline was surprising and the bank was now expected to stagnate at least until the end of summer.</p>
<p>Wednesday's biggest gainer was shipper Jadranska Plovidba. It added five kuna or 5.3 pct to 100, on volume of 222 shares.</p>
<p>Both active hotelier stocks were on the gaining side.</p>
<p>Istraturist added 10 kuna to 165 on volume of 20 shares and Laguna Porec inched up five kuna to 1,315, with 145 units sold. ($ = 6.139 Croatian Kuna)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
