<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636455" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria seeks guarantees to import farm machinery.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria seeks guarantees to import farm machinery.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria is seeking bank guarantees to import farming equipment against the export of 40,000 tonnes of wheat from this year's crop, an agriculture ministry official said.</p>
<p>&quot;Agriculture minister Ventsislav Varbanov met on Wednesday with the Central Cooperative Bank (CCB) executive director to ask for bank guarantees required for the import of farm machinery under future contracts,&quot; the official told Reuters.</p>
<p>CCB officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>The interim government, which stepped down on May 21, approved the export of 40,000 tonnes of wheat from this year's crop against imports of equipment needed to replace outdated machinery and help collect this year's harvest on time.</p>
<p>Bulgarian grains producers said on Wednesday they expected this year's harvest campaign to last 90 days instead of the usual 30 days because of a lack of combine harvesters.</p>
<p>&quot;The quality of the crop could deteriorate over such a long period,&quot; Bulgarian Agriculture Chamber president Todor Pandov told a news conference.</p>
<p>Bulgaria has only 6,600 outdated combine harvesters at present, he added.</p>
<p>Bank credits and guarantees have been hard to secure because of the unprecedented financial crisis that has hit Bulgaria's banking system over the past year.</p>
<p>Bulgaria is due to introduce on July 1 a restrictive monetary mechanism, known as the currency board, which bans central bank lending to commercial banks. This in turn makes bankers even more cautious.</p>
<p>Varbanov said last week that Bulgaria will need to import 53,000 tonnes of bread wheat to cover needs until the new crop arrives and a further 1.072 million tonnes of bread and feed wheat before next year's crop.</p>
<p>Varbanov also said Bulgaria needs to import a total of 200,000 tonnes of feed maize in the period leading up to this year's harvest.</p>
<p>Excessive wheat exports two years ago and a bad harvest last year led to acute grain and bread shortages earlier this year.</p>
<p>-- Ivan Mastagarkov, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-91188</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
