<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636501" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - June 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - June 4.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in Serbian and Montenegrin press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified them nor does it vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>			   - S E R B I A -</p>
<p>POLITIKA</p>
<p>- Yugoslav government determines draft amendements to the foreign trade law which will more efficiently control movement of goods and funds and adjust Yugoslav regulations to European Union standards.</p>
<p>- Yugoslav delegation at succession talks of the ex-Yugoslavia in Brussels insists on two key facts - beginning date for estimating division cannot be 1974 and there should be four end dates in line with the departure of the republics from the former federation.</p>
<p>- Bor copper mines and American company Volvo Euclid signed an agreement on a credit $3.2 million for the purchase of 170-190 tonne trucks.</p>
<p>- Serbia will reduce road tolls by 50 percent for foreign vehicles during the tourist season.</p>
<p>- Average pensions in Serbia are 20 percent higher than average wages and this is unsustainable for the economy, says economist Zoran Popov.</p>
<p>- Doctors and nurses reach an agreement in principle with Serbian government to stop strike if outstanding April wages are paid by the end of next week.</p>
<p>- Federal telecommunications ministry informed owners of radio and television stations that June 30 is the deadline to file legalisation documents if their stations are working without them.</p>
<p>- The prime defendant in the trial of 15 Kosovo Albanians which started Tuesday in Pristina Besim Rama admits to shooting at a police car on June 17 when one policeman was killed and another injured.</p>
<p>NASA BORBA</p>
<p>- Twelve Serbian opposition parties to sign an agreement on minimum election conditions. Two largest opposition parties Serbian Renewal Movement (SPO) and Serbian Radical Party (SRS) not to attend.</p>
<p>- Teachers seperate on end of strike, Belgrade high schools decide to continue. Schools in Vojvodina also join strike.</p>
<p>- The Serbian government to determine guaranteed wheat price on June 15.</p>
<p>- Democratic Party (DS) president and Belgrade mayor Zoran Djindjic said if his coalition partner SPO supports the radicals for his replacement as mayor the coalition would collapse.</p>
<p>POLITIKA EKSPRES</p>
<p>- There is pluralism of the Yugoslav media but also a frightening irresponsibility for the public word, says former information minister and member of SPS main board Ratomir Vico.</p>
<p>- Yugoslav army to sell its garages and use the 120 million dinars it expects to obtain for purchase of flats.</p>
<p>VECERNJE NOVOSTI</p>
<p>- The left will be united at the forthcoming republican and presidential elections and it still has not determined its presidential candidate, says SPS vice-president Milorad Vucelic in interview.</p>
<p>- We should exert pressure on the parties in power in Bosnia to implement the Dayton accord, says new Bosnia High Representative Carlos Westendorp in interview.</p>
<p>- Increasing number of homeless in Belgrade.</p>
<p>BORBA</p>
<p>- Serbia's bus factory Ikarbus and Germany's Mercedes sign cooperation deal on joint production and sale of buses.</p>
<p>		     - M O N T E N E G R O -</p>
<p>POBJEDA</p>
<p>- Montenegrin President Momir Bulatovic accused the state security service of illegally extorting a hard currency tax on cigarette trade in Montenegro.</p>
<p>- Montenegrin Prime Minister Milo Djukanovic said in Pljevlja on the border with Bosnia that the Montenegrin government would create conditions for the return of all those who have left their homes during the war.</p>
<p>- The republic's Montenegro airlines has a regular line to Bari in Italy and announces the opening of seven new lines. -- Belgrade newsroom +381 11 222 4305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
