<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636535" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: China's CNPC wins 60 pct of Kazakh Oil co.</title>
<headline>China's CNPC wins 60 pct of Kazakh Oil co.</headline>
<dateline>ALMATY 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kazakhstan said on Wednesday that the Chinese National Petroleum Company, or CNPC, had won a 60 percent stake in its large Aktyubinsk oil enterprise, with CNPC promising to pay $4.325 billion in investment and bonuses.</p>
<p>&quot;The inter-departmental commission for privatisation of the Republic of Kazakhstan, after considering competitors' offers, has chosen the Chinese National Petroleum Company as the winner of the tender,&quot; said a statement given to reporters by the ex-Soviet state's privatisation committee.</p>
<p>&quot;The overall value of the deal is $4.325 billion,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>U.S. oil majors Texaco Inc and Amoco Corp along with Russian company Yuzhny Most competed against CNPC in the tender. The committee said earlier that U.S. company Exxon dropped out of the competition.</p>
<p>Under the deal, CNPC has promised to invest $4 billion in the enterprise over the next 20 years, with $585 million to be invested from 1998 to 2003. CNPC will pay the Kazakh government a $320 million bonus along with a signing bonus of $5 million.</p>
<p>Located in the west of the Central Asian state, Aktyubinsk currently produces about 2.6 million tonnes of crude annually and has estimated reserves of about 483 million tonnes of oil. The contract also envisages the construction of a 3,000 km (2,000 miles) oil pipeline from the enterprise to China's troubled western province of Xinjiang.</p>
<p>The Kazakh government has said it aimed to finish by July 1 privatisation of the country's potentially rich but troubled oil industry in the teeth of opposition from the enterprises' Soviet era managers.</p>
<p>-- Chris Bird, Almaty Newsroom +7 3272 509410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
