<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636556" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: FOCUS-Brazil bond swap helps shed debtor stigma.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Brazil bond swap helps shed debtor stigma.</headline>
<byline>John Miller</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil took a big step toward freeing itself from the stigma of Latin America's 1980s debt crisis Wednesday when investors agreed to swap the nation's restructured U.S.-backed bonds for new uncollateralized bonds.</p>
<p>&quot;We became more friendly to big institutional savers as we restructured away from rescheduled debt,&quot; said Gustavo Franco, Brazilian Central Bank director for international affairs.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is always good to retire restructured debt,&quot; Franco told reporters in New York following the retirement of some $2.72 billion in Brady bonds in a swap for 30-year uncollateralized bonds.</p>
<p>Brady bonds, named after former U.S. Treasury Secretary Nicholas Brady, have been issued by emerging market nations to restructure commercial bank debt of the 1980s.</p>
<p>Brazil, along with Mexico and Argentina, led the pack of Latin American debtors that emerged from default status through the issue of Brady bonds since 1990.  </p>
<p>Wednesday's bond exchange essentially asked investors to give up their U.S. Treasury-backed Brady bonds for higher yielding bonds backed solely by the credit-worthiness of the Brazilian government.</p>
<p>Brazilian officials cheered the deal, saying it showed global investors were confident Brazil could stand behind its own long-term paper.</p>
<p>It also follows a credit upgrade earlier in the year by U.S. rating agency Standard &amp; Poor's Corp to BB-minus from B-plus, a move Brazilian officials said was long overdue.  </p>
<p>The bond swap retired only $2.71 billion of the nation's total $44 billion in Brady debt. But more important, analysts said, was the fact that investors jumped at the opportunity to buy long-term uncollateralized bonds from Brazil.</p>
<p>&quot;The major benefit was probably to define a long-dated benchmark for Brazil,&quot; said Kurt Schmid, head of proprietary trading at SBC Warburg in New York.  </p>
<p>The newly issued uncollateralized bond totaled $3.0 billion, the second largest 30-year bond in the market after Italy's $3.5 billion issue, according to Brazil's Central Bank.</p>
<p>Mexico carried out a similar Brady bond swap last year, but managed to sell only about $1.7 billion in new bonds.</p>
<p>&quot;We had over $16 billion in cash offers for the 30-year bond, which shows how interested investors were in the issue,&quot; said Linaldo Aguiar, head of the Brazilian Central Bank's foreign debt department.</p>
<p>Still, the deal was seen as the first step in a long-term plan to retire the collateralized debt.</p>
<p>&quot;This demand signals that there is further potential (for a swap), but that doesn't mean we would want to do something tomorrow,&quot; Aguiar said.</p>
<p>((-- Sao Paulo newsroom, 5511 248-5414))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
