<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636682" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuela oil stakes rise in second day of auction.</title>
<headline>Venezuela oil stakes rise in second day of auction.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuela netted $647 million in cash bids from private companies on Tuesday, the second day of its third round of operating agreement sales, bringing the total for two days to just under $1 billion with many of the biggest fields still to go under the hammer.</p>
<p>The size of some bids surprised some of the oilmen who came to Caracas in the hope of getting one of the contracts.</p>
<p>Venezuela is offering 20 contracts in its least desirable oilfields for private companies to reactivate, while state oil company Petroleos de Venezuela (PDVSA) concentrates on bigger projects.</p>
<p>The 20-year contracts also allow for some exploration near the existing fields, and it is here that the highest bidders saw the real opportunity in this round.</p>
<p>Tuesday's winning bids ranged from $46 million by a consortium by Pennzoil Co for the B2X.68/79 field in Lake Maracaibo to $330 million by Spain's Repsol SA for the Mene Grande field located just east of the lake.</p>
<p>Repsol beat its nearest rival by $141 million, and offered $325 million more than the lowest bid for the contract, illustrating how differently companies evaluated the exploration and technical risk.</p>
<p>Both B2X.68/79 and Mene Grande had about 100 million barrels of proven reserves. Repsol, which paid $3.30 per barrel of reserves, saw their returns coming from new exploration while Pennzoil, which paid 46 cents, saw it coming from existing reservoirs, delegates said.</p>
<p>One delegate said Repsol would have its job cut out just to get its money back within the 20 year contract, given their huge initial outlay and high exploration risk in such a well-explored field.</p>
<p>But Repsol's exploration manager, Salvador Castalla Pages, said he expected to find significant new deposits. &quot;We believe there is a big exploration potential and the reserves figures were a secondary consideration in our evaluation of the field,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>China's National Petroleum Corporation (CNPC) bid aggressively on two blocks and came away with the Intercampo contract for $118 million, with 200 million barrels of reserves. At 60 cents per proven barrel, this came in at the lower end of the day's ratings, delegates said.</p>
<p>Argentina's Perez Companc, which won one contract on Monday, beat the Chinese narrowly to get the La Concepcion contract, with 150 million barrels reserves, for $153 million.</p>
<p>PDVSA hopes production from the 20 fields in this round will reach 350,000 barrels per day in 10 years, from 67,000 barrels per day now -- part of its ambitious plan to double the country's 3 million barrels per day capacity.</p>
<p>Some delegates from the world's biggest oil companies were so shocked at the size of the winning bids they were considering pulling out altogether.</p>
<p>But other delegates said the size of bids and level of participation showed that Venezuela was taking off in terms of investment opportunities.</p>
<p>&quot;Venezuela is the Saudi Arabia of Latin America. The opportunities that I can see for this type of activity is unique to Venezuela,&quot; said Pennzoil Latin America chief Carl Evans.</p>
<p>((-- Caracas newsroom 582 505 2611))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
