<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636680" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Pre-election jitters force up Mexican rates.</title>
<headline>Pre-election jitters force up Mexican rates.</headline>
<byline>David Luhnow</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jitters ahead of Mexico's national elections and fears of higher U.S. interest rates pushed up Mexico's bellwether 28-day Cetes paper at Tuesday's weekly central bank auction.</p>
<p>Rates rose at the shorter end of the yield curve but fell very slightly in the one-year term.</p>
<p>The widely-watched one-month paper rose 99 basis points, slightly more than expected, to 19.30 percent. An earlier Reuters survey of money market dealers predicted a rise of 71 basis points in the 28-day paper.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was ready for this. Rates were coming off a low level and now that we're in June, people are looking at the elections and U.S. rates,&quot; said Scott Grimberg, an analyst at MMS International in New York.</p>
<p>The rate hike was sharper than last week's rise, which broke two weeks of falling rates that had pushed the yield on one-month paper down to 18.07 percent.</p>
<p>Demand fell slightly to 10.55 billion pesos from 12.7 billion the week before.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is showing nerves ahead of the elections,&quot; said Enrique Ramirez Mena, a money market analyst at Santander Investment in Mexico City.</p>
<p>&quot;The only rate that fell was the one year paper, which is pretty logical given a better long-term fundamental outlook once elections are over,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Mexicans go to the polls on July 6 to elect most of Congress, six state governors and, for the first time, a mayor of Mexico City.</p>
<p>Recent polls show President Ernesto Zedillo's Institutional Revolutionary Party might lose its majority in the lower house of Congress for the first time in seven decades.</p>
<p>Analysts said many investors have discounted a PRI loss in the lower house, but are not too worried because the most likely beneficiary will be the conservative National Action Party, whose economic policy is similar to that of Zedillo.</p>
<p>But recent gains by the leftist Party of the Democratic Revolution (PRD) have blurred the picture, causing some to wonder how big gains by the PRD could affect the government's economic goals of liberalisation and lower inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has not priced in a PRD victory,&quot; Grimberg said.</p>
<p>Adding to tension is the grim prospect of another hike in U.S. interest rates. The Federal Reserve is slated to meet on July 2 to set interest rate policy.</p>
<p>Grimberg said positive news on inflation, due out a day before next week's auction, could tame any further rises in short-term rates.</p>
<p>Investors will be watching the peso closely in the next few weeks to see how it reacts to pre-election nerves and April revised trade figures.</p>
<p>((--Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9565))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
