<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636658" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Six groups bid for Argentine post privatization.</title>
<headline>Six groups bid for Argentine post privatization.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Six groups bid Tuesday for a 30-year concession to run Argentina's national postal firm ENCOTESA, the company said late Tuesday in comments reported by the official news agency Telam Wednesday.</p>
<p>Three groups have a strong banking presence as many of ECONTESA's more than 6,000 branches could be turned into banking outlets, at a moment when competition is increasing in the Argentine banking sector.</p>
<p>Argentina, a country with relatively low banking penetration, witnessed a foreign buying spree of local banks last month.  </p>
<p>The winner will be the group that offers the highest fee for the ENCOTESA concession. All bidders must have the technical support of the official post office of a member country of the Universal Postal Union.</p>
<p>The result of the bidding will be announced July 28.</p>
<p>The bidding groups consist of five consortia, plus an Argentine construction company.</p>
<p>1 -- Local transport company TAC, local group Roman, and businessman Samuel Liberman with Germany's state post office as operator.  </p>
<p>2 -- Itron and Sideco -- controlled by local holding company Macri --, and local Banco de Galicia, with the British Post Office.</p>
<p>3 -- Local banking group Werthein and COINTEL, a holding that controls Telefonica de Argentina, with New Zealand Post.</p>
<p>Cointel is 50 percent owned by Telefonica de Espana, the operator of Telefonica de Argentina. The remaining 50 percent of Cointel is in the hands of Argentina's CEI Citicorp Holdings SA, which is about 40 percent indirectly owned by Citibank.  </p>
<p>4 -- Dutch group ING Bank-Cayman Islands Fund with the Dutch postal service.</p>
<p>5 - Argentine construction company Roggio with the Canadian Post Office acting as a consultant.</p>
<p>6 - Brazilian airline company Vasp and Argentine private postal firm Andreani with Italy's postal service.</p>
<p>Private Argentine post company OCA, owned by tycoon Alfredo Yabran, did not bid for ENCOTESA despite having bought the privatization prospectus for $50,000.</p>
<p>Arturo Puricelli, ENCOTESA's President, told reporters that OCA's withdrawal &quot;rebukes those who said this was a tender tailor-made for this group.&quot;</p>
<p>France's postal service, which had initially expressed interest in ENCOTESA's privatization, was also a last minute defector.</p>
<p>Communications Secretary German Kammerath said recent polls in France, won by new Socialist Prime Minister Lionel Jospin, &quot;prevented them (the French postal service) from assuming a definitive commitment.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Guillermo Hskel, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 541 318-0650))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
