<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636765" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK airlines to put aircraft back in air this week.</title>
<headline>HK airlines to put aircraft back in air this week.</headline>
<byline>Carrie Lee</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's two airlines said on Wednesday they expected their entire fleets of Airbus Industrie A330-300 aircraft to be flying again by this weekend after being grounded since May 24 with engine trouble.</p>
<p>Both Cathay Pacific Airways Ltd and Dragon Airlines Ltd (Dragonair) said their first A330-300s would resume service on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're confident that we will have the entire fleet flying by the weekend,&quot; Cathay engineering director Roland Fairfield told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;It is expected that all of Dragonair's A330s will be flying again normally by the end of this week,&quot; Dragonair said in a statement issued at the news conference.</p>
<p>Swire Pacific Ltd and Cathay Pacific together hold about 26 percent of Dragonair, whose major shareholder is China National Aviation Corp (CNAC). The airlines decided to resume the aircraft after testing and certification of modified engines, they said.</p>
<p>The two carriers suspended their entire fleets of A330-300s on May 24 after three inflight engine shutdowns on Cathay and a fourth on Dragonair raised questions about the reliability of the Rolls-Royce Plc Trent 700 engine.</p>
<p>Cathay sent out one of its Airbus aircraft fitted with modified engines on a test-flight on Wednesday. Fairfield said the test flight showed the integrity of the modifications to the Trent 700 engines.</p>
<p>&quot;The Hong Kong Civil Aviation Authority on Wednesday gave its approval for the Trent-powered A330 to resume normal commercial flights,&quot; Dragonair said in a statement.</p>
<p>Cathay said the French and British aviation authorities have also certified the engine modifications.</p>
<p>The problem, which was due to insufficient lubrication of a bearing in the engine's step-aside gearbox, has been rectified and the airline and regulatory authorities are satisfied that the modification is completely airworthy, Cathay said in a statement.</p>
<p>Cathay has 11 A330-300s and Dragonair has four.</p>
<p>Cathay said in statement it had operated at 85 to 90 percent of its capacity every day since the aircraft suspension, and had cancelled a total of 192 flights as of Wednesday.</p>
<p>Cathay chairman Peter Sutch said last week the grounding would slice between HK$120 million (US$15.5 million) and HK$150 million from the airline's bottom line this year.</p>
<p>The airline's director in corporate development, Antony Tyler, told the news conference that represented an estimated cost and the final figure would depend on a number of factors including the compensation they could obtain from Rolls-Royce.</p>
<p>Dragonair chief executive Stanley Hui said the aircraft suspension had incurred a net loss of about 10 percent of its normal available seating capacity.</p>
<p>He said Dragonair's loss would be far less than Cathay's estimated loss, and Dragonair would seek compensation from Rolls-Royce. He declined to elaborate.</p>
<p>(US$1=HK$7.74)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
