<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636715" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: INTERVIEW-Clark optimistic for new left line-up.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Clark optimistic for new left line-up.</headline>
<byline>Vernon Small</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand's opposition Labour leader Helen Clark on Thursday welcomed signals from the left wing Alliance grouping that it was prepared to join her party in a coalition government after the next election.</p>
<p>&quot;The Alliance is now being more explicit about its desire to support or be part of a change of government. It is a logical development under MMP and is to be welcomed as such,&quot; Clark told Reuters in a telephone interview.  </p>
<p>Before the 1996 election, the first held under German-style mixed member proportional (MMP) voting, the Alliance had called for Labour to outline the shape of a coalition before polling day, and had refused to strike a deal after the election.</p>
<p>But in talks after the October election, which saw a coalition centre-right government formed between the conservative National Party and nationalist New Zealand First, Labour and the Alliance achieved a new rapport.  </p>
<p>&quot;We had a reasonable agreement with them at the end of the coalition talks and it has moved on from there. As (Alliance leader) Jim Anderton has said, putting themselves outside having any role in government cost them support. They want to be relevant,&quot; Clark said.</p>
<p>In one recent opinion poll Labour support surged to 45 percent support, and with the Alliance's six percent backing they could potentially build a majority centre-left coalition.</p>
<p>The next election is due in 1999, but the ruling coalition has only a one seat majority in the single chamber parliament.  </p>
<p>Clark said she foresaw a general understanding on the centre-left before an election, but not a detailed programme.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there should be a campaign on a common programme. There are areas where there will continue to be significant differences, such as foreign investment, where Labour will continue to favour a reasonably open regime.&quot;</p>
<p>She said there would need to be agreement on a Budget strategy but other policy differences could be maintained.  </p>
<p>&quot;We should all learn from the mistakes National and New Zealand First have made in putting together a maximalist programme after the election and pretending the parties are of one mind around this programme.</p>
<p>&quot;We should look a bit more widely around the European models and probably go for governmental agreements which do not purport to have the parties in government agreeing on everything, because clearly they don't.&quot;</p>
<p>She said apart from the Budget strategy she was relatively relaxed about a junior partner in government pushing its own policies.  </p>
<p>&quot;I mean in foreign investment the Alliance should be free to push its own barrow. It is not going to pass through the Parliament, but I think it causes a lot of unnecesary problems if you stop people expressing a viewpoint they have.&quot;</p>
<p>Clark said Labour would accept either a minority government with Alliance support or a majority coalition.</p>
<p>&quot;Given their change of position both options must be on the table. I can personally, and the Labour Party can, live with either.&quot;</p>
<p>Clark ruled out a coalition deal with free-market Act, National or NZ First &quot;in its current form&quot;.  </p>
<p>She said NZ First, which won all five seats set aside for Maori in 1996, was likely to split.</p>
<p>&quot;From Maoridom I hear that the Maori members minus (Associate Treasurer Tuariki) Delamere are unhappy. NZ First is down to almost Maori support so what have the Maori members got to gain from staying in?&quot;</p>
<p>She said it was unlikely the current government would fall before 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;We know that bad and foolish governments can stagger on. So that has to be a possibility. Probably a strong one,&quot; Clark said.  </p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
