<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636807" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Sanwa Hong Kong unit securitises mortgages.</title>
<headline>Sanwa Hong Kong unit securitises mortgages.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sanwa International Finance said on Wednesday that it launched a U.S.-dollar denominated residential mortgage-backed securities issue to securitise a portion of the mortgage portfolio of Sanwa Finance Hong Kong.</p>
<p>The size of the issue is tentatively set at US$144 million, Sanwa said.</p>
<p>The issuer is Hong Kong Homes Funding Corp (1) Ltd, a special purpose vehicle incorporated in the Cayman Islands.</p>
<p>The notes, which mature in May 2017, were priced and re-offered at par.</p>
<p>They will float at 20 basis points over the three-month U.S. dollar London Interbank Offered Rate up to August 2007 and at 45 basis points over the three-month dollar LIBOR thereafter.</p>
<p>Fees are 12.5 basis points, split as 7.5 basis points for management and underwriting and five basis points for selling.</p>
<p>Listing will be in Luxembourg and there is a short first coupon.</p>
<p>The notes are 100 percent guaranteed by MBIA Insurance Corp and are expected to be rated AAA by Standard and Poor's Corp and Aaa by Moody's Investors Service.  </p>
<p>A passthrough cross-currency swap will be entered into between Hong Kong Homes Funding Corp (1) Ltd and Chase Manhattan Bank to convert the U.S. dollar proceeds raised from the issuance of the securities into Hong Kong dollars.</p>
<p>The securitised mortgage portfolio will generate Hong Kong-dollar cashflow and all future interest and principal payments to investors in U.S. dollars are covered by the swap.</p>
<p>Investors' interests on the notes will be effectively covered by MBIA's U.S. dollar note policy, Sanwa said.</p>
<p>The issue is the first cross-border AAA/Aaa-rated mortage-backed securities issue collateralized by residential mortgages originated in Hong Kong, Sanwa said.</p>
<p>Sanwa International Finance is the sole lead manager for the transaction. Sanwa Bank Hong Kong branch is the arranger.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843-6371 http://www.hk97.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
