<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636819" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul premier calls for arrest after beating death.</title>
<headline>Seoul premier calls for arrest after beating death.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's Prime Minister Koh Kun on Wednesday called for the speedy arrest of those responsible for the death of a man whom students have admitted they beat as a suspected police informer.</p>
<p>&quot;The Prime Minister has ordered a quick arrest of those connected to the death at Hanyang University,&quot; an official at his office said.  </p>
<p>It was not clear whether Koh's comments indicated that authorities had given a go-ahead to a police raid on the campus, where hundreds of left-wing members of the radical Hanchongryon student organisation are holed up.</p>
<p>Witnesses said police reinforcements were pouring in to streets around the campus, which was already ringed by helmeted riot officers.</p>
<p>In August last year, police staged a military-style assault on another Seoul campus to end violent protests led by the Hanchongryon.</p>
<p>A Hanchongryon leader admitted that a badly bruised corpse delivered to the Hanyang University teaching hospital on Wednesday was that of a man students had beaten during an interrogation in the night.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
