<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636933" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton firm on Weld as U.S. envoy to Mexico.</title>
<headline>Clinton firm on Weld as U.S. envoy to Mexico.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton plans to name Massachusetts Gov. William Weld as U.S. ambassador to Mexico despite the objections of powerful Sen. Jesse Helms and has assigned Secretary of State Madeleine Albright to salvage the nomination, the White House said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Clinton &quot;believes Secretary Albright can spend some time with Senator Helms and we'll be able to satisfy Senator Helms' concerns,&quot; White House spokesman Mike McCurry told reporters.</p>
<p>Helms, chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, startled diplomatic circles on Tuesday by announcing he would block Weld's nomination because &quot;he is a little loose with his lips sometimes and that sort of thing.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think that he is ambassador quality and neither do a great many of the conservatives and Republicans in the state of Massachusetts,&quot; the conservative North Carolina Republican told Fox News Channel.</p>
<p>Helms, whose committee must approve all ambassadorial nominees, said he objected to Weld's views on the use of marijuana as medicine, but he declined further criticism of his fellow Republican.</p>
<p>But McCurry said factional strife between the Republican right that Helms represents and the moderate wing to which Weld belongs seemed to be the main reason for the senator's obstructionism. &quot;It's more about Republican intermural politics than it is about diplomacy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Weld told reporters at the state capitol in Boston he was uncertain of his chances at being confirmed but looked forward to meeting senators and telling them why he wanted the job.</p>
<p>&quot;The more I think about it the more I'm looking forward to going down there and try and make a case for myself,&quot; he said. Asked for his assessment of his chances of being confirmed, Weld replied, &quot;I don't know. I'm going to make the best argument I can on why I would be qualified for the position.&quot;</p>
<p>He said it was his understanding that after the president formally submits the nomination &quot;then that would free me up to go down there and make courtesy calls, touch base with people who are friendly to the nomination and see what I can do.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
