<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="636964" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Efforts mount to block hasty tobacco pact.</title>
<headline>Efforts mount to block hasty tobacco pact.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Gail Appleson, Law Correspondent</p>
<p>Efforts are mounting by health groups, some congressmen and the White House to slow or perhaps even block tobacco negotiations from reaching a hasty settlement.</p>
<p>These moves come as state attorneys general and plaintiffs lawyers hope to return to the negotiating table next week with a proposal for the industry's consideration.</p>
<p>The timing is crucial as the date fast approaches for the first trial of a state's lawsuit against the industry to recoup Medicaid costs for smoking-related illnesses.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel more than cautiously optimistic. We've had some stumbling blocks but I see it moving forward, I don't see it falling apart,&quot; said Stanley Chesley, a prominent Cincinnati plaintiffs lawyer involved in the talks.</p>
<p>But many others were more pessimistic, including members of Congress who would decide the fate of any accord.</p>
<p>House Speaker Newt Gingrich said on Tuesday there was only a one-in-three chance that a broad settlement of tobacco-related lawsuits would be reached and then be approved by Congress.</p>
<p>The Georgia Republican said that was his personal opinion and that he set those odds because &quot;there's some very, very big issues still out there.&quot;</p>
<p>A total of 32 state attorneys general have sued cigarette makers in a bid to recoup health care costs of smokers and on Monday California's senate passed a law clearing the way for the state to join the battle.</p>
<p>A group of attorneys general, lawyers pressing individual and class-action cases and members of the health care industry began negotiating with tobacco officials in April in an effort to resolve mounting litigation against cigarette manufacturers in exchange for major health and monetary concessions.</p>
<p>Mississippi's case is scheduled to be the first to go to trial, on July 7, and the state's attorney general, Mike Moore, a key negotiator, hoped to know by next week whether a deal could be reached or if he should get ready for trial.</p>
<p>Moore and Richard Scruggs, a plaintiffs lawyer helping Mississippi and many other states, have been leading efforts to reach a deal before the Mississippi trial begins.</p>
<p>Scruggs has indicated a willingness to give in to certain industry demands -- including a bar on punitive damages, which are used to punish a defendant or deter similar conduct.</p>
<p>However, not all the attorneys generals agree and some say they would not approve any pact that would limit an individual's ability to sue the industry.</p>
<p>Another key adviser to the states predicted Wednesday that a settlement in the talks was not likely until a few the cases go to trial.</p>
<p>James Tierney, who is helping coordinate the states' legal efforts, said he believed the industry and its opponents were &quot;heading towards a settlement&quot; but warned it could take &quot;a couple of trials&quot; to make both sides willing to reach a deal.</p>
<p>&quot;That would make some of the people on my side more realistic if we lose a few, and it certainly will make them (the companies) more realistic (if the states win),&quot; Tierney, a former Maine attorney general, told a business gathering in that state.</p>
<p>Scruggs recently told the New York Times that he believed a plan could be presented to the industry without the participation of all states.</p>
<p>Chesley would not comment on whether a proposal would be offered without a full accord, but he told Reuters, &quot;I've never seen unanimous in anything ... Unanimous is nice but unanimous is difficult to achieve and I don't think unanimous is a key issue here.&quot;</p>
<p>Others involved in the talks said that no deal could win approval from the White House or Congress without the blessing of health groups.</p>
<p>Matthew Myers, executive vice president of the National Centre for Tobacco-Free Kids and the key negotiator for health groups, has opposed limitations on individuals' rights to sue.</p>
<p>&quot;Our position has been pretty clear and that is the right of an individual to seek just compensation can't be abridged,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;My purpose there (in negotiations) is not to make sure there's a deal. It's to make sure that if there is an agreement, it takes into account fully the public health community's interests and goals,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Indeed, Health and Human Services Secretary Donna Shalala has warned negotiators not to expect the White House to sign off immediately on any deal and White House spokesman Mike McCurry made similar comments on Monday.</p>
<p>On Tuesday anti-smoking lawmakers unveiled legislation to clamp down on secondhand smoke and curtail cigarette sales to minors and made it clear they will not agree to a deal granting wide immunity.</p>
<p>&quot;These bills make the settlement more specific. We don't want settlement at any cost. We want a settlement that's good for America, that's good for the public health of our nation,&quot; said Illinois Democratic Sen. Dick Durbin.</p>
<p>More scepticism is expected as a coalition of major health groups convenes in Washington on Thursday to begin drafting public health guidelines they want included in any settlement.</p>
<p>The effort will be led by former Surgeon General C. Everett Koop and former Food and Drug Administration head David Kessler.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
