<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="637020" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: On anniversary, White House defends MFN for China.</title>
<headline>On anniversary, White House defends MFN for China.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>On the eighth anniversary of the Tiananmen Square crackdown, the White House on Wednesday said China could &quot;turn in a much more dangerous direction&quot; if America were to deny favourable trade status to Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;The president is convinced that remaining engaged with them is a way to have some real impact on the kind of behaviour that was so tragically manifested at Tiananmen Square on this anniversary,&quot; White House spokesman Mike McCurry said.</p>
<p>In Beijing, families of students killed in China's 1989 crackdown on dissent marked the date by flocking to cemeteries to mourn those killed when troops stormed the square.</p>
<p>Clinton has announced his intention to grant China another one-year extension of Most Favoured Nation status, which gives Beijing favourable tariff treatment on its exports to the United States.</p>
<p>Considerable opposition to the move is brewing in Congress. Critics of Clinton's actions range across the political spectrum, from liberals angry about China's human rights record to conservatives upset about China's stance toward Taiwan and repression of religious freedom.</p>
<p>The situation has been further complicated by allegations that China funnelled money to U.S. political candidates during last year's campaign in an effort to buy influence in Washington.</p>
<p>House of Representatives Democratic leader Dick Gephardt of Missouri, a possible rival to Vice President Al Gore for the Democratic nomination for president in 2000, has announced his opposition to MFN for China this year.</p>
<p>McCurry laid out the case for granting China the trade status, saying that as China enjoys the benefits of commerce with democratic, market economies, &quot;they inevitably are going to see some of the impact of that system of doing business infiltrate and have some impact on their own society.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The alternative, of course, is to declare economic war on China, isolate them, suspend any kind of normal trade relations, suffer the consequences and, most likely, see China turn in a much more dangerous direction,&quot; McCurry said.</p>
<p>He said normal trade relations with China had never prevented the United States from raising human rights concerns and pressing &quot;very vigorously and aggressively in a variety of places to try to change the behaviour of the Chinese leadership.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
