<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="637000" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. networks earn $6.1 billion from advance ads.</title>
<headline>U.S. networks earn $6.1 billion from advance ads.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Benkoe</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The top four U.S. television networks have generated about $6.1 billion in advance advertising sales for the coming primetime season, reflecting a robust ad market even they keep losing audience share.</p>
<p>Most of the so-called &quot;upfront&quot; selling was wrapped up by Wednesday, with sales in line with industry expectations.</p>
<p>The upfront sales ended a frenetic three weeks that began when the networks took over venues like Carnegie Hall to unveil new shows and held glitzy parties for advertisers.</p>
<p>Ad executives and Wall Street analysts said the campaigns apparently worked. Advertisers were generally receptive to the new shows, leading to a healthy ad market that is about five percent higher than a year ago.</p>
<p>Last season's ratings winner, NBC Television, generated about $2.15 billion in primetime sales, versus $2 billion last season, said Larry Hoffner, president of NBC television sales.</p>
<p>ABC Television, which came in third last season in household audience share, generated $1.6 billion, compared with $1.5 billion last year, said Marvin Goldsmith, president of ABC television network sales.</p>
<p>Joe Abruzzese, president of CBS network television sales said CBS had about $1.25 billion in sales, up about $100 million. The total jumped to $1.81 billion when the sales of its Nagano Winter Olympics next year were included.</p>
<p>Fox Broadcasting posted about $1.1 billion versus about $960 million last year, said Jon Nesvig, president of Fox's national advertising TV sales.</p>
<p>ABC Television is a unit of the Walt Disney Co, NBC Television is owned by General Electric Co, CBS Television is part of Westinghouse Electric Corp, and Fox Broadcasting belongs to News Corp.</p>
<p>Industry officials attributed the good ad market to a strong U.S. economy, renewed consumer confidence and the long-held belief the networks can deliver mass audiences.</p>
<p>&quot;The reason (for the increase) is that there's a fairly strong economy and demand is fairly great,&quot; said Joel Segal, executive vice president at McCann Erickson, a unit of Interpublic Group of Cos. &quot;The networks are still the mass media and the only way to reach large audiences.&quot;</p>
<p>Nonetheless, the networks have continued to lose audience share to basic cable channels.</p>
<p>According to Cognizant Corp's Nielsen Media Research, the four networks had 62.1 percent audience share last season, down from 65.2 percent the previous year. Basic cable channels saw their audience share rise to 32.4 percent from 29.5 percent.</p>
<p>ABC, fighting to pull away from third place, will launch 10 new shows, including five new comedies and five dramas. To capitalize on the strength of the market, the network was first out of the gate last month in selling spots, Goldsmith confirmed to Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The other networks were not in a hurry,&quot; said Robert Igiel, executive vice president at Young &amp; Rubicam. &quot;They don't have as many programming problems.&quot;</p>
<p>NBC, led by a ratings powerhouse Thursday night lineup that includes &quot;Seinfeld&quot; and &quot;ER&quot;, was again the one to beat.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, you can't negate that NBC is the number one network,&quot; said Igiel. &quot;They have a very effective schedule.&quot;</p>
<p>The lineup includes a slew of comedies from Monday through Wednesday that are viewed as interchangeable.</p>
<p>But NBC has a challenge: It must come up with at least two comedy hits, especially as current hits get shopworn.</p>
<p>Observers and ad buyers are geared for knock-down confrontations, including NBC's sitcom hit, &quot;Third Rock from the Sun&quot; against ABC's &quot;Drew Carey Show&quot; on Wednesday at 2100 ET, and CBS's &quot;Chicago Hope&quot; versus NBC's &quot;Law &amp; Order&quot; the same night at 2200 ET.</p>
<p>Another time when hand-to-hand combat may arise is Friday night, when CBS will challenge ABC for the attention of young audiences from 2000 ET to 2200 ET.</p>
<p>As the season approaches and advertisers have placed their bets on shows in the hope of high ratings, &quot;There's always a sense of optimism...&quot; said Jessica Reif, an analyst at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>At the same time, she noted, network executives will be hard at work, trying to create buzz around their new shows.</p>
<p>But sometimes the buzz amounts to a fizzle.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year, there was a huge amount of hype for &quot;Spin City&quot; and it just did OK,&quot; she added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
