<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="637120" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S bonds could sink if wrong on BLS jobs revision.</title>
<headline>U.S bonds could sink if wrong on BLS jobs revision.</headline>
<byline>Steven Scheer</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Expectations for a weak May U.S. payrolls figure helped fuel the latest Treasury rally, but players warned that the market is getting way ahead of itself and risks a big correction should the data come in strong.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is lulled into a false sense of security thinking (payrolls) will be weaker,&quot; said Richard Gilhooly, Treasury market strategist at Paribas Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is asymetrically biased for a weaker number. But if it is strong, there is a lot of downside,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Treasury market participants are largely positioned for a Friday report of a non-farm payroll gain of about 175,000 to 200,000 in May, a figure that was reduced from about 275,000 to 300,000 after the Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) last week revised its May seasonal adjustment factors to smooth the impact of inflow of student workers in May.</p>
<p>But while traders figured that the BLS adjustment translates into about a 100,000 reduction from earlier forecasts, only a handful of economists lowered predictions that much, with most cutting their estimates by 10,000 to 25,000, if at all.  </p>
<p>Since last Wednesday's close, Treasury yields have fallen 10 to 18 basis points across the curve, with the two-year note down to 6.20 percent and the 30-year bond to 6.88 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is trading like it is pricing in an (Federal Reserve) ease,&quot; said Bill Kirby, co-head trader at Prudential Securities Inc, half jokingly.</p>
<p>Although not all of the rally was due to the new market view on payrolls, players said expectations of a weaker number -- and in turn, expectations of less need for further tightening by the Fed -- played a big part.  </p>
<p>&quot;I am surprised at how the market seemed to glom on to it,&quot; said Douglas Schindewolf, money market economist at Smith Barney Inc. &quot;(The BLS) is not changing the reality that the job market is very tight.&quot;</p>
<p>Indeed, analysts said that the results of the BLS adjustments will lead the market to interpret a payroll increase of 200,000 as a strong gain, which many may read as a 300,000 gain. And, a 300,000 rise could be understood as a 400,000 gain without the seasonal factor adjustments.  </p>
<p>&quot;The May seasonal adjustment factor is the most agressive on record for May. So, logically, it should dampen the reported increase,&quot; Schindewolf said. &quot;But to read softness into the number would be a mistake.&quot;</p>
<p>The initial market reaction may rest squarely on the reported payrolls, but traders said average hourly earnings, the unemployment rate and hours worked will garner much attention -- partly because deciphering the payroll number may prove too difficult.  </p>
<p>&quot;If we get a hint of strength in the economy the market will do worse, and if the market reads it as weakness, the market will do better,&quot; Kirby said.</p>
<p>But how far a rally or selloff will go is tough to predict, traders said. The upside is seen more limited than the downside, especially with the Federal Reserve meeting in early July.</p>
<p>&quot;The market seems like it's getting a bit steamy,&quot; Kirby said. &quot;And with a good chance the Fed will raise rates, then if you have two-year notes at 6.10-6.12 percent, that's pretty pricey with 5-3/4 percent funds.&quot;</p>
<p>Gilhooly suspects that much of the &quot;good news&quot; has already been factored into the market, which would limit its reaction should the market get it right.</p>
<p>But, a &quot;neutral&quot; number would be slightly negative because the market is looking for weakness, he added.</p>
<p>Yet others are not so sure. The National Association of Purchasing Management's May manufacturing survey on Monday had a strong tenor, but the market -- after falling early -- ended the day higher.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in one of those times where the tone is good,&quot; Schindewolf said, &quot;and the market will find a silver lining in just about anything.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1867))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
