<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="637323" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Top U.N. official says &quot;radical reform&quot; in works.</title>
<headline>Top U.N. official says &quot;radical reform&quot; in works.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior United Nations official said on Wednesday a radical reform programme was being studied which would reshape and rationalise operations of the world body's humanitarian and development agencies.</p>
<p>Maurice Strong, under-secretary general leading a task force working on the reform blueprint, also left open the possibility that some U.N. bodies and even regional offices might disappear if the organisation's 185-member governments approved the plan.</p>
<p>But he told a news conference the aim of the programme was not &quot;to slash and burn, to cut meat off the bone&quot;, but to make the U.N. more effective to better serve the majority of its members, whom he defined as the developing countries.</p>
<p>His group, which includes heads of all leading agencies in the U.N. system, would be presenting Secretary-General Kofi Annan with &quot;some fairly radical proposals&quot; by the end of the month for the plan Annan will announce on July 16.</p>
<p>&quot;This will be the first time any secretary-general has himself put up a comprehensive reform programme...This is a unique opportunity to do the kinds of things the U.N. has needed for years, that will improve and strengthen it,&quot; Strong said.</p>
<p>The remarks by Strong, a Canadian who has long worked in the U.N. system and who set up the 1992 &quot;Earth Summit&quot; in Rio de Janeiro, provided the first public confirmation from Annan's entourage of some of the measures under consideration.</p>
<p>Earlier this week Carol Bellamy, head of the New York--based U.N. Childrens' Fund (UNICEF), voiced concern that her agency might be swallowed up in an overarching new body in a measure that she said would undermine its effectiveness.</p>
<p>Strong, hinting displeasure over her decision to go public on ideas he said she had agreed as part of his team to keep under wraps until presented to Annan, said nothing would be done to damage UNICEF, &quot;one of the very best (agencies) of the U.N.&quot;</p>
<p>But he confirmed that a key proposal under consideration was giving an overall coordination role for humanitarian affairs to the Geneva-based office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, the UNHCR, headed by the respected Sadako Ogata of Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;UNHCR has become de facto the lead humanitarian agency in the system. It is that, whether you want it or not...The interfaces between refugees and others needing humanitarian assistance are very much harder to define nowadays,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Recognising this reality would not require folding other agencies such as UNICEF and the Rome-based World Food Programme (WFP) into a new body, but would make it possible to strengthen coordination of emergency relief, he added.</p>
<p>Strong also indicated that his team was considering proposing the dissolution of the New York-based Department of Humanitarian Affairs (DHA), whose functions often overlap with those of other U.N. bodies.</p>
<p>A single body for relief and development agencies was very unlikely, he said. &quot;What is likely is a common framework within which each of these would be able to bring their responsabilities to bear,&quot; sharing services and facilities.</p>
<p>Strong said the reform process was not driven by pressure from the U.S. Congress which has been holding back approval for payment of contributions, although he acknowledged this had created problems.</p>
<p>&quot;But the U.N. needs reform for its own sake,&quot; he said. &quot;We believe that if the U.N. does not reform itself now, it will be changed by the Helms' of this world, and in the wrong way.&quot;</p>
<p>He was referring to U.S. Senator Jesse Helms, chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee and a bitter critic of the world body.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
