<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="637339" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: U.S. firm sees new hi-tech devices getting smaller.</title>
<headline>U.S. firm sees new hi-tech devices getting smaller.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Neil Winton, Science and Technology Correspondent</p>
<p>Miniaturisation is the key to developments in forthcoming new personal communications devices, according to Silicon Valley high tech company VSLI Technology Inc.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters, VSLI President and Chief Operating Officer Richard Beyer said smaller than ever chips will allow the information techology industry to provide a mind-boggling array of new products.</p>
<p>&quot;The shrinking size of chips - with current technology able to cram tens of millions of transistors on to centimetre-square chips - reduces the size of personal communications devices to handheld and, in the near future, to lapel pin size,&quot; Beyer said.</p>
<p>Beyer said products in the future will allow finger nail-sized devices implanted in the ear, with radio communication, to instantly translate languages and allow normal conversation between people with no knowledge of each others' languages.</p>
<p>Tiny medical devices implanted in the body will allow instant diagnosis of problems like heart attacks and automatically offer mitigating treatment.</p>
<p>&quot;In the last 20 years computing power which would take a whole room full of equipment, crammed with people and climate controlled, would be needed for tasks which can now be done with a lap-top computer. Soon these circuits will be able to be reduced to the size of an infant's finger nail,&quot; said Beyer.</p>
<p>&quot;We will see an enormous increase in computing and communications power at exceptionally low prices with very low power requirements leading to easy portability.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Twenty years ago, you only saw the cellphone in the hands of presidents or military leaders. They would be surrounded by aides and have the equipment packed on to a truck. Now it has been miniaturised to hand-held size. Soon it will be the size of a finger-nail.&quot;</p>
<p>VLSI is based in San Jose, California, and makes chips used in communications, digital entertainment, and to a declining degree, personal computers. Last year its sales totalled $717 million, and it made a net loss of $49.5 million after a charge of $116 million mainly due to the personal computer business.</p>
<p>For several years the company has been undergoing a transition out of the computer chip business and into more profitable areas like wireless communications and TV set-top boxes.</p>
<p>Beyer was in Brussels to address a Wall Street Journal Europe sponsored conference.</p>
<p>&quot;If the last half of the 20th Century was dominated by a continuing revolution in computer technology, I'm convinced that the first half of the 21st century will witness a personal communications revolution with the development of low-cost, high performance intelligent integrated circuits,&quot; Beyer said.</p>
<p>Products to be expected include -</p>
<p>*Personal communications devices linked by satellite which allow real time navigation.</p>
<p>*Wireless personal entertainment centres, combining satllite TV receiver, Internet browser and telephone.</p>
<p>*Electronic wallets connected to banks allowing access to bank account data and the loading of cash.</p>
<p>--Neil Winton 44-171-542-7975 neil@jinks.demon.co.uk</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
