<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="637342" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Stockholm stock exchange/OM may resume merger talk.</title>
<headline>Stockholm stock exchange/OM may resume merger talk.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Futures and derivatives exchange OM Gruppen AB said on Wednesday it could resume merger talks with the Stockholm Stock Exchange when the government representative's task had been clarified.</p>
<p>The government has appointed deputy Riksbank governor Stefan Ingves as its representative, saying it wants to keep a hold in one of the core businesses of the financial sector.</p>
<p>The government has proposed to use 500 million crowns from a possible sale of its shares in central securities depository VPC to buy such a stake but it has not given further details.</p>
<p>OM and the stock exchange are waiting to find out what the government's intentions are but still see a merger as beneficial.</p>
<p>&quot;As in all situations like this there are different opinions but there is still a common view that a merger of the stock exchange and OM would be good,&quot; OM's chairman Olof Stenhammar told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The interruption (of negotiations) should more be seen as a time-out and we will look at the conditions again later.&quot;</p>
<p>The groups will contact Ingves when it has been made clear what task he has, Stenhammar said.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now it is an open matter how the government sees its ownership role,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ownership issues were an important reason behind the failed merger negotiations, Stenhammar said.</p>
<p>&quot;OM is strong on its own,&quot; he said. &quot;We have taken the intitiative all along as we believe a merger or cooperation would be good.</p>
<p>&quot;Some owners of the stock exchange have wanted to have more control over a merged OM/stock exchange -- and it is not the stock exchange itself which has pushed for this.&quot;</p>
<p>Talks about merging the Stockholm Stock Exchange and OM began last November but the two groups, both of which are listed, announced earlier on Wednesday that negotiations had ended for the time being.</p>
<p>-- Jorgen Osterberg, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
