<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="637432" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan army chief vows answer to India missiles.</title>
<headline>Pakistan army chief vows answer to India missiles.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Army chief General Jehangir Karamat said on Wednesday that Pakistan must develop an &quot;indigenous capability&quot; to meet a perceived missile threat from neighbouring arch-rival India.</p>
<p>The general, quoted by the official APP news, made the statement in a speech at the Naval War College in Lahore, capital of Punjab province.</p>
<p>He was referring to a U.S. newspaper report that India had moved some of its medium-range Prithvi missiles to a prospective launch site near the border.</p>
<p>APP quoted Karamat as saying &quot;in the absence of reassurances, we would have no option but to go ahead with the development of our indigenous capability&quot;.</p>
<p>He said the missile deployment and a recent alleged violation of Pakistan's airspace by an Indian aircraft seemed to be &quot;deliberate policy decisions and would inevitably influence our response and the overall efforts for peace&quot;.</p>
<p>Pakistan voiced serious concern on Tuesday on the alleged deployment, reported by the Washington Post in Tuesday's editions, and said the move could trigger &quot;a dangerous ballistic arms race&quot; in South Asia.</p>
<p>The United States on Tuesday declared itself in &quot;outright opposition&quot; to the deployment of ballistic missiles by India and Pakistan, and said it was working to prevent such a move.</p>
<p>U.S. State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns, speaking at a news briefing in Washington, refused to confirm that India had moved such weapons to a prospective launch site.</p>
<p>The Washington Post report said U.S. intelligence agencies had concluded that less than a dozen missiles were now located near the city of Jullundur in the state of Punjab in northwest India.</p>
<p>Karamat said Pakistan's army had developed indigenous capabilities to ensure operational readiness and would &quot;restructure to maintain effectiveness&quot; without increasing defence expenditure.</p>
<p>&quot;Our assertive defence in Siachen and on the line of control (in Kashmir) is a manifestation of this resolve,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He was referring to several years of confrontation between the two sides on the disputed 20,000-foot (6,100-metre) high Siachen glacier, the world's highest battlefield, and the military control line dividing the disputed Himalayan region of Kashmir.</p>
<p>The Prithvi missiles currently are capable of carrying conventional but not nuclear warheads.</p>
<p>There have been repeated reports that Pakistan obtained M-11 missiles from China, which Islamabad denies, but Burns said Washington still had not decided that actual deployment of the Indian missiles had taken place.</p>
<p>Pakistan and India have fought three wars since their independence from Britain in 1947, two of them over Kashmir.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
