<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63750" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria's AIICO sees income rising.</title>
<headline>Nigeria's AIICO sees income rising.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>AIICO Insurance Plc, one of Nigeria's leading insurance firms, on Thursday said its income was poised to rise as gains from past investments fell due.</p>
<p>&quot;Our investment income is sure to go up in the third quarter when we put into consideration gains from our investments in the capital market,&quot; said company secretary Aderemi Awosanmi.</p>
<p>The company's result for the first half of 1996 showed a drop in investment income to 64.1 million naira from 86.5 million in the corresponding period of 1995.</p>
<p>Gross premium was, however, up at 379 million naira, against 261.3 million naira in 1995.</p>
<p>One stockbroker told Reuters the fall in investment income was partly due to the drop in interest rates in the country's money market.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest rates have fallen to 15 percent and may drop further as the PTF (Petroleum Trust Fund) releases more money into the economy,&quot; said Niyi Opeodu of Lead Investments Ltd.</p>
<p>The fund was set up by the military rulers in 1994 to cushion the blow of a four-fold increase in domestic fuel prices by investing the gains in public infrastructure.</p>
<p>Awosanmi said: &quot;Investment income has dropped in view of low yields on deposits.&quot;</p>
<p>The maximum lending rate is officially fixed at 21 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We have withdrawn from the money market and have moved into the capital market where we are at least assured of good return on our investment,&quot; Awosanmi said.</p>
<p>Analysts said most insurance firms had lost huge sums in Nigeria's troubled money market in the last three years, especially in finance companies that had since folded up.</p>
<p>AIICO's pre-tax profit in the period was 22.2 million naira compared to 15.4 million naira last year, a good result in view of the tough operating environment, according to analysts.</p>
<p>The company had been able to plough back retained earnings into profitable investment, Tunde Ayeni, an analyst at CSL Stockbrokers, said.</p>
<p>&quot;Any company showing an improvement over last year's result should be commended,&quot; Ayeni said.</p>
<p>Net profit rose to 20 million naira to end-June 1996 from 11.5 million naira in the corresponding period of 1995.</p>
<p>Awosanmi said AIICO's management would ensure prudent investments and a better result in the second half of 1996.</p>
<p>The company, owned by Nigerians and American Life Insurance Company (ALICO) of the U.S., was rewarded with a 10 kobo gain on the Nigerian stock market on Thursday. It ended at 6.00 naira.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
