<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="637837" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Treasuries drift lower in London, await key data.</title>
<headline>Treasuries drift lower in London, await key data.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries dipped lower in London in slim volumes on Wednesday, with little to shift the market before payrolls data on Friday.</p>
<p>Traders had expected comments from Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan at the International Monetary Conference in Switzerland to provide a diversion but he pulled out of the news conference because of travel arrangements.</p>
<p>&quot;There's very little going on,&quot; a trader at a U.S. bank in London said. &quot;There's been a little bit of liquidation from some accounts out of Japan.&quot;</p>
<p>At 1015 GMT, the long bond was quoted at 96-22, down from 96-27 in Tokyo and 96-29 at the close in New York on Tuesday.</p>
<p>September T-bond futures were quoted at 110-01, down 2/32 in automated trade.</p>
<p>Greenspan was due attend a news briefing with Bank of France Governor Jean-Claude Trichet at the IMC.</p>
<p>April factory orders at 1400 GMT, were expected to have risen 0.8 percent after a 1.6 percent drop in March but the real focus for the market would be May payrolls on Friday.</p>
<p>Economists have revised down their payroll estimates after the Bureau of Labor Statistics changed its seasonal adjustment factors on the data.</p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters now expected jobs growth of 219,000 for the month compared to an initial consensus of 221,000.</p>
<p>Mark Henry, analyst at GNI Ltd in London, said the unemployment rate would be key for the market after the drop in April to a 24-year low of 4.9 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;If we see that kind of level again Treasuries will look closely at it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the market was still likely to turn defensive ahead of the data after robust figures from the National Association of Purchasing Management and recent strong consumer confidence data.</p>
<p>--Jacqueline Thorpe, International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
