<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="637986" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Holbrooke expected to be new U.S. Cyprus envoy.</title>
<headline>Holbrooke expected to be new U.S. Cyprus envoy.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Clinton administration is expected to announce the appointment of Richard Holbrooke, who negotiated a Bosnia peace agreement, as new presidential emissary to Cyprus, U.S. officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The officials, who asked not to be identified, said an announcement was expected later in the day.</p>
<p>Holbrooke would replace Richard Beattie, who was named last month by Secretary of State Madeleine Albright as her adviser on incorporating three foreign affairs agencies into the State Department.</p>
<p>Holbrooke, noted for his tough bargaining style, made his name by negotiating the 1995 Dayton peace agreement which ended a 43-month civil war in Bosnia.</p>
<p>In February last year he resigned as assistant secretary of state and took a job with Credit Suisse First Boston bank in New York, which he still holds.</p>
<p>Shortly before that he had been due to make a push to resolve the long-standing Cyprus dispute but abandoned the attempt after a fresh outbreak of tension between Greece and Turkey over Aegean issues.</p>
<p>Albright, who took office in January, has said several times that Cyprus will be one of her priorities.</p>
<p>Officials said Holbrooke was expected to bring a new vigour to tackling the Cyprus problem. &quot;I think that with Holbrooke there will be serious attention and movement. Look at what he did in Bosnia,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an important problem and this is obviously someone who has quite a track record in solving difficult negotiating problems,&quot; another official said. &quot;President Clinton has said for some time he wanted to adress the Cyprus issue and he has great confidence in ambassador Holbrooke.&quot;</p>
<p>Leaders of the Greek and Turkish Cypriot communities are to hold U.N.-sponsored talks next month on how to reunite the island, divided after a Turkish invasion in 1974.</p>
<p>President Glafcos Clerides, as Greek Cypriot leader, and Turkish Cypriot leader Rauf Denktash, who heads a Turkish Cypriot breakaway state in northern Cyprus recognised only by Ankara, are to meet in New York in their first face-to-face encounter for nearly three years.</p>
<p>Some 30,000 Turkish troops are stationed in northern Cyprus, occupied in 1974 in response to a brief Greek Cypriot coup engineered by the military then ruling Greece.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
