<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638037" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Eastern Canada, New England to target industries.</title>
<headline>Eastern Canada, New England to target industries.</headline>
<dateline>NEWPORT, Rhode Island 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Quebec's premier Lucien Bouchard Tuesday proposed Eastern Canada and New England explore targeting industries to develop synergies.</p>
<p>Bouchard, noting the private sector would be involved in the effort, said, &quot;While companies have already initiated strategies dealing with the integration of the northeastern region, there is reason to review the initiatives in which we participate to promote and deepen the integration...to position the region more effectively.&quot;</p>
<p>He addressed the Annual Conference of the New England Governors and Eastern Canadian Premiers.</p>
<p>A resolution, which was approved, urged targeting industries with the greatest potential for synergistic development.</p>
<p>The sectors that would be aided might include energy, including natural gas and petroleum, transportation equipment and services, information technology and telecommunications, and environmental equipment and services, the Quebec premier said.</p>
<p>Bouchard, who noted Quebec already has strategic alliances with several New England states, said the analysis of what could be further steps could be taken by the region would be assisted at a series of planned conferences over the next year or so.</p>
<p>The effort aims to find ways to reduce or eliminate obstacles to trade, boost the region's competitiveness in target sectors, perhaps by opening up public procurement or harmonizing some administrative practices, and improving the zone's means of transport and communication.</p>
<p>Technological, commercial and industrial partnerships that would be favored also are envisioned, along with working out a way to favor them, he explained.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, U.S. Municipal Desk</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEWPORT, Rhode Island"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
