<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638069" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Texas executes serial rapist convicted of murder.</title>
<headline>Texas executes serial rapist convicted of murder.</headline>
<dateline>HUNTSVILLE, Texas 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A serial rapist convicted of murdering a Houston woman in 1986 was executed by injection at the Huntsville State Prison in Texas on Tuesday, a prison spokesman said.</p>
<p>Kenneth Harris, 34, was sentenced to die for the murder of Lisa Stonestreet, a legal secretary who lived next door to Harris and was found strangled and drowned in the bathtub of her apartment in June 1986, prosecutors said.</p>
<p>The execution was the second of a record 11 set for Texas in June. It was the 18th in the state this year and the 125th since capital punishment resumed here in December 1982.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sorry for all the pain I have caused both families, my family and yours. I would like for you to know that I am sorry for all the pain I caused all these years ... I am ready, warden,&quot; Harris said to his relatives and members of the victim's family who witnessed the execution.</p>
<p>He was injected with a dose of chemicals and died shortly after 6 p.m. CDT (2300 GMT).</p>
<p>Harris was arrested and charged with murder after his fingerprints were found in Stonestreet's apartment, which had been ransacked and robbed. Police also found Harris' palm print on the victim's car, which was stolen and set on fire five days after her body was found, prosecutors said.</p>
<p>Stonestreet was reported missing by co-workers after she failed to show up for work at the Vinson and Elkins law firm. Police found her nude body draped face down over the tub, with her head submerged in about eight inches of water (20 cm).</p>
<p>Prosecutors said Harris committed at least five other rapes and robberies in the Houston area between December 1985 and July 1986, when he was arrested and charged with Stonestreet's murder.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HUNTSVILLE, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
