<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638182" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy to send ex-CIA agent to trial for crime ring.</title>
<headline>Italy to send ex-CIA agent to trial for crime ring.</headline>
<dateline>NAPLES, Italy 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former CIA agent and 64 other people, including financiers from across Europe, will stand trial as part of an investigation into an international crime ring, Italian state prosecutors said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Alfredo Ormanni, chief prosecutor of the southern town of Torre Annunziata, near Naples, said former U.S. Central Intelligence Agency officer Roger d'Onofrio and the others would face charges of money laudering, false accounting and producing fake government bonds, which were distributed throughout Europe.</p>
<p>The date for the first hearing was not immediately known.</p>
<p>The two-year-old investigations, dubbed the &quot;cheque-to-cheque&quot; probe, caused a storm in 1995 when Ormanni asked to question Barcelona's Roman Catholic archibishop Ricardo Maria Carles over allegations he helped launder $65 million through the Vatican Bank.</p>
<p>Spanish authorities said later they had found no proof that Carles had been involved in the crime ring.</p>
<p>D'Onofrio, a 73-year-old retired CIA agent with dual U.S.-Italian citizenship, was arrested a month later on suspicion of using CIA contacts to help the crime ring launder money and traffick in arms, drugs and radioactive materials.</p>
<p>He was later granted house arrest on account of his age.</p>
<p>Russian ultra-nationalist Vladimir Zhirinovsky, a candidate for the 1996 presidential elections, was also investigated in connection with the ring, but neither he nor Bishop Carles were among those named by prosecutors on Wednesday to stand trial.</p>
<p>Prosecutors said other defendants included accountants, bankers and public officials from a number of countries who are suspected of helping to maintain the network across Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAPLES, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
