<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638141" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German parliament rejects motion to sack Waigel.</title>
<headline>German parliament rejects motion to sack Waigel.</headline>
<byline>Tom Heneghan</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chancellor Helmut Kohl's majority in parliament beat back an opposition motion on Wednesday to sack Finance Minister Theo Waigel over his bid to force the Bundesbank help Germany qualify for a single euro currency.</p>
<p>The centre-right coalition, deeply split over ways to fill gaping budget gaps to meet the Maastricht treaty criteria properly, mustered 328 votes against 311 for the opposition after Kohl threw his weight fully behind the struggling minister.</p>
<p>But Waigel had to struggle to save face after backing off on Tuesday from his grab for Bundesbank gold following strong resistance from the central bank and a threatened revolt by government deputies unwilling to risk a backlash from voters by supporting such a widely-criticised move.</p>
<p>Now back to foraging for extra funds, Kohl and Waigel both said Bonn would meet the three percent deficit-to-gross domestic product target for European economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>Waigel suggested further spending cuts and privatisations to raise 19 billion marks ($11 billion) to keep its 1997 budget on target.</p>
<p>&quot;A delay (in EMU) would have an enormous impact on financial markets and the German economy's chances in the export market,&quot; Kohl said. &quot;The German government will keep firmly to the timetable and criteria for currency union.&quot;</p>
<p>The stormy debate, punctuated by jeering and name-calling which one deputy said reminded him of Nazi-style debating tactics, came amid rising calls for Waigel's head.</p>
<p>Apart from the opposition parties, even the influential business daily Handelsblatt said Waigel now had to quit after his move for the gold shook the credibility of Bonn's preparations for EMU but failed to procure the much-needed funds this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Waigel did not get one step closer to fulfilling his aim to meet the Maastricht criteria,&quot; it wrote. &quot;There is no way around it. The only thing left for Waigel to do is resign.&quot;</p>
<p>In a fighting mood, Waigel said he and Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer had agreed a common approach to revalue bank assets and to pay out extra profits next year.</p>
<p>But apart from saying no gold would be sold, Waigel gave few details of the agreement, which he said was still under discussion with the influential central bank.</p>
<p>Quoting the terms of what he and Tietmeyer agreed on Tuesday, he said, &quot;There will be a serious attempt to seek a mutually acceptable solution that will permit a revaluation of certain assets in the year 1997 with a pay-out (of resulting profits) to take effect in 1998.&quot;</p>
<p>Details of an agreement would still have to be worked out with the Bundesbank and then discussed by the bank's council and the Bonn cabinet, Kohl added.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer said on Tuesday evening his urgent talks with Waigel earlier that day did not deal with Germany's gold reserves. The Bundesbank stressed on Wednesday that no formal agreement had yet been made.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer, swamped by journalists while at a banking conference in Interlaken, Switzerland, said: &quot;I have the impression that we can find a solution. Whether it needs some change of Bundesbank laws must be investigated.&quot;</p>
<p>The confusion over what the two men agreed dominated the debate and opposition deputies accused Waigel of trying to fool the public by suggesting an agreement when one was not there.</p>
<p>&quot;All you've said is that you'll make an effort,&quot; Greens deputy Werner Schulz barked at Waigel. &quot;There is no agreement at all.&quot;</p>
<p>Kohl and Waigel also proclaimed unchanged respect for the independence of the Bundesbank in monetary affairs but the chancellor pointedly noted it must in turn respect parliament. The legislature has the power to alter Bundesbank statutes.</p>
<p>Waigel said he had imposed a spending freeze, requiring all new spending and expenditures over one million marks to have his personal approval, and Bonn would make extra savings and privatisation efforts to finance the 1997 budget properly.</p>
<p>Opposition Social Democrat (SPD) chairman Oskar Lafontaine, heartened by recent left-wing successes in Britain and France, accused Kohl of failing to support a European-wide initiative to create jobs, saying: &quot;Europe must be a Europe in which its citizens have access to employment.&quot;</p>
<p>Although Lafontaine spoke out for a punctual euro launch, his main SPD rival, Gerhard Schroeder, called in an interview for a delay in starting EMU to allow the qualification criteria to be kept.</p>
<p>Under Waigel's original plan, which the government announced with Kohl's full approval following the Bundesbank's &quot;no&quot; last week, parliament was supposed to change the bank's statutes to have it revalue its underpriced gold and currency reserves and pay Bonn 20 billion marks in windfall profits.</p>
<p>($ = 1.731 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
