<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638233" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Aramco improves offer for Petrogal stake - papers.</title>
<headline>Aramco improves offer for Petrogal stake - papers.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi Aramco, which has held talks in recent months to buy a stake in Portuguese state oil company Petrogal, has boosted its offer, paving the way for a possible outline agreement by end-June, Lisbon newspapers reported.</p>
<p>Diario Economico said it had learned that Saudi Aramco had raised its offer following a revaluation of Petrogal by J.P.Morgan based on its 1996 accounts, which valued the Portuguese oil company at at least 230 billion escudos.</p>
<p>Newspapers did not give details of the offer.</p>
<p>Under-Secretary for Energy Jose Penedos told Diario Economico: &quot;Conditions have been created to reach an outline agreement by the end of June.&quot;</p>
<p>Petrogal shareholders were expected to meet on Thursday to consider Saudi Aramco's offer.</p>
<p>Diario Economico and Diario de Noticias said that the revaluation of Petrogal did not account for a recent substantial offshore oil find in northern Angola by a consortium that includes Petrogal.</p>
<p>Sources involved in the talks have said that Saudi Aramco could take a stake of around 35 percent in Petrogal.</p>
<p>A private shareholders' group Petrocontrol would hold another 35 percent, the state 10 percent, and 20 percent would be floated on Lisbon bourse.</p>
<p>Government officials were not immediately available to comment on the newspaper report.</p>
<p>-- Lisbon newsroom +351-1-3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
