<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638259" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Coffee industry bullish on gourmet market growth.</title>
<headline>Coffee industry bullish on gourmet market growth.</headline>
<byline>Maja Wallengren</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading coffee industry officials meeting in the Austrian capital this week have expressed hope towards seeing high growth rates in the market of specialty and gourmet coffees.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a real big trend of selling unblended coffees from origin countries. The consumers get excited that they can taste the original product,&quot; said Ted Lingle, executive director of the Specialty Coffee Association of America.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a very strong demand for good quality coffees and there is a great potential for expansion in that market,&quot; Lingle told Reuters late Tuesday, on the opening day of a three-day Tea and Coffee Symposium conference.</p>
<p>He said about half of the U.S. market of 207 million people were coffee drinkers, out of which 11 percent were willing to pay more for a high-quality special gourmet product than the cheaper blends on sale in supermarkets.</p>
<p>&quot;The coffee market in the 21st century is going to be different from today. The U.S. market for specialty coffees can grow (eventually) from about 11 percent of consumers to about 30 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the growth rate to remain between seven to 10 percent a year in the specialty coffee market,&quot; the senior executive said.</p>
<p>The U.S. market today consumes some 18 million 60-kg bags of coffee a year out of which some two million are of high-quality mild arabicas for the specialty market, Lingle said. &quot;We think that will continue to grow to somewhere between five and nine million bags a year.&quot;</p>
<p>Serge Hoorens, managing director of Belgium's AKC Coffee &amp; Tea, said his company had doubled its production of specialty coffees many times since entering the gourmet market two years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Origins coffee was first introduced two years ago and now we are producing about 1,000 tonnes a year. People go after something with an added value. This trend has started and you can no longer stop it,&quot; said Hoorens.</p>
<p>Producing countries, roasters, importers, exporters and traders at the conference all agreed that the specialty market had big growth potential.</p>
<p>&quot;I am seeing more and more a demand for high-quality coffees. Consumers are starting to get bored and want something special. This is a phenomenon which is growing very fast,&quot; said Joaquim Libanio Ferreira Leite.</p>
<p>Leite, of leading Brazilian coffee cooperative Cooperativa Regional de Cafeicultores em Guaxupe Ltda, said he saw additional world demand growth of 5-10 million 60-kilo bags for high-quality coffee in the next five to ten year period.</p>
<p>&quot;People are travelling a lot more today and that helps create more and more a global trend awareness for high-quality coffee,&quot; Leite said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
