<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638338" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: OPTIONS - Dollar vols edge higher as spot firms.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - Dollar vols edge higher as spot firms.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dollar/mark implied volatilities edged higher in Europe as a fiery spot dollar eyed 1997 peaks.</p>
<p>The dollar, which ripped through Tuesday's high at 1.7330 marks, was seen heading for 1997 peaks around 1.7390 marks as fears of a weak single Euroepean currency were fanned by Germany's apparent failure to use revaluation of central bank assets as help in qualifying for European monetary union.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar has vaulted higher. It appears there is only single-way traffic,&quot; said a spot trader at a U.S. bank. Options dealers said the firm spot pushed up dollar/mark vols.</p>
<p>Dollar/mark one-month implied volatilities were firm in Europe, trading at 9.90/10.30 percent at 0825 GMT.  </p>
<p>This compared with 9.85/10.10 percent in late Europe on Tuesday</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen a spike up in short-dated volatilities as spot jumped higher...But apart from that, there is not too much activity,&quot; said an options trader at a U.S. bank.</p>
<p>He said short-dated volatility could ease after climbing higher, but vols were likely to remain well bid in the short-term as uncertainty over the timing and strength of the single European currency rumbled on.</p>
<p>Traders said vols were also likely to remain supported during the International Monetary Conference in Switzerland, which ends on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Central bank presidents from major nations attend the conference and traders will be keeping an ear to the ground for any comments.</p>
<p>&quot;The monetary meeting will prevent vols from falling too much,&quot; said an options trader.</p>
<p>Options interest is centred on one-month vols, said traders, as they cover the June 20 G7 meeting, the Bank of Japan's Tankan report on business sentiment, June 24, and the Federal Open Market Committee (FMC) meeting on July 1-2.</p>
<p>Dollar/mark risk-reversal, the put/call pricing differential, remained slanted in favour of mark puts on Wednesday, with one-month at 0.15/0.45 skewed in favour of puts.</p>
<p>Dollar/yen one-month volatilities were steady to a touch easier in Europe as spot dollar/yen drifted from peaks at 116.49 yen. At 0900 GMT, dollar/yen one-month vols were at 10.10/10.60 percent against 10.70/11.00 percent in early Europe.</p>
<p>Dollar/yen risk-reversal remained skewed in favour of yen calls with one-month at 1.0/1.3 skewed in favour of calls.</p>
<p>Mark/French franc one-month vols. were steady, trading at 1.60/1.90 percent against 1.50/2.00 in late Europe on Tuesday as the mark remained mostly soft against its European crosses.</p>
<p>--Julia Meehan, London forex desk, 4471 542 6701</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
