<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638392" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>New Zealand: NZ debt markets end unchanged, look to wages data.</title>
<headline>NZ debt markets end unchanged, look to wages data.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>----------------------(Snapshot at close)-----------------------</p>
<p>Figures in brackets compare against previous day's close</p>
<p>FUTURES					  PHYSICAL YIELD (PCT)</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS (JUN) 93.05 (PREV 93.07)  90-DAYS  6.97 (PREV 6.96)</p>
<p>3-YR BONDS   (JUN) 92.90 (PREV 92.92)  02/00    7.06 (PREV 7.06)</p>
<p>10-YR BONDS  (JUN) 92.67 (PREV 92.63)  11/06    7.32 (PREV 7.34)</p>
<p>OVERNIGHT CASH 6.90 PCT  (PREV 6.90)   US 5-YR  6.48 (PREV 6.51)</p>
<p>NZD/USD    0.6885/92 (PREV 0.6883/90)  US 10-YR 6.62 (PREV 6.66)</p>
<p>TWI  67.62 (PREV 67.70)		    US 30-YR 6.88 (PREV 6.90)</p>
<p>NZ MCI vs -0.81 vs -0.77</p>
<p>---------------------------(JUNE 4)-----------------------------</p>
<p>* NZ debt markets end unchanged</p>
<p>* Talk of 5-year eurokiwi bond issue on the way</p>
<p>* Market awaits private sector wages data on Thursday</p>
<p>New Zealand debt markets barely moved on Wednesday, with little on the domestic front to nudge yields in either direction.</p>
<p>A steady Trade-Weighted Index held the short end firmly in check, while bond yields slowly gave away early gains to end on Tuesday's closing levels.</p>
<p>An auction of index-linked bonds and private sector wages data on Thursday could provide a short-term lead, dealers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The TWI was steady all day, and it has really been a TWI-following market. There's nothing in the offshore markets to move it, there's been no axes to grind,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>The 90-day bank bill rate closed a point higher at 6.97 percent.</p>
<p>In the bond market, yields were marked down a couple of points at the open on the back of a further rally in U.S. Treasuries overnight, but then spent the rest of the day drifting off.  </p>
<p>One senior Wellington bond dealer said the 2002s were bought first up as talk of a five-year eurokiwi issue circulated the market. &quot;There's a lot of talk, but we haven't seen any evidence of it yet,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>New Zealand bonds are expected to take their lead from the U.S. market in the near-term, with U.S. non-farm payrolls data on Friday, well after the New Zealand close, a key indicator.</p>
<p>But the release on Thursday of private sector average hourly ordinary time earnings will be watched with interest by the debt markets for signs of inflationary wages pressure.  </p>
<p>The private sector wages data, due out at 10.45 a.m. (2245 GMT) are part of Statistics New Zealand's Quarterly Employment Survey, the rest of which remains scheduled for June 12.</p>
<p>An auction of NZ$50 million of February 2016 bonds during Thursday morning could also raise some interest as some players expect it to be the last stock in the series to be issued.</p>
<p>-- Matthew Brockett, Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 473-3736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
