<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638397" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks push higher at noon.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks push higher at noon.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>-----------------(Snapshot 12.00 p.m./0200 GMT)----------------</p>
<p>AORD cl	    2621.8   +8.2    DJIA cl	7312.15   +22.75</p>
<p>SPI Futures	2633.0   +9.0    US 30yr cl	6.87   -0.04</p>
<p>10yrbond futs    92.675   +0.020  Gold NY 347.10 Lon fix 343.55</p>
<p>AUD   US$0.7612  (local $0.7602)  CRB Index cl  248.44   -0.20</p>
<p>NIKKEI cl	20,598.96  -35.40  FTSE cl	 4557.8   -5.0</p>
<p>S&amp;P500(Globex)   843.25   +0.10   NZSE40	 2356.15   +6.73</p>
<p>--------------------------(June 4)-----------------------------</p>
<p>*Stocks overcome early dip to record moderate gains to noon</p>
<p>in quiet trade. Volume 168.2 million, A$472.72 million value, 919 stocks</p>
<p>traded, 331 steady, 339 up, 249 down.</p>
<p>Australian stocks pushed higher in late morning trade, consolidating above the 2,600 mark although there was little fresh to drive the market.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries was up 8.2 points at 2,621.8 after an early dip, with gains spread across the board, but brokers said trade was quiet. &quot;Despite the fact the market is up the activity is not there to go with it,&quot; a Sydney-based dealer said.</p>
<p>The June share price index futures contract was up 9.0 points at 2633.0, an 11.2 point premium to the physical market.  </p>
<p>The positive tone partially reversed Tuesday's falls, and followed a rise in U.S. blue chips and mixed metals prices.</p>
<p>Brokers said expectations of a further official interest rate cut, which boosted the market on Friday and Monday, appeared to have eased.</p>
<p>Official data showing a 0.9 percent rise in gross domestic product in the March quarter was largely seen as irrelevant. &quot;It all seems a long time ago,&quot; one broker noted.</p>
<p>The Australia and New Zealand Banking Group (ANZ), which went ex-dividend 22 cents, topped morning turnover.  </p>
<p>ANZ was down 22 cents at A$8.90, in effect steady, on turnover of 17.6 million shares.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth Bank of Australia was up strongly 45 cents at A$14.14, while the other big banks also made gains.</p>
<p>Bottler Coca-Cola Amatil rose sharply after announcing it had reached final agreement on a share swap deal with San Miguel Corp to acquire the Philippine group's soft drink operations. C-C Amatil briefly breached the A$16.00 level before settling back to A$15.81, a 41-cent gain.  </p>
<p>Queensland's Rundle shale oil twins, Central Pacific Minerals and Southern Pacific Petroleum also rose sharply after announcing they had agreed with financiers to proceed with stage one of the long-mooted development of the Stuart shale oil deposit.</p>
<p>In the building sector, James Hardie added another seven cents to A$4.22 ahead of the release of its annual result on Thursday.</p>
<p>Bellwether Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd added 10 cents to A$18.97 and other big miners were also firmer.</p>
<p>------------------------(TECHNICALS)---------------------------</p>
<p>Short-term range    Support   Restnce   RSI-14  MA-10  MA-20</p>
<p>AORD   2600/2640     2590	2630	76.38   2592   2560</p>
<p>SPI    2600/2640     2600	2640	74.31   2598   2566</p>
<p>------------------------KEY ACTIVES----------------------------</p>
<p>*ANZ A$8.89 (-.23) 8.852/8.94 Vol: 17,636,088 ANZ goes ex-dividend, tops turnover.</p>
<p>*Commonwealth A$14.44 14.00/14.45 Vol: 549,343 Commonwealth retraces losses, other big banks firm</p>
<p>*Fosters A$2.63 (-.01) 2.62/2.65 Vol: 1,602,899 Brewer steady as Asahi says considers new relationship</p>
<p>The media sector was off about 1.1 percent, with News Ltd down nine cents to A$5.77.</p>
<p>In other markets, debt futures eased back after the GDP figures were in line with expectations and cast doubts over future policy easings.</p>
<p>Ten year T-bonds were at 92.645, off 0.01 at noon.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar was a touch stronger at US$0.7612 from US$0.7602.  </p>
<p>*C-C Amatil A$15.81 (+0.41) 15.40/16.02 Vol: 350,997 Bottler rises on deal with San Miguel of the Philippines</p>
<p>*BHP A$18.96 (+.09) 18.86/19.02 Vol: 1,188,880</p>
<p>*Rio Tinto A$21.23 (+.11) 21.07/21.25 Vol: 372,352</p>
<p>*WMC A$8.23 (+.05) 8.18/8.27 Vol: 1,052,616</p>
<p>Bellwether rises, other major miners a touch stronger</p>
<p>*Southern Pacific A$4.35 (+.37) 4.111/4.65 Vol: 586,161</p>
<p>*Central Pacific A$11.00 (+1.25) 10.487/11.1 Vol:76.300</p>
<p>Rundle twins rise on agreement on shale oil project</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
