<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638473" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>indonesia: Japan's Jakarta embassy gets second bomb threat.</title>
<headline>Japan's Jakarta embassy gets second bomb threat.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian police searched the Japanese embassy in Jakarta on Wednesday after the second telephoned bomb threat to the mission in eight days, but they said no explosives were found.</p>
<p>&quot;We found no bomb in the compound. Things are clear there,&quot; an official at the local police station said.</p>
<p>Some embassy members had been cleared from the main building while police and mission staff searched the area.</p>
<p>A policeman inside the embassy compound said an anonymous caller had telephoned the switchboard at 9.25 a.m. (0225 GMT) and said there was a bomb in the building. The caller then hung up.</p>
<p>The embassy, on a main throughfare through Jakarta's central business district, was evacuated following a hoax telephoned bomb threat on Wednesday last week on the eve of Indonesia's general elections.</p>
<p>Japanese sources said it was not clear if the two calls were made by the same person.</p>
<p>Diplomatic sources said they were unable to explain why the Japanese embassy was being targetted.</p>
<p>The main strain in relations between Indonesia and Japan at the moment is a complaint by Tokyo -- alongside the United States and the European Union -- to the World Trade Organisation (WTO) over Jakarta's national car policy.</p>
<p>Indonesia has given tax and tariff breaks to a company headed by one of President Suharto's sons in conjunction with a South Korean firm to produce a national car, which Japan and other complainants say discriminates against other manufacturers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
