<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63845" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine admits higher Chernobyl radiation.</title>
<headline>Ukraine admits higher Chernobyl radiation.</headline>
<byline>Ron Popeski</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukrainian officials said on Thursday that neutron radiation readings had risen considerably inside the Chernobyl nuclear plant's ruined fourth reactor and called for new efforts to rebuild the &quot;sarcophagus&quot; housing it.</p>
<p>Viktor Baryakhtar, vice-president of Ukraine's Academy of Sciences, told Ukrinform news agency that readings of neutron activity in the cracking steel and concrete &quot;sarcophagus&quot; covering the reactor had risen by five to 110 times this week.</p>
<p>Independent experts said even those readings posed no immediate danger, 10 years after the reactor caught fire and exploded in the world's worst civil nuclear disaster.</p>
<p>President Leonid Kuchma, who has pledged to close Chernobyl by the year 2000, expressed concern over the state of the sarcophagus at talks with an envoy of the G7 wealthy countries, one of the chief paymasters in financing the shutdown.</p>
<p>Baryakhtar, Kuchma's top nuclear adviser, described the increased readings as a &quot;chain reaction&quot; which had lasted from four to five hours on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a rather dangerous phenomenon which has been observed three times this year,&quot; he told Ukrinform.</p>
<p>&quot;The main reason is leakage under the sarcophagus of rainwater, which speeds up neutrons. The only way to avoid these instances is to build a new structure around the sarcophagus without delay.&quot;</p>
<p>One independent report this week said neutron radiation readings twice normal levels had been recorded inside the &quot;tomb&quot; hurriedly erected around the reactor after the 1986 disaster.</p>
<p>But it said rises of tens of thousands times the norm would be required to cause a new nuclear reaction.</p>
<p>Baryakhtar's statement, and its appearance on Ukraine's official news agency, appeared aimed at pressing for quicker action in replacing the sarcophagus.</p>
<p>&quot;Such levels are still well below anything constituting a danger but it is important to understand just what is happening inside there. It all must be explained,&quot; Patrick Michaille, a French nuclear safety expert in Ukraine, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;If levels continue to be abnormal that makes the problem of the sarcophagus more urgent. The Ukrainians are clearly trying to draw attention to this. But even if more money is allocated that does not necessarily deal with the problem.&quot;</p>
<p>Ukraine's top negotiator on closing Chernobyl, Environment Minister Yuri Kostenko, initially suggested on Wednesday that the readings were caused by faulty equipment.</p>
<p>But he later said that, if the levels proved correct, they required quick investigation which Ukraine could not afford.</p>
<p>At a meeting attended by G7 ambassadors, special envoy Claude Mandil handed Kuchma a letter from French President Jacques Chirac, the current G7 chairman, responding to Kiev's plea to speed up promised aid and grants of about $3 billion.</p>
<p>A spokesman said Kuchma expressed concern to Mandil about delays in financing construction of two unfinished reactors at other power stations &quot;and the 200 tonnes of nuclear fuel under the sarcophagus. I expect clear decisions on this from G7.&quot;</p>
<p>Kuchma was also meeting a senior official of the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development, which is negotiating a separate financing accord on Chernobyl.</p>
<p>Ukraine has complained that Western efforts have focused on restructuring the former Soviet republic's energy sector and do not recognise a new sarcophagus as an urgent priority.</p>
<p>A Franco-British plan devised three years ago to build a new structure has been all but abandoned as too expensive and the winner of a new tender for a less complex project is expected to be announced next month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I1610109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
