<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638400" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Jubilee says more good results at Cosmos.</title>
<headline>Jubilee says more good results at Cosmos.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jubilee Gold Mines NL said on Wednesday it had received further positive results from recent shallow rotary air blast drilling at its Cosmos nickel project at Kathleen Valley near Leinster, Western Australia.</p>
<p>The results were from drill holes located 100 metres to the north of the previously announced intersections at Cosmos.</p>
<p>&quot;The latest intercepts contain similar widths and grades of nickel and cobalt mineralisation together with high levels of copper and chromium,&quot; the company said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The results are again significant in that most holes terminated in mineralisation and the combination and high levels of indicator elements confirm the strong possibility for the presence of nickel sulphide mineralisation in fresh rock.&quot;</p>
<p>Jubilee, which wholly owns the project, said it had also received platinum and palladium assay results from the first line of RAB drilling.</p>
<p>&quot;Highly anomalous grades up to 240 ppb (parts per billion) platinum and 380 ppb palladium have been received from drill holes JCB133 - JCB148, which were strongly mineralised in nickel, cobalt and other indicator elements,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>Best intersections included 20 metres at 0.80 percent nickel, 0.09 percent cobalt from surface; four metres at 0.70 percent nickel, 0.25 percent coboat, 740 ppm (parts per million) copper from 16 metres; 10 metres at 1.04 percent nickel, 0.03 percent cobalt from 24 metres; and eight metres at 0.92 percent nickel, 0.16 percent cobalt, 1560 ppm copper from 16 metres.</p>
<p>&quot;These mineralised intercepts are of similar tenor to those previously announced from Cosmos, and confirm the presence of a zone of near surface nickel mineralisation averaging 135 metres in width,&quot; Jubilee said.  </p>
<p>&quot;These latest assays provide significant additional support for the presence of primary nickel sulphide mineralisation.</p>
<p>Jubilee said it would start a deep reverse circulation drilling programme at Cosmos on Friday.</p>
<p>Jubilee shares unchanged at 20.5 cents, valuing the company at A$19.63 million.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
