<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638413" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ Treasury admits growth slower than expected.</title>
<headline>NZ Treasury admits growth slower than expected.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Treasury officials admitted on Wednesday that the economy was slower to pick up this year than expected and that as a result the growth forecast underlying the first year of budget projections due on June 26 would be lower.</p>
<p>Treasury secretary Murray Horn told Parliament's finance and expenditure committee that Treasury had been expecting growth to re-accelerate by &quot;about now&quot;, the New Zealand Press Association reported.  </p>
<p>&quot;It looks like the economy in the last two quarters -- the March quarter and the June quarter -- was a bit weaker than expected. It's likely to push that re-acceleration of growth out a bit,&quot; Horn said.</p>
<p>Asked specifically if growth forecasts in the budget would be lower, Horn said: &quot;Given that the first quarter of the year is likely to be a bit weaker than expected they (growth forecasts) will probably be a bit lower for the first year.&quot;  </p>
<p>However, Finance Minister Bill Birch also later told the committee that while growth in the first half of the year may be flatter than forecasters were anticipating, there would be compensating higher growth further out.</p>
<p>The 1997/98 budget is due on June 26 and accompanying it will be economic and fiscal forecasts for the next five years.</p>
<p>The Government's December Economic and Fiscal Update was criticised for being based on growth forecasts that were too optimistic.  </p>
<p>Treasurer Winston Peters also told committee members that reports of a sharp fall in company taxes were being misrepresented by some commentators who had suggested the economy was going down the tubes.</p>
<p>&quot;Far from it. Company profit growth has been lower than expected. But in addition the Treasury December forecast underestimated the extent to which companies over-paid the provisional tax in the previous financial year.  </p>
<p>&quot;The gloomy prognosis (by commentators) reflected either an incomplete representation of the facts or an incomplete understanding of what is driving recent changes in tax collection,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The figures were disclosed in the Government's current year fiscal update released on May 21 which showed a NZ$566 million fall in company tax since the last forecast was released in December. This was partially offset by a $211 million rise in revenues from non-resident withholding tax.  </p>
<p>Peters said that nearly half the decline in revenue from company tax had been offset by increases in other tax collections.</p>
<p>Changes in the international tax regime had also had an impact on the company tax data.</p>
<p>Inland Revenue officials explained that a change to international tax rules at the end of 1995 relaxed a non-resident withholding tax regime which had applied to foreign investors with less than 10 percent of a company and extended it to all foreign investors.  </p>
<p>Companies had taken advantage of the scheme to payout retained earnings and it had been difficult to forecast these. There were timing issues with these payments. Also companies had paid too much provisional tax last year and consequently collections this year were lower.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Bill Birch said it would have been difficult for either Treasury or the IRD to look behind the thought processes of company managers to decide how much of their accumulated profits they were going to pay out in dividends as a result of the tax change.  </p>
<p>Tax forecasts released by the Government are derived from Treasury. Separate data is compiled by IRD and it is understood that this anticipated the movements in company tax totals earlier.</p>
<p>Birch said the two departments' estimates were currently quite close.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
