<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638503" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore shares end weaker, seen staying that way.</title>
<headline>Singapore shares end weaker, seen staying that way.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore shares drifted down on Wednesday, and dealers said they saw no signs of a rally in the short term.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is settling into a trading range and will stick to it for some time,&quot; said one. The Straits Times Industrials Index (STII) fell 13.33 points to end the day at 2,047.89.</p>
<p>With no compelling reason for investors to jump into the market, sideways shifts and downward drifts were seen as the main features in coming weeks, another dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't expect to see a recovery until the latter part of June,&quot; the dealer said.  </p>
<p>Small capitalised stocks saw most of the action on a during which 128.1 million shares changed hands to give 211 losers and 126 gainers.</p>
<p>Benefun International and New Toyo both saw more than six million shares traded to end the day at Hong Kong $1.45 -- up a cent -- and Singapore $0.895 -- up S$0.015 -- respectively.</p>
<p>Shares in DBS Land reacted badly to Tuesday's announcement of a 92 million share placement capital raising exercise, falling briefly below the S$4.75 placement price before gaining a cent to end the day down 24 cents at S$4.76.</p>
<p>-- Nick Edwards, Singapore newsroom (65 8703011)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
