<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638555" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan eases some China investments, bans others.</title>
<headline>Taiwan eases some China investments, bans others.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan said on Wednesday it would allow local firms to engage in a wider range of investments in arch rival China, but slapped an outright ban on real estate and large power plant projects.</p>
<p>&quot;The Investment Commission and relevant departments decided late on Tuesday to remove investment constraints on 411 mainland categories,&quot; a commission spokesman said.</p>
<p>Approval by the economics ministry and cabinet were likely, officials said.</p>
<p>The liberalisation gives a green light to travel agencies, hotels, recreation facilities, warehouses, merchandise agents, rental businesses, saunas, printing machines, sewing machines and car and motorcycle parts, the commission spokesman said.</p>
<p>The 411 categories had been permitted, but only by firms whose investment proposals had obtained explicit commission approval, the official said.</p>
<p>There remain 2,477 items in this discretionary category.</p>
<p>The spokesman said property and power plant projects had been moved from the discretionary category and placed on a &quot;ban list&quot; -- 299 items where China investments by Taiwan interests remain forbidden.</p>
<p>The spokesman noted, however, that the power plant ban would apply only to large projects. Small hydropower plants and steam and electricity co-generation facilities with capacity of up to 20 megawatts would be permitted, he said.</p>
<p>The decision nonetheless would put an explicit end to Formosa Plastics Group's plan to invest US$3 billion in a 3,600-megawatt mainland power station.</p>
<p>A dejected Formosa spokesman told Reuters: &quot;We have no more power plant (project) on the mainland now.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Formosa group could only &quot;patiently wait&quot; for a shift in policy by the Nationalist government, which has grown wary of allowing Taiwan to become overdependent on the economy of its arch rival.</p>
<p>Taiwan, which has banned direct links with China since a civil war split them in 1949, has allowed a range of &quot;indirect&quot; investments under a political thaw dating to the late 1980s.</p>
<p>Some 4,350 investment types are permitted, though capital must be routed through Hong Kong or a third country.</p>
<p>In its drive to avoid becoming economically vulnerable in China, Taipei said in late May it was restricting investment in mainland infrastructure -- specifically water works, railways, harbours, airports, roads and power plants.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I48100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
