<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638667" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: LME seen consolidating, but nickel rally not over.</title>
<headline>LME seen consolidating, but nickel rally not over.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nickel prices are likely to climb further on the London Metal Exchange (LME) as a strike at Inco Ltd continues, while copper is expected to take a break after recent rises, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Nickel will remain volatile, but it might test the next resistance at $7,250 (a tonne),&quot; said a trader at a Japanese trade house. &quot;It depends on what U.S. funds do with their short positions.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said news of a 20 percent production increase by Russia's Norilsk, the world's largest nickel manufacturer, had been expected sooner or later, while they were watching carefully the strike at Inco's Sudbury facility in Canada.</p>
<p>About 4,670 unionised workers at Inco, the world's second largest nickel maker, went on strike on Tuesday after voting down a tentative contract agreement reached on Friday.</p>
<p>Company and union officials said they did not know when talks would resume.</p>
<p>&quot;We understand Inco has stocks for one or two months,&quot; said another Japanese trader. &quot;But if the strike continues, it will have to purchase nickel from outside.&quot;</p>
<p>At 0205 GMT, three-month LME nickel was quoted in Asian trade at $7,170/200 a tonne, little changed from Tuesday's close at $7,180 in London, up $155 from the previous day.</p>
<p>Three-month copper rose to $2,491/96 a tonne from $2,479 at the close in London, and aluminium climbed to 1,586/78 from $1,578.</p>
<p>&quot;Although copper remains in an upward trend, it needs some kind of consolidation after the latest straight-line advance,&quot; said one trader, who added that aluminium might face even stronger pressure after falling through support earlier this week at $1,600.</p>
<p>&quot;In the near term, aluminium might test the $1,560-1,550 level,&quot; the trader added.</p>
<p>-- Nao Nakanishi, Tokyo Commodities Desk +81-3-3432-7431</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
