<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="638643" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan CO2 reform marks policy reversal -- Greenpeace.</title>
<headline>Japan CO2 reform marks policy reversal -- Greenpeace.</headline>
<byline>Peter Lardner</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Environment Agency is taking aim at the growing problem of auto emissions, a move that may help counter Japan's oil-thirsty image as it prepares to host a high-profile summit on global warming in December.</p>
<p>The agency's 1997 annual report, which calls for dramatic changes in Japan's regulatory policy on carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions, was well-received even by the environmental group Greenpeace, a long-time critic of Japan's clean air policies.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel that (policy-makers) have shown a very public change of attitude and a new level of cooperation this week,&quot; a Greenpeace spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>The report's focus on some formerly inflexible positions of Japan's powerful Ministry of International Trade and Industry (MITI) shows an about-face in MITI policy, Greenpeace said.</p>
<p>&quot;The release of this report, which has received cabinet approval, means that it has MITI's tacit approval,&quot; the spokeswoman said. &quot;I think we're seeing progress here, where previously there was a sort of deadlock.&quot;</p>
<p>MITI and the Environment Agency have had a long-standing dispute over how to handle the hot issue of greenhouse gas emissions, but face heavy government pressure to harmonise their views ahead of December's global warming conference in Kyoto, Western Japan.</p>
<p>The report specifically calls for new discussion on tax changes that would encourage consumers to buy cars that are more fuel-efficient, helping bringing about a cut in carbon dioxide emissions, plus new legislation to pin-point mandatory fuel efficiency standards.</p>
<p>Both suggestions fly in the face of past MITI positions.</p>
<p>&quot;MITI has long been against taxation policies, but they have given little explanation. But we are starting to see a change,&quot; Greenpeace said.</p>
<p>On Monday, MITI issued its first-ever suggestion that a government panel be created that would regulate emissions. The statement was part of a broader package of suggested reform measures which included liberalising Japan's oil product exports, stirring competition among oil product wholesalers, and fostering greater price transparency.</p>
<p>&quot;The importance of the Environment Agency report is that it emphasises the necessity for early reduction of CO2 as well as a longer-term reduction. This is a very clear government signal to industry as to which direction industry should go,&quot; Greenpeace said.</p>
<p>December's high-profile global warming conference in Kyoto, a follow-up to the so-called Rio de Janeiro Earth summit in Brazil in 1992, represents the third meeting of the U.N. Framework Convention on Climate Change.</p>
<p>In Rio, a long-list of developed nations made non-binding calls to reduce emissions of carbon dioxide to 1990 levels by the year 2000. The Kyoto meeting will seek agreement on legally binding cuts in greenhouse gases.</p>
<p>Most countries will fail to meet carbon dioxide emissions targets set during the Rio summit in 1992.</p>
<p>Japan's carbon dioxide emission levels in the year that ended in March 1996 were 8.3 percent higher than in 1990.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
