<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639093" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-ENGLAND MAKE DREAM START TO ASHES SERIES.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-ENGLAND MAKE DREAM START TO ASHES SERIES.</headline>
<byline>Steve Tongue</byline>
<dateline>BIRMINGHAM, England 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>England, fired by pace pair Darren Gough and Andy Caddick, made a perfect start to the first test against Australia on one of the most compelling opening days of an Ashes series on Thursday.</p>
<p>Gough captured three for 43 and Caddick took five for 50 as Australia, who won the toss and opted to bat, were routed for 118 shortly after lunch.</p>
<p>Having exploited favourable conditions to make just the start they wanted, England faltered briefly, losing captain Michael Atherton and debutant Mark Butcher for 16 in the first four overs.</p>
<p>But the damage was repaired as Nasser Hussain (80 not out) and Graham Thorpe (83 not out), coming together at 50 for three after Alec Stewart was out, shared an unbroken fourth wicket partnership of 150 to spur England to 200 for three at the close.</p>
<p>They were both severe on Australia's potential match-winner Shane Warne, who can only hope the pitch is taking spin by the time England bat again - if they need to.</p>
<p>Equally disappointing for Australian captain Mark Taylor was the fact that his highly-regarded strike bowler Glenn McGrath was unable to take greater advantage of humid conditions after dismissing Atherton cheaply.</p>
<p>With Jason Gillespie straining a hamstring and another paceman, Andy Bichel, already ruled out, the Australians are likely to send for another bowler.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks as though we're going to need one,&quot; said coach Geoff Marsh, who named Paul Reiffel of Victoria and Adam Dale of Queensland as contenders.</p>
<p>Marsh admitted: &quot;We batted badly and bowled badly. We've got to work hard tp turn it round.&quot;</p>
<p>Taylor's poor form continued when he was dismissed for only seven and his lack of confidence spread to to his team mates.</p>
<p>He saw his opening partner Matthew Elliott bowled by Gough for six, then lost his own wicket when he edged a wide ball from Devon Malcolm to Butcher at second slip.</p>
<p>When Gough, roared on by a noisy and enthusiastic sell-out crowd of 22,000, bowled Mark Waugh (five) and had Greg Blewett (seven) taken at third slip, Australia were 28 for four with less than an hour played.</p>
<p>As Gough rested, with figures of three for 18 in eight overs, New Zealand-born Caddick took over to send back Steve Waugh (12) and Ian Healy (0) in successive balls. Both were given out caught behind by Alec Stewart, though television replays suggested that Waugh had not touched the ball.</p>
<p>Michael Bevan (eight), the last recognised batsman, was next to go, giving Mark Ealham an easy catch at gully off Malcolm, who was returning to test cricket after an absence of 17 months.</p>
<p>Jason Gillespie, having narrowly avoided becoming a hat-trick victim, fell lbw in Caddick's next over for four.</p>
<p>Only Warne, with a spirited 47 from 46 balls, resisted for long, with none of the recognised batsmen lasting more than 25 balls.</p>
<p>England's coach David Lloyd described the day as the best of his 12 months in charge. But he insisted: &quot;There's a long way to go. We won't be preening ourselves on one day's cricket.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BIRMINGHAM, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
