<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639187" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-ZOLA BOTH PRAISES AND WARNS ENGLAND.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ZOLA BOTH PRAISES AND WARNS ENGLAND.</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett</byline>
<dateline>NANTES, France 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The irony was not lost on Chelsea striker Gianfranco Zola.</p>
<p>On Wednesday night, England's Footballer of the Year was doing his best to help Italy beat England in their opening match in the Tournoi de France.</p>
<p>The fact that England beat Italy 2-0, and that they played so impressively, did not suprise him. What did was the style, the flair and the confidence shown by Glenn Hoddle's team.</p>
<p>&quot;Being at Chelsea so soon after Glenn Hoddle was the manager there I know very well of what he did for the club,&quot; Zola said afterwards.</p>
<p>&quot;I was not at the club when he was there, but much of our success this season in winning the F.A. Cup came as a result of the foundations he laid at the club.</p>
<p>&quot;Now I see him doing the same for England. They played very well against Poland, and they played very well against us.</p>
<p>&quot;Playing in England I know how much talent and skill English players have and they showed it against us. The coach has got hold of this talent and he is molding it into a force that could be very dangerous for the rest of the world.&quot;</p>
<p>But he played down the significance of the victory four months before the two sides meet again in a vital World Cup qualifier in Rome in October.</p>
<p>&quot;You cannot read anything into that match from this result&quot; said Zola, who scored the only goal of the game when Italy beat England 1-0 in their first qualifier at Wembley in February.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of the Italian team are tired, it is the end of the season, and the English players have had to stay at peak for their qualifier against Poland last Saturday. It will be very different in Rome, that is for sure. England must take nothing for granted from this win.&quot;</p>
<p>While Zola battled for 90 minutes without reward against a resolute England defence, his Chelsea team mate Roberto di Matteo lasted only 18 minutes before limping off following a rock-solid tackle from England's 35-year-old defender Stuart Pearace.</p>
<p>Italian coach Cesare Maldini was critical of some of England's tackling in a match which produced six bookings little -- four of them English -- but Pearce was unrepentant about his performance.</p>
<p>Told of Maldini's comments, Pearce replied only: &quot;Shame. You're on the pitch, you're there to win the match. There are a lot of England players trying to force their way into the team and there is a lot of friendly rivalry for places. We all want to be winners, there is a World Cup next summer, and you want to win every game you play.&quot;</p>
<p>Zola echoed Pearce's comments: &quot;There is no doubt at all they wanted to win more than we did,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But they mustn't think it will be like that in Rome, that's for sure.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NANTES, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
