<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639118" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA BASKETBALL-JORDAN CARRIES BULLS TO 2-0 LEAD OVER JAZZ IN FINALS.</title>
<headline>NBA BASKETBALL-JORDAN CARRIES BULLS TO 2-0 LEAD OVER JAZZ IN FINALS.</headline>
<byline>Gary Hill</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Michael Jordan repelled every Utah threat and the Jazz had no answer for him as the Chicago Bulls won a convincing 97-85 victory Wednesday to go up two games to none in the NBA Finals.</p>
<p>Jordan scored 38 points with 13 rebounds, nine assists and two steals -- one assist short of a triple-double, and game highs for points, rebounds and assists -- as Chicago built a 22-point lead in the third quarter, then coasted home.</p>
<p>&quot;We as a team have great momentum. Myself, I seem to have a pretty good rhythm,&quot; Jordan said.</p>
<p>&quot;Michael was terrific tonight,&quot; said Bulls coach Phil Jackson.</p>
<p>Jordan sounded almost disappointed the Jazz hadn't made more changes after losing Game 1 on his buzzer-beater.</p>
<p>&quot;As we looked for adjustments, we didn't see as many adjustments as we anticipated,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I came into the game to evaluate the changes and adjustments they were going to make. A lot of conversation has been made over the last couple of days about the shot that I made and stopping Michael Jordan.&quot;</p>
<p>Ron Harper was second high scorer for the Bulls with just 13 points.</p>
<p>The Jazz, who never led, cut Chicago's advantage to one point two-thirds of the way through the first quarter and to two midway through the second. But each time the Jazz go close, Jordan triggered spurts to virtually put the game away by halftime with a 47-31 lead.</p>
<p>Karl Malone led Utah with 20 points and 13 rebounds, but this season's narrow winner of the Most Valuable Player award had to endure chants of &quot;MVP, MVP&quot; every time Jordan, who came in second in the voting, went to the free throw line.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously tonight was terrible as far as I'm concerned,&quot; Malone said.</p>
<p>Jeff Hornacek had 19 points and John Stockton 14 -- on just 4-for-12 shooting -- for the Jazz.</p>
<p>Stockton said it was the Bulls' defence that won the game.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought they put on a defensive clinic. As well as some people might think they played offensively, I think they beat us defensively,&quot; Stockton said.</p>
<p>&quot;Defense wins championships. We've known that for a while,&quot; said Jordan, looking for his fifth title in seven years.</p>
<p>The best-of-seven series moves to Utah for Game 3 on Friday. Games 4 and, if necessary, 5 will also be in Salt Lake City, where the Jazz had the best home record in the NBA for the second half of the season and are 8-0 in the playoffs.</p>
<p>Malone shot only 6-for-20 from the field, bringing questions again about his injured shooting hand, but he refused again to use that as an excuse.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as I'm concerned I'm not getting it done. We'll try to bounce back on Friday,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Utah coach Jerry Sloan raked his team's effort for a second game in the row, saying: &quot;I really didn't think we put all of our energy into it.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought we were intimidated right from the beginning of the game.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Basically what he means is we played soft,&quot; said Malone. &quot;And you can't argue with it.&quot;</p>
<p>Utah stumbled out of the gate, missing shots -- Malone missed two free throws, an unpleasant reminder of his failure at the end of Game 1 -- and turning the ball over -- another reminder -- to fall behind 8-1.</p>
<p>But the Jazz then outscored the Bulls 12-6 to pull within a point at 14-13 before Jordan hit a three-pointer, then faked his defender Hornacek into flying by and hit another jumper. Steve Kerr hit two straight treys -- both on assists from Jordan -- in an 11-2 run that put Chicago up 25-15.</p>
<p>The Jazz produced a 5-0 mini-run to close the quarter trailing 25-20, then cut the lead to 31-29.</p>
<p>And Jordan responded again, rebounding a Harper miss and scoring on a layup. Then after Scottie Pippen blocked a Malone shot, forcing a 24-second violation, Harper hit a three and the Bulls were pulling away again.</p>
<p>It turned into a 14-0 streak that was part of a 16-2 finish to the half. Jordan had 20 points at the half.</p>
<p>Utah shot only 11-of-35 (.314) in the first half -- well below their NBA-leading .504 rate in the regular season -- and was held to just 11 points in the second quarter.</p>
<p>Jordan added 10 more points in the third quarter and did not take his customary rest at the start of the fourth.</p>
<p>&quot;I asked to stay in the game because we seemed to have a good rhythm and they still had their two starters, Malone and Stockton, in the game,&quot; Jordan said. &quot;They stayed in there so I stayed in there.&quot;</p>
<p>Late in the fourth quarter the Jazz began forcing turnovers and cut the lead to eight on a Hornacek three-pointer with just over a minute and a half to go, but Jordan converted 1-of-2 free throws and Dennis Rodman made a three-pointer for the final margin.</p>
<p>Only twice has a team come back from an 0-2 NBA Finals deficit.</p>
<p>Of playing at Salt Lake City's noisy Delta Centre, Jordan said: &quot;Hopefully our defence can live up to the challenge and our offence can take the crowd out of the game.&quot;</p>
<p>Said Malone: &quot;We have to give them something to cheer for.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
