<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639190" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-CROATIA'S BOKSIC TO SIGN FOR LAZIO, NEWSPAPERS SAY.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-CROATIA'S BOKSIC TO SIGN FOR LAZIO, NEWSPAPERS SAY.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian striker Alen Boksic is expected to return to serie A side Lazio next season after only a year at league champions Juventus, Italian newspapers reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>Gazzetta dello Sport quoted Lazio owner Sergio Cragnotti as saying he had reached an agreement with Juventus for the 27-year-old striker, who played for the Rome club from 1993-96.</p>
<p>&quot;With Juve there is a preliminary signature. With the player it is already worked out,&quot; Cragnotti said.</p>
<p>Boksic, who made his name by scoring 23 goals for French club Marseille in the 1992-93 season, had to fight for a regular place alongside Christian Vieri in the Juventus attack after getting injured late last year.</p>
<p>Gazzetta said Juventus wanted 24 billion lire ($14.1 million) from Lazio for the Croatian international who is under contract with the Turin side until 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;If they accept our conditions we will happily let him go,&quot; Juventus general manager Luciano Moggi was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Boksic would join experienced international Pierluigi Casiraghi and former Italy striker Roberto Mancini up front at Lazio. The 32-year-old Mancini signed a three-year contract with Lazio on Monday after 15 seasons at Sampdoria.</p>
<p>Cragnotti denied speculation that there would be no room in the new attacking line-up for Beppe Signori, who was serie A joint top goalscorer last season.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not selling anybody. With Boksic, Casiraghi, Mancini, Signori, we have a great attack,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
