<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639160" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: HOCKEY-AUSTRALIA THRASH U.S. TO REACH TROPHY FINAL.</title>
<headline>HOCKEY-AUSTRALIA THRASH U.S. TO REACH TROPHY FINAL.</headline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Olympic and World Cup champions Australia moved into top gear by trouncing the United States 5-0 on Thursday to become the first country to qualify for the women's Champions Trophy final.</p>
<p>Their opponents in the final on Sunday will be Germany, South Korea or the Netherlands.</p>
<p>Germany are best placed to join them after beating Britain 3-0. Their final group match on Saturday -- Friday is a rest day -- is against the Netherlands while Korea meet Australia in a repeat of the Atlanta Olympic final, in their last game of the round robin series.</p>
<p>Australia have 10 points from four games, Germany eight and Korea and Netherlands six.</p>
<p>Australia have improved with every game here after their 1-1 draw with Germany on the opening day. Their win over the U.S. was their biggest ever in their 28 matches against the Americans.</p>
<p>Alyson Annan, again outstanding, gave them the lead in 90 seconds from their first corner with a rasping low drive.</p>
<p>Australia's captain Jennifer Morris added their next two goals, converting a penalty stroke (22nd minute) and a penalty corner (47th) and is now the tournament's top scorer with four goals in four games.</p>
<p>Katrina Powell (55th) and Nicole Mott (57th) completed the rout of the United States, who did not have a shot in the game.</p>
<p>A fine solo goal by local girl Natascha Keller put Germany on the winning path against Britain in the 24th minute.</p>
<p>The German captain, Katrin Kauschke, turned in a cross by Heike Latzsch for Germany's second goal in the 52nd minute and Latzsch herself took advantage of a defensive error to add the third.</p>
<p>Asked if Germany who are unbeaten, could win the Champions Trophy at home, their coach, Berti Rauth, said: &quot;Motivation yes, power no. I have eight new players and they are becoming more confident but the team is tired.&quot;</p>
<p>Lee Eun-young, the South Korean inside forward taken to hospital with a neck injury on the first day of the tournament, took the field for the first time since last Sunday to the side to a 2-0 victory over European champions the Netherlands.</p>
<p>Korea were holding a tenuous 1-0 advantage when Lee, who had been wearing a neck brace until Wednesday, was called off the bench to replace another of her team-mates who was injured.</p>
<p>Lee promptly won the ball, took on the Dutch defence and set up a goal by Choi Kwan-sook .</p>
<p>Korea's second win took them from fifth to second place and above the Dutch in the round robin table.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
