<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639112" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-UNITED'S YOUNGSTERS PROVIDE ENGLAND'S INSPIRATION.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-UNITED'S YOUNGSTERS PROVIDE ENGLAND'S INSPIRATION.</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett</byline>
<dateline>LA BAULE, France 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Manchester United's domination of domestic English football over the last five years could now provide the platform for success for the England national team.</p>
<p>When the final whistle blew on England's 2-0 win over Italy in the Tournoi de France on Wednesday, there were five Manchester United players -- and former United midfielder Paul Ince -- on the pitch.</p>
<p>And Ince, along with his former United colleagues David Beckham, Philip and Gary Neville and full debutant Paul Scholes provided the inpsiration for England's first victory over Italy in five matches since November 1977.</p>
<p>While the victory was a well-deserved one, the England camp were keeping it in perspective on Thursday.</p>
<p>Italy gave a low-key performance, did not seem particularly bothered whether they won the match or not and coach Cesare Maldini appeared angry that England played with as much aggression as they did.</p>
<p>But one aspect of the England performance that cannot be overlooked was the contributuion made by the young United players in the side.</p>
<p>Defender Stuart Pearce, 35, winning his 76th cap, said at England's training camp on the Atlantic coast at La Baule: &quot;I have seen a lot of footballers move up to the England squad but I don't think I can remember a better debut than Paul Scholes'.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought he was outstanding and I would like to give all credit to Alex Ferguson, the Manchester United manager.</p>
<p>&quot;My brief flirtation with management at Nottingham Forest this season showed me how hard a job it is but you have to praise Ferguson and his club for developing the young players like they do. The way he has brought them along speaks volumes for him and United as a club.&quot;</p>
<p>Scholes, who came on as substitute for 25 minutes against South Africa, made one goal and scored the other in his full debut on Wednesday. He said it helped that so many of his club mates were in the team.</p>
<p>&quot;We have come through the youth team, the reserve team and the first team at Manchester United together and now the England team. Of course it helps having everyone around.&quot;</p>
<p>And he also explained why he appeared so at ease in the environment.</p>
<p>&quot;Every match at Manchester United is a big match, home or away, and you grow up with the pressure. Right now, getting a game in the England team is a bonus. But looking around and seeing David or Gary or Phil, knowing how they play, helped a lot.&quot;</p>
<p>Beckham, who has just turned 22 and has eight caps, agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;Every game you play for United is like a Cup Final, every game you play away is a full house. To tell you the truth I wasn't even nervous last night. I got on the field, looked at the Italians and thought 'they are just the same as us'. After 20 minutes I knew we were going to win it.&quot;</p>
<p>Hoddle started the match with Beckham in an experimental central midfield role, with Philip Neville, 20, earning only his third cap wide on the right and Scholes playing behind striker Ian Wright alongside Teddy Sheringham in an attacking midfield role.</p>
<p>After the break, Neveille's brother Gary, 22, replaced Graeme Le Saux and late in the game Andy Cole was brought on for Wright to become the fifth United player in the team.</p>
<p>There was no doubt their understanding and harmony helped England dominate the midfield and several one-touch counter- attacking moves were pure United.</p>
<p>Many times in the past the idea of basing a national side on a successful club side has failed to produce successful results for the national team. Former England manager Ron Greenwood fielded up to seven Liverpool players in the late 1970s without much tangible reward.</p>
<p>And while there is no suggestion Hoddle is planning to base his team on a one-club idea, having those United players at his disposal is a big bonus.</p>
<p>United have steadily improved in European competition over the last two seasons, reaching the semifinals of the European Cup this season before losing to eventual winners Borussia Dortmund.</p>
<p>That exposure and the quality of their youngsters could well help England go even further in their quest for success in the very near future.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LA BAULE, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
