<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639249" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARY BOURSE TO TIGTHEN RULES FOR LISTED FIRMS.</title>
<headline>HUNGARY BOURSE TO TIGTHEN RULES FOR LISTED FIRMS.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Budapest Stock Exchange (BSE) has decided to tighten its regulations for listing and keeping listed companies in trading, the BSE said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The rules have generally become stricter,&quot; BSE Managing Director Jozsef Rotyis told a news conference.</p>
<p>The council of the BSE decided to drop the idea of launching a third or &quot;C&quot; category, in which trading and reporting rules would be looser than in the existing &quot;A&quot; and &quot;B&quot; categories, Rotyis said.</p>
<p>In category &quot;A&quot;, the minimum total trading value of the shares of each listed company was increased to five billion forints from 500 million.</p>
<p>The minimum number of shareholders was raised to 1,000 from 100 in category &quot;A&quot;, while the obligatory minimum percentage of publicly held shares remained 25 percent or at least two billion forints at trading value instead of the current minimum of 200 million forints.</p>
<p>Two of the shares listed in category &quot;A&quot;, holding companies Konzum Kereskedelmi and Ipari Rt and Dunaholding Rt do not meet the new rules and they may be placed in category &quot;B&quot;, Rotyis said.</p>
<p>In category &quot;B&quot;, where trading and reporting requirements are looser than in category A, the obligatory minimum number of shareholders of each company was raised to 36 from 25, he said.</p>
<p>The new regulations are likely to be approved by Hungary's bourse watchdog APTF in one month, and they will go into effect in six months after the approval, Rotyis said.</p>
<p>A further change for category &quot;B&quot; companies is that they will be required to publish half year reports only one year after the listing, he added.</p>
<p>The BSE's council also decided to work out stricter trading liquidity rules for category &quot;A&quot; shares.</p>
<p>According to the planned new rules, the bourse would twice a year examine certain turnover indicators of the shares in trading on the BSE, and if a company does not meet the minimum liquidity requirements for two or three halves of years, it will be downgraded to category &quot;B&quot;, Rotyis said.</p>
<p>The BSE council also decided on the restructuring of the bourse's fees.</p>
<p>Rotyis said that the changes are not likely to affect investors in the sense that they do not represent a rise in average terms.</p>
<p>Listing fees rose, while trading fees dropped, and for the longer term the BSE, which is already relatively cheap, wishes to compete with the cheapest bourses in the world, Rotyis said.</p>
<p>-- Sandor Peto, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
