<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63941" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian Varazdinska Banka to sign EBRD deal Oct 1. [CORRECTED 14:27 GMT]</title>
<headline>Croatian Varazdinska Banka to sign EBRD deal Oct 1. [CORRECTED 14:27 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian bank Varazdinska Banka d.d. said on Thursday it would sign an agreement with the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) for some 23 million German marks (corrects from 52 million) investment on October 1.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been finalised and has passed the (EBRD) board of directors,&quot; Mato Lukinic, president of Varazdinska's board, told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>He said the EBRD would buy a 10 percent equity stake in the Croatian bank, or 1,000 shares from its own portfolio at 3,200 German marks a share. It would be entitled to appoint one member of its supervisory board to oversee business.</p>
<p>He said Varazdinska's share value had risen from a nominal 1,300 marks since 1990, as it retained profits for three years to boost its capital to 175 million kuna (corrects to give figure and deletes reference to third issue of shares).</p>
<p>Varazdinska would become the second company after drugs firm Pliva and the first commercial bank in Croatia to draw EBRD's portfolio investment.</p>
<p>The European bank, which opened its representative office in Zagreb in June, has been negotiating two other investments, into the country's leading confectioner Kras and food processing firm Podravka.</p>
<p>Lukinic said the EBRD would also open a 20 million marks credit line for Varazdinska, probably this year, for financing small and medium-sized private companies.</p>
<p>The loan would be repayable over eight years with a grace period of two years. -- Kolumbina Bencevic, Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
