<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639567" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: Estonia shares boosted by bank news, Hansa leads.</title>
<headline>Estonia shares boosted by bank news, Hansa leads.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Estonian stock exchange was more active on Thursday, given a kick by latest bank and company results, dealers said.</p>
<p>Total trade on the main list was 30.8 million kroons with the Talse 0.8 percent up at 252.39. Trade yesterday was 19.8 million kroons.</p>
<p>Hansapank was most active to gain 2.42 kroons to 131.17 kroons on trade worth 7.7 million kroons.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems that investors are more choosy and need more information on company fundamentals to make their decisions, then they did some months ago,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Several leading banks released their May earnings figures, including second and third placed banks Hoiupank and Uhispank.</p>
<p>&quot;It was the amount of information from the banks that helped the bourse along,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market should be active tomorrow as well, as people digest the news from today,&quot; another added.</p>
<p>Hoiupank turned over 7.1 million kroons on the strength of its May results to gain 0.10 kroons to 132.30 kroons.</p>
<p>Hoiupank said it made a record profit in May of 18.1 million kroons. Forekspank said its May profit was 5.1 million kroons. Dealers said that although the figure was as expected, the stock has underperformed.</p>
<p>Uhispank released a profit figure lower than April at nine million kroons but picked up 0.15 kroons to close on 52.30 kroons after turning over 5.6 million kroons.</p>
<p>Baltika, a clothing maker and retailer, made its debut on the bourse. Baltika turned over 1.5 million kroons to close at 45.85 kroons after reaching a high of 48.00 kroons.</p>
<p>Viisnurk, a ski and furniture maker, was the other first-timer with its share price hitting 240 kroons during the day to close on 225 kroons on a trade of 1.5 million kroons.</p>
<p>The free market turned over 3.5 million kroons down on Wednesday's total of 4.6 million kroons.</p>
<p>-- David Mardiste, Tallinn newsroom, +372 620 9202/1 reuters@reuters.ee</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
