<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639566" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks mixed, trade helped by foreigners.</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks mixed, trade helped by foreigners.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks were mixed in livelier trade on Thursday and traders said renewed interest from foreign investors was likely to push prices upward.</p>
<p>&quot;As soon as the foreigners turned up the market came alive,&quot; said trader Ratko Bubalo of East Brokers. &quot;They are the ones who make a difference.&quot;</p>
<p>Volume rose to 11,776 shares and the turnover almost doubled to 6.4 million kuna.</p>
<p>Bubalo pointed to intensive trading with shares other than the two market heavywights -- drugs firm Pliva and Zagrebacka Banka -- which usually make up most of the trading.</p>
<p>Lower prices after a recent slide in the market as well as signs that Croatia may finally be willing to meet Western political demands, and therefore open the door to further international loans, have boosted trade in recent days.</p>
<p>Podravka food concern was the most active issue, selling 2,773 shares and adding seven kuna to 270, and traders said it is the hottest issue at the moment.</p>
<p>&quot;After hitting 250 kuna, which is its absolute low, I think Podravka can only go upwards, at least until they come up with the 1996 results,&quot; said Josko Milisa of I.C.F. brokerage.</p>
<p>Podravka has long been due to issue its 1996 results, which are rumoured to include a large loss after the sell-off of the company's loss-making non-core subsidiaries.</p>
<p>But Podravka looks good for the first six months of 1997, one trader said, which can explain the renewed interest of investors.</p>
<p>Both Pliva and Zagrebacka lost some ground in relatively lively trading. Pliva lost one kuna to 459 selling 1,279 shares and Zagrebacka lost 15 kuna to 2,110 on 1,100 shares.</p>
<p>But the two Istrian hoteliers owned by Zagrebacka and managed by its subsidiary did well -- Jadranturist was top gainer, adding 10 kuna to 250, on unusually high volume of 1,031 shares while Istraturist rose five kuna to 170, but on a small volume of 48 shares.</p>
<p>Laguna Porec also added 35 kuna to 1,350, trading 483 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are speculating that tourist shares will go up because of predictions of a good season,&quot; Milisa said.</p>
<p>Two other hoteliers fell with Riviera the biggest loser, falling 11 kuna to 130. Suncani Hvar lost four kuna to close at 50 on volume of 1,580 shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
