<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639557" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech crown faces further attacks as govt lurches.</title>
<headline>Czech crown faces further attacks as govt lurches.</headline>
<byline>Alan Crosby</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech crown, steady in recent days after a two-week speculative attack, faces more assaults if the government does not resolve political infighting, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Speculators and the Czech National Bank (CNB) fought for two weeks before the central bank was forced to give in and remove the 15 percent band within which it fixed the currency against the midpoint of a dollar/mark basket.</p>
<p>The newly-floating crown, supported by CNB tightening moves including hikes to its key interest rates, has since settled at around 9-10 percent below its former basket parity.</p>
<p>But analysts said a series of attacks on Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus are threatening to put the crown back into a spiral. One allegation is that the International Monetary Fund warned him in advance of the impending crown crisis but he refused to tell cabinet members.</p>
<p>&quot;If that story is true, then I think we are in for some more attacks on the currency and more weakness in the market,&quot; Jonathan Hoffman, an economist at Credit Suisse First Boston told Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>Earlier this week deputy prime minister Josef Lux,  chairman of the centrist Christina Democrats, said Klaus had intentionally withheld from ministers an IMF fax warning him earlier this year of a possible currency crisis.</p>
<p>Klaus has denied he withheld the IMF's warning from ministers but Foreign Minister Josef Zieleniec, deputy chairman of his Civic Democratic Party (ODS), corroborated Lux's claim.</p>
<p>Zieleniec's statement has sparked a rash of local media reports that a power struggle was blazing within the ODS.</p>
<p>ODS issued a statement on Thursday aimed at putting these reports to rest before a confidence vote in the lower house of parliament where the Klaus coalition holds 100 out of 200 seats.</p>
<p>A simple majority is required for approval of the motion, expected to be debated at a session starting next week.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if Klaus manages to ride (this) through, there is still a lot of concern about the way he has handled the economy and the way he has handled this particular episode. I think the writing may be on the wall for the PM,&quot; Hoffman said.</p>
<p>One local currency trader said: &quot;Klaus's credibility is not high right now, and if he is caught on this, the markets -- all of them and not just the crown -- are in for a stormy ride.&quot;</p>
<p>The crown was trading in a tight range for most of Thursday, although it weakened about 50 basis points against the dollar and mark from the central bank daily fixing.</p>
<p>In late afternoon trading the crown was at 19.277 against the mark and 33.265 against the dollar, while the central bank fixed the crown at 33.127 to the dollar and 19.19 to the mark.</p>
<p>Three weeks ago, the central bank moved to shore up the crown by raising its Lombard rate to 50 percent from 14 percent, and its repo rate to 75 percent from 12.9 percent, while cutting off non-residents' access to crowns.</p>
<p>The central bank has taken a few small steps in recent days to ease its grip on the crown, letting repo rates fall to 39 percent on Thursday. But traders said the market, especially foreign players, remained very short of crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't get the crowns we need on demand, in fact it is tough to get any at all,&quot; said one London-based trader.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as the central bank keeps us from getting them, it can support the crown, but when they ease rates, the political turmoil may compound the pressure on the crown and it could fall 5-10 percent more,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 420-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
