<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639698" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Oil firms vote for Venezuela with their wallets.</title>
<headline>Oil firms vote for Venezuela with their wallets.</headline>
<byline>Tom Ashby</byline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign oil companies went on another spending spree in Venezuela on Thursday, paying almost $500 million on four contracts to reactivate oilfields for state- owned Petroleos de Venezuela.</p>
<p>Total bids for 16 contracts awarded this week teetered on the $2 billion mark, and one major field, Boqueron, was still to go under the hammer on Friday.</p>
<p>U.K. independent exploration company Lasmo stole the show on Thursday, paying the round record so far of $453 million for the Dacion contract, located in the east of the country.</p>
<p>+For us it is a fantastic opportunity to come into a country that has the world's sixth largest reserve base... Venezuela's opportunities are on a par with the biggest producers in the world and we want to be here in the long term to do business,+ said Lasmo business development director Roger Tucker.</p>
<p>Oil executives said the level of bids just for a chance to work as a contractor in some of Venezuela's ageing and abandoned oilfields illustrated just how popular oil exploration has become since oil prices turned upwards in 1995.</p>
<p>+Everyone's had their fling in Russia and the ex-Soviet Union, the North Sea is maturing, the Middle East is unstable. This is one of the largest petroleum basins in the world and its one of the only places you can book reserves in a short space of time,+ said an oil company executive at the round.</p>
<p>State oil company Petroleos de Venezuela (PDVSA) had predicted the 20 contracts on offer this week might attract $5 billion in investment over the next 20 years, but it seems even their optimistic expectation will fall short of reality.</p>
<p>Before the Dacion bid, which attracted 12 offers from some of the largest oil companies in the world, one bidder held up a sign to the cameras: +Hi mom. Please send $$$$.+</p>
<p>It was a moment of releif in four days of hectic deal-making and gambling which at times looked more like an extended version of a television game-show.</p>
<p>Luis Urdaneta, PDVSA vice president, played host as winning bids were splashed across a massive screen, greeted by attendees with gasps and rapturous applause.</p>
<p>But Thusday was also a day of contrast, with three contracts attracting only one bidder each with offers of just $1 million and less.</p>
<p>Participants said this reflected the complex geology and high exploration risk of some fields, but also the toughness of the contractual terms.</p>
<p>Winning consortia receive a fee based on a complex formula, which participants say offers the contractor the chance to recoup their investment by raising production and then get 30 percent of the profits from any additional output, up to a pre-set ceiling.</p>
<p>+PDVSA has been very clever with this contract, they have protected the downside but they have capped the upside, so there is a very narrow margin for profitability,+ said one participant.</p>
<p>+Some companies are not bidding on economics, they just want to get into Venezuela. We want to get in here but we are not prepared to overbid,+ he added.</p>
<p>The bidding round is a key plank in PDVSA's strategy to double oil output in ten years. It sees these contracts as a way of attracting technology and capital lost in the twenty years since nationalisation.</p>
<p>((--Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2611))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
