<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639628" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary says encourages electricity firms' listing.</title>
<headline>Hungary says encourages electricity firms' listing.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's state privatisation agency APV Rt remains committed to encourage the listing of electricity distributors on the Budapest Stock Exchange this year, but the companies themselves have to initiate the flotation under Hungarian law, an APV official said.</p>
<p>&quot;APV is determined to see the six electricity distributors on the bourse,&quot; Gyorgy Pinke, head of APV's Capital Market and Property Transfer Managing Directorate, told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;However, this will not depend on APV's mood as under the securities act the company has to initiate (the listing).&quot;</p>
<p>Hungary's new securities law has been effective since the beginning of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in negotiations and we'll accelerate talks in the near future with other shareholders in order to have the electricity distributors on the bourse within the foreseeable future,&quot; Pinke said.</p>
<p>&quot;This would be good from the point of view of both the Hungarian capital market and the competition of the electricity distributors' privatisation,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Pinke said that APV would continue a share-for-compensation coupon swap programme which began last year for the electricity suppliers and would offer share packages worth three to eight percent of the suppliers' capital for coupons.</p>
<p>APV sold minority stakes in the regional electricity distributors to strategic investors in 1995.</p>
<p>In 1996, eight percent stakes were offered in each of the companies in a share-for-coupon swap,</p>
<p>Compensation coupons were awarded to victims of injustice under the country's fascist and communist regimes and were used as payment mean in privatisations.</p>
<p>The coupons trade on the Budapest Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
