<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639722" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>PANAMA: Panama phones to improve in two years - C&amp;W.</title>
<headline>Panama phones to improve in two years - C&amp;W.</headline>
<dateline>PANAMA CITY 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Improvements to Panama's telephone service should be seen within two years, a top official from new operator Britain's Cable and Wireless Plc said Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I would hope that in the next year or two you will see the real progress starting to be made,&quot; Brian Smith, chairman of the board of Cable and Wireless, told Reuters.</p>
<p>C&amp;W won a controlling 49 percent interest in Panama's National Telecommunications Institute (INTEL) last month with a bid of $652 million.  </p>
<p>Smith, on a one-day visit to Panama, said &quot;the basic fiber network for international use is there, what we've got to do is improve the access to it locally.&quot; He did not provide figures..</p>
<p>Smith attended a ceremony at the presidential palace where he presented President Ernesto Perez Balladares with a check for the company's controlling interest in INTEL.</p>
<p>Government officials expect INTEL's new operators to invest at least $500 million. Line density is expected to double and reach 25 per 100 inhabitants from 12.2 per 100 at present.</p>
<p>The concession also requires C&amp;W to set up Band B cellular service within 12 months.</p>
<p>C&amp;W beat out GTE Corp which offered $452 million, below the government's base price of $500 million. No other companies registered to bid in the auction.</p>
<p>((-- Laurens Grant, Panama City newsroom, 507 2237739))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PANAMA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PANAMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
