<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639741" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Crystallex, Placer battle on over Venezula gold.</title>
<headline>Crystallex, Placer battle on over Venezula gold.</headline>
<byline>John Paul Rathbone</byline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's Placer Dome has issued a writ in Venezuela's Supreme Court to block a recent motion filed by rival Crystallex that Crystallex says would secure its claim to the gold-rich Las Cristinas concession, a Placer spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We filed the writ in mid-May...we're hoping the case won't be heard,&quot; Placer's Hugh Leggat told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>Crystallex reiterated Thursday its claim for the Las Cristinas 4 and 6 concessions after an April 15 Supreme Court confirmed that Inversores Mael once owned the concessions. Crystallex bought Mael in late 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Crystallex) believe they have a decison which they are now going to enforce,&quot; Placer's Leggat said. But the enforcement of that decision is &quot;based on a (legal) interpretation that we believe is erroneous,&quot; Leggat added.</p>
<p>Crystallex says Mael's 1964 concession allowed for automatic renewal of the contract -- a renewal that was denied by the Ministry of Energy and Mines in 1989. Claim-staking concessions such as Mael's, that allowed for automatic renewal, were ended in 1974.</p>
<p>&quot;Crystallex's current action before the Surpreme Court includes the enformcement of its ownership right provisions for automatic renewal through the year 2014 of the concessions to Cristinas 4 &amp; 6,&quot; Crystallex said in a statement.</p>
<p>The cointinuing and increasingly acrimonious legal battle has sent Crystallex stock soaring in recent weeks. It has also spotlit Venezuelan judicial insecurity just as the country is trying to open its mining industry to foreign investment.</p>
<p>&quot;It's undeniable we have the right to the concession ... that the Ministry has not recognized that is why it (the motion) is at the Supreme Court,&quot; Crystallex Vice President Ricahrd Marshall told Reuters.</p>
<p>Marshall added he expected a Surpeme Court decision &quot;soon. We do not think it will be months.&quot;</p>
<p>Venezuelan government officials and the CVG, the Venezuelan state-owned company that is a 30 percent partner with Placer in the Cristinas project, have sided with Placer. The dispute has delayed the start of construction of $576 million mine at the site.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite a rival's claim that it holds clear title, no finacial rating agency has been willing to recognise that assertion,&quot; Crystallex added in its release.</p>
<p>Placer's Leggat countered: &quot;the strucutre of the financing is in place, all we're dickering with now is the interest rates ... although I don't deny that final clarity is necessary.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
