<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63991" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine unions vow to carry out general strike.</title>
<headline>Argentine unions vow to carry out general strike.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's biggest union group, the Central Labor Confederation (CGT), said Thursday its 36-hour general strike on September 26-27 would go ahead as planned.</p>
<p>CGT Secretary-General Rodolfo Daer, who will lead a march on President Carlos Menem's Casa Rosada government house in Buenos Aires, vowed that workers would &quot;take the Plaza de Mayo by storm,&quot; referring to the landmark plaza where the planned demonstration will take place.  </p>
<p>The CGT, in the past an ally of the Peronist government, is staging its second general strike in two months to protest the country's 17 percent unemployment rate, government austerity measures and Menem's attempts to make labor laws more flexible.</p>
<p>In a speech to regional unionists, Daer said workers would &quot;no longer put up with austerity for austerity's sake.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There are starvation pensions, poverty-line salaries and no stability or security for workers,&quot; said the new CGT chief.  </p>
<p>Menem's labor bill, which is expected to be sent to Congress this week, proposes scrapping collective pay deals and swapping redundancy payments for an unemployment insurance scheme with employer contributions. Menem threatens to push it through by decree if Congress puts up a fight.</p>
<p>The union protests escalated this week after Labor Minister Armando Caro Figueroa said he wanted pay deals to make a proportion of workers' wages variable, &quot;taking into account the economic conditions of each company.&quot;</p>
<p>The minister said Thursday he would also like the bill to include modifications in working hours and vacations.  </p>
<p>A World Bank report published Thursday in the Clarin newspaper said Argentine unemployment could drop to single digits if the government succeeded in implementing labor reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;Unemployment in Argentina could fall eight percentage points...if the government moves ahead with a reduction in labor costs and new compensation schemes that are included in the latest government labor flexibilization plan,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The World Bank said a 10 percent cut in labor costs could foster five percent job growth and that less costly redundancy rules could help employment grow by three percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
