<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="640065" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ralston on list for top U.S. officer despite affair.</title>
<headline>Ralston on list for top U.S. officer despite affair.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The White House and Pentagon said on Thursday that Air Force Gen. Joseph Ralston remained a leading candidate to become chairman of the U.S. Joint Chiefs of Staff despite an adulterous affair 13 years ago.</p>
<p>That decision not to reject Ralston's candidacy for the nation's top military job was announced after he revealed the affair this week amid a major debate in Washington over marital morals and sexual harassment in the armed forces.</p>
<p>Ralston, vice chairman of the joint chiefs, issued a statement taking &quot;full responsibility for my conduct some years ago&quot; and thanking Defence Secretary William Cohen and others for their confidence in &quot;my ability to further serve this nation.&quot;</p>
<p>Ralston, 53, gave no indication that he might withdraw his candidacy to succeed Army Gen. John Shalikashvili as chairman.</p>
<p>Cohen said in a strong statement he would make a recommendation to President Bill Clinton in the coming two weeks and stressed that Ralston remained a top candidate.</p>
<p>Ralston this week revealed to Cohen in response to media inquiries that he had an affair while separated from his first wife 13 years ago. They were later divorced.</p>
<p>&quot;I am satisfied that General Ralston's conduct was neither prejudicial to good order and discipline, nor discrediting to the armed forces,&quot; Cohen said in the statement.</p>
<p>&quot;General Ralston was a leading candidate before I learned of these events in his past and he is still a leading candidate. If I recommend General Ralston to the President, I will do so in full confidence of his character and leadership,&quot; said Cohen.</p>
<p>Beyond the issue of any violation of military law in the case, Cohen stressed, the ability to exercise moral leadership in the military &quot;does not come from notions of perfection,&quot; but from maturity and courage to learn from errors, acknowledge mistakes and and make things right.</p>
<p>The news of the Ralston affair follows a series of embarrassing cases in which U.S. officers have been removed from command or retired over allegations of adultery or sexual harassment, which is strictly prohibited in the armed forces.</p>
<p>Air Force Lt. Kelly Flinn, the first female B-52 pilot, last month agreed to accept a general discharge rather than face a court-martial on charges of adultery, lying and failing to obey orders.</p>
<p>Ralston is &quot;an outstanding soldier and an outstanding vice chairman who has outstanding qualifications for the job, but the recommendation has not yet gone to the president,&quot; White House spokeswoman Anne Luzzatto told reporters on Thursday.</p>
<p>She said Cohen had discussed Ralston's past sexual relationship with a woman who was not his wife and that &quot;he remains a candidate&quot; for the joint chiefs' chairmanship.</p>
<p>Ralston, travelling in Kazakhstan and other former Soviet states, said in a brief statement issued at the Pentagon that he was thankful for support from Cohen, Shalikashvili, his family and others in recent days.</p>
<p>&quot;I take full responsibility for my conduct some years ago and have worked diligently to learn from my mistakes. Our armed forces are composed of human beings that strive to meet the highest standards every day, but I am acutely aware of human strengths and human frailties.&quot;</p>
<p>Cohen told the Washington Post in an interview published on Thursday that the Ralston affair lasted about one year and occurred while Ralston and his first wife, Linda, were separated. The Ralstons reconciled but then divorced in 1988.</p>
<p>&quot;In my view,&quot; Cohen added in the statement on Thursday, &quot;these events standing alone do not disqualify General Ralston from possioble elevation to the position of Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.&quot;</p>
<p>While adultery is a crime in the military, the Pentagon rarely prosecutes soldiers and officers for adultery. But service members have often been forced into early retirement or had their pay and rank reduced.</p>
<p>Defence officials have said Ralston has been Cohen's favourite to succeed Shalikashvili but that Marine Corps Gen. John Sheehan, head of the U.S. military's Atlantic Command in Norfolk, Va., is also high on the list of candidates.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
