<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="640186" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Public health groups worry about tobacco deal.</title>
<headline>Public health groups worry about tobacco deal.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prominent anti-smoking advocates Thursday voiced strong doubts about any negotiated settlement between U.S. states and the tobacco industry that gave cigarette makers immunity from future lawsuits.</p>
<p>The advocates and health leaders said they wanted to make sure that any negotiated settlement looked beyond money, immunity and liability and protect future generations from tobacco.</p>
<p>With settlement talks set to resume next week between the industry and the 33 state attorneys general who have filed lawsuits, representatives of leading U.S. medical and public health groups voiced concerns that the industry will get, and Congress could approve, too much immunity from future lawsuits or too generous limits on their financial liability.</p>
<p>At a meeting of the newly-constituted Advisory Committee on Tobacco Policy and Public Health, formed at the request of some Congressional critics of the tobacco industry, is co-chaired by former U.S. Surgeon General Dr. C. Everett Koop and former Food and Drug Administration head Dr. David Kessler.</p>
<p>Neither Koop nor Kessler is directly involved with the settlement talks. Both told reporters that based on what they have heard about a proposed deal, it is &quot;not yet&quot; acceptable but that they do not want to flatly reject the possibility that a better agreement could be reached.</p>
<p>&quot;At the present time, there are very significant concerns, but I'm not ruling out the possiblity that there can be a settlement,&quot; Kessler said as he tried to mend some of the rifts that have emerged among public health advocates and identify agreement on such topics as fighting teen smoking and examining the U.S. role as a tobacco exporter.</p>
<p>The meeting had some acrimonious moments, with some members openly attacking Matt Myers, a public interest lawyer and one of the leaders of the Campaign for Tobacco Free Kids.</p>
<p>Myers has provoked the wrath of some health advocates for playing a role in the tobacco talks, and some at the meeting did not appear placated by his pledge that they would have &quot;ample time&quot; to review any settlement proposal.</p>
<p>Congress would probably have to approve any settlement. Both House Speaker Newt Gingrich and Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott this week expressed doubts about whether it would be possible to get a bill through Congress this year.</p>
<p>But some of the public health advocates fear that pressure is mounting for a swift deal, and it would be harder for them to attack a fait accompli, particularly one endorsed by the state attorneys.</p>
<p>John Banzhaf, director of Action on Smoking and Health and an advocate of pushing tobacco cases through the courts instead of settling, said of the attorneys general,  &quot;Their clients are their states, and their goal is to get a lot of money.&quot;</p>
<p>Immunity, he said, would &quot;be giving them (tobacco companies) a pardon for deaths they've caused in the past,&quot; and a license to cause more in the future.</p>
<p>The panel agreed to work swiftly, and will convene again in two weeks with proposals for education, health, research, taxation and regulation in five key areas.</p>
<p>Three teams will focus on specific populations, working on ways to prevent teenagers from taking up smoking, helping the 50 million adult smokers to quit, and protecting nonsmokers from &quot;second-hand&quot; or environmental tobacco smoke,</p>
<p>A fourth group will look at how nicotine and tobacco products can be regulated and whether they can be made less hazardous. And the fifth will examine the economic future of the industry, including the legal immunity question and the role that U.S. tobacco has in exporting.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want to become known as the largest exporter of death to developing countries,&quot; said Dr. Jonathan Fielding, a pediatrician at the University of California at Los Angeles and a leader of the Partnership for Prevention.</p>
<p>Traditionally, Congressional critics of tobacco have had an uphill battle. But several panelists said they believe that public opinion is with them and the industry is in retreat.</p>
<p>&quot;The tobacco lobby's influence even on those it has bought and paid for has rapidly eroded,&quot; said Mike Pertschuk of the Advocacy Institute. &quot;The politics of the possible have been changing daily.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
