<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="640295" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: World Bank urges G7 to back Russian CFC phase-out.</title>
<headline>World Bank urges G7 to back Russian CFC phase-out.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The World Bank on Thursday urged the world's richest countries when they meet in Denver this month to come up with about $12 million to help finance the phase-out of production of chlorofluorocarbons in Russia.</p>
<p>Under international agreements, Russia and other industrialised countries were supposed to end production of CFCs, which destroy the protective layer of ozone in the earth's atmosphere, for domestic use by 1996.</p>
<p>Russia, a major source of CFC's on the black market, said it was unable to meet the deadline because it was too costly to replace the CFCs, which are used as coolants.</p>
<p>World Bank officials said it would cost about $27 million to shut down seven CFC factories in Russia by 2000, and the Bank had raised more than half the amount needed.</p>
<p>They were counting on the Group of Seven leading industrialised democracies to agree to provide the rest of the money when they meet with Russia at their Denver summit.</p>
<p>&quot;Great progress has been made -- the technology, the financing body -- the progress is there to get rid of that problem,&quot; said Caio Koch-Weser, the World Bank's managing director of operations.</p>
<p>&quot;With the Denver summit, with Russia there, with everything else in place, this is really an appeal to the G7 to come up with the remaining amount,&quot; he said at a news briefing.</p>
<p>According to United Nations figures, Russia produced about 18,000 metric tons of CFCs in 1996.</p>
<p>Developing countries have until 2010 to phase out use of CFC's. The World Bank said it hoped that if the Russian example worked, internatinal donors would also help finance the phase-out of CFCs in major producing countries like China, India, and Brazil.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
