<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="640354" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Holder urges TRM to boost stock value.</title>
<headline>Holder urges TRM to boost stock value.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Laifer Capital Management Inc said Thursday it had urged TRM Copy Centers Corp to &quot;take proactive steps to increase the value of its shares.&quot;</p>
<p>In a filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission, Laifer, in a June 4 letter to the TRM board, suggested the company use its excess cash flow to implement a share repurchase program, dutch tender auction or special dividend.</p>
<p>Laifer said the board should then consider and take additional steps to manage the company's &quot;capital structure to benefit its owners -- the shareholders.&quot;</p>
<p>Laifer has a 11.3 percent stake in TRM, or 780,650 common shares. It holds the stake for investment purposes.</p>
<p>Laifer wrote that in spite of the good job being done by the day-to-day operating management, TRM's overly conservative capital structure and lack of focus on enhancing shareholder value were compromising shareholder returns.</p>
<p>Laifer said it believes the company's fundamental business prospects are extremely promising but the company's per share price does not reflect the intrinsic value of TRM if it were operated with a greater emphasis on return.</p>
<p>Portland, Or.,-based TRM owns and operates self-service copy centers in the United States, Canada and UK.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
