<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="640343" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX electricity higher despite weather, nukes.</title>
<headline>NYMEX electricity higher despite weather, nukes.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX electricity futures were trading higher Thursday mild weather in the U.S. West and increased generation from two key Western nuclear power units, industry sources said.</p>
<p>While physical power prices were said to have eased Thursday due to some bearish fundamentals, futures bucked the downward move as some players looked to reverse a recent sharp decline in values, sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some market players who were long on the way down are moving to try and push it up,&quot; said one Houston-based futures trader.</p>
<p>As of 1230 EDT, July Palo Verde (PV) futures were up $1.14 at $28.25 following trades in a range of $27.30-28.50 per megawatt hour (MWh), while August PV was up $1.10 at the at the day's high of $30.75 following trade as low as $30.50 per MWh.</p>
<p>July California Oregon Border (COB) was trading up $1.11 at the day's high of $18.25 following exchanges as low as $17.15 per MWh, while August was up $1.09 at the day's high of $22.25 following trade as low as $21.25 per MWh.</p>
<p>NYMEX said as of 1150 EDT and estimated total of 502 COB and 463 PV contracts had traded.</p>
<p>In the physical markets, next-day peak COB was said to be talked at $13.00-13.75 from $12.50-14.00 on Wednesday for Thursday delivery.</p>
<p>Power futures values have fallen strongly this week. On May 30, July PV settled at 33.40, while July COB settled at $24.44 per MWh.</p>
<p>Sources said fundamentals in the West remained bearish, with generation increasing and weather continuing mild.</p>
<p>The Diablo Canyon 1 and Palo Verde 3 nuclear power units continued to boost output as of early Thursday.</p>
<p>The 1,087 megawatt (MW) Diablo Canyon 1, located in Avila Beach, Calif., was operating at 48 percent of capacity as of early Thursday from 30 percent of capacity as of early Wednesday.</p>
<p>The 1,221 MW Palo Verde 3, located in Wintersburg, Ariz., was operating at 80 percent of capacity and was holding at that level for instrument calibration from 45 percent of capacity as of early Wednesday.</p>
<p>Palo Verde 3 was taken off line Saturday due to a circuit problem.</p>
<p>In the Pacific Northwest, the Bonneville Power Administration (BPA) did not offer electricity for peak hour delivery Friday, though it had been offering peak power earlier this week.</p>
<p>Trade sources said BPA was not reducing its power supply, but had simply forward sold its peak power for the next week.</p>
<p>Also, BPA said the DC (direct current) segment of the Pacific Intertie, which carries hydropower from the Northwest to southern California, tripped off line Wednesday afternoon after a crane came in contact with the line.</p>
<p>BPA said it hoped to restore the DC portion of the intertie, rated at 3,100 megawatts (MW), by late yesterday or early today.</p>
<p>As of 1225 EDT, NYMEX July Henry Hub natural gas was trading down 1.2 cents at $2.145 per million British thermal units.</p>
<p>The Southwest was forecast to see an unseasonally strong cold front through Sunday, with temperatures falling to around two to five degrees below normal.</p>
<p>Temperatures in the Pacific Northwest were forecast to average two to six degrees below normal over the same period.</p>
<p>((--Chris Reese, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1627))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
