<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="640447" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: New French minister pledges judicial independence.</title>
<headline>New French minister pledges judicial independence.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's new Socialist Justice Minister Elisabeth Guigou said on Thursday her top priority would be to restore confidence in the justice system and ensure its independence.</p>
<p>&quot;It is indispensable to restore confidence,&quot; she said at a ceremony marking the transfer of power to the new government.</p>
<p>Guigou was a surprise choice for the justice portfolio as little in her background appeared to prepare her for the delicate task of fulfilling a Socialist campaign pledge to make the judiciary independent of political authorities.</p>
<p>Outgoing minister Jacques Toubon used the handover ceremony to take a swipe at the incoming government, saying it would have a hard time equalling his achievements.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of image, you will have no problem succeeding me and even surpassing me. This will not be so easy in terms of achievement,&quot; Toubon said.</p>
<p>Toubon, who lost his seat in last Sunday's parliamentary election, was accused by the media and by Socialists of derailing sleaze investigations targeting individuals and parties from the former centre-right majority.</p>
<p>In one highly publicised incident, his ministry chartered a helicopter last year to try to track down a state prosecutor trekking in Nepal in an unsuccessful attempt to head off an inquiry into Gaullist Paris mayor Jean Tiberi.</p>
<p>Judges unions welcomed Guigou's remarks. &quot;The Socialist Party has made some precise commitments. We will now try to hold them to their word,&quot; said Jean-Pierre Boucher of the Syndicat de la Magistrature union.</p>
<p>Several major investigations involving the former centre-right majority have already been launched since Sunday's election.</p>
<p>In one case, a Paris judge placed three centrist former ministers under investigation in an investigation into alleged illegal funding of the Democratic Force party.</p>
<p>In a second case, a prosecutor opened an inquiry into suspected graft over public works contracts by the Paris regional council, led by an ally of conservative President Jacques Chirac.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
