<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64044" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAMAICA: Caribbean Community lays out plan for trade talks.</title>
<headline>Caribbean Community lays out plan for trade talks.</headline>
<byline>Michael Becker</byline>
<dateline>KINGSTON 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Caribbean Community has decided to appoint a chief negotiator for trade talks to help bring the 14-member regional bloc into free trade agreements with its neighbors by the end of the decade.</p>
<p>&quot;Never before as a region have we had to undertake so many complex negotiations simultaneously,&quot; said Jamaica's prime minister P.J. Patterson after the two-day meeting ended on Wednesday night.  </p>
<p>Five of Caricom's member countries gathered in Kingston to lay out a plan that includes searching for someone of ambassadorial rank to act as chief negotiator and coordinator of Caricom's numerous trade talks.</p>
<p>Caricom also plans to name an advisory council of private sector and government officials to provide support.  </p>
<p>Patterson said Caricom will participate in a half-dozen trade talks including the Free Trade Agreement of the Americas (FTAA); efforts to obtain NAFTA parity for Caribbean Basin exports to the United States; talks with the European Union on the Lome V trade and aid accord; and negotiations at the World Trade Organization over banana export preferences with Europe.</p>
<p>Guyana President Cheddi Jagan said the region must begin lobbying for a lengthier transition period to free trade for Caricom as part of the FTAA.  He said the Asian Pacific Economic Council (APEC) allows a 10-year period for developed countries and 20 years for less developed economies.  </p>
<p>Trinidad and Tobago's prime minister Basdeo Panday said that Caricom's intention, announced earlier this year, to sign free trade accords with blocs in south and central America by December is &quot;not possible.&quot;</p>
<p>Caricom has also agreed to proceed with an accord with Venezuela to be signed within the next two months, Panday said.</p>
<p>Talks with the Central American Common Market should begin by year-end, and Caricom is also targeting a trade deal with South American trade bloc Mercosur.</p>
<p>Five years ago Caricom and Venezuela signed a trade deal that gave Caricom exports duty-free access to Venezuela. Panday said the new trade deal would allow for &quot;two-way free trade, with the exclusion of certain Venezuelan exports that would be detrimental to smaller Caricom countries.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Miami news bureau, 305-374-5013</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CARCOM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINGSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAMAICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
