<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="640525" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: IBIS DAX index higher, stalls shy of 3,700 points.</title>
<headline>IBIS DAX index higher, stalls shy of 3,700 points.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares traded higher in late electronic trade on Thursday, but off earlier highs when the IBIS DAX index briefly threatened to penetrate the psychologically-important 3,700-point level.</p>
<p>At 1424 GMT the IBIS DAX index stood at 3,677.92 points, up 26.33 points or 0.72 percent, while the June DAX future contract stood at 3,684 points, up 23.5.</p>
<p>The index at one point went as high as 3,690.85 points, and looked set to hit 3,700, but lacked the necessary impetus to deliver the gains and fell back.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is the futures market driving us higher today,&quot; said one trader, who said the market was jittery in the absence of any new data to help deliver new gains.</p>
<p>The big corporate news of the afternoon was graphite and carbon maker SGL Carbon SGCG.F, which fell 11 percent in late trade on Thursday amid market speculation that one its units in the U.S. faced a legal battle over alleged price fixing.</p>
<p>Shares in the carbon and graphite maker ended down 29 marks, or 11.11 percent, at 232 marks. Shares in SGL Carbon were suspended in New York after share trade in Germany ended pending an announcement.  </p>
<p>No-one at the company was available for comment.</p>
<p>Dealers said the speculation surrounded charges against the company that it was allegedly involved in price fixing. &quot;But these are just rumours, nothing is confirmed,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>SGL Carbon ended bourse trade in Frankfurt earlier on down 30 pfennigs at 260.20 marks.</p>
<p>Other traders said that the share was also hit by rumours that one of SGL Carbon's rivals had discovered a carbon replacement. The share was suspended on Wall Street after German share trade ended, pending an announcement.  </p>
<p>Otherwise, interest was focused on individual stocks, with Deutsche Bank AG remaining in vogue to trade up 90 pfennigs to 99.90 marks.</p>
<p>Dealers said there was no particular reason for Deutsche's popularity, but that the bank was catching up after lagging others in the financial sector.</p>
<p>Steelmaker Thyssen AG ended up 3.60 marks at 409.60, despite a downgrade by Salomon Brothers. Other analysts had been raising their estimates on the stock, dealers said.</p>
<p>Airline Deutsche Lufthansa AG also ended sharply higher, up 1.15 marks or nearly four percent at 30.75 marks.  </p>
<p>Dealers said there was no single reason for its gains, but said sentiment regarding the share was generally good.</p>
<p>&quot;Lufthansa strikes me as a clear buy,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Adidas also traded strongly higher, ending up 4,92 percent at 199.55 marks, after losing ground recently following a profit warning by its U.S. rival Nike.</p>
<p>--Clifford Coonan, Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
