<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="640625" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Exports now less attractive - India Arvind.</title>
<headline>Exports now less attractive - India Arvind.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Exports are becoming less attractive to Indian companies due to an overvalued rupee, among other reasons, a top official of textile major Arvind Mills said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Exports are becoming less attractive,&quot; Sanjay Dalal, general manager (finance), told Reuters.</p>
<p>Arvind Mills is India's largest and the world's fifth largest manufacturer of denim fabrics.</p>
<p>The company's exports exceeded $110 million in the year ended March 31, 1997.</p>
<p>Dalal said a 10 percent fall in India's merchandise exports in April 1997 compared with the same month in 1996 was the outcome of several factors.</p>
<p>&quot;An overvalued rupee is an important factor,&quot; Dalal said. Other factors were infrastructure bottlenecks and a truckers' strike in April which held up export consignments.</p>
<p>The Indian rupee has been steady at 35.75/85 against the dollar ever since mid-1996 despite rising cost of production of Indian firms and the dollar's rise against major currencies.</p>
<p>&quot;The fall in exports during April is the first sign the overvalued rupee is beginning to hurt exports,&quot; said a foreign exchange dealer at a European bank in Bombay.</p>
<p>Infrastructure was another major constraint, Dalal said.</p>
<p>&quot;Productivity gains which will have to take place over a period of time are not happening because of infrastructure bottlenecks,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dalal said his own company was not facing any deceleration in exports. &quot;Our volumes won't be affected,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts agreed with the company's assessment.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect them to post higher exports than last year in value terms,&quot; V. Ramanan, analyst at Peregrine Capital, said.</p>
<p>He said a reduction in cotton prices this year would help Arvind Mills.</p>
<p>-- Shyam Kumar, Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
