<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="640622" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Glaxo jumps 5.0 pct on fund bids.</title>
<headline>India's Glaxo jumps 5.0 pct on fund bids.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of leading pharmaceuticals firm Glaxo India jumped 17.50 rupees, or five percent, to 349 in afternoon trade on the Bombay bourse on Thursday, traders said.</p>
<p>They said foreign funds were bidders in the stock.  </p>
<p>&quot;There's obvious buying interest in the stock,&quot; said an analyst at a foreign broking firm, adding that Glaxo was his top recommendation in the pharmaceutical sector.</p>
<p>&quot;It's our top pick in the sector primarily because of the brand equity it commands in the market,&quot; he said citing strong distribution network and good earnings growth among other investment positives.</p>
<p>He said the Glaxo shares were also rising probably due to the recent rise in the stock price of Burroughs Wellcome.</p>
<p>Shares of Burroughs have risen more than three percent this week. They were trading 5.0 rupees higher at 344 on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The swap ratio between Burroughs and Glaxo is likely to be be one-for-one,&quot; the analyst said. He was referring to Glaxo's medium-term plans to merge Burroughs Wellcome with it.</p>
<p>The two firms have a common top management.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
