<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="640775" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Junk bond new issue downpour to hit U.S. market.</title>
<headline>Junk bond new issue downpour to hit U.S. market.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investors are eagerly awaiting a downpour of junk bond deals scheduled to hit the U.S. market on Thursday, syndicate officials said.</p>
<p>Five separate junk bond offerings, representing roughly $2.3 billion (face value) of new debt are expected to price on Thursday, they noted.</p>
<p>Two of the deals are in the energy sector: TransAmerican Energy Corp's $1.53 billion two-part offering via Jefferies &amp; Co Inc and Snyder Oil Corp's $150 million offering via NationsBanc Capital Markets Inc.  </p>
<p>A telecommunications offering is also expected. InterCel Inc, a wireless phone service provider, plans to sell $300 million in debt via Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. Some of the proceeds from the offering will be set aside to guarantee the coupon payment on the notes for the first three years.</p>
<p>Falcon Building Products Inc, a maker of products for residential and commercial construction, plans to sell $245 million in debt via Smith Barney Inc.</p>
<p>The two-part offering will include $145 million in 10-year senior subordinated notes and $100 million in 10-year senior subordinated discount notes.  </p>
<p>On Thursday morning, W.R. Carpenter North America Inc sold $105 million in 10-year senior subordinated notes to yield 10.70 percent via CIBC Wood Gundy Securities Corp. The notes are rated B3/B-minus.</p>
<p>W.R. Carpenter manufactures aerial and scissor lifts.</p>
<p>New issue activity in the investment-grade corporate bond sector is expected to be light on Thursday, following moderate activity earlier in the week, syndicate officals said.</p>
<p>PECO Energy is expected to issue $50 million in 40-year capital trust securities, non-callable for five years, via Smith Barney Inc, market sources said.  </p>
<p>Market sources speculated high-grade corporate bond issuers may stay out of the market until after the release of the closely-watched monthly U.S. employment report on Friday.</p>
<p>((-Douglas Brown, 212-859-1662))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
