<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64089" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News -Sept 20.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News -Sept 20.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>The Essendon and North Melbourne Australian Football League clubs owe their strong performances this year to the personal computer as much as to players' skills. Essendon revised its tactics earlier this year after seeing a spreadsheet analysis of its players' performances, which breaks down the achievement of every AFL player according to key indicators and gives them a rating.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a bid to reassure Japanese business leaders about a sharp rise in industrial militancy, which is damaging Australia's reputation as a reliable export supplier, Prime Minister John Howard yesterday deleted a paragraph from a prepared speech which indicated there would be &quot;short-term transition costs&quot; associated with his new industrial relations legislation. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Maritime workers in the offshore oil and gas industry are set to vote on a new industrial agreement which would give them an immediate 11 per cent pay rise and provide for a historic shift from industry-level wage bargaining to company bargaining among firms providing maritime support services to the offshore oil industry.  Page 4.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In the wake of the Hindmarsh Island bridge controversy, the Federal Government is proposing a reform to the Aboriginal Heritage Protection Act which would see decisions about the &quot;sacredness&quot; of Aboriginal sites threatened by proposed developments handed over to the States. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>In Tokyo, Prime Minister John Howard has assured Japanese industry his sweeping changes to Australia's industrial relations system would produce a more efficient workforce with fewer costly strikes. Howard's assurances came in a speech to Japan's business elite and was designed to allay concerns that recent industrial unrest could impede exports to Japan. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Industrial Relations Minister Peter Reith has acknowledged the easing of wage pressures, saying increases under enterprise agreements had shown &quot;no acceleration&quot; in the three months to June. These comments have backed the optimistic view of senior Reserve Bank officials, bolstering views that a further interest rate cut might be foreseeable in the near future. Page 2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A HIV-positive man who was harassed by neighbours was awarded A$50,000 compensation yesterday in a decision by the New South Wales Equal Opportunity Tribunal, upholding the nation's only homosexual and HIV vilification laws. A Sydney pensioner and his estanged wife were ordered to pay the HIV-positive man A$25,000 each for subjecting him to verbal abuse, threats of physical violence and harassment for a year. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A member of the team investigating the Black Hawk helicopter tragedy which claimed the lives of 18 servicemen near Townsville in June, was told by Group Captain Gary Lee that mid-air near-collisions were common knowledge in the army but rarely reported to army command. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Rising domestic industrial unrest has prompted Prime Minister John Howard to delete a reference to &quot;short-term transition costs&quot; in a crucial speech selling an industrial reforms package to Japanese business. Howard claimed his reforms would deliver a more efficient and flexible labour market. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following the presentation of evidence to the inquiry into the army Black Hawk helicopter collision which claimed 18 lives, Defence Minister Ian McLachlan has pledged immediate action to rectify safety problems identified before waiting for the inquiry's final report to be tabled in December. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a landmark case in which homosexual and AIDS vilification laws have come before a tribunal for the first time since the legislation was passed in 1994, a Sydney couple has been ordered to pay A$50,000 after an Equal Opportunity Tribunal concluded that they vilified their homosexual neighbour. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>With travellers able to choose either an Australian or New Zealand airline on domestic flights from November, Transport Minister John Sharp yesterday predicted that the single aviation market between Australia and New Zealand would lead to falls in domestic air fares.  Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Keen to assure Japanese investors on his industrial relations changes, Prime Minister John Howard deleted from a prepared speech a line that suggested unemployment might go up and productivity worsen in the short term before the speech was delivered at a lunch of the Japan-Australia Business Cooperation Committee. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Retail group Coles Myer is likely to be sued by its director, largest shareholder and former chairman Solomon Lew, with Lew and his associates keen to prevent Coles reading transcripts of evidence he and his company lawyer Monica Vinson gave during the Australian Securities Commission's investigation of the Yannon transaction this year. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Winds of up to 105 kph ripped through Melbourne's outer south-eastern suburbs late on Wednesday night, leaving a trail of destruction and a multi-million-dollar repair bill. Thousands of homes experienced electricity blackouts and power surges and widespead damage was reported to homes and other buildings in Frankston, Seaford, Cranbourne and Langwarrin. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Transport Minister John Sharp yesterday announced a single aviation market worth A$5 billion a year will be open to Qantas, Ansett Australia and New Zealand's two domestic carriers from November, clearing the way for reductions in air fares of at least five per cent. Page A1.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
