<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64083" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: German Chancellor Kohl arrives in Mexico.</title>
<headline>German Chancellor Kohl arrives in Mexico.</headline>
<byline>Martin Langfield</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl arrived in Mexico on Wednesday for a four-day visit on the last leg of a tour of Latin America.</p>
<p>Kohl arrived at Mexico City's international airport shortly before 10.30 p.m. (0330 GMT) and was greeted by Mexican Foreign Minister Jose Angel Gurria.</p>
<p>Kohl, who was accompanied by 14 government officials and 11 top businessmen, made no statement to waiting reporters.</p>
<p>As his plane was approaching Mexico, a passenger jet of German airline Lufthansa had to return to Mexico City after authorities received a bomb threat, an airport official said.</p>
<p>No bomb was found after the plane made a safe landing, the official told Reuters. There was no indication of who had made the threat, although the government has attributed a spate of bomb threats in several cities in recent weeks to the leftist rebel Popular Revolutionary Army (EPR).</p>
<p>The EPR denies making the threats and says they are part of a government disinformation campaign against them.</p>
<p>Kohl was due to meet President Ernesto Zedillo on Thursday and to receive the keys of Mexico City from Mayor Oscar Villareal before visiting on Friday the central city of Puebla, where German auto firm Volkswagen has a large production plant and will make its new Beetle car.</p>
<p>Kohl was then scheduled to travel to the eastern Yucatan peninsula to visit the city of Merida, Maya ruins at Chichen Itza and the holiday resort of Cancun before leaving Mexico on Saturday.</p>
<p>High on Kohl's agenda was the issue of free trade talks due to begin in October between Mexico and the European Union, which Mexican officials hope will allow their country to diversify its trade links, now heavily weighted towards the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;Germany has been an important motor for seeking the accord with the European Union,&quot; Mexico's deputy Foreign Minister Juan Rebolledo said earlier on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Bilateral trade between the two countries in 1995 was $3.2 billion, making Germany Mexico's biggest EU trading partner, although Mexico is keen to reduce its trade deficit of almost $2.2 billion with Germany.</p>
<p>Despite the Mexican peso crisis of late 1994 and ensuing deep recession, German investment in Mexico last year rose to $3.15 billion from $2.61 billion in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;For us it is not only important that the established companies have expansion plans, but also to attract new companies,&quot; Rebolledo said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
