<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="640991" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE coffee slows decline on roaster support.</title>
<headline>LIFFE coffee slows decline on roaster support.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>LIFFE coffee futures slowed their decline by Thursday midsession as trade selling found keen roaster buying at the lows.</p>
<p>Traders said while technicals point to more downside potential after the recent sharp sell-off, manufacturer buying on the dips could help the market consolidate at these levels.</p>
<p>Benchmark September sank to an intraday low of $2,060 a tonne, just above its immediate support at $2,040, before ending the morning at $2,100, still a $15 loss.</p>
<p>Front-month July also ended the session with pared losses but managed to steer clear of the closely-watched $2,000 support. It stood at $2,070, down $13, after a low of $2,020.</p>
<p>Dealings were quite slow with the bulk of the activity centred on structure. July/Sept switch was actively-trade at $30.</p>
<p>In the outrights, traders said trade selling was well absorbed by roaster price-fixing. Food giant Nestle was rumoured to make a buying comeback but the volume was far less aggressive that last's week buying spree.</p>
<p>Nestle is said to be looking for a large share of the Mexican robusta imports recently approved by the government.</p>
<p>The company is the leader in the soluble market in the country. The government had allowed import of up to 150,000 bags of robustas to help fill in a supply gap.</p>
<p>New York's nearby arabica futures prices stayed low  by the close on Wednesday on news of Colombia opening &quot;unlimited&quot; coffee sales for July to August.</p>
<p>On the weather front, no damaging cold was expected for Brazil's coffee growing regions this weekend although cooling temperatures to between below and well below normal levels were predicted.</p>
<p>The last severe frosts in 1994, one in June and another in July, devastated Brazilian crop and sent world prices spiralling.</p>
<p>-- Jalil Hamid, London newsroom +44 171 542 4985</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
