<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641046" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli officers gambled while on Holocaust tour.</title>
<headline>Israeli officers gambled while on Holocaust tour.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel ordered its army on Thursday to investigate the behaviour of commanders-in-training who gambled their nights away at Polish casinos while touring Nazi Holocaust death camps by day.</p>
<p>Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai demanded the army immediately launch an investigation and submit &quot;conclusions and recommendations&quot; after it admitted several officers had visited casinos two or three times during the trip to Poland.</p>
<p>Israel Radio said nearly 60 officers at the Jewish state's School of High Command hit hotel casinos for six nights.</p>
<p>It said they also played cards while on the bus to the Auschwitz-Birkenau camp, where the Nazis killed at least a million of the six million Jews they systematically exterminated during World War Two.</p>
<p>&quot;We are speaking of seven, eight officers and not the whole group who during the two or three nights visited casinos and that in itself testifies to poor judgment,&quot; Brigadier-General Yossi Raveh, commander of the school, told the radio.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a lack of sensitivity even for a private visit and certainly when it's a visit on the part of the army and an official visit for that matter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Raveh had said he was unsure whether disciplinary steps would be necessary. Overall the tour was respectable and emotional, and top officers had been moved to tears, he said.</p>
<p>But he added further educational steps were needed.</p>
<p>&quot;We must examine how we got to this situation,&quot; he said. &quot;It's certainly judgment we are sorry about.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
