<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641070" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraq slams U.S. for holding up education contracts.</title>
<headline>Iraq slams U.S. for holding up education contracts.</headline>
<byline>Leon Barkho</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Iraqi minister accused the United States of impeding contracts to supply Iraq with education material under its U.N. oil-for-food deal.</p>
<p>Education minister Abduljabbar Tawfiq said the Americans blocked a contract with Pakistan for the purchase of one million pencils, saying the graphite in them could be used to paint missile warheads.</p>
<p>Tawfiq told a news conference that Iraq was in desperate need of more school buildings, desks, inks and spare parts to run its printing houses.</p>
<p>Under the deal which the Security Council renewed for next six months on Wednesday, Iraq had allocated $12 million to meet needs in the education sector, he said.</p>
<p>Iraq signed contracts in January but none passed the U.N. sanctions committee due to &quot;the obstructive attitude&quot; of the U.S. envoy.</p>
<p>&quot;We expected the materials to reach us in three months to be used before the start of the academic year (in September),&quot; the minister said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have received nothing so far and have not even been told of the result of our contracts.&quot;</p>
<p>He said also Iraq money for education in its three Kurdish provinces in northern Iraq. &quot;To my knowledge they have also received nothing so far,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tawfiq said Iraq needed billions of dollars to rehabilitate its educational system.</p>
<p>He said no school was built in nearly seven years of U.N. trade sanctions and classes were crammed with pupils. Tens of thousand were sitting on the ground for lack of desks and books had to be recycled.</p>
<p>Prior to U.N. trade sanctions imposed on Iraq for invading Kuwait in 1990, Iraq spent about $12.5 billion every year on education, Tawfiq added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
