<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641064" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Ruling on fx dealings puts UAE banks on the spot.</title>
<headline>Ruling on fx dealings puts UAE banks on the spot.</headline>
<byline>Hilary Gush</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A United Arab Emirates court ruling that foreign currency dealings which are speculative by nature are against Islamic sharia law and illegal has sparked widespread debate in the Gulf Arab state.</p>
<p>Bankers and lawyers say the judgement at issue is that of the Abu Dhabi Federal Supreme Court, which ruled in favour of an investor who took a bank to court after losses of some $380,000 on currency transactions made on the plaintiff's behalf.</p>
<p>&quot;This judgement was based on the ground that the buying and selling of foreign currency is done via speculation to generate profit and there are no actual goods or currency transacted by sale or purchase,&quot; UAE lawyer Essam al-Tamimi said.</p>
<p>&quot;(It) underscores and expands the Court's hostility to margin trading,&quot; lawyers Afridi &amp; Angell said in their latest newsletter, referring to the bank practice allowing customers to assume significant positions in foreign currencies on the basis of a 10 percent cash margin held by the bank.</p>
<p>The judgement was made last year, but only recently attracted debate once it was translated into English.</p>
<p>Lawyers said the court viewed the contract as no more than gambling, banned in Islam, by betting on currency fluctuations in a bid to make profit, rather than actually buying currency.</p>
<p>&quot;The specific ruling was in regard to margin trading, which is different from everyday forex dealing between corporates and banks,&quot; said one Western treasurer based in Dubai.</p>
<p>&quot;But it certainly does give banks something to think about and underscores the fact that banks need to know their customer and keep in mind the legal framework,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Others said it was cause for concern as banks in the UAE are specifically authorised by Central Bank regulation to engage in currency trading. &quot;No one held a gun to his (the plaintiff's) head and forced him into the transaction,&quot; a senior banker said.</p>
<p>&quot;Banks ought to be careful. They must be sure their clients are prepared to take risk. Businessmen also should not engage bankers who are trading above their heads,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;The suitability and appropriateness of the transaction is the issue. The client needs to be fully aware of the risk potential, because many are not,&quot; a Central Bank source said.</p>
<p>Lawyers said the result of the ruling would differ depending on where banks are in the UAE. As Dubai and Ras al-Khaimah emirates of the seven-member UAE have their own courts, which are not part of the federal judicial system, the Abu Dhabi ruling does not affect them directly.</p>
<p>In fact, Dubai has ruled differently in similar cases.</p>
<p>&quot;This judgement stands in marked contrast with the reasoning followed by the Court of Cassation in Dubai, which has consistently viewed both commodity and currency futures trading as inherently enforceable, focusing instead on whether the customer authorised the disputed trades,&quot; Afridi &amp; Angell said.</p>
<p>This means that banks will feel more secure carrying out these transactions in Dubai rather than the capital, Abu Dhabi. &quot;People will just close their accounts in Abu Dhabi and move to Dubai, or even offshore,&quot; said a lawyer, adding the ruling flew in the face of efforts to make the UAE the Gulf's financial hub.</p>
<p>&quot;Indeed, things in Dubai will be no different from any other western country where foreign currency transactions are considered perfectly legal and subject to the agreement entered into by the contracting parties,&quot; Tamimi said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
