<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641137" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ralston candidate for top U.S officer despite affair.</title>
<headline>Ralston candidate for top U.S officer despite affair.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Cohen has not disqualified Air Force Gen. Joseph Ralston as a top candidate to become the U.S. military's commanding officer despite Ralston's adulterous affair 13 years ago, the Pentagon said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;He has not made any final decision, but he has not disqualified Ralston because of this,&quot; Pentagon spokesman Ken Bacon told Reuters as the key question arose over Ralston's candidacy to become new Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</p>
<p>Cohen told the Washington Post in an interview published on Thursday he had decided to retain Ralston, currently vice chairman of the joint chiefs, as a top candidate to succeed Army Gen. John Shalikashvili as chairman later this year.</p>
<p>The controversy arose on the heels of a series of embarrassing cases in which U.S. military officers have been removed from command or retired over allegations of adultery, which is strictly prohibited in the armed forces.</p>
<p>Cohen told the Post that the Ralston affair was about a year long and occurred while Ralston and his first wife, Linda, were separated. The Ralstons reconciled for a time, but divorced in 1988.</p>
<p>Ralston, travelling in Kazakstan, denied through a senior Cohen aide that his affair continued during the time he reconciled with Linda, the Post said. He has since remarried.</p>
<p>Bacon told Reuters that Ralston did not reveal the affair that he had with a CIA employee until news media organisations inquired about it this week.</p>
<p>&quot;He did not believe it was an issue,&quot; said Bacon.</p>
<p>Defence officials have said Ralston has been Cohen's favourite to succeed Shalikashvili but that Marine Corps Gen. John Sheehan, head of the U.S. military's Atlantic Command in Norfolk, Va., is also high on the list of candidates.</p>
<p>Cohen made the decision to keep Ralston in consideration after consulting with President Bill Clinton on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Clinton in the coming weeks will nominate a successor to Shalikashvili, who retires in September, and the Senate will vote on that nomination.</p>
<p>In recent public statements, Cohen has stood firmly behind strict rules in the military which make marital cheating technically a crime and prohibit most social contact between officers and lower-ranking members of the military.</p>
<p>But he told the Post in the interview that the line had to be drawn somewhere. &quot;We need to come back to a rule of reason instead of a rule of thumb,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cohen told the Post he would wait another week or two before making a final recommendation to Clinton, possibly to gauge public opinion.</p>
<p>&quot;This (Ralston affair) occurred a long time ago and the secretary feels that it is not a threat to good order and discipline&quot; in the military, Bacon said on Thursday. &quot;In a perfect world, there would be no separations or divorces.&quot;</p>
<p>While adultery is a crime in the military, the Pentagon rarely prosecutes soldiers and officers for adultery. But service members have often been forced into early retirement or had their pay and rank reduced.</p>
<p>News of Ralston's adulterous affair came just after Air Force Major Kelly Flinn, the first female B-52 pilot, agreed to accept a general discharge rather than face a court-martial on charges of adultery, lying and failing to obey orders.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
