<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641250" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian appeal court upholds Craxi graft sentence.</title>
<headline>Italian appeal court upholds Craxi graft sentence.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Italian appeal court on Thursday upheld a jail sentence of eight years and three months for disgraced former prime minister Bettino Craxi on charges of corruption.</p>
<p>Craxi, who served as Socialist prime minister from 1983 to 1987, was convicted in April 1996 of corruption relating to the construction of Milan's underground system in the 1980s.</p>
<p>At the trial, Craxi, who now lives in self-imposed exile in Tunisia, was alleged to have taken bribes for himself and his Socialist party in exchange for supporting companies' bids to build the system.</p>
<p>This is not the final stage of the appeal process. Appeals can go to the Court of Cassation, Italy's highest court, and under the country's judicial system the conviction does not take effect until the appeal process is exhausted.</p>
<p>The appeal court quashed a three-year sentence against onetime Communist member of parliament Gianni Cervetti, convicted in the same trial of illegal party funding.</p>
<p>But it upheld the conviction of businessman Luigi Civard who was also tried alongside Craxi.</p>
<p>The Court of Cassation has already confirmed a five and a half year prison sentence against Craxi for illegal party funding, meaning he would go to jail if he returned to Italy.</p>
<p>Craxi has appeals pending against other convictions and has jail sentences totalling more than 25 years hanging over him.</p>
<p>Italy has requested an international arrest warrant for Craxi but Tunisia has not responded. Italy cannot request extradition unless such a warrant has been served.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
