<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641222" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French Socialist sentenced in party financing case.</title>
<headline>French Socialist sentenced in party financing case.</headline>
<dateline>LYON, France 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A French court gave a former leader of the ruling Socialist Party, Henri Emmanuelli, an 18-month suspended sentence on Thursday for illicit party fundraising activities.</p>
<p>The court announced the sentence hours after the cabinet of Socialist Prime Minister Lionel Jospin cabinet took office following the left's victory in last Sunday's parliamentary election.</p>
<p>The verdict, due a week ago, had been postponed to avoid interfering with the campaign. Emmanuelli was re-elected to parliament on Sunday.</p>
<p>A former cabinet minister who served as Socialist party treasurer in the 1980s and leader in 1994-95, Emmanuelli was charged with handling stolen goods and influence-peddling.</p>
<p>He had already been convicted on similar charges in a 1995 trial in Brittany when he was given a one-year suspended jail term and a 30,000 franc ($5,150) fine for receiving illicit campaign funds from a front company run by party insiders.</p>
<p>Emmanuelli took political reponsibility for schemes to funnel money to the party in the late 1980s via the Urba consultancy firm, which took rake-offs on public works contracts.</p>
<p>But he said he had not profited personally and denied breaking the law.</p>
<p>Lawyers argued that there had been a legal vacuum at the time on political financing.</p>
<p>All mainstream French parties ran covert funding schemes before a 1990 law put party finances on a legal footing.</p>
<p>Magistrates are investigating similar cases involving the centre-right RPR and UDF parties and the Communist party. ($ = 5.825 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LYON, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
