<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641454" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU FINANCE MINISTERS TO MEET ON EMU ON SUNDAY.</title>
<headline>EU FINANCE MINISTERS TO MEET ON EMU ON SUNDAY.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Gaunt</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union finance ministers will meet for a special session on Sunday evening in Luxembourg where their struggling plans for economic and monetary union (EMU) are expected to take pride of place.</p>
<p>The get-together for cocktails and dinner before a regular session on Monday has long been planned. But it will now take place amid the most serious worries to date about plans for the single currency.</p>
<p>The ability of Germany and France to meet the strict tests for EMU have been thrown into doubt by an aborted German plan to revalue gold and the election of a French Socialist government hostile to further economic austerity.</p>
<p>Sunday's meeting will be the first chance the finance ministers will have had to quiz their German counterpart Theo Waigel about what many of them see as questionable moves to ensure German EMU qualification.</p>
<p>It is also expected to be their first chance to size up their new French colleague Dominique Strauss-Kahn, who was appointed on Wednesday, and to gauge how serious is the new French government's threat to open up the Stability Pact agreed at last December's EU summit in Dublin.</p>
<p>One EU diplomat noted that European Commission President Jacques Santer considered the meeting important enough to urge the Dutch EU presidency not to hold a special foreign ministers meeting at the same time to discuss EU treaty negotiations.</p>
<p>Santer wanted to attend the finance ministers' meeting, the diplomat said.</p>
<p>Officially, the Sunday evening meeting was organised to allow the ministers to consider designs of new euro coins before the EU summit in Amsterdam on June 16 and 17.</p>
<p>It was believed that an extra meeting was needed because most of Monday morning's session would be taken up with the annual meeting between finance ministers and the European Investment Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been in the pipeline for some time,&quot; the diplomat said.</p>
<p>But he said it was clear that ministers would discuss both on Sunday and again on Monday outstanding EMU issues including the Stability Pact and the post-EMU exchange rate mechanism, issues that must be formally agreed at the EU summit in Amsterdam.</p>
<p>The Stability Pact is designed to enforce budgetary rigour in participating EMU countries after its launch. It has been criticised by the incoming French government.</p>
<p>Europe's plans for a single currency to begin on January 1, 1999, have been shaken in recent weeks, first by German plans to revalue gold reserves to help meet EMU criteria and secondly by the French election.</p>
<p>Waigel backed down in a confrontation with the Bundesbank on Tuesday, giving up a controversial plan to force the central bank to pay out this year the profits from a gold revaluation.</p>
<p>He told a stormy parliamentary session in Bonn that he and Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer had agreed an approach to revalue bank assets and to pay out extra profits next year, a gain which would thus be too late to help the 1997 finances on which EMU qualification will be based.</p>
<p>His original proposal was seen as a sign that Germany was struggling to meet the criteria and that its politicians might be willing to fudge.</p>
<p>With the French Socialists also campaigning against further austerity, market analysts say the choice for the bloc now is a stark one between starting EMU on time with a weaker-than-planned currency or delaying the project.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
