<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641644" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK people show China defiant mettle over Tiananmen.</title>
<headline>HK people show China defiant mettle over Tiananmen.</headline>
<byline>Peter Humphrey</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong people have sent a powerful signal to Beijing that they will not give up their pro-democracy protests after the government that crushed China's 1989 democracy movement becomes their new master.</p>
<p>Some 55,000 people from all walks of life turned out for a candlelit vigil on Wednesday night in a vivid denunciation of the military crackdown against the Tiananmen Square student movement which killed hundreds, possibly thousands.</p>
<p>The rally produced only minor, last-minute scuffles with police over whether a democracy icon called the &quot;Pillar of Shame&quot; could be placed on the campus of Hong Kong University.</p>
<p>But the otherwise orderly behaviour of demonstrators holding flickering candles showed this was no melee of reckless youth but a cross-section of Hong Kong's thriving civic society.</p>
<p>Intellectuals and politicians, Chinese dissidents, grandmothers and grandfathers, parents and children, besuited lawyers and businessmen, entire families. All categories came.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very happy with such a good turnout. It shows people in Hong Kong do not forget what happened on June 4, 1989,&quot; said Yeung Sum, a leader of Hong Kong's Democratic Party.</p>
<p>&quot;This meeting has been a very peaceful one and I don't see why we can't hold this gathering next year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked what the movement would do if the vigil is banned next year, he said activists would resort to civil disobedience and hold it anyway and &quot;pay the price for it&quot;.</p>
<p>With Britain's 156-year-long rule over Hong Kong expiring in 26 days time, fears of communist-style repression by the new sovereign power run high among Hong Kong's 6.4 million people.</p>
<p>Future leader Tung Chee-hwa, carefully appointed by Beijing, has launched plans to trim back civil rights and electoral democracy. The elected legislature is also to be dissolved, at least until fresh polls are held in 1998 -- under new rules.</p>
<p>Political analyst Michael DeGolyer at Hong Kong's Baptist University said Wednesday's rally was a clear message to Tung and China that the protest movement would continue.</p>
<p>Tung urged people to forget Tiananamen on the eve of the rally in the interests of a &quot;smooth transition&quot; and instead to look to the future and set aside the &quot;baggage of June 4&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;This was pretty much a reply to that,&quot; DeGolyer said of the rally. &quot;It's not going to happen.&quot;</p>
<p>Tung seemed unfazed that Hong Kong people had ignored his plea to forget the 1989 Beijing massacre and halt the rallies.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Tung's position is the same as before. It is not going to change overnight,&quot; a spokesman for his office said.</p>
<p>Such protests also tested the notion of &quot;one country two systems&quot; and &quot;Hong Kong people ruling Hong Kong&quot;, promises made by China in terms of the sovereignty transfer agreed with Britain in 1984, DeGolyer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking at Wednesday night's turnout and the quiet determination of the people there, it's clear that a very large segment of the Hong Kong community has developed a unity and an interest in politics...and in determining to protect their freedom and their rights.</p>
<p>&quot;The slogan of Hong Kong people ruling Hong Kong does have some substance now,&quot; DeGolyer said.</p>
<p>The success of the latest vigil bolstered the confidence of pro-democracy legislators who face unemployment on July 1, when the provisional legislature loyal to Beijing takes over.</p>
<p>It was, too, a poignant memorial to the victims when People's Liberation Army tanks and troops stormed into Beijing.</p>
<p>Many shed a tear as they sang anthems associated with the annual candlit vigils held each year since 1989 in the park named after Britain's 19th century Queen Victoria.</p>
<p>The towering grey &quot;Pillar of Shame&quot; statue of twisted human bodies depicting oppression stood spotlit in the dark.</p>
<p>Protesters urged Beijing to strike down its verdict the protesters were counter-revolutionaries. But there were few signs of past anger and no crude effigies of Chinese leaders.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
