<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641731" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: DKB says informed foreign regulators about loans.</title>
<headline>DKB says informed foreign regulators about loans.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Katsuhiko Kondo, president of Dai-Ichi Kangyo Bank Ltd, said on Thursday that the bank has informed overseas regulators about loans linked to racketeers.  </p>
<p>Kondo said the bank had not been told by any overseas regulators that they would annul DKB's business licences.</p>
<p>Kondo was appearing before the budget committee of the Lower House of parliament as an unsworn witness regarding questionable loans to racketeer Ryuichi Koike, the figure at the centre of a payoff scandal involving Nomura Securities Co Ltd.  </p>
<p>Kondo told the committee that he had begun to doubt the credibility of the DKB's internal investigation which found that questionable loans were made to a company owned by Yoshinori Koike, the younger brother of Ryuichi Koike.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm getting a feeling that there might be the presence of Ryuichi Koike&quot; in the loans provided to his younger brother and his company, he said.</p>
<p>DKB has admitted extending a total of 27.5 billion yen in loans to the company run by Koike's younger brother and his company, but does not think loans were made to Koike.</p>
<p>DKB has also admitted concealing non-performing loans to them during Ministry of Finance (MOF) inspections in 1990 and 1994.</p>
<p>The two Koike brothers were arrested last month on suspicion of taking about 50 million yen in illegal payments from Nomura Securities.</p>
<p>Kondo told the committee that the loans to the younger Koike and his company were extended through the bank's general affairs section.</p>
<p>The general affairs sections of Japanese companies traditionally handle any dealings with racketeers, financial industry sources said.  </p>
<p>Kondo said he felt deeply responsible for not recognising earlier the existence of the questionable loans.</p>
<p>On May 23, top executives of DKB, including Kondo, announced that they would resign after the bank's  annual shareholders' meeting on June 26 to take responsibility for the loan scandal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
