<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64180" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Euroyen end flat after hitting new high.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Euroyen end flat after hitting new high.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Euroyen futures ended steady on Thursday as the market shed its early gains following an afternoon bounce in the Nikkei.</p>
<p>After creeping up to a new contract high of 99.20 in thin early dealings, March Euroyen finished at 99.17 against its CME close at 99.17 on light volume of 5830 lots.</p>
<p>&quot;It might have been a little bit overbought,&quot; said a trader with a U.S. institution. He said the March contract was likely to be supported at 99.15 and at the more solid level of 99.12.  </p>
<p>Dealers said sentiment on Euroyen and Japanese government bond (JGB) futures remained bullish on expectations the Bank of Japan would not hike interest rates this year.</p>
<p>December JGBs ended at 122.23 against their opening 122.40. Eurodollar futures were little changed after being glued in a tight band as players sat on their hands ahead of the Federal Reserve's policy-setting meeting on September 24.</p>
<p>The dearth of major economic indicators and uncertainty over the Fed's likely stance on interest rates next week kept trading interest to a minimum, dealers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Eurodollars traded in a one-tick range until the afternoon,&quot; said a dealer. The most active December contract finished at 94.08 against its IMM settlement at 94.07.</p>
<p>-- Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
