<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641871" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Guangnan plans US$100 mln bonds issue.</title>
<headline>Guangnan plans US$100 mln bonds issue.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Guangnan (Holdings) Ltd said on Thursday it proposed to issue not less than US$100 million in guaranteed convertible bonds due 2000.</p>
<p>The live and fresh food distributor said the bonds would bear interest at a rate to be fixed on the closing date of the offering which was expected to be on June 18.</p>
<p>The bonds holders will have the right to convert the bonds into Guangnan shares at any time prior to the maturity of the bonds which will be redeemed on June 17, 2000, at about 100 percent of the principal together with interest, it said.</p>
<p>Guangnan said it would be required to issue 56 million new shares, or 6.3 percent of its enlarged share capital, on full conversion of the bonds into company shares.</p>
<p>The company will also be required to issue up to a further US$10 million bonds to cover over-allotments, it said.</p>
<p>Application has been made to list the bonds in Luxembourg. Goldman Sachs (Asia) L.L.C. is the manager of the bond issue.</p>
<p>It gave no further details on the bond issue.</p>
<p>Guangnan said the net proceeds of bond issue after expenses would be equivalent to about 97.3 percent of the gross proceeds of the offering.</p>
<p>About HK$114 million will be used to buy an interest in seven companies under Guangdong Anhua Pearl Industry Group Co Ltd, a prawn and pearl farming concern, the company said.</p>
<p>It said about HK$40 million would be used to build a central warehouse in China's Guangdong Province for distributing imported foodstuffs and daily necessities to its supermarket outlets in Guangdong Province, and HK$100 million would be used to buy an interest in seasoning powders joint ventures.</p>
<p>Guangnan said it planned to spend HK$100 million in 1997 to expand the number of its supermarkets outlets in Hong Kong and in China and the balance of the offering would be used to finance other acquisitions and for general corporate purposes.</p>
<p>The company's shares eased HK$0.10 to HK$12.75 in early trade on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6370.  http://www.hk97.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
