<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641852" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China frees dissident on Tiananmen anniversary.</title>
<headline>China frees dissident on Tiananmen anniversary.</headline>
<byline>Scott Hillis</byline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prominent Shanghai dissident Bao Ge has been freed from a Chinese labour camp, after being detained for three years without trial, friends of his family said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Bao Ge was released at 8.30 last night (1230 GMT),&quot; said a family friend who requested anonymity.</p>
<p>Bao, 33, had written to his family in May saying he expected to be released on the eighth anniversary of China's June 4, 1989 crackdown on pro-democracy demonstrations centred on Beijing's Tiananmen Square.</p>
<p>Telephone lines to the family's Shanghai home had been cut and police had warned family members not to talk to journalists, the family friend said.</p>
<p>&quot;The police came over yesterday before they released him and told (the family) not to talk to foreign reporters,&quot; she said. Family members could not be contacted for comment.</p>
<p>Bao was sentenced in September 1994 to three years of &quot;re-education through labour&quot;, a form of administrative detention that can be imposed without trial.</p>
<p>His release came eight years after China sent troops and tanks into Beijing to crush the student-led pro-democracy protests in central Tiananmen Square.</p>
<p>Bao's mother, Wang Yufen, said earlier there was no link between his release and the emotive anniversary, but a Western diplomat said she doubted it was sheer coincidence.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a message that they (Chinese authorities) are comfortable enough with this day that they can go ahead and do this,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Bao had been a member of the Shanghai-based Association for Human Rights, but was better known to the authorities as a campaigner for compensation from Tokyo for Chinese victims of Japanese war atrocities.</p>
<p>The issue of Japanese compensation is politically sensitive because Beijing signed away all such claims in the 1970s, a decision that still infuriates many Chinese.</p>
<p>Bao has frequently been jailed for his outspoken views, and sparked a diplomatic flap when he and another dissident were detained during a visit to Shanghai by then French prime minister Edouard Balladur in April 1994.</p>
<p>Bao's mother said last month she had not seen her son for more than 18 months as authorities would not allow her to visit him.</p>
<p>She said she was worried he would get into more trouble by protesting to the authorities that his three-year detention was illegal.</p>
<p>China's small circle of active dissidents has dwindled in recent years, with most activists fleeing into exile or serving lengthy jail terms.</p>
<p>Last week a court in the southern boom city of Shenzhen jailed two labour activists for 3-1/2 years each for conspiring to subvert the government in a ruling denounced by human rights groups.</p>
<p>Beijing frequently comes under fire from Western governments and human rights watchdogs for its heavy-handed treatment of political dissidents.</p>
<p>China rejects such criticism of its human rights record as interference in its internal affairs, arguing that ensuring adequate food and clothing for its 1.2 billion people is more important than political freedoms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
