<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641993" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALTA: PRESS DIGEST - Malta - June 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malta - June 5.</headline>
<dateline>VALLETTA 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the leading stories in the Maltese press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>- Court finds discrimination in expropriation of foreshore. The previous government last year expropriated part of the coast belonging to a restaurant to ensure that swimmers were allowed access. The court found the measure was discriminatory because public purpose to justify expropriation had not been proved and there were many other establishments that enjoyed beach concessions and had not had their properties expropriated.</p>
<p>L-ORIZZONT</p>
<p>- Malta Drydocks offers 275,000 Malta pounds (about $1 million) compensation for relatives of tanker explosion victims. Nine workers died when a small Libyan tanker exploded in an accident at Malta Drydocks in February 1995. Compensation is the subject of a court case, but the dockyard is seeking to settle out of court.</p>
<p>IN-NAZZJON</p>
<p>- Government-Chamber of Commerce argue over new tax system. Members of the Chamber argued at a meeting with Prime Minister Alfred Sant on Wednesday that a new excise tax on services, being introduced on July 1, will hit profits of companies relying on sub-contracting, such as advertising agencies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALTA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALLETTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALTA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
