<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641901" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: PRESS DIGEST - Taiwan newspapers - June 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Taiwan newspapers - June 5.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Taiwan press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>Newspaper headlines</p>
<p>CHINA TIMES - Nationalist, Democratic Progressive parties sign agreement to cooperate in amending constitution</p>
<p>Floods wreak havoc to central, southern Taiwan, one killed, two missing</p>
<p>UNITED DAILY NEWS - Democratic Progressive Party faces imminent split due to internal rift over constitutional amendments, opponents demand resignation of party chief</p>
<p>Fifty-thousand attend candlelight vigil in Hong Kong in memory of victims of 1989 crackdown at Beijing's Tiananmen</p>
<p>LIBERTY TIMES - National Science Council issues white paper on state plan to develop Taiwan into technology centre</p>
<p>COMMERCIAL TIMES - Cabinet to review proposal on imposing 10 percent tax on retained surplus gains</p>
<p>Economic and trade activities to be axis of future Taiwan, Hong Kong relations</p>
<p>ECONOMIC DAILY NEWS - Chinese Petroleum, Taiwan Sugar plan selloff of all their China Petrochemical shares</p>
<p>Bank of Taiwan reduces interest rates on long-term time deposits</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
