<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641905" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine inflation falls to ten-year low.</title>
<headline>Philippine inflation falls to ten-year low.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine inflation in May fell to a ten-year low since July 1987, the National Statistics Office said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The agency reported earlier that year-on-year inflation in May slackened to 4.2 percent in May compared with 4.6 percent in April.</p>
<p>That is the lowest increase since June 1987, when it reached 4.0 percent.</p>
<p>The agency said the year-on-year decline in the May inflation rate were led by three areas.</p>
<p>Food, beverages and tobacco, which comprise 58.5 percent of the consumer price index, went down by 0.6 percentage points.</p>
<p>Fuel, light and water, which make up 4.5 percent of the total, slipped 1.5 percentage points. Clothing, which accounts for 4.35 percent of the total, dipped 0.1 percentage point.</p>
<p>However, services, which contribute 10.9 percent of the index, rose 0.2 percentage points on a year-on-year basis. Housing and repairs, which contribute 13.3 percent of the total, were unchanged.</p>
<p>In Metro Manila, year-on-year inflation slowed to 5.9 percent in May from 6.0 in April. In areas outside Metro Manila, inflation was 3.6 percent in May, lower than the 4.0 percent in April, the agency said.</p>
<p>- Manila Newsroom 63 2 841-8937 fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
