<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642021" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Eurotunnel sets French shareholder hotline.</title>
<headline>Eurotunnel sets French shareholder hotline.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Channel Tunnel operator Eurotunnel SA/Plc said on Thursday it has set up a special telephone line for French small investors to support its July 10 shareholders' meeting which will vote on its debt restructuring.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel is also launching a financial information campaign in the press, to get as many shareholders as possible to take part in the meeting, it said in a statement.</p>
<p>Shareholders can use the telephone hot line to ask for documents including the restructuring prospectus, voting forms and a guide to shareholder meetings.</p>
<p>&quot;Following the many difficulties encountered last year by our shareholders in taking part in our meetings, I have personally asked the stock market authorities to ensure that similar problems will not recur,&quot; Eurotunnel executive chairman Patrick Ponsolle said in the statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The exceptional measure that we have put in place this year is the result of our official consultations. I hope that it will allow a high level of shareholder participation in decisions that concern them directly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel has 721,000 small shareholders, of which around 600,000 are in France.</p>
<p>The company needs a two thirds majority of French shareholder and 75 percent of British investors to approve the refinancing of its 70 billion francs of junior bank debt.</p>
<p>The terms include a dilution of existing shareholders down to 54.5 percent of the capital, with new shares to being issued to creditor banks in exchange for eight billion francs of debt.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel last week presented its restructuring prospectus and said it could pay a first dividend in 2006 if it makes a net profit in 2005, using what it called a &quot;base case&quot;. That compares to a forecast first payout in 2003 in its prospectus for the 1994 rights issue.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
