<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642013" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU set to raise doubts over P&amp;O/Stena ferry link.</title>
<headline>EU set to raise doubts over P&amp;O/Stena ferry link.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission could raise doubts next week over the proposed joint venture between the Peninsular and Oriental Steam Navigation Company (P&amp;O) and Stena Line AB of Sweden, EU sources said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Commission's competition service has drafted a &quot;letter of serious doubts&quot; about the deal, which would merge the two companies' ferry operation on the English channel.</p>
<p>But the final decision on whether to send the letter must be taken by Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert in consultation with his transport couterpart Neil Kinnock and the Commission's legal service, one of the sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not certain that the Commission will send the letter; it has until June 11 to do it,&quot; the source told Reuters.</p>
<p>Van Miert usually follows his services' advice.</p>
<p>P&amp;O said in London it was &quot;still confident&quot; its proposed joint venture with Stena would go ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not expecting any major delay,&quot; a P &amp; O spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>The EU sources declined to give details about the concerns that the deal might harm fair competition.</p>
<p>Under EU rules covering corporate agreements in the shipping sector, the Commission has until next Wednesday to raise any objections or the planned link-up between P&amp;O and Stena will get an automatic six-year exemption from EU competition rules.</p>
<p>If the Commission indeed raises problems, the exemption could be reduced or the deal could be blocked if the companies do not offer any remedies.</p>
<p>The sources played down the announcement earlier this week by Stena that the French authorities, which together with the British government are also investigating the deal, had given their green light.</p>
<p>&quot;What the French said was we let this go, but we will be watching this carefully in a number of points,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>There is no deadline for the Commission to come to a final ruling if the EU investigation goes beyond next week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
