<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642105" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Worldwide Advertising &amp; Media Digest -June 5, 1997.</title>
<headline>Worldwide Advertising &amp; Media Digest -June 5, 1997.</headline>
<text>
<p>------------------------- WAM ------------------------</p>
<p>....REUTERS WORLDWIDE ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA DIGEST.....</p>
<p>------------------- June 5, 1997------------------</p>
<p>Reuters news from around the world on Advertising, Marketing, Media, the Internet, Brand-name Products and Consumer Trends ***********************************************</p>
<p>ADVERTISING &amp; MARKETING:</p>
<p>LONDON - A British advertising trade group, the Advertising Association, announces a campaign to make political advertising subject to the same regulatory standards as other ads and to shorten significantly the time allowed for each political TV commercial.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>VIENNA - The Danish Coffee Roasters Association launches an aggressive marketing drive aimed at persuading young people to develop a taste for coffee rather than soft drinks. Jens Wang Jensen, a DCRA board member, tells the Second International Coffee and Tea Symposium conference in Vienna that if the younger generation was not targeted, the coffee industry would lose out badly to soft drinks firms. As part of its new campaign, DCRA is using video advertising, posters and youth magazines to sell coffee to a new generation of consumers.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>CHICAGO - Samsonite Corp., the world's leading luggage maker, is to run a $30 million global ad campaign created by Omnicom Group's TBWA Chiat/Day, of Venice, California.</p>
<p>The campaign is designed to reposition the Denver-based company as a provider of global travel solutions</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>AMSTERDAM - Europe's biggest advertising trade body, the European Association of Advertising Agencies, urges an end to restrictions on the advertising industry that it says go against the trend to liberalise and deregulate other businesses in the region. Albert Winninghoff, its president says the advertising sector has been unfairly singled out.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - A British ad agency has dispensed with traditional offices and desks and replaced them with bean bags, lockers and mobile phones in a bid to boost creative thinking. &quot;We call it romping and it's about talking, gathering and interacting rather than being locked away in your own little office,&quot; Ann Harris a partner in the Howell Henry Chaldecott Lury &amp; Partners agency says.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>MEDIA &amp; THE INTERNET:</p>
<p>NEW YORK - The top four U.S. television networks have generated about $6.1 billion in advance advertising sales for the coming primetime season, reflecting a robust ad market even though they keep losing audience share. Most of the so-called &quot;upfront&quot; selling is now wrapped up, say ad executives.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - Britain's Channel 5, launched two months ago, is on course to meet its target of a five percent TV audience share by the end of the year, chief executive David Elstein says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - The new left-wing French government is expected to overhaul the country's media law, according to the newspaper Le Monde. It says the Socialists will change the &quot;Carignon law&quot;, named after a former communications minister, that raised the limit on stakes in television companies held by private firms to 49 percent and awarded broadcast licences for 10 years.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SYDNEY - News Ltd, the Australian offshoot of Rupert Murdoch's News Corp Ltd, says his eldest son Lachlan has been appointed chairman. Murdoch junior is already managing director of News Ltd, which is the largest metropolitan newspaper publisher in Australia.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PALO ALTO, California - WebTV Networks Inc says it has launched &quot;WebTV PrimeTime for Developers&quot; -- a package of technical, artistic and marketing resources to help developers of on-line content for broadcast television. The program will help developers reach the growing Internet market by providing software tools like WebTV Simulator for desktop computers.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>BRAND-NAME PRODUCTS &amp; MARKETS:</p>
<p>NEW YORK - PepsiCo Inc stock falls after the company disappoints analysts with its outlook on earnings and U.S. beverage sales, traders and analysts say.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BOMBAY - The entry of smaller ice cream marketers has stirred Hindustan Lever, India's ice cream market leader, into action with new flavours, attractive packaging and bargain prices. Lever hopes to push its products more aggressively this summer by introducing vending carts with freezers.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BANGKOK - Procter &amp; Gamble Co says its wholly owned Thai unit will raise its sales revenue by 14 percent during the year ending June 30 to about 5.7 billion baht ($219 million).</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SEOUL - Daewoo Electronics Co, an affiliate of South Korea's Daewoo Group, says it will spend $1 billion by 2002 to become the world's largest refrigerator producer.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>CARACAS - Pirated computer software accounted for 70 percent of the total sold in Venezuela last year, signifying a loss to the industry of $209 million, according to a study by accounting firm Price Waterhouse.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SINGAPORE - Asia's chocolate market will grow strongly over the next few years although consumption still lags behind North America and Western Europe, officials of the Swiss-based Barry Callebaut company say.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>OSLO - Norway's food-based conglomerate Orkla ASA says gains in branded goods and its investment portfolio boosted pre-tax profits for the first four months by 35 percent to 933 million crowns ($130.6 million). Orkla said trends in the most important markets for the branded goods business were mixed in the first four months. Volumes in the Swedish groceries market remained virtually unchanged while the Norwegian groceries market recorded moderate volume growth.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>CONSUMER TRENDS:</p>
<p>CLEVELAND, Ohio - American Greetings Corp., the No. 2 greeting card seller in the U.S. says it would overhaul its largest greeting card line in a bid to reflect changing demographics. The &quot;All New American Way&quot; marketing strategy will replace 80 percent of the birthday and everyday cards offered by the company, putting more than 100 million new cards in store. The new cards will reflect multiculturalism, changing attitudes toward ageing and changing family dynamics, the company says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>HAVANA - Authorities in the Cuban capital, apparently inspired by the success of small privately-owned restaurants, have introduced a similar concept of small places to eat, run by the state. The state news agency AIN says 113 branches of the chain &quot;Ofertas&quot; (&quot;Offers&quot;), have opened to date in the city.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - A Republican senator proposes banning computer games in federal government offices and requiring a person, rather than a machine, to answer the telephone to ensure that constituents are dealt with properly.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - In one of France's biggest wine sales, century-old Paris restaurant Maxim's has auctioned off 8,000 of its 100,000 bottles of great vintage wines that age had made too expensive for diners. Auctioneer Jacques Tajan says the sale netted more than nine million francs ($1.5 million) almost doubling forecasts. More than 500 people crowded the auction and 23 telephone lines were kept open to buyers all over the world, including in the United States, Japan, Taiwan and several European countries.</p>
<p>**********************************************</p>
<p>-- London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2792</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>See full stories on Reuters Advertising &amp; Media Briefing. And why not visit our Internet site at http://www.bizinfo.reuters.com?</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>($ = 7.142 Norwegian Crowns) ($ = 5.825 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
