<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642377" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ATHLETICS-CLUTCH JUMP GIVES HOWARD NCAA LONG JUMP TITLE.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-CLUTCH JUMP GIVES HOWARD NCAA LONG JUMP TITLE.</headline>
<byline>Gene Cherry</byline>
<dateline>BLOOMINGTON, Indiana 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Olympian Robert Howard, in danger of being eliminated, used a clutch third attempt to win the men's long jump at the U.S. collegiate championships on Thursday.</p>
<p>The winning leap of 8.21 meters (26 feet, 11 1/4 inches), was inferior to Howard's seasonal best of 8.40 metres (27 feet, 6 3/4 inches) -- the second best jump in the world this year -- but it brought instant elation to the University of Arkansas student, who finished eighth in the triple jump at the Atlanta Olympics.</p>
<p>He quickly thrust both arms in the air after hearing the winning mark, which came on his last attempt in the preliminary round of three jumps.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a pressure jumper,&quot; said Howard.</p>
<p>Before the jump he had been tied for ninth in the competition and risked elimination had he not improved.</p>
<p>He had jumped only 7.56 metres (24 feet, 9 3/4 inches) on his first attempt and fouled on his second jump.</p>
<p>He did not improve in the finals, passing one attempt and then jumping 7.53 (24 feet 8 1/2 inches) and 7.95 (26 feet 1 inch). But his final preliminary jump held up.</p>
<p>American Ivan Wagner, a second-year student at the University of Texas, surprised the men's high jump field with a leap of 2.30 meters (7 feet, 6 1/2 inches) to win by 11 centimetres (4 1/4 inches).</p>
<p>Tressa Thompson, who had always dreamed of playing football for the University of Nebraska, won a national championship for her school in another sport.</p>
<p>The former high school tight end won the women's shot put with a throw of 18.50 meters (60 feet, 8 1/2 inches).</p>
<p>She said her mother made her give up football because of the contact involved in the sport.</p>
<p>&quot;But football gave me the aggressiveness that has carried me through all my sports,&quot; said Thompson.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BLOOMINGTON, Indiana"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
