<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642467" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - POLAND - JUNE 6.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - POLAND - JUNE 6.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning</p>
<p>POLITICAL FRONT PAGE NEWS</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- There is no reason to think that Poland will not be included in the first group of countries to be considered for EU membership, Polish Foreign Minister Dariusz Rosati said.</p>
<p>- A group of Polish intellectuals including Janusz Beksiak, Cezary Jozefiak, Waclaw Wilczynski, Andrzej Paczkowski, Stefan Bratkowski and Jacek Fedorowicz signed a letter criticising the tax bill proposed by the finance ministry. They accused the bill of infringing personal and economic rights of citizens.</p>
<p>- Poland's defence ministry has denied reports in the Jerusalem Post that it has decided to contract Israel's Elbit to supply a missile system for Polish Huzar helicopters.</p>
<p>ZYCIE</p>
<p>- Parliament passed an law on a so-called Profits Register which will report additional earnings of civil servants and members of parliament. The act is intended to curb corruption and bribery among civil servants and politicians.</p>
<p>ECONOMIC AND MARKET NEWS</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- The Polish Securities Commission (KPW) has approved the KGHM copper conglomerate's issue of 200 million shares for public trading on the Warsaw bourse. KPW also gave the green light to share issues of the Biurosystem office equipment firm and Universal foreign trade firm.</p>
<p>- Germany's Gardinia blind and shutter maker has opened a new plant in Domoslaw, south-western Poland, which cost 2.7 million zlotys to build.</p>
<p>- The Laziska electric power plant has installed desulphurisation equipment on two blocks which will cut emissions of sulphur and nitrogen compounds by up to 95 percent, the plant said.</p>
<p>- The Gdansk Refinery from today increases prices of various petrol fuels by 0.3 to 0.5 zlotys per litre.</p>
<p>- Belgium's Palm brewery, which controls the Kielce brewery in south Poland, will invest 100 million zlotys in building a new plant in the province next year. The plant will produce several hundred thousand hectolitres of Palm beer each year, the company said.</p>
<p>- The Konstilana SA textile maker is in talks with three prospective strategic investors. The successful bidder will be allowed to buy a 51 percent stake, Konstilana president Witold Michalak said.</p>
<p>- The listed Indykpol SA poultry processing firm has offered to buy the ZM Olsztyn meat processing plant for 3.0 million zlotys. Indykpol will invest 5.0 million zlotys in developing the plant, grant a social package to the 500 workers and keep employment at present levels, Indykpol said.</p>
<p>- The KPW will shortly examine a share issue prospectus of the Lubelskie Towarzystwo Leasingowe (LTL) leasing firm. In 1996 LTL earned a net profit of 2.809 million zlotys showing a 77 percent decline compared with the year before.</p>
<p>DZIENNIK PRAWA I GOSPODARKI</p>
<p>- The Council of the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) has decided to buy an up to 15 percent stake in the Powszechny Bank Kredytowy (PBK) now in privatisation, EBRD's spokesperson Rebecca Hill said.</p>
<p>- Bank Depozytowo- Kredytowy (BDK) and the EBRD have formed a SRP Investment joint venture which will carry out a restructuring programme in a group of selected companies.</p>
<p>The new company will invest $80 million in the programme.</p>
<p>- The KPW has applied to the Consumer and Competition Protection Office (UOKK) to examine the television advert of Bank Handlowy now in privatisation.</p>
<p>&quot;The spot is unclear and imprecise ... It is improperly constructed in my opinion&quot;, KPW's president Jacek Socha said.</p>
<p>- V.A.B Poland will invest 27 million marks in the Katowice Special Economic Zone in south Poland in the Opel car body component plant to employ 500 workers, V.A.B's president Czeslaw Tomkiewicz said.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>- The PZU, Poland's biggest insurance firm, collected gross premiums of 2.49 billion in the first quarter of this year netting 205 million which has already covered the 1996 net loss of 93 million zlotys, PZU said.</p>
<p>ZYCIE</p>
<p>- The convertible bond market will boom in the next two or three year, the MC Concordia investment advisor's president Andrzej Sykulski said.</p>
<p>- The Pozmeat meat processor's shares have been priced at 25.5 zlotys per share, Pozmeat's president Edmund Flaczyk said.</p>
<p>PARKIET</p>
<p>- The listed ZML Kety non-ferrous metal smelter will invest 90 million zlotys in plant development, its president Jan Kryjak said.</p>
<p>- The listed Exbud construction firm made a net profit of 5.1 million zlotys in the first quarter of 1997, showing growth of more than 100 percent compared with the 2.3 million zlotys it made in the same period last year.</p>
<p>NOTE - Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
