<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64248" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan lambasts China over failed bid for UN seat.</title>
<headline>Taiwan lambasts China over failed bid for UN seat.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Chen</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan, defeated in a fourth bid to join the United Nations, on Thursday denounced rival China's efforts to make it a global pariah and vowed to fight on for a U.N. voice for its 21 million people.</p>
<p>China and its supporters on Wednesday blocked moves in the General Assembly to consider U.N. membership for Taiwan, scuttling Taipei's bid for a fourth straight year.</p>
<p>&quot;Communist China's negative attitude toward our efforts to expand our room for advancement in the international community is unacceptable to us,&quot; Taiwan's foreign affairs vice minister Cheng Chien-jen said on state television.</p>
<p>The proposal to put the issue on the agenda was introduced by the Solomon Islands and strongly opposed by Beijing's U.N. ambassador. Delegates from 38 countries opposed the item while 17 spoke in favour.</p>
<p>Cheng, noting that more countries spoke on the issue during Wednesday's session than in previous years, said he remained hopeful that Taiwan would succeed eventually.</p>
<p>&quot;It is obvious that this case is gaining more attention and understanding from more countries,&quot; he said. &quot;I believe that as long as we keep pushing, our chances will be even better in the future.&quot;</p>
<p>The Nationalist Republic of China government, which fled to Taiwan in 1949 after defeat by the communists in a civil war, held China's U.N. seat for two decades.</p>
<p>Taipei was expelled by the General Assembly in 1971 and the China seat given to Beijing, which considers Taiwan a renegade province that must eventually be integrated into the People's Republic of China.</p>
<p>China regards any bid to give Taiwan U.N. membership as an intolerable encroachment on its sovereignty and interference in its internal affairs.</p>
<p>Beijing's U.N. ambassador Qin Huasun told the world body that Taiwan had been part of China since ancient times.</p>
<p>Qin assailed what he called a &quot;very small number of member states instigated by the Taiwan authorities&quot; striving to create &quot;two Chinas&quot; or &quot;one China, one Taiwan&quot; in the United Nations.</p>
<p>Taiwan's Cheng shrugged off China's accusations.</p>
<p>&quot;Our efforts at the U.N. are not to challenge communist China's seat, and are not to push for two Chinas,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;What we want is to fight for the survival and advancement of the 21 million people in the Republic of China in the Taiwan region.&quot;</p>
<p>Taiwan has diplomatic ties with only 30 countries despite being the world's 14th largest trading nation.</p>
<p>Beijing refuses to recognise those countries that maintain official ties with Taiwan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
