<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642414" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-REYNOSO BLANKS MARLINS ON FIVE-HIT SHUTOUT FOR METS.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-REYNOSO BLANKS MARLINS ON FIVE-HIT SHUTOUT FOR METS.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Armando Reynoso threw a five-hitter for his first major league shutout and Edgardo Alfonzo drove in two runs Thursday to lead the New York Mets to a 6-0 victory over the Florida Marlins.</p>
<p>Reynoso (5-0) walked one and struck out four and also helped himself with an RBI single in the fourth inning. In his 10 starts, Reynoso has allowed more than three runs just once and the Mets have won his last eight starts.</p>
<p>Reynoso also benefitted from the Mets' club record-tying five double plays, which kept him from being pulled for a reliever.</p>
<p>&quot;If he doesn't get the double plays, that's five more batters and he's out of the game in the eighth inning,&quot; New York manager Bobby Valentine said. &quot;I'm not surprised by Reynoso. When I saw him in spring training, I thought that he would fit in with what we want to do.&quot;</p>
<p>Reynoso allowed just one runner to reach third base while not giving up an extra-base hit in his first complete game.</p>
<p>Florida's Kevin Brown (5-4) surrendered six runs and 12 hits seven innings to suffer the loss.</p>
<p>In Montreal, Denny Neagle pitched a six-hitter for his second career shutout and added two RBI as the Atlanta Braves won their fourth straight road game, a 9-0 victory over the Montreal Expos.</p>
<p>Neagle (8-1) walked two and struck out seven.</p>
<p>The Braves got solo homers from Keith Lockhart, Javier Lopez and Andruw Jones to pad Neagle's lead.</p>
<p>Expos starter Dustin Hermanson (2-4) allowed three runs, four hits and five walks in three-plus innings.</p>
<p>In Cincinnati, Lenny Harris, who came in to replace the injured Deion Sanders, homered and went 3-for-3 with a pair of RBI as the Reds held off the Houston Astros 6-5.</p>
<p>Pete Schourek (5-4) allowed two runs over five innings for his third consecutive win. Shane Reynolds (4-6) lasted five innings in the loss.</p>
<p>Craig Biggio led off the game with the 100th homer of his career, but it was not enough to spark the Astros, who had their winning streak snapped at three games.</p>
<p>Sanders left in the third inning with a sprained left ankle. X-rays were negative and he is listed as day-to-day.</p>
<p>At Colorado, Larry Walker slugged a two-run homer, his second homer of the game, in the bottom of the 11th inning to lift the Rockies to a 9-7 win over the San Diego Padres.</p>
<p>Walker hit his 17th homer of the season on an 0-1 pitch from Terry Burrows (0-1) over the right-centre field fence, scoring Eric Young, who had singled to open the inning.</p>
<p>Steve Reed (1-2) picked up the win.</p>
<p>Wally Joyner rapped his fourth hit of the day in the ninth, an RBI single that scored Tony Gwynn to tie it at 6-6 and send the game into extra innings. Gwynn's ninth-inning single extended his hitting streak to 15 games.</p>
<p>In Pittsburgh, Joe Randa homered and drove in three runs and Keith Osik added three RBI to lead the Pirates to a 9-3 victory over the St Louis Cardinals.</p>
<p>Esteban Loaiza (5-2) pitched eight innings and allowed two runs and seven hits to earn his first win in six career decisions against the Cardinals.</p>
<p>The Cardinals' John Mabry went 2-for-4, extending his hitting streak to a career-high 16 games.</p>
<p>Todd Stottlemyre (4-4) surrendered five runs and five hits in just four innings for the loss.</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, Scott Rolen, who stole home earlier in the game, singled home Mickey Morandini with the winning run in the 10th inning to lift the Phillies to a 9-8 victory over the Chicago Cubs.</p>
<p>Ken Ryan (1-0) pitched a scoreless 10th to notch the victory, which was made possible by a clutch three-run homer by Mike Lieberthal with the Phillies down to their last strike in the ninth.</p>
<p>Terry Adams (0-2), who started the 10th in relief of Mel Rojas, took the loss.</p>
<p>In Los Angeles, Darryl Hamilton knocked in a pair of runs and William Vanlandingham pitched six strong innings as the San Francisco Giants edged the Dodgers 5-4.</p>
<p>Hamilton had a two-run single in a three-run second which gave the Giants a 3-0 lead.</p>
<p>San Francisco extended its lead to 5-0 in the fifth when Barry Bonds delivered a run-scoring single and came home on Mike Piazza's second error of the inning.</p>
<p>Greg Gagne hit a two-run homer for the Dodgers, who have lost seven of their last nine games.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
