<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642541" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Coffee prices take another hit.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Coffee prices take another hit.</headline>
<byline>Donald Bradshaw</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>This week's headlong fall in coffee prices continued on Friday as speculators tried to salvage some of their fast diminishing profits.</p>
<p>Among other commodities palladium remained volatile due to a desperate shortage of the metal, several base metals turned higher after being a target of the bears for most of the week, and weather concerns boosted wheat prices.</p>
<p>On the London robusta coffee futures market the July position lost another $80 a tonne, and its day's low of $1,815 showed a 32 percent retracement from last week's 20 months high of $2,670.</p>
<p>&quot;There was nothing new today but once momentum builds in these markets they don't change direction easily,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Traders said this week's fall was a combination of the dizzy rise being overdone, Colombia stepping-up exports and claiming it was finding consumer resistance to high prices, and lack of any signs so far of a damaging frost in the peak June/July winter months in Brazil.</p>
<p>In Europe, palladium reached $240 an ounce, its highest price since 1980, as traders indicated it could be early July before resumed Russian exports, after a six-month absence, began to reach export markets.</p>
<p>The lack of palladium shipments by the world's number one exporter of the metal which is a vital component of auto-catalysts, used to clean up exhaust fumes, has seen the price double since the start of the year.</p>
<p>A big investment fund is holding 1.5 million ounce of pallaidum and this has exacerbated the market shortage quite considerably as world supply is only around five million ounces a year.</p>
<p>Fund involvement was also evident on the London Metal Exchange where a position was believed to have been built up in the tin market which could cause some tightness in supplies during July.</p>
<p>This has seen players with sales commitments rushing to cover their positions and has pushed the price up by around $200 a tonne during the week to $5,700.</p>
<p>Nickel also ended the week on a firm note as neither company or unions involved in the strike at the west's number one nickel producer, Canada's Inco, showed any sign of resuming pay talks.</p>
<p>The possibility that a prolonged strike could see Inco dip into the London Metal Exchange 50,000 tonnes stocpile of the metal helped boost prices above the $7,300 a tonne level, $60 up on the day.</p>
<p>The LMEs flagship copper contract continued its slow recovery from an early-week sell-off to end at $2,487, nearly $30 above the week's low but still short of the $2,500 traded on Monday.</p>
<p>Heavy rains in the wheat growing areas of Texas were delaying the harvest and this pushed Chicago Board of trade prices up by some five cents a bushel.</p>
<p>Some key prices at 1700 GMT.</p>
<p>						   Friday  Thursday</p>
<p>Ldn Spot Gold($ per ounce)		344.45     341.75</p>
<p>IPE Brent Crude Oil (Jul)		  18.06     18.45</p>
<p>London Metal Exchange</p>
<p>(3 mths delivery)</p>
<p>Copper ($ per tonne)		    2,487.00   2,481.00</p>
<p>Aluminium ($ per tonne)		 1,597.00   1,600.00</p>
<p>LIFFE</p>
<p>Robusta Coffee ($/tonne) (Jul)	1,825.00   1,905.00</p>
<p>Cocoa (Stg/tonne) (Jul)		   995.00     995.00</p>
<p>White Sugar ($/tonne Aug)		 326.00     326.90</p>
<p>Chicago Board of Trade Wheat</p>
<p>     $/bushel) (Jul)			  3.60	 3.55</p>
<p>Wednesday, 4 June 1997 16:24</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
