<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642603" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: CS Resources urges shareholders to wait.</title>
<headline>CS Resources urges shareholders to wait.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Takeover target CS Resources Ltd said on Friday it expected to be in a position to announce a &quot;strategic alliance with an industry partner&quot; and urged shareholders not to act until its board came out with further information.</p>
<p>Gulf Canada Resources Ltd said on Friday it planned to make a C$413 million offer for CS in a deal that had yet to be deemed hostile or friendly.  </p>
<p>CS said it &quot;has had active discussions regarding a strategic alliance with an industry partner to accelerate the growth of the company's extensive resource base.</p>
<p>&quot;These discussions have advanced to the stage which involves the commitment by the strategic partner of an equity participation as a well as prospective resource properties,&quot; CS said, adding it expected to be in a position to announce an agreement.</p>
<p>Gulf Canada initiated discussions with CS on May 28 with the intention of hammering out a friendly transaction, but Friday's bid was unsolicited, Gulf Canada Chief Executive J.P Bryan said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;When they announced the adoption of a poison pill that we saw on the wire this morning, we felt we had no choice but to go ahead and make our offer because we feared that the market would see that as a precursor to an offer and the stock would begin to move,&quot; Bryan said.</p>
<p>He said he believed CS, with its announcement of a strategic partner, was referring to a company other than Gulf Canada.</p>
<p>Gulf Canada said earlier today it would offer CS shareholders either C$14.25 in cash, subject to a maximum of C$100 million, or 1.1539 Gulf Canada shares for each CS share.</p>
<p>((Reuters Calgary Bureau (403) 531-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
