<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642628" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian shares close higher, outlook quiet.</title>
<headline>Nigerian shares close higher, outlook quiet.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Equities closed up again on Friday at the Nigerian stock market after an initial rally on Thursday, but traders said business would still be low in the coming week.</p>
<p>The all-share index ended at 8569.78 from 8566.78 on Thursday when it strengthened slightly.</p>
<p>Analysts said trading activity was still low as reflected in in a shorter than normal session on the Lagos floor on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;People wanted to sell shares but there were no buyers,&quot; said one, attributing the trend to lack of funds.</p>
<p>Traders say the money market was beginning to attract funds from stocks.</p>
<p>Brewing and cement firms were the main losers, falling on continuous dumping of their shares, traders said.</p>
<p>Nigerian Breweries eased to 19.60 naira, down 20 kobo, while Guinness was down 10 kobo at 7.00 naira.</p>
<p>West African Portland Cement Company (WAPCO) and sister-company Ashaka Cement were both 10 kobo down, respectively at 64.50 naira and 13.00 naira.</p>
<p>Healthcare firm Smithkline Beecham ended weaker too, at 6.00 naira, down 30 kobo.</p>
<p>Strong finishers were few, led by Nigerian Flour Mills, which is rising on the expectation of improved results. It closed 15 kobo more at 17.00 naira.</p>
<p>An oil miller P.S. Mandrides shot up 20 kobo on the strength of its recent good performances, closing at 5.90 naira.</p>
<p>But Nestle, the current hottest stock on the market, was steady on Friday at 45.55 naira.</p>
<p>Petroleum shares, until displaced by Nestle recently as the toast of the market, were also relatively quiet. Only Agip saw a change, sliding 20 kobo to 20.60 naira.</p>
<p>($1=85 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
