<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642702" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Henkel opens HUF1.2bln plant in Hungary.</title>
<headline>Henkel opens HUF1.2bln plant in Hungary.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>German consumer products and chemicals group Henkel KGaA opened on Friday a 1.2 billion forint greenfield investment in Hungary, Henkel's largest investment in the country to date.</p>
<p>Henkel's investment in Korosladany, south-east Hungary, where the company produces liquid detergents, scourers and rinsers, includes new producing plants, sewage facilities and warehouses, it said in a statement.</p>
<p>The new plant will operate next to an existing formerly state-owned unit which has operated since 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to make Henkel Hungary's three plants the three producing units of key importance to Henkel Austria group,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Henkel Hungary was founded via the German company's Austrian unit.</p>
<p>Henkel, which also has producing facilities in Szolnok, central Hungary and Vac, north Hungary, has invested a total of five billion forints into production since 1992.</p>
<p>In 1996 Henkel in Hungary posted a consolidated sales revenue of 15 billion forints, including 2.7 billion forints of exports and for 1997 it plans to boost its sales to 18 billion with five billion of exports.</p>
<p>It gave no earnings figures but said profits as a percentage of sales have hovered in recent years between five and eight percent and all profits and have been reinvested.</p>
<p>Since the beginning of the decade, when Henkel set up in Korosladany, it has boosted the number of employees at the plant to 300 from 142 in 1991, its assets to 2.005 billion forints from 210 million and its capacities to 34,500 tonnes from 10,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>These figures include the new plant and only refer to its facilities in Korosladany.</p>
<p>Henkel first came to Hungary in 1927, established its first joint venture in Hungary in 1987 and began to launch its producing units between 1990 and 1992.</p>
<p>Henkel's three units produce wide range of products from detergents to industrial and consumer adhesives, and employed a total of 520 people at the end of 1996.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
