<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642712" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian ex-regional governor detained over graft.</title>
<headline>Russian ex-regional governor detained over graft.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The former governor of Russia's Tula region, south of Moscow, has been detained on corruption charges, Russian news agencies reported on Friday.</p>
<p>On a day when President Boris Yeltsin reaffirmed his latest clean-up campaign by saying &quot;the bribe-takers' hands are shaking&quot;, Yeltsin appointee Nikolai Sevryugin was being questioned on suspicion of taking $100,000 in bribes, according to the agencies.</p>
<p>An Interior Ministry spokesman declined to comment on reports that Sevryugin, who was ousted by a communist rival in an election in March, had been arrested on Thursday along with his son and an official of a Moscow commercial bank.</p>
<p>In February, Sevryugin's deputy was sentenced to six years imprisonment for corruption and had his assets confiscated.</p>
<p>&quot;I know there are a lot of bosses who got big powers and immediately opened up their own, big pockets,&quot; Yeltsin said in a regular radio address on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;They think they are far away from Moscow and there will be no control over them. They are wrong. We will start with checking their income and assets declarations and slap their hands to teach them a lesson.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
