<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64274" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Iraqi Kurd leader asks for Western backing.</title>
<headline>Iraqi Kurd leader asks for Western backing.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Bell</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Iraqi Kurdish leader who made a military pact with the Baghdad government has asked the West not to abandon him to President Saddam Hussein, a source close to talks held with a senior U.S. official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The source said Kurdish leader Massoud Barzani had urged the West not to scrap a no-fly zone over northern Iraq or pull out any more humanitarian aid from the impoverished region.</p>
<p>&quot;He was emphatic about Provide Comfort staying. He was emphatic about the aid continuing,&quot; the source told Reuters.</p>
<p>Barzani, leader of the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP), met U.S. assistant secretary of state Robert Pelletreau in Ankara on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Barzani's military alliance with Baghdad against a Kurdish rival last month undermined the U.S.-led air patrols, known as Provide Comfort, and brought Saddam's influence in northern Iraq to its highest level since the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>&quot;Now (Barzani) has woken up to the fact that he has opened the cage door and the lion is out,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>He said the Kurdish leader, previously a staunch opponent of Saddam, had indicated his flirtation with Baghdad was temporary and that it would go no further.</p>
<p>&quot;The doors are still open between us and the KDP,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>CIA Director John Deutch told the Senate Intelligence Committee in Washington that Barzani had approached Western allies &quot;for protection in an effort to hold Saddam Hussein at arm's length.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Saddam Hussein is putting increasing pressure on Barzani to negotiate a framework for autonomy under Baghdad's overall control,&quot; Deutch said.</p>
<p>Deutch said Barzani's KDP controls nearly all of the Kurdish part of northern Iraq, with only isolated pockets held by the opposition Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK) which combined KDP and Iraqi forces drove out of the city of Arbil on August 31.</p>
<p>Baghdad's involvement prompted U.S. missile strikes against Iraqi military targets in southern Iraq and an expansion of a southern no-fly zone up to the edge of Baghdad.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns described the meeting between Barzani and Pelletreau, also attended by British and Turkish diplomats, as &quot;very productive&quot;.</p>
<p>He said Barzani had been asked to stay clear of Saddam from now on.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't see that the Iraqi Kurds can profit in the long term from an association with Saddam Hussein. In fact on the contrary, we think that such a relationship would be detrimental,&quot; Burns said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Barzani has been at the forefront of the decades-old Kurdish fight for autonomy from Baghdad which has often singled out members of his powerful clan for executions and internal exile.</p>
<p>The KDP has said it only invited the Iraqi army to help it take Arbil last month because Washington did not halt alleged Iranian backing for a rival militia.</p>
<p>Tehran warned Barzani against seeking U.S. support.</p>
<p>&quot;One should be aware that the Americans would interfere in the Kurdistan region only if they have direct interests. Even then, they would easily turn their backs on their commitments and accords once their needs are met,&quot; Iranian state radio said.</p>
<p>Washington has called for the two Kurdish militias to make peace but the source said the Ankara meeting &quot;was not a mediation effort&quot;.</p>
<p>A Turkey-based European Union representative is to meet Barzani in northern Iraq soon to ask him to protect aid workers.</p>
<p>Diplomats say the number of Kurds and their family members working for EU-subsidised aid agencies who have asked to leave the region is around to 6,000.</p>
<p>More than 2,000 pro-U.S. Kurds and their relatives fled Iraq to Turkey last week on their way to asylum in the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
