<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642761" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELARUS: Belarus starts food price controls June 1-Eco Min.</title>
<headline>Belarus starts food price controls June 1-Eco Min.</headline>
<dateline>MINSK 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belarus will institute price controls for foodstuffs starting June 10 to try and meet inflation targets set by President Alexander Lukashenko, the head of the Economy Ministry's prices committee, said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The limits on prices will apply to all basic foodstuffs, milk and meat products, and bread,&quot; Lidia Kupreyeva told Reuters.</p>
<p>She said prices were being lowered to conform with a decree issued recently by President Alexander Lukashenko.</p>
<p>&quot;The decree said average monthly inflation cannot be higher than two percent, but you know it has been higher,&quot; Kupreyeva said.</p>
<p>January-April inflation stood at 28.8 percent, compared to 13.7 percent for the same period in 1996. April inflation was 4.3 percent against 2.3 percent in March.</p>
<p>May inflation figures were not yet available.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a temporary measure and does not mean Belarus is rejecting a strategic path towards free, unregulated prices,&quot; Kupreyeva added.</p>
<p>Last month Prime Minister Sergei Ling told parliament inflation was causing devaluation of the Belarussian rouble, had forced the government to raise monthly salaries at a cost of 2.5 trillion roubles, and had resulted in the government paying an extra 5.3 trillion roubles in credits to the agriculture sector.</p>
<p>Government price regulation was one of the reasons the International Monetary Fund froze $250 million in stand-by credits to the former Soviet republic last year.</p>
<p>Late last year Lukashenko released an economic plan to 2000 which also ordered low inflation levels.</p>
<p>--Kiev Newsroom +380 44 244-9150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINSK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELARUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
