<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642754" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares rebound, seen extending gains.</title>
<headline>Polish shares rebound, seen extending gains.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares rose after a three-session fall and analysts said strong buying after price fixing and most stocks closing in the continuous trade above their main market's fixing signalled further growth.</p>
<p>The main market's WIG index rose 182.5 points, or 1.2 percent, to 16,000.6 on Friday, and trade fell 10 percent to 118.9 million zlotys ($37.2 million) on all three markets as 77 issues rose, 19 fell and nine were flat.</p>
<p>Analysts said, however, the market would still be under pressure from large privatisations, which might keep it locked in its over 2.5-month long horizontal trend in longer term.</p>
<p>&quot;The falls were strong enough to make investors use the situation for buying...at least the beginning of the next week should be good,&quot; said Krzysztof Olszewski, an analyst at Bank Slaski brokerage.</p>
<p>Analysts said the undergoing sale of Poland's large Bank Handlowy, offering one-billion-zloty worth ($312 million) shares and KGHM, which in late June will offer at least 300 million-zloty ($93 million) worth shares, could hamper buying on the exchange.</p>
<p>They said, however, that attractiveness of investments in Poland should prevent more painful falls.</p>
<p>Traders were surprised with brewer Zywiec 10-percent jump and said after such unexpected growth profit-taking was likely to hit the stock in the beginning of the next week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
