<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642803" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin seeks Lenin burial, hits out at corruption.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin seeks Lenin burial, hits out at corruption.</headline>
<byline>Philippa Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>ST PETERSBURG, Russia 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin, speaking in Russia's revolutionary capital, said on Friday the people should decide whether to give the embalmed corpse of Bolshevik leader Vladimir Lenin a Christian burial.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, shaping up for another row with Russia's communist-dominated parliament, said a referendum should be held this autumn on removing Lenin's mummified corpse from the red marble mausoleum outside the Kremlin walls.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope we will gradually rid Red Square of its status of a cemetery,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The wax-like corpse, shielded behind bullet-proof glass in the polished mausoleum, has become the focus of an intensive struggle between reformers, led by the Kremlin leader, and the communist opposition which views Lenin as an icon.</p>
<p>Communist deputies are fiercely opposed to removing Lenin's body and the State Duma lower house of parliament has passed a law banning changes in the appearance of Red Square. Yeltsin has not signed the law and is unlikely to do so.</p>
<p>The president has also clashed with the Duma on economic policy. Deputies lashed out at his government's privatisation policies on Thursday and they are furious at government plans to slash spending to offset dismal tax revenues.</p>
<p>Yeltsin told residents of Russia's second city St Petersburg that he was fit again after months of illness with heart problems and pneumonia and he had corrupt officials on the run.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm in good, sporting form. That's it. I'm working full strength. The bribetakers' hands are already shaking,&quot; Yeltsin, 66, told a small crowd who had turned out to watch him laying flowers at a statue to poet Alexander Pushkin.</p>
<p>&quot;They took my heart, pulled it out and put it back again. Now everything's okay,&quot; Yeltsin said, referring in typical light-hearted way to the multiple heart bypass operation he underwent in November.</p>
<p>It was Yeltsin's first trip to Russia's regions for months the first in a planned series across the Russian federation. He warned administrators and managers in regions spread across 11 time zones they were not immune to his drive against graft.</p>
<p>&quot;We've already thrown one in jail, a second, a third. There are now 1,400 such people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His comments followed a tongue-lashing for corrupt officials in a radio broadcast earlier on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I know there are a lot of bosses who got big powers and immediately opened up their own, big pockets,&quot; Yeltsin said.</p>
<p>&quot;They think they are far away from Moscow and there will be no control over them. They are wrong. We will start with checking their income and assets declarations and slap their hands to teach them a lesson.&quot;</p>
<p>Yeltsin has published his own income declaration and told all other senior officials to do the same.</p>
<p>He spent most of May on foreign policy matters, signing deals with NATO and the former Soviet republics of Belarus and Ukraine. He also signed a peace deal with Russia's separatist region of Chechnya and said on Friday that it was time to concentrate on domestic policy, including regional problems.</p>
<p>&quot;The economic policy of the regions should be modern and competent, like in Moscow, Nizhny Novgorod and Novosibirsk,&quot; Yeltsin said, referring to two Russian regions where reforms have started to bear fruit.</p>
<p>He travelled to St Petersburg with reform guru and First Deputy Prime Minister Anatoly Chubais, who launched his political career in St Petersburg and who clearly had a hand in Yeltsin's trip.</p>
<p>The city has failed since communism fell to live up to the vision of its 18th century founder Peter the Great as a &quot;window on the West&quot;.</p>
<p>It is seeking to turn things around with a debut Eurobond to raise $300 million, but museums, including the richly endowed Russian Museum which Yeltsin visited on Friday, are desperately short of cash.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST PETERSBURG, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
