<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642904" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine stocks close at session highs.</title>
<headline>Argentine stocks close at session highs.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>After a three-day pause Argentine stocks picked up steam again Friday and closed at session highs in strong turnover.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's recent momentum was fizzling, but then foreign factors emerged on the scene and fuelled a fresh rally,&quot; said Adolfo Adorno of brokers Agra.</p>
<p>Dealers expected the tone to remain firm when trading resumes after Monday's Sovereignty Day holiday.</p>
<p>The blue-chip MerVal index  jumped 1.8 percent to 802.95, closing above 800 points for the first time in almost exactly five years.  </p>
<p>&quot;The sharp fall in U.S. long bond yields today (to a three-and-a-half month low of 6.78 percent) encouraged players to buy in emerging markets,&quot; an analyst at a foreign brokerage said. &quot;Argentina is a good option, because economic fundamentals like tax collection and GDP forecasts are looking very attractive.&quot;</p>
<p>The government said this week the economy grew 8.1 percent in the first quarter of 1997, higher than consensus forecasts, and growth for the whole year is seen at between 6.0 percent and 6.5 percent.</p>
<p>May tax revenue reached a six-year high of $4.6 billion.  </p>
<p>In the session the broad market rose 0.9 percent, with winners smashing losers 69 to eight and 11 stocks ending flat.</p>
<p>Floor volume surged to 42.3 million pesos from 24 million Thursday, while over-the-counter deals totaled 125.9 million pesos against 76.6 million Thursday.</p>
<p>Pulp and paper maker Celulosa was the day's standout, soaring 10 percent, while carmakers Sevel and Ciadea jumped 6.4 percent and 4.0 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>The only MerVal losers were holding company Garovaglio and oil giant YPF, off 0.6 percent and 0.3 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>((-- Carmen Pignotti, Buenos Aires Newsroom 541 318-0657))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
