<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64298" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey to award barley export tender on Friday.</title>
<headline>Turkey to award barley export tender on Friday.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's state grain board (TMO) on Thursday said results of its tender to export barley would be announced on Friday.</p>
<p>A TMO official said assessment of the bids collected from eight international and local firms was continuing.</p>
<p>The tender, announced earlier for at least 200,000 tonnes of feed and malting barley, attracted Tradigrain, Romak, Louis Dreyfus, Alfred Toepfer International, Glencore, Cargill International, Grains and Fourrages, and the local firm BEM.</p>
<p>The FOB prices for feed barley ranged from $121 per tonne, given by Tradigrain for 50,000 tonnes for November and December shipment, to $136.07 by Glencore for 125,000 tonnes for shipment in the second half of October.</p>
<p>Feed barley shipment dates varied from October to end-December.</p>
<p>FOB prices for malting barley were in the range from $148 per tonne to $150.75. Only Toepfer and Glencore made bids for malting barley -- for 10,000 to 15,000 tonnes for October and November shipments.</p>
<p>Shipment will be mainly from Derince and Mersin ports but Iskenderun was also included in some bids.</p>
<p>--Ercan Ersoy, Ankara Newsroom, 90-312-4462940</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
