<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642981" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: CGC sees swift oil output rise in Venezuela area.</title>
<headline>CGC sees swift oil output rise in Venezuela area.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>A consortium led by Argentina's Compania General de Combustibles (CGC) expects to be producing 20,000 barrels per day (bpd) of crude oil from its Venezuelan Onado contract within two years, a company official said on Friday.</p>
<p>CGC upstream manager Carlos Garcia was speaking to journalists after winning the 20-year contract in a consortium with Canada's Carmanah Resources.</p>
<p>Garcia said the two-year target was achievable because there were several wells already drilled in the oil-bearing strata and he could achieve up to 17,000 bpd by reactivating just three, from zero output now.</p>
<p>&quot;There are wells already in the strata, the problem is that they have collapsed and we think we can solve this within a short period of time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Proven reserves of the field were about 60 million barrels, but Garcia expected to produce about 120 million barrels over the life of the contract. He said there was about a 50 percent &quot;risk factor&quot; in his reserves estimate.</p>
<p>CGC, with 74 percent share in the consortium, won the contract with a cash bid of $90 million, and expected to invest a similar amount in the field over the life of the contract. The consortium narrowly beat competition from China National Petroleum Company and France's Total.</p>
<p>Onado was one of 20 contracts in ageing or abandoned Venezuelan oilfields being offered to private firms under Venezuela's third round of operating licences.</p>
<p>Winning consortia receive a fee based on a complex formula, which participants say offers the contractor the chance to recoup their investment by raising production and then get 30 percent of the profits from any additional output, up to a pre-set ceiling.</p>
<p>((--Tom Ashby, Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2611))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
