<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="643044" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: FOCUS-Thai bourse beaten to 8-yr low, future bleak.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Thai bourse beaten to 8-yr low, future bleak.</headline>
<byline>Rajan Moses</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's already-battered stock market was hammered down to a new eight-year low on Friday by foreign selling as analysts said the immediate future looked bleak for the seriously wounded bourse.</p>
<p>Brokers said the market plunged on selling over concerns about asset quality of troubled Thai financial institutions, believed to be facing non-performing loans problems, mainly to the depressed and cash-strapped property sector.</p>
<p>Friday's selling also came from investment funds urgently needing to raise baht to cover short positions after mid-May's speculative attack on the Thai currency, brokers added.</p>
<p>&quot;There were a lot of selling orders from foreigners in the afternoon session,&quot; said one dealer at a local brokerage. &quot;Some foreign investment funds now face a shortage of baht. Selling stocks is one way to get the currency.&quot;</p>
<p>The stock index sank 17.43 points to close at 530.62, the lowest level since May 26, 1989, when it plummeted to 528.20.</p>
<p>Over the past year, the Thai bourse has lost 59 percent of its value amid a string of bad news.</p>
<p>Thailand's once-robust economy has slumped, the baht has come under speculative attacks, the ailing finance and property sectors face liquidity problems, interest rates remain high and the government is scrambling to regain lost foreign investor confidence, analysts said.</p>
<p>A rush for baht developed after the Bank of Thailand cut off supply from local sources to foreign speculators following the last speculative attack on the currency. The trend had now spilled over into the stock market, analysts said.</p>
<p>The central bank move to punish speculators created a two-tier baht market -- one offshore with trading at a hefty premium and another locally at a much lower rate.</p>
<p>The baht was at a 13-year high against the dollar in the offshore forex market as foreign players offered premiums for the Thai unit and dumped dollars to get it, dealers said.</p>
<p>In the offshore market, the baht was quoted at 23.900/000 to the dollar late, while onshore it was at around 25.850.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the selling will continue into next week. The market is unlikely to bottom out. I would say the index could hover around 500 before edging up if there are supporting factors,&quot; said a broker from Nava Finance and Securities.</p>
<p>Analysts said the future of the Thai bourse in some ways hinged on how long the central bank would retain exchange controls and put a squeeze on baht for foreign investors.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the future of the market could depend on what the central bank does. As long as the informal exchange controls exist, there is a strong chance for foreign holders of Thai assets to sell them for cash,&quot; said Richard Henderson, head of research at KrungThai Thanakit Plc.</p>
<p>But other analysts said the bourse's steep fall could spark a local investor run into the currently cheap, large capitalised stocks sector, especially banks that have been sold heavily.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
