<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64303" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole, unruffled by fall or polls, vows to win.</title>
<headline>Dole, unruffled by fall or polls, vows to win.</headline>
<byline>Randall Mikkelsen</byline>
<dateline>DENVER 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole, unruffled by either a tumble from a campaign stage or polls showing him trailing President Bill Clinton, said on Thursday he was confident of rebounding to win the election.</p>
<p>&quot;The bottom line is, we're going to win the election. You've got to have confidence,&quot; Dole told a meeting of U.S. newspaper editors, where he had been asked his assessment of the state of the campaign.</p>
<p>This comment came after Dole sought to enlist the news media in his fight against drugs and crime. Dole said the media needed to focus more on the personal implications and pervasive extent of drug abuse.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that some in the news media are missing a very important story,&quot; Dole said. &quot;It is my view that soaring teen drug abuse and resurgence of a drug culture is one of the important news stories of our times.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;When you tell the story of drug use, bringing us ... into emergency rooms and schools and shooting galleries, it's not just good journalism, it's genuine community service,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dole's speech continued an anti-drug theme he began to promote heavily on Monday, and sharpened on Wednesday with criticism of the entertainment industry for what he said was a glamorization of drug use.</p>
<p>But he also told the editors group he aimed to make trade policy a theme of his campaigning next week. &quot;Next week we'll talk about the seven-point trade policy,&quot; Dole said.</p>
<p>Dole took a couple of questions from the group, a relatively rare event for a candidate who has shied away from press conferences. He was asked about polls showing him behind Clinton and whether his message was getting through.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't worry about all these polls you write about,&quot; he said. &quot;I think our message is getting out ... we have a good solid message.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It could be down to the wire, unless we break it open here,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier on Thursday, at a rally in Las Vegas, Dole joked about his spill on Wednesday from a stage in Chico, Calif.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't be afraid of standing close to the stage. I'm not going to dive off today,&quot; Dole quipped as he addressed a rally at a ballroom in the MGM Grand casino hotel.</p>
<p>In Chico, a piece of decorative stage railing, which had not been nailed down, had given way as the candidate leaned over to shake hands.</p>
<p>Dole bruised his eye in the incident, but was otherwise unhurt. Witnesses said Dole was saved from far more serious injury by two wire-service photographers who broke his fall and caught the candidate's head as he landed face-up on the fallen railing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
