<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="643053" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai rubber prices lower on softer Tokyo.</title>
<headline>Thai rubber prices lower on softer Tokyo.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai rubber prices were steady to lower on Friday in line with Tokyo futures which were dragged down by long liquidation, traders said.</p>
<p>Trade was moderate as Japan was said to have bought big lots. China remained out of the market, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;China's idea of prices was much lower than what is quoted in the market now. I don't think heavy buying interest from that country will emerge at this level,&quot; said on Hat Yai trader.</p>
<p>Others said China might keep a low profile in the market for some time due to oversupplies.</p>
<p>&quot;On the top of that, it is more difficult to get letter of credit for rubber these days in China. One has to put 30-50 percent deposit up front. It is not a kind of rubber trade that we knew in 1996 when it was overbought,&quot; said a Bangkok-based trader.</p>
<p>Despite rising supplies in the market, traders said they expected the downside to be limited due to the government price intervention scheme which will last until the end of July.</p>
<p>Traders welcomed a remark by an official that on Friday that the government was likely to spend only one fourth of the budget to buy rubber from domestic market and that it would not sell accumulated rubber until world prices improved.</p>
<p>&quot;It is good to know that it will not spend all the four billion baht to prop up prices. The government intervention helps in the way that it drains out excess supply but at the same time it forces us to buy at high prices while the world prices are bearish,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>Chakant Saengraksawong, director of Hat Yai rubber auction market, told Reuters on Friday that the government had bought 5,770 tonnes of rubber from local producers under the intervention scheme since May 15.</p>
<p>He said the government was expected to spend only one billion baht from the earmarked budget of four billion to buy rubber under the program.</p>
<p>Thai benchmark RSS3 was quoted around 116.00 US cent a kg for August shipment and 117.00 US cents a kg for September shipment. --Anchalee Koetsawang (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
