<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="643112" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: ILO backs arrested Lebanese labour leader.</title>
<headline>ILO backs arrested Lebanese labour leader.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Labour Organisation demanded on Friday the release of Lebanese leftist union leader Elias Abou Rizk arrested for claiming to head the country's divided labour movement.</p>
<p>The action by the Geneva-based ILO followed a similar appeal on Thursday by Amnesty International which called the fiery, 54-year-old unionist a prisoner of conscience.</p>
<p>ILO envoy Walid Hamdan said he told Prosecutor-General Adnan Addoum that Abou Rizk, arrested on May 30, was the elected representative of Lebanon's General Labour Confederation (CGTL) on the U.N.-affiliated organisation's board and he should be released.</p>
<p>&quot;We say it is wrong to arrest any labour leader because of his union activity. We asked Addoum to release Abou Rizk immediately,&quot; Hamdan told reporters. Hamdan is the ILO's senior expert on labour relations for Arab countries.</p>
<p>Addoum replied that the case would be dropped if the charges of falsely claiming to head the CGTL brought by rival unionist Ghneim al-Zoghbi were withdrawn, Hamdan said.</p>
<p>Abou Rizk was arrested after CGTL elections in April which produced two leaderships -- one headed by him and one by Zoghbi, who was recognised by the government.</p>
<p>Hamdan said after visiting Abou Rizk in hospital where he is being held under detention that he was in poor health with high blood pressure and respiratory and urinary tract problems.</p>
<p>Abou Rizk, who was seeking re-election to a second four-year term as CGTL chief in the elections, had harried Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri during his first term with general strikes and attempted demonstrations to demand better conditions for workers whom he said had been forgotten by the government.</p>
<p>Abou Rizk's campaign against the government gained wide support from the political opposition and he came close to obtaining election to parliament on a leftwing ticket in general elections last summer.</p>
<p>The CGTL split and Abou Rizk's arrest have aroused widespread protests in Lebanon and charges that they are politically motivated.</p>
<p>A support committee of unionists, politicians and intellectuals on Thursday decided to call a general strike and demonstrations to demand his release.</p>
<p>Signs of a possible solution emerged on Friday after Zoghbi's supporters asked journalists' union chief Melhem Karam on Thursday to help work out a reconciliation with Abou Rizk.</p>
<p>Beirut newspapers said the release on Wednesday after questioning of Yasser Nehme, a CGTL supporter of Abou Rizk, and the decision of a magistrate not to charge the two with denigrating Lebanon's reputation abroad indicated that the authorities might back down.</p>
<p>Nehme said after his release that Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri had taken a &quot;personal interest&quot; in his case. Newspapers said Hariri intervened with the judiciary to obtain his release but this could not be independently confirmed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
