<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64318" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar finishes on firmer note in U.S. after data.</title>
<headline>Dollar finishes on firmer note in U.S. after data.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar closed moderately higher against most leading currencies, bolstered by U.S. economic reports that hinted the Federal Reserve might need to hike interest rates next Tuesday, currency experts said.</p>
<p>Strong U.S. housing starts figures and a pick-up in the price indices of the Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia's manufacturing survey bolstered expectations of a rate rise.</p>
<p>&quot;That meant that people were starting to look for a Fed rate hike at the next FOMC (Federal Open Market Committee) meeting which is why the dollar bounced up early on,&quot; said Peter Wadkins, a vice president at Standard Chartered Bank.</p>
<p>Although the business outlook index of the Philadelphia Fed survey fell, the prices paid component climbed to 18 in September from 4.6 in August and the prices received index rose to 4.6 from a previous reading of negative three.</p>
<p>As for the U.S. housing sector, the Commerce Department reported housing starts jumped 4.5 percent to an annualized rate of 1.525 million units in August, the fastest pace in about 2-1/2 years. July starts were revised to an annualized rate of 1.46 million units from a prior 1.455 million.</p>
<p>The dollar closed at 1.5135/40 marks and 109.40/45 yen, up from 1.5105/10 and 109.28/33 at the opening.</p>
<p>U.S. figures helped the dollar, but solid German economic data also released on Thursday failed to boost the mark, causing it to weaken further against the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;The failure of the mark to benefit from the European news sort of sapped the strength of the mark against the dollar,&quot; said Chris Widness, an international economist at Chase Securities Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's because the market is convinced that as long as there is a political will in Europe to proceed with monetary union, it really doesn't matter that much what the economic data are,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>German money supply or M3, which the Bundesbank sees as an important indicator of inflationary trends, unexpectedly grew at an annualized rate of 8.7 percent in August compared with an 8.6 percent rise in July. That was above economists' forecasts for growth of about 8.0 percent and marked the first pick-up in M3 growth since February.</p>
<p>The German Ifo economic research institute also reported West Germany business climate index rose to 94.4 in August from a revised 94 in July. This figure was broadly in line with the average forecast of economists polled by Reuters who expected the reading to improve to about 94.5.</p>
<p>With no other major U.S. economic data due out this week, currency traders are now free to focus on next Tuesday's Fed meeting. Heading into that all important gathering, the dollar maintains a positive underlying trend, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously the interest rate advantage of the dollar is not going to disappear on the twenty fourth,&quot; said Diego Giurleo, a vice president of the Treasury Department at Royal Bank of Canada. &quot;The only question is, does it get wider?&quot;</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the dollar finished at 1.2425/35 Swiss francs, up from 1.2395/05 at the opening. Sterling fell to $1.5532/37 from $1.5585/95.</p>
<p>The U.S. unit also finished at Canadian $1.3702/07, slightly weaker than C$1.3706/11 at the open.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar ended at $0.7904/09.</p>
<p>-- Donna Sells 212-859-1668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
