<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64314" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Two die in shooting at Florida law office.</title>
<headline>Two die in shooting at Florida law office.</headline>
<dateline>WEST PALM BEACH, Fla 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A man angry about the outcome of a worker's compensation case shot two people and held hostages at a law office Thursday, police and a friend of the gunman said.</p>
<p>Police found the gunman dead when they entered the offices 4-1/2 hours after the standoff began. Investigators believe he took his own life, said West Palm Beach Assistant Police Chief Rick Bradshaw.</p>
<p>A lawyer with the firm was wounded and another employee, believed to be a lawyer, was killed when the gunman opened fire, police said.</p>
<p>The incident began when the gunman entered the law firm of Donaldson, Danielson, Pumpian, Clark and Ford, which specialises in worker's compensation cases, police said.</p>
<p>Authorities cordoned off a half-mile area around the scene and SWAT team members staked out the building as negotiators tried to talk the man out.</p>
<p>The gunman was &quot;upset over an issue that he was discussing with these individuals, and once inside the confrontation took place and that's when he decided he was going to shoot some people,&quot; Bradshaw said.</p>
<p>The gunman allowed two members of the law firm to carry the wounded lawyer, Art Pumpian, from the building, according to police. He was taken to St. Mary's Hospital for treatment of an arm wound.</p>
<p>A man who said he was a close friend of the gunman said the man had been injured while working at a condominium complex and had gone to the law offices because he was unhappy with the outcome of his worker's compensation case.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WEST PALM BEACH, Fla"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
