<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="643296" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: White House cautiously defends Ralston.</title>
<headline>White House cautiously defends Ralston.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The White House Friday cautiously defended a top candidate for chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in the face of congressional charges of a military double standard on extramarital sex.</p>
<p>For the second day in a row, White House officials attempted to deflect questions about Gen. Joseph Ralston by saying Defence Secretary William Cohen had not yet formally recommended Ralston for the joint chairmanship.</p>
<p>&quot;The president has not evaluated the facts and Secretary Cohen is doing that and we've got a lot of confidence in his ability to do it and get it right,&quot; White House spokesman Mike McCurry said.</p>
<p>Cohen announced Thursday that he was backing Ralston to take over the Joint Chiefs of Staff despite revelations he engaged in an adulterous affair 13 years ago.</p>
<p>The news followed a recent series of embarrassing cases in which U.S. military officers have been removed from command or retired over allegations of adultery or sexual harassment, both of which are strictly prohibited in the armed forces.</p>
<p>It also comes at a time when Clinton himself is the subject of a high-profile sexual harassment lawsuit filed by a former Arkansas state employee who claims Clinton asked her for oral sex when he was Arkansas governor in 1991. Clinton has denied the charge.</p>
<p>There was every indication the White House and the Pentagon were waiting to see which way public reaction went on Ralston before deciding if he should be nominated. One test will be how the Sunday television talk shows handle it.</p>
<p>A leading member of the Senate Armed Services Committee, Maine Republican Sen. Olympia Snowe, said she had &quot;serious concerns&quot; about Ralston and would be talking with Cohen and her colleagues on the committee about it.</p>
<p>Snowe said she was concerned over Cohen's open support of Ralston just weeks after First Lt. Kelly Flinn, the Air Force's first woman B-52 bomber pilot, was forced to resign to avoid a court-martial on adultery and other charges.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it does give the appearance of preferential treatment with respect to gender or with respect to rank. The issue here is how we apply these standards and whether or not they're applied uniformly,&quot; she told NBC's &quot;Today&quot; show.</p>
<p>McCurry said those charging a double standard were people &quot;who don't recognise that each and every one of these cases have got their own separate facts and they need to be evaluated based on facts.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We don't just sort of lump everything together and make judgments based on perception, particularly when it comes to substantive matters that involve justice. Justice in this country is a case-by-case proposition and you have to look at the underlying facts of any situation, and that's what they're doing at the Pentagon,&quot; McCurry told reporters.</p>
<p>Ralston, 53, who was travelling in former Soviet states in Asia, has given no indication he will withdraw as a possible candidate to succeed Army Gen. John Shalikashvili this year.</p>
<p>Ralston this week disclosed to Cohen in response to media inquiries that he had an affair with a civilian woman while he was a colonel and separated from his first wife 13 years ago. They were later reconciled but divorced in 1988.</p>
<p>In a statement Thursday, Ralston, vice chairman of the joint chiefs, took &quot;full responsibility for my conduct some years ago.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
