<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="643299" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT - T-bond futures rebound after jobs report.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - T-bond futures rebound after jobs report.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasury bond futures displayed a bullish tenacity Friday, bouncing back from early losses to take out key resistance and register a 3 1/2-month high, technicians said.</p>
<p>September bond futures continued to push to fresh highs in the final hour of the session and were last trading up 1 1/32 at 111-01, their highest point since reaching 111-24 on Feb. 26.</p>
<p>Persistent technically based buying fed the rally following this morning's mixed news on U.S. employment growth, bond traders said.  </p>
<p>The Labor Department this morning said the U.S. economy added 138,000 jobs in May, far below expectations. However, the unemployment rate slipped to a 23-1/2 year low of 4.8 percent, and April payrolls were revised up to 323,000 from 142,000, with March jobs also revised upward.</p>
<p>The rally in bond futures did not catch fire until midmorning when September moved decisively above downtrend resistance near 110-03 drawn from the December highs, floor traders said. The contract had stalled repeatedly at that juncture throughout the week.  </p>
<p>The surge touched off buy-stops clustered near 110-04 and 110-09 in the September contract, traders said. &quot;There were boatloads of stops in there,&quot; said one floor broker.</p>
<p>Technical analysts said the breakout, which pushed September up through an array of moving averages after expanding the previous day's range in both directions, portended an extension to the 112-00 area.</p>
<p>However, some also expressed concern about excess exuberance as momentum indicators ratcheted higher.  </p>
<p>&quot;I'm a little concerned that the market is overbought on a short-term basis,&quot; said Michael Krauss, chief technical strategist for Chase Securities Inc. &quot;The market is actually a lot better off than I would have thought given the news.&quot;</p>
<p>Krauss pointed to a daily sentiment index indicating the market had flipped to 72 percent bullish before today's session from just 27 percent last week as a cautionary signal.</p>
<p>Still, longterm and intermediate stochastics corroborate the market's underlying strength, said James Grauer, president of Omnitrage.  </p>
<p>Further supporting the uptrend are daily stochastics that earlier this week turned down but could not gain momentum and truncated a cycle pattern, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;When the market is in a state of equivocation, technicals take over, and the technicals are unequivocally bullish,&quot; Grauer said.</p>
<p>-- Susan Kelly, Derivatives Desk ((312-408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
