<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="643395" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: UK's Blair urges reform to tackle mass joblessness.</title>
<headline>UK's Blair urges reform to tackle mass joblessness.</headline>
<byline>Alan Wheatley</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Prime Minister Tony Blair wrapped up a hectic two days of diplomacy on Friday confident that Europe was heeding his message that economic reform to tackle mass unemployment can be delayed no longer.</p>
<p>Buoyed by an opinion poll at home showing that within five weeks of taking power he was the most popular prime minister on record, Blair made it clear after talks in Bonn with German Chancellor Helmut Kohl that he wanted to use his honeymoon to re-establish Britain as a leading player on the European stage.</p>
<p>&quot;What is important for us to understand as a country is that people are looking to Britain to give some leadership in what are very difficult times in Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;People like the idea of a Britain that is constructive and is setting the agenda,&quot; Blair told reporters after two hours of talks with Kohl that British officials called friendly and constructive.</p>
<p>The Labour prime minister pressed on Kohl the same message he had delivered at a meeting of Europe's centre-left parties in the southern Swedish city of Malmo: new economic times, and Europe's 18 million jobless, require governments to come up with new solutions.</p>
<p>Blair said he believed his mantra of flexible markets was striking a chord -- even in a country like Germany whose successful social market economic model relies on a degree of state intervention that would be anathema in new Labour Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;I was delighted that there was a very strong measure of agreement between myself and Chancellor Kohl that we do require economic reform in Europe,&quot; Blair said.</p>
<p>&quot;People know it's a different type of economy today and we have to focus on education, technology, developing small businesses -- not the old state intervention of the 60s,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Blair's aides said he received a similarly positive response from leaders of countries such as Sweden, Denmark, Portugal and the Netherlands during the Malmo congress.</p>
<p>And although Blair would not go along with some of the ideas of French Prime Minister Lionel Jospin -- who said in Malmo that unfettered market forces would threaten civilisation as we know it -- he was content that the new French premier also wanted to put jobs at the top of the European agenda.</p>
<p>Blair's advice to Kohl on economic reform was particularly telling on a day that another rise in German unemployment dealt a fresh blow to the chancellor's cherished hopes of qualifying for the European Union's planned single currency.</p>
<p>But Blair, who ended 18 years of Conservative rule in a landslide victory on May 1, denied that it was presumptuous of him to come and lecture Kohl, Europe's elder statesman, and other much more experienced leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not a question of lecturing, but it is a question of saying to people: come on, let's face the common challenges that we have in our countries. Everyone can see the problems that Europe has -- particularly the high levels of unemployment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's in our interests that Europe succeeds with Britain as a leading player in it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Blair said he was very pleased that Kohl had expressed his strong personal commitment to the four-nation Eurofighter project, which has been dogged by Germany's deepening budget problems.</p>
<p>He also believed that Kohl now understood better Britain's insistence on retaining control over its borders as part of the revised EU treaty due to be concluded at a summit in Amsterdam on June 16-17.</p>
<p>&quot;Britain is an island. We have a particuar view on our frontiers and our borders and that is absolutely unchangeable for us. Now I hope that everyone in Europe understands that, and I think they do,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
