<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="643483" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: FOCUS-Saab sees 10,000 sales of new model.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Saab sees 10,000 sales of new model.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Schmelz</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish luxury carmaker Saab Automobile AB, gearing up for the launch of its 9-5 top-end model, said on Friday it expected to sell 10,000 of the new cars in 1997.</p>
<p>Analysts said the company's future could very well ride on the success of this model. With only two platforms and plagued by financial woes for most of the 1990s, Saab Auto can ill afford a flop.</p>
<p>Saab Auto's owners are U.S. car giant General Motors and Swedish investment company Investor, although Investor is considering selling its stake to GM.</p>
<p>&quot;It's really important that no one spots quality problems with this new model. They really can't afford that,&quot; said Gustaf von Essen, automotive analyst at Carnegie in Stockholm.</p>
<p>&quot;It's extremely important. I am surprised that they are not making more out of the introduction,&quot; said Den Danske Bank analyst Hans Westerberg.</p>
<p>The 9-5 is destined to replace the 9000 series, used mainly by company executives and targeted at the image-conscious end of the car market, unlike the sporty 900 series.</p>
<p>Saab Automobile has invited some 1,000 journalists to its headquarters in Trollhattan, on Sweden's west coast, to test drive the car ahead of the car's commercial launch in September.</p>
<p>Pre-launch publicity suffered a jolt this week when an elderly woman was killed when the car she was driving on a rural Swedish track was in collision with a 9-5 test car.</p>
<p>The company has a targeted total sales of 150,000 cars in 2000, of which the 9-5 model is expected to account for almost half and the smaller 900 series for about the same. The larger 9000 series, which is due to be phased out, will still account for around 10,000 sales in 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect sales of Saab cars to exceed 100,000 cars in 1997,&quot; Saab Automobile spokesman Olle Axelsson told Reuters. &quot;We expect 10 percent of the sold cars to be of the 9-5 model.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;To launch a new model is a key event for all companies and big investments and resources are put into it. Saab's new model is extremely important for the company and we are sure the new model will be a boost for Saab Auto,&quot; Axelsson said.</p>
<p>In 1996 Saab Automobile swung into the red, posting a pre-tax loss of 1.24 billion crowns ($159.7 million) -- of which about half was because of marketing costs -- compared with a profit of 148 million crowns a year earlier.</p>
<p>Saab Automobile managing director Robert Hendry has said the company's 1997 result will still suffer from strategic investments before returning to the black in 1998 and reaching an acceptable profit level in 2000.</p>
<p>Salomon Brothers analyst John Lawson said the 9-5 launch was critical for the company if it was going to boost sales volumes and post profits in the medium term. He added, however, that talk so far about the new model had been positive.</p>
<p>&quot;Every expectation is that the new 9-5 will be a much more successful collaboration from Saab's perspective and I've heard nothing but very positive things from the suppliers that are involved in this project,&quot; Lawson said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is going to be much more successful in being a real alternative to some of the other image manufacturers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although they've had two vehicles for some time, they've never really had two youthful ones. In fact, the 900 is enjoying something of a revival...it's not sinking into the tail end of its cycle,&quot; Lawson said.</p>
<p>&quot;With GM's help, this is the first time they've had the opportunity to have two relatively modern platforms on the go at the same time,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A General Motors spokesman based in Zurich said the launch was important and that the company was confident about its success.</p>
<p>&quot;We have shown our financial commitment to Saab for the past eight years and I think that speaks for itself,&quot; he said. ($ = 7.765 Swedish Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
