<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="643546" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Total peace for Hill Tracts may elude Bangladesh.</title>
<headline>Total peace for Hill Tracts may elude Bangladesh.</headline>
<byline>Nizamuddin Ahmed</byline>
<dateline>CHITTAGONG, Bangladesh 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>A pact between the government and tribes in Bangladesh's Chittagong Hill Tracts may not be able to bring peace to the region while other restive forces continue to rebel, civil and military officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are expecting the agreement between authorities and tribal Shanti Bahini guerrillas by early next month,&quot; one official in the Hill Tracts said.</p>
<p>&quot;But this may not lead to a total peace in the region,&quot; said the official, who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>Officials say an insurgency by the Shanti Bahini since 1973, over demand for autonomy for the 5,500 sq-mile (14,200 sq-km) Hill Tracts bordering India and Burma, has killed over 8,500 people.</p>
<p>The victims include rebels, soldiers, police, tribespeople and Bengali-speaking settlers, whom the Shantis want to be expelled from the Hill Tracts, which they consider a tribal homeland.</p>
<p>The insurgency also forced up to 50,000 tribespeople to flee into northeast India's Tripura state but about 7,000 of them had been repatriated in March-April. The rest of the refugees are expected to return home soon.</p>
<p>&quot;Peace is in the offing but (it) may be threatened by armed insurgents from outside the Shanti Bahini ranks,&quot; an intelligence officer in the Hill Tracts said.</p>
<p>He said tribal rebels from India's Mizoram state and Moslem insurgents from Burma's western Arakan province often crossed into Bandarban, one of three Hill Tract districts, and attacked Bangladesh security personnel.</p>
<p>Bangladesh police on Wednesday arrested Indian national Zing Thwai Marma, 30, of Mizoram at Thanchi, a remote border area in Bandarban.</p>
<p>Marma told police that he, along with 11 other Mizo tribesmen and some Burmese rebels, raided a camp of Bangladesh border guards (BDR) at Thanchi on May 3.</p>
<p>One BDR officer was killed in the raid, police said. Police believed the same group was involved in another attack in February, killing one soldier and two policemen.</p>
<p>Marma was detained by police at a hideout where he was being treated secretly for gunshot wounds received during the May 3 raid.</p>
<p>During his interrogation Marma said all his comrades had been killed. Police said he might be telling lies to protect his friends.</p>
<p>Police had blamed the May 3 raid on the Shanti Bahini, which denied the charge.</p>
<p>&quot;Now it appears that the region has been infested with other guerrillas than the Shantis. Even if we sign a deal (for peace with the Shantis) a total peace may still be eluding us,&quot; one Hill Tracts official said on Friday.</p>
<p>Police said they found two dead tribals with weapons at Thanchi early last month.</p>
<p>&quot;But they may not belong to the Shanti Bahini,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>More than 12,000 army troops and 18,000 other security forces were now deployed in the Hill Tracts, many of whom were expected to be pulled back once the peace deal was signed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHITTAGONG, Bangladesh"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
