<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="643870" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE coffee above lows by noon, July off 3.7 pct.</title>
<headline>LIFFE coffee above lows by noon, July off 3.7 pct.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>LIFFE robusta coffee futures, extending Thursday's steep technical-related losses, stumbled further at the start on Friday before ending midsession above the morning lows.</p>
<p>Prices gapped just $45 lower basis July, well above earlier expecations of $110 down. After opening at $1,850, July headed to a low of $1,815 after breaking the immediate $1,835 support.</p>
<p>But it managed to fight back and finished the morning trade 3.7 percent or $70 down at the $1,835 support level.</p>
<p>In all, the market had lost some 32 percent in a week alone as the robustas took a sharp downward swing from a rally that has taken prices to 20-month highs in May.</p>
<p>Traders said Thursday's slide on sell-stops, which eroded values by some 8.5 percent, was further exaggerated by long liquidation by day-traders.</p>
<p>Last week's breakthrough to $2,670, the 20-month-peak basis July, was also fuelled by aggressive industry price-fixing. But roasters had since stood aside, awaiting to see further falls before committing themselves.</p>
<p>Volume reached 4,400 lots. July-Sept switch was traded at $25-$30 and Sept/Nov at $10-12.</p>
<p>Traders said it was still uncertain to say whether the rally since early January had come to an end.</p>
<p>Technical analysts said the rally over the last few weeks had been overdone and the market was now staging a downward correction which was long overdue.</p>
<p>&quot;It became parabolic,&quot; said Elli Gifford, an independent technical analyst. &quot;Having retraced virtually two-thirds of its gains, and with a weak close, it's likely to be followed by a test of support at $1,835,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>If this level were to break, then prices would target a trading band placed around $1,600 and above -- the base from which London launched its explosive rally.</p>
<p>Brazil's coffee belt is expected to escape a damaging cold this weekend although temperatures might drop to below normal levels.</p>
<p>Lack of any damaging cold to Brazil's coffee trees so far at the onset of winter there has temporarily allayed fears that next year's production might be damaged by frost, as occurred in 1994.</p>
<p>-- Jalil Hamid, London Newsroom +44 171 542 4985</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
