<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64394" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Want to quit smoking? Call us, psychiatrists say.</title>
<headline>Want to quit smoking? Call us, psychiatrists say.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Can't quit smoking? Maybe it's time to see a psychiatrist.</p>
<p>The American Psychiatric Association on Thursday released its first guidelines on helping smokers who have tried and failed to quit on their own, or even after getting the help of their regular family doctors.</p>
<p>&quot;The people who find it easy to quit are quitting. The rest need a new approach,&quot; said Dr. John Hughes, a University of Vermont psychiatrist who helped develop these guidelines.</p>
<p>Smokers, said the APA's deputy medical director Dr. Deborah Zarin, are &quot;repeatedly engaging in life-threatening behaviour.&quot;</p>
<p>That itself should be reason enough to get a specialists' help, she said, adding that it is not all that different from a car owner seeking a transmission shop when the auto breaks down despite repeated trips to the regular mechanic.</p>
<p>Family doctors themselves got new clinical guidelines on smoking this year. Physicians, researchers and health administrators gathered in Washington for a conference this week on how to make sure they are really put into practice to help the 25 percent of U.S. adults who still smoke despite decades of warnings about heart disease and cancer.</p>
<p>That two-day conference, sponsored by the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, stressed research that shows that doctors can improve the &quot;quit smoking rates&quot; by spending as little as three minutes counselling a smoker.</p>
<p>&quot;Patients report that the personal input by their clinician often is the element to sustain them through the first critical weeks after quitting,&quot; said Dr. Michael Fiori of the University of Wisconsin, who helped draft the doctors' guidelines for the U.S. Agency for Health Care Policy and Research.</p>
<p>&quot;A doctor can help with the simple problem solving skills and techniques that will help a smoker quit, and understand what went wrong the last time,&quot; Fiori added in an interview.</p>
<p>Psychiatrists agree with that. Their guidelines start out with the recommendation that people try to quit on their own, through widely available self-help programmes or with nicotine patches and gum, now available without a prescription, or with the help of their doctor.</p>
<p>But even after all that, some smokers will not be able to give up cigarettes. Psychiatrists believe that with their extra training and experience in addiction, substance abuse and behaviour patterns, they are well-positioned to help.</p>
<p>In addition, many smokers who have the most trouble quitting actually have undiagnosed psychiatric problems such as alcoholism or depression that may make giving up the tobacco habit even more difficult, the APA said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
