<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="644121" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy finance police search ski star Tomba's house.</title>
<headline>Italy finance police search ski star Tomba's house.</headline>
<dateline>BOLOGNA, Italy 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian police were searching the house of Alberto Tomba on Friday in a probe into allegations that the Olympic ski hero may have avoided paying taxes on sponsorship earnings, a magistrate said.</p>
<p>Investigating magistrate Enrico Cieri told Reuters that paramilitary and finance police were searching an apartment in the grounds of a house owned by Tomba's parents near the northern town of Bologna.</p>
<p>Cieri did not specify the exact nature of the accusations against Tomba but confirmed that public prosecutors in Bologna were investigating possible irregularities in the declaration of income from sponsorship and advertising deals.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear whether the triple Olympic gold medallist and former world champion was present during the search of the house at Castel De Britti.</p>
<p>Tomba, one of Italy's foremost sporting heroes, was reportedly due to travel to the Bosnian capital Sarajevo on Monday to look into the possibility of holding a &quot;slalom for peace&quot; there later in the year.</p>
<p>His last season was marred by injury and Tomba has been involved in much unwanted publicity recently after being sued by a photographer who was hurt by a heavy glass trophy that the Italian threw at him after a race in 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOLOGNA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
