<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64414" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Western Resources seen winning Kansas City Power.</title>
<headline>Western Resources seen winning Kansas City Power.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Intindola</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kansas City Power &amp; Light Co. could become the first U.S. utility to fall to a hostile takeover after a lack of shareholder support forced it to abandon its $1.7 billion merger agreement with UtiliCorp United Inc.</p>
<p>Rival bidder Western Resources Inc. is now expected to sweep up Kansas City Power, capping a successful raid against the company and potentially spurring a new wave of hostile utility mergers, industry analysts said.</p>
<p>Kansas City Power, based in Kansas City, Mo., said Wednesday it failed to win shareholder approval for its proposed merger with Utilicorp, also based in Kansas City.</p>
<p>KCP&amp;L is still playing defence since it is opposed to Western's $1.9 billion offer, but analysts say Western has already won over KCP&amp;L shareholders in its five-month takeover battle and will likely succeed.</p>
<p>A source close to KCP&amp;L said the company is still recommending shareholders not tender their shares to Western.</p>
<p>KCP&amp;L shareholders must now weigh Western's offer of $31 of its stock per KCP&amp;L share.</p>
<p>In trading Thursday, Kansas City Power was unchanged at $27.25 a share, Utilicorp was up 12.5 cents at $28 a share, and Western was up 12.5 cents at $29 a share, all on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Western said if a majority of the shareholders back the deal, but the directors balk, they are prepared to nominate their own slate of directors who will approve the merger.</p>
<p>The offer expires Oct. 25 but can be extended by Western if necessary.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Wall Street was already buzzing over which would be the next utility to attract an unwanted bidder.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a brave new world out there and hostile takeovers are now a part of that,&quot; said Penelope Adelmann, Gruntal &amp; Co. utility analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;It certainly opens up the hostile as another possibility. I think it will be a trend,&quot; said Linda Byus, Nesbitt Burns utility analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;It is significant industrywide because it shows shareholders now have a say. Historically, utility retail shareholders -- the moms and pops, widows and orphans -- have gone along with management. But this is a wakeup call that managements work for shareholders,&quot; Byus said.</p>
<p>But Adelmann noted hostile takeovers do not suit every company.</p>
<p>&quot;When Western has a particular goal in mind, they go after it strongly. So hostile takeovers take a particular type of management, and there are not many like Western. With a hostile, you have got to use your own management (in the post-deal company) and feel you can make it with your own people.&quot;</p>
<p>A recent issue of the Utility Forecaster newsletter identified some potential takeover targets, including Citizens Utilities Co., Energen Corp. and Central Louisiana Electric.</p>
<p>Six weeks ago, another hostile offer was announced. MidAmerican Energy Co., based in Des Moines, Iowa, launched a bid to break up a friendly three-way merger by offering $1.2 billion in cash and stock, or $39 per share, for IES Industries Inc., of Cedar Rapids, Iowa.</p>
<p>IES agreed last fall to combine with Interstate Power Co. of Dubuque, Iowa, and WPL Holdings Inc. of Madison, Wis.</p>
<p>One of the few hostile utility mergers previously attempted -- all have failed -- included Western's predecessor company and KCP&amp;L.</p>
<p>Five years ago, KCP&amp;L made a hostile run at Kansas Gas and Electric Co., but Kansas Power &amp; Light came in as a white knight and merged with KGE to create Western Resources.</p>
<p>Roger Conrad, editor of the Utility Forecaster newsletter, said KCP&amp;L's decision to back out of the UtiliCorp pact has &quot;enormous implications because if the Western deal comes off, it shows utilities don't necessarily need the approval of the other board to launch a takeover. So we will see more of these types of deals, or at least more pressure to enter negotiations.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
