<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="644298" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Gulf Canada to bid for CS Resources.</title>
<headline>Gulf Canada to bid for CS Resources.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Jones</byline>
<dateline>CALGARY, Alberta 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Acquisition-hungry Gulf Canada Resources Ltd. said on Friday it would make a C$413 million ($301 million) takeover bid for high-tech Canadian heavy oil producer CS Resources Ltd..</p>
<p>Calgary-based Gulf Canada, which earlier this year acquired Britain's Clyde Petroleum in a bitter fight, said it intended to offer C$14.25 ($10.40) for each CS share in a cash or stock deal.</p>
<p>Merger discussions between the two companies started on May 28 and Gulf Canada said it hoped the talks would continue despite making its bid intentions public.</p>
<p>CS had no immediate response to the Gulf Canada announcement.</p>
<p>CS, known for advanced horizontal drilling techniques used under an exclusive license with France's Institut Francais du Petrole, as well as thermal heavy oil recovery, expected to produce 19,500 barrels of oil a day equivalent this year, up from 14,800 last year.</p>
<p>Heavy oil is a thick, gooey form of crude oil that sells at a discount to light oil because it requires more refining. It is Canada's fastest growing grade of crude and the target of billions of dollars in projects in Alberta and Saskatchewan.</p>
<p>Calgary-based CS's drilling and production techniques are aimed at boosting the amount of heavy oil that can be pumped from the fewest number of wells.</p>
<p>&quot;We have indicated to our shareholders and the financial community that a key element of Gulf's strategy is to become a leading developer of heavy oil,&quot; Gulf Canada Chief Executive J.P. Bryan said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;This acquisition of substantial heavy oil assets, quality people and technological expertise, combined with Gulf's existing oil sands assets and expertise, will establish Gulf Canada Resources as the leader in Canadian heavy oil and oil sands development.&quot;</p>
<p>Under the proposal, CS shareholders would be offered either 1.1539 Gulf Canada common shares or all cash, subject to a maximum of C$100 million ($73 million), for each CS share.</p>
<p>The offer represented a 26 percent premium to Thursday's CS closing price of C$11.30 and a 39 percent premium to the closing price of C$10.25 on May 28, when discussions began, Gulf Canada said.</p>
<p>CS said earlier on Friday its board approved a shareholder rights plan, allowing permitted bids an offer period of a minimum of 45 days. Its stock was halted on the Toronto Stock Exchange on Friday for the bid announcement.</p>
<p>Gulf Canada shares were down C45 cents to C$11.90 in morning trade on Friday in Toronto.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY, Alberta"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
