<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="644290" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SGL Carbon denies alleged price fixing.</title>
<headline>SGL Carbon denies alleged price fixing.</headline>
<byline>John Gilardi</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT, Germany 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's SGL Carbon AG, being probed by U.S. and European Union officials on allegations of price-fixing, denied Friday that it was part of a cartel and said authorities had made no concrete charges.</p>
<p>An SGL Carbon spokesman said the group was cooperating with investigators in Germany and the United States who searched its offices on Thursday and Friday in the Frankfurt area and in Charlotte, N.C., and took away documents.</p>
<p>A U.S. federal grand jury in Pennsylvania is investigating allegations of possible price-fixing in the graphite electrode industry, whose products are mainly used in steel making.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been no concrete accusations by the cartel authorities against SGL Carbon,&quot; a company spokesman in Wiesbaden, Germany, told Reuters in response to an inquiry.</p>
<p>&quot;We have laid everything open,&quot; the spokesman said. &quot;We have nothing to hide. SGL Carbon has not engaged in any illegal price-fixing activities.&quot;</p>
<p>Other companies targeted in the probe of pricing policies for graphite electrodes include industry leader UCAR International Inc. and Carbide/Graphite Group Inc., both of the United States.</p>
<p>The German Cartel Office in Berlin, aiding the EU in Brussels, said Friday it also searched the offices of Viag AG units VAW and VAW Carbon and those of Z. Konradty Nuernberg GmbH in Roethenbach in addition to SGL Carbon.</p>
<p>Carbide/Graphite, based in Pittsburgh, said Thursday it had agreed to cooperate with the probe in return for immunity from criminal charges for it and certain former executives.</p>
<p>UCAR, the world's largest maker of graphite and carbon electrodes, also said it was cooperating with the probe.</p>
<p>But UCAR, along with SGL Carbon, considered No. 2 in industry sales, have not said whether they would seek immunity from prosecution.</p>
<p>Shares in SGL, a darling of the German stock market after it was spun off from chemical group Hoechst AG last year, tumbled 10 percent to about 236 marks on Friday after SGL first announced the raid on its offices late Thursday.</p>
<p>The shares later pared some of the losses to close bourse trade at 239 marks, down 8 percent, as some analysts reaffirmed &quot;buy&quot; ratings.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. watchdog authorities continuously monitor all industries and it is only natural that the electrode industry would come under a usual investigation at some stage,&quot; said Paribas Capital Markets in a commentary rating SGL a &quot;buy.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Our knowledge of the industry and of the companies makes us certain that this investigation will have no effect and not result in any fines,&quot; Paribas said.</p>
<p>The graphite electrode industry was burdened with major overcapacity in the 1980s, causing manufacturers to suffer large losses and for SGL Carbon to be formed out of the consolidation, according to industry analysts.</p>
<p>Prices for electrodes have still not reached the price per ton seen in the mid-1980s despite attempts to raise them due to higher costs for needle coke, electricity and labour.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said profit margins remain low, making it difficult for new competition, one reason that may have prompted the investigation by authorities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
