<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64421" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. finds racial mix among church fire suspects.</title>
<headline>U.S. finds racial mix among church fire suspects.</headline>
<byline>James Vicini</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>One-third of the suspects arrested since January 1995 for the burning of predominately black churches in the South were black, federal officials investigating the recent wave of fires said Thursday.</p>
<p>They also disclosed one case where a black, in retaliation, burned down a white church in a Southern state.</p>
<p>The spate of widely publicised church fires initially revived memories of Ku Klux Klan firebombings of black churches in the 1960s during the civil rights movement, but the new arrest figures painted a different picture.</p>
<p>&quot;We know from the evidence and from the arrests made that race is driving many of these fires. We know that race is not driving all of these fires,&quot; Deval Patrick, head of the Justice Department's Civil Rights Division, said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our responsibility as prosecutors and investigators is to follow all the leads where they lead us and to get to the bottom of each one of these fires, regardless of what the motivation is,&quot; he told a news briefing.</p>
<p>More than half of the 100 suspects arrested since January 1995 for church fires or bombings appear to be motivated by racial hatred or bigotry, said federal officials who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>But they said they have found other motives as well, including pranks, internal disputes within the congregation and attacks carried out by mentally ill individuals.</p>
<p>They were unable to cite any evidence of a national conspiracy behind church burnings but said a small number of fires in South Carolina and Tennessee may have been related.</p>
<p>&quot;The evidence does not suggest, based on the arrests we have, that there is one plan that connects all these dots around the South,&quot; one official said.</p>
<p>Since January 1995, there have been arsons or bombings at 100 predominantly black churches and 130 mainly white churches nationwide, the officials said. In just the South, about half of the 150 fires occurred at black churches.</p>
<p>At the mainly white churches, black suspects were arrested in seven percent of the incidents, they said.</p>
<p>Investigators found that more than 40 percent of those arrested were under age 18 and most of the fires took place on weekends and in rural areas, the officials said. They said the most vulnerable churches were not used regularly during the week or every Sunday.</p>
<p>Treasury Assistant Secretary Jim Johnson emphasised that special training for federal agents had helped address concerns by some black congregations about the investigations. Black officials initially complained that investigators unfairly made church members targets of their questioning.</p>
<p>The fires received national attention this summer, with President Clinton in June visiting a black church in South Carolina that had burned down. Republicans in Congress charged he was trying to score political points with the visit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
