<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="644365" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IEA sees oil refinery maintenance peaking in Asia.</title>
<headline>IEA sees oil refinery maintenance peaking in Asia.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spring maintenance shutdowns at oil refineries are currently peaking in Asia but falling in Europe, said the International energy Agency (IEA) on Friday.</p>
<p>In the United States refineries are thought to have completely emerged from the turnaround season, the IEA said in it's latest Monthly Oil Market Report.</p>
<p>European and Asian maintenance is expected to be lighter than in the previous three years but there is some flexibility on the timing and the extent of shutdowns, the IEA said.</p>
<p>In Europe the capacity closed by maintenance is expected to be 550,000 barrels per day (bpd) in June, falling to 140,000 bpd in July and just 70,000 in August.</p>
<p>In Japan 1.23 million bpd of capacity is expected to shut in June, falling to 450,000 bpd in July and 160,000 bpd in August.</p>
<p>In other areas of the Asia/Pacific region capacity closed falls from 670,000 bpd in June to 310,000 bpd in July but 570,000 bpd in August.</p>
<p>In a survey of how refinery capacity will expend over the next two years the IEA said that the recent rapid expansion in Asia will begin to slow this year and next.</p>
<p>In 1995 and 1996 the region saw increases of 670,000 bpd and 1 million bpd respectively. But in 1997 and 1998 the increases will be 418,000 bpd and 604,000 bpd respectively.</p>
<p>The Middle East and Asia-Pacific regions now appear to be the only areas with sizeable refining capacity additions in coming years, the IEA said.</p>
<p>--London newsroom, 542 4984</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
