<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="644406" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks end lower, placement lifts trade.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks end lower, placement lifts trade.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>-----------------(Snapshot 4.30 p.m./0630 GMT)-----------------</p>
<p>AORD		2,600.9    -3.3   DJIA cl     7,305.29   +35.63</p>
<p>SPI Sycom	 2,611.0    +5.0   US 30yr cl	6.88    unch</p>
<p>10yrbond futs    92.675  +0.045   Gold NY 343.35 Lon fix 340.80</p>
<p>AUD	 $0.7595 (Thu $0.7577)   CRB Index cl  246.64    -0.36</p>
<p>NIKKEI cl     20,485.75   -2.40   FTSE cl	4,576.2    +19.1</p>
<p>S&amp;P500(Globex)   846.30   +0.30   NZSE40 cl   2,376.14   +13.35</p>
<p>--------------------------(June 6)-----------------------------</p>
<p>*Stocks close easier but off lows in trade dominated by A$1.5 billion Foster's placement. Volume 1.01 billion, A$2.58 billion, 1,113 stocks traded, 332 steady, 377 up, 404 down.</p>
<p>The Australian stock market held its head just above the 2,600 mark on Friday in a day dominated by the placement of A$1.54 billion of Foster's Brewing Group shares.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries Index firmed off its lows in afternoon trade to close down just 3.3 points at 2,600.9, a fall of 9.6 points from the previous Friday's close.</p>
<p>Dealers said there appeared to be some institutional selling to fund the Foster's take-up, but less than might have been expected given the size of the placement.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market hasn't been hit too badly,&quot; said Simon Burge, investment manager at Tyndall Australia.</p>
<p>Many institutions had been sitting on cash this year and may not have needed to dispose of assets to fund the purchase, while much of the stock also went overseas, he said.</p>
<p>The placement of 616.6 million Foster's shares owned by the the Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd followed its long-awaited move to end aan 11-year link with the brewing group.  </p>
<p>Were Stockbroking managing director John Paterson said retail investors bought about A$150 million of the A$1.535 billion package, with overseas institutions taking 55 percent of the remainder and local institutions 45 percent.</p>
<p>Foster's closed seven cents lower at A$2.53, but above the A$2.49 price at which the package was specialled.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the Australia and New Zealand Banking Group provided the main highlight, soaring 30 cents to A$9.09 on turnover of 2.19 million shares.  </p>
<p>Dealers said appetite for ANZ may have been renewed by investors discounting a rumour on Thursday of a possible takeover bid for rival Westpac Banking Corp</p>
<p>Such a takeover would have left ANZ on the shelf, as the Federal government would not countenance a bid for more than one of Australia's four big banks.</p>
<p>Westpac eased after strong gains on Thursday, while Westpac target Bank of Melbourne recovered some losses after Competition and Consumer Commission (ACCC) chairman Alan Fels said rumours he had rejected the bid were premature.  </p>
<p>Westpac also confirmed it had sold a 2.99 percent stake in publishing group John Fairfax Holdings Ltd. Merrill Lynch specialled the line of 22.75 million shares at A$3.30.</p>
<p>Other stocks to show strong turnover included Pacific Dunlop, which eased 10 cents to A$3.64 on turnover of 15 million shares, and National Australia Bank which fell 10 cents to A$18.77 million on turnover of 10.5 million.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, retailers Woolworths and David Jones were stronger, while the gold index firmed in line with a rebound in the gold price.  </p>
<p>The June share price index ended up 5.0 points at 2,611.0, a 10.1 point premium to the underlying index, while falls narrowly outpointed rises.</p>
<p>In other markets, the Australian dollar ended subdued at US$0.7593, but up from SU$0.7577 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Australian bond yields closed lower on hopes of a further easing in official interest rates. The 10-year T-bond was up 5.0 points at 92.680.</p>
<p>-------------------------(TECHNICALS)--------------------------</p>
<p>	   Short-term range Support Restnce RSI-14 MA-10 MA-20</p>
<p>AORD	   2580/2620	2590    2615   68.18  2601  2569</p>
<p>SPI	    2600/2640	2600    2640   65.37  2608  2574</p>
<p>------------------------KEY ACTIVES----------------------------</p>
<p>*BHP A$18.72 (-.11) 18.63/18.858 Vol: 3,974,108</p>
<p>*Foster's A$2.53 (-.07) 2.481/2.56 Vol: 678.3 million</p>
<p>Bellwether softens as it exits 11-year link with brewer</p>
<p>*ANZ A$9.09 (-.30) 8.76/9.10 Vol: 2,193,369</p>
<p>Bank soars on discouting of takeover rumour for rival</p>
<p>*Westpac A$7.17 (-.03) 7.15/7.33 Vol: 3,702,183</p>
<p>*Bank of Melbourne A$9.09 (+.14) 8.91/9.15 Vol:177,748</p>
<p>ACCC says market premature on bid block speculation</p>
<p>*John Fairfax A$3.30 (+.01) 3.25/3.30 Vol:24.03 million</p>
<p>Westpac sells 2.99 percent stake in publisher</p>
<p>*Pacific Dunlop A$3.64 (-.10) 3.63/3.76 Vol:15,070,909</p>
<p>Line of 13.25 million shares specialled</p>
<p>*NAB A$18.77 (-.11) 18.77/18.944 Vol: 10.59 million</p>
<p>*Strong turnover in favoured bank sector</p>
<p>*Rio Tinto A$20.85 (-.22) 20.70/21.023 Vol: 684,861</p>
<p>Former CRA continues to ease after recent rally</p>
<p>-- Richard Pullin, Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
