<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="644441" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Car makers applaud as Australia slows tariff cuts.</title>
<headline>Car makers applaud as Australia slows tariff cuts.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Perrett</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>A historic slowdown in Australia's headlong rush to lower tariffs brought applause from local car makers on Friday but criticism from farmers, who said their efficient industry would pay for manufacturing protection.</p>
<p>Australians have become increasing hostile to the country's decade-long unilateral assault on manufacturing protection, and the government and Opposition fought to take credit for Prime Minister John Howard's Thursday decision to hold the automotive import tariff no lower than 15 percent until 2005.</p>
<p>&quot;In making a decision to retain a tariff regime, the prime minister and his cabinet colleagues have ensured that Australa will retain a strong automotive industry able to compete internationally and, as well, able to deliver quality products at reasonable prices to Australian consumers,&quot; the Motor Trades Association said.</p>
<p>General Motors Corp's Australian subsidiary, Holden, said the retention of higher tariff protection gave it the confidence to continue significant investment.</p>
<p>&quot;The outcome also laid the foundation for Holden and others becoming key global players within the Asia Pacific region,&quot; Holden chairman and managing director Jim Wiemels said in a statement.</p>
<p>Farmers, unprotected and competing against heavily subsidised foreign producers, were less enthusiastic.</p>
<p>&quot;Australia's farmers will ask this government why the self-proclaimed world-competitive automotive industry should continue to be protected, while the demonstrably world-competitive agricultural sector bears the cost,&quot; the National Farmers Federation said.</p>
<p>&quot;Protection comes at a cost -- currently estimated at A$3,000 (US$2,300) per car -- and the entire country will pay.&quot;</p>
<p>General Motors, Ford Motor Co, Toyota Motor Corp and Mitsubishi Motors Corp all make cars in Australia, mostly in the states of South Australia and Victoria.</p>
<p>Australia's small manufacturing sector was heavily protected from World War II until the mid-1980s, when the then Labor government started cutting tariffs -- without negotiating reciprocal concessions from trading partners.</p>
<p>But as manufacturing employment plummets, researchers are finding voters increasingly sceptical about tariff cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;A nostalgia for an Australia that was seen as making things, combined with a worry about an over-reliance on imported products is leading to an emerging popular consensus that enough is enough when it comes to tariff cuts,&quot; social researcher Rod Cameron said last week.</p>
<p>Populist politician Pauline Hanson has gained 10 percent voter support with her campaign for, among other things, the retention of tariffs.</p>
<p>So the Opposition tried to claim credit when Howard announced on Thursday that he had rejected the advice of government economists, who wanted the tariff cut to five percent in 2004 from the current 22.5 percent.</p>
<p>Instead, the tariff would fall to 15 percent in 2000, as currently planned, and then stay there until 2005, when it would go to 10 percent with an immediate inquiry into future moves, Hward said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's nice to be running the government from Opposition,&quot; said Opposition leader Kim Beazley, who had proposed a very similar plan.</p>
<p>Beazley was a senior member of the former Labor government that began the free-market approach to the manufacturing industry in the 1980s.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
