<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="644558" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai shares end sharply down on bank ban.</title>
<headline>Shanghai shares end sharply down on bank ban.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai's A and B shares closed sharply down on Friday with market sentiment badly hurt by Beijing's ban on state banks trading on the stock markets and the state debt repurchase markets, brokers said.</p>
<p>The domestic A share index ended down 89.498 points or 6.3 percent to 1,331.937 points and the foreign currency B share index lost 3.869 points or 4.34 percent to 85.337 points.</p>
<p>The People's Bank of China, the central bank, announced the ban late on Thursday, ordering state banks to offset their existing stock positions within 10 days and stop trading on the state debt repo market from Friday.  </p>
<p>&quot;Investors sold heavily on the market today with sentiment greatly hurt by the ban,&quot; said one A share trader.</p>
<p>Brokers said state banks accounted for about 50 percent of liquidity on the state debt repurchase market, which has served as a fund reservoir for the A share markets on the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock exchanges.</p>
<p>&quot;The indices still have the potential to fall because money is expected to flow out of the market,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected the A share index to fall another 15 percent and the B share index to lose five to eight percent next week before stock prices stabilise.  </p>
<p>Trading volume on the A share market was heavy at 869.8 million shares valued at 12.9 billion yuan.</p>
<p>B share volume was only 23.3 million shares worth $18.6 millioin, indicating selling was much heavier on the A market, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Selling on the B share market mainly came from domestic investors,&quot; said a B share trader.</p>
<p>&quot;The A share plunge was part of the reason for the B market to fall sharply today,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Shanghai Post and Telecommunications Equipment Co Ltd was the worst B share performer, losing $0.50 to close at its 10 percent limit-down level of $0.45.</p>
<p>Many A share companies hit their 10-percent limit-down level as well.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
