<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="644732" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBS end up on book-squaring, cash bond buying.</title>
<headline>JGBS end up on book-squaring, cash bond buying.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key 10-year September Japanese government bond (JGB) futures contract ended higher in quiet trade in Tokyo on Friday, boosted by cash bond purchases and pre-weekend book-squaring, traders said.</p>
<p>But activity was confined to a relatively narrow range amid a lack of fresh factors as the market turns its eyes to U.S. jobs data due later today and the Bank of Japan's &quot;tankan&quot; quarterly survey of business sentiment on June 25.</p>
<p>Key September ended trade at 122.84, up 0.16 from Thursday's close, after moving from 122.69 to 122.87. Turnover was a low 29,377 contracts.  </p>
<p>A lack of fresh market factors kept trade lethargic, traders said, adding that attention was already mainly fixed on the tankan despite the fact it is not due out for almost three weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade next week is likely to be mostly consolidation, with the market fluttering from around 122 to 124, mostly on statements from officials, as the market waits for the tankan,&quot; one city bank trader said.</p>
<p>Some buying of the 190th to 196th cash bonds was detected, mainly on expectations that the 190th will take over as benchmark from the current 182nd sometime soon, traders said.  </p>
<p>The 190th bond is likely to replace the 182nd issue as the key cash JGB benchmark early next week, market sources said. &quot;The cash JGB issue with the greatest turnover becomes the benchmark, but there is no clear rule about when a benchmark shift becomes official,&quot; said Takeshi Naito, assistant general manager for the market intelligence unit at Daiwa Securities Co Ltd's bond department.</p>
<p>Some operators were shifting holdings from the 182nd to 190th, with short-covering of the 190-series bonds also likely.</p>
<p>Yield of the 190th was at 2.620 percent at 0619 GMT and the 182nd at 2.505 against 2.520 percent at Thursday's close.  </p>
<p>U.S. May jobs data is due out at 1230 GMT today.  A Reuters polls of economists forecast an average of new non-farm payrolls at around 221,000 against 142,000 last month, with a range from 125,000 to 275,000.</p>
<p>Tokyo bond traders said the extent of the impact would depend on how strong the numbers are and whether speculation is re-ignited about a possible U.S. interest rate hike.</p>
<p>&quot;This could lead to some JGB sales, but the effect is likely to be limited,&quot; the city bank trader said.</p>
<p>More attention is being paid to the tankan, although the market is unable to reach a consensus, dealers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It seems hard to believe, from recent indicators such as new car sales, that the tankan will be good. But a poor tankan is factored in to a certain extent, so the impact is likely to be limited,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Figures released on Monday showed that May domestic vehicle sales fell 9.4 percent from a year earlier.</p>
<p>But a report from Tokyo-Mitsubishi Securities Co on Friday said the tankan is likely to show a better outlook, with the key business diffusion index expected to improve to plus four among major manufacturing firms from plus two in the previous survey. -- Elaine Lies, Tokyo Treasuries Desk +81-3-3432-8806</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
