<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="644755" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Dog bites 19 children in rampage at Japan school.</title>
<headline>Dog bites 19 children in rampage at Japan school.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>A homeless dog bit 19 students on Friday in a frightening rampage through classrooms of a primary school on Japan's northernmost island of Hokkaido, a police spokesman said.</p>
<p>The spokesman said hospital authorities were checking to ensure the animal, a long-haired Shetland Collie, was not a rabies carrier.</p>
<p>He said the dog's attack was triggered when children surrounded the animal to pet it after it strayed onto the school's playground in the village of Asahikawa.</p>
<p>Confused and angered by the attention, the animal snapped at the children and chased them when they fled from the playground into the school's classrooms.</p>
<p>The dog continued to chase the children as they ran from room to room until it was subdued by the school's headmaster.</p>
<p>Hospital authorities treated 19 children, mainly nine-year-olds, for minor scratches and bites.</p>
<p>The animal had no collar and its shaggy hair and half-starved condition indicated it had lived in the wild for some time, the police spokesman said.</p>
<p>Police have caged the animal until a decision is made on its fate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
