<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="644885" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Kai Peng to buy all Maju Steel shares.</title>
<headline>Kai Peng to buy all Maju Steel shares.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's Kai Peng Bhd has entered into agreements to buy the remaining 40.59 percent equity in Maju Steel Sdn Bhd which it does not already own for 64.3 million ringgit, the national Bernama news agency reported.</p>
<p>The proposed purchase which comprises 13.7 million shares would be paid by the issue of 7.15 million new Kai Peng shares at 9.0 ringgit each to the vendors.</p>
<p>Kai Peng in April entered an agreement to buy 59.41 percent equity in Maju Steel for 94.1 million ringgit to be paid by issuing 10.5 million new Kai Peng shares at 9.0 ringgit apiece.</p>
<p>On completion of the acquisition, Maju Holdings Sdn Bhd and its group executive director Khairuddin Abdul Rahman -- the vendors of Maju Steel -- would together hold 15.7 million shares in Kai Peng or 37.6 percent of its enlarged issued and paid-up capital, Bernama quoted a company statement as saying.</p>
<p>Maju Holdings and Khairuddin would apply to the regulatory authorities for a waiver from having to make a mandatory takeover offer of Kai Peng.</p>
<p>Maju Holdings is leading the rescue of loss-making, state-controlled Perwaja Steel.</p>
<p>Industry sources last month said Maju Holdings was buying an 80 percent stake in appliance maker Berjaya Singer Bhd.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
