<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64484" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: More money seen for Clinton's programs.</title>
<headline>More money seen for Clinton's programs.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>House and Senate leaders said Thursday they are negotiating with President Clinton to give him around $6 billion in additional funds for 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The chances are the president is going to get a lot of what he asked for, but this is not a capitulation,&quot; House Appropriations Committee chairman Bob Livingston, R-Louisiana, told a news conference.</p>
<p>To meet Clinton's request, Congress is looking at sales of radio spectrum and at bolstering the undercapitalized thrift deposit insurance fund, Livingston said.</p>
<p>House Speaker Newt Gingrich and Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott said they expect to finish work on the fiscal 1997 appropriations next week. The unfinished legislation will be wrapped into the 1997 defense appropriation and will be debated under procedures that do not permit amendments.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe we can reach agreements that will provide for keeping the government open,&quot; Gingrich said.</p>
<p>Agencies must have 1997 funding by Oct. 1 or risk shutting down at least temporarily. Republicans, who felt the brunt of public wrath for two government shutdowns last winter, are eager to keep the government running without interruption.  </p>
<p>The only cuts in the defense budget are expected to be used to pay for about $200 million in programs related to fighting terrorism. Clinton requested $1.1 billion in new anti-terrorism programs, $500 million to fight forest fires in Western states and $250 million for anti-drug programs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
