<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="644827" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Empire East falls 4.76 pct in late trade.</title>
<headline>Empire East falls 4.76 pct in late trade.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Empire East Land Holdings Inc shed 15 centavos, or 4.76 percent, to three pesos in late trade on Friday but traders said it seemed just to be following the market downtrend.</p>
<p>&quot;This decline could be because of the way the general market is behaving where investors are selective and picky,&quot; said one foreign trader.</p>
<p>In mid-trade, the issue briefly dropped to an all-time low of 2.85 pesos before bouncing back.</p>
<p>Henry Ong, analyst at Sapphire Securities, said that investors may be selling the issue prior to the announcement of the ex-date for its dividend.</p>
<p>Empire East has not yet set the ex-date for its 88 percent stock dividend.</p>
<p>&quot;Many people may be selling prior to the ex-dividend date because if they don't their money will be tied up for three to six months until the company can deliver those shares and they can sell them,&quot; Ong said.</p>
<p>Empire was among the actively traded issues of the day. It has been battered in recent weeks by the fear of a property glut and rumours that it is suffering financial problems which the company denied.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (63 2) 8418939 Fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010022">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
