<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="644973" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: CERA says in talks with Belgian, foreign banks.</title>
<headline>CERA says in talks with Belgian, foreign banks.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian CERA Bank said on Friday it was in talks with Belgian and foreign banks as part of expansion plans aimed at cutting costs and preparing for introduction of the euro and increased competition.</p>
<p>&quot;We are holding exploratory talks with a number of domestic and foreign banks but we do not want to put any names on them...everybody's talking with everyone,&quot; a spokesman said.</p>
<p>Belgian newspapers on Friday quoted Dutch Rabobank chairman Herman Wijffels as telling the annual meeting of local member bank representatives on Thursday that the co-operative bank was in talks with Kredietbank (KB) and CERA.</p>
<p>KB already confirmed last month it was in exploratory talks with Rabobank as part of expansion plans.</p>
<p>Rabobank itself said in May it had been holding talks over the past year with KB about the unification of European markets, the single euro currency and globalisation of world financial markets but denied the banks wanted to forge a close alliance.</p>
<p>-- Bert Lauwers, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6815, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
