<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="645022" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Ireland's McCreevy - a straight-talking finance man.</title>
<headline>Ireland's McCreevy - a straight-talking finance man.</headline>
<byline>Carmel Linnane</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Charlie McCreevy, tipped as Finance Minister if Fianna Fail and its Progressive Democrat allies win Friday's Irish election, is a rough diamond known for no-nonsense talking and contempt for government overspending.</p>
<p>The combative 47-year-old Kildare accountant is a key aspirant for the enviable task of presiding over an Irish economic boom, low inflation, abundant coffers and more room to manoeuvre than for the past decade or more.</p>
<p>He has been unwavering in his commitment, over the years, to cut government spending, reduce taxes and slash the national debt of 30 billion Irish pounds ($44.4 billion).</p>
<p>McCreevy says that if he is made Finance Minister government spending will not increase above the inflation rate plus 2.0 percent, a total spend of four percent against the current government's eight percent.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to decide what spending will be and then stick to it,&quot; McCreevy told Reuters.</p>
<p>He has been indefatigable in his criticism of the current government's &quot;spending spree,&quot; warning that when the economy dubbed the &quot;Celtic Tiger&quot; runs out of steam it will be impossible to reduce spending.</p>
<p>His outspoken manner has landed McCreevy in trouble more than once.</p>
<p>As Fianna Fail spokesman on finance, he blotted his copybook in January by using his own party's errors to highlight weaknesses in the budget of the three-party centre-left coalition government Fianna Fail hopes to dislodge.</p>
<p>In off-the-cuff comments McCreevy pointed to an attempt by Fianna Fail &quot;to spend its way out of a crisis in 1977&quot;, which, he confessed, had not worked. It was seen as a sloppy &quot;own goal.&quot;</p>
<p>Equally, he said current government strategy of increasing spending while cutting taxes, would also fail.</p>
<p>In 1982, McCreevy found himself briefly expelled from Fianna Fail for his persistent demands for fiscal rectitude which were seen as a criticism of the party leadership under former Prime Minister Charles Haughey.</p>
<p>He reserves much of his anger, which has a genuinely sharp edge, for the Labour Party of Dick Spring, which pulled out of a coalition government with Fianna Fail in 1994 and switched its support to John Bruton's Fine Gael party.</p>
<p>Spring, whose party has held the balance of power in recent governments, has ruled out any coalition with Fianna Fail.</p>
<p>McCreevy is scathing about Spring, a man Fianna Fail has drubbed &quot;Tricky Dicky&quot; and &quot;Chicken Dick&quot; since 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no point ruling out Fianna Fail and Labour as a coalition, that is the bullshit principle of Irish politics,&quot; McCreevy told Irish media.</p>
<p>While Fianna Fail leader Bertie Ahern has voiced his commitment to Ireland joining European Monetary Union, McCreevy is not so convinced.</p>
<p>&quot;Lets be honest about it, if Britain is staying out there are going to be problems,&quot; he told the Irish Times in an interview in April.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though we have reduced our dependence on trade with Britain, it still is and always will be, our major trading partner.&quot;</p>
<p>He has weathered a disappointingly chequered 20 years in politics sometimes favoured, sometimes shunned, often hampered by his lack of adherence to &quot;club rules&quot;.</p>
<p>A racing enthusiast, McCreevy backed a hunch in 1991 and supported the challenger, Albert Reynolds, for the leadership, a move which rescued him from a decade of backbench wrangling.</p>
<p>When Reynolds became Prime Minister he rewarded him with the post of minister for Social Welfare.</p>
<p>But once again McCreevy sparked controversy when he introduced a set of proposals later dubbed the &quot;dirty dozen&quot; which recommended highly unpopular cuts in welfare payments and benefits.</p>
<p>The fall of Albert Reynolds' Fianna Fail/Labour coalition in 1994 and the accession of Bertie Ahern as a &quot;consensus&quot; party leader resulted in a surprise promotion for McCreevy to Fianna Fail's spokesman on finance.</p>
<p>The previous holder of the position was Fianna Fail leader Bertie Ahern, who once boasted that he had put government finances in the best shape for a generation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
