<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64534" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Don't expect disclosure checklist from SEC--lawyer.</title>
<headline>Don't expect disclosure checklist from SEC--lawyer.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Municipal bond issuers that are hoping for a &quot;handy-dandy check list&quot; from SEC on how to avoid securities fraud charges better think again, a prominent bond lawyer told attorneys meeting here Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The Securities and Exchange Commission will, I am confident, steadfastly refuse to tell local officials exactly how to avoid liability under the federal securities law,&quot; Dean Pope, a partner with Hunton &amp; Williams in Richmond, said in a keynote address at the National Association of Bond Lawyers annual workshop.</p>
<p>Bond lawyers who advise local governments &quot;have a responsibility to point that out to local officials,&quot; Pope told the 1,000 lawyers attending the three day-meeting.</p>
<p>SEC officials agreed last week to meet soon with municipal bond groups about their concerns with the agency's aggressive municipal enforcement program.</p>
<p>SEC has brought 20 enforcement actions involving the muni market since SEC Chairman Arthur Levitt took office. Most involved charges against bond underwriters, financial advisers and other professionals.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, however, SEC brought its first enforcement action against a general purpose issuer, Orange County, Calif. And the agency has other issuer probes in the works.</p>
<p>Alarmed by the trend, issuer representatives say SEC is overstepping its authority. They argue they do not have the same expertise and funds as corporations to avoid lawsuits.</p>
<p>But Pope said it is &quot;completely unrealistic&quot; to expect SEC to consider &quot;fraud any less fraudulent&quot; when committed by a municipality.</p>
<p>&quot;A local government that disguises its financial problems to avoid embarrassing its mayor is no less a target of the SEC than a corporation attempting to manipulate its stock price,&quot; Pope said.</p>
<p>Pope urged bond lawers to give municipal clients &quot;common-sense steps&quot; to avoid fraud charges. He also recommended that bond lawyers and their clients send questions to Government Finance Officers Association, which is developing guidelines on how localities can avoid fraud.</p>
<p>Pope said press reports that SEC may bring charges soon against Orange County's former bond counsel highlights a growing problem for bond lawyers.</p>
<p>Bond counsel traditionally are not responsible for disclosure, but many local government officials incorrectly think otherwise, Pope said. &quot;It is in the interest of both ourselves and our clients to clear up misunderstandings,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Pope said a lawsuit Orange County brought against the former bond counsel raises another issue -- when should a bond counsel go over the head of the day-to-day client to elected city boards?</p>
<p>The bond counsel only was permitted to contact the county attorney on disclosure matters, Pope said. Yet the lawsuit damns bond counsel for failure to report certain matters to the county board,&quot; Pope said. &quot;I offer no easy answers for this thorny problem,&quot;  Pope said.</p>
<p>But, he added, &quot;It now seems, however, extremely dangerous to accept a limitation on your right to discuss matters with the elected officials of the public body you are representing.&quot;</p>
<p>Pope said SEC's probe of Orange County also raises questions about whether public officials must read disclosure documents.</p>
<p>&quot;Common sense suggest(s) that elected officials should certainly read at least the basic disclosure document,&quot; he said. That way they can question statements that do not make sense or they know are wrong, Pope said.</p>
<p>In other comments, Pope predicted that conflicts of interest in the muni arena probably will get a lot of attention from regulators in the coming year.</p>
<p>&quot;SEC has given us ample warning that any whiff of conflict is a prime subject for disclosure,&quot; Pope said.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 312-836-0100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
