<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="645446" id="root" date="1997-06-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: SOCCER-STOICHKOV SCORES IN BULGARIAN COMEBACK.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-STOICHKOV SCORES IN BULGARIAN COMEBACK.</headline>
<dateline>BOURGAS, Bulgaria 1997-06-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hristo Stoichkov marked his return to the Bulgarian national side after a year-long absence with the opening goal in the 4-0 World Cup qualifying win over Luxembourg on Sunday.</p>
<p>Barcelona striker Stoichkov, at odds with Bulgarian Football Union officials, scored from the penalty spot two minutes before the interval.</p>
<p>The outcome of the group five qualifier was decided in the opening five minutes of the second half with goals by two other exiles, Fenerbahce's Emil Kostadinov and Stuttgart's Krasimir Balakov, who converted the Bulgarians' second penalty.</p>
<p>Substitute Yordan Lechkov added the fourth in the 81st minute.</p>
<p>The win left the Bulgarians, World Cup semifinalists in 1994, two points behind group leaders Russia but with a game in hand.</p>
<p>Stoichkov netted after Luxembourg defender Frank Deville brought down Emil Kostadinov.</p>
<p>He also set up the fourth goal with a long pass to substitute Lechkov who volleyed home.</p>
<p>In the first half, the Bulgarians failed to take advantage of their territorial advantage and missed several chances.</p>
<p>But two minutes after the break Kostadinov, alone in front of goal, fired powerfully past diving Luxembourg goalkeeper Paul Koch. Balakov converted his spot kick in the 50th minute after Penev was brought down in the box by Mark Birsens.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOURGAS, Bulgaria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
