<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="645616" id="root" date="1997-06-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain could not stay outside successful EMU - Cook.</title>
<headline>Britain could not stay outside successful EMU - Cook.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain is unlikely to sign up for the European Union's planned single currency at the outset but would have to join in the long run if the project succeeded, Foreign Secretary Robin Cook said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Interviewed by BBC television, Cook said Prime Minister Tony Blair's government would make a hard-headed assessment towards the end of this year whether it was in Britain's interest to join the currency, which is due to be launched in January 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, we think it unlikely that that assessment would point to us joining,&quot; Cook said, before adding: &quot;If it proceeded on time and if then proved a success, then in the long run Britain could not stay outside...&quot;</p>
<p>Cook said the question as to whether economic and monetary union (EMU) would in fact proceed on time was an open one given Germany's budget woes and the new French socialist government's opposition to further austerity to meet EMU targets.</p>
<p>&quot;The last week has raised some very significant questions in the minds of politicians on the continent as well as commentators within Britain,&quot; Cook said.</p>
<p>Echoing comments made by Blair in Sweden on Friday, Cook firmly ruled out softening the economic criteria for EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;If the European single currency is to proceed on time it is very important that it proceeds on time both with credible criteria which will make sure that it is a credible strong currency and secondly, as we have always stressed, with popular backing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>For the same reason, he said he had reservations about the French socialists' demand that Italy and Spain be admitted automatically to the single currency. They should be admitted only if they pass the membership test. &quot;I don't think you should name countries that ought to be in as of right,&quot; Cook said.</p>
<p>But he said he did have sympathy for French Prime Minister Lionel Jospin's call for more emphasis on tackling unemployment.</p>
<p>&quot;If you are going to have commitments to clear, precise and tight monetary objectives, then that also has to be balanced by a macroeconomic policy which does stress growth and jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there's a broad recognition on the continent that maybe over the last few years they have not given sufficient stress in their economic management to jobs and growth,&quot; Cook said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
