<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="645632" id="root" date="1997-06-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RUGBY UNION - Umaga scores test jersey.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION - Umaga scores test jersey.</headline>
<text>
<p>ROTORUA, June 9 - Starved of opportunities on the flank in yesterday's All Black rugby trials, Tana Umaga was left in some despair.</p>
<p>He walked off Rotorua Stadium wondering just how long he'd have to wait for another real crack at the exclusive club.</p>
<p>About an hour later All Black coach John Hart dropped the bombshell on the 24-year-old Wellington winger that he had won selection for the test against the touring Fijians on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;Unbelievable. I was stunned,&quot; Umaga said later.  </p>
<p>Ironically, as the rugby public waited with bated breath for the announcement of the team on Sky Sport last night, the live broadcast was delayed by the world club league match between Halifax and Canberra beamed live from Canberra.</p>
<p>Umaga's brother Mike, a former Wellington rugby representative and Western Samoan international, was playing for Halifax.</p>
<p>As one brother disappeared from the screen, the other flashed in trying to find words to describe his pride and joy of becoming an All Black.  </p>
<p>&quot;I had no idea. I knew I had one foot in the door by being in the (New Zealand Barbarians) reserves, but you can't take anything for granted.&quot;</p>
<p>What stunned the dreadlocked Wellington Hurricanes star was that he hardly had a dab in the 30 minutes he spent on the field yesterday.</p>
<p>&quot;You can get frustrated if you don't go out and look for work, no good just standing there and hoping the ball will come.&quot;  </p>
<p>Umaga is one of two new caps for Saturday, the other being Otago captain Taine Randell, who led the All Blacks' non-test team in South Africa last year.</p>
<p>Randell's selection was expected as he was moved from the bench to No 8 in the Barbarians or shadow test side for the trial match against New Zealand A.</p>
<p>Lee Stensness, who played three tests in 1993 and then discarded by the then All Black coach Laurie Mains, was confirmed as test second fie-eighth in place of the injured Walter Little.  </p>
<p>The biggest surprise sprung by Hart and his fellow selectors Ross Cooper and Gordon Hunter was the replacement of perennial reserve hooker Norm Hewitt with Anton Oliver.</p>
<p>Hart, however, described Hewitt's omission as a strategy adopted by the selectors to keep the storming front rower in action by slipping him to the NZ Maori team, who play four games in the next two weeks.</p>
<p>He said Hewitt needed matches to keep him in shape in case he was needed for immediate service in the test team.  </p>
<p>&quot;If he didn't get those games (for the Maori team), he could go for the next six-seven weeks of test rugby without any rugby. He would have been the reserve hooker. There's no hidden agenda,&quot; Hart said.</p>
<p>The other new faces at test level are reserves -- Ofisa Tonu'u, who swept past Jon Preston to become the reserve halfback, Carlos Spencer, the backup fist five-eighth, and blindside flanker/lock Charles Reichelmann.  </p>
<p>Auckland's Mark Carter, who made an unsuccessful attempt at league with the Warriors last season, is also in the eight-member bench, which will be reduced to six just before the floodlit test at Albany on Saturday.</p>
<p>The selection of two loose forwards, Reichelmann and Carter, was necessary, Hart said, as test trio Michael Jones, Josh Kronfeld and Randell were nursing minor injuries.</p>
<p>Jones had a chipped bone removed from hs elbow last week while Kronfeld (strained shoulder) and Randell (calf muscle) were injured in yesterday's trials, won 29-22 by the Barbarians.  </p>
<p>It was apparent from the selection that the test team had been settled before yesterday's match. Only Tonu'u appeared to gain selection from the game as Preston's clearance from the heels of his forwards was far from sharp.</p>
<p>&quot;He had a good year but unfortunately he got exposed today. With the speed of the backs we have now in Christian Cullen and Jeff Wilson it's absolutely necessary for speed ball, long and quick,&quot; Hart said.</p>
<p>&quot;One got exposed and the other (Tonu'u) showed.&quot;  </p>
<p>Had selection been based solely on yesterday's performance, Eroni Clarke instead of Frank Bunce and Todd Blackadder instead of Reichelmann should have been picked.</p>
<p>Mark Allen, who filled in for Craig Dowd in the Barbarians' team, showed that he deserved a test spot.</p>
<p>It prompted suggestions that he should be the test loosehead prop and Dowd the tighthead instead of Olo Brown. Neither Brown nor Bunce has played much rugby in the recent weeks due to injury.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
