<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="645765" id="root" date="1997-06-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Confident Hong Kong seen posing challenge to China.</title>
<headline>Confident Hong Kong seen posing challenge to China.</headline>
<byline>Diane Stormont</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>If Hong Kong people fear China will strangle their freedom after the July 1 handover, they are showing remarkably little anxiety as the clock ticks closer.</p>
<p>With little more than three weeks to go before the extrovert community of 6.4 million people returns to Beijing's fold, more than 50,000 simply ignored future leader Tung Chee-hwa's exhortation to forget &quot;the baggage of June 4&quot;.</p>
<p>Young and old, rich and poor, cradling flickering candles and crooning democracy anthems, they turned out on Wednesday to mourn those those killed when Chinese tanks crushed a nascent pro-democracy movement at Beijing's Tiananmen Square on June 4, 1989.</p>
<p>There was no repeat of the burnings in effigy of Chinese leaders, of defaced Communist flags or calls for the overthrow of &quot;the butchers&quot; of Beijing which propelled more than one million horrified people to the streets eight years earlier.</p>
<p>The protests were peaceful, even benign.</p>
<p>Political scientist Michael Yahuda of the London School of Economics has written that China's emergence as a world player will be judged by how it handles Hong Kong -- hugely successful under British rule -- when it takes over at midnight on June 30.</p>
<p>The fact that so many Hong Kong people casually dismissed the hint to stay home demonstrates that China has a challenge on its hands in absorbing such a brash, self-confident community into the motherland.</p>
<p>Hong Kong, just 23 days before the British leave, has had 13 years since Britain agreed to return its colony to scrutinise the &quot;what-ifs ?&quot; of the handover from every conceivable angle.</p>
<p>The pessimists have decamped in a tide of &quot;yacht people&quot;. Between quarter-to-half a million of them left primarily for Canada and Australia -- many in the aftermath of Tiananmen.</p>
<p>The cautious have furnished their boltholes and judiciously spread their funds in a variety of markets.</p>
<p>With their bets hedged, a philosophical but generally positive mood of wait and see has spread in the British colony.</p>
<p>&quot;Hong Kong people are generally satisfed with their lives, they approve of the way they are governed,&quot; says Michael DeGolyer, director of a long-term study into the transition based at Hong Kong's Baptist University.</p>
<p>The message from Hong Kong is that China should demonstrate it will be business as usual, to carry out promises contained in the 1984 Sino-British treaty on the handover to leave capitalist Hong Kong alone to run itself.</p>
<p>It would appear that the message to handle Hong Kong with kid gloves has been received loud and clear in the senior ranks of China's People's Liberation Army (PLA).</p>
<p>&quot;Tiananmen is the hurdle the PLA has got to jump,&quot; the last Commander of British Forces Major-General Bryan Dutton observed on Thursday, the day after the Tiananmen vigil in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Dutton said the incoming commanders were well aware they had to demonstrate such incidents lay in the past.</p>
<p>He reserved judgement on how events would unfold -- &quot;the PLA must answer for themselves&quot; -- but gave credit to the diplomacy and professionalism of the advance guard, the cream of the crop, sent in recent weeks to prepare for the PLA garrison.</p>
<p>In smart new uniforms designed for the occasion, unarmed in accordance with London's wishes, their arrival led by Major-General Zhou Borong, China's only graduate of Britain's Royal College of Defence Studies, was low-key and unthreatening.</p>
<p>&quot;Even in 1988 he (Zhou) appeared to be the perfect choice for a senior officer in such a sensitive appointment as Hong Kong after its handover to China,&quot; Major-General John Evans, one of Zhou's former tutors, told Reuters recently.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
