<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="645898" id="root" date="1997-06-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lawmaker says top brass would face tough fight.</title>
<headline>Lawmaker says top brass would face tough fight.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Air Force general who was in line to become the next chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff would have a very difficult time getting Senate confirmation because of his admission of an adulterous affair, a key member of Congress said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Representative Steve Buyer, the Indiana Republican who heads the House subcommittee on Military Personnel, said he anticipated that the Air Force officer, Gen. Joseph Ralston, would take his name out of consideration.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe it is acceptable of the American people to expect the higher standard out of the military. We don't want to lower the ceiling. We do, in fact, want high standards,&quot; Buyer said on the NBC programme &quot;Meet the Press.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;And that's why I anticipate General Ralston to withdraw,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Ralston, reported to have been Defence Secretary William Cohen's first choice for the job, was widely expected to pull his name after a scheduled meeting with Cohen on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that there's been such a cloud created in this climate as we're looking into the issues of sexual misconduct that it would be very difficult for him to be confirmed before the U.S. Senate,&quot; Buyer said.</p>
<p>He said that Ralston, who acknowledged to Cohen last week that he had an affair 13 years ago while separated from his wife, should remain vice chairman of the Joint Chiefs.</p>
<p>Representative Jane Harman, a California Democrat who is also a member of the Military Personnel subcommittee, said the admission of adultery should not automatically disqualify Ralston for the job of top uniformed officer.</p>
<p>But &quot;that doesn't mean that Secretary Cohen should recommend him or the president should nominate him,&quot; she said on &quot;Meet the Press.&quot;</p>
<p>Harman said the sex lives of men and women in the military should not be an issue of public concern as long as they do &quot;not interfere with good order and discipline in the military.&quot;</p>
<p>Cohen announced on Saturday he had asked his legal advisers to review procedures for handling adultery charges amid charges by lawmakers and other critics of double standards in the military justice system.</p>
<p>Pentagon spokesman Ken Bacon told reporters that as of Saturday, Ralston was still a &quot;leading candidate&quot; to head the Joint Chiefs, who run the Pentagon.</p>
<p>Ralston, 56, a much-decorated Vietnam War veteran and fighter pilot, has been on an official trip in central Asia and was reportedly due to return Sunday. Critics have said his case highlights alleged unfairness in the treatment of the Air Force's first woman bomber pilot, Lt. Kelly Flinn.</p>
<p>Flinn, 26, was forced to resign without an honourable discharge in order to avoid court-martial on charges of adultery, having sex with an enlisted man, lying and disobeying matters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
