<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="645814" id="root" date="1997-06-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>BAHRAIN: Bahraini bank equity placement oversubscribed.</title>
<headline>Bahraini bank equity placement oversubscribed.</headline>
<dateline>MANAMA 1997-06-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Bahrain-based Islamic investment bank said on Sunday a $35 million private equity placement offered to investors in Gulf Arab states and Malaysia had been oversubscribed.</p>
<p>First Islamic Investment Bank (FIIB) said the placement had originally been aimed at increasing its paid-in capital to $50 million from $15 million but it had been oversubscribed.</p>
<p>&quot;FIIB has completed a private equity placement of $100 million which represent a three-fold increase over the capital originally sought. This oversubscription reflects the continued strong interest in FIIB,&quot; a bank official said.</p>
<p>Major shareholder Abdul-Aziz al-Jomaih told reporters in Bahrain on Sunday &quot;We have raised the bank's paid-in capital to $100 million. The subscription had been great.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the private equity placement, which closed on May 25, had been offered to selected investors in the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) and Malaysia with a maximum subscription of $6 million and a $500,000 minimum.</p>
<p>The GCC groups  Saudi Arabia, Oman, Qatar, the United Arab Emirates (UAE), Bahrain and Kuwait.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia's al-Jomaih group and Kuwaiti investors established FIIB last year as an offshore investment bank based in Bahrain.</p>
<p>The bank is 30 percent owned by investors and financial institutions in Saudi Arabia, 21 percent in Kuwait and 14 perent each in the UAE and Malaysia. The rest is owned by investors in Bahrain, Qatar and Oman.</p>
<p>Allied Bank (Malaysia) Bhd owns a five percent stake in FIIB, a bank official said.</p>
<p>The bank's activities include asset management advisory services in South East Asia and the GCC. It will also participate alongside its clients in private equity transactions in the United States, the Middle East and South East Asia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BAHRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BAHRAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
