<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="646169" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Penske names Gregory Penske president, CEO.</title>
<headline>Penske names Gregory Penske president, CEO.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Penske Motorsports Inc said Monday it named Gregory Penske as president and chief executive officer of the company, which owns several speedways in the U.S.</p>
<p>Penske Motorsports is a subsidiary of Penske Corp, a privately held company that owns several transportation industry firms such as Penske Auto Centers Inc, a chain of auto repair shops, and Detroit Diesel Corp, a heavy duty engine maker.</p>
<p>Gregory Penske replaces Richard Peters, who is resigning to form a corporate finance advisory firm.  </p>
<p>Peters will retain his board seats on Penske Motorsports, Penske Auto Centers and Penske Corp. Gregory Penske, the 35-year-old son of Penske Corp founder Roger Penske, had been president of Penske Automotive Group, which operates auto dealerships.</p>
<p>Separately, Penske Corp said it and Chase Capital Partners formed Penske Capital Partners LLC to buy $1 billion of assets in industrial businesses over the next three years.</p>
<p>The new venture will be managed by James Hislop, president and CEO, who was previously a managing director in the investment banking group of Merrill Lynch. Hislop will also be proposed for election to the Penske Corp board.</p>
<p>Chase Capital Partners is a global partnership with approximately $4 billion under management. Chase Capital partner Donald Hofmann said the new venture is already starting to look at possible purchases. Acquisition targets will be about several hundred million in revenues and include companies outside of the transportation area, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;These are going to be businesses that are fairly substantial,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Penske Capital will mostly take a majority stake in the deals, but may also make minority investments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
