<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="646139" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY precious metals end mixed, volumes low.</title>
<headline>NY precious metals end mixed, volumes low.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX and NYMEX precious metals ended mixed Monday, after giving back the session's early gains, on light volumes.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold found some support as the dollar slipped further, but silver saw some fund and bullion bank selling, and platinum and palladium both saw some light profit taking, but volumes were very thin,&quot; North American Equity Services floor trader John Geraghty said.</p>
<p>COMEX August gold ended up 60 cents at $346.30 an ounce, but ended off the session highs at $347.30 on very low volumes.  </p>
<p>In the bullion market, spot gold ended quoted $344.00/50 an ounce, compared to the London Monday afternoon fix at $344.25 and the New York close Friday around $343.20/70.</p>
<p>COMEX July silver ended down 3.8 cents at $4.511 an ounce. ounce, after seeing a $345.80-347.30 range in the session.</p>
<p>COMEX July silver was up 0.7 cent at $4.790 early</p>
<p>The recent strength in PGM markets and the lower U.S. dollar were both supporting gold and silver, analysts said.</p>
<p>In addition, the possible delay to the introduction of European Monetary Union (EMU), following the victory of the Socialists in France's elections last week may lessen the need for European central banks to sell gold, analysts said.</p>
<p>Hedge fund manager, Richard Pomboy of Pomboy Capital Corp in Greenwich, Connecticut, took out paid adverisements in both the Wall Street Journal and the London Financial Times Monday, arguing that central banks were causing unrealised losses for themselves by mobilizing their gold reserves.</p>
<p>Central bank gold lending was depressing gold prices which otherwise might be closer to $500 an ounce, creating a book profit for central banks, if only they would revalue their reserves to market prices, Pomboy argued.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, NYMEX July platinum ended down $3.80 an ounce at $451.10, after seeing a new contract high last week at $473.40, when spot platinum prices in the physical market saw a seven-year high at $500.</p>
<p>NYMEX September palladium ended off $4.10 at $174.90, after also seeing a contract high last week at $185.00 an ounce, when spot palladium in the physical market saw 17 year highs, due to the acute shortage of the while metals caused by the absence of Russian supplies for five months.</p>
<p>Deliveries were still a problem in the physical market Monday, with refiners being asked to upgrade palladium sponge to alleviate the shortage.</p>
<p>If Russian supplies were delayed for another month, platinum prices could reach $600 an ounce and palladium $300 an ounce, Derek Engelbrecht, global marketing manager South Africa's Impala Platinum, said.</p>
<p>Reports Monday indicated Russia's Finance Ministry had put a temporary hold on platinum group metal (PGM) export licences while it reviewed the terms of the export contract being negotiated by metal export agency, Almaz, with Japanese trade houses.</p>
<p>Last week Russian officals said a resumption of Russian PGM exports, suspended since December 1996, was likely on June 20.</p>
<p>Funds remain heavily net long both platinum and palladium according to the CFTC Commitment of Traders data released late Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Non-commercials&quot; increased net long platinum positions to 8,953 lots as of June 3rd from May 13, though they lowered net long palladium positions to 2,722 lots from 4,176 contracts.</p>
<p>((Clive McKeef, New York Commodities Desk, 859-1641))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
