<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64624" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Pope praises martyrs who opposed French Revolution.</title>
<headline>Pope praises martyrs who opposed French Revolution.</headline>
<byline>Paul Holmes</byline>
<dateline>SAINT-LAURENT-SUR-SEVRE, France 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pope John Paul, visiting a town where a crude anti-papal bomb was defused two weeks ago, on Thursday praised Roman Catholic martyrs who fought against the 1789 French Revolution.</p>
<p>On the first day of a four-day trip to France, the Pontiff hailed those who fought in the 1793-95 Vendee uprising in western France against the fledgling Revolution, but he said there was sin on both sides.</p>
<p>An estimated 100,000 people were killed when the revolutionary government crushed the counter-revolt, led by local nobles and clergy in alliance with peasants resisting conscription.</p>
<p>&quot;You are the heirs of men and women who were courageous enough to remain faithful to the Church of Jesus Christ at a time when its freedom and independence were threatened,&quot; the Pope told about 3,000 youths in Saint-Laurent-sur-Sevre.</p>
<p>&quot;In the terrible struggles, many actions were marked by sin, on both sides. But it was in union with Christ that numerous martyrs offered their life here,&quot; he said in the so-called Garden of Cherries in a Saint-Laurent convent.</p>
<p>In 1984, the Pope beatified several dozen priests executed at Arleville by republican troops in the Vendee uprising. The rural area remains among the most conservative of modern France.</p>
<p>After his speech, the Pope prayed at the Saint-Laurent basilica dedicated to an 18th century missionary. A homemade bomb was found there early this month and the words &quot;In nomine Pape-BOOM!&quot; were daubed on a wall.</p>
<p>The Pope's visit has stirred controversy in France about the separation of Church and State and opposition to his conservative moral teachings. No one has been arrested for planting the bomb.</p>
<p>He prayed before the tomb of missionary Saint Louis-Marie Grignion de Montfort, where the bundle of dynamite was placed, and the tomb of Blessed Marie-Louise Trichet. Both were 18th century founders of religious orders.</p>
<p>The Pontiff adopted Saint Louis-Marie Grignion de Montfort's Latin motto &quot;Totus Tuus&quot; (All Yours) as a symbol of devotion to the Virgin Mary. As a student, he translated some of the saint's works into his native Polish.</p>
<p>&quot;I am happy to begin my pilgrimage on French soil under the patronage of this outstanding saint, he said in a speech. &quot;You know that I am very indebted to him and his Treatise.&quot;</p>
<p>The 76-year-old Pope, looking alert and on form on his last trip before an operation in October to remove his appendix, shook hands with admirers in the crowd and even joked about a break in the rain.</p>
<p>In praising the Vendee rebels, the Pope urged young modern Catholics to assert their faith. &quot;I pray that the martyrs of other times will guide you on your way,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the Vendee rebels had &quot;desired sincerely the necessary renewal of society, but they could not accept being cut off from communion with the church.&quot;</p>
<p>In one atrocity, the republican military commander in the city of Nantes had nuns and priests bound together naked and thrown from a bridge into the Loire river to drown in so-called &quot;republican marriages.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAINT-LAURENT-SUR-SEVRE, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
