<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="646602" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian defence chief to cut waste in reform drive.</title>
<headline>Russian defence chief to cut waste in reform drive.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's new defence minister, getting to grips with the need to reform the country's cumbersome armed forces, vowed on Monday to cut bureaucratic waste and target scarce funds at improving the troops' fighting ability.</p>
<p>&quot;Troops should concern themselves solely with military training. If they don't do this they decay,&quot; Igor Sergeyev told Interfax news agency after meeting President Boris Yeltsin in the Kremlin.</p>
<p>&quot;For military training we need money and we will find it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But, certainly aware that complaining about a lack of funds cost his predecessor, Igor Rodionov, his job last month, Sergeyev signalled he was ready to carry out long-delayed military reforms within tight budgetary constraints.</p>
<p>The presidential press service said Yeltsin had endorsed a document presented to him by Sergeyev outlining the reforms.</p>
<p>Sergeyev, formerly in charge of Russia's strategic missile command, said more than 60 percent of resources allocated to the armed forces went towards maintenance costs like the payment of allowances and purchase of provisions.</p>
<p>&quot;If we carried on in this way then the army could become incapable of functioning by the year 2000,&quot; Interfax quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>He said money could be saved by cutting the number of installations and depots, reducing duplication of responsibilities and selling off unprofitable enterprises run by the military.</p>
<p>Sergeyev said delaying compensation payments to retiring officers could also help ease pressure on his ministry's budget.</p>
<p>Underlining the difficulties of military reform in Russia, First Deputy Defence Minister, Andrei Kokoshin, told Itar-Tass news agency on Monday that the real costs of running a regiment, a division and a military school had been calculated only last year &quot;for the first time in Russian history&quot;.</p>
<p>Russia's armed forces, once the nation's pride, have seen their funding and morale plunge in recent years as the country has moved towards a market economy. Many soldiers are underfed and officers often wait months for their wages.</p>
<p>Quoting Defence Ministry sources, Interfax said on Sunday that most officers were planning to quit military service when their current contracts expire.</p>
<p>It said 61 percent of officers were suffering from chronic financial problems and 29 percent existed beneath the poverty line. A Russian army colonel gets less than $200 a month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
