<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="646775" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: LatAm shrs seen firming, extending gains this week.</title>
<headline>LatAm shrs seen firming, extending gains this week.</headline>
<byline>James Craig</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks across Latin America were likely to firm or continue upwards this week, extending Friday's gains on strong capital flows and solid economic indicators, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>They forecast continued rallies in Argentina, Brazil, Mexico and Caracas and a reversal of slides in Chile as share prices are aided by local factors and rises on Wall Street.  </p>
<p>Brazilian stocks were seen rising on speculation regarding congressional votes on a new General Telecommunications Law and civil service reform but volatility also was expected to increase ahead of June 16 options expiry, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The political scenario should heat up this week and should help the market to continue to move higher,&quot; Bozano, Simonsen analysts Quentin Lewis and Robert Drummond wrote in a market report.  </p>
<p>Sao Paulo's Bovespa index  closed strongly higher Friday on hefty foreign and domestic capital flows, as local funds snapped up second-tier stocks to end the week at 11,334 points.</p>
<p>Traders said the bolsa should repeat the huge daily volumes of recent sessions as large capital flows to Brazilian equities continue.</p>
<p>Mexican stocks were seen as having upside potential to add to record gains this week on a technical breakthrough and positive fund flows to the country.  </p>
<p>&quot;We see the IPC gaining to 4,200 points, possibly next week, before profit-takers step in,&quot; said Francisco Blanco, research chief at the Akra brokerage.</p>
<p>Blanco said one potential tripwire would be fallout on the U.S. bond market from producer prices due on June 13.</p>
<p>The bolsa already has begun to discount the potentially adverse effects of the July 2 Federal Open Market Committee review of U.S. interest rates and July 6 congressional, state and city elections, analysts said.</p>
<p>Mexico's blue chip IPC  index closed at a record of 4,160.85 points on Friday, a gain of 4.15 percent on the week.  </p>
<p>Caracas shares were seen firming as positive sentiment continued to spill over from from last week's successful marginal oil field contract auction that netted Venezuela over $2 billion in bids, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The bulls are running and they are not likely to be stopped,&quot; wrote InvestAnalysis consultant Alex Dalmady in a market report.</p>
<p>The Caracas bolsa's 19-share  index closed 5.7 percent higher last week at 7,244.17 points, helped by rating agency Standard and Poor's upgrade of Venezuela's long-term foreign currency debt rating to B-plus.  </p>
<p>Chilean share prices were likely to regain composure and stabilize after last week's rollercoaster ride.</p>
<p>The market could be set for a small technical rise early in the week after four straight daily losses snapped a three-week bull run which pushed prices to record levels on heavy buying by foreign institutional investors, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will return to a more normal pace. We could see some gains in the electricals,&quot; said one broker.  </p>
<p>The bolsa also will be awaiting news on the Telecom de Chile's long-expected merger with rival VTR. The blue-chip IPSA index ended up one percent Friday at 130.59 points.</p>
<p>Argentine stocks were likely to follow through on recent strong gains when trade resumes after Monday's Day of Affirmation of Sovereignty Rights over the Malvinas Islands holiday.</p>
<p>&quot;Local stocks were powered by fresh foreign cash flows Friday, when U.S. long-bond yields dropped suddenly, and so they should be able to continue rising,&quot; said Adolfo Adorno of Agra brokerage.</p>
<p>The blue-chip MerVal index  rose 3.2 percent in strong volume last week to 802.95 points, closing above 800 Friday for the first time in five years.</p>
<p>((-- Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 248-5413))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
