<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="646788" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil's civil service reform faces decisive votes.</title>
<headline>Brazil's civil service reform faces decisive votes.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Brazilian government faces a decisive week in Congress as its new chief whip seeks to revive a struggling civil service reform bill, officials said.</p>
<p>Deputy Luis Eduardo Magalhaes, who was appointed government leader in the Chamber of Deputies amid much fanfare last week, may also try to speed up progress of a bill outlining the rules for privatization of the telecommunications sector, they said.  </p>
<p>&quot;This week, it looks like Luis Eduardo will press ahead, no matter the risk of losing key votes,&quot; said an official involved in drawing up the civil service reform bill.</p>
<p>The bill was approved for a first time on the floor of the lower house in April. The goverment then failed to muster the three-fifths majority it needed to kill an opposition amendment and, fearing more defeats, blocked voting on other amendments.  </p>
<p>One outstanding amendment would do away with a central article of the reform: an end to jobs-for-life guarantees for qualified civil servants.</p>
<p>In a newspaper interview published Monday, Magalhaes recognized the reform bill faces entrenched opposition in Congress and that he might suffer a defeat in his first test as chief whip.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear that our margin (of support for civil service reform) is very tight. I am prepared for that,&quot; he told Jornal do Brasil.  </p>
<p>Officials said that as well as civil service reform, Magalhaes might seek to speed up approval its General Telecommunications Law by putting forward a motion which would make the bill a priority.</p>
<p>If given priority status, the telecommunications bill could be put this week or next to a vote on the lower house floor. Under congressional rules, the Chamber of Deputies is currently restricted to dealing with the civil service reform bill.  </p>
<p>Another important piece of legislation, a bill extending the Fiscal Stabilization Fund (FEF), is also expected to begin its long journey through Congress this week.</p>
<p>The FEF allows the government to sidestep constitutional rules on distributing revenues to state and municipal governments and is considered an important tool in its battle to keep a grip on public spending.  </p>
<p>An existing version of the fund expires on June 30. A constitutional amendment extending it until 1999 may be put this week to a vote in its lower house committee. The bill also needs two three-fifths majorities on the floors of each of Congress' two houses.</p>
<p>In the Senate, the most important action of the week is likely to be the presentation of a rewritten version of the government's pension reform bill.</p>
<p>The bill has been substantially revised to include important points lost during voting in the Chamber of Deputies last year.</p>
<p>An aide to Senator Benavides Veras, who did the rewrite, said the new-look bill would be read to its upper house committee Tuesday. If approved in the upper house, the bill will return to the Chamber of Deputies for approval of the changes.</p>
<p>Congress-watchers doubt the government will manage to get the bill through Congress before September, when next year's elections will make approval of reforms next to impossible.</p>
<p>(( -- William Schomberg, Brasilia newsroom 5561 2230358))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
