<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="646754" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil shrs track Wall St, end up in strong trade.</title>
<headline>Brazil shrs track Wall St, end up in strong trade.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian stocks tracked Wall Street to close firmly higher on Monday in heavy trade amid rising options-related volatility and led by climbing electrical shares, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was really no news today. We had activity in Telebras and second-tier shares, but trading was calm,&quot; a local trader told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Sao Paulo bolsa's Bovespa index of 48 most-traded shares ended up 0.55 percent at 11,334 points on volume totalling 761.3 million reais ($709 million).  </p>
<p>Brokers said Monday's trend was set by Wall Street and bellwether Telebras, whose benchmark preferred rose to 149.80 reais before slipping back to close at 147.80 reais for a rise of 0.75 percent.</p>
<p>Its common ended up 0.35 percent at 138.99 reais.</p>
<p>Rises in New York prompted a parallel surge in Sao Paulo early in the day, but the market was later hit by profit-taking, which some dealers expect will continue Tuesday on an absence of market-moving news.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has a lot of fat that can come off,&quot; one broker said.  </p>
<p>Brokers said the market began to show some volatility ahead of June 16 options expiration.</p>
<p>Apart from Telebras, the bolsa also saw healthy rises in other blue chips, including state oil firm Petrobras and mining giant Cia Vale do Rio Doce (CVRD).</p>
<p>Petrobras preferred rose 1.93 percent to 265.00 reais while CVRD's preferred jumped 2.16 percent to close at 23.60 reais.</p>
<p>The bolsa's Electrical Energy Index of nine most-traded power stocks closed up a strong 2.33 percent at 3,000 points on positive outlooks for the sector's privatization.</p>
<p>Eletrobras preferred rose 0.59 percent to 515 reais while preferred shares of Sao Paulo state power firm Cia Paulista de Forca e Luz (CPFL), one of the first Brazilian electrical utilities expected to be sold off, surged 6.09 percent to end at 157.01 reais.</p>
<p>(( --James Craig, Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 2485413 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
