<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="646710" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - June 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - June 9.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Slovenia's Monday morning newspapers:</p>
<p>DELO</p>
<p>- Agreement on workers' benefits between the government, unions and employers -- which was expected to be signed on Monday -- could be delayed as employers said they would not sign the deal until official data on the 1997 budget is available.</p>
<p>- Eight central European presidents,  during their meeting in coastal Portoroz, backed the swift integration of ex-communist countries into the EU and NATO.</p>
<p>- Sunday's visits to Slovenian coastal hotels increased to 4,002 guests, a 82 percent rise from the same day in 1996.</p>
<p>DNEVNIK</p>
<p>- National programme of road construction in Slovenia includes 499 kilometres (304 miles) of roads going from west to east and north to south and is expected to cost 2.2 billion tolars ($13.8 million), the Slovenian Motorway Company said.</p>
<p>- The regular annual refitting of Slovenia's only nuclear power plant Krsko is expected to be finished by June 11.</p>
<p>VECER</p>
<p>- Bankers from the largest central and eastern European banks met in Portoroz over the weekend in order to discuss their experience in the privatisation of state-owned banks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
