<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="646852" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China planning rare earth catalytic converters.</title>
<headline>China planning rare earth catalytic converters.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>China plans to begin limited production of rare earth-based catalytic converters by 2000, but much research is still needed to solve efficiency and endurance problems, officials and researchers said on Monday.</p>
<p>Using China's rare earth resources to substitute for platinum, palladium and rhodium would cut the cost of catalytic converters, large numbers of which would be needed to cut emissions from the nation's growing number of vehicles, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are currently carrying out research and testing...of rare earth catalytic converters,&quot; said an official of the science department of the Ministry of Machine Building Industry.</p>
<p>The ministry was working with the State Science and Technology Commission and U.S. auto giant Ford Motor Co on the research, officials said.</p>
<p>Officials were unable to give details of Ford's role but said that input was expected to come from the United States or from Ford operations in the northern port city of Tianjin.</p>
<p>Production was expected to begin by 2000 but would be limited initially. The new converters would still require a small amount of platinum, palladium and rhodium, the official said by telephone.</p>
<p>Price was a key consideration for pollution control measures in the Chinese auto industry and the rare earth converters were expected to cost around $100, compared with $200-$300 for models using the more expensive metals, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;That would make the price acceptable to Chinese consumers,&quot; he said. He did not give details.</p>
<p>Researchers still had far to go to raise the efficiency and endurance of rare earth catalytic converters, said Feng Xinye, director of international cooperation at the China Automotive Technology and Research Centre in the northern city of Tianjin.</p>
<p>&quot;The project is at the moment...just at the initial stage,&quot; Feng said.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though rare earth materials have many advantages over the expensive metals, there are also many problems involved,&quot; he said. &quot;Maybe after three to five years of...experiments they will be put into batch production.&quot;</p>
<p>Industry officials have said China wants to adopt automobile emission standards that would require the use of catalytic converters.</p>
<p>No cars currently produced in China are fitted with such converters, which require an electronic engine management system and the use of unleaded petrol.</p>
<p>China has pledged to phase out the use of leaded petrol by 2000, with major cities such as Beijing, Guangzhou and Shanghai leading the way.</p>
<p>Shanghai manufacturers would next year begin mass-producing electronic fuel injection systems, and such systems would be installed in all domestically assembled cars by 2000, the China Daily Business Weekly said on Sunday.</p>
<p>China made 385,000 cars in 1996, far below production capacity of 850,000 units, but officials are determined to boost both capacity and output.</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
<p>-- Beijing Newsroom (8610) 6532 1921</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
