<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="646817" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News - June 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News - June 10.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Foster's Brewing Group chief executive Ted Kunkel confirmed yesterday that Foster's would not allow its A$625 million share buyback to impede its expansion plans, with the group currently negotiating new brewing and wine deals in Asia and North America. Kunkel claimed all deals would be funded by existing credit facilities and/or group cash flow. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian Securities Commission and the accounting authorities have announced they will allow companies to use equity accounting in their accounts for this financial year. The move is expected to be welcomed by the business sector, with firms such a CRA, Goodman Fielder, WMC and Burns Philp expected to take up the option. Page 24.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Email Ltd's whitegoods division has outperformed its main rival, New Zealand-based Fisher &amp; Paykel Ltd, in the past six months to record a 1996-96 profit of A$28 million, up from A$12.3 million for the previous year. The result represents a turn around for Email, which has been losing market share to Fisher &amp; Paykel Ltd for the last five years. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>American executive Jim Wiemels arrived in Australia six weeks ago to take up the position of managing director for General Motors-Holden Automotive Australia. Wiemels former position was as vice-president of the company's small car production in North America. His appointment reflects the growing importance of the Australian Holden division in multi-national General Motors. Page 26.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Planned talks this week between Optus and Australis Media Ltd have taken on a new importance in light of Australis' disappointing earnings and the cancellation of the planned infrastructure sharing agreement between the two companies. Figures released lat week show Australis suffered a net loss of nearly A$200 million for the nine months to March. Page 28.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Luxury car importer BMW Australia lifted its profits by 60 per cent in 1996 to record a profit of A$25.9 million. The excellent result was achieved through currency changes and a rapidly expanding and profitable finance arm, despite only small increases in car sales. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Liquor Hospitality and Miscellaneous Workers Union spokesman Ann Drohn said yesterday that the collapsed Bells restaurant chain represented &quot;one of the worst cases&quot; of employee exploitation in the hospitality sector. Drohn claimed that staff were told they would lose their jobs if they did not preform duties outside their job specifications. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Ansett International chairman Ken Cowley said last night the company is staking its future viability on the results of its expansion into the Chinese market. Cowley was speaking at a Shanghai function to mark Ansett's inaugural flight to China on Sunday.Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>St George Bank has announced it will enter the A$120 billion funds management industry with managing director Russell Hooper set to head the team from Advance Bank's funds management division, Advance Asset Management, which became a subsidiary of St Geore following the merger of the two companies earlier this year. Hooper has assured clients that the division's name, personnel and current business practices will be maintained. Page 22.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Major companies in the superannuation industry are preparing for a year of heavy competition by promoting a year of strong performances early. For example, C+Bus, the construction and building industry fund, is claiming a profit increase of 15.7 per cent in calendar 1996, and the Health Employees Superannuation Trust has announced a 13.8 per cent profit rise over the same period. Page 22</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>American-based funds management group Scudder Stevens &amp; Clark, which controls approximately A$150 billion in assets, is planning to establish an Australian office. Australian executive Paul Bolinowsky has been appointed the firm's head of institutional business development, and charged with extending the company's existing A$300 million in Australian interests. Page 22.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Federal Government is coming under pressure from the equity and derivatives industries to reform important Budget measures which affect franking credits. The measures were imported from US tax law and are designed to abolish the tax-driven trade in franking credits, however industry experts have stated they need to be adapted to Australian conditions. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Olympic Video Gaming, Australia's second largest poker machine manufacturer, has enlisted corporate adviser Ernst and Young to seek offers for the group within the next two weeks. Stockbroker Deutsche Morgan Grenfell has valued the proposed sharemarket float at A$180 million. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Sausage Software shares are languishing at 24 cents, having peaked at A$1.50 on the company's stockmarket debut. The company's 190 staff has been reduced to 49, and founder Steve Outtrim is in Silicon Valley, California, trying to find a US partner with capital and marketing expertise. Nine months ago the company's prospectus predicted a pre-tax profit of A$6.6 million for 1997-98, but the company has decided not to provide revenue forecasts for the next financial year. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Federal Department of Health and Family Services has forced ANZ to withdraw its latest credit card program, which provided health insurance discounts based on the amount spent on the bank's gold MasterCard. Health authorities were concerned that since not everyone qualified for a gold card, the bank was offering discounts to a select group of society. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Mobil Oil is preparing to offload nearly A$400 million in assets it inherited with its A$1.8 billion takeover of Ampolex last year. The main assets to be sold are likely to be in the waters off the north-west Australian coast, and are likely to attract emrging oil and gas producers anxious to add to their production bases. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Industry Fund Services has predicted leading superannuation industry funds will exceed a 15 per cent investment return for 1996-97, based on fund earnings to the end of May. This will mean a return close to 30 per cent in total for the last two years. IF executive chairman Garry Weaven said industry funds have become more assertive in investing in infrastructure projects and development capital. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Comalco has announced plans to sell its A$50 million Southern Aluminium wheel plant in Tasmania to the US aluminium group Reynolds. The plant has struggled to make a profit since it was commissioned in 1989, and the sale price to Reynolds is expected to be a fraction of the original A$50 million invested in the plant, but given its written-down value a loss is not expected. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Sausage Software, Australia's first publicly listed Internet software company, is to seek capital backing from US investors to help it out of its financial difficulties. Sausage chairman Ian Clark has said the bid for overseas support is crucial to the company's future, claiming the company must expand or face collapse. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Melbourne-based company Olympic Video Gaming, the second largest manufacturer of poker machines in Australia, aims to raise A$180 million in preparation before a sharemarket float at the end of the year. The company has recruited corporate adviser Ernest&amp; Young to seek out prospective buyers. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Sydney Futures Exchange chief executive Les Hosking yesterday confirmed that preliminary investigations had been made into uncommonly heavy trading of bank bill futures contracts last month. Hosking denied however that the exchange was considering any further inquiries. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Comalco Ltd plans to sell its Southern Aluminium wheel plant in Tasmania to US aluminium group Reynolds within the next few weeks. The move will complete Comalco's withdrawal from the downstream sector of the aluminium industry. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Giant energy company Mobil Oil is set to sell approximately A$400 million in assets acquired as part of its A$1.8 billion 1996 takeover of Ampolex. The sale is expected to attract strong interest from newly formed oil and gas producers in Australia who are anxious to build up their infrastructure and production base nation-wide. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The ANZ Bank has been obliged to cancel its proposed credit-card program, under pressure by the Federal Department of Health and Family Services. The scheme would have allowed consumers to obtain health insurance discounts based on the amount spent on ANZ's gold MasterCard. Page B3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
