<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="646978" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BankAmerica buys investment banker; sells lender.</title>
<headline>BankAmerica buys investment banker; sells lender.</headline>
<byline>Sue Zeidler</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>BankAmerica Corp. stepped up its yearlong restructuring effort Monday, saying it would sell its consumer finance unit for $1.6 billion and buy investment bank Robertson Stephens &amp; Co. for about $540 million.</p>
<p>The deals are part of BankAmerica Chairman David Coulter's effort to focus on more profitable areas and jettison non-core assets. In the past year, the giant company has sold several underperforming units, launched an overhaul of its overseas operations and cut 3,700 jobs out of 92,000 companywide.</p>
<p>The sale of the consumer finance operation, Security Pacific Financial Services, to a unit of Travelers Group Inc., an insurance and financial services company, comes three months after BankAmerica said it planned to sell the unit, acquired in its 1992 acquisition of Security Pacific Corp.</p>
<p>The Robertson Stephens pact is the latest by a commercial bank to buy an investment bank as the Federal Reserve and other regulators have eased restrictions on commercial banks' ability to engage in brokerage activities. Bankers Trust New York Corp. agreed in April to buy Alex Brown &amp; Sons Inc. for $1.7 billion and Swiss Bank Corp. agreed to buy Dillon Read &amp; Co. for $600 million in May.</p>
<p>BankAmerica Chief Financial Officer Mike O'Neill said the restructuring will continue.</p>
<p>&quot;We're never done restructuring. We've done a lot of that at this point, but there's still more to do,&quot; he said during a conference call.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Robertson Stephens acquisition, while expensive at five times book value, would give BankAmerica new underwriting business, which it has sought for some time.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a high price for a firm with about $107 million in equity capital, (but) makes strategic sense for BankAmerica, and is small enough not to have a significant effect on BankAmerica's earnings,&quot; said Raphael Soifer, analyst with Brown Brothers Harriman.</p>
<p>Robertson Stephens, with about 800 employees, is one of a few West Coast investment banks specialising in initial public offerings in the high-tech and health care sectors. In 1996, it was lead underwriter on 26 offerings worth $1.2 billion.</p>
<p>During the conference call, Robertson Stephens Chief Executive Mike McCaffery said the firm had pretax earnings of $43.5 million on revenues of $353 million last year.</p>
<p>Under the deal, BankAmerica will make an initial payment of $245 million to Robertson Stephens' managing directors and pay $225 million over three years to executives who stay with the company. Another $70 million will be paid as compensation over four years to certain employees who stay with the firm.</p>
<p>The deal is structured so that much of the payments will help retain 60 key officers for up to four years.</p>
<p>BankAmerica said McCaffery will continue as Robertson Stephens CEO, reporting to Mike Murray, president of BankAmerica's Global Wholesale Bank. Robertson Stephens Chairman Sanford Robertson will be invited to join the BankAmerica board.</p>
<p>O'Neill said he did not expect any culture clashes between the two firms, as some merger specialists have predicted.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not propose to impose any commercial banking approaches to their business. I think that would be something that would doom it to failure and we recognise that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The price for Security Pacific Financial Services is $300 million more than the net tangible assets of the unit, which provides home equity and other real estate loans through about 300 offices, the companies said. The deal includes $1.2 billion in consumer finance receivables and $70 million of other assets.</p>
<p>Commercial Credit Co., the Travelers Group unit buying Security Pacific Financial, is a consumer lending company based in Baltimore with 859 offices in 44 states.</p>
<p>Both deals are subject to approval by regulators and are expected to be completed later this year.</p>
<p>BankAmerica stock rose 75 cents to $124 and Travelers added 62.5 cents to $58.125, both in consolidated trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
