<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64709" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian shares down ahead of index change Friday.</title>
<headline>Belgian shares down ahead of index change Friday.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian stocks ended slightly lower on Thursday with shares affected by Friday's reweighting of the Bel-20 index among the heaviest traded.</p>
<p>&quot;Tomorrow will be an interesting day,&quot; said one dealer, noting that trading times had been shortened to smooth anticipated price swings as portfolios are reweighted.</p>
<p>The Bel-20 lost 3.78 points to 1,750.87.</p>
<p>Bekaert, which loses weight in the Bel-20, was the second heaviest traded stock, rising 425 francs to 22,625.</p>
<p>Kredietbank and Petrofina, which gain weight in the index, were also volume leaders losing 1.7 and 0.6 percent respectively.</p>
<p>&quot;I think most people have already adjusted their portfolios and today was just fine-tuning,&quot; explained one trader.</p>
<p>Kredietbank NV director Remi Vermeiren said expectations of record volume levels on Friday might prove unfounded.</p>
<p>&quot;Logically, it should be a non-event. People should really already have taken positions,&quot; Vermeiren told Reuters.</p>
<p>Tractebel led turnover closing unchanged at 14,800 francs after a five percent surge on Wednesday.  REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
