<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64707" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Iraqi envoy in discreet talks with French.</title>
<headline>Iraqi envoy in discreet talks with French.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq's deputy foreign minister quietly met French foreign ministry officials on Thursday to try to convince them that the no-fly zones imposed over his country were unjust.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry spokesman Jacques Rummelhardt, confirming the visit, merely said Ryad Qeisi would call at the ministry to discuss implementation of U.N. Security Council resolutions.</p>
<p>&quot;Within the framework of France's constant consultations following the latest developments, Ryad Qeisi's visit will provide an opportunity to remind him of our position,&quot; he told a news briefing.</p>
<p>Apparently keen to avoid publicity about the visit following France's disagreement with the United States concerning the extension of the no-fly zone over southern Iraq, the ministry refused to say when the meeting was taking place and said Qeisi would not meet the press.</p>
<p>A Ministry official later confirmed the meeting was over and had covered &quot;implementation of the Security Council resolutions and Iraq's cooperation with the U.N. special committee&quot; which monitors Baghdad's compliance with the resolutions imposed after its 1990 invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>Qeisi said during a visit to Moscow earlier this week that he wanted to give Paris Baghdad's views on the ban on flights by Iraqi warplanes over southern and northern Iraq which was imposed by the United States, Britain and France in 1991 after the Gulf War.</p>
<p>He said France's Middle east policies had changed since then and no longer had to keep helping its allies enforce the no-fly zones just because it had agreed to their imposition in 1991.</p>
<p>France earlier this month distanced itself from Washington's decisions to launch missile strikes against Iraq and extend the southern no-fly zone in retaliation for Baghdad's operation against separatist Kurds in the north.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
