<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="647274" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: McVeigh trial ignites debate over death penalty.</title>
<headline>McVeigh trial ignites debate over death penalty.</headline>
<byline>Alan Elsner</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The trial of Timothy McVeigh, convicted in the Oklahoma City bombing that left 168 people dead, has ignited a rare debate over capital punishment in a country that takes it for granted.</p>
<p>Opponents of the death penalty, whose voices are usually drowned out by overwhelming public sentiment favouring capital punishment, have suddenly found a new opportunity to make themselves heard. The result has been a serious moral discussion on editorial pages and television talk shows.</p>
<p>Prominent among those who oppose death for McVeigh have been clergymen like Bishop William Skylstad of the National Conference of Catholic Bishops.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's look at this moment as a wonderful moment of opportunity,&quot; Skylstad said on one Sunday talk show. &quot;We see, in our modern day, a tremendous need to break the cycle of violence. Execution does not do that ... An execution does not really heal the hurt and pain.&quot;</p>
<p>On the other side, many argue that if there is one person truly deserving of the death penalty, it is McVeigh.</p>
<p>&quot;If you have a death penalty statute, how much more horrific can you be than someone like Timothy McVeigh who intentionally killed 168 of our neighbours and friends?&quot; Oklahoma Gov. Frank Keating asked. &quot;If you are going to have a capital punishment, that's a perfect person to use that punishment against.&quot;</p>
<p>If the jury in Denver decides against the death penalty for McVeigh, opponents of capital punishment are likely to turn Keating's argument around by saying that if McVeigh was not condemned to death, nobody should be.</p>
<p>Since the United States resumed executions in 1976, there have been 391 executions, most by lethal injection. Some 3,200 prisoners are awaiting execution on death row in 34 states. Recent laws have greatly expanded the crimes for which capital punishment may be applied and curtailed some of the legal resources of those condemned to death.</p>
<p>Public approval of capital punishment in most recent polls runs at around 75 percent and politicians who publicly oppose it risk being tagged as &quot;soft on crime&quot; by their opponents. But a Newsweek poll last week found that only 67 percent favoured the death penalty for McVeigh.</p>
<p>Civil rights leader Jesse Jackson, who believes society is demeaned when it takes the lives of murderers, acknowledged that McVeigh's apparent lack of remorse made it hard to argue that his life should be preserved.</p>
<p>&quot;He makes the toughest case for one to attempt to defend the principle, because he is such a pathetically cold and sick person,&quot; Jackson said. &quot;But I can't help but think that when it was time to kill Jesus by capital punishment, the people cheered, 'Kill him, kill him.' And yet, they were wrong.&quot;</p>
<p>But William Berns of the American Enterprise Institute think tank wrote in the Washington Post that there were some crimes -- he cited mass murders and crimes against humanity -- for which any lesser punishment would be inadequate.</p>
<p>To many opponents, a major problem with capital punishment is the inconsistency with which it is applied, not so much in high profile cases like McVeigh's but in the many anonymous trials that take place around the country every year.</p>
<p>The American Bar Association last year called for the death penalty to be suspended because a disproportionate number of those condemned were poor and black and many had received inadequate or incompetent legal representation.</p>
<p>Recent cases demonstrate that not all violent crimes end with the death sentence. Two white Marines recently convicted of murdering blacks in pursuit of their neo-Nazi beliefs were both sentenced to life imprisonment although it was unclear what mitigating circumstances applied.</p>
<p>And a women convicted of drowning her two infant sons in her car, ignoring their pleas for help, received life imprisonment after the state of South Carolina decided not to seek the death penalty, apparently because she was a woman.</p>
<p>Even before O.J. Simpson went to trial and successfully beat murder charges, the prosecution decided not to seek the death penalty in his case because the public celebrity and financial resources of the defendant might make it difficult to get the execution carried out.</p>
<p>In New Jersey, a jury this week began hearing arguments about whether Jesse Timmendequas should die for the sexual assault and murder of 7-year-old Megan Kanka. The defence will argue that Timmendequas was sexually and physically abused by his own father as a child and that he is mentally impaired.</p>
<p>If McVeigh escapes death while Timmendequas is condemned, the debate over justice is sure to escalate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
