<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="647262" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PS Enterprise forms 3rd Chinese venture.</title>
<headline>PS Enterprise forms 3rd Chinese venture.</headline>
<dateline>NEWARK, N.J. 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Public Service Enterprise Group said Monday its CEA Asia Inc subsidiary has concluded two expansions in Asia by forming a third venture in China and by taking a stake in a Filipino energy company.</p>
<p>In China, CEA Asia will own 80 percent of a new venture, Tongzhou Meiya Cogeneration Co Ltd. The remaining 20 percent will be owned by the Tongzhou Energy Co.</p>
<p>Enterprise said the venture will construct, own and operate a 30 megawatt coal-fired cogeneration power plant in the city of Tongzhou, Jiangsu Province, Enterprise said.  </p>
<p>Its statement included no financial details.</p>
<p>Construction will begin in June 1997 and commercial operation is expected by the end of 1998.  The plant will supply electricity and some 700 tons of steam per year to industrial and commercial users in the city and the Shanghai Tongzhou City Development Zone.</p>
<p>This is CEA Asia's third joint venture in China. The company is also the developer of the Jingyuan, Gansu Province, 600 megawatt coal-fired power plant and owns a majority interest in a district heating company in Pudong City, Shanghai.</p>
<p>In the Philippines, CEA Asia purchased about 27 percent of Manila based Magellan Capital Holding Co.</p>
<p>Spokesman Paul Rosengren said the remaining 73 percent is held by Ultrana Energy and Resources Corp.</p>
<p>He said terms of the transaction are not available.</p>
<p>Magellan owns 56 percent of a 48 megawatt operating diesel facility in Cavite, Philippines, with an additional 15 megawatts of capacity under construction. It also owns 42.5 percent of a 315 megawatt pulverized coal-fired plant under development in Bantangas, Philippines.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEWARK, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
