<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="647324" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Jochimsen-EMU delay needed if criteria not met.</title>
<headline>Jochimsen-EMU delay needed if criteria not met.</headline>
<dateline>WUPPERTAL, Germany 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bundesbank council member Raimut Jochimsen on Monday called for strict interpretation of the Maastricht criteria for European currency union membership.</p>
<p>The need for convergence to the criteria contained in the Maastricht treaty for membership of EMU was greater than the need for a timely start, Jochimsen said at a meeting in Wuppertal.</p>
<p>He said that it was gradually looking more likely that it would not be possible to have a timely start and meet the convergence criteria at the same time.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not a terrible thing to delay it if (efforts to meet the criteria) are not enough,&quot; Jochimsen said.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, a leading member of Chancellor Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU) called on Monday for a timely start to EMU on January 1 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;The most important thing is that people have the necessary trust in the stability of currency union,&quot; Wolfgang Schaeuble, CDU parliamentary leader, said in the advance text of a television interview to be broadcast later this evening.</p>
<p>In the same edition of the EURO konkret programme, Wolfgang Franz, a member of the Council of Economic Advisors dubbed Germany's &quot;Five Wise Men&quot;, called for a generous interpretation of the Maastricht treaty guidelines.</p>
<p>&quot;Currency union is an historical achievement, which should not be allowed to fail because of a tenth of a percentage point,&quot; Franz said.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WUPPERTAL, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
