<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="647591" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. debt futures down slightly in quiet trading.</title>
<headline>U.S. debt futures down slightly in quiet trading.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. debt futures futures slipped in quiet trading, pressed by mild profit-taking from Friday's big gains.</p>
<p>A weak dollar and a lack of data on Monday's agenda added to the dim, quiet tone, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;So far it is our typical Monday trade here,&quot; said John Kadich, futures analyst with Dean Witter Futures.</p>
<p>Kadich said September T-bonds could try for Friday's 111-9/32 high, but would extend only a few ticks above there.</p>
<p>&quot;I just don't think we can drive too much above Friday's high,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>On Friday, September T-bonds broke decisively above the 110-00 handle and rallied to the highest price since late February.</p>
<p>Kadich pegged resistance now at 111-15/32 to 17/32 and at 111-22/32 to 23/32. On the downside, he identified 110-23/32 to 25/32 as support.</p>
<p>Others said the market was due to consolidate after Friday. So far Monday, September's range was tight and contained within the top portion of Friday's range.</p>
<p>In the short end, traders said the market was similarly on hold.  </p>
<p>One Eurodollar broker said December euro resistance was 93.90, but he said he doubted the contract would muster the energy Monday to challenge it.</p>
<p>He blamed an empty data line-up and a consolidative mood after last week.</p>
<p>&quot;It's pretty dead in here,&quot; the euro broker said.</p>
<p>Tuesday's data line-up includes private retail sales surveys and the Richmond Fed survey for May. No economic news was slated for Wednesday, with May retail sales, the latest weekly jobless claims, and May's Atlanta Fed index on Thursday. May producer prices will be released Friday.  </p>
<p>At 0807 CDT/1307 GMT, Sept T-bonds were down 2/32 to 111-05/32, 10-yr notes fell 1/32 to 108-16/32, munis fell 2/32 to 118-17/32, Sept bills were flat at 94.695, Dec Euros fell 0.015 to 93.845. ((DerivativesDesk(312)408-8750)) E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
