<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="648066" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French shares remain jittery in wake of EMU talks.</title>
<headline>French shares remain jittery in wake of EMU talks.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>French shares remained jittery but traded above their lows after they had been dented by new French Finance Minister Dominique Strauss-Kahn telling European ministers in Luxembourg France needed time to discuss the stability pact with its National Assembly.</p>
<p>Finance Ministers, in particular Germany, had wanted an agreement on the stability pact -- calling for harmonised budget policies in parallel with monetary policy -- ahead of the June 16 and 17 summit of heads of state in Amsterdam.</p>
<p>German diplomats said they remain confident that the stability pact could be signed by the end of June.</p>
<p>Strauss-Kahn said he was committed to EMU but needed at least a week to discuss the stability pact.</p>
<p>Iain Lindsay of Credit Lyonnais said that the Socialist government had still not stated its position but was keeping its powder dry.</p>
<p>A market strategist at Paribas said that the Socialist government's first act on the international scene showed that it was not the kind of &quot;free-market socialists&quot; some Anglo-Saxon investors had been hoping for with the example of the British labour government. He expected volatility to remain until Prime Minister Lionel Jospin's policy declaration expected on June 17.</p>
<p>* CAC-40 index down 49.45, or 1.82 percent, at 2,669.8 at 1212 GMT.</p>
<p>* CAC-40 June futures 2,654 vs 2,700 at Friday's close.</p>
<p>* Broader SBF120 index down 28.72 at 1,842.47</p>
<p>* CAC-40 volume 4.15 billion francs.</p>
<p>* Bouygues, up 0.58 percent at 522 francs, only blue-chip to rise after obtaining financing for telecoms plans last week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
