<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="648214" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Mauritius scraps sugar levy in budget.</title>
<headline>Mauritius scraps sugar levy in budget.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government in the Indian Ocean island of Mauritius announced its 1997/98 budget on Monday, proposing the removal of a levy on sugar introduced last year.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Vasant Bunwaree said removal of the levy was necessary because the sugar industry, an important source of government revenue, had not registered previously expected windfall gains on the 1996 crop.</p>
<p>Introducing the levy last year, the government had forecast the levy would raise up to 300 million rupees ($14.6 million) on windfall gains.</p>
<p>&quot;The sugar industry has made the case that there has been no windfall gains on the 1996 crop,&quot; Bunwaree told parliament in his maiden budget speech.</p>
<p>He added: &quot;In view of this unexpected turn of event, there is at present no justification for imposing this special levy on the sugar industry.&quot;</p>
<p>Industry officials have forecast output at between 600,000 -620,000 tonnes this year compared to 590,000 tonnes achieved last year and 540,000 the year before.</p>
<p>The minister said in return, the sugar industry would be invited to implement a social programme in favour of sugar industry employees and their families.</p>
<p>Bunwaree announced that the sugar industry would make available interest-free loans amounted in total to 100 million rupees ($4.86 million) to its employees for the purchase of Sugar Investment Trust shares presently on offer.</p>
<p>&quot;For each of the 17 sugar estates, the industry will grant five scholarships tenable at the University of Mauritius or at polytechnics to children of both agricultural and non- agricultural workers,&quot; Bunwaree said.</p>
<p>The sugar industry would be also required to contribute to the Mauritius Sugar Authority a total amount of 150 million rupees ($7.29 million) by the end of September 1997, for the execution of various projects in the sugar sector.</p>
<p>($ = 20.55 Mauritian rupees)</p>
<p>Clifford Vellien  ++230  211-9555</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100136">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
