<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="648296" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - Bund set sights on 101.25 resistance.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Bund set sights on 101.25 resistance.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>September Bund futures are aiming for the 101.25 level, although the early break of support at 101.00 may lead to a pullback, technical analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The new contract will be stuck between the support and resistance, and it needs to break out before it can set up a major trend,&quot; said Nico Bakker, inter-market technical analyst at ABN-AMRO in Amsterdam.</p>
<p>The 101.25 level was a 38.2 percent retracement of the rally on the June contract from 99.05 in April to 102.59 in May.</p>
<p>September Bund futures were up 0.24 at 100.98 by 0700 GMT.  </p>
<p>David Sneddon technical analyst at Credit Suisse in London said the break above 100.70/85 last week had been bullish for the contract.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we're above there, it should rally further,&quot; he said. &quot;We should see it heading for the resistance line at 101.40 from the February and May highs.&quot;</p>
<p>In February, the contract set a high of 101.99, and in May the high was 101.55.</p>
<p>&quot;Once above the line it can challenge the May high,&quot; he said. He also cited slight resistance at 101.12/14 from price action. The contract stalled there in early trade on Monday.  </p>
<p>On the downside, the 101.00 support has come under pressure, and there may be a pullback to price support around 100.85.</p>
<p>The accelerated uptrend means the market appears overextended in the short term, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless it breaks down through 100.50, not much damage will be done,&quot; said Sneddon.</p>
<p>At the short end September Euromarks were at 96.81, up two basis points from Friday's close.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
