<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="648258" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: US fund managers to sell European stocks - Merrill.</title>
<headline>US fund managers to sell European stocks - Merrill.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S.-based fund managers will seek to sell European equities in the wake of the Socialist election victory in France, a survey by Merrill Lynch said.</p>
<p>The survey, which covered 42 institutions with $2.2 trillion under management, said sellers outnumbered buyers by 19 percent in the June survey.</p>
<p>&quot;Bullishness for European equities has all but evaporated: bulls outnumber bears by just five percent on a year's view, down from 34 percent in May,&quot; the survey said.</p>
<p>Since the Fed left rates unchanged at the May FOMC meeting, there has been a sharp drop in the number of managers expecting Fed Funds to rise in the coming year. Only 55 percent of managers expect rates to go up, down from 70 percent in May.</p>
<p>U.S. fund managers now favour energy stocks, with bulls outnumbering bears by 12 percent. Financial and technical stocks fell in popularity.</p>
<p>Japanese equities continue to gain, with buyers outnumbering sellers by 33 percent, a rise for the fifth month running.</p>
<p>Bonds outside the U.S. were big losers, with sellers outnumbering buyers by 19 percent.</p>
<p>The survey was carried out for Merrill by Gallup between the 30th of May and the 4th of June.</p>
<p>- James Saft, London newsroom, +171 542 2734</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
