<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="648201" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Switzerland - June 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Switzerland - June 9.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights from Swiss newspapers on Monday:</p>
<p>NEUE ZUERCHER ZEITUNG - Switzerland may still export arms and the Swiss government does not have to seek advance approval from voters to conduct bilateral negotiations on joining the European Union, Swiss voters decided in weekend referenda. Representatives of the Swiss arms industry said that the decision not to ban arms exports will strengthen Switzerland as a production base. - Voters in the canton of Basle decided to ease shopping hours regulations, allowing shop keepers to open and close their stores whenever they want. - Canton of Zug changed its electorial procedures for its cantonal parliament from a proportional system to one based on majority.</p>
<p>TAGES ANZEIGER</p>
<p>- Despite continuing scepticism among customers, Swiss banks are introducing new so-called green funds, investment opportunities for ecolocially sensitive clients. - The economic crisis of the canton of Valais over the last few years has structural reasons. Depending on the construction industry and a quantity-oriented tourism sector, the French-speaking part in particular will encounter many obstacles in the future.</p>
<p>JOURNAL DE GENEVE</p>
<p>- Citizens of the canton of Valais this Sunday voted in favour of a 30 million Swiss franc credit to support the candiature of the 2006 Olympic winter games.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
