<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="648245" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - June 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - June 9.</headline>
<text>
<p>This daily press summary is produced for Reuters by the Broadcast Monitoring Company, which is responsible for its contents. For further information on these articles or details of BMC's other international press and broadcast services call Simon McMillan on +44 (0)171 256 5130 or e-mail bmc.co@ft.com</p>
<p>-- COMPUTER TRADING MAY ROB REVENUE OF 'BILLIONS'</p>
<p>The UK Chartered Institute of Taxation has pleaded with the Inland revenue to endorse a joint scheme to secure tax receipts which have been threatened by the significant increase of Internet transactions. The institute warned that the 'fiscal black hole' created by computer trading could lead to the loss of 'billions of pounds'. Research indicates that by 1999, 60 per cent of financial services will use the Internet for deals, compared with 13 per cent today.</p>
<p>-- BANKS TO SET UP GROUP TO SETTLE FOREX PAYMENTS</p>
<p>The Group of Twenty, a coalition of banks from Europe, the US, Canada and Japan, is planning to set up a bank to deal with payments in the 800 billion sterling per-day foreign exchange market. The group will hold a meeting in London next week in talks to create the venture which could serve as a holding company not only for the settlement bank, but possibly for other solutions for settling accounts in the foreign exchange market, such as netting systems.</p>
<p>-- CAMELOT SET FOR TV GAME SHOW TO BOOST CARD SALES</p>
<p>Camelot, operators of the National Lottery in the UK, is expected to be granted permission to begin a television show for scratch card winners offering prizes up to 100,000 sterling. The company hopes the TV show will boost sagging sales for its scratch cards which peaked at sales of 40 million sterling per week in 1995, but since have dropped to 15 million sterling per week. Camelot has also revealed it will prepare loyalty bonuses for all 650 of its staff later this year, intended to keep them in place until 2001, when its lottery licence runs out.</p>
<p>-- OIL COMPANY WILL WORK SMALL NORTH SEA FIELDS</p>
<p>The Venture Production Company, specialising in the development of small, 'economically marginal' North Sea oil fields, has been formed in Aberdeen, in what has been labeled the third phase in the evolution of the area. Executives from Venture say they will use the latest technology, including computerized 'smart wells', to 'redefine the marginality' of the over 500 small pools of oil bypassed in the area in the past.</p>
<p>-- CASH STILL PREFERRED FOR SMALL PAYMENTS</p>
<p>Research Surveys of Great Britain has revealed that cash is the most often method of payment for small purchases, with 80 per cent of the 2,000 adults it questioned admitting they preferred to use notes or coins for purchases of about ten pounds sterling. A similar poll in 1996 found the result of cash use to be at 82 per cent. Debit cards have overtaken cheques in terms of popularity, but have had little impact on smaller-item purchases. Cash and cheques have given way to plastic cards for larger purchases, though 57 per cent of people polled believed they could get a better deal by paying cash.</p>
<p>-- ABB TO CUT JOBS IN WESTERN EUROPE</p>
<p>In an attempt to cut costs and spread manufacturing operations around the world, Swiss-Swedish engineering group ABB is set to cut thousands of jobs around western Europe. To balance the cuts and encourage growth, the company is hoping to create more jobs in emerging economies such as India, China and eastern Europe to take advantage of lower labour costs and increase proximity with customers in local markets.</p>
<p>-- ITALY TO SELL THIRD TRANCHE OF SHARES IN ENI GROUP</p>
<p>Beginning its biggest privatisation of the year, the Italian government has sold the third tranche of shares (totalling some one billion) in state-controlled oil and gas group Eni, in a deal worth nearly 3.6bn stg. The government has indicated that if strong demand continues for the shares, it will offer more for sale while retaining control of the company.</p>
<p>-- GRANADA SELLS BROWN'S FOR 45M STG</p>
<p>Granada has announced the sale of Brown's Hotel in London to Raffles Holdings of Singapore for 45m stg in cash, increasing the total of money made from the sale of its Exclusive hotels following the Forte acquisition to over 450m stg. Brown's is the eighth of 17 Exclusive hotels to be sold, with the next Exclusive hotel to go expected to be The Ritz in Madrid.</p>
<p>-- AIT FLOAT TAG UP TO 25M STG</p>
<p>UK software group AIT, which specialises in the production of systems for retail financial organisations, is set to be listed on the market with a placing valuing it between 20m stg and 25m stg. Of the ten million stg in proceeds, a large portion is expected to go to directors and employees who will be selling part of their stakes. The remaining two million stg will fund the group in its financing of new facilities and undertaking of new products.</p>
<p> -- IBM PINS HOPES ON G4 MAINFRAMES</p>
<p>IBM will unveil its latest line of high-performance 'G4' CMOS mainframe computers on Monday which are built on low-cost microprocessor chips. The computer company hopes the new systems will rejuvenate the life of its flagship products, as the G4 is capable of matching the processing speed of the most powerful IBM bipolar mainframes at 63 Mips. For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
