<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="648269" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BAA says T5 delays will not slow investment.</title>
<headline>BAA says T5 delays will not slow investment.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>British airports operator BAA Plc said on Monday it would go on spending 450 to 500 million pounds a year on infrastructure despite the delays in starting the 1.5 billion pounds Heathrow Terminal Five project.</p>
<p>Delays in completing the public planning inquiry have put back the opening date for the new terminal by at least two years to the year 2004.</p>
<p>But finance director Russell Walls said the delays would not cut BAA's overall capital spending because it would reschedule other work, and therefore he did not expect a fresh review of BAA's regulated airline charges.  </p>
<p>&quot;The total has not materially changed but the order of things will change because Terminal Five will slip back and other things will probably come in,&quot; he told Reuters in a post-results interview.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be more expenditure at Gatwick, for example, as it grows, perhaps more baggage systems than we had previously planned and probably some (investment) at Stansted as well,&quot; Walls said.</p>
<p>Terminal Five is designed to increase capacity at Heathrow by nearly 50 percent to 80 million passengers a year. But the delays mean faster growth at Gatwick and Stansted.  </p>
<p>But overall BAA still expected to spend some 4.4 billion pounds on infrastructure projects, including Terminal Five, over the next 10 years, which was the amount indicated when airport charges were set last year, Walls said.</p>
<p>The current delay for Terminal Five therefore would not trigger any interim review of regulated airport charges, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;No, that would only happen if Terminal Five was disallowed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Civil Aviation Authority ruled in November that BAA must cut airport user charges at London Heathrow and Gatwick airports by inflation minus three percentage points a year for the next five years from April 1997. But the CAA had said the cut was relatively benign to smooth price changes over the next 10 years in anticipation of Terminal Five going ahead.</p>
<p>Walls said that with such huge spending plans his task would be to keep borrowing, interest cover and gearing under control. &quot;And I think we have done it very well in the last two years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our debt has gone up by just over 100 million pounds in each of the last two years whereas we have been saying to the (share) market thjat they should assume it would go up by perhaps 150 to even 200 million pounds in some years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Net debt stood at 1.15 billion stg in the year to March 31 and gearing of 33 percent of equity. Walls said debt was going to &quot;creep up&quot; by around two to three percent a year which would take gearing 20 or 30 percent higher in ten years' time.</p>
<p>&quot;It is really managing the cashflow that is the key to success...by judicious and efficient spending,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Greg Mahlich, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
