<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="648371" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Dollar seen faltering further before G7 summit.</title>
<headline>Dollar seen faltering further before G7 summit.</headline>
<byline>Tatsuo Ito</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar is likely to sag further to around 110 yen in the coming weeks, as traders are betting that Japan will have to let the yen climb in order to keep its ballooning trade surplus in check.</p>
<p>Traders said on Monday that Japan is keen to defuse trade tension ahead of the meeting of the world's seven leading industrialised nations in Denver later this month, and will therefore tolerate a reinvigorated yen.</p>
<p>The threat of trade friction and shifting interest rate differentials helped trigger torrents of yen-buying on Monday. Traders said the dollar's future course was uncertain, but it was likely to retreat further.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is betting that Japan is trying to avoid criticism at the (Denver) summit by letting the yen drift higher,&quot; said Ryosuke Tsuji, senior vice president of the foreign exchange department at Societe Generale in Tokyo.</p>
<p>The dollar briefly fell to 111.80 yen, its lowest level in more than six months, in Tokyo trade on Monday, as traders unloaded heaps of dollars they had bought in bulk when the greenback was muscling its way higher.</p>
<p>At its lowest point on Monday, the dollar was around two and a half yen below its late level in New York trade on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a chance of the yen's strengthening to 110 yen, although a clear break of that point could alter the longer-term outlook for the dollar,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Japanese trade figures to be published on Wednesday are expected to show the politically sensitive current account surplus surged in April, as a rise in the nation's sales tax dampened demand for imports.</p>
<p>After its dip on Monday at Tokyo's midday, the dollar recovered slightly to trade just under 113 yen after Japanese Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka said stable currency rates were important in achieving a sustainable economic recovery in Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;We had anticipated such remarks from monetary authorities, but they were not strong enough to reverse the dollar's downward trend,&quot; said a dealer at a Japanese bank.</p>
<p>Dealers said that Japanese authorities may tolerate a dollar fall to around 110 yen ahead of the Group of Seven (G7) leaders' summit in Denver on June 20-22.</p>
<p>The dollar's tumble was also spurred by weak U.S. jobs data on Friday and yen strength against European currencies due to uncertainty over the prospects for a single European currency.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Japanese monetary authorities seemed in no hurry to clip the yen's wings.</p>
<p>When the dollar sank to 111.98 on May 20, compared with a five-year high of 127.47 yen on May 1, policymakers were quick to signal displeasure. Then, the dollar stopped falling when influential Finance Ministry official Eisuke Sakakibara and Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka said that the yen's downward correction had come to a halt.</p>
<p>But Sakakibara was conspicuously silent this time, telling Reuters that he could not comment on the dollar's slide.</p>
<p>Asked whether the yen is likely to drift higher before the summit, Sakakibara said: &quot;I will not make any comment (on currencies), it would be normal (for the authorities) not to comment on currencies so often.&quot;</p>
<p>Kazunori Iida, a manager at the foreign exchange department of Nissho Iwai Corp, said the yen had been gathering strength as the focus shifted to the trade relationship.</p>
<p>&quot;Amid weak domestic demand and a lack of measures to boost it, Japan may need to demonstrate that it is not exporting its way out of recession,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The United States has been showing increasing signs of discomfort at the trade picture, warning Japan against using exports to drive its domestic recovery. A higher yen would make Japan's exports less competitive in global markets, while promoting imports into Japan, shifting the trade balance.</p>
<p>Given Tokyo's strong determination to cut public spending and to bring its budget deficit under control, a higher yen is the only near-term option for reining in the mushrooming trade surplus, dealers said.</p>
<p>Quoting sources close to summit participants in Washington, the Nihon Keizai Shimbun business daily said on Friday that G7 nations will call on Japan to curb the trade surplus. U.S. Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky also voiced concerns on Friday over Japan's rising surplus with the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
