<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="64841" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Afghan city tense but calm after Taleban takeover.</title>
<headline>Afghan city tense but calm after Taleban takeover.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Lyon</byline>
<dateline>JALALABAD, Afghanistan 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The rebel Islamic Taleban movement plans to impose the same strictures on women, music and drugs in Jalalabad, the latest Afghan city to fall into its hands, as it has enforced in other areas it controls.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever is in the sharia (Islamic law) will be implemented here, as our elders in Kandahar decide,&quot; Haji Ata Mohammed, security chief for Jalalabad, told Reuters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He was speaking one week after the Taleban swept into Jalalabad, capital of Nangarhar province. They met little resistance from neutral factions led by former governor Haji Abdul Qadir, who fled to Pakistan.</p>
<p>The Taleban, who burst onto the Afghan scene two years ago from religious Islamic schools in Pakistan, have barred women from working outside the health sector and stopped girls from going to school in areas where its writ runs.</p>
<p>The black-turbaned warriors have carried out executions and amputations according to their stringent version of Islamic law, as well as opposing music, football, television and drugs.</p>
<p>Mohammed, who was recovering from a chest wound in the gardens of the bomb-damaged Bagh-i-Shahi palace, said Jalalabad was completely calm and the Taleban were in full control.</p>
<p>&quot;We have taken over from all the factions that were here before and we will bring peace here,&quot; he said. &quot;We have removed the checkposts and we are taking no money from drivers.&quot;</p>
<p>Mohammed said the Taleban would not prevent United Nations or other relief convoys from travelling to Kabul, but government forces had blocked the road with landmines to defend the town of Sarobi, about 130 km (80 miles) west of Jalalabad.</p>
<p>He said Taleban fighters were about 30 km (19 miles) short of Sarobi, awaiting orders to advance on the capital.</p>
<p>The Sunni Moslem rebels now hold more than half of Afghanistan's 33 provinces, with the rest split between the Tajik-dominated government of President Burhanuddin Rabbani and northern opposition Uzbek leader General Abdul Rashid Dostum.</p>
<p>Taleban land includes most areas populated by Afghanistan's traditionally ruling ethnic Pashtun group, but extends to mostly Tajik areas such as Herat in the west, captured a year ago.</p>
<p>The people of Jalalabad, most of them Pashtun, seem outwardly less disturbed by the advent of the Taleban than by Sunday's air raid, in which government jets bombed the former royal Bagh-i-Shahi palace, the airport and a hotel.</p>
<p>&quot;This was not a military arsenal, but was used as a dining room and a depot to store 5,000 holy Korans,&quot; said Baz Mohammed, a Taleban commander, in a rubble-strewn domed room.</p>
<p>He stood near a large bomb crater in which cardboard boxes that had held Korans published in Saudi Arabia were scattered among mudbricks and fallen tiles.</p>
<p>The raid, which killed 12 civilians and wounded 50, was a new experience for Jalalabad, whose previous rulers kept the strategic city out of the factional fighting that has raged for the past four years elsewhere in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Three days after the attack, many shops in Jalalabad were still shuttered, a rare sight in this trading town even during the Soviet occupation in the 1980s.</p>
<p>&quot;People are afraid after the bombing,&quot; said 17-year-old taxi-driver Baghdad Shah.</p>
<p>He said he was pleased because the Taleban were exacting no tolls on the highway from Jalalabad to the Pakistani border. &quot;Before, different militias were stopping vehicles at every point, demanding money and sometimes stealing cars,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Taleban are treating people very well. They took three of my music cassettes and asked me to drive over them, but I don't mind that as long as they keep the road open,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At the airport east of the city, boisterous Taleban fighters milled around outside the terminal, posing for photographs on armoured vehicles mounted with anti-aircraft guns before piling into pickup trucks and driving off in clouds of dust.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not closed the airport. There are flights to Kandarhar and we have no objection to international flights, but they have stopped for the moment because of the air raid,&quot; said a portly Taleban commander, Mullah Akhter Mohammed al-Mansoor.</p>
<p>Two Russian-made MiG fighters and a couple of captured helicopters stood on the otherwise deserted tarmac.</p>
<p>Pakistan denies Afghan government charges that it backs the Taleban, saying it has no favourites among rival factions.</p>
<p>The Taleban clearly face few difficulties in bringing fresh recruits across the porous border. At Torkham, at the head of the rugged Khyber Pass, about 20 young would-be fighters were striding from Pakistan towards a Taleban office at the frontier.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JALALABAD, Afghanistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
