<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="648620" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore stocks steady, Jardine units stay active.</title>
<headline>Singapore stocks steady, Jardine units stay active.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Singapore stock market traded steadily at mid-morning on Monday, with the Hong Kong-based Jardine group of companies dominating the actives.</p>
<p>Jardine Matheson Holdings, Jardine Strategic Holdings Ltd and HongKong Land Holdings Ltd continued to enjoy buying support after three institutions issued call warrants on them on Friday. HK Land, trading US$0.01 up at US$2.96, led the actives with over 2.8 million shares.</p>
<p>At 0155 GMT, the Straits Times Industrials Index was up 5.95 points at 2,038.25. Volume was light, around 29 million shares with 86 gainers and 29 losers.</p>
<p>Most foreign institutions stayed sidelined but dealers noted some occasional nibbling of blue chips like DBS Land, Keppel and foreign tranches of banks price dips.</p>
<p>DBS Land shares were down S$0.02 at S$4.66 after hotel arm Raffles Holdings was reported to have bought a London hotel for about S$105. Dealers said that did not affect the shares despite uncertainty over the financing.</p>
<p>&quot;While financing is unclear, strategically it is a good move for Raffles,&quot; one said. Soft drinks group Fraser &amp; Neave rose S$0.20 to S$10.70. Creative Technology fell S$0.40 to S$22.90.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
