<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="648766" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: European roads disrupted in truckers' pay protest.</title>
<headline>European roads disrupted in truckers' pay protest.</headline>
<byline>Alister Doyle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>French truck drivers set up dozens of barricades on roads and at frontiers on Monday, spearheading a European day of action for better pay and conditions that disrupted traffic from Germany to Portugal.</p>
<p>French drivers, often cooperating with European neighbours, parked lorries across the Spanish, Italian, German, Belgian and Swiss borders. In many places only private cars were allowed to pass the blockades, which caused huge tailbacks.</p>
<p>Spanish truckers blocked three crossings with France and one with Portugal as part of the push to secure new European Union rules limiting working hours and standardising benefits like sick pay and earlier retirement.</p>
<p>Truckers also set up dozens of barriers inside France, hitting traffic around Paris and other major cities. Many of the blockades were dismantled around midday.</p>
<p>&quot;We work 80 hours (a week), we get paid for 56 at the most,&quot; said Roger Poletti, secretary general of the truckers' section of the independent Force Ouvriere union that called the stoppage in France with the pro-Socialist CFDT and Communist-led CGT.</p>
<p>&quot;There's not just driving. there's waiting time -- loading, unloading, customs etc. There are plenty of other jobs that the bosses don't pay for and don't want to take into account,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The stoppage was called before France's Socialist-led government swept to power in an upset election last week, ousting President Jacques Chirac's centre-right coalition.</p>
<p>French truckers accuse employers of back-tracking on promises they made to end a 12-day strike last year and hope their cause has been helped by the appointment of a Communist transport minister, Jean-Claude Gayssot.</p>
<p>Gayssot's chief aide was due to meet representatives of the unions and employers on Monday afternoon, his office said.</p>
<p>In the south-west, truckers blocked the Biriatou crossing to Spain, forcing cars to be diverted around Saint-Jean-de-Luz on the Atlantic. The barricade was lifted in late morning.</p>
<p>A lorry across the road blocked the access to the Mont Blanc tunnel in the Alps, letting only small vehicles drive through to Italy. A dozen trucks completely blocked the road leading to the Frejus tunnel linking France and Italy.</p>
<p>Near Strasbourg in eastern France, French and German truckers set up a barrier on a bridge over the Rhine. French and Swiss truckers also blocked a crossing at the Saint-Louis-Basle, leading to a two km (1.5 mile) tailback.</p>
<p>Felix Perrolaz, head of the Swiss customs post, said more than 100 trucks were backed up in the protest, due to be dismantled in the morning.</p>
<p>In Madrid, Eladio San Romar, head of the truckers' division of the CCOO union, said Spanish truckers wanted retirement at 60 rather than 65 and limits on working hours.</p>
<p>French truckers accuse bosses of failing to respect last year's deal cutting the retirement age to 55 from 60 for drivers with 25 years experience, as well as providing for sick pay, travel expenses, union rights and a ban on Sunday driving.</p>
<p>Joel le Coq, of the pro-Socialist CFDT truckers' union, said that just five to 10 percent of employers had paid a promised 3,000 franc ($515) bonus to drivers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
