<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="648763" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Russia's Gazprom to study gas supply to Israel.</title>
<headline>Russia's Gazprom to study gas supply to Israel.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's Gazprom will send a delegation to Israel in July to examine the possible supply of natural gas to the Jewish state, the National Infrastructure Ministry said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The delegation will arrive in Israel on July 7 and enter intensive contacts on all technical and economic issues of price, means and guarantees of supply,&quot; the ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>The statement said the visit was agreed at a meeting between Infrastructure Minister Ariel Sharon and Gazprom chairman Rem Vyakhirev in Moscow on Sunday.</p>
<p>It said the two men discussed the price of supplying gas until the year 2000 with an eye to longer-term supply.</p>
<p>Any natural gas brought from Russia would have to travel via pipeline to Turkey and then by undersea pipeline to Israel.</p>
<p>Israel has been trying to reach long-term agreements on gas sales to diversify its energy sources and lower energy costs.</p>
<p>The Haaretz newspaper said Israel's Ofer Brothers, with interests in shipping and energy, had submitted a proposal to the infrastructure and finance ministries to import natural gas from Norway.</p>
<p>The newspaper said the proposal, in conjunction with Norway's Den norske stats oljeselskap AS (Statoil), called for shipping liquefied natural gas (LNG) to Israel from the North Sea to be processed in a $150 million gasification plant to be built in Israel.</p>
<p>An infrastructure ministry spokeswoman said she could not confirm or deny the report.</p>
<p>- Jerusalem newsroom, 972-2-537-0502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
