<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="648918" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Yellen sees Japan economy aided by forex, demand.</title>
<headline>Yellen sees Japan economy aided by forex, demand.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>White House economist Janet Yellen said Tuesday that she sees the Japanese economy being aided by exchange rate changes and more domestic investment that will lead to more domestic demand.</p>
<p>&quot;The movement in exchange rates, I think, will be a stimulus to the economy through the external sector,&quot; Yellen told a small group of reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;But also it looks like domestic investment in Japan is a likely source of strength as well,&quot; she added. &quot;My perception is that they are not simply relying on foreign sales as a source of growth.&quot;  </p>
<p>The United States has been concerned that Japan might try to export its way out of its economic troubles.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be my hope there will be continue improvement in the Japanese economy,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Yellen says she sees the U.S. economy continuing to do well with continued low inflation and low unemployment.</p>
<p>&quot;It is hard to see what clouds are on the horizon,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She said the low 4.8 percent U.S. unemployment rate, low inflation and reduced budget deficits will be the envy of the meeting of leaders from the Group of Seven industrial nations in Denver this month.</p>
<p>She noted that during the 1980s the U.S. budget deficit attracted criticism from countries around the world.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that our economy has done so well that it is really the envy of most of our trading partners and most of the countries that will be present,&quot; Yellen said. &quot;Think about how low unemployment is, most of the countries there would be envious to have unemployment rates like ours.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a combination of low inflation, of low unemployment that is making us the envy of the world,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
