<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="649078" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: RUGBY UNION-LIONS TEST PLACES STILL UP FOR GRABS SAYS JOHNSON.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-LIONS TEST PLACES STILL UP FOR GRABS SAYS JOHNSON.</headline>
<byline>Andy Colquhoun</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Lions skipper Martin Johnson believes places for the first test side are still up for grabs even though the Lions are likely to name a test strength side to play Natal on Saturday.</p>
<p>Johnson dismissed the suggestion that the side picked to play the Gauteng Lions (formerly Transvaal) in Johannesburg on Wednesday night were already out of the running.</p>
<p>&quot;That's not the case at all. There are still places available if players put in good performances,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have said all along that there isn't a midweek side and a test side. All 35 players have a chance of making the internationals.&quot;</p>
<p>However the Lions have always intended to make Saturday's trip to Durban their dress rehearsal for the first test in Cape Town on June 21.</p>
<p>That means those selected to play the Gauteng Lions know they will need big performances to change the selectors' thinking.</p>
<p>Mike Catt and Nigel Redman have been called up from England's tour of Argentina as replacements for the injured Paul Grayson and Doddie Weir and have their first chance to impress the selectors.</p>
<p>Weir may never play again after Mpumalanga lock forward Darius Bosman stamped on his knee last week. Bosman was fined 10,000 rand ($2,230) on Monday and although Lions' tour officials refused to comment on the punishment sources close to the camp said they were upset he had not been banned.</p>
<p>After Saturday's 35-30 defeat by Northern Transvaal a victory and good performances from Wednesday's team could alter the selectors' thinking.</p>
<p>Full-back, left-wing and inside centre among the backs, number eight, openside and all three front row positions among the forwards are all far from clear cut.</p>
<p>The visitors face a Gauteng Lions side which on paper is stronger than Northern Transvaal and far stronger than the Mpumalanga side they swept aside in Witbank.</p>
<p>The Ellis Park team finished three places above Northerns in the Super 12 and have been less affected by calls to the Springbok side. They will feature World Cup winners in centre Hennie le Roux and lock Kobus Wiese who were surprisingly omitted fom the Springbok side to meet Tonga on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They have five other internationals in the side including Argentinian prop Roberto Grau. The Lions have won four and lost one of their tour matches to date.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Gauteng Lions (probable) - 15-Dawie Du Toit, 14-Joe Gillingham, 13-Jannie van der Walt, 12-Hennie le Roux, 11-Pieter Hendricks, 10-Louis van Rensburg, 9-Johan Roux, 8-Warren Brosnihan, 7-Piet Krause, 6-Andre Vos, 5-Bruce Thorne, 4-Kobus Wiese (captain, 3-Kapstock van Greuning, 2-Chris Rossouw, 1-Roberto Grau.</p>
<p>British Lions - 15-Nick Beal, 14-John Bentley, 13-Allan Bateman, 12-Will Greenwood, 11-Tony Underwood, 10-Mike Catt, 9-Austin Healey, 8-Tim Rodber (captain), 7-Neil Back, 6-Rob Wainwright, 5-Jeremy Davidson, 4-Nigel Redman, 3-Paul Wallace, 2-Barry Wiliams, 1-Tom Smith.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
