<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="649247" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Physical tin sees buying, Russian metal shipped.</title>
<headline>Physical tin sees buying, Russian metal shipped.</headline>
<byline>Eric Onstad</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pockets of physical tin buying are emerging in Europe when futures prices dip, but some consumers are holding out for still weaker prices, traders said.</p>
<p>The physical market has also seen parcels of Russian ex-stockpile material shipped, with more expected, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems the end users are trickling back,&quot; one trader on continental Europe said.</p>
<p>&quot;We had some prompt business this morning and also several enquiries for August and September. But they didn't book the forward business because they (consumers) are hoping to see it get back down to $5,500,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>LME three months prices slid to $5,580 on Monday, within reach of the June 2 low of $5,510.</p>
<p>Consumers on the continent would also be influenced by the dollar rate against the mark, which dipped to 1.704 on Tuesday morning.</p>
<p>Other traders have also seen bits and pieces of business appear, but the physical market quietens down when futures prices try the upside.</p>
<p>&quot;We see the buying come in around $5,600, both on the LME and on physicals...At $5,500, there would be a lot of it,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Premiums were little changed, with Chinese tin cif Rotterdam changing hands at $40 over LME cash on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Another trader said he had already purchased one 750-tonne load of ex-stockpile tin from Russia and another 1,000-tonne shipment was in transit.</p>
<p>The metal was bypassing the LME, moving straight to consumers, since it was too old to be registered. More Russian metal was expected to be offered, but some traders said they have so far been unable to get their hands on some.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542-8065</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
