<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="649225" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Euro oil swaps touch easier, bar heavy fuel up $1.</title>
<headline>Euro oil swaps touch easier, bar heavy fuel up $1.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>European oil swaps were steady to a touch weaker by the end of Tuesday despite showing some resilience and strength earlier in the day. Tight prompt wet supplies of heavy fuel helped boost swap numbers by $1.</p>
<p>Brent CFDs were marginally easier with the balance of this week about one cent lower at -92/93 cents under August Brent. Further out there was evidence of more weakness with June 16-20 at -77 cents against August from -66 cents under August on Monday. June 23-27 was put at -67/68 (-64) while June 30-July 4 was assessed at -59 cents under August (-54).</p>
<p>The month of July traded at August -36 cents, June 16-20 went at July -50 cents and June 23-27 was concluded at July -38.</p>
<p>Heavy fuel swaps gained support from tight physical supplies and levels were about $1 a tonne stronger. June and July slipped in and out of contango and backwardation during the course of the day to end about 50 cents backwardated. June traded at $85.50 and 4Q went at $92.50.</p>
<p>Low sulphur swaps slipped about $1 since the physical market is not tight. June traded at $91.50 and $91.75, but there was little interest on July.</p>
<p>Attention on gasoline markets was directed towards wet deals where barges were done in a range of $188-193 with an early deal at $185. Dealers said barges had been hovering at $186-187 around lunchtime before jumping up on the back of a scramble to cover nominations.</p>
<p>June swaps were plugged around $189 with July at about $184. An August swap was concluded at $183.50.</p>
<p>Naphtha faced a slow market with swaps losing ground with June pegged at $179 and July about 25 to 50 cents backwardated.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8980</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
