<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="649260" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britons want govt to guarantee financial security.</title>
<headline>Britons want govt to guarantee financial security.</headline>
<byline>Gordon Mackenzie</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most Britons still want the government to guarantee their financial security and prefer state to private pensions, according to a survey to be published on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The 1997 Insurance Report, which polled 1,500 adults to assess consumer attitudes towards insurance, showed that a big majority were strongly in favour of keeping the welfare state.</p>
<p>&quot;Individuals typically say that the government should retain responsibility for most of the traditional areas of the welfare state. Indeed the majority are even likely to say they would welcome tax increases to pay for improved provision,&quot; the report from the Henley research centre and British-based Swiss Re(UK) said.</p>
<p>Asked who should take responsibility for making financial provision for a range of areas such as general or emergency medical care, income if unable to work and nursing care for the elderly, an average of more than 70 percent of the sample said the government should take responsibility.</p>
<p>&quot;The evidence shows that in many of those policy areas bearing directly on the insurance industry, Britain has been left of centre throughout the last eighteen years,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Only for dental care, income in retirement, and financial security of dependants was there any degree of support for the idea that responsibility should fall elsewhere.</p>
<p>Opinions were consistent across different demographic groups. The report added that in fact opinion on these issues appeared to have hardened.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible that the prospect of a general election and a possible change of government had led people to hold a more positive expectation of what a future government might do,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Britain's opposition Labour party swept to power with a landslide general election victory on May 1, ending 18 years of Conservative rule.</p>
<p>The survey said it detected a sense of disappointment with the previous government, particularly among older groups.</p>
<p>Maeve Geraghty, associate director of the Henley Centre told Reuters: &quot;This left of centre view that the government should provide these things (state guarantee of financial security) has been around for a long time, no matter who was in power.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Unless the new government builds bridges from the public to the private sector, there still remains a huge gulf for the public to leap which they haven't been prepared for,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
