<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="649395" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Klaus squeaks through vote on currency crisis.</title>
<headline>Klaus squeaks through vote on currency crisis.</headline>
<byline>Jan Lopatka</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus squeaked through a vote of confidence on Tuesday, winning endorsement of his rescue plan for the Czech Republic's hard pressed currency by promising parliament a say in key bank and utility privatisations.</p>
<p>In a dramatic vote, Klaus and his centre-right cabinet made the privatisation concession to win over a single independent deputy who added his vote to the 100 which the three coalition parties control in the 200-seat lower house.</p>
<p>Klaus had called for the confidence test on the cabinet's plans for budget cuts to counter an economic downturn and sharp depreciation in the Czech crown. If he had lost he would have been forced to resign.</p>
<p>The vote had seemed safe for Klaus when a Communist deputy, Miroslav Vacek, announced he was too ill to take part.</p>
<p>But Vacek showed up just before voting began, putting the onus for the government's survival on independent deputy Jozef Wagner, who is chairman of the budget committee. .</p>
<p>Wagner had his price -- demanding that the house get a say on privatisations of major banks and utilities proposed by the Finance Ministry.</p>
<p>Klaus rejected that demand just minutes before the vote -- then, when Vacek arrived, held a hasty meeting with Wagner and announced that the cabinet would submit the privatisations to the house.</p>
<p>The government's crisis economic plans will cut the 1997 budget by 20 billion crowns in an effort to check domestic demand and reduce a huge current account deficit.</p>
<p>Klaus, an economist, was the main architect of post-communist economic transformation but has been sharply criticised as the economy has soured.</p>
<p>The austerity package followed two turbulent weeks in the foreign exchange market when investors, alarmed at a widening current account gap and mounting political uncertainty, dumped the crown forcing the central bank to float the currency.</p>
<p>&quot;We should not forget that the Czech Republic was up to now considered an economically and politically stable country and that was a success for us all,&quot; Klaus told the house before the vote.</p>
<p>&quot;We should agree that it is in our national interest to preserve this credit, and never irreparably damage it or lose it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wagner was expelled from the opposition Social Democrats after he voted with the government and gave Klaus a narrow victory in approving the 1997 budget late last year.</p>
<p>He said after the Tuesday vote he was happy his manoeuvre effectively delayed the privatisation of Komercni Banka a.s. and Ceskovslovenska Obchodni Banka a.s. which was scheduled for discussion in Thursday's government agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;Clear divides between industrial companies and banks have to be sorted out and then the 'cleaned' companies could be privatised... otherwise I will not support the privatisation,&quot; Wagner told reporters after the vote.</p>
<p>Milos Zeman, leader of the main opposition Social Democrats, told the house before the vote that Klaus's government did not deserve trust.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to express my deep conviction that the basic factor of economic instability in the Czech Republic is the current government in its current personnel composition,&quot; Zeman said.</p>
<p>After winning the vote Klaus told the chamber: &quot;The government is ready to take on this work, knowing that it will not be applauded for everything it does now.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
