<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="649618" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Sparks LatAm unit to open branch in Sao Paulo.</title>
<headline>Sparks LatAm unit to open branch in Sao Paulo.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sparks America del Sur, the Latin American unit of Sparks Companies Inc, plans to open an office in Sao Paulo by the end of the year, Sparks America del Sur (SAS) vice-president Juan Rebolini said.</p>
<p>&quot;It has still not been decided (when the branch will open)...but we think it will be before the end of 1997,&quot; Rebolini told Reuters at an international seminar on agrobusiness.</p>
<p>The company, based in Buenos Aires, is currently interviewing Brazilian economists and elaborating a profile of its future operations here. Rebolini said it was too early to estimate how much it would be investing in the branch.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea is to cover all agricultural commodities, not only corn, wheat and soybeans but also chicken, pork, cattle as well as the whole area of sugar, coffee, cotton and rice,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sparks plans to employ at least four economists in the Sao Paulo bureau, which would be its second in Latin America. It was also studying opening a branch in Mexico, Rebolini said.</p>
<p>It is currently negotiating to transmit daily research reports to clients via local news agency Agencia do Estado's specialized AgroCast commodities news service.</p>
<p>&quot;The AgroCast deal has not been closed yet,&quot; said Rebolini. &quot;It wouldn't be the case that everyone who has access to AgroCast will have access to our information. (We plan to use it) as a means of direct access to clients.&quot;</p>
<p>The information would be directed at specific market sectors, mainly producers and industries without their own research facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a less sophisticated client who needs information to be more digested,&quot; Rebolini said.</p>
<p>Sparks' regular research documents and crop forecasts would continue to be transmitted via its traditional network, he added.</p>
<p>((--Joelle Diderich, Sao paulo newsroom +55 11 248 5417))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
