<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="649852" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Petronas eyes Texaco Burma stake, Texaco eyes image.</title>
<headline>Petronas eyes Texaco Burma stake, Texaco eyes image.</headline>
<byline>Raj Rajendran</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian national oil firm Petronas is studying the purchase of Texaco Inc's 42.9 percent stake in Burma's Yetagun gas field, president and chief executive Hassan Marican said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>If concluded, Texaco would be the latest U.S. company to withdraw from Burma amid protests by activists against the human rights record of Rangoon's ruling generals.</p>
<p>It would also be a blow to other U.S. oil companies, which are lobbying against sanctions imposed by Washington over alleged political repression, analysts said.</p>
<p>Texaco is the largest shareholder and operator of the Yetagun, which lies 125 miles off Burma's western coast in the Indian Ocean and has estimated gas reserves of one trillion cubic feet.</p>
<p>It is expected to start production in 1999 and has already secured a 30-year gas sales agreement with Thailand.</p>
<p>Marican said Texaco had appointed an investment banker to look for buyers of the U.S. oil giant's stake.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been approached by the investment banker. Yes, we are looking and studying the opportunity,&quot; he told reporters on the sidelines of an industry conference in Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>Texaco was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Texaco said in May it might sell the stake, citing financial reasons, rather than a response to human rights issues.</p>
<p>But analysts questioned the timing of Texaco's move, coming so soon after Washington announced sanctions.</p>
<p>&quot;You can look at the timing of it. The two issues are clearly linked,&quot; said Robin Shoemaker, oil and gas analyst at investment bank Lehman Brothers in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>But at the same time a withdrawal from Burma would clearly help boost Texaco's domestic U.S. image, which has suffered in the past year.</p>
<p>The company settled a racial discrimination suit for $115 million last year. It has also faced allegations of causing pollution to rainforests in Ecuador, which the company denies.</p>
<p>Burma protests added to the company's public image woes.</p>
<p>&quot;They are not affected by the sanctions, but they have faced a lot of pressure from lobbyists. It would help their U.S. image,&quot; said Gordon Kwan, oil and gas analyst at Daiwa Securities in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Texaco is expected to find several willing buyers apart from Petronas for its stake.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a highly attractive commercial proposition,&quot; said Shoemaker.</p>
<p>But Texaco's withdrawal from Burma could mean that the oil lobby working against sanctions would lose an influential member.</p>
<p>Unocal Corp, which has a 28 percent stake in the US$1.2 billion Yadana gas field, Texaco and Atlantic Richfield Co (ARCO) are the biggest oil investors in Burma.</p>
<p>They have argued that unilateral sanctions do not work and the best way to promote change is from within the country through investment.</p>
<p>But Shoemaker said that at the end of the day each company had its own agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;Each company has separate interests and have made their own determination as to what was in their own interests,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
