<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="649957" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. will back $13 million IFC loan to Croatia.</title>
<headline>U.S. will back $13 million IFC loan to Croatia.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States, despite much publicised threats to deny aid, will support a $13 million International Finance Corporation (IFC) loan to Croatia, the State Department said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Spokesman Nicholas Burns said Washington had decided to back the loan because of recent actions by Croatian President Franjo Tudjman that met human rights demands set down by Secretary of State Madeleine Albright.</p>
<p>&quot;We have decided not to block this very modest loan&quot; by the IFC, the private sector arm of the World Bank, Burns told reporters.</p>
<p>An IFC spokeswoman, Amy Conran, said the loan was not going to the Croatian government but to modernise a private Swiss-owned cement plant in the Croatian village of Koromacno. The IFC has 172 member countries.</p>
<p>Burns said Tudjman had met U.S. wishes by opening a long-closed bridge at Brcko between Croatia and Bosnia and ordering the arrest of several people suspected of brutalizing Serbs who tried to return to their pre-war homes in Croatia.</p>
<p>He added that Tudjman, on a campaign swing through Eastern Slavonia last weekend, had also publicly committed Croatia to inter-ethnic reconciliation and to making sure that Serbs had a place to live there.</p>
<p>Eastern Slavonia, a largely Serb-inhabited area of Croatia, was captured by Belgrade-backed Serb rebels after Croatia seceded from Yugoslavia in 1991 but will return to Zagreb's control next month.</p>
<p>&quot;Now that we've seen concrete positive steps, not just words, by the Croatian government and by Tudjman personally, surely we want to send a positive signal that this is the kind of action that will warrant support from the West,&quot; Burns said.</p>
<p>But he said that if Tudjman did not follow up on his commitments, the United States would act to block future loans and assistance, including a much larger World Bank loan on which action is expected at the end of the month.</p>
<p>Washington has warned both Croatia and Serbia that they will not get Western aid unless they improve their human rights performance and cooperate with a Bosnia war crimes tribunal based in The Hague.</p>
<p>Albright publicly upbraided Croatian Foreign Minister Mate Granic and other officials over the treatment of Serbs during a visit to Croatia at the end of last month.</p>
<p>&quot;I think you've got to give the secretary a little bit of credit for having produced this dramatic turnaround in Croatian government behaviour,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
