<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="650133" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Police arrest man in California triple murder.</title>
<headline>Police arrest man in California triple murder.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police on Tuesday arrested a man for allegedly killing his mother, a former girlfriend and her 11-month-old child in a bloody rampage in his California home.</p>
<p>Police said Issa Abujabar, 23, used a handgun in the San Francisco attacks late on Monday. He was taken into custody early on Tuesday and was charged with three counts of murder.</p>
<p>Police Lt. David Robinson said officers found blood throughout the house, where authorities believe Abujabar lived with his mother.</p>
<p>&quot;They found blood on the floors in every room and on some of the walls,&quot; Robinson said, adding that it was the worst crime scene he had ever seen.</p>
<p>Robinson said police have not determined the motive behind the attack. The suspect refused to talk to police. Reports said the shooting may have been part of a satanic ritual.</p>
<p>&quot;Abujabar stated to a witness that he was Lucifer,&quot; Robinson said. &quot;But we found no satanic items or indications of any satanic rituals.&quot;</p>
<p>The names of the three victims were not released.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
