<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="650215" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US adj retail sales up 2.3 pct w/e June 7-Redbook.</title>
<headline>US adj retail sales up 2.3 pct w/e June 7-Redbook.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. seasonally adjusted retail sales rose 2.3 percent in the first week of fiscal June versus May, according to the Lynch, Jones &amp; Ryan Inc Redbook Retail Sales Index.</p>
<p>The index rose 8.8 percent compared to the same month a year ago, the report said. Adjusted retail sales also climbed 8.8 percent in the week ended June 7, compared with the same week a year ago, it said.  </p>
<p>Retailers noted a pickup in business nationwide, as the long-awaited warmer weather attracted consumers towards seasonal goods, said Howard Eilenberg, a retail analyst at Redbook Research.</p>
<p>&quot;Discounters finally came around and sold (goods) that was on the shelves since early in the season,&quot; said Eilenberg in an interview with Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>&quot;(The customers) had the money, and they were waiting to buy... until the need arose,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Eilenberg said retail activity should pick up for the rest of June, citing benign weather and comparisons against softer sales registered in June 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;The comparisons against a year ago are rather easy,&quot; the Redbook Research analyst said, adding that shoppers, for many reasons, refrained from buying apparel goods last June.</p>
<p>The spending power that was held back in April and May, coupled with the easy year-ago comparisons, should boost sales in June, Eilenberg said. As a result, retailers may not have to adjust their sales plans as they had anticipated, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The markdowns won't be as steep as (retailers) thought, and therefore, they can make some money at it,&quot; Eilenberg added.</p>
<p>(( -- Jeff Coelho, 212-859-1562 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
