<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="650446" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Buba likely to discuss gold, leave rates steady.</title>
<headline>Buba likely to discuss gold, leave rates steady.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bundesbank is likely to leave rates steady and spend more time at its regular council meeting on Thursday reviewing Bonn's plans to revalue its reserves, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank will leave everything evenly balanced,&quot; predicted Michael Lewis, economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in London, referring to rates.</p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters echoed this, in a unanimous forecast that Germany's discount rate and Lombard rates would remain unchanged at 2.50 percent and 4.50 percent respectively.</p>
<p>They agreed the Bundesbank would keep its main money market rate fixed at three percent by offering the next two securities repurchase agreements at that level, having held money market rates at three percent for nearly one year.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank faced little pressure to alter monetary policy, economists said, citing moderate economic growth and inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>&quot;For interest rates, there are few changed conditions. The development of economic growth is reasonable and inflationary pressure remains in check,&quot; said Gertrud Traud, economist at Bank Julius Baer in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Additionally economists said the Bundesbank, keenly aware of the financial markets' focus on the proposed European currency union, would steer clear of sending wrong signals on that.</p>
<p>&quot;An interest rate rise now would signal the Bundesbank is blocking the currency union, and an interest rate cut would signal fiscal policy discipline is waning,&quot; said Stefan Bergheim, economist at Dresdner Kleinwort Benson in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>But more interesting than the expected decision on rates will be the Bundesbank's reaction to Bonn's blueprint to revalue German gold and currency assets, seen in its initial form as a ploy to plug fiscal holes and qualify for monetary union on time, economists said.</p>
<p>Clouds have been cast over Europe's single currency, scheduled to begin on January 1, 1999, as Germany struggles to meet entry criteria and France's new government pushes for more time to consider the issue.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank has said the revaluation issue will be discussed but has not said whether a statement may be released.</p>
<p>Talks between Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer and Finance Minister Theo Waigel last week signalled Bonn had backed off demanding a payout from the plan this year, and the central bank had backed off demands the revaluation be postponed until currency union starts.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Tietmeyer would never have agreed to any sort of compromise plans for which he would not have had the full support of the council,&quot; Joerg Kraemer, economist at Merrill Lynch in Frankfurt said.</p>
<p>Successful in uniting public opinion behind its stand on the gold row, the Bundesbank can claim victory in preventing Bonn from resorting to the creative accounting methods Germany had accused others of using.</p>
<p>As important, it succeeded in defending its independence against government meddling.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank can be satisfied with progress made on talks. It will consider Bonn's plans as long as it does not have to present an interim balance for the 1997 year,&quot; Ulrich Beckmann, Deutsche Bank Research economist said, referring to Bonn's efforts to obtain a payout this year.</p>
<p>Market reaction to any possible statement confirming no money will flow to the Bonn government this year would likely be muted, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;This news has already been priced in and so I expect there would be little reaction,&quot; Merrill's Kraemer said.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
