<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="650421" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU wheat tax on Fischler-Glickman agenda June 16.</title>
<headline>EU wheat tax on Fischler-Glickman agenda June 16.</headline>
<byline>Peter Blackburn</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>European wheat export taxes and labelling of gene-altered grain will be high on the agenda when EU Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler meets his U.S. counterpart Dan Glickman in Washington on June 16, EU sources said.</p>
<p>The United States disapproves of recent EU steps to save scarce wheat supplies for domestic consumers by slapping taxes on wheat exports made under a daily tendering system.</p>
<p>Washington argues that wheat export taxes distort trade and are as bad as export subsidies.</p>
<p>&quot;Glickman is likely to press for the speedy removal of the tax,&quot; said one EU source, noting however that the tax on soft wheat grain was cut to five ecus a tonne, from 15 ecus, in line with falling world prices.</p>
<p>A European Commission spokesman conceded Glickman would probably criticise the export tax when World Trade Organisation grain export limits were discussed.</p>
<p>Fischler is also likely to be quizzed on his draft proposal for compulsory labelling and segregation of genetically modified grain and other farm products throughout the production chain from seeds to foodstuffs sold in supermarkets.</p>
<p>The U.S. has argued that such action, which is aimed at meeting European consumer concern about food safety, is impractical and unnecessary because the genetically engineered products pose no risk to human health.</p>
<p>European biotech companies have been willing to voluntarily label their products in order to obtain EU approval but U.S. firms have been reluctant to do so.</p>
<p>On meat hormones, the European Commission has requested a review of a World Trade Organisation interim ruling that it unfairly banned imports of U.S. beef. A final ruling is expected at the end of June.</p>
<p>The EU, which banned imports of beef produced with synthetic growth hormones in 1988, says the move is based on sound science and is aimed at protecting public health.</p>
<p>During the half-day meeting Fischler is expected to sound out Glickman's view of holding a meeting of the world's five main farm trading nations -- U.S., EU, Canada, Japan and Australia -- in Europe in March 1998.</p>
<p>The meeting would provide an opportunity for a preliminary exchange of views ahead of the next round of WTO farm trade negotiations in 1999.</p>
<p>Other items expected to be discussed next week are U.S. concern about the increase in EU wheat gluten exports and U.S. problems with the management of the EU rice import tariff quota.</p>
<p>Continuing disagreement over poultry decontamination rules and U.S. steps to officially recognise that European livestock disease trade curbs can be applied regionally, instead of nationally, will also be discussed.</p>
<p>The two issues are hangovers from a recent agreementy on mutually acceptable veterinary inspection rules covering some $3 billion trade in red meat, dairy products, fish, eggs and pet food.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
