<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="650418" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Jaguar sees X200 pushing sales past 90,000 in 1999.</title>
<headline>Jaguar sees X200 pushing sales past 90,000 in 1999.</headline>
<byline>Neil Winton</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jaguar Cars Ltd expects its new smaller X200 model to spur sales on to over 90,000 in 1999, more than double last year's 40,000, chairman and chief executive Nick Scheele said Tuesday.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters, Scheele said the luxury car maker, now owned by Ford Motor Co, would spend more than $800 million on the move down market. Two years ago the company estimated it would spend $640 million on the new car.</p>
<p>Ford bought Jaguar for $2.5 billion in 1989.</p>
<p>The X200, which will be launched early in 1999, would be the smallest Jaguar ever produced and compete with middle range German marques like the BMW 5 series and the Mercedes E class.</p>
<p>Currently Jaguar produces the XJ6 saloon, and XK8 roadsters and coupes.</p>
<p>Scheele said Jaguar would not reveal yet the range of engines that would be available for the X200.</p>
<p>&quot;All I can say is that it will be class-leading, instantly desirable and incorporate the latest technology,&quot; Scheele said.</p>
<p>Jaguar will build the X200 at its new plant at Castle Bromwich in the West Midlands. Ford persuaded Britain to present Jaguar with aid totalling $108.2 million to build the plant, after it warned that it might build it in the U.S.</p>
<p>Scheele said Jaguar had made great progress in recent years and was now profitable, although he declined to give details.</p>
<p>Scheele said Jaguar had made great strides in improving quality.</p>
<p>&quot;It wasn't that long ago that in a U.S. J.D.Power survey we came 34th out of 35, edged out of last place by that great bastion of quality, Yugo cars,&quot; Scheele said.</p>
<p>&quot;The latest data shows us in eighth place. That's good but we want to be number one,&quot; Scheele said.</p>
<p>Would Jaguar extend its range and introduce a smaller car?</p>
<p>&quot;We don't have any plans right now but wouldn't rule it out. But we won't be building any sport utility vehicles, multi-purpose vehicles or city cars,&quot; Scheele said answering questions after making a speech to the Automotive News Europe conference.</p>
<p>Scheele wouldn't rule out the possibility of building cars in the future outside Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;BMW and Mercedes have shown that you can build outside your home base. Whether we will or not only time will tell,&quot; Scheele said.</p>
<p>Neil Winton 44-171-542-7975 neil@jinks.demon.co.uk</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
