<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="650729" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: NATL MORTGAGE BANK TO REFINANCE MORTGAGES.</title>
<headline>NATL MORTGAGE BANK TO REFINANCE MORTGAGES.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greece's National Mortgage Bank will refinance outstanding mortgage loans and will introduce new mortgage and consumer credit-related products, it said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision to refinance outstanding mortgage loans at lower rates is aimed at helping clients who took out a fixed-rate mortgages at times when floating rate notes were not available,&quot; the bank said in a statement.</p>
<p>National Mortgage, Greece's largest player in mortgage loans and a subsidiary of National Bank , will refinance oustanding loans at lower rates, also embarking on a new repayment schedule, as long as they are properly serviced at the time refinancing is applied for, it said.</p>
<p>Loans taken out before end-1989 will be refinanced immediately, followed in 1998 by loans secured in the early 1990s.</p>
<p>The bank will apply its going floating rates, offering a choice of monthly or semi-annual payments, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our new approach seeks to reward good customers and expand our business relations to other products, besides mortgage loans, to boost client loyalty,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>To this extent, the bank will apply a 'bonus' on good customers and attempt to cross-sell consumer credit and insurance products, it said.</p>
<p>The bank is introducing new medium-term mortgage loans with a combination of fixed- and floating-rate periods at rates below 11.5 percent.</p>
<p>It will also launch mortgage products priced at the bank's base monthly borrowing rate which closely follows the one-month Athibor. There will be a minimum 3.0 percent add-on.</p>
<p>National Mortgage will also offer full mortgage financing to investors in its mutual funds and rate cuts up to 4.0 percent on credit cards and personal loans to clients making use of a combination of the bank's consumer credit products. --Angelos Kiosklis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
