<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="650857" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT -T-bonds to remain positive above 110-12.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT -T-bonds to remain positive above 110-12.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>September T-bond futures will maintain their buoyant stance on Friday provided the contract can hold above 110-12, technical analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;T-bonds had a quiet, slightly reactive, day on Monday to the powerful day on Friday,&quot; said Adrian Sells, director at Crane Analysis in London. &quot;We're still pretty positive on it as long as we don't start to get back below the 110-12 area, which is around 50 percent of the range on Friday.&quot;</p>
<p>Friday's contract range stretched from 109-15 to 111-09, after the market rallied sharply on the back of weak U.S. employment data.</p>
<p>At 0945 GMT, September T-bond futures were at 110-22 in automated trade, up 3/32 on the day.</p>
<p>Sells said while he did not envisage a deeper correction, a concerted break below 110-12 could take the contract down to below 110-00.</p>
<p>Donna Liu, technical analyst at DKB International in London, noted some initial support from a 38.2 percent Fibonacci retracement of Friday's range at 110-19.</p>
<p>&quot;Yesterday the market closed just below the 200-day moving average at 110-19. This was a considerable negative but last Friday's volumes were so huge and open interest was up around 42,000 to 43,000 that...buying pressure will still remain,&quot; she said, adding that for the near term she remained positive on T-bonds.</p>
<p>To the upside, Sells said the contract would face an initial hurdle in the 111-08 area.</p>
<p>&quot;It would have to break out of those 111-08, 09 highs we saw yesterday and on Friday in order to re-accelerate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Liu saw resistance at 111-11. That is the current level on a trendline drawn through the May 2 109-29 high, the May 13 109-12 high and the high on Friday.</p>
<p>Above there a further barrier is offered at 111-18, retracing part of the decline from mid-February to mid-April.</p>
<p>&quot;That's a 76.4 percent retracement from 113-09 to 105-30,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>At the short end, September Eurodollars were at 94.030, unchanged on the day. December Eurodollars were quoted at 93.820, also unchanged.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
