<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="650875" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British watchdog plans petrol price war review.</title>
<headline>British watchdog plans petrol price war review.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>British business watchdog the Office of Fair Trading (OFT) said on Tuesday it would shortly launch a review of allegations that a petrol price war was driving independent gasoline retailers out of business.</p>
<p>&quot;We are expecting to announce such a review shortly,&quot; OFT spokesman Terry Larkin told Reuters, adding this could mean an announcement within one or two weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;Independent petrol retailers have complained that they are being squeezed between the price cutting by the big petrol firms and the supermarkets.&quot;</p>
<p>Nearly 10 percent, or 1,500, petrol stations closed in the U.K. last year as the cut-throat struggle squeezed margins and pump prices fell to the lowest in Europe.</p>
<p>A pledge by Esso, a unit of U.S. oil giant Exxon Corp, early last year to match its lowest-priced competitor as part of its Pricewatch campaign was a bonus for motorists, keeping U.K. pump prices the lowest in Europe.</p>
<p>But margins were squeezed to break-even levels at the height of the price war last summer, forcing the higher-cost independent retailers out of business.</p>
<p>British petrol stations selling the Esso brand have protested against Pricewatch.</p>
<p>&quot;The retailers feel that they are being unreasonably exploited by Esso and that the capital investments put into their businesses will be wiped out with the consequent loss of their livelihoods,&quot; the Esso Licensed Retailers Association said in a statement in May.</p>
<p>Larkin said the OFT had no powers to force companies to change their strategies but it could recommend that that commercial regulator the Monopolies and Mergers Commmission study whether the market was being distorted.</p>
<p>Consumer Affairs Minister Nigel Griffiths has said he would wait for the OFT's advice before considering taking any action to curb predatory petrol pricing.</p>
<p>Analysts have said that while Pricewatch may have been intended to narrow price differentials between filling stations, it may actually increase the price variances between rural and urban areas.</p>
<p>The association has already filed a complaint against Esso with the European Commission and Parliamentary hearings last year in the U.K. which examined whether motorists were enjoying unrealistically low petrol prices and whether the industry needed to be regulated.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
