<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="650900" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey money market report.</title>
<headline>Turkey money market report.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The market opened 18.1 trillion lira long on Tuesday, causing the average overnight money rate to fall to 67.20 percent from Monday's 71.45 percent.</p>
<p>But the central bank lent 25.2 trillion lira at 69 percent via tmrw/next and 400 billion at 70 percent via tmrw/week to meet expected cash shortage for Wednesday.</p>
<p>The average overnight repo rate rose to 72.97 percent from Monday's 69.65 percent on intra-day cash demand as the repo market closed two hours earlier than the money market, bankers said.</p>
<p>They said the average annual cost of funding in bonds increased to 107 percent based on the average overnight repo rate of 72.97 percent, but bond yields firmed slightly to around 103 percent from Monday's 102.60-102.80 percent levels.</p>
<p>&quot;Market maker banks with heavy bond portfolios dominate bond trade and do not allow the yields to move outside the 100-105 percent range,&quot; said one banker.</p>
<p>He said the most heavily traded papers -- April 22 and 29, 1998 -- were mostly held in the portfolios of one or two banks.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore today's sales cannot be considered as part of a trend. The yields moved in a narrow range because the market is still depressed by political uncertainty,&quot; they added.</p>
<p>The April 22, 1998 paper yielded 103.09 percent, up 0.24 percentage points from Monday. Volume in others were negligable.</p>
<p>Private investors and some banks whose paper portfolios diminished due to maturing bonds, began to show interest in two-year, inflation-indexed bonds issued since the beginning of April, bankers said.</p>
<p>Demand mostly focused on the last two-year bond issued by the Treasury in an auction on June 3 at 32 percent risk premium, up sharply from the previous auctions.</p>
<p>The Turkish lira eased to 143,200 against the dollar, compared to Monday's 142,980 close in line with the dollar/mark parity.</p>
<p>-- Istanbul newsroom +90-212-275 0875.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
