<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="650928" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Iran to replace old tanker fleet, buys from Daewoo.</title>
<headline>Iran to replace old tanker fleet, buys from Daewoo.</headline>
<byline>Steven Swindells</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran's state-owned National Iranian Tanker Company (NITC) is moving quickly to buy new oil tankers to replace its ageing fleet, Iranian and Gulf shipping sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>NITC has awarded a contract to South Korea's Daewoo Heavy Industries Co for five 158,000-tonne Suezmax type oil tankers and will award a contract for five more 100,000-tonne Aframax tankers in the next two months, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The first Suezmax cargo will arrive within 27 months and each of the other four will be delivered every 45 days after that,&quot; NITC chairman Mohammad Souri told Reuters.</p>
<p>A contract for Aframax tankers -- which will be mainly used to supply Iranian crude to the country's new refinery at Bandar Abbas -- was planned to be awarded within two months, he added.</p>
<p>NITC aims to buy five oil product carriers and five Very Large Crude Carriers (VLCC) after the Aframax purchases.</p>
<p>A Daewoo spokesman in Seoul on Tuesday said its Suezmax contract, which will take oil produced by the National Iranian Oil Co (NIOC) to Mediterranean markets, was worth $300 million.</p>
<p>Souri estimated that each of the Aframax cargoes would be worth around $40 million.</p>
<p>NITC has secured new tankers to replace its fleet much of which pre-dated the country's 1979 Islamic revolution. NITC has scrapped 15 of its tankers in recent years, reducing its own fleet to 11 crude tankers and nine product tankers.</p>
<p>This has frequently forced NITC to spend scarce hard currency to time-charter vessels from the international spot market to transport oil to Iran's main export markets in Asia, Europe and the Americas, shipping sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;Their fleet was simply rusting or becoming dangerous...They suffered from breakdowns and high costs so the time came when they simply had to buy new,&quot; said a Gulf shipping source.</p>
<p>NITC, a wholly owned subsidiary of NIOC, is responsible for exporting some 950,000 barrels per day (bpd) of Iran's 2.6 million bpd crude exports on a &quot;delivered&quot; or charge, insurance and freight (cif) basis.</p>
<p>It also time charters its own VLCCs in the spot market.</p>
<p>Iran is the world's third largest oil exporter behind Saudi Arabia and Norway and is heavily reliant on the $18 billion a year that oil revenues brings to the country.</p>
<p>Daewoo supplied NITC with five 300,000-tonne VLCCs in 1996.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
