<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="651165" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian IPSO-ILG aims to clean up on world market.</title>
<headline>Belgian IPSO-ILG aims to clean up on world market.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Industrial washing machine manufacturer IPSO-International Laundry Group aims to build on its world number three position when it floats some 51 percent of itself on the Brussels bourse later this month.</p>
<p>IPSO-ILG does not sell domestic appliances and is therefore not be a household name like its major competitors Electrolux and Raytheon, chief executive officer Eddy Coppieters told a promotional roadshow on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Instead it concentrates on using its world wide web of exclusive distributorships to push its products into sectors ranging from launderettes to hotels, hospitals, prisons and contract launderers, a market estimated at $1.2 billion a year.</p>
<p>&quot;IPSO-ILG is one of the most important producers of industrial washing machines and dryers in the world,&quot; Coppieters told the roadshow, entitled &quot;Wash and Grow&quot;. &quot;No competitor has such a focused product range&quot;.</p>
<p>Among some of its higher profile clients he named British soccer team Manchester United, French soccer team Paris St Germain and the Hilton Hotel in Mecca.</p>
<p>IPSO has managed to spin impressive growth both by manufacture and the acquisition in 1993 of Belgium's D'Hooge and in 1994 of Cissell of the United States since it was created in northern Belgium in 1973.</p>
<p>IPSO-ILG was formed in April last year to bring together the three complementary prongs.</p>
<p>IPSO itself makes washing machines capable of carrying loads of between five and 57 kg. D'Hooge's range goes from 20 to 300 kg and Cissell makes a full range of dryers, ironers and finishing equipment.</p>
<p>On a proforma basis turnover has remained fairly steady at around 2.5 billion francs a year between 1993/94 and 1995/96, while net current profit has risen from 101 million francs to 152 million francs.</p>
<p>It is forecast to hit 175 million francs in the year to July 31, 1997.</p>
<p>IPSO accounts for about 44 percent of the turnover, with Cissell contributing 42 percent and D'Hooge 14 percent.</p>
<p>The group will float 960,000 shares representing 48 percent of its two million existing shares, as well as issuing 120,000 new shares or which 100,000 are earmarked for institutions and 20,000 for employees.</p>
<p>There is a green shoe of 100,000 shares held jointly by lead manager Generale de Banque and co-lead manager Petercam.</p>
<p>Book building opens on June 11 and the introduction price will be announced on June 14. There is a price fork of 1,350 francs to 1,500 francs.</p>
<p>The public offer will run from June 16 to June 20 at the latest and the shares will be listed on the bourse from June 27.</p>
<p>Institutions are expected to take 60 percent of the shares, with the general public taking the remainder.</p>
<p>&quot;IPSO-ILG has outstanding prospects. It has a unique market position and potential to expand,&quot; Marc Moonens, corporate research manager of Generale de Banque, told the roadshow.</p>
<p>He said that on a dividend discount model the shares were worth 1,592 francs each, while on a discounted free cash flow model their value was 1,533 francs.</p>
<p>On a bourse ratio they were worth between 1,429 and 1,537 francs, while on a sector comparison basis the value was between 1,345 and 1,550 francs.</p>
<p>($ = 35.35 Belgian francs)</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6836, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
