<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="651134" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany will not meet EMU criteria - FDPs Lambsdorff.</title>
<headline>Germany will not meet EMU criteria - FDPs Lambsdorff.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leader of the Free Democrats (FDP) said on Tuesday Chancellor Helmut Kohl and Finance Minister Theo Waigel should face up to the fact Germany will not be fulfill the Maastricht criteria for monetary union in 1997.</p>
<p>Otto Lambsdorff, a former economics minister and honourary chairman of Kohl's junior coalition partner, said he saw little chance that Germany would be able to hold its budget deficit this year to three percent of gross domestic product (GDP).</p>
<p>&quot;One day the finance minister is going to have to back down from his position of 3.0 percent,&quot; Lambsdorff said, referring to Waigel's view that Germany must keep its deficit at or below that level in order to qualify for the euro.</p>
<p>&quot;I have always thought it was odd from an economics point of view to cling firmly to that number.&quot;</p>
<p>Lambsdorff, joining a chorus of coalition figures urging Waigel to take a more relaxed view on the criteria for European economic and monetary union (EMU), said that the EMU should move ahead as long as Germany can limit its deficit to 3.3 percent of GDP or less.</p>
<p>He said the government should raise borrowing for 1997 in order to resolve the row in the coalition over new budget holes.</p>
<p>&quot;If the tax revenues are down because of a weaker economy, it would be wrong to worsen the situation with addition taxes,&quot; Lambsdorff said.</p>
<p>He said the FDP has no interest in ending the coalition and added Kohl's Christian Democrats know that there can be no tax increases.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
