<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="651219" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek stocks firm 0.88pct on upbeat OTE.</title>
<headline>Greek stocks firm 0.88pct on upbeat OTE.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek shares advanced 0.88 percent in quiet trading on Tuesday, clearing the 1,600 level and brokers said the broader market reflected a strong performance in OTE shares, currently going through a part-flotation procedure.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was pulled higher by OTE which returned to the limelight today,&quot; said Mathios Doulos, a broker at Kyranis Securities.</p>
<p>Buying interest in the stock rose on rumours of satisfactory coverage by international institutionals of its privately placed tranche, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;OTE dominated the scene today as some investors opted for direct purchase of OTE's shares from the bourse on early indications of a high oversubscription rate which would lower their allotments,&quot; said Nick Soulimiotis, broker at Pentedekas Securities.</p>
<p>Eased pressure on Alpha Credit also helped enliven the market, he added.</p>
<p>The book-building process for the private placement of state telecom OTE with international investors ends June 11.</p>
<p>It will be followed by a public offering 200 drachmas below the final book-building strike price.</p>
<p>Subscriptions to the public tranche will last between June 11-13 with an indicative price range to be announced later on Tuesday by lead underwriter and global coordinator National Bank.</p>
<p>The relative success of OTE's private placement and public subscription will determine the market's short-term direction, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will be delighted to see a over-subscription rate in excess of two or three times,&quot; said Soulimiotis.</p>
<p>The market was seen moving sideways for the rest of the week with investors remaining sidelined due to a temporary drop in liquidity caused by OTE's subscription.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will remain stagnant for a few days because OTE's subscriptions have drained considerable liquidity, resulting in lower trading volumes,&quot; said Doulos.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will remain rangebound in the 1,600 vicinity while subscriptions for OTE's part-flotation are running and cash is locked in bank accounts,&quot; said Soulimiotis.</p>
<p>The Athens general index added 0.88 percent or 14.05 points to close at 1,603.84 from Monday's 1,589.79, having peaked at 1,614.72 in early deals.</p>
<p>Banks led the market with a 0.95 percent climb. Industrials were mixed rising 0.13 percent while construction slipped 0.51 percent.</p>
<p>Turnover was subdued at 13.4 billion drachmas with only 3.4 million shares being traded.</p>
<p>Advancers led decliners 113 to 104 with 25 shares unchanged on 242 traded.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
