<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="651335" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: By Tim Farrand.</title>
<headline>By Tim Farrand.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>British food and dairy company Northern Foods will raise its investment by some 35 million stg in the coming year to improve productivity, mainly in its prepared foods division, said chairman Christopher Haskins on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Haskins also said he expected Britain's dairy industry to undergo large scale consolidation as some of Northern's competitors were losing money and there remained serious overcapacity in the industry.</p>
<p>&quot;Three dairies have gone bust in the last twelve months. There's the Waterford and Avonmore merger in Ireland and we bought a UHT plant from Scottish Pride,&quot; said Haskins.</p>
<p>&quot;We think one or two of our competitors are losing money and that can't last,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>There remains intense pressure on dairy companies from supermarkets for lower milk prices such that if they are able to agree more favourable terms with farmers, that saving is absorbed by the retailers.</p>
<p>Northern, Unigate and Dairy Crest have also been squeezed by the collapse in world commodity prices in the last year.</p>
<p>Dairy companies produce large quantities of semi-skimmed and skimmed liquid milk of which butter fat is a by-product. Butter fat prices on world commodity markets have fallen sharply over the last year partly due the absence of heavy Russian buying in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Northern reported earlier a 26 percent drop in profits from its dairy division to 44.8 million for 1996/97 due to the 17 million stg impact of lower commodity prices.</p>
<p>If approved, the merger of Ireland's Waterford Foods and Avonmore Foods Plc  will create the largest dairy company in Britain and Ireland and the fourth largest milk processor in the world.</p>
<p>&quot;There are dairy mergers going on world-wide -- in Australia, New Zealand, Holland and France, it's happening all over the world as there is too much capacity and everyone is getting on with sorting it out,&quot; Haskins said.</p>
<p>In Britain a four pint bottle of milk from the supermarket costs about 85p or 22p a pint, some 2p cheaper a pint than last year. A pint delivered to the doorstep can cost as much as 40p in London.</p>
<p>However, dairy companies are now more optimistic about their doorstep delivery business, where the rate of decline has slowed, after plummeting in the previous two years.</p>
<p>Northern planned to raise its investment programme in 1997/98 now that the management focus on shutting dairies and re-shaping its doorstep delivery business is complete, said Haskins.</p>
<p>Most of the investment will be directed at prepared foods, where Northern has factories producing ready made foods like pies and sandwiches for Marks and Spencer Plc, worth 300 million stg in sales a year.</p>
<p>&quot;Food is cheaper now than a year ago and competition among supermarkets is still pretty heavy, so our main gains are coming through improved productivity,&quot; said Haskins.</p>
<p>&quot;We are investing heavily in productivity, improving the quality and consistency of products and lowering the cost of production,&quot; said Haskins.</p>
<p>Earlier, Northern Foods reported a modest 2.3 percent increase in its profit before tax and exceptional items to 127.1 million stg for the year ended March 31, 1997.</p>
<p>Its shares were 3-1/2p higher at 206p in early trade.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 6437</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
