<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="651358" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Severn boosts with profits, buyback.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Severn boosts with profits, buyback.</headline>
<byline>Jo Winterbottom</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>British water and sewerage company Severn Trent Plc turned in a rise in year pretax profits and dividend on Tuesday and boosted shares with plans to complete a share buyback announced last year.</p>
<p>Severn Trent said year pretax profits rose to 391 million pounds ($639.3 million) from 373 million previously before an exceptional charge of 20 million for restructuring, and paid out a dividend of 36.5 pence per share compared with 32.37 pence.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no surprises in there. But the profits were above some people's forecasts, and they also announced they were completing their share buyback,&quot; said Simon Champion, analyst at Charterhouse Tilney.</p>
<p>Severn Trent's shares were up 4.5 pence by 0835 GMT at 774.5 pence, off a high of 778 pence.</p>
<p>The company said last year that it would buy back up to 10 percent of its shares after its plans to buy South West Water last year were blocked by the then Conservative government.</p>
<p>It bought 5.6 percent of its shares in December and said on Tuesday it would seek approval for the remainder of the buyback at its annual meeting in July.</p>
<p>Finance director Alan Costin said the buyback should raise gearing to around 35 percent from current levels of 27.4 percent, with interest cover at six times.</p>
<p>The company said in a statement with results that strategy would focus on building a world-class water services organisation, looking for opportunities for profitable growth in the waste industry and expanding its presence in selected markets for utility related services.</p>
<p>Chief executive Vic Cocker told Reuters that non-regulated activities, such as the group's waste management arm Biffa, contributed some 42 percent of the growth in operating profits during the year.</p>
<p>He said profits in non-regulated activities had grown 28 percent in the year and the company aimed to see 20 percent growth per year in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly we should be able to grow them at 20 percent per year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said in waste management, the focus was on organic growth but the company would look at small to medium-sized acquisitions.</p>
<p>Non-regulated activities accounted for around 30-40 percent of the rise in the dividend of 12.8 percent, Cocker said.</p>
<p>Water companies, which are reporting annual results at the moment, have come under pressure from regulator Ofwat for apparently hefty dividends and the new Labour government has also been critical.</p>
<p>It has vowed to introduce a one-off tax on the excess profits of privatised utilities as a central plank of its first budget on July 2.</p>
<p>The government has also drawn up a 10-point plan, including mandatory targets to cut leakage, for companies aimed at tackling the country's current drought.</p>
<p>Cocker said Severn Trent had cut leakage to 16 percent and was on target to reach 12 percent by 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;We're committed to achieving 12 percent by 2000 and we're already at 16, a year ahead of...targets that were agreed with Ofwat, so we feel we're well on track to achieve what has been promised,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the company had also started offering a free repair service for leaks on the pipes of customers, in line with proposals in the government's 10-point plan.</p>
<p>On the so-called windfall tax, Cocker said the company had made a submission to the government, emphasising &quot;the need to think in the long term about the need for investment in the industry.&quot;</p>
<p>Severn had also stressed the need &quot;to take into account those companies who, like us, have made rebates (to customers),&quot; Cocker said.</p>
<p>On Monday, multi-utility Hyder Plc said it felt rebates and extra investment should be taken into account in allocating the windfall tax and suggested the best approach to achieve this would be a levy based on turnover or operating profit.</p>
<p>($ = 0.611 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
