<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="651461" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian bonds stay firm, underpinned by job ads.</title>
<headline>Australian bonds stay firm, underpinned by job ads.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>----------(Snapshot at 12.05 P.M./0205 GMT)-----------------</p>
<p>FUTURES					  CASH YIELD</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS  (JUN) 94.59  (UNCH)	5.46    (- 0.01)</p>
<p>3-YR T-BONDS  (JUN) 93.88  (+ 0.05)    6.11    (- 0.04)</p>
<p>10-YR T-BONDS (JUN) 92.755 (+0.075)    7.25    (- 0.08)</p>
<p>AUD/USD  0.7605 (PREV 0.7591) US 30-YR 6.82    (6.82 NY)</p>
<p>---------------------(June 10)------------------------------</p>
<p>*Australian bond prices kept to a tight trading range after an initial sharp mark-up following the gyrations in U.S. Treasuries either side of the weekend.</p>
<p>*ANZ job advertisements fall 7.3 percent in May.  </p>
<p>Australian bond prices kept to a tight trading range after an initial sharp mark-up following the gyrations in U.S. Treasuries either side of the weekend.</p>
<p>Yields were trading just above the lows seen in after-hours trading on Friday. Monday's session in U.S. Treasuries was easier and put a cap on Friday's U.S.-led local rally as the market awaited this week's major local data.</p>
<p>The local market was closed on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The key has to be this Thursday's employment numbers, and if they are weak, the short-end is going to get another lift,&quot; one trader at a European bank based in Sydney said.  </p>
<p>A prelude to the data was today's monthly ANZ job advertisement series which recorded a seasonally adjusted 7.3 percent fall in May.</p>
<p>ANZ chief economist Saul Eslake described the fall as a payback to the articially large 16.7 percent rise in April which was inflated by the earlier timing of Easter.</p>
<p>He said the trend in job advertising over the past few months was consistent with net new job creation averaging around 14,000 per month over the next three months, an improvement on the 6,100 per month recorded over the first four months of 1997.  </p>
<p>&quot;The pace of net new job creation would then need to step up to an average of around 19,000 per month between August and June 1998 to meet the government's Budget forecast of two percent employment growth in 1997/98 as a whole,&quot; Eslake added.</p>
<p>Before the official employment data on Thursday, the market sees housing finance for April on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Economists' median forecasts centre on a hefty 12 percent rise, but the key issue will be how much of this is made up of new mortgages against mortgage refinancings.  </p>
<p>---------------------(SPREADS)---------------------------------</p>
<p> AUD VS   3-YR	   10-YR	* AUD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p> USD	-19 (- 02)    71 (- 01) * FUTURES   113   (- 01)</p>
<p> CAD	106 (- 06)    88 (+ 05) * CASH	115   (- 01)</p>
<p> NZD	-95 (- 12)   -06 (- 10) *</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The local market showed a narrowing bias to the dollar bloc, although it was outpaced by the long end of the Canadian curve.</p>
<p>The yield curve flattened slightly as the long-end benefitted more from the net advance in U.S. Treasuries either side of the weekend.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
