<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="651536" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - June 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - June 10.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Chinese political and business stories in leading newspapers, prepared by Reuters in Beijing. Reuters has not checked the stories and does not guarantee their accuracy. Telephone: (8610) 6532-1921. Fax: (8610) 6532-4978.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PEOPLE'S DAILY</p>
<p>- China hopes all parties of former Yugoslavia can continue with patient negotiations to solve remaining problems among themselves, President Jiang Zemin tells visiting Macedonian President Kiro Gligorov.</p>
<p>- Frontpage story summarises experience of 10 state-owned enterprises that successfully launched reform and are regarded as models for China's other state-owned enterprises.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>XINHUA DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>- Premier Li Peng tells visiting Japanese Minister of International Trade and Industry Shinji Sato that relations can have healthy, steady and lasting development so long as two sides abide by principles in joint statement and treaty of peace and friendship and handle the development direction of bilateral ties from a long-term and strategic perspective.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BEIJING DAILY</p>
<p>- Survey shows 36 percent of ice cream is below standard</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FINANCIAL NEWS</p>
<p>- Central bank governor Dai Xianglong stresses need to control financial risk in China's banking system</p>
<p>- Guangzhou International Trust and Investment Co wins foreign exchange business licence</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA SECURITIES</p>
<p>- State-owned architectural enterprises show 700 milloin yuan losses in first quarter</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BEIJING ECONOMIC DAILY</p>
<p>- Beijing banks complete sales of 11.46 billion yuan of treasury bonds by end-May, completing local quota</p>
<p>- China output of mobile phones seen at 1.5 million, pagers seen at 4.0 million</p>
<p>- China production of personal computers seen at 1.5 million sets in 1996</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FINANCIAL MORNING POST</p>
<p>- Legend sales of computers reach 67,000 in first quarter, up 141 percent, sales in April-May at 68,000.</p>
<p>- Legend mulls asset injection to listed company in Hong Kong, awaits official approval</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA DAILY</p>
<p>- Official cites facts to refute some Western slanders against freedom of religious belief in China</p>
<p>- Seventeen people arrive in Beijing's Tiananmen Square after 2,850-km walk from Hong Kong.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
