<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="651582" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan to allow mobile phone roaming in China.</title>
<headline>Taiwan to allow mobile phone roaming in China.</headline>
<byline>Lawrence Chung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan will permit customers to use their mobile telephones in China from July, modestly easing a ban on direct telecommunications with the rival communist mainland, telecom officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Officials denied that adding the mainland to Taiwan's &quot;international roaming&quot; network was a change of Taipei's policy of no direct contacts with China, saying such connections were still not being switched directly across the Taiwan strait.</p>
<p>&quot;All call connections still must be routed through either Hong Kong and Japan to uphold the government ban on direct links with the mainland,&quot; said a spokeswoman for state-owned Chung Hwa Telecom, Taiwan's main telephone company.</p>
<p>Taiwan's Nationalist Republic of China has imposed the ban since 1949, when it was defeated by the Chinese communists on the mainland and driven into exile.</p>
<p>Pressure to ease the ban has soared since the late 1980s, when Taiwan began allowing unofficial mainland contacts and business ties.</p>
<p>Taiwan investors, who have poured US$30 billion into China, say prohibiting direct telecommunications, shipping and aviation puts them at a competitive disadvantage by forcing them to spend needlessly to route business through Hong Kong.</p>
<p>The mobile phone liberalisation will bring great convenience to the 600,000 users of Chung Hwa's digital GSM handphones, enabling them to make calls even from remote corners of the Chinese mainland -- as long as those areas offer local GSM service.</p>
<p>Convenience will have its cost, the spokewoman added.</p>
<p>&quot;The cost will be about twice that of ordinary long-distance fees due to mainland China's high phone charges,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The liberalisation brings mobile telephone links into line with fixed-line service. Though ordinary long-distance calls appear to the caller to pass directly between Taiwan and China, the signals actually are patched indirectly through Hong Kong, Singapore or even as far away as the United States.</p>
<p>Chung Hwa said Hong Kong Telecommunications Ltd, acting as a go-between, brokered a tacit agreement with China's state-run telecom system for operation of the roaming service.</p>
<p>Chung Hwa said Hong Kong Telecom would serve as a middleman for payments and fund transfers between the rivals, which have not been on speaking terms since mid-1995 when Beijing broke off quasi-official talks.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman acknowledged that Taiwan-China calls &quot;would be a lot cheaper if the government permitted direct phone links, since they no longer would need to go through a third area&quot;.</p>
<p>Taipei has signed international roaming service agreements with 24 countries and areas, including Singapore and Hong Kong, allowing Taiwan customers to use their mobile phones there.</p>
<p>Taiwan is seeking to sign agreements with the United States and Russia, the officials said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
