<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="651651" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Toshiba to develop chip to ease Internet access.</title>
<headline>Toshiba to develop chip to ease Internet access.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toshiba Corp said on Tuesday it plans to develop a chip that will make it easier to link various electronic products, including mobile phones, televisions and facsimile machines, to the Internet.</p>
<p>The firm said that it has licensed technology from iReady Corp of the United States that can be easily integrated with the functions of consumer electronics products.</p>
<p>&quot;Incorporating this technology in electronics devices, such as mobile phones, for example, makes them Internet-ready at only a small incremental cost and gives users easy wireless access to the Internet for e-mail and other information,&quot; Toshiba said in a statement.</p>
<p>If installed in a facsimile machine, users would be able to directly fax information from the Internet through the fax machine, a Toshiba spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>It would be possible to view information and images from the Internet on televisions equipped with the chip, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;This technology agreement allows Toshiba to move forward aggressively in development of a new generation of Internet-ready consumer electronics products,&quot; said Tadatoshi Minamikawa, general manager of Toshiba's LSI planning division.</p>
<p>Toshiba said it would develop the technology as the core of its application-specific integrated circuits (ASIC) products and introduce it to the world market.</p>
<p>Based in San Jose, California, iReady was founded in January 1996 as a provider of technology in the form of intellectual property.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
