<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="65165" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Dissident says Saudi Arabia may need military rule.</title>
<headline>Dissident says Saudi Arabia may need military rule.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi dissident Mohammad al-Masari said in an interview released on Thursday that Saudi Arabia might benefit from a military dictatorship as a temporary stage between corrupt monarchy and constitutional government.</p>
<p>&quot;Military dictatorships are not generally a positive thing, but in Saudi Arabia's case it might be a necessary transitional period. The new generation of army officers are reform-minded... It would be the middle classes' day,&quot; he told the regional weekly newspaper the Middle East Times.</p>
<p>The newspaper had planned to print the interview in this week's edition but Egyptian government censors said in advance they would not let the edition into the country. The newspaper made a copy of the interview available to Reuters.</p>
<p>Masari, head of the Committee for the Defence of Legitimate Rights in exile in London, has achieved fame as an irritant in Saudi-British relations. The British government decided to deport him to Dominica but the courts overruled the decision.</p>
<p>In the interview he said he saw no prospect of the Saudi royal family reforming itself and its best bet was for the dominant Sudairi group to let Crown Prince Abdullah bin Abdul-Aziz succeed King Fahd, who has been seriously ill.</p>
<p>The seven Sudairis, sons of one wife of the late king Abdul-Aziz Bin Saud, include King Fahd, Defence Minister Prince Sultan and five other brothers. Abdullah is their half-brother.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no capability for reform, no strong character to stop the princes from corruption. You'd need someone to line tens of them up against the wall and shoot them, they're so used to spending that amount of money,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be smart for the Sudairis to bring in Abdullah. I hope they don't do it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;If Fahd dies, the situation may explode. You may see internecine war in the next two years. The other scenario, if things go smoothly, is that we would be able to make a real mass movement, maybe at the beginning of the next century,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Masari, an Islamist academic, has conducted his campaign against the Saudi family mainly by bombarding the kingdom with subversive faxed messages but he said he had cut the faxes down to batches of 750 from 2,000 at a time.</p>
<p>&quot;We've decided that 750 is enough to saturate. We send them to government offices, Saudi Arabian airlines, which employ a number of dynamic young people, hospitals -- often they're not under supervision,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The level of popular disgust is massive. Right now our support is passive, the antipathy is passive. They're neither ready nor capable of mass action. This is changing,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
