<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="651816" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL interbank rates steady in thin market.</title>
<headline>KL interbank rates steady in thin market.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Interbank rates were mostly unchanged in Kuala Lumpur as a liquidity crunch continued to pressure the market, dealers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said foreign banks had some excess funds, but it was not helping to ease the tightness in the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Money is in certain sectors, not in all tenures,&quot; said a dealer with a Malaysian bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The bids are in a very wide range. Bidders are mainly smaller names (small financial institutions) and offers are from mainly foreign banks,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said medium-sized commercial banks were well squared up.</p>
<p>Dealers said internal restrictions on foreign banks did not allow them to lend to many borrowers in the market considered higher risk, like small finance companies and merchant banks.</p>
<p>One-week money was at 8.50/60 percent, two-week to one-month at 8.40/50 percent and three-month at 8.00/20 percent were all unchanged from Monday.</p>
<p>The overnight rate, which fell to around 7.0 percent, after mostly trading around 9.0 percent on Monday, was expected to remain at the higher end of the range, dealers said.</p>
<p>Interest rate futures on the Malaysia Monetary Exchange were down across the board on the expectation of a further rise in interest rates, futures dealers said.</p>
<p>At 0420 GMT, the three-month Kuala Lumpur Interbank Offered Rate (KLIBOR) June contract was down seven points to 91.99, or an implied yield of 8.01 percent.</p>
<p>September contract was down seven at 92.33, or 7.67 percent, December was down four at 92.48, or 7.52 percent, and March 1998 was down six at 92.54, or 7.46 percent.</p>
<p>-- Madhav Reddy (603-206 2323) .</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
