<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="651800" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai PM says senior adviser to lead economic team.</title>
<headline>Thai PM says senior adviser to lead economic team.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's prime minister has named a senior adviser from his six-party coalition, Chatichai Choonhavan, to lead the government's team of economic ministers, government officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The move was aimed at defusing tension between Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan and other politicians in the coalition over the handling of the current economic downturn -- the worst Thailand has faced in over a decade, they told Reuters.</p>
<p>Premier Chavalit Yongchaiyudh said Chatichai, who heads the Chart Pattana Party (CPP), the second largest in the coalition, would chair weekly meetings of economic ministers to formulate strategies to overcome the nation's economic woes.</p>
<p>Economic strategies at the weekly meetings would be forwarded to him for discussion with other cabinet ministers and decisions made after that, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Chatichai is the most senior person in the coalition and he always gives us useful advice,&quot; Chavalit told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;From now on he will chair the meeting of economic ministers every Thursday. Resolutions of the meeting will be put forward to me for consideration every Monday,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Chatichai is a former prime minister and an influential politician.</p>
<p>Thailand's economy has slowed sharply this year and private economists see economic growth falling to between three and five percent in 1997 from 6.4 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Troubles have also hit the depressed and cash-strapped finance and property sectors, exports have turned sluggish, high interest rates are stifling business activity, the baht is the target of speculative attacks and the stock market has sunk to eight-year lows.</p>
<p>Some coalition partners, led by some CPP leaders keen on Amnuay's job, recently launched a fresh attempt to oust the unelected Amnuay from his job and called for a cabinet reshuffle, political sources said.</p>
<p>Amnuay's sweeping economic revival measures, sometimes without consultation with senior government politicians, had upset some coalition partners, they added.</p>
<p>On Monday Amnuay, who was handpicked by Chavalit for the finance job when the government came to power in December, said he had no plans to quit despite the talk that he may be pressured to leave.</p>
<p>&quot;I have never given any thought to resigning,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Economic analysts said Amnuay's future appeared secure for now but in the longer term he could lose his job if stronger pressure for his removal was exerted on the premier by his opponents.</p>
<p>They said the move to name Chatichai as head of the economic team was a symbolic one aimed at defusing intra-coalition tension rather than taking away powers from Amnuay.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
