<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="651984" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: PRESS DIGEST - Norway - June 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Norway - June 10.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in Norwegian newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>AFTENPOSTEN</p>
<p>- Between 1995 and 1996, 23 percent of house buyers took out mortgages for 100 percent of their needs. Now 10 percent of these borrowers say they have trouble paying back the loans.</p>
<p>- Police are demanding that restrictions governing police carrying weapons are relaxed due to the escalation of the war between motorcycle gangs. The Justice Ministry is sceptical, however, and says it sees no reason to change today's policy. Only police in Oslo and other major cities are allowed to carry weapons in their cars.</p>
<p>- The Norwegian Banking, Insurance and Securities Commission is considering whether to step into the takeover war for Fokus Bank. Sparebankgruppen, a group of Norwegian savings banks, has extended its bid to Fokus shareholders by six weeks. Fokus Bank complained to the commission that it was impossible to continue normal business if the bidding period is continuously extended.</p>
<p>DAGENS NAERINGSLIV</p>
<p>- U.S. investment giant Tiger Management Fund is the great hope of head of insurer Storebrand, Aage Korsvold, in the proposed merger between Norway's largest insurance group and Christiania Bank og Kreditkasse. Korsvold belives that foreign shareholders will follow Tiger and support the merger.</p>
<p>- Christiania Bank og Kreditkasse has become the largest financier in the American rig market. In the last six months the bank has lent $246 million to listed drilling companies in the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
