<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652030" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Gas industry meets to ponder booming market.</title>
<headline>Gas industry meets to ponder booming market.</headline>
<byline>Sebastian Alison</byline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Natural gas is grabbing energy market share around the world and Europe is emerging as the centre for the greatest changes in the business.</p>
<p>Delegates gathering here for the 20th World Gas Conference starting on Tuesday will hear that their industry is now as competitive, as global, and as laden with opportunity as &quot;big oil&quot;, beside which it has long been considered a poor relation.</p>
<p>Gas demand is booming.</p>
<p>In Europe alone it is set to almost double in 15 years from 334 million tonnes of oil equivalent (mtoe) in 1995 to 535 mtoe by 2010.</p>
<p>The key growth market is in electricity generation, where its advantages as a clean, cheap and plentiful fuel have given it an edge over coal and oil.</p>
<p>Power generation within Europe will account for the great majority of extra gas used.</p>
<p>Generating demand was 63 mtoe in 1995, but will leap to 175 mtoe by 2010, according to analysts Wood Mackenzie. Gas as a proportion of all input into power generation is set to rise to 22.5 percent by 2010, from 9.8 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>As a proportion of all energy consumed, gas' share is steadily rising as well, from 19.2 percent in 1995 to 25.7 percent by 2010.</p>
<p>&quot;Fundamentally gas is very competitive, and there's no shortage of supply and, for that matter, supply infrastructure into Europe,&quot; said Ben Hollins, energy analyst at Wood Mackenzie.</p>
<p>Political developments are helping gas use in Europe.</p>
<p>Following the liberalisation of gas markets in the United States a decade ago, Britain was the first European nation to follow.</p>
<p>The former monopoly supplier, British Gas plc, has been split into two separate companies and by next year all households will be able to buy gas on the open market.</p>
<p>Progress is slower in the rest of Europe, although Dutch consultant Floor Touber believes the attempt to conclude a European Union gas directive is the main development facing the region now.</p>
<p>EU energy ministers failed to agree a formula for gas liberalisation at the end of May, with the Netherlands occupying the EU presidency.</p>
<p>&quot;It was politically rather doubtful during the Dutch presidency because of the dominant position of the Netherlands in the gas industry,&quot; Floor Touber said.</p>
<p>&quot;Similarly I doubt if anyone would want to allow the UK to finalise a gas directive (during the UK's presidency in the first half of 1998). I believe it will happen during Luxembourg's presidency (in the second half of this year).&quot;</p>
<p>If European demand is booming, supply is keeping pace with ease.</p>
<p>The main producers are Russia, dominated by gigantic monopoly holder Gazprom, Norway and Algeria.</p>
<p>Russia has long supplied Europe by pipeline through Ukraine, but is now working on a second pipeline to run from the vast underdeveloped reserves of the Yamal peninsula in the far North, through Belarus and Poland to Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;The pipeline continues to be constructed, though there is no confirmation yet that the project will be completed,&quot; said analyst Stephen O'Sullivan of MC Securities Ltd.</p>
<p>The pipeline is being built backwards from the point of consumption to the point of supply, and it is expected that it will only be extended to Yamal if the demand is sufficient.</p>
<p>Gazprom has also signed an agreement to deliver gas to Turkey, O'Sullivan said, and is looking to build a pipeline to Finland which could also take gas to central Europe</p>
<p>Russia's Prime Minster, Viktor Chernomyrdin, is a former head of Gazprom, and the gas industry in Russia has long enjoyed immense influence.</p>
<p>O'Sullivan said Gazprom as a company has the same influence as other whole Norway is also rapidly extending its export infrastructure, with pipelines taking gas direct to France, Germany and Britain, and contracts in place to deliver as far afield as the Czech Republic and Spain.</p>
<p>Algeria completes the triangle, with a pipeline opened last year taking gas to Spain in addition to an earlier subsea line supplying Italy.</p>
<p>The arrival of British gas via the Interconnector pipeline to Belgium next year will add to an infrastructure giving Europe unprecedented security of supply.</p>
<p>Further east, Iran and Iraq are seeking to supply Turkey with gas.</p>
<p>The Indian sub-continent could also see increased supplies, if the government of Turkmenistan agrees terms with competing companies looking to transport gas from the Dauletabad field to Pakistan and ultimately to India.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
