<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652110" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. House Democrats united on tax-cut alternative.</title>
<headline>U.S. House Democrats united on tax-cut alternative.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>House Democrats voted unanimously Wednesday to back an alternative five-year tax cut proposed by Rep. Charles Rangel of New York, the party's senior member on the tax-writing House Ways and Means Committee.</p>
<p>The plan was also endorsed by Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin, who said it offered more tax relief to the middle class than did the five-year tax cut proposed by Republican Rep. Bill Archer, chairman of the influential committee.</p>
<p>Archer's plan is the base for House work on tax cuts and is expected to emerge from the committee this week with few major changes.  </p>
<p>Rubin told reporters the Democratic alternative was &quot;consistent&quot; with the bipartisan budget agreement. The White House had been critical of the Republican plan for failing to provide the agreed-upon tax relief for education benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;The caucus has approved a plan that is strong, that is consistent with and supportive of the principles the president believes a tax plan should contain, particularly a focus on middle-income and working Americans,&quot; Rubin said after the closed caucus meeting of House Democrats.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Democrats had failed to approve a tax proposal after some in their group argued for a smaller tax cut.</p>
<p>One of those members, Rep. John Tanner, Democrat of Tennessee, said Wednesday he supported the Democratic plan. &quot;I am from the wing of the caucus that has trouble with tax cuts because my overriding concern is still balancing the nation's budget. It seemed to me if we are going to have tax cuts it ought to be the sort that generated economic activity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He supported the Democratic plan for its cut in capital gains taxes and estate taxes paid by small businesses and farms.  </p>
<p>House Minority Leader Richard Gephardt, Democrat of Missouri, said the Democratic tax plan would provide 70 percent of tax relief to those earning less than $50,000 a year while the Republican plan would provide 70 percent of tax relief to those earning more than $100,000 a year.</p>
<p>The Democratic alternative would provide $40 billion over five years for college education tax incentives and $71 billion for a phased-in $500-per-child tax credit for children under age 18. Archer's child tax credit would cover children under age 17.</p>
<p>The Democratic plan would provide a more targeted capital gains tax cut than Archer's plan, focusing on small businesses, family farms and real estate and would not cut the tax rate on gains from publicly traded stock. Republicans proposed a cut in the capital gains tax rate from 28 percent to 20 percent on all investments.</p>
<p>The Democratic plan would raise $30 billion in revenue from an extension of the airline ticket tax and an increase in the international departure fees to $10 from $6, as were also proposed by Republicans.</p>
<p>The Democratic plan would not raise the ticket tax or reduce the ethanol tax credit. It also would not tax gaming or other businesses on Indian lands.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
