<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="65212" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: August housing starts highest in nearly 2-1/2 years.</title>
<headline>August housing starts highest in nearly 2-1/2 years.</headline>
<byline>Glenn Somerville</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Construction starts on new homes and apartments climbed unexpectedly in August to the highest level in nearly 2-1/2 years, the Commerce Department said Thursday.</p>
<p>The building rate increased 4.5 percent to a seasonally adjusted annual rate of 1.525 million units -- the highest rate since March 1994, when it was at 1.531 million, and well above Wall Street economists' forecasts of a 1.445-million-unit building rate.</p>
<p>In addition, the department revised upward its estimates for building activity in both June and July, indicating the housing market entered the second half with brisk momentum despite generally higher long-term interest rates.</p>
<p>The unexpectedly strong figures sent the inflation-sensitive 30-year U.S. Treasury bond off half a point, or $5 per $1,000 face value. Its yield, which moves in the opposite direction, climbed to 7.06 percent, from 7.01 percent Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a wake-up call,&quot; said Veronika White, senior economist at First Union Corp. &quot;Given this number, the chances are greater than 50 percent for a rate hike on Tuesday,&quot; she said, referring to next week's meeting of the Federal Reserve's Open Markets Committee to review whether higher interest rates are needed to cool the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;This is one of the best leading indicators you have for forecasting the economy two quarters out,&quot; said Alan Ruskin, research director at I.D.E.A. Inc. &quot;It is indicative of an economy that's unlikely to slow dramatically into the first quarter of 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>There were some signs that the building rate may ease later in the year, as applications for new building permits fell 4.4 percent last month to a rate of 1.393 million after rising 3 percent in July.</p>
<p>The department revised its estimate of July housing starts to an annual rate of 1.46 million from a previously reported 1.455 million and said June construction was at a stronger rate of 1.49 million a year, instead of 1.474 million.</p>
<p>Housing starts were expected to level off in the summer because of the increase in long-term mortgage rates since the beginning of the year. Analysts said high levels of consumer confidence and strong job growth meant any easing in housing would be modest but did not foresee the continuing pickup in August building.</p>
<p>Construction starts on new single-family homes jumped in August by 8.3 percent to a rate of 1.238 million a year after a 5.5 percent decline in July. The August starts rate on single-family homes also was the highest since March 1994, when it was at 1.28 million.</p>
<p>Building of apartments dropped in August by 9.5 percent to a rate of 287,000 following a 12.8 percent increase in July.</p>
<p>Regionally, the only area where building declined in August was in the Midwest, where starts fell 2 percent to a rate of 342,000.</p>
<p>Starts in the West surged 13.5 percent to 378,000 a year and in the Northeast they gained 7 percent to a rate of 138,000. Construction in the South, the nation's biggest housing market, picked up 2.8 percent to a rate of 667,000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E61">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
