<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652315" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FORMULA ONE TEAMS NEAR SHARE DEAL - NEWSPAPER.</title>
<headline>FORMULA ONE TEAMS NEAR SHARE DEAL - NEWSPAPER.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading motor racing teams are nearing a deal under which they will give up some television revenues in exchange for shares in Formula One Holdings, the company which markets broadcasting rights for the sport, the Financial Times newspaper reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The paper said that a decision would be made by Friday on the timing of a planned flotation which analysts have estimated could value the company at about 1.8 billion pounds ($2.9 billion).</p>
<p>Under the equity deal, the 10 teams would trade a share of their future revenues for individual stakes in the company, it said. The aggregate holding would be no less than the 10 percent to be held by the FIA -- the paris-based world governing body of the sport.</p>
<p>Sources close to the sale have said it is likely that both the FIA and the racing teams will secure a 10 percent stake each in the company.</p>
<p>But speculation that the complex sale has been delayed has been partly fuelled by talk that the grand prix teams were arguing with the company about their revenue share and their stake in the floated company.</p>
<p>Formula One, which is owned by multi-millionaire Bernie Ecclestone and whose racing teams include Williams, Benetton, Jordan, Tyrell and McLaren, has said it expects a flotation around July. ($ = 0.610 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
