<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652373" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIA OPENS FIRST COURT CASE ON PIRATE CDS.</title>
<headline>BULGARIA OPENS FIRST COURT CASE ON PIRATE CDS.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Bulgarian court on Wednesday opened the country's first case involving alleged piracy of compact discs, in which Bulgaria ranks second only to China.</p>
<p>State news agency BTA said a regional court began hearings in the town of Veliko Tarnovo.</p>
<p>It said the prosecutor's office accused Marko Mihailov, 37, manager of a local firm called SMC, of organising production of CDs in 1995-96 in breach of copyright law.</p>
<p>Preliminary investigation showed that illegal CDs produced in Veliko Tarnovo had been supplied to firms in Russia, the Czech Republic and Romania, BTA said.</p>
<p>The International Federation of the Phonographic Industry has estimated illegal production in Bulgaria at 15 million discs a year.</p>
<p>The worldwide body, representing the $40 billion international recording industry, has urged Bulgaria to act against five CD plants which are estimated to supply approximately one in eight of all illegal copies on the world's CD black market.</p>
<p>The United States put Bulgaria on a &quot;watch list&quot; last October. European Union External Relations Commissioner Hans van den Broek, who visited Sofia earlier this week, urged tougher measures to protect intellectual property rights in view of Bulgaria's commitments as a member of the World Trade Organisation.</p>
<p>The Interior Ministry launched nationwide raids in March, confiscating thousands of suspected pirate discs.</p>
<p>Last year Bulgarian police investigated more than 200 audio and video producers and distributors, and 83 cases were referred to the prosecutor's office, but no one has been convicted yet.  REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
