<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652382" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIA FINES GERMANY'S WAZ IN COMPETITION CASE.</title>
<headline>BULGARIA FINES GERMANY'S WAZ IN COMPETITION CASE.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's Fair Competition Commission (FCC) on Wednesday fined Germany's WAZ Group which holds the majority stakes in the country's two most circulated dailies for unfair competition.</p>
<p>The FCC also said it will seek through the court to cancel the registration of WAZ's second acquisition in Bulgaria, the Trud Publishing House, where the Essen-based publisher of Westdeutsche Algemeine Zeitung holds 70 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The commission imposed a fine on WAZ for violation of the country's fair competition law and will ask the Sofia City Court to cancel the registration contract of Trud Publishing House,&quot; FCC chairman Stefan Neshev told a news conference.</p>
<p>In February the WAZ Group bought the majority stake in Media Holding press group, which includes the popular Trud daily and set up the Trud Publishing House Ltd, in which its daughter company WAZ Bulgaria holds a 70 percent stake.</p>
<p>The Trud daily held 28.3 percent share of the local newspaper market last year, the FCC said.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the law, the WAZ Group should have requested permission from the FCC for acquiring the majority stake in Media Holding press group,&quot; Neshev said.</p>
<p>The FCC then would have checked whether this aquisition did not restrict freedom of competition and whether it violated free price formation, said Neshev.</p>
<p>The fine imposed on WAZ ranged between 200,000 and 1,000,000 levs.</p>
<p>WAZ Group officials, who were present at the announcement of the FCC decision, declined comment.</p>
<p>The Group's first acquisition in Bulgaria was a 70 percent stake in the country's biggest 168 Chasa Pressgroup, (168 Hours), publisher of the widely circulated 24 Chasa daily, and some magazines.</p>
<p>The daily had 46.3 percent share of the local newspaper market in 1996, said the FCC.</p>
<p>The FCC ruled against complaints by local newpapers that WAZ Group was dumping newspaper prices in the country, saying the German group had not used its monopoly position to oust other participants from the local newspaper market.</p>
<p>&quot;Germany is very important economic partner for Bulgaria, but attracting of foreign investment should not be at the expense of violating the country's fair competition law,&quot; said Neshev. ($=1.667 levs) REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
