<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652488" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Cuba sticks to growth goal, undeterred by US.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Cuba sticks to growth goal, undeterred by US.</headline>
<byline>Diane Craft</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Cuban economy, despite the damaging effects of U.S. legislation, is on course to meet its 1997 target of up to five percent growth, Cuba's central bank president said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Francisco Soberon, in an interview with Reuters, said the U.S. Helms-Burton law, which punishes some foreign firms dealing with Cuba, was hurting the country but would not debilitate its economy.</p>
<p>Soberon, who has been visiting a number of countries in Europe with ties to Cuba, said growth would come from manufacturing, services and tourist industries.</p>
<p>&quot;If the goal (of the Helms Burton law) is to collapse our economy, they are not doing that. It creates problems for us but it is not an obstacle that we cannot overcome,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Helms-Burton law was enacted last year to tighten the U.S. embargo against Cuba.</p>
<p>The law seeks to punish foreign firms investing in property seized from U.S. citizens and companies in Cuba after the 1959 revolution that brought President Fidel Castro to power.</p>
<p>Since the law passed, the U.S. government has imposed sanctions on a Canadian mining firm and a Mexican industrial group.</p>
<p>&quot;Whenever we have a new obstacle, it's a new challenge for us and that makes us work harder,&quot; Soberon said. &quot;We have to be more efficient, more creative and to think of new alternatives and we are doing that.&quot;</p>
<p>Soberon said he could not comment on exact figures for first quarter growth, but he was sticking with previous targets.</p>
<p>&quot;We maintain our estimates of four to five percent this year. We could say that we are complying with our main goal this year which is to reduce our short-term exposure,&quot; he said, noting that exposure includes debt and credits.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel we have the infrastructure, the skilled labour and organisation to be able to continue with a very steady rate of growth. But we have sacrificed growth in order to reduce our short-term exposure...and that means a healthier growth.&quot;</p>
<p>Soberon said to keep the economic recovery going and to finance the economy, the central bank was mainly depending on short-term credits. He also said it wanted to reduce short-term debt because it created tension in management of the economy.</p>
<p>He declined to quantify total internal debt but said it would be cut by year-end.</p>
<p>&quot;What I can tell you is that we are reducing it. At the end of the year, we will have short-term debt less than we started in 1997. That I can tell you definitely,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Soberon said external debt, which included Paris Club debt, totalled about $10.4 billion and had not risen in 1996.</p>
<p>Soberon said Cuba's sugar crop, which accounts for one-third of the economy, would be less than last year but he said growth would come from the manufacturing and tourist industries as well as the services sector.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
