<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652468" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British MPs consider electronic voting.</title>
<headline>British MPs consider electronic voting.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>It is enough to make British traditionalists splutter into their port: parliament is considering introducing electronic voting.</p>
<p>Ann Taylor, the first woman to hold the post of leader of the House of Commons, said on Wednesday she was tempted by the idea of voting by means of electronic swipe cards as part of a drive to drag the House of Commons into the modern age.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot rule out electronic voting,&quot; she told reporters.</p>
<p>Members of parliament, who agreed only last decade to have their proceedings televised, currently vote by trooping through so-called division lobbies where their names are ticked off by tellers.</p>
<p>Taylor said the system had the advantage of enabling rank-and-file MPs to collar ministers.</p>
<p>&quot;But that doesn't preclude speeding up the process or combining it with perhaps having some kind of swipe card and then being counted as you come out,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The new Labour government has already shown that it is prepared to tinker with age-old parliamentary traditions.</p>
<p>It has changed the format for prime minister's question time and Taylor said a modernisation committee she is chairing would look at ways of improving the legislative process and shortening parliament's three-month summer break.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm hoping there is enough momentum in the government and the House to get realistic change and make Parliament more effective and more efficient,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
