<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652425" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil prices renew slide on fund selling, Iraq.</title>
<headline>Oil prices renew slide on fund selling, Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Mark Thompson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street fund selling pushed world oil prices lower on Wednesday, wiping out earlier gains made on news of Iraqi interference with United Nations' helicopters.</p>
<p>The selling was triggered mainly in reaction to an Iraqi statement suggesting Baghdad expected no undue delay in renewing Iraq's oil-for-food deal with the United Nations.</p>
<p>London July futures for benchmark Brent Blend crude oil last traded at $17.42 a barrel, a slide of eight cents on the day and a big 48 cent drop from the session high.</p>
<p>Earlier the contract had touched a new 13-month low of $17.32, a level not seen since May 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is technically weak and it only needs one headline to pull it sharply down,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>He was referring to a Reuters report that Iraqi Ambassador Nizar Hamdoon said he foresaw no political wrangling over setting in motion the renewed &quot;oil-for-food&quot; deal with the United Nations.</p>
<p>Hamdoon told Reuters Iraq was simply following procedures that a new aid distribution plan be in place before oil sales can restart.</p>
<p>Big funds that play the oil markets used the news bearishly to sell oil futures down in New York to protect their large short trading positions, and London's futures market declined in sympathy, brokers said.</p>
<p>Earlier bulls had taken heart from reports that Rolf Ekeus, chief of the U.N. special commission (UNSCOM) in charge of scrapping Iraq's weapons of mass destruction, had written to the Security Council detailing &quot;four serious incidents in which the lives of the crews... and the aircraft themselves were endangered.&quot;</p>
<p>The Security Council was expected to discuss the incidents on Wednesday and the Council president Sergei Lavrov of Russia said he would be calling in Iraq's U.N. envoy Nizar Hamdoon.</p>
<p>The report of Iraqi threats against U.N. personnel came less than a week after the Security Council approved the extension of its oil-for-food deal allowing Baghdad to raise some $2 billion over six months for humanitarian imports.</p>
<p>Oil markets are eagerly awaiting the resumption of Iraqi exports after the first tranche averaging about 660,000 barrels per day was completed in late May.</p>
<p>A bear run which slashed $3, or 15 percent, off a barrel of Brent blend crude oil over the last three weeks was fuelled by the deal's renewal and any hint of delay could push prices higher again.</p>
<p>Iraq's State Oil Marketing Organisation (SOMO) appears to be in no hurry to sign new contracts and there is little prospect of shipments from the Turkish port of Ceyhan and the Gulf terminal of Mina al-Bakr resuming before early July, European oil traders said.</p>
<p>The strength of U.S. gasoline demand as millions of Americans take to the roads for their summer holidays continued to attract attention with latest industry data confirming the recent negative tone.</p>
<p>The American Petroleum Institute (API) said refineries were running flat out, churning out gasoline faster than motorists could consume it.</p>
<p>API data showed nationwide gasoline stocks rose 2.7 million barrels in the week to June 6, a figure confirmed by the Department of Energy, returning to year-ago levels.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						June 11   June 10</p>
<p>					     (close)    (close)</p>
<p> Dated Brent				 $16.72   $16.85</p>
<p> IPE July Brent			    $17.42   $17.50</p>
<p> NYMEX July light crude		  $18.56   $18.73</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
