<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652525" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dlr/yen ends lower in Europe, trade friction bites.</title>
<headline>Dlr/yen ends lower in Europe, trade friction bites.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar ended down more than one full yen in Europe after setting a seven-month low against the Japanese unit earlier in the session amid concern about rising trade friction between the U.S. and Japan.</p>
<p>The yen surged across the board and also set a 21-month high against a subdued German mark, which was dampened by easing tensions about preparations for European monetary union.</p>
<p>The yen's latest surge was fueled by overnight news of a 92.7 percent rise in Japan's April current account surplus from a year earlier and comments from U.S. Deputy Treasury Secretary Lawrence Summers urging Japan to avoid rising trade surpluses.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market is focussing on the trade numbers but this is a development that has been apparent for many months now,&quot; said Claudio Demolli, currency analyst at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>&quot;The Japanese now see the dollar/yen pullback since May as excessive, intervention to support it is not out of the question and we feel the move will be limited to the 110 area.&quot;</p>
<p>At 1515 GMT, the dollar was trading at 111.29/39 yen compared with 112.43/53 late Tuesday but off the new low set at 110.62 earlier. Mark/yen, meantime, ended at 64.95/97 compared with 65.41/44 late yesterday and just off the low at 64.69 set earlier.  </p>
<p>Japanese protests at the latest yen surge follwed the overnight lunge. Japan's Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka said Japan would act to counter excessive foreign exchange moves and Bank of Japan governor Yasuo Matsushita called for stability.</p>
<p>Leaders of the Group of Seven industrialised nations (G7) meet in Denver on June 20-22.</p>
<p>Analysts cited a number of reasons why the yen rise may be in its final throes for now at least.</p>
<p>One reason is its 13 percent rise since May 1 is seen as offsetting pressure for rise in interest rates near-term. Euroyen interest rate futures rallied today, as a result.  </p>
<p>&quot;One dampening effect on the yen will be that its very strong rise over the past month will take some of the pressure off for a rise in Japanese rates for now at least,&quot; said Tony Norfield, treasury economist at ABN Amro.</p>
<p>Analysts said the 110 level is also an area that will satisfy U.S. car manufacturers, traditionally hyper-sensitive to the yen exchange rate because of fierce competition with their Japanese rivals.</p>
<p>Concerns about the need for some central bank intervention to steady dollar/yen were also stoked by extremely skewed prices in the currency options, often monitored closely by authorities.  </p>
<p>Risk reversals, which effectively show the difference in price between dollar/yen call options and put options, are biased in favour of one-month dollar puts to the tune of more than two percentage points - levels last seen in 1995.</p>
<p>Dollar/mark mapped a tight range during the session, meantime, and it was well supported on dips as mark losses agains European currencies like the Italian lira were fueled by an easing of pre-EMU tensions in Europew.</p>
<p>The latest barrage of comments from senior German, French and other EU officials pointed to increasing optimism about an agreement on a budgetary stability pact at next week's summit.  </p>
<p>Analysts said it looks as if French demands on the stability pact will be satisfied by tagging on a section on the need for job creation but this would leave the basic text of the existing pact unaltered. That should avoid stiff German opposition.</p>
<p>French finance minister Dominque Strauss-Kahn said he hoped for an early solution and Germany's opposition Social Demcrats backed the French call for an employment tag to the pact.</p>
<p>&quot;The market seems a bit tired the whole story, to be honest, and once the fog clears no one really expects this to develop into a crisis,&quot; said Demolli at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>--Mike Dolan, London newsroom +44 171 542 6762</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
