<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652680" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Poland - June 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Poland - June 11.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>FRONT PAGE POLITICAL NEWS</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- Poland will not give in to pressure from any foreign country on legal issues as it is bound to obey Polish laws, Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz said in response to Russian foreign ministry calls for the extradition of Sergei Stankevich, a former aid of President Boris Yeltsin accused of accepting a bribe. Poland has no extradition agreement with Russia, Cimoszewicz said.</p>
<p>- The rightist Solidarity Elections Action (AWS) and Movement for the Reconstruction of Poland (ROP) will start talks on cooperation in parliamentary elections in September.</p>
<p>ECONOMIC AND MARKET STORIES</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- Former board members of PZU SA, Poland's biggest insurance firm, have presented the finance minister with proposals for restructuring based on reappraising of PZU stock and exchanging share stakes between PZU's non-life and life firms and avoiding the sale of stakes to outside investors.</p>
<p>- Cod fishing in the Baltic will be banned from June 6 to August 20. Polish fishermen are worried by the decision as they have so far caught only 30 percent of their quota due to the lack of fish, the Polish Fishermen's Association (SAR) said.</p>
<p>- Poland's export sales of pallets made according to EU standards were worth $127 million in 1996, Polish pallet makers' association official Andrzej Repulak said.</p>
<p>- The state-owned export credit insurance corporation (KUKE) earned a net profit of 7.26 million zlotys in 1996 showing a 44.8 percent growth on the year before, KUKE's president Krzysztof Jasinski said.</p>
<p>- Bank Handlowy has been acclaimed Poland's best bank in Euromoney magazine's Awards for Excellence contest.</p>
<p>- Mostostal Siedlce construction firm will apply for a share listing by autumn this year. The company does not plan a public offering, Mostostal said.</p>
<p>DZIENNIK PRAWA I GOSPODARKI</p>
<p>- Stan Szczurek will stand down as the ING Bank's Warsaw branch president as of July 1 and will be appointed president of the international Netia telecoms operator active in several provinces around Poland.</p>
<p>- The legal department of Telekomunikacja Polska SA (TPSA) Poland's state-owned telecoms operator has challenged a recent telecommunications ministry ruling on connection costs between TPSA and the GSM mobile phone operators.</p>
<p>- Polish-Belarus trade exchange declined by 14 percent in the first quarter of 1997 compared with the last quarter of 1996, Poland's economy deputy minister Jan Chaladaj said.</p>
<p>- The US Hudson Foods concern has bought a 30 percent stake in the Cedrob SA poultry processor in Ciechanow, central Poland. Cedrob plans to acquire a stake in a poultry processing plant in Krakow, southern Poland, Cedrob said.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>- Fiat Auto Poland has invested 80 million zlotys in production of the Siena model the sale of which will start this month, the firm's president Massimo Gentilini said.</p>
<p>- Subsidies to Poland's agricultural sector are 30 percent smaller than in the EU countries but double the subsidies going to Czech or Hungarian farmers, a report by the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) said.</p>
<p>ZYCIE</p>
<p>- Strawberry prices will grow by 40 percent this season compared with 1996 due to a decline in Poland's strawberry harvests to 140,000 tonnes, 40,000 tonnes less than last year, a report by the Agricultural and Food Economy Institute (IERiGZ) said.</p>
<p>PARKIET</p>
<p>- Poland's gross domestic product (GDP) will grow by 5.7 percent in 1997, the cabinet's strategic studies centre said. NOTE - Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
