<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652601" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria's FSB Bank reaps from charges.</title>
<headline>Nigeria's FSB Bank reaps from charges.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Interest margin and income from fee-based activities helped Nigeria's FSB International Bank to boost 1996/97 earnings substantially, its chief executive said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Gross earnings increased by 86 percent to 1.4 billion naira in the year ended March 1997 from 787 million naira in the comparable period a year earlier, Mohammed Hayatu-Deen told stock traders at a forum on the Lagos floor of the Nigerian stock market.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of profitability, the bank recorded a phenomenal rise in profit after taxes from the 242 million naira reported for the year ended March 31, 1996 to 433 million naira in 1997, representing about 80 percent increase from the performance of the previous year,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Formerly Federal savings Bank, FSB was listed on the exchange four years ago after its privatisation by federal authorities and is now owned by institutional investors and the public.</p>
<p>Hayatu-Deen said FSB was investing in information technology to enhance its services.</p>
<p>FSB shares closed unchanged at 4.50 naira at Wednesday's trading.</p>
<p>($1=85 naira)</p>
<p>__ Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
