<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652600" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa rethinks bills after drug firms ire.</title>
<headline>S.Africa rethinks bills after drug firms ire.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African Health Minister Nkosazana Zuma on Wednesday withdrew three controversial health bills and said she would review the proposed changes to the rules for the acquisition and dispensing of medicines.</p>
<p>Zuma said in a statement to parliament she remained committed to the purpose of the bills, which have provoked the ire of pharmaceuticals companies, but would withdraw them from the parliamentary process for further study.</p>
<p>&quot;The bills before (parliament) are about lowering the prices of medicines in this country and are designed to benefit all South Africans by providing them with cheaper, quality and safe medicine,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The proposals included measures to promote cheaper generic substitutes over brand name drugs by instructing pharmacists to dispense them unless expressly forbidden to do so.</p>
<p>The industry said this amounted to mandatory substitution.</p>
<p>A second controversial proposal would have curbed brands by barring sales to the state of medicines containing the brand-name in the label and would have barred incentive schemes to encourage doctors to dispense specific drugs.</p>
<p>South Africa's drugs industry cautiously welcomed the move.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome the fact and we certainly hope that she takes note of the issues and areas of concern that we raised,&quot; said Erica Mann, vice-president of the Pharmaceutical Manufacturers' Association.</p>
<p>Doctors, nurses, the pharmaceutical industry and all opposition parties in parliament had criticised the three bills during two days of public hearings earlier this month.</p>
<p>Industry spokesmen charged that South Africa would lose control of the quality of medicines and could become a dumping ground for poor quality or out-of-date products.</p>
<p>Opposition parties walked out of the hearings when Health Committee chairman Abe Nkomo insisted on pressing ahead in the face of almost universal objections.</p>
<p>Zuma, who has run into opposition over many of her major health policy proposals, said she had not expected support from pharmaceutical companies for all aspects of her proposals.</p>
<p>&quot;I will, however, continue to work with them because we need each other and together we shall deliver an affordable, quality health care,&quot; she told parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to study the submissions and make sure that the genuine concerns and suggestions are taken on board. I will therefore resubmit the bills to cabinet next week,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The bills withdrawn were the Pharmacy Amendment Bill, the Medicines and Related Substances Control Amendment Bill and the Medical, Dental and Supplementary Health Service Professions Amendment Bill.</p>
<p>Representatives of several parties congratulated Zuma on her decision to withdraw the bills and renew consultations on their contents.</p>
<p>Her decision means the measures cannot be adopted until after parliament's winter recess, which ends late in July.</p>
<p>&quot;It is absolutely right that these bills should have been withdrawn,&quot; said Democratic Party health specialist Mike Ellis.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been an attempt on the part of the ANC (African National Congress) to steamroller these bills through parliament...the process we have been through has been absolutely atrocious,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is essential now that the entire process is reopened, that evidence is called for, that the process is followed through absolutely properly,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
