<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652713" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: IMF team arrives in Prague to study currency woes.</title>
<headline>IMF team arrives in Prague to study currency woes.</headline>
<byline>John Mastrini</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>An International Monetary Fund (IMF) team of economists began a special mission to Prague on Wednesday to analyse the recent sharp drop of the crown currency and the broader Czech economy.</p>
<p>Czech National Bank (CNB) spokesman Martin Svehla told Reuters that the IMF mission, led by economist Zervou Dakis, would most likely meet Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus, Finance Minister Ivan Pilip, Czech National Bank Governor Josef Tosovsky and other senior economic officials.</p>
<p>The mission comes after a brief visit last week by IMF deputy managing director Stanley Fischer who had talks with Klaus and Pilip about the late-May attacks on the Czech crown, while en route to a conference in Budapest.</p>
<p>The Czech news agency CTK quoted Klaus saying after the meeting with Fischer last week that Prague would be maintaining &quot;very intensive communication&quot; with the IMF.</p>
<p>The Czech crown came heavy downward pressure last month as speculators targetted the currency as overvalued, and the ruling coalition government teetered near a possible collapse.</p>
<p>A letter from Fischer to Klaus in March, expressing concern over recent results -- mainly low productivity growth, strong wage growth, heavy domestic demand and a widening current account deficit -- led to a row within the ruling coalition.</p>
<p>Senior ministers, including deputy prime ministers Josef Lux and Josef Zieleniec, complained that Klaus had not shown the IMF warning to the rest of the cabinet.</p>
<p>Local media reports suggested that a deal with the IMF for a loan to help back the Czech currency was in the works, but IMF officials in Washington would not confirm this.</p>
<p>The CNB last week mandated four private banks to arrange a $1.5 billion, one-year revolving credit facility as a standby to strengthen the central bank's foreign exchange reserves.</p>
<p>The syndicate included Chase Investment Bank Ltd, Commerzbank AG, JP Morgan Securities Ltd and SBC Warburg, a division of Swiss Bank Corp.</p>
<p>Central bank reserves were just over $11 billion at the end of April, before several CNB interventions in late May -- which analysts estimated totalling between $1 billion and $3 billion -- to bolster the Czech crown against speculative attacks.</p>
<p>The CNB was eventually forced on May 27 to float the currency and abandon its 15 percent fluctuation band within which it would fix the currency against a mark/dollar peg.</p>
<p>The crown had lost more than 15 percent of its value against major currencies since February, but strengthened about four percent in recent days as the government launched its austerity programme and narrowly won a parliamentary vote of confidence.</p>
<p>The Czech Republic paid off its entire $471 million in post-Communist transformation credit granted by the IMF ahead of schedule in 1994, because of strong growth in foreign exchange reserves. The debt was scheduled to be paid off between the years 1996 and 1999.</p>
<p>Foreign exchange reserves grew backed by a fixed exchange rate and strong interest yield differentials against major currencies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
