<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652875" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazilian government loses reform vote in congress.</title>
<headline>Brazilian government loses reform vote in congress.</headline>
<byline>William Schomberg</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Fernando Henrique Cardoso suffered a setback on Tuesday in his anti-inflation drive, when the lower house of congress struck down an important article of a civil service reform bill.</p>
<p>The government, hoping to regain momentum in its faltering reform drives before next year's elections, fell seven votes short of a three-fifths majority of 308 votes that were needed to defeat an opposition amendment to the bill, a congressional official said.</p>
<p>The amendment prevents cash-strapped states and municipal governments from setting ceilings on pay and pensions below a $10,188 monthly cap included in the reform for federal workers.</p>
<p>The civil service reform as a whole is considered crucial to the long-term prospects of Cardoso's anti-inflation program. It would allow states and municipalities to fire many workers who currently cannot be fired and who account for virtually all of the state and municipal spending.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the government in Congress said the defeat might have been due to the fact that there was a low turnout among government-allied lawmakers. &quot;It seems a lot of people got stuck in the south of Brazil where the airports were closed because of bad weather,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesay Cardoso argued for the reforms in a radio address, saying, &quot;Without reform, we will not be able to cure the social security system.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the current system, which permits some public-sector workers to claim a pension when they are as young as 35, was unjust.</p>
<p>The government had hoped to make headway on the amendment votes this week and regain lost political momentum after a couple of dismal months marked by infighting among allied parties and a corruption scandal.</p>
<p>Shortly after the Chamber of Deputies approved the reform itself by the margin of just one vote in April, the government failed to kill an opposition amendment. For two months, fearing more defeats, it blocked further voting on the amendments.</p>
<p>The real test of the government's reform program might come on Wednesday when another amendment, which would render the reform effectively useless by keeping civil service lifetime job guarantees, was expected to be voted on, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
