<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652857" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - ROMANIA - JUNE 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - ROMANIA - JUNE 11.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>BURSA</p>
<p>- Four foreign companies are vying for a majority stake in Otel Inox, a steel maker based in Tirgoviste, west of Bucharest.</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- The Finance Ministry decided to sack the chief of the financial police, Gica Danila.</p>
<p>- Heavy rains in recent days flooded hundreds of hectares of cropland and scores of homes in Moldova.</p>
<p>- Western companies bidding for a controlling stake in Otel Inox SA steel smelter in Tirgoviste failed to offer the price expected by the State Ownership Fund, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Investments in the economy have fallen dramatically due to dearer money policies, with the domestic housing construction market still an illusion, the newspaper says.</p>
<p>- The court of appeals has postponed to June 30 a verdict in the case pitting Italy's New Holland against the employees of Romanian harvester maker Semanatoarea.</p>
<p>- Labour leaders say they expect up to 40,000 industrial workers to attend protests in several Romanian cities, over fears of looming unemployment as the government restructures communist-era industries.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Trade unions from Romania's Tarom airline are suing the State Ownership Fund, the Private Ownership Funds and the Transport Ministry over plans to restructure the company.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Newspaper says Germany supports Romania's first-wave admission to NATO, a sea change in Bonn's attitude expressed at a summit in France of European Christian Democrats.</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- The Chamber of Deputies has adopted a law on organs transplant.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Victor Ciorbea, Finance Minister Mircea Ciumara, Public Works Minister Nicolae Noica, Agriculture Minister Dinu Gavrilescu, Labour and Social Protection Minister Alexandru Athanasiu, Justice Minister Valeriu Stoica and Education Minister Virgil Petrescu have been invited by the Civic Alliance for a debate on progress in implementing the &quot;Contract with Romania&quot; after 200 days in office.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- A newspaper report on the fate of Romanians in Ukraine says their plight has not changed since Stalin.</p>
<p>- Parliament's lower Chamber of Deputies has voted to allow Romanian fathers to take paternity leave for two years.</p>
<p>- American folk star Joan Baez will perform in Bucharest on June 22 to promote her latest album.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Romanian Jews accuse the World Jewish Restitution Organisation (WJRO) of trying to blackmail Romania, says newspaper editorial.</p>
<p>Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
