<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652929" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico peso closes firmer on Cetes auction results.</title>
<headline>Mexico peso closes firmer on Cetes auction results.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mexican peso extended earlier strength to close firmer for the third session in a row on Wednesday on favorable market reaction to higher primary Cetes rates, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Dealers preferred to square dollar positions and take advantage of higher interest rates in local currency,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>The benchmark 48-hour peso and its 24-hour stablemate ended 1.2 and 1.0 centavo firmer, respectively, at 7.9640/7.9660 and 7.9590/7.9640 per dollar.  </p>
<p>Same-day peso contracts closed mid-morning 0.6 of a centavo weaker at 7.9650/7.9680 per dollar.</p>
<p>Banco de Mxico assigned bellwether 28-day Cetes at 20.43 percent at Tuesday night's primary auction, an increase of 113 basis points since last week.</p>
<p>Dealers said trading was slow due to investor caution ahead of revised trade balance data for April that were released after the close of trade.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry said Mexico chalked up a trade surplus of barely $50 million on April, half the preliminary figure of $109 million.</p>
<p>Dealers said the data came too late to have any impact on Wednesday's session, but could well spawn jitters in the market on Thursday and rekindle fears the peso is not competitively priced for exporting companies.</p>
<p>Traders said they would also look out for U.S. bond market reaction to U.S. consumer prices, due to be released on Thursday shortly before foreign exchange trading opens in Mexico.</p>
<p>(( -- Alexis Quiones, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9555))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
