<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="652958" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Bradesco denies report on joint Banerj bid.</title>
<headline>Bradesco denies report on joint Banerj bid.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's largest private bank Bradesco denied a newspaper report saying it was holding talks with the bank Opportunity over possible joint participation in the June 17 privatization auction of Banco do Estado do Rio de Janeiro SA, or Banerj.</p>
<p>&quot;That report is untrue. There is nothing in that direction</p>
<p>despite the good relatioship between the two banks,&quot; said a Bradesco spokeswoman.  </p>
<p>The newspaper O Globo on Wednesday said Opportunity could become Bradesco's partner in Banerj's selloff. Bradesco prequalified for the auction last year, when the Rio de Janeiro state government first attempted to sell the bank.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman said Bradesco was still studying whether it would take part in the auction.</p>
<p>Other six financial institutions are prequalified: Cia de Investimentos Latino-Americana, Banco Itau, General Electric's GE Capital, BankBoston Corp's Brazilian unit, Credit Commerciale de France's (CCF) Brazil unit and Banco BBA Creditanstalt.  </p>
<p>O Globo also said Brazil's central bank was due to announce the list of prequalified bidders on Wednesday, but a bank spokesman said he could not confirm the report.</p>
<p>BankBoston in Brazil has said it is not interested in Banerj, while Itau confirmed its interest and said it was likely to participate in the auction.</p>
<p>Rio de Janeiro state attempted to sell Banerj twice last year but court injunctions against the auction and debts related to the bank's pension fund prevented the sale from taking place.</p>
<p>The state plans to auction Banerj, including insurer Banerj Seguros, for 310 million reais on the Rio de Janeiro Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>((--Fatima Cristina, Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 2485412))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
