<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653096" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Author says secret Sino-British pact solves riddle.</title>
<headline>Author says secret Sino-British pact solves riddle.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's British colonial rulers signed a secret agreement with the Chinese communists just after World War Two in a pact that kept the communist armies from taking back the territory, a Chinese author says.</p>
<p>In an article titled &quot;The Secret Sino-British Agreement of Hong Kong, 1945&quot;, published in the influential Japanese monthly Bungei Shunju, author Tang Lumei wrote that the secret agreement evolved into a policy by late Chinese Premier Zhou Enlai to allow Britain to hold on to Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Hong Kong reverts to Chinese sovereignty after more than 150 years of British colonial rule at midnight on June 30.</p>
<p>Tang, 47, a Chinese author born in Japan and now living in the United States, said the secret deal was signed on September 27, 1945 in Hong Kong. That was even before the communists had swept to power but when they already controlled parts of southern Guangdong province that borders Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Tang Tiandu, deputy head of the communists' Political and Economic Committee in southern Guangdong province, signed the agreement on behalf of the Chinese Communist Party and Britain was represented by senior diplomat D.M. McDougal, she wrote.</p>
<p>Tang, 104, no relation to the author, is still alive in a hospital in Guangdong. The author said she interviewed Tang and his secretary and historian Gao Hendi.</p>
<p>&quot;This (agreement) will reveal what was unexplained...about why China did not re-take Hong Kong when it could have easily done so,&quot; said the article in Bungei Shunju's July issue.</p>
<p>Four days before Japan's August 15, 1945 surrender, Zhou Enlai first ordered communist troops to take Hong Kong from the Japanese, but abandoned the plan on August 23 because of an accord to hand over big cities to Nationalist Chinese armies.</p>
<p>It was at this point that the communist leadership ordered Tang to enter into a secret agreement with the British.</p>
<p>Under the nine-point agreement, the communists promised not to try to re-take Hong Kong in exchange for official status in Hong Kong and the right to keep newspaper offices and communications bases in the colony.</p>
<p>Such an agreement had to be kept secret because it amounted to a communist sell-out to Britain over Hong Kong. A copy survives in the party's archives in Guangdong, the author says.</p>
<p>One day after the signing, the Guangdong regional party headquarters announced its underground military unit in Hong Kong would be pulled out.</p>
<p>But the commander of the British garrison asked Tang to leave the battalion to maintain law and order until a full British contingent and a new governor arrived in May 1946.</p>
<p>In line with the secret pact, the communists in June 1946 set up an operations committee and a year later opened a branch of their Xinhua news agency office, later the de facto communist Chinese embassy.</p>
<p>The secret accord explains why Britain allowed the communists to open such a bureau at the height of the Chinese civil war and two years before the 1949 proclamation of the People's Republic of China, the author says. The pact also kept the People's Liberation Army out of British Hong Kong. In October 1949, the communist armies halted just 40 km (25 miles) from Hong Kong -- probably to keep to the terms of that secret accord, the author says.</p>
<p>A result of the mutual confidence-building was London's recognition of communist China in 1950, the author says.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
