<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653093" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Pearl to check investors into hotel.</title>
<headline>Pearl to check investors into hotel.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ultra-luxury property developer and hotelier Pearl Oriental Holdings Ltd will sell rooms in its latest hotel project to individual investors, senior company executives said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;As the majority owner, we will retain a 50 percent interest in the hotel, then invite small investors to buy one, ten or fifteen units in the hotel,&quot; Pearl Oriental chairman Wong Kwan said at a news conference.</p>
<p>Pearl Oriental, which owns and manages several hotels in Hong Kong, Taiwan and China, will retain management of the entire hotel under a contract that gives management three percent of the hotel's total turnover and another three percent of its profit as a management incentive.</p>
<p>Investors will lease back their rooms in this four-star hotel to the hotel operating company and share in the total profit from the hotel services, said Wong.</p>
<p>The company will launch the sale of rooms on the first five floors on Thursday, and the sales price is likely to exceed HK$8,000 per sq ft, Wong said.</p>
<p>The 27-storey building was originally built for use as an office building and still must be converted.</p>
<p>&quot;To protect investors from any delay in the conversion work or in the granting of government approvals, we will guarantee a six percent return on the investment,&quot; Wong said.</p>
<p>The rate was based on an average room rental of HK$1,350 per day and average hotel occupancy rates of 70 percent in the low season and more than 90 percent in the peak season, he said.</p>
<p>The Pearl Island Hotel, located at the northwestern end of Hong Kong island, will have 330 rooms with 14 units of between 300 sq ft and 700 sq ft on each floor after conversion, the chairman said.</p>
<p>At HK$8,000 per sq ft, some larger rooms could fetch HK$5.6 million.</p>
<p>The chairman was not sure how banks would react to this type of investment, but said he thought many investors would not need financing.</p>
<p>Pearl Oriental, whose projects are believed to be the most expensive in the world, is redeveloping luxury residental property on the Peak -- Hong Kong's most exclusive residential area.</p>
<p>-- Kathleen Kearney (852) 2843 6933  http://www.hk97.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
