<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653060" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL palm oil ends up on Pakistan duty cut talk.</title>
<headline>KL palm oil ends up on Pakistan duty cut talk.</headline>
<text>
<p>PALM OIL FUTURES	   PALM OIL PHYSICAL</p>
<p>Aug (3rd pos) 1,192 rgt/tonne	    June (south) 1,230</p>
<p>Open/Hi/Low  1,177/1,194/1,175	   Prev close 1,212.50</p>
<p>Prev settlement 1,179			* sellers prices</p>
<p>PALM OIL FUTURES - Talk that Pakistan may reduce its import duty on palm oil, fears of bad weather in India and technical buying pushed up prices at close. Activity picked up in late trade as near-term's prospect is firm. August broke the support of 1,180 ringgit and next resistance is 1,200 rgt level. Earlier prices fell on poor soyoil prices.</p>
<p>PALM OIL PHYSICALS -Firmed strongly on covering and buying by refiners, also followed futures. Interest was widepread.  </p>
<p>Another trader said: &quot;There are also worries about the weather conditions in India. That's why prices were moving up strongly in the afternoon session.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The weather would affect the Indian crops and might lead to a tight supply there. This means that India may come into our palm market to import more from us.&quot;</p>
<p>The bullish factors in the afternoon suddenly saw futures contracts rise sharply and double-digit gains were posted at the close, traders said. &quot;The firmer sentiment spilled-over to August futures which hit the resistance level of 1,180 ringgit,&quot; a technical analyst said.  </p>
<p>&quot;August futures contract is trying to test the 1,200 rgt,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>The contract closed 13 ringgit higher at 1,192 ringgit ($473.96) a tonne after falling to a low of 1,175 ringgit.</p>
<p>Opening prices were marked down as the market took its cue from a weak Chicago soyoil futures overnight, they said.</p>
<p>But traders said firmer sentiment also prevailed among physicals which saw buying and shortcovering from refiners.</p>
<p>Physicals June (south) saw offers at 1,230 ringgit against bids at 1,225 after trading from 1,220 and 1,225 earlier.  </p>
<p>June (central) was offered at 1,220 versus 1,215 with earlier trades at 1,210 and 1,215.</p>
<p>July (south) saw offers at 1,230 after bids of 1,225 and trades of 1,220 and 1,225. July (central) saw offers at 1,220 against bids of 1,212.50.</p>
<p>In refined products, June RBD palm oil was offered at $520, July at $515 and Aug/Sept at $512.50. July was traded at $512.50 and August at $510.  </p>
<p>June RBD palm olein saw offers at $565, July at $560 and Aug/Sept at $555. July was traded at $552.50.</p>
<p>June/July RBD palm stearin was offered at $382.50 and June/July palm fatty acid distillate saw sellers at $275.</p>
<p>-- Tan Lee Lee  (275-6834)  ($1-2.5150)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
