<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653125" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: FOCUS - Fears of El Nino stalk Asian harvests.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Fears of El Nino stalk Asian harvests.</headline>
<byline>Steve Hays</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Off the coast of South America, the Pacific Ocean is warming up and a weather pattern is developing called &quot;El Nino&quot; that strikes fear in the hearts of farmers from India to Australia.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the U.S. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration's climatic prediction centre said ocean temperatures to the west of South America were the highest since August 1983 and an El Nino was in progess.</p>
<p>El Nino, or the boy child in Spanish, can have a profound effect on global weather patterns for as long as 18 months, depending on how rapidly ocean temperatures return to normal.</p>
<p>Oil World, a respected Hamburg-based agricultural newsletter, said on Tuesday the developing El Nino had increased the chance of drought across Southeast Asia, Australia and India, threatening oilseeds and grain crops.</p>
<p>But some meteorologists say it is still too early to predict the effects of the weather phenonomen this year, although dryer than normal conditions are already occurring in Indonesia and other parts of Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>India's annual southwestern monsoon rains, which broke over the southern and northeastern regions of the subcontinent on Monday, arrived 10 days later than usual.</p>
<p>The last major El Nino began in late 1991 and lasted until mid-1992. A less intense one occurred in 1994-95.</p>
<p>The 1983 El Nino, the most severe in recent memory, caused a searing drought in Indonesia, South Africa, Australia and the Philippines, triggered floods in South America and India and caused billions of dollars of damage.</p>
<p>&quot;The El Nino will cause a lot of misery for everybody,&quot; a veteran grains trader who remembers past El Ninos in 1988 and the devastating one in 1983 told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It's ominous. It's hanging over the market.&quot;</p>
<p>The result of interaction between warm sea temperatures which appear off the South American coast and atmospheric conditions, El Nino is a weather effect which has hit commodity production in Pacific nations for decades.</p>
<p>It was named by Peruvian anchovy fishermen in reference to the Christ child, to describe the appearance around Christmas of a warm ocean current off the South American coast, adjacent to Ecuador and extending into Peruvian waters.</p>
<p>R.R. Kelkar, a senior official at the Indian Meteorological Department (IMD), said on Wednesday it was too early to predict the impact of El Nino.</p>
<p>He said an update on the progress of the weather pattern and its impact on the monsoon would be possible only by the end of June.</p>
<p>Last month, the IMD predicted a &quot;normal&quot; monsoon for the 10th consecutive year. Nine of 16 measures the department monitors to predict the monsoon indicated rainfall would be about 92 percent of the long-term average.</p>
<p>But the IMD also said the El Nino pattern, near normal since 1995, was exhibiting an &quot;unfavourable trend&quot; this year.</p>
<p>Australian agricultural commodities, from grains to oilseeds to wool to beef, face possible severe production cuts this year or next because of the threatened drought from the El Nino effect now spreading across the southern Pacific and into the east of the country, analysts said.</p>
<p>Last week Australia's 1997/98 wheat crop was forecast by the government's Australian Bureau of Agricultural and Resource Economics (ABARE) at 19.2 million tonnes.</p>
<p>But commodities broker Phil Lindsay of Ord Minnett Jardine Fleming Futures said that if El Nino struck, the crop would struggle to reach even 14.5 million tonnes.</p>
<p>An official with Queensland grain cooperative Grainco, however, played down possible El Nino effects on crops in the northeastern Australian state.</p>
<p>&quot;First of all its got to come through. At this point its far too early for us to get too concerned about that far ahead. So we don't see that as being a major influence.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65-870-3080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
