<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653102" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Airport caps Britain's rich legacy to HK -- Patten.</title>
<headline>Airport caps Britain's rich legacy to HK -- Patten.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Governor Chris Patten on Wednesday visited a vast, bustling HK$70 billion (US$ 9 billion) construction site which will open as Hong Kong's new airport next year and invoked the project's rapid progress as an example of the territory's fabled efficiency.</p>
<p>It was the governor's last look at a perceived jewel in the crown of Britain's rich legacy to Hong Kong, to be handed back to China at midnight on June 30 after 156 years of colonial rule.</p>
<p>Patten will leave Hong Kong on the royal yacht Britannia immediately following the handover ceremony.</p>
<p>&quot;This of course is one of the very biggest civil engineering projects that the world has ever seen,&quot; Patten told reporters in the Chek Lap Kok airport's main terminal building, all but inaudible above the din of construction work around him.</p>
<p>&quot;The project is 80 per cent complete and on target to be completed in the late spring next year...I think we can take pride in the speed with which we do things and the competence with which we do things.&quot;</p>
<p>The airport project was delayed by years of wrangling between British and mainland Chinese officials. It replaces Hong Kong's existing but outmoded Kai Tak airport, freeing up a valuable waterfront site in Kowloon for commercial redevelopment.</p>
<p>Asked by reporters how he rated Britain's contribution to Hong Kong, Governor Patten responded enthusiastically.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the greatest legacy is that I'll leave Hong Kong immensely prosperous, very stable and with a rich fabric of civil society,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Patten made a symbolic flight into the airport on Wednesday, landing in a twin-engined government plane amid a site entirely reclaimed from Hong Kong harbour.</p>
<p>The governor waved a white hard-hat on arrival and then waded into a group of Airport Authority officials, shaking hands. Convoys of heavy construction vehicles could be seen lumbering across the horizon as scores of huge cranes pivoted against the sky.</p>
<p>Patten then entered the terminal building, walking past a jungle of scaffolding in a cavernous space.</p>
<p>In a pantomime staged for the benefit of television and still cameras, the governor then checked a suitcase at one of the terminal's baggage counters.</p>
<p>As the suitcase disappeared down the conveyor belt, Patten quipped: &quot;Well, the bag's gone to London slightly ahead of me.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
