<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653145" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Round-the-clock cartoon channel to debut in Japan.</title>
<headline>Round-the-clock cartoon channel to debut in Japan.</headline>
<byline>Ayumi Moriyama</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Popular cartoon characters like Tom and Jerry and Bugs Bunny are ready to keep Japanese kids glued to the television round-the-clock, as they &quot;toon in&quot; to Japan's first 24-hour animation channel.</p>
<p>Cartoon Network Japan will begin airing on September 1 as a joint offering by the Japanese units of Turner Broadcasting System Inc and Time Warner Inc, and giant Japanese trade house Itochu Corp.</p>
<p>The three partners said on Wednesday that the channel would feature Japanese and Western animation, including more than 10,000 titles from Time Warner's library ranging from Wacky Races and Popeye to Daffy Duck and Bugs Bunny.</p>
<p>Cartoons will be aired primarily in Japanese, although the original English will also be available for some programmes on a separate sub-channel, the companies said in a statement.</p>
<p>They added that they are still in negotiations with providers of Japanese animation programmes.</p>
<p>&quot;Cartoon Network Japan marks the first time a country-specific cartoon network has been created for the Asia-Pacific region, and emphasises the importance that Turner Broadcasting places on the Japanese market place,&quot; said Mike Byrd, managing director of Turner Broadcasting System Asia Pacific Inc, one of the project's three partners.</p>
<p>Time Warner Entertainment Japan Inc, another one of the partners, is a movie and television programme distribution venture formed by Time Warner, the U.S. West Media Group, Toshiba Corp and Itochu.</p>
<p>Turner already offers a 24-hour cartoon-and-movie channel in some countries of the Asia-Pacific region in languages including English, Chinese and Thai.</p>
<p>Cartoon Network Japan will be delivered to Japanese subscribers via satellite and cable providers, including PerfecTV, a satellite broadcasting venture headed by Itochu that began broadcasting last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Cartoon Network Japan is Itochu's first venture with Turner in the content field and the first Japanese network to air both Turner Broadcasting and Warner Bros material,&quot; said Akira Yokota, and executive vice president at Itochu.</p>
<p>Turner Broadcasting, a wholly owned subsidiary of Time Warner, offers the CNN news channel and other media and entertainment services, including cartoon channels in Europe and Latin America.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
