<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653219" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turks plans secondary mkt inflation-indexed bond.</title>
<headline>Turks plans secondary mkt inflation-indexed bond.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey is planning to develop secondary market trading for inflation-indexed coupon bonds -- the treasury's major borrowing instrument in the recent months, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Officials from the treasury, Istanbul stock exchange and the central bank met last week to discuss the details of the plan,&quot; a treasury official told Reuters.</p>
<p>The official said the plan was based on the idea of separating the principal and coupons of the bonds for them to trade separately on the secondary market.</p>
<p>&quot;This will improve the secondary market and make these papers more liquid. The risk premium banks bid to the treasury to buy these papers will drop when they become tradable on the secondary market,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>The treasury has sold a nominal of 559.37 trillion lira worth of two-year inflation-indexed bonds since early March at seven auctions.</p>
<p>Bankers say the papers hedge investors against any sharp rise in inflation, but the handicaps in trading them on the secondary market weakens demand for these bonds.</p>
<p>The official said the studies would be completed after taking the Finance Ministry's opinion on the taxation of the gains from secondary market transactions.</p>
<p>At present, the principal of these coupon bonds are exempted from income tax. But bond-holders pay witholding tax on coupon earnings and premiums on the principal amount.</p>
<p>-- Servet Yildirim, Istanbul Newsroom, 90-212-2747558</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
