<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653337" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Suffolk County, NY, advances plan to repay LILCO.</title>
<headline>Suffolk County, NY, advances plan to repay LILCO.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Suffolk County, New York, said its legislature has advanced a plan to raise the local sales tax to help back bonds that would be sold to repay Long Island Lighting Co, whose taxes were overassessed.</p>
<p>The director of the Suffolk County Legislature's budget review office explained that the county's plan would not interfere with Gov George Pataki's proposal for a partial state takeover of LILCO by the Long Island Power Authority.</p>
<p>The Authority in mid-March unveiled its plan to sell a total of $7.3 billion of bonds--which would be the nation's biggest ever sale of municipal bonds--to buy assets from LILCO and Brooklyn Union Gas, which are merging.</p>
<p>The transaction aims to lower electricity rates for Long Island residents, who now pay some of the highest prices in the United States. It also would pay for an approximately $1.2 billion state court judgement against Brookhaven, one of Suffolk County's 10 towns, which was found to have overassessed LILCO's shuttered Shoreham nuclear plant.</p>
<p>The deal, which has not been concluded between the two companies and the Authority, also has yet to win approval from Albany lawmakers. However, the Authority's executive director, Seth Hulkower, was receptive to the county's plan, saying: &quot;We're prepared to work with the officials in Suffolk County.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that the Authority in a couple of days expected to respond to a negative report on the deal that a citizen's advisory panel presented to the board at a Wednesday meeting. The Authority also expects to soon unveil its reaction to a critical analysis by an economist, Charles Studness, who questioned if it could carry such a big burden of debt.</p>
<p>Suffolk County's plan could save at least $603 million because it would sell a smaller amount of bonds--$390 million versus almost $463 million--with a shorter maturity--16 years versus 30 years--than the Authority, Fred Pollert, the county legislature's budget review director, told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>The proceeds of the bond sale would be paid to the Authority, which then could funnel the money back to the ratepayers, who were forced to pay higher electricity rates in part because LILCO's Shoreham plant was overassessed.</p>
<p>The bonds would be backed by a 0.25 percent rise in the county's sales tax as well as the county's full faith and credit, enabling the issue to be priced with lower interest rates than the Authority, Pollert said. &quot;In effect, it becomes a double-barreled bond.&quot; Raising Suffolk County's sales taxes by 0.25 percent would produce about $39 million of revenues and equalize rates with neighboring Nassau County.</p>
<p>The amount of money the county's plan could save could top the $603 million estimate, Pollert said, provided sales tax revenues, which have been rising about five percent a year, continue climbing. &quot;If, in fact, you have normal, historical growth in sales tax revenues, you can further shorten the bonds.&quot;</p>
<p>Under the Suffolk County plan, its residents and those who did not live in the county would get the same rate relief as the governor proposed. But the county projected it would have to pay just under $598 million in interest and principal, roughly half of the $1.2 billion that the Authority would have to pay.</p>
<p>The Authority would gain from the county's plan as it would free up capacity in the bond insurance market for the agency's bonds, Pollert said, adding Suffolk County typically finds it economic to insure its own debt.</p>
<p>County officials predicted that they would be able to go ahead with their plan to pay off the $1.2 billion tax certiorari even if the Authority's plan, which also needs a host of federal, regulatory approvals, were not approved.</p>
<p>&quot;Regardless of whether that plan goes through or not, we have to pay LILCO, and if the Long Island Power Authority plan unravels, we still would be faced with the tax certiorari. Ultimately, we would have to settle with the courts and LILCO on what the county obligation would be,&quot; said Warren Greene, a spokesman for the legislature.</p>
<p>Suffolk County has yet to take a stand on the Republican governor's proposal, but might do so as soon as about two weeks, when it expects to hear back from consultants it hired to study the plan. It already has asked bond counsel to begin drafting a bill needed for the proposed debt sale. Should Albany agree to the proposed increase in the county's sales tax, the legislature also would need to approve a bill for that, as well as one authorizing the bond sale.</p>
<p>((--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
