<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="65337" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Renault truck sales fall, mkt share steady.</title>
<headline>Renault truck sales fall, mkt share steady.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Renault said on Thursday its truck sales fell sharply in the first half of 1996 but that it hung on to its share of the U.S. and European truck markets.</p>
<p>Sales in the truck unit, which includes Renault VI (Vehicules Industriels) and Mack Trucks, fell to 33,640 in the first half from 36,900, a year-over-year drop of 11 percent.</p>
<p>The fall reflected an anticipated contraction in U.S. truck sales from last year's record levels and an unexpected relapse in the European market, the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>It said it expected European sales of trucks over five tonnes to slip four percent in 1996 to around 250,000.</p>
<p>Its share of the European market for trucks over five tonnes was 11.5 percent at the end of June, compared with 11.4 percent a year earlier. Its share of the market for trucks over 16 tonnes was 12 percent, compared with 11.9 percent.</p>
<p>In the United States, the market in Class 8 trucks (over 16 tonnes) is expected to fall 16 percent this year to around 170,000. Total first-half sales fell to 88,570 from 103,800, but Renault's market share rose to 12.1 percent from 11.8 percent.</p>
<p>Renault said its new products, a Magnum equipped with a 12 litre engine, and the Premium, which replaces the Manager and Major, would boost its competitive edge in a tough environment.</p>
<p>It said 5,000 orders had been received for the Premium between April, when it was launched, and the end of August -- nearly 45 percent of them outside France.</p>
<p>Renault last week reported its first-half results, which showed a sharp deterioration in the truck unit. Its operating income fell to 26 million francs from 519 million, and the company forecast an operating loss for the unit in the second half of the year.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
