<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653416" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Integrated Device sees weak Q1 results.</title>
<headline>Integrated Device sees weak Q1 results.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA CLARA, Calif. 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Integrated Device Technology Inc said Wednesday it expects earnings for its first fiscal quarter will be below analysts' expectations and its earnings for the preceeding quarter.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected the company to report first quarter earnings of $0.06 a share compared with profits of $0.11 a share in the year-ago period, according to First Call. The company said it expects to report a profit for its first quarter but that it will fall below fourth quarter levels.</p>
<p>The company had fourth quarter profits of $2.1 million, or $0.03 a share on revenues $143.2 million.  </p>
<p>Integrated Device said in a statement that revenues for the June quarter will be flat to slightly up compared with the fourth quarter. The company's book-to- bill ratio for the first quarter is expected to be about 1.0.</p>
<p>The company attributed the weaker than expected results to lower than anticipated demand, particularly in the PC-related business segments. The PC sector accounted for about 22 percent of Integrated Device's revenue in the most recent fiscal year.</p>
<p>&quot;We had strong bookings early in the month of April, but since then the order rate has softened,&quot; President and Chief Executive Len Perham said in a statement.</p>
<p>Perham said the weakness was concentrated in the static random access memory modules used in personal computers and to a lesser extent, logic components used by dynamic random access memory module vendors.</p>
<p>&quot;A slowing of PC-related demand, together with typical seasonal weakness in the summer months, are reasons to be cautious,&quot; Perham said.</p>
<p>He said he still expects significant revenue growth and improved profitability over the coming year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA CLARA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
