<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653450" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs close up, pork bellies down on cash ideas.</title>
<headline>CME hogs close up, pork bellies down on cash ideas.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME hog futures closed up on support from firmer cash hog markets while pork bellies ended lower, weighed down by weaker cash belly prices, traders said.</p>
<p>Hog futures closed mostly 0.725 to 0.100 cent per lb higher with June up most and July up 0.375 at 80.825 cents. Pork bellies finished 0.725 to 1.100 lower with July off 0.900 at 81.900 cents.</p>
<p>Expectations for steady to mostly higher cash hog markets again Thursday on light hog runs boosted hog futures, especially June which moved to a premium over the latest CME lean hog index after starting the day under, traders said.</p>
<p>June was rising in anticipation the index would be moving up into the June expiration on Friday. Some short covering demand in June also stemmed from the fact that there is no trading limit in the month the last two days of trade, they said.</p>
<p>The latest CME lean hog index was up $0.11 to $80.88 per cwt and June ended Wednesday at 81.600.</p>
<p>However, late resistance was evident in July from the continued weak tone to cash pork prices. Pork cut-out values slipped $0.82 to $0.91 per cwt on Tuesday and further losses were seen as product values were pressured at midday.  </p>
<p>Rand Financials, Cargill Investor Services and Dean Witter bought hogs early but Cargill sold late. Lind-Waldock sold August and local spreaders took the opposite side of the 'Goldman roll' to add to the pressure in August, In hog options, commission houses sold June 80 straddle, pit sources said.</p>
<p>Sharp declines in cash pork belly prices knocked belly futures lower, traders said.</p>
<p>Cash bellies fell to lowest levels since early May with USDA reporting 14-16 lb bellies at $74 to $77 per cwt early Wednesday, off $1 to $3 and others off $3 to $5.</p>
<p>Also, futures started the session with a large premium to cash and amid floor talk of expected heavy deliveries in July. Futures at a level higher than cash would encourage storings at a time of year when product generally moves out of storage, traders said.</p>
<p>However, belly futures showed a late rally as the trade was swept up in the strength in hog futures, bringing values in the belly pit near unchanged. Some buy stops were hit on the rally before selling by Cargill prompted renewed local selling and again pushed prices lower, traders said.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
