<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653525" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS - Sallie Mae fight seen ending in compromise.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Sallie Mae fight seen ending in compromise.</headline>
<byline>Cal Mankowski</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Signs that the long battle for control of Student Loan Marketing Association (Sallie Mae) were heading for a compromise finish helped boost the company's shares Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think you're probably going to see a middle-of-the-road course,&quot; said Thomas O'Donnell, analyst at Smith Barney Inc.</p>
<p>Lawrence Hough, president and chief executive of Sallie Mae, said he would step down to &quot;break the &quot;deadlock&quot; that has prevented both Sallie Mae management and an opposition group from gettng a majority of shareholders to back their competing plans.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the market likes it,&quot; O'Donnell said, noting that Sallie Mae shares were up 4-3/4 to 125 in early afternoon trade.</p>
<p>Following Sallie Mae's announcement in January that its board approved a reorganization that would end its ties to the U.S. government, the management has been sparring with a group called the Committee to Restore Value (CRV), headed by Albert Lord, a former chief operating officer of the company. The dispute with Lord go back to 1994, when Lord left Sallie Mae citing differences with management. A CRV slate of eight directors was elected to the Sallie Mae board in 1995.  </p>
<p>Both Sallie Mae management and the CRV have been seeking to have Sallie Mae privatize and end its government tie. But the two have differed on business strategy, with the CRV advocating a major role as an originator of student loans.</p>
<p>Sallie Mae has countered that if it originates loans it will impair relationships with hundreds of banks. Sallie Mae has since the 1970's been in the business of buying federally subsidized and guaranteed loans from banks and other lenders, then securitizing them in the market place. In an interview Wednesday, Sallie Mae vice chairman David Vitale said some banks have backed away already.  </p>
<p>A fundamental problem for Sallie Mae has been the decision of the Clinton administration in the early and mid-1990's to shift government involvement in student loans from subsidies and guarantees to direct lending. The government now has about one-third of the market. The Sallie Mae stock took a dive from $75 per share to $31 around 1993. It began recovering in 1994.</p>
<p>Although some of the recovery has been attributed to Republican gains in Congress and a belief that government would back off, the CRV and the Sallie Mae management have both claimed credit for pursuing business strategies that lifted the stock.  </p>
<p>Hough's announcement that he will resign after the company becomes private and a successor is named represented a major change in a situation that was thrown into confusion when the CRV and management both failed to win majorities for their privatization plans last month.</p>
<p>A new vote on competing slates of directors is now expected in July.</p>
<p>&quot;Regardless of the outcome of the election, there will be restraints on the winner,&quot; O'Donnell said. He believes there will initally be a moderate level of loan origination that will grow over time.  </p>
<p>Sallie Mae said Vitale, whose full-time job is vice chairman of First Chicago NBD Corp, would be proposed as non-executive chairman. It said it was proposing a slate with 10 nominees and room for five nominees to be named by the CRV.</p>
<p>But the CRV said it was not interested in being in a minority position on a slate headed by Vitale.</p>
<p>O'Donnell reiterated a buy on the stock and said he has a price target of $140 near term and $250-$300 in three to five years. But he said investors should be aware of the risk that a government intent on closing its budget gap could squeeze loans and guarantees. That, he said, could crimp Sallie Mae profits.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
