<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653545" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Democrats to block Senate action for second day.</title>
<headline>Democrats to block Senate action for second day.</headline>
<byline>Jackie Frank</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senate Democrats said Wednesday they will block legislation and prevent committees from meeting for a second day in their effort to persuade Republicans to release disaster relief funds.</p>
<p>President Clinton vetoed the $8.6 billion spending bill Monday and urged Congress to pass it again without political riders attached by Republicans to prevent a government shutdown this fall and to restrict the 2000 census to the traditional house-by-house count.</p>
<p>Senate Democratic Leader Tom Daschle, bleary-eyed from an all-night talkathon designed to draw public attention to the plight of states waiting for the disaster aid, remained firm that no legislation would be voted on in the Senate until the impasse is broken. His state of South Dakota is high on the list of those needing the funds.</p>
<p>During what they called a &quot;vigil&quot; for disaster victims, 40 Democratic members of Congress met in Daschle's office until 6 a.m. to participate in interviews with more than 75 radio and television stations across the country.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't think when I came to the U.S. Senate I would be talking at 2 a.m. with 'The Trucking Bozo,'&quot; said Sen. Byron Dorgan, a Democrat from North Dakota, who was interviewed on a nationwide radio programme aimed at truck drivers.</p>
<p>Democrats originally wanted to keep the Senate in session all night but were blocked in that attempt. Instead, they refused to give permission for any legislation to be brought to the floor or to allow any committee to meet.</p>
<p>Republicans in the House and Senate were divided on how to move the disaster relief legislation. House Republicans were willing to drop the government shutdown language but were standing firm on the need to prevent changes in the census. Senate Republicans took the opposite view.</p>
<p>Senate Republican Leader Trent Lott of Mississippi has also suggested Congress pass a scaled-down version that would address only emergency funding needs. But for the upper Midwest, where the construction season is short, full funding is necessary to release contracts for rebuilding roads, businesses and homes, Democrats said.</p>
<p>At least one senior Republican said after the veto it was time to negotiate with the White House. &quot;They've got the political leverage. They think they are winning the PR (public relations) battle, and perhaps they are,&quot; Sen. John McCain of Arizona said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Missouri Republican Sen. Christopher Bond told reporters, &quot;He has the right to veto the bill but because he vetoed the bill is the reason why the disaster assistance didn't go forward.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;And that's unfortunate,&quot; Bond said. &quot;Now, we have to figure out how to do it.&quot;</p>
<p>The bill provided $5.4 billion for disaster assistance in 32 states plus North and South Dakota and Minnesota, which were reeling from the worst floods of the century.</p>
<p>What raised Democratic ire was a Republican rider to guarantee federal agencies funding at the 1997 level if the Republican-led Congress and the Democratic White House failed to agree by the Oct. 1 start of the fiscal year. The White House and congressional Democrats see this as a strategem that would enable Republicans to prevail in spending disputes.</p>
<p>Another provision Clinton refused to accept would block the use of statistical sampling to try to account for people missed by the traditional census. Supporters say this would better count traditionally undercounted minorities in urban areas but opponents say the census should be a strict headcount.</p>
<p>The original bill also would have provided $1.9 billion to pay for military operations in Bosnia and the Gulf and $262 million for feeding poor women and their children, for education and for a new transportation system at Yosemite National Park. The rest of the money was earmarked for highway construction, veteran's benefits and other purposes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
