<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653562" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Northeast defends nuke outage costs.</title>
<headline>Northeast defends nuke outage costs.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Lewis</byline>
<dateline>HARTFORD 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Northeast Utilities said Wednesday it does not expect the public to foot the bill for any past mismanagement of its nuclear operations.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not seek recovery of any costs associated with the nuclear outages that we believe were the direct result of management imprudence,&quot; Northeast spokeswoman Myra Humphries told Reuters.</p>
<p>She was responding to sharp criticism of the utility by Connecticut Attorney General Richard Blumenthal, who said Wednesday that Northeast was trying to wiggle its way into getting consumers to pay for nuclear mismanagement.</p>
<p>The dispute stemmed from a state Department of Public Utility Control (DPUC) filing made by Northeast on Monday.</p>
<p>Northeast said in the required filing that its replacement power and nuclear outage-related costs for the April 1-June 30, 1996 period were $89 million.</p>
<p>The utility projected that its total costs from April 1996 through December 31, 1998, for outage recovery, system reliability and capacity projects, would be $990 million, Humphries said.</p>
<p>Blumenthal felt the DPUC document signalled a change in position by Northeast, which he said cited many of these costs as &quot;normal.&quot;</p>
<p>Humphries disagreed. &quot;We did not specifically quantify any amount we ultimately would seek recovery for, from customers,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;There may very well be prudent or normal costs folded into that ($990 million), but we have not determined what those costs would be. And whatever our determination would be, it would still go through DPUC prudency,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have said that we may seek recovery costs for some discreet maintainance projects, things that we would have had to do anyway, but we have not determined what those would be. No determination would be made until the plants went back online... This is not a backdoor thing,&quot; Humphries said.</p>
<p>Northeast's three Millstone nuclear power plants in Waterford, Conn., have been closed for safety reasons since March 1996. The company has said it intends to have all three plants ready for restart by early 1998, pending approval by federal regulators.</p>
<p>Northeast's other nuclear plant, Connecticut Yankee, was permanently shut down last December after safety concerns arose last July.</p>
<p>&quot;It's important to note that customers are not paying a dime now for the nuclear outages, for replacement costs, or for reliability projects for the capacity situation,&quot; Humphries said.</p>
<p>She said the utility is &quot;cautiously optimistic&quot; that customers will not suffer power brownouts or blackouts in the hottest days of the summer.</p>
<p>Northeast has taken &quot;extraordinary measures&quot; to mitigate the possibility, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;In Connecticut we pretty much have everything in place that we had last summer... the additional generation that we installed, the reactivated units are still on line, we have special contracts with customers for them to curtail their usage, we have increased our transmission imports into the state,&quot; Humphries said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've gone though maintainance projects both in our transmission lines and also our generating units in the state. We have a fairly comfortable reserve margin on a peak load day, if everything is available.&quot;</p>
<p>--Hartford newsroom (860) 727-0224</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARTFORD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
