<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653613" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mich. court backs schools in funding mandate issue.</title>
<headline>Mich. court backs schools in funding mandate issue.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Michigan Supreme Court justices upheld a ruling for school districts challenging an old education funding formula, but have asked for more information before deciding what remedy to apply to the case.</p>
<p>Michigan Gov. John Engler had been appealing a lower court judgment of $492 million for 84 school districts that contended the state Constitution required funding for certain education and special education programs.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court on Tuesday said Michigan had to provide state funding for the programs under a formula since replaced, but also asked attorneys to submit additional briefs before deciding whether the districts are entitled to compensation.</p>
<p>An attorney representing the districts and a spokesman for the governor both said they were pleased by the decision in the 17-year-old case that has now been before the Supreme Court four times.</p>
<p>&quot;We are delighted that the Court has vindicated our position after the 17 long years in which it has taken us to try this suit,&quot; said Dennis Pollard, who represents the school districts.</p>
<p>But Engler spokesman John Truscott said the state admitted it had some liability and the Supreme Court's request for more briefing on the question of a remedy makes the governor optimistic that Michigan will not have to pay a judgment to the districts.</p>
<p>&quot;While the Supreme Court may have found the state at fault and in violation of the Constitution they have questioned whether we had to pay damages or not and that was our major issue,&quot; Truscott said. &quot;Our major concern was the potential for damages.&quot;</p>
<p>Pollard estimated before oral arguments in April that the state would owe the districts more than $600 million with interest on the September 1995 decision.</p>
<p>The state budget office had estimated that Michigan could face a liability of up to $3.5 billion for retroactive and future claims from school districts statewide.</p>
<p>The order affirmed the lower court's decision awarding the school districts their costs, including attorney fees.</p>
<p>The briefs requested are to address whether the school districts can receive compensation and, if so, what a reasonable payment schedule would include and to whom the money should be distributed, the court order stated.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court also directed attorneys to address whether compensation should include interest and how to calculate the amounts owed.</p>
<p>The order gives the parties 21 days to submit their briefs and seven days for replies before the Supreme Court will issue a written decision in the matter with no extensions.</p>
<p>((--David Bailey, Chicago Newsroom, 312-408-8647))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
