<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653600" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORECAST--U.S. May PPI seen up, but still subdued.</title>
<headline>FORECAST--U.S. May PPI seen up, but still subdued.</headline>
<byline>Jose Paulo Vicente</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. wholesale inflation data, spurred by mild increases in some food categories, will probably show a bit of a rise in May after four months of consecutive declines, Wall Street analysts said.</p>
<p>But tame energy prices were likely to offset most of the incipient upward pressures on the Producer Price Index (PPI) in May, they said, adding that overall wholesale inflation continued to be fairly subdued.</p>
<p>The Labor Department will release its May report on the Producer Price Index on Friday at 0830 EDT/1230 GMT.  </p>
<p>&quot;Some information I have shows that some food prices are rising ... and certainly increases in coffee prices have been widely discussed,&quot; said Carol Stone, senior economist at Nomura Securities International Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;There is some upward pressure there, although it's certainly not going to be alarming,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>In a Reuters poll, economists forecast on average the PPI would post a 0.1 percent rise in May against a 0.6 percent decline in the previous month. The core index, which excludes food and energy price fluctuations, was also seen up 0.1 percent in May against a 0.1 percent drop in April.  </p>
<p>Analysts said energy prices were seen mostly contained in May, particularly oil derivatives. Gasoline prices, for example, are expected to be lower this summer than they were a year ago, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;Energy prices should be down, and hold (the index) down in May,&quot; Astrid Adolfson, vice president at MCM MoneyWatch Inc. &quot;Our sense right now continues to be that there is no inflation in the manufacturing sector.&quot;</p>
<p>Also, analysts said the firmness of the dollar against key major currencies most likely continued to work as an invisible hand holding domestic manufacturing prices down.  </p>
<p>&quot;Manufacturers are still having a difficult time passing on any price increases ... with the competition from imports and other things,&quot; Adolfson said. &quot;It just confirms we have a very low inflation environment.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts also cited some Wall Street talk of heavy discounting in the automobile sector, which could hold down car prices in the May PPI report.</p>
<p>Pundits said core intermediate prices were expected to continue to show very soft inflation as well.  </p>
<p>&quot;You should be looking for the same subdued advance in prices that we've seen in the PPI for some time,&quot; said Michael Moran, chief economist at Daiwa Securities America Inc.</p>
<p>If the May PPI numbers falls in line with expectactions, analysts said the Federal Reserve might leave interest rates unchanged once again during the July 1-2 meeting of its policy-setting body.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they will have no reason to change policy right now,&quot; MCM's Adolfson said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Manufacturers are telling (Fed Chairman Alan) Greenspan everyday: 'How can you worry about inflation? We can't raise prices,'&quot; Adolfson added.</p>
<p>Nomura's Stone said she is also expecting the Fed to stand pat at the next meeting, but added that &quot;it's still a very close call.&quot;</p>
<p>The Fed last tightened monetary policy on March 25, when it boosted its target for the federal funds rate by 25 basis points to 5.50 percent.</p>
<p>The Fed left rates unchanged during the latest meeting of its policy setting body, on May 20.</p>
<p>(( -- 212-859-1676 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
