<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653778" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian gold ends lower, silver steady.</title>
<headline>Indian gold ends lower, silver steady.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Silver (.999) lost its modest gains from early trade to close steady at 6,800 rupees per kg on Wednesday, dealers said.</p>
<p>It opened five rupees higher at 6,805 rupees per kg following a mild recovery due to demand at lower price levels, dealers said.</p>
<p>Silver lost 95 rupees in the last two trading sessions on a lack of demand from individual consumers as well as industrial users, they said.</p>
<p>Standard gold (24 carats) closed 15 rupees lower at 4,665 rupees per 10 grammes on a weak world trend and poor local demand.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no demand for gold at all,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;We need to wait for at least two months for the market to revive.&quot; Gold last gained 10 rupees per 10 grammes on Friday.</p>
<p>Dealers said demand for bullion disappeared with the conclusion of the traditional wedding season in May. Some rural demand is expected to emerge around August when the progress of monsoon rains and winter crops is known, the dealers added.</p>
<p>Gold biscuits (116.50 grammes) lost 200 rupees to 54,600 rupees per piece.</p>
<p>(Conversion $1=35.78 rupees)</p>
<p>-- Bombay Newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
