<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653820" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India call ends firm as SBI stays away, gilts rise.</title>
<headline>India call ends firm as SBI stays away, gilts rise.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian call money closed steady at 7.00-8.00 percent on Wednesday, dealers said.</p>
<p>The lowest deals were at 6.50 percent, they said.</p>
<p>The absence of a leading lender State Bank of India from the market on Wednesday led to sudden increase in call rates, which touched a high of 9.25 percent before closing at 7.50 percent, a dealer at state-run bank said.</p>
<p>The call rates are expected to open at 8.50-9.00 percent on Thursday but ease to 7.00 percent towards the close, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is sentiment-driven rather than a demand-supply driven,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;The market is flush with funds, and there is no need to panic,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An outflow of funds towards a seven-year bond auction and advance tax payment later this month will not affect the market, dealers said.</p>
<p>The bond market saw buying interest in mid-term securities, Umesh Gupta, a dealer at Mata Securities said.</p>
<p>Security prices rose by 10 to 15 paise despite of the low volume at 3.15 billion rupees compared to the previous 3.75 billion rupees, Gupta said.</p>
<p>The 12.14 percent government stock 2000 rose to 100.70 rupees compared to previous 100.50 rupees, 12.69 percent 2002 to 101.30 rupees from 101.25, 13.40 percent 1999 to 104.40 rupees compared to its last traded value of 104.10 rupees, Gupta said.</p>
<p>The certificate of deposit for one year maturity was quoted at 11.50/12.00 percent and six-months maturity at 10.00/10.25 percent. The P1+ rated commercial paper for three months maturity was quoted at 9.50/9.75 percent.</p>
<p>--- Suresh Gonsalves, Bombay Newsroom +91 22 265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
