<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653894" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Lebanon to set up $350 mln road company.</title>
<headline>Lebanon to set up $350 mln road company.</headline>
<byline>Zeina Soufan</byline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Lebanese government approved on Wednesday a plan to set up a $350 million Lebanon Toll Road Company to finance and construct about 100 km (60 miles) of roads and motorways across Lebanon.</p>
<p>&quot;The creation of a private company has been approved by the cabinet today in principle,&quot; Minister of Public Works Ali Harajli told Reuters after an evening cabinet session.</p>
<p>The plan comes after the government decided to scrap initial deals worth $1.65 billion with French companies Dumez and Bouygues and German companies Dywid AG and Walter Bau AG after they &quot;failed to raise needed funds for the project.&quot;</p>
<p>Finance Minister Fouad Siniora told Reuters that the government entrusted the Investment Development Authority of Lebanon (IDAL), a government agency, with calling on investors to form ALTROC's founding committee.</p>
<p>The project does not need the approval of parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;First of all, we will start contacts through investment banks in order to assess the scope of interest of potential investors. We have to really measure the response of the prospective investor,&quot; Siniora said.</p>
<p>The starting capital was calculated at one third of the total cost of construction which amounts to over $1 billion, said Harajli who expected the company &quot;to be set before the end of the year&quot;.</p>
<p>Under the plan approved by cabinet and obtained by Reuters, LATROC's capital would comprise 70 million shares -- each with a nominal value of $5, open for Lebanese and foreign subscription. Thirty percent should remain in Lebanese hands.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Lebanese can raise all the 350 million that's fine. If they can't we don't mind at all, on the opposite we go for Arab capital as well as foreign capital, which I think will mainly come from institutions,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The plan also gives the company the right to issue bonds and convertible bonds. Siniora said it could raise funds on international money markets.</p>
<p>&quot;All the company shares except guarantee shares (held by members of the company's board) become immediately susceptible to transfer of ownership and they are traded on the Beirut bourse,&quot; the written plan said.</p>
<p>Siniora said the project was an important step in &quot;enriching Lebanon's financial market and deepening it...Once it happens it is very good.&quot;</p>
<p>The French companies Dumez and Bouygues had initially won a $1.2 billion BOT (Build, Operate and Transfer) contract to build a 60 km (38 mile) toll motorway from Beirut to Syria's border and an 11 km (seven mile) stretch of ring road round southern Beirut provided they secured needed financing.</p>
<p>The German companies along with Bouygues were also initially awarded a $450 million BOT project to build the remaining 26 km (16 miles) of road north of Beirut under the same financing condition. Both deals were agreed upon in late 1995.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri told reporters after the session that the small size of the foreign companies' capital prevented them from securing needed financing.</p>
<p>&quot;That was the original problem. They set it at $125-$150 million and this is why they found it difficult to find necessary money,&quot; Hariri said.</p>
<p>He said a company with a larger capital base stood better chances of getting funding on money markets. &quot;Then the company can divide the projects into smaller ones and award them to Lebanese companies.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020041">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
