<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="654226" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada to name new financial services minister.</title>
<headline>Canada to name new financial services minister.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's next junior minister for financial institutions will be long-time member of parliament Jim Peterson, Canadian newspapers reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The 55-year-old Peterson, from the Toronto area, is to work under the Finance Minister as the secretary of state for financial institutions, the Toronto Globe and Mail and the Ottawa Citizen said.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Jean Chretien is to announce a new cabinet on Wednesday morning after his Liberal party was voted back into power in a federal election on June 2.</p>
<p>Chretien has settled on a sweeping cabinet shuffle, but one that leaves his overall economic direction intact.</p>
<p>Most importantly, Finance Minister Paul Martin will be reappointed, showing financial markets that the government plans to stay the course on deficit reduction and tight fiscal management.</p>
<p>Peterson, formerly head of the House of Commons finance committee, will work under Martin.</p>
<p>The former secretary of state for financial institutions, Doug Peters, retired at the end of the last parliament.</p>
<p>Canada's big banks and financial institutions will likely be lobbying the new minister to lift a surtax on banks and further deregulate the banking industry.</p>
<p>And foreign bankers will be watching to see if the new minister lightens restrictions on foreign investment in the banking sector.</p>
<p>In other economic portfolios, Canadian newspapers and television reported that Marcel Masse is expected to stay as head of the Treasury Board and John Manley is to keep his industry ministry portfolio. But Art Eggleton is expected to move over to the defence ministry, to be replaced by Sergio Marchi, the former environment minister considered to be on the left wing of the Liberal Party.</p>
<p>Agriculture will be filled by eastern Ontario's Lyle Vanclief, former chairman of the Standing Committee on Agriculture. Ralph Goodale, the former minister of agriculture, is expected to move over to Natural Resources, in charge of energy and mines.</p>
<p>((Reuters Ottawa Bureau 613 235-6745))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
