<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="654238" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt envoy on Mideast mission on Thursday.</title>
<headline>Egypt envoy on Mideast mission on Thursday.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak's political adviser, Osama al-Baz, will meet separately with Israeli and Palestinian leaders on Thursday in an attempt to organise another round of talks between the two sides.</p>
<p>Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussa told reporters on Wednesday that Baz's meeting with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Palestinian President Yasser Arafat would determine whether a second round of negotiations would take place this week under Egyptian auspices.</p>
<p>&quot;Osama al-Baz will come tomorrow. He'll meet with President Arafat and Prime Minister Netanyahu. After that, there will be a reassessment and a decision will be taken on what steps should follow,&quot; agreed top Palestinian negotiator Saeb Erekat.</p>
<p>A senior Israeli official said it was unlikely that a three-way meeting of negotiators would take place before the weekend.</p>
<p>A PLO official said he did not expect a breakthrough even if such a meeting took place. &quot;I doubt the Israelis would make acceptable proposals,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>Peace talks have been frozen since Israel began a new Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem in March. Palestinians have demanded Israel halt construction before peace talks can resume.</p>
<p>Egypt, which sees itself an unofficial sponsor of the Middle East peace process, intensified its role after U.S. envoy Dennis Ross failed in April to break the deadlock.</p>
<p>PLO officials said they expected Washington to actively resume its mediation efforts next month.</p>
<p>Israeli and Palestinian negotiators met formally for the first time in more than two months in Cairo on Sunday in a meeting attended by Baz.</p>
<p>The Egyptian mediator and Israeli officials said at the end of the talks that some progress had been made and that the two sides planned to meet again, but a Palestinian official was not as positive on what the talks had achieved.</p>
<p>Moussa said statements by Netanyahu on Tuesday that Israel would not return all the land it occupied in the 1967 Arab-Israeli war would condemn to failure any peace efforts.</p>
<p>Netanyahu had told Reuters television in an interview in Jerusalem: &quot;There has to be an adjustment of the Palestinian ideological goals to reality. Arafat has to stop talking about a return to the '67 lines&quot;.</p>
<p>Responded Moussa: &quot;These kind of statements are what create difficulty in the peace process. If this is the position, then failure is the fate of all ongoing efforts.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There is still a lack of complete understanding of the situation because peace cannot prevail unless it is balanced and it cannot be based on the imposition of the opinion of one side on the other. These statements are very harmful,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
