<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="654294" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Qatar leader stresses security of U.S. Gulf forces.</title>
<headline>Qatar leader stresses security of U.S. Gulf forces.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The emir of Qatar said on Wednesday that security of U.S. forces in the Gulf is a major priority, and he planned to discuss sharing defense intelligence in the region.</p>
<p>At the start of a meeting with Defense Secretary William Cohen, Emir Hamad bin Khalifa al-Thani said Qatar had taken special precautions to safeguard U.S. forces, notably an Air Expeditionary Force, stationed there.</p>
<p>&quot;With this in mind, it is also my goal to identify further opportunities to share defense intelligence on security threats in the region,&quot; Hamad said through a translator.</p>
<p>Hamad, who also serves as Qatar's defense minister, was scheduled to meet with President Bill Clinton later on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Asked directly what message he would take to Clinton with regard to U.S. policy toward Iran and Iraq, Hamad replied, &quot;It is natural that since the United States is a friendly country we must discuss frankly all the matters concerning security in the region. The United States has interests in the region and so do we.&quot;</p>
<p>In an interview published on Wednesday in the Washington Post, Hamad said he could not endorse the U.S. strategy of &quot;dual containment&quot; of Iran and Iraq.</p>
<p>Hamad said in the interview that the United States should work to develop better ties with Iran after the election last month of moderate leader Mohammad Khatami.</p>
<p>&quot;With Iran, you have no more excuses,&quot; he was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Hamad stopped short of saying sanctions against Iraq should be lifted, but said the &quot;Iraqi people have suffered enough&quot; because of the embargo imposed by the U.N. Security Council after Iraq invaded Kuwait in 1990.</p>
<p>Hamad told the paper the main purpose of his trip was to promote a November regional economic summit conference in Qatar's capital, Doha, the fourth of such conferences promoting Arab-Israeli ties.</p>
<p>He cited pressure to cancel the conference because of the breakdown in Israeli-Palestinian peace talks but said his country continued to support the peace process. &quot;We are a peaceful country and we want to see peace in the area,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
