<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="654402" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: LSI sees Q2 results in line with consensus.</title>
<headline>LSI sees Q2 results in line with consensus.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-06-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>LSI Logic Corp said it expects second quarter results to be in line with Wall Street's consensus.</p>
<p>&quot;We anticipate LSI Logic's second quarter financial results will be in line with second quarter consensus estimates,&quot; chief financial officer Doug Norby said in a statement to the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;Moreover, we expect sequential revenue growth in the third quarter,&quot; the statement added.</p>
<p>The statement was released to the media after the market close late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Earlier, LSI shares plunged 13 percent amid concerns that the computer chip maker's revenue growth could be less than expected in the September quarter.</p>
<p>Stock in LSI, based in Milpitas, Calif., fell $5-1/8 to $34 on New York Stock Exchange trading of 8.72 million shares, making it the second-most active issue on the Big Board.</p>
<p>In after-hours trade it edged down another 1/4 point to 33-2/4, dealers said.</p>
<p>Norby's statement came after after an analyst at San Francisco-based investment bank Montgomery Securities wrote in a research report that the company was &quot;being cautious regarding prospects.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We still expect LSI to deliver growth in the third quarter, but it may be lower than our prior expectations of a nine percent increase from (the June quarter),&quot; analyst Clark Westmont said in the report.</p>
<p>LSI books its orders from customers a few months in advance, so its backlog should be in place by now, Westmont said.</p>
<p>He said he will keep earnings forecasts for the September quarter unchanged until June quarter results are released.</p>
<p>Earlier in the day, Robert Sison, LSI's manager of investor relations, had said the company had not released any new information and that company executives were not available for further comment due to business meetings abroad.</p>
<p>LSI's major customers include Cabletron Systems Inc, Intel Corp and Seagate Technology Inc -- all of which have warned in recent days that they face a slower-than-expected second quarter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
