<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="65468" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IBM offers voluntary buyout to U.S. staff.</title>
<headline>IBM offers voluntary buyout to U.S. staff.</headline>
<byline>Therese Poletti</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>International Business Machines Corp. said Thursday it is offering a voluntary buyout programme to an unspecified number of its U.S. employees as it seeks to rebalance the skills of its work force.</p>
<p>An IBM spokesman said the Armonk, N.Y.-based computer giant was offering the buyout to certain support staff in various businesses nationwide. He said employees who decide to accept the deal will leave IBM by the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not giving any figures on the number of people we are offering the programme to,&quot; said an IBM spokesman. &quot;We simply do not know how many will accept.&quot;</p>
<p>The spokesman pointed out that even with the buyout plan, IBM expects its U.S. personnel to grow in 1996, from 110,000 staffers in 1995, as the company builds up its computer services business. IBM had 225,000 employees worldwide at the end of 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;The key is the total number of U.S. employees at the end of 1996 will be greater than the 110,000 we had at the end of 1995,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Only employees who have been with IBM for more than five years are eligible, because in recent years the company has been hiring experienced people with critical skills.</p>
<p>Analysts said the move is aimed at getting 6,000 to 10,000 employees worldwide out of its slower growth areas.</p>
<p>Layoffs are likely before the end of the year if not enough employees accept the buyout offer, they added. Others may also be offered jobs at IBM's faster-growing units, such as its services business, which has added about 10,000 staff this year and plans to add 4,000-5,000 more before year end, they said.</p>
<p>Analysts do not expect a charge for the buyout plan, because IBM has told analysts to include $800 million for restructuring costs into their financial models this year.</p>
<p>IBM's stock was unchanged at $124.50 on the New York Stock Exchange in late morning trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
