<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="654754" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Granada edges up after top-end H1 profits.</title>
<headline>Granada edges up after top-end H1 profits.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Granada Group Plc nudged higher in pre-market trade on Wednesday after the media-to-hotels group posted first half profits at the top end of most analyst expectations, dealers said.</p>
<p>The stock was up 1p at 903-1/2 by 0702 GMT, extending a rebound since it dropped to a six-month low of 849-1/2 on June 4.  </p>
<p>&quot;Profits are at the top end of expectations but the dividend looks at the low end, though that's probably understandable given their high debt levels,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;But I think the meeeting will be more important, people will be looking to see how they are progressing their disposals and at the underlying growth of the former Forte businesses.&quot;</p>
<p>However, the analyst noted a strong performance in Granada's hotels businesses, with yield for instance up 16 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Hotels look to be having a storming time, with yield and occupancy rates very good...it suggests they bought Forte at a good time.&quot;</p>
<p>Chairman Gerry Robinson said all four of Granada's divisions had performed strongly. &quot;We will continue to grow these businesses organically and maximise the benefit of the tremendous assets that the company now has.&quot;</p>
<p>Chief executive Charles Allen added that the &quot;first few weeks of the second half are showing an encouraging start to trading.&quot;</p>
<p>-- David Holmes, London Newsroom +44 171 542 4367</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
