<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="654816" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: DB says Warriors' performance a concern.</title>
<headline>DB says Warriors' performance a concern.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>DB Group Ltd, primary sponsor of the Auckland Warriors rugby league team, said on Wednesday the poor performance of the team this season was a concern.</p>
<p>DB was reviewing its sponsorship obligations but the brewer remained committed to seeing out the rest of the contract.</p>
<p>The Warriors have performed badly so far this season and are currently at the bottom of the Telstra Cup rugby league table.</p>
<p>The Warriors had benefitted the DB Bitter brand in its initial two years but that was no longer the case in the third, chief executive Erik Korthals Altes told a news conference.  </p>
<p>DB's contract with the Warriors has two years to run &quot;and we will be loyal to that to the bitter end.</p>
<p>&quot;That doesn't say that if the Warriors are privatised that we may have discussions with the new owner ... whether he was interested in naming rights,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Korthals Altes said big sponsorship by breweries was becoming a thing of the past &quot;when it was a matter of them or us and the price would ratchet up to very high levels.</p>
<p>&quot;We are reviewing all these kinds of commitments and relating them back to the real volumes that you are talking about,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Sponsorship had in the past been important because of a ban on television liquor advertising, which has since been lifted.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at sponsorships in a marketing sense, a sponsorship is definitely something to increase brand awareness, but now we have so many other, and maybe better, means to do that, we have to re-evaluate sponsorships in that mix.</p>
<p>&quot;It was very dominant and it will be much less dominant in the future as we re-negotiate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom +64-4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
