<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="654906" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia installs general as information chief.</title>
<headline>Indonesia installs general as information chief.</headline>
<byline>Ian MacKenzie</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's army chief of staff General Hartono swapped the sword for the pen on Wednesday when he was installed as new information minister on his retirement after 35 years as a soldier.</p>
<p>President Suharto swore Hartono in at the state palace, making him the first new face in the cabinet since the current government was formed in 1993.</p>
<p>He replaced Harmoko, a former journalist who had served as minister for 14 years in three cabinets.</p>
<p>Harmoko, who is also general chairman of the ruling Golkar party, becomes minister for special affairs and is tipped to become speaker of parliament when the House of Representatives meets again in October following the May 29 general elections.</p>
<p>Hartono was succeeded as army chief of staff by General Wiranto, the former commander of the strategic reserve (Kostrad) who is regarded as a potential successor to General Feisal Tanjung as chief of the armed forces (ABRI).</p>
<p>Hartono's appointment took the country by surprise, and analysts said they were still assessing the implications.</p>
<p>Hartono, who reached the extended military retirement age of 56 on Tuesday, told reporters after his installation he would first study his new job at the information ministry.</p>
<p>&quot;I will continue things that are good and improve those things that need improvement,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>There has been speculation in the media that his appointment might herald a crackdown on an increasingly free-wheeling press following the May 29 general elections in which Golkar won a sweeping victory.</p>
<p>The election campaign was the most violent in three decades and received open coverage in the media.</p>
<p>&quot;We are keeping a wary eye on him. It's too early to say what the implications are,&quot; one analyst said. Another analyst said however Hartono had broad experience in dealing with the public and the media as army chief.</p>
<p>The new minister, soberly dressed in a dark double-breasted suit and grey pattern tie, was in a jovial mood after his installation, answering questions and cracking jokes with reporters.</p>
<p>He is regarded as close to the Suharto family and has been mentioned as a possible vice-presidential running mate with Suharto if the president -- as is widely expected -- seeks a seventh five-year term in office next March.</p>
<p>Hartono is from the strongly Moslem island of Madura off the East Java coast. Political analysts said he raised some eyebrows, particularly in the military, when he wore a yellow Golkar jacket during the election campaign.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
