<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="655142" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: INDONESIAN STOCKS - factors to watch - June 11.</title>
<headline>INDONESIAN STOCKS - factors to watch - June 11.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main factors likely to affect Indonesian stocks on Wednesday:</p>
<p>* The Dow Jones industrial average roared past yet another milestone on Tuesday, rising 60.77 to close at a historic high of 7,539.27, reflecting a market that remained awash in cash.</p>
<p>* Indonesia said on Tuesday that Japanese officials had asked for a cut in import tariffs on automobiles brought into the country and that the proposal was being studied.</p>
<p>MARKET</p>
<p>* On Tuesday, the Jakarta composite index was down 2.74 points at 689.77 points on continued local-led profit-taking focused on medium and small stocks, brokers said.</p>
<p>* On Wednesday, the rupiah was quoted at 2,427.50/28.00 at 0210 GMT, compared with an opening of 2,428.00/29.00.</p>
<p>STOCKS TO WATCH</p>
<p>* Blue chip Bank Negara Indonesia on market talk of a possible merger with another state bank Bank Tabungan Negara. The speculation was revived by reports in a local newspaper which said the government will merge the seven state banks into four banks.</p>
<p>* Bank Duta after it said that it will pay 130 rupiah dividend for 1996 compared with 125 rupiah in 1995.</p>
<p>* Glass maker Asahimas following the firm's announcement that it expected its export sales to grow to 34.0 percent of total net sales for 1997, compared to 28.5 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>* Bank Panin after its shareholders approved a plan for a 14-for-7 rights issue with three attached warrants at a price of 1,200 rupiah each.</p>
<p>* Consumer finance firm PT Bunas Finance after the company indicated that its first quarter net profit was 135 percent higher compared with the same 1996 period.</p>
<p>* Bank Mashill following reports that Bank Brussels Lambert of Belgium has bought a 10 percent stake from its outstanding shares in the market.</p>
<p>* Confectionery firm Mayora Indah on reports that its planned 300 billion rupiah bond had received an &quot;A &quot;rating from Indonesia's rating agency Pefindo.</p>
<p>* Small paper manufacturer Suparma on reports that it has received shareholder approval to acquire privately-owned PT Siantar Maju at an estimated value of 9.9 billion rupiah.</p>
<p>* PT Apac Centertex Corporation , formerly known as Mayatexdian, on a plan to build a pulp plant in Kalimantan with annual production capacity of over 300,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>* Shipping and sea transportation company PT Berlian Laju Tanker on reports that it had secured a $68 million syndicated loan. It will be used to purchase 10 chemical tankers.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
