<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="655265" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - FRANCE - JUNE 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - FRANCE - JUNE 11.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in this morning's Paris newspapers.</p>
<p>-- President Jacques Chirac says he hopes France will be ready next week to sign stability pact limiting the budget deficits of countries that join the single European currency after Prime Minister Lionel Jospin requested a delay to study the stability pact and emphasised need for social measures and economic policy coordination. (Les Echos, La Tribune, Le Figaro, Liberation).</p>
<p>LES ECHOS</p>
<p>-- The planned shutdown of a Renault assembly plant in Vilvoorde, Belgium may be delayed in view of report by independent expert appointed to review alternative solutions, due in a fortnight.</p>
<p>-- Public deficits expected to reach 3.3 to 3.8 percent of GDP in 1997 according to some Finance Ministry forecasts.</p>
<p>-- Germany's Dasa denies that an agreement has been reached between the four partners in Airbus consortium about its future status.</p>
<p>-- U.S. court orders businessman Giancarlo Parretti to pay CDR holding company selling off Credit Lyonnais assets 1.5 billion dollars over loan to buy MGM studios in 1990.</p>
<p>-- Consortium including France Telecom loses ground to Italy's Stet in race for privatisation of Spanish television network Retevision.</p>
<p>LA TRIBUNE</p>
<p>-- Investigation into alleged insiders' trading in Eurotunnel in 1994 to widen to London and the United States.</p>
<p>-- Havas media group chairman Pierre Dauzier says in an interview the company must press ahead with its strategy. Eric Licoys named managing director of Havas.</p>
<p>L'AGEFI</p>
<p>-- Schneider chairman Didier Pineau Valencienne confirms turnover growth goal of five percent for 1997.</p>
<p>-- Renault chairman Louis Schweitzer said he expects profits for 1997.</p>
<p>LE FIGARO-ECONOMIE</p>
<p>-- Eurotunnel shareholders expected to make conditions to their approval of the company's financial restructuring plan, at shareholders' meeting on July 10.</p>
<p>LIBERATION (Economic section)</p>
<p>-- European Commission seeks legal action against French farmers linked to attacks on Spanish lorries in Southern France.</p>
<p>THE INTERNATIONAL HERALD TRIBUNE</p>
<p>-- Possible restrictions on ownership of media companies, called for by new culture minister Catherine Trautmann, hit media stocks.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5381</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
