<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="655284" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: FEATURE - Greece renews bid to retrieve Parthenon marbles.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Greece renews bid to retrieve Parthenon marbles.</headline>
<byline>Dina Kyriakidou</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Oh, Greece beloved, your sacred objects plundered by profane English,&quot; Byron lamented when the British diplomat Lord Elgin sent the Parthenon's marble sculptures to London nearly 200 years ago.</p>
<p>Byron's outrage may be music to Greece's ears as it launches a new crusade to retrieve the exquisite classical era sculptures from the British Museum but such passionate rhetoric has done little to sway the British government.</p>
<p>Shattering long-nurtured Greek hopes that a Labour government would be more sympathetic to the request, Heritage Secretary Chris Smith flatly turned down Greek demands just days after Tony Blair's May 1 election victory.</p>
<p>&quot;It's something that we had a look at over the course of the last five years; we decided it was not a feasible or sensible option and we won't do it,&quot; Smith told the BBC.</p>
<p>Greece, refusing to take 'no' for an answer, is determined to renew its efforts to recover what are considered some of the finest examples of art from the Golden Age of Athens.</p>
<p>GREEK DETERMINATION</p>
<p>Culture Minister Evangelos Venizelos has vowed to write to the British government on the issue and approach Smith at the next European Union culture ministers' meeting on June 30.</p>
<p>&quot;The most important monument of Western civilisation is mutilated. The Parthenon itself demands its Marbles back,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>The fifth century BC Doric temple on the Acropolis is seen as the crowning glory of classical Greece.</p>
<p>Gods and mortals in flowing robes and flying mantles, beasts and mythical monsters in battle or processions designed by antiquity's finest sculptor, Pheidias, adorned its exterior.</p>
<p>Thomas Bruce, seventh Earl of Elgin, then British envoy to the Ottoman court in Istanbul, stripped much of its surviving inner frieze and most of the pedimental sculptures and shipped them to England.</p>
<p>In 1816 he sold the sculptures, known in Britain as the &quot;Elgin Marbles&quot;, to the British Museum, where they took pride of place and became the object of a lengthy dispute between Greece and Britain.</p>
<p>Greece's late culture minister, the actress Melina Mercouri, lent her glamour to a campaign in the 1980s, winning a promise from then Labour leader Neil Kinnock that should his party return to power, the marbles would be returned home.</p>
<p>&quot;We are practical enough and fair enough not to consider that a binding committment,&quot; said Mercouri's husband, American film director Jules Dassin, who has been continuing her campaign as president of the Melina Mercouri Foundation.</p>
<p>But the campaign will be intensified to convince the public that it is morally and aesthetically right for the Marbles to return to bask in the light they were created for, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have learned that as soon as people really know the history and the facts they say 'Oh my God, they should go back'. It's a matter of education,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>ELGIN CONTROVERSY</p>
<p>At the centre of the moral argument is Elgin himself, seen by some as art lover and benefactor but by most Greeks as pilferer of a nation's heritage and destroyer of one of humanity's greatest achievements.</p>
<p>He admittedly stretched the powers of a permit secured at the Ottoman court, allowing him to collect inscriptions and slabs from the Acropolis, and his crews greatly damaged the temple in their rushed efforts to remove the Marbles.</p>
<p>&quot;They were obviously in a hurry. Instead of removing things slowly and safely they hacked away and mutilated. They pushed three-tonne ledges from 15 metres (yards) high, shattering them and damaging the base of the temple,&quot; said Manolis Korres, the architect heading a major restoration project at the Acropolis.</p>
<p>Elgin's defenders say he saved the Marbles from the ravages of earthquakes, looting and, most recently, pollution.</p>
<p>Athens' notorious smog has damaged monuments and forced experts to move all remaining sculptures on the Acropolis indoors.</p>
<p>Greece admits the chances are very slim that Britain would even consider returning the marbles until a long-awaited Acropolis museum is built near the Parthenon to house them.</p>
<p>Construction of an Italian-designed museum, chosen after an international competition, is expected to start later this year, Venizelos said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will obviously point out the absence of the marbles (in the new museum),&quot; he said. &quot;The void will be manifest.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain's reluctance to give up a treasure -- even if it secretly admits it was seized under dubious conditions -- also hinges on a more broad-based concern.</p>
<p>&quot;...if you start embarking on questioning where particular works of art are located around the world, then you get into all sorts of difficult areas of discussion,&quot; Smith told the BBC.</p>
<p>&quot;You're going to have swaps of works of art taking place throughout the entire world, disrupting everything.&quot;</p>
<p>An international argument has surfaced in recent years that antiquities are best appreciated when displayed near their place of origin, disturbing museums whose collections are based on artefacts collected from far-away lands over the centuries.</p>
<p>&quot;Is this some part of a post-colonial guilt trip,&quot; asked a European Union diplomat, quickly dismissing the controversy.</p>
<p>But Greece, eager to appease such concerns, insists it is making a special case for the Parthenon Marbles and will not seek its numerous works of art from museums around the world.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a unique case because it is part of a monument,&quot; Dassin said. &quot;We are talking about re-integrating a whole.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
