<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="655305" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: DB SEES FALL IN BEER SALES SLOWING DOWN.</title>
<headline>DB SEES FALL IN BEER SALES SLOWING DOWN.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>DB Group Ltd said on Wednesday it saw the ongoing decline in beer sales slowing later this year.</p>
<p>The brewer earlier reported a NZ$17.2 million first half profit against $16.0 million a year earlier. Market expectations were for net profit of around $15-16 million.</p>
<p>DB said first half Heineken sales had outstripped optimistic forecasts.</p>
<p>DB said the New Zealand market would continue to be highly competitive for all products in its beer, wine and spirit brand portfolios.</p>
<p>&quot;The ongoing decline of the beer market is expected to slow down in the later part of the year,&quot; it said in a commentary.</p>
<p>While spirits and liqueur volumes were starting to reduce, this was being offset by what the company called &quot;huge growth&quot; in its ready-to-drink range.</p>
<p>In the wine market DB said it was expected that an ongoing market shift from casks (boxes) to bottles would continue.</p>
<p>&quot;The directors have every confidence that the group will produce a satisfactory result for the full year based on the consistent implementation of brand-building policies in all its core markets,&quot; the statement added.</p>
<p>In its comment on Heineken, the company said first half sales had outstripped &quot;the most optimistic forecast&quot;, but gave no more specific details.</p>
<p>DB Group is majority owned through a Heineken NV , Fraser and Neave Ltd joint venture.</p>
<p>The firm restructured its balance sheet in May, resulting in the cancellation of three out of four fully-paid shares, and analysts say one of the wider implications of the rejig will be to make the company a net payer of interest in the second half.</p>
<p>--Wellington newsroom +64 4 471 4273</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
