<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="655437" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sonat's Ryon misses target on first try.</title>
<headline>Sonat's Ryon misses target on first try.</headline>
<dateline>BIRMINGHAM, Ala. 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sonat Inc said Thursday the Ryon No. 1 well drilled to a total depth of 12,650 feet and failed to encounter the Cotton Valley Pinnacle Reef target identified on 3-D seismic data.</p>
<p>Analysis of petrophysical information indicates the presence of a limestone layer in the overlying Bossier Shale, which likely caused a false indication of the actual location of the reefal limestone buildup, Sonat said.</p>
<p>The company said it is proceeding to obtain additional borehole seismic surveys to verify the actual reef position, after which the well will be sidetracked to the new target. Sonat said the re-drilling will likely begin in about a week. It has a 59 percent interest in the well while a 30 percent interest is held by United Meridian Corp and nine percent by Energen Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;This was a very big well,&quot; according to Howard Weil analyst Susan Weaver. &quot;It would have extended the Cotton Valley Pinnacle Reef trend north,&quot; she explained.</p>
<p>Sonat's stock was down 2-1/4 to 53-5/8 in late trading. Unioted Meridian was off 1-5/8 to 32-3/4. But Energen was up 38 to 34-1/2.  </p>
<p>Stating &quot;Sonat is a great company and they are going to have some dry wells,&quot; Weaver said she was recommending her clients buy the shares on the weakness.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the Cotton Valley Pinnacle Reef trend, Sonat said, the Blazek No. 4 in the Bear Grass area, on which operations were suspended after failure to find the target reef, has been successfully sidetracked into the target and has drilled about 120 feet into the reef with good gas shows.</p>
<p>The company said its Sonat Exploration Co subsidiary believes the well should be another Pinnacle Reef discovery.</p>
<p>In addition to the Ryon No. 1 and Blazek No. 4 operations, Sonat Exploration is presently drilling five other Pinnacle Reef wells, the company noted.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BIRMINGHAM, Ala."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
