<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="655425" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dow soars as interest rate concerns dissipate.</title>
<headline>Dow soars as interest rate concerns dissipate.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. blue chips roared to their fifth straight record finish on Thursday, riding a renewed wave of optimism on the outlook for interest rates.</p>
<p>The Dow industrials surged 136 points to end unofficially at 7711 after a surge that pushed the blue-chip average over both the 7600 and 7700 hurdles for the first time.</p>
<p>The catalyst for the rally came directly from the bond market, where interest rates tumbled after the release of fresh data that suggested U.S. economic growth has moderated from a torrid first-quarter pace.  </p>
<p>The speed of the rally, coupled with very heavy volume that approached 600 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange, left the impression that investors were almost tripping over themselves to join the advance.</p>
<p>&quot;We now have all the fence-sitters jumping in,&quot; said Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter Ltd. &quot;I had figured we'd pause at 7500, but here we are two days later and 200 points higher.&quot;</p>
<p>Almost lost in the blistering buying spree were new caution signals on the outlook for semiconductor bellwether Intel Corp.  </p>
<p>Shares in Intel fell 3-27/32 to 143-21/32 after several Wall Street firms lowered ratings or earnings estimates on the company. Intel also announced price reductions on its high-end MMX family of processors.</p>
<p>But in contrast to just two weeks ago, when an Intel warning about its near-term profit outlook rattled Wall Street and sent much of the market tumbling, investors largely brushed off the latest developments.</p>
<p>&quot;That may have been the most bullish aspect of today's action,&quot; said Marshall Acuff, portfolio strategist at Smith Barney. &quot;The market just shook it off and really roared.&quot;  </p>
<p>Financial and cyclical stocks were among the strongest, although the rally was broadly based, with more than two stocks gaining for every one that fell.</p>
<p>BankAmerica Corp rose 2-5/8 to 129-5/8, First Union Corp gained 1-7/8 to 93-1/8 and Merrill Lynch and Co jumped 1-3/8 to 59-3/4.</p>
<p>To be sure, the market faces a bit of a test Friday, with release of the May Producer Price Index (PPI), analysts said.</p>
<p>The report, a gauge of wholesale prices, has remained stubbornly low month after month, and economists are expecting a meager 0.1 percent rise for May.  </p>
<p>If prices rise more than expected, the market could fall into retreat, analysts said. On the other hand, a tame inflation report would provide yet another sign the economy is operating exactly the way investors like -- moderate growth without inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now, you ask 'What's wrong with this picture?' and you get silence,&quot; said Hugh Johnson, chief investment officer at First Albany. &quot;I just wonder how long it can last.&quot;</p>
<p>Among individual issues, Polo Ralph Lauren Corp jumped 5-1/2 to 31-1/2 in the company's market debut after an initial public stock offering.  </p>
<p>VISX Inc slid six points to 22-1/4 after the maker of laser systems for eye surgery said its earnings for the second quarter and year would fall short of expectations.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P 500 index rose 13.89 points to 883.46, a record.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite rose 3.47 points to 1411.32.</p>
<p>((-- Wall Street desk, 212-859-1730))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
