<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="655786" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Options-Coffee volatility mixed, cocoa still quiet.</title>
<headline>Options-Coffee volatility mixed, cocoa still quiet.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coffee options volatilities were mixed this week as investors tried to figure out which direction coffee would take next.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, cocoa options remained fairly inactive despite a steep rise amid active futures trading that pushed July and September to fresh contract highs.</p>
<p>In coffee, traders said July volatilities rose to 100 percent or more across the board with only six days left to trade.</p>
<p>But September volatilities slid about 10 percent this week. Traders pegged implied at-the-money September volatility near 64 percent, down from the mid- to high-70s a week ago.</p>
<p>November volatility was seen about flat, between 58 and 59 percent.</p>
<p>Traders attributed the drop in September to forecasts of warm weather moving into Brazil as well as a calmer, more rangebound market in the past couple of days.</p>
<p>&quot;They are probably discounting a frost,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Coffee options activity was also mixed, with skew favouring neither puts nor calls. Most trading was also done earlier in the week, traders said.</p>
<p>They said options have quieted as investors digest coffee's violent gyrations in the past few weeks. New York arabica futures hit 20-year highs last month but quickly fell back to six-week lows on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Traders said activity in London's July coffee options continued to centre around out-of-the-money calls between about $1,900 and $2,800.</p>
<p>In September, traders saw mostly local interest in September $1,700 calls and puts.</p>
<p>In cocoa, options remained quiet with only about 75 contracts changing hands on Thursday despite a futures buying frenzy.</p>
<p>By midday, 25 September 1,000 puts and 50 September 1,025 puts changed hands. Traders said locals were the main buyers of the 1,025-stg puts at 24.5 percent voaltility.</p>
<p>July and September cocoa futures scored new contract highs on worries that the developing El Nino weather pattern would cause drought in many cocoa-producing regions, including Southeast Asia and the Ivory Coast.</p>
<p>Talk that Ivory Coast settings for the new crop also buoyed prices, traders said.</p>
<p>Funds joined the buying spree after July and September drove through triple resistances to break out of a flag formation on the charts, traders said.</p>
<p>But options activity has remained subdued as underlying futures prices moved swiftly. Traders speculated that once cocoa futures settle down, options might pick up.</p>
<p>Implied at-the-money cocoa options volatilities were slightly up for the week as of Wednesday's close but slightly lower from Tuesday due to the lack of interest. At-the-money implied July volatility was about 22.5 percent, down from 27 percent earlier in the week, traders said.</p>
<p>September was seen between 22.5 and 23.5 percent and December near 24.5 percent.</p>
<p>--Medora Lee, London newsroom +44 171 542 8072</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
