<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="655827" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: North and Central America port conditions - Lloyds.</title>
<headline>North and Central America port conditions - Lloyds.</headline>
<text>
<p>Port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service --</p>
<p>CANADA, June 11 - Vancouver, B.C. - GRAIN - 6 Vessels loading, 6 waiting. Delays of 5-7 days expected, depending on grade to be loaded with higher quality grades giving longer delays. Situation expected to continue for foreseeable future. Roberts Bank - COAL - 2 Vessels loading, 3 waiting, 16 due by end-June. 18 Vessels/positions nominated for July. Prince Rupert - GRAIN - 1 Vessel loading, 2 waiting. Terminal full butrying to get right grades for waiting vessels. Delays 3-5 days.</p>
<p>HONDURAS, June 7 - Puerto Cortes - Four vessels berthed loading/discharging containers, 1 awaiting berth to load/discharge containers. 12 Due of which 7 to discharge (5 bananas, 1 potash, 1 ammonium sulphate), 4 to load/discharge containers and discharge wheat, 1 passengers/vehicles. June 9 - Four vessels berthed loading/discharging containers/general cargo. 23 Due of which 1 passenger, 12 to discharge/load containers/general cargo, 6 to discharge/load containers/bananas, 3 to discharge (1 wheat, 1 corn, 1 lpg), 1 to load lumber.</p>
<p>MEXICO, June 10 - All ports working normally. Tampico - Five vessels in port of which 1 general cargo, 1 steel coils, 1 coke, 1 minerals, 1 under repair. Altamira - Five vessels in port of which 1 cars, 1 steel coils, 1 lpg with butadiene, 1 under repair, 1 fertiliser. Veracruz - 16 Vessels in port of which 1 steel coils, 3 sugar, 3 containers, 2 general cargo, 2 minerals, 3 grain, 1 pipes, 1 scrap. Manzanillo - 10 Vessels in port of which 2 cement, 3 general cargo, 2 containers, 1 fertiliser, 2 minerals. Coatzacoalcos - 17 Vessels in port of which 7 chemicals, 9 oil tankers, 1 under repair.</p>
<p>PANAMA, June 9 - Cristobal, Balboa - Working normally. Panama Canal lane outages for maintenance and repairs at Pedro Miguel for 8 hours daily 9-13/6, at Gatun 8 hours on 11/6 and at Miraflores 6 hours daily 9-14/6. Position 9/6, 39 vessels due, 15 in queue, 8 booked, 33 scheduled. 8/6 Actual arrivals 34, transits 38. Average of booked and non-booked canal waters time 19.3 hours.</p>
<p>UNITED STATES, June 9 - Jersey City, NJ - One vessel in port. Port Newark, NJ - Three vessels in port. Port Elizabeth, NJ - Five vessels in port. Perth Amboy, NJ - One vessel in port. Bayway, NJ - One vessel in port. Cartaret, NJ - One vessel in port. All northern New Jersey ports working normally, with no congestion/delays. Baltimore, MD - Port working normally. 6 Bulkers, 2 container vessels, 1 ro/ro, 2 auto vessels, 1 tanker, 2 general cargo vessels. 2 cable vessels on stand-by, 2 bulkers awaiting berths of which 1 to discharge sugar, 1 awaiting orders. Hampton Roads, Va - Four general cargo/container vessels berthed and operating 1 bulker discharging cement, 1 tanker discharging crude oil, 1 vessel berthed at layberth. Honolulu, HI - Honolulu harbour - 1 Container vessel, 4 tugs and barges berthed. Honolulu anchorage - 1 Bulk carrier. Barbers Point harbour - 1 Barge berthed. Barbers Point off port mooring - No vessels.</p>
<p>EAST COAST - Baltimore, MD - No congestion at Dundalk terminal anticipated this week. Clear C and D Canal/Baltimore harbour. Elevators and coal operations working well, with no delays. Average waiting time at Consol Coal 3 days. Liquid bulk facilities working normally with no berthing congestion. Anchorage available at Baltimore and Annapolis. Charleston, SC. - Dredging along the Columbus Street terminal continues again this week. The I-HI cranes at the Wando Welch terminal will be receiving some routine maintenance, but this should not have any adverse effects on cargo operations. There are no vessels scheduled for the grain elevator. Oil facilities are running without delay. Jacksonville, FL - No heavy berthing congestion or delays for the ports of Jacksonville or Fernandina Beach, FL. Miami, FL - No heavy traffic expected at either Miami or Everglades.</p>
<p>New York, NY - Congestion at Stapleton anchorage and in tanker terminals. No congestion at Bay Ridge anchorage or sugar terminals. Norfolk, Va - Southern Coal pier - 11 Vessels due during this week. Dominion terminal - 7 Vessels due. Pier IX terminal - 4 Vessels due during next week. Norfolk - Southern Coal - Pier 6 will, effective June 1, 1997, increase the cost of vessel docking, shifting and undocking (all services) from .0.23/nrt to .0.25/nrt. Cargill - No vessels due during the coming week. Container and general cargo terminals working normally, with no delays. Oil and bulk terminals also working normally. All channels open, with prevailing depths available. Philadelphia, PA - No congestion in the ports of Philadelphia, Camden or Wilmington. No dredging, repairs or navigational problems. Savannah, GA - Garden City - Terminals are expecting heavy congestion early in the week. Ocean terminals are expecting a steady week.</p>
<p>East coast terminal is expecting a moderate week, with no delays expected. Colonial marine terminals bulk clay facility expects long delays. Savannah sugar refinery will be busy with a couple of ships and a barge. All bulk liquid facilities are working normally, with no congestion expected. Navigational conditions remain normal. Weather conditions are seasonal. As the weather warms, afternoon thunderstorms may cause some downtime on weather-sensitive cargoes.</p>
<p>GULF COAST - Houston, TX - Port congested for vessels requiring open docks. This will last until next week. Congestion also exists in some oil/chemical terminals and private terminals for break-bulk cargo such as Greensport and Manchester. Farmland grain elevator has been under repair until 4/6, but public grain elevator has been open, with no delays. New Orleans, LA - Seasonal rains occurring which cause delays in cargo operations, especially grain. River stage at 8.9 feet and expected to rise to 11.5 feet by 15/6. High river conditions will cause delays in ship movements and vessel transit times. Bar pilots advise that the draft for the Mississippi river gulf outlet will be 36 feet. Present max. permissible draft at SW Pass is 46 feet fresh water for vessels under 100,000 dwt, 45 feet fresh water for vessels over 100,000 dwt. All vessels advised to maintain sufficient air draft for transit under the bridges in Mississippi. Some elevators not working weekends due to slower than usual grain shipments.</p>
<p>WEST COAST - Columbia river - High water conditions continue to slow vessel transits and in certain cases bulk loading productions due to vessels sitting too high in the water to place loading spouts into cargo holds. Cargill - Terminal 4 recently had a fire in their north loading spout system. Coos Bay, OR - The past week has been slow. Only one wood-chip carrier is due at Roseburg dock early in the week. Two lumber vessels are scheduled in latter part of the week. Coos Bay channel deepening project to recommence after 1 July. As reported earlier, upper shipping channel silted in from last winter's heavy rains/landslides. Port authorities re-estimated over 1,000,000 cubic yards of unwanted silt/mud moved into shipping channel, closing one terminal and forcing another to apply for emergency dredging to stay open. Authorities expect dredging to be completed late autumn/early winter, first deepening the shipping channel then dredging private terminals.</p>
<p>Honolulu, HI - Honolulu and Barber's Point traffic is medium for forthcoming week. Several auto carriers scheduled for discharging at piers 32-33. Delays may be experienced for vessels wishing to use these berths. Off-port bunkering expected to proceed with no delays as long as wind direction remains from the E-NE. Long Beach, CA, Los Angeles, CA - No congestion at bulk terminals. Port of Los Angeles conducting dredging operations to widen the entrance into the western basin. Construction projects at new coal terminal continue (piers 300-400). Facility may open in October/November this year. Early next year, dredging in port of Los Angeles main channel scheduled, deepening the channel from 45-50 ft. San Francisco, CA - Port of Sacramento has had its draft restriction raised. The new guidelines, as set forth by the pilots, allow for maximum transit draft (fresh water) of 30.5 feet. The port of Stockton is still operating under the existing guidelines (32 feet fresh water, with no delays experienced). The w</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
