<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="655884" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwean shares continue firmer on Thursday.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwean shares continue firmer on Thursday.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe's industrial index closed firmer on Thursday, feeding on continued speculation that the May annual inflation figure would be lower than expected, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said inflation was expected to go down on the back of a reduction in the weighting of food in the all-items consumer basket, which market analysts say is exaggerated at 29.2 percent and distorts the overall inflation figure.</p>
<p>High inflation of around 22.4 percent and consequently higher interest rates, had lured investors away from the bourse to the neighbouring local money market.</p>
<p>But on Thursday the key industrial index added 130.28 points to close at 10,424.56. Counters to advance included tobacco firm Rothmans which lept 500 cents to 5,000 while Zimbabwe Sugar Refineries went up 125 cents to 1,500 and bankers Barclays were 100 cents firmer at 3,500.</p>
<p>Steel door and window manufacturers Radar and cool drink company Schweppes both posted 50 cent gains to 450 and 360 respectively while plate and glass firm PGI and clothing retailer Edgars both climbed 30 cents higher to 450 and 780 respectively.</p>
<p>Minings continud dull with nickel producer Bindura five cents down at 800, the only counter to trade. The seven-share index slipped 2.65 points to 997.05</p>
<p>--Stella Mapenzauswa, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
