<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="655950" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - CZECH REPUBLIC - JUNE 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - CZECH REPUBLIC - JUNE 12.</headline>
<text>
<p>PRAVO - According to polls from IVVM, the opposition Social Democrats (CSSD) would obtain 28 percent of the vote if an election were held compared with 20 percent for the leading party in the governing coaliton, the Civic Democratic Party (ODS).</p>
<p>- The cabinet considers it possible for production in Poldi Steel to be renewed by Liechtenstein Blax Corporation working together with Poldi's bankruptcy administrator, Tomas Pelikan.</p>
<p>- On May 31, the National Property Fund held shares in 615 joint-stock companies amounting to 192.91 billion crowns, of which more than 172.45 billion is made up of shares of 54 strategic companies.</p>
<p>- New Finance Minister Ivan Pilip left his post in parliament on Wednesday in order to focus all his attention on his new post.</p>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Next week, the cabinet will discuss proposals on methods of privatising the two largest domestic banks, Komercni Banka and CSOB, which are completely controlled by the state. The cabinet will also soon decide on privatising its stakes in 16 energy distribution companies.</p>
<p>- Yesterday, the crown strengthened to 6.4 percent below its former central parity, which is the largest climb for the crown since the fluctuation band was cancelled.</p>
<p>- Opposition representatives did not succeed in parliament yesterday with their proposals to delay deregulation of rents and energy prices, which the cabinet previously approved for July 1.</p>
<p>- Shareholders of Ceskomoravska Zarucni a Rozvojova Banka approved an increase in basic capital of 185 million crowns from net profits from 1996.</p>
<p>- The Czech Army wants to sell 100 T-72 tanks to Algeria. According to Defence Minister Miloslav Vyborny, the transaction should be mediated by Omnipol.</p>
<p>MLADA FRONTA DNES - The Senate approved larger social support for families with low incomes after deregulation of rents in July.</p>
<p>- According to the Czech top 100 from ING Bank and Resources, the two largest Czech companies are Skoda Automobilova and CEZ.</p>
<p>- According to spokesman Martin Svehla, the Czech National Bank will receive a loan in the next few days of $1.5 billion or more from a group of foreign banks made up primarily of Chase Manhattan, Commerzbank, SBC Warburg and JP Morgan.</p>
<p>- Raiffeisenbank won a tender to become the new partner of customs authorities to ensure their financial services after the bankruptcy of Kreditni Banka.</p>
<p>- Ceskoslovenska Obchodni Banka had net profits for the first quarter of this year of 577.4 million crowns, when its gross profits before reserves and correction items reached 1.6 billion.</p>
<p>- After a one-year delay, Aero Vodochody will present its new L-159 fighter aircraft to the public today.</p>
<p>LIDOVE NOVINY - A new law on unemployment, which the cabinet should discuss today would cut the budget's expenses by 220 million crowns and decrease support for the unemployed by 10 percent.</p>
<p>- The chairman of the railway workers union, Jaromir Dusek, said cuts in the government budget, which decrease funding for Czech Railways by 200 million crowns, are unacceptable. If Dusek cannot reduce these cuts in talks with the Transport Ministry, the union is prepared to take radical steps.</p>
<p>- The first general meeting of the Central Energy Dispatcher will be held today in order to set work tasks for this union of manufacturers and distributors of electricity.</p>
<p>- In its last meeting, the banking council of the central bank approved Expandia's request to enter Zemska Banka. Now Expandia, the third company allowed to enter the banking market this year, could obtain 100 percent of shares in the bank.</p>
<p>- The two-day conference of Justice Ministers from member countries of the European council ended yesterday with a resolution over relations between corruption and organised crime.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 420-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
