<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656016" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: Olainfarm rebounds, dominates Latvian bourse.</title>
<headline>Olainfarm rebounds, dominates Latvian bourse.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Market newcomer Olainfarm rebounded on the Latvian bourse on Thursday and accounted for the lion's share of trade, but dealers remained divided over its value.</p>
<p>Overall market volume rose to 112,000 lats from 56,000 lats and the Rietumu index slipped 0.94 percent to 154.44.</p>
<p>Olainfarm, which lost almost 15 percent on Wednesday, leapt to 2.40 lats from 2.09 lats in trade of 91,700 lats.</p>
<p>Some dealers said that the pharmaceutical company, which made its bourse debut on Monday, has good long-term prospects and that its poor first quarter results do not give a clear picture of its potential. Others were less generous.</p>
<p>&quot;The price seems to be held up artificially and its real value to my mind is closer to a bit over one lat,&quot; a dealer with Saules Bank told Reuters.</p>
<p>Most official list stocks held steady with only Unibanka easing. It lost 0.6 percent to 3.33 lats in trade of 1,000 lats.</p>
<p>Overall, dealers were in a bearish mood.</p>
<p>&quot;No drastic changes are expected in the coming weeks,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;Local resources seem to have been drained and only an injection of foreign funds will liven things up,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Ed Stoddard, +371 721 52 40</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
