<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656232" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - June 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - June 13.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE DOMINION</p>
<p>Car dealer loses licence for &quot;clocking&quot; amid clampdown: A car dealer accused of &quot;clocking&quot; used import vehicles had its licence suspended and witnesses' costs of $9500 awarded against it at an industry hearing in Wellington on Thursday. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Cost could stop building says minister: Tender prices for building the proposed ministerial wing were more likely to stop the government from going ahead with the $94 million project than a negative report from a select committee, minister in charge of the building Don McKinnon said on Thursday. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>State bosses to get pay boost in bid to attract 'top' people: State Services Minister Jenny Shipley announced on Thursday that public sector bosses' pay would be boosted, after concerns about a widening gap with the private sector. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>PM considers charging for OIA requests: Prime Minister Jim Bolger is considering charging for information requested under the Official Information Act. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Meat giant to take over NZ Casing: Giant meat company Anzco is taking over one of the world's five biggest natural sausage casing companies, New Zealand Casing Company, partly owned by former Rugby Union chairman Eddie Tonks. Page 11.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Results will improve says Contact Energy: Contact Energy's dissappointing financial performance was not sustainable over the long term, Contact chairman Phil Pryke said on Thursday. Page 11.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Disclosure law 'close to useless': The government's financial products disclosure regime, set to come into force in October, would be costly, &quot;close to useless&quot;, and could mislead some investors, according to a report. Page 12.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Tax audits increasing, accountant warns: The Inland Revenue Department is increasing the frequency of audits of businesses, according to accountants BDO Hogg Young Cathie. Page 12.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE NEW ZEALAND HERALD</p>
<p>Clocked car redress funds tight: Buyers seeking refunds for clocked cars will have to move swiftly or they may miss out.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Probe launched into Skellerup prospectus: The Registrar of Companies has begun a formal investigation into the Skellerup bond prospectus over whether investors in the $77 million issue were misled.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Food chain attracts big players: National Mutual and Bankers Trust have each taken a five percent holding in the newly-listed Restaurant Brands.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Power NZ eyes Mercury link: Power New Zealand has formed a subsidiary, Power New Zealand Generation, that is considering investing in electricity plants developed by the Takapuna-based company's main rival, Mercury Energy.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>F&amp;P confident Cellnet has sound future: Fisher and Paykel believes it has a future as an independent cellular service provider despite a difficult operating market for its Cellnet division, which racked up $2 million in bad debts in the 1996/7 financial year.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE PRESS</p>
<p>The cold facts of winter in Chch: Winter is not looking good in Christchurch. People face a state house rent rise; a government decision on abolishing the South Island power-price differential that gives cheaper power to the south; and moves to reduce smog, which could include an open-fire ban. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Winebox parties win extra time: The Cook Islands tax commission of inquiry received another setback on Thursday with an agreement that the parties need not file their closing submissions for another ten days. Page 5.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>BIL associate to start on Indonesian power project: Construction will start this month on a US$660 million (NZ$964 million) geothermal power project being developed by a Brierley Investments Ltd associate in Indonesia. Page 14.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
