<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656276" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: UK, China lock horns on HK 19 days before handover.</title>
<headline>UK, China lock horns on HK 19 days before handover.</headline>
<byline>Diane Stormont</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>With just 19 days left before Hong Kong reverts to Chinese rule, Beijing and London locked horns on Thursday over China's troop deployment plans and Britain decision to boycott of part of the ceremony.</p>
<p>Britain flatly rejected Beijing's request to admit more Chinese troops to the colony before the formal transfer ceremony at midnight on June 30 so the People's Liberation Army (PLA) could be in position for the historic moment.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question of Britain agreeing to the deployment of the main PLA garrison in Hong Kong before July 1,&quot; said British Foreign Office spokesman Bill Dickson.</p>
<p>&quot;Britain is the sovereign power and is responsible for the defence of Hong Kong up to the last stroke of midnight on June 30 and that is when China assumes its sovereign responsibility.&quot;</p>
<p>The clash deepened a handover rift over British Prime Minister Tony Blair's decision to boycott the latter half of the grand handover ceremony when Beijing will inaugurate an unelected, post-handover legislature to replace the territory's current elected body.</p>
<p>The plan to install the chamber promptly after the flag change, in the presence of international dignitaries who came for the handover celebration, put Blair and VIPs from other countries that contest the legitimacy of the provisional legislature in a diplomatic bind.</p>
<p>Australia, however, dashed British hopes of a unified Western stand by putting national interest first and declining to join the United States and Britain in shunning the post-midnight investiture ceremony.</p>
<p>Frequent Sino-British disputes have marred Hong Kong's 13-year transition to Chinese rule under the terms of a 1984 treaty, but relations plummeted to an all-time low over mild democratic reforms instigated by the British governor Chris Patten.</p>
<p>China, infuriated by the last minute changes, vowed to wipe them out by dissolving the reformed Legislative Council returned in 1995 by one million voters.</p>
<p>In its place goes the Provisional Legislature, a 60-member chamber chosen by a hand-picked panel of 400 pro-Beijing worthies in Hong Kong and denounced by the territory's democratic lobby as a travesty of democracy.</p>
<p>Australian Prime Minister Michael Howard said on Thursday that Canberra had to put its own national interest first.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't disguise the fact that China is a very illiberal, undemocratic country,&quot; Howard said in a television interview. &quot;But...it is in Australia's national interest to build a sound relationship with China.&quot;</p>
<p>Future Hong Kong leader Tung Chee-hwa, senior government officials and top judges will also be sworn in during the ceremony in the first few hours of July 1. The timing of the inauguration was decided by a China-backed committee.</p>
<p>Henry Tang, a member of Tung's inner council, said there were no plans to change the agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an event that is a Chinese people's event and we will not be swayed by those who don't belong here,&quot; Tang said.</p>
<p>More than 4,000 guests invited by Britain and China are expected to witness the extravagant joint handover ceremony marking the end of Britain's once-sprawling empire in Asia and what China regards as 156 years of humiliation.</p>
<p>Heir to the throne Prince Charles and Foreign Secretary Robin Cook will attend as Britain's top representatives.</p>
<p>Political analyst Michael DeGolyer said discord between Beijing and London over Patten's democratic reforms had set the stage for the &quot;awkward dispute&quot; surrounding the ceremonies.</p>
<p>The handover would be a matter of &quot;you have your party and I'll have mine&quot;, with any interaction between the British and Chinese kept as formal and ceremonial as possible, said DeGolyer, director of a long-term study on the transition based at Hong Kong's Baptist University.</p>
<p>China ended months of speculation on Wednesday by announcing that President Jiang Zemin would lead its delegation, the first visit to the territory by a Chinese head of state.</p>
<p>Hong Kong police have liaised with their Chinese counterparts, but they alone will be responsible for protecting Jiang during his fleeting visit, police chief Eddie Hui said.</p>
<p>Jiang will accept the transfer of sovereignty from Prince Charles, then remain just long enough for the swearing-in of the new administration before flying home for China's own gala celebrations of the return of Hong Kong to the fold.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
