<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656220" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chilean board confirms Enersis ruling.</title>
<headline>Chilean board confirms Enersis ruling.</headline>
<byline>Paulina Modiano</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile's Anti-Monopoly Commission confirmed that it ruled in favor of power investment company Enersis in a closely-watched antitrust suit.</p>
<p>But the commission, in a unanimous ruling, also issued &quot;instructions&quot; to Enersis to open up stock participation in Transelec, a power transmission company owned 100 percent by Enersis' generation unit Endesa.</p>
<p>&quot;The suit filed by the National Economic Prosecutors' office has been denied,&quot; the commission said in its ruling.</p>
<p>The ruling was announced earlier by lawyers for both sides.</p>
<p>The prosecutors, acting on a suit filed by private lawyer Ramon Briones, had charged that Enersis violated antitrust codes by taking controlling stakes in Chile's main power generation, transmission and distribution companies and crowding out rivals.</p>
<p>Enersis' involvement in all three stages of the power business had a chilling effect on competition, the prosecutors said, noting that no new power company has joined Chile's central electricity grid in 10 years despite fast economic growth.</p>
<p>The commission denied the suit but criticized &quot;ambiguous&quot; regulations on terms and fees for power transmission and distribution for smaller players in the market, calling on the government to clarify the laws.</p>
<p>It also instructed Enersis to follow through on plans to sell part of Transelec's stock to other parties.</p>
<p>&quot;The lack of a procedure to ensure effective growth in the main power transmission network, when that becomes necessary, makes it advisable that the transmission company (Transelec) have its stock participation opened up to third parties, whether they are generators or not,&quot; said the ruling.</p>
<p>The instructions don't have the full force of law but they can be cited by prosecutors in appeals or follow-up suits.</p>
<p>The court said Enersis should carry out the instructions &quot;in the way its stockholders decide and within a prudent period of time.&quot; Endesa has said in the past that it plans to place some of Transelec's shares on the stock exchange but that it was not a very profitable operation.</p>
<p>Power generators on the Central Power Grid serving about 80 percent of Chilean power consumers must pay a toll to Transelec for transmission of electricity -- except Endesa, because it owns Transelec.</p>
<p>Enersis' only major competitor in the power generation business is Chilgener, with smaller rivals in hydroelectric generator Colbun and Pilmaiquen.</p>
<p>Enersis has fought off antitrust challenges in the past.</p>
<p>But the current suit was filed after Enersis raised its share in Endesa to 25 percent from 19 percent in late 1995, making it largest shareholder in Chile's biggest generator. Enersis General Manager Jose Yuraszeck is also the president of Endesa.</p>
<p>The share prices of Enersis, Endesa and their power distribution unit Chilectra all rose sharply on the Santiago Stock Exchange on Wednesday, largely on expectations that the ruling would go in their favor.</p>
<p>((--Santiago newsroom +56-2-699-5595 x211))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
