<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656271" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: INTERVIEW - HK's Giordano still hopeful on China.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - HK's Giordano still hopeful on China.</headline>
<byline>Andrea Ricci</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Clothing retailer Giordano International Ltd retains a positive outlook on China despite the company's well-publicised setbacks there, chairman and chief executive Peter Lau said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook is good,&quot; Lau told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Lau said he had a &quot;lot of faith&quot; in China's economic development. He said the mainland also is making progress in the adoption of international business norms.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact is that China is going to learn to cope with the international rules of the game if it wants to play on the world stage, and that means that the rule of law will have to take hold,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The retailer has suffered setbacks with its expansion in China, which most analysts believe are at least partially linked to unflattering comments that company founder Jimmy Lai made about Chinese Premier Li Peng in an article in 1994.</p>
<p>Lau said the link between the Lai article and the company's troubles in China was &quot;coincidental.&quot; But he added that China in some cases has not explained its actions against the company.</p>
<p>&quot;All of the actions that have been taken have a legal grounding but they may not be equally applied to all parties,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lau said that Giordano planned to continue its expansion throughout Asia, including China.</p>
<p>He said that Giordano management recently &quot;had decided that even though we are in Hong Kong, China is still a foreign country and that we should view China as just as foreign as Korea, for example.&quot;</p>
<p>In May, the company knocked down a rumour that China's state-run Everbright Group planned to buy a stake in Giordano.</p>
<p>Lau said Giordano had no reason to invite the partication of a major shareholder, saying the company is &quot;quite cash rich.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The only way for something like that to happen is if there was a long-term business synergy and it would have to be a world class company,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Everbright rumours started because people speculated that a China partner could help Giordano overcome its problems in the mainland, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think that is a long-term valid reason to have an investment like that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Giordano said its subsidiaries in China had received penalty notices in 1996 from the authorities totalling about HK$93 million for alleged import regularities and breach of business licence.</p>
<p>Lau said it was too early to tell how the penalties would affect the company's bottom line because the charges are on appeal.</p>
<p>Lau said the company's results should be better in 1997 than in 1996 because it has turned around a slump in Taiwan.</p>
<p>&quot;Results will be better. We are quite pleased with the first five months of this year,&quot; Lau said.</p>
<p>He declined to be more specific.</p>
<p>Giordano posted net profit of HK$261.23 million for the year ended 1996, a 4.4 percent gain over the prior year.</p>
<p>Lau said the company improved its Taiwan performance by changing the way it had been dealing with stiff competition by a rival retailer started up by a former Giordano employee.</p>
<p>&quot;Taiwan was the major disaster of 1996,&quot; said Lau.</p>
<p>Rather than focusing on cutting prices to entice customers, which hurt profits, the company instead has emphasized certain product lines, improved quality and service and introduced more stylish products, he said.</p>
<p>Giordano has some 200 outlets in Taiwan, about a third of its total. It has franchises or joint ventures throughout Asia and in the Middle East. It opened its first joint venture franchise in London this year.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843-6371 http://www.hk97.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
