<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="65623" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia stocks bounce higher at end, ignore Dow.</title>
<headline>Australia stocks bounce higher at end, ignore Dow.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian share market closed higher on Thursday after recently-weak resource giants BHP and CRA rebounded on bargain hunting in late trading.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index closed 12 points higher at 2247.1, ignoring a fall on Wall Street.</p>
<p>Brokers said BHP and CRA had been oversold on concerns over metal prices and now represented good value, particularly with some confidence returning to metal markets overnight.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was looking fairly ordinary earlier on, but BHP and CRA started to come back a bit in the afternoon after people thought they had been sold down too far,&quot; said Matthew Bloom a trader at stockbrokers James Capel.</p>
<p>Bloom said steady gains in bond prices helped lift bank and other yield-sensitive stocks.</p>
<p>He said News Corp's annoucement that a budgeted strong profit rise in 1996/97 was attainable was also a plus for a market which had lacked good news lately.</p>
<p>The focus of the market on Friday will be BHP's first quarter results.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has got such a range on BHP that it's difficult to know which way it's going to go,&quot; Bloom said.</p>
<p>September share price index futures also finished with a 12 point gain to 2246 but remained at a slight discount to the underlying index.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
