<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656363" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong gold ends down on stronger dollar/yen.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong gold ends down on stronger dollar/yen.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong spot gold ended down on Thursday from New York's previous close following dealer sales on the back of a stronger dollar, bullion traders said.</p>
<p>Gold ended at US$342.10/342.60 an ounce on Thursday, down from New York's US$343.60/344.10 close on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said strong selling on the back of a firmer dollar pushed gold down.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody was just selling,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Traders said the gold was likely to head further south, but slowly. Some dealers also reported gold sales on a lower Australian dollar.</p>
<p>The U.S. dollar surged to 115.80 yen by early afternoon, a steep 4.5 yen jump from Wednesday's New York close.</p>
<p>The dollar skyrocketed on Thursday after Eisuke Sakakibara, head of the Japanese Ministry of Finance's International Bureau, said the country's trade surplus was not a cause for concern.</p>
<p>Physical demand was average, but some dealers reported healthy buying interest when gold dipped below $342 per ounce.</p>
<p>Hong Kong tael gold ended HK$11 down at HK$3,165 per tael.</p>
<p>The carry over charge at the Chinese Gold and Silver Exchange Society dropped to -5.50 from its previous fix at nil.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
