<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656452" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Retail sales fell in May, pointing to slowdown; stocks rally.</title>
<headline>Retail sales fell in May, pointing to slowdown; stocks rally.</headline>
<byline>Glenn Somerville</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Retail sales fell for the third straight month in May, the government said Thursday, sparking a stock market rally as investors bet slower growth would forestall another interest rate increase by the Federal Reserve.</p>
<p>Retail sales fell 0.1 percent in May to a seasonally adjusted $210.3 billion after dropping 0.9 percent in April and 0.3 percent in March, the Commerce Department said. It was the first time in 15 years that retail sales declined three months in a row.</p>
<p>Analysts said ebbing consumer demand and evidence of muted inflation meant that Fed policy-makers almost certainly would not raise short-term rates at a meeting on July 1-2.</p>
<p>&quot;Inflation remains quiescent and relief in the labour market may be in the offing,&quot; said economist Marilyn Schaja of Donaldson, Lufkin &amp; Jenrette Securities Corp. in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;A stable economy, characterised by slow growth without inflation, has arrived,&quot; said Howard Lewis, vice-president of the National Association of Manufacturers. &quot;Consumers went on a buying spree in the first quarter and drew down on their savings. (They) are showing more restraint now.&quot;</p>
<p>A separate Labour Department report pointed to some weakness in the job market that may help keep wages in check. The department said new claims for jobless benefits rose in the first week of June by 1,000 to 339,000.</p>
<p>The department's four-week moving average, which smoothes out weekly fluctuations in new state unemployment claims, rose 5,500 to 329,500 in the week ended June 7.</p>
<p>The signs of cooling consumer demand set off a huge rally in financial markets as traders bet the Fed will stand pat at its next policy-makers' meeting.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average jumped 135.64 points to 7,711.47, its fifth straight record. The benchmark 30-year Treasury rose about 3/4 of a point, sending its yield down to 6.78 percent from 6.84 percent on Wednesday. Bond prices and yields move in opposite directions.</p>
<p>The Fed raised short-term rates in March, the first increase in more than two years, in a bid to slow the economy and ward off inflation. The central bank's policy-makers held rates steady after meeting late last month.</p>
<p>The last time retail sales fell for three consecutive months was from September through November 1981 during the 1980-81 recession, Commerce Department officials said.</p>
<p>The drop in May sales was accentuated by big revisions to the March and April data. The department had said April sales fell 0.3 percent but revised that to a 0.9 percent drop and revised March sales to off 0.3 percent from unchanged.</p>
<p>During May, auto sales fell 0.2 percent after a revised 2 percent drop in April, which was the steepest drop since a 2.9 percent fall in April 1996.</p>
<p>New cars account for about a quarter of all retail sales. But even excluding cars, retail sales were down 0.1 percent in May after a 0.5 percent drop in April.</p>
<p>Other weakness was evident in building materials and hardware, where sales fell 0.6 percent after a 0.3 percent April decline. New housing activity has leveled off after a spurt at the start of the year helped by mild weather.</p>
<p>Sales of durable goods fell 0.3 percent after a 1.2 percent plunge in April. Sales of more quickly used goods such as food and paper products were flat after falling 0.6 percent.</p>
<p>A few segments of retailing were stronger in May.</p>
<p>Sales at general merchandise stores rose 0.7 percent after a 1 percent decline. Sales at clothing stores edged up 0.8 percent after decreasing 0.5 percent in April.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
