<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="65656" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Australia tin output seen same after ATP exit.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Australia tin output seen same after ATP exit.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian tin production will not be affected by the government's decision to withdraw from the Association of Tin Producing Countries (ATPC), tin mining companies said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The 13 year old association had become no more than a discussion forum in recent years with no regulatory powers to control production and exports, they said. The Australian government plans to withdraw from the ATPC from December 10.</p>
<p>Peter Robinson, director of operations for RGC said the association was &quot;already dead in all but name,&quot; and had long outlived its usefulness.  </p>
<p>Renison expects to produce about 10,000 tonnes of tin from its Renison Bell mine in Tasmania in 1996.</p>
<p>Another 10,000 tonnes will be produced from Renison's 75 pct owned Pt Koba mine in Indonesia.</p>
<p>Norminco Ltd, which plans to export up to 800 tonnes of tin concentrates to Malaysia in 1996, also sees little impact from the withdrawal. &quot;Our view is that it is not a critical blow,&quot; said company secretary George Strickland.</p>
<p>Thailand recently signalled its intention to withdraw from the ATPC and other countries may follow. Robinson said he would not be surprised if Indonesia was to quit at some stage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22471">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
