<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="65669" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Australia government mulling senator's Telstra plan.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Australia government mulling senator's Telstra plan.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Communications Minister Richard Alston said on Thursday the government was still considering a key Independent senator's proposed alternative to the partial sale of Telstra Corp Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all agreed, as (Treasurer Peter) Costello made plain yesterday, that the government is not attracted to proposals that would increase government debt and would be not cost-effective in the management of government debt,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's also quite clear, as we've indicated, that we're considering Senator Harradine's proposal and we'll be having further discussions with him in due course,&quot; he told the Senate.  </p>
<p>Independent senator Brian Harradine has proposed that the government issue redeemable preference shares in Telstra rather than sell one-third of the telecommunications carrier.</p>
<p>However, he refused on Wednesday to rule out voting for the partial sale if the government rejected the proposal.</p>
<p>In addition to the redeemable preference share proposal, Harradine has asked the government for substantial environmental funding for his home state of Tasmania if the sale goes ahead. The government plans to raise A$8.0 billion through the sale with A$1.0 billion of that earmarked to establish a Natural Heritage Trust.  </p>
<p>Harradine and fellow independent senator Mal Colston are crucial to passage of the Telstra legislation as the government needs two extra votes to pass any legislation in the Senate.</p>
<p>All other non-government parties are opposed to the sale.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273 2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
