<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656676" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr posts small gains in U.S. after earlier leap.</title>
<headline>Dlr posts small gains in U.S. after earlier leap.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dollar/yen inched higher in U.S. trade but failed to repeat its spectacular leap overseas after Japanese officials played down signs of trade friction with the United States and chances for an imminent rate rise.</p>
<p>The dollar jumped a staggering 4-1/2 yen in Asian trade -- from a low of 111.20 yen to a high of 115.70 -- after senior Japanese Ministry of Finance official Eisuke Sakakibara said recent concern over Japan's growing trade surplus with the United States &quot;is being played up excessively&quot;.  </p>
<p>Sakakibara, believed to be orchestrator of Japanese foreign exchange policy, also said Japanese interest rates were unlikely to rise soon, as had been speculated in the currency market, given current economic conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;It was the biggest move in dollar/yen since the Iraqi war,&quot; said Bob Houck, trader and vice president at Norwest Bank in Minneapolis.</p>
<p>&quot;Seeing a 4-1/2 yen move in one session is pretty much unheard of,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>The dollar inched slightly higher against the yen by the U.S. close, despite a slip in May U.S. retail sales which suggested Federal Reserve policymakers may not hike U.S. interest rates at their upcoming July meeting.</p>
<p>A sharp rally in U.S. bonds and stocks underpinned the dollar. The Dow Jones industrials average surged to new record highs to close up 135 points at 7711 while the 30-year benchmark U.S. Treasury rose just shy of a full point to yield 6.77 percent.</p>
<p>The dollar ended up at 114.15/25 yen compared to 114.03/08 at the open and rose to 1.7285/95 marks from 1.7245/55.  </p>
<p>Dollar trade has been exceptionally volatile recently, dealers said, as evidenced by the U.S. unit's impressive recovery on Thursday after hitting a seven-month low of 110.52 yen just one day prior.</p>
<p>Remarks from U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin and his deputy Lawrence Summers failed to give the dollar fresh direction, dealers said.</p>
<p>Rubin repeated recent comments that a sustained rise in Japan's trade suprlus could hurt global growth and spark a protectionist backlash in the U.S.  </p>
<p>However, he added there was no sign yet the growth in Japan's trade surplus will be sustained and that the dollar never has and never will be used as a tool to manipulate international trade.</p>
<p>Summers, speaking shortly after Rubin in afternoon U.S. trade, underscored many of Rubin's remarks and lauded Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto's commitment to avoiding an excessive resurgence in Japan's external surplus.  </p>
<p>The dollar also edged higher against the mark as the German unit gave back gains made earlier this week on speculation Europe's drive to form a single currency by 1999 would fail to meet deadline.</p>
<p>Tensions eased as the German government was expected to acquiesce to demands from the new French administration to include a commitment to employment in the review of the Maastricht Treaty.</p>
<p>French and German officials meet tomorrow in the French town of Poitiers for their regular bilateral summit ahead of the Amsterdam summit of European Union leaders scheduled to begin on Monday.</p>
<p>Jeffrey Yu, senior dealer at Sanwa Bank Ltd in New York, said the dollar tried but failed to move above 1.73 marks, which will remain the target for trade on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;There are more stops above 1.73 and the market is gunning for that,&quot; Yu said.</p>
<p>In other trade, the dollar was nearly flat at 1.4435/40 Swiss francs from 1.4440/50 but dipped to Canadian $1.3834/39 from C$1.3877/82. The British pound slipped to $1.6300/10 from $1.6342/47. The Australian dollar rose to $0.7525/30 from $0.7504/09.</p>
<p>((-- Roanne Daniels, 212-859-1677))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
