<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656769" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FAA blasted over air traffic control system.</title>
<headline>FAA blasted over air traffic control system.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Wilson</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Aviation Administration is endangering the lives of the flying public with a hopelessly outdated and understaffed air traffic control system, a congressional panel was told Thursday.</p>
<p>Witnesses testified that the number of near misses in the New York corridor -- the most congested and complex airspace in the world -- had increased by 26 percent, that equipment was so antiquated controllers had been observed plotting the course of aircraft with grease pencils, and that radar screens charting the position of each plane often went blank.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a joke, it's a travesty and it's not getting better, it's getting worse,&quot; said Republican Sen. Alfonse D'Amato of New York. &quot;FAA management at top levels in Washington is short-changing the public and endangering their lives.&quot;</p>
<p>A Senate subcommittee on transportation heard that planes had been coming dangerously close to each other at the rate of more than three a month in the New York region and that there had been six near misses there since April, including one this past week.</p>
<p>The New York Centre controls airspace over New York, New Jersey and parts of Pennsylvania and Maryland, as well as international airspace over the Atlantic Ocean, parts of the Caribbean and South America.</p>
<p>The centre, which routes the flights of 6,500 planes a day, had &quot;a dangerously low&quot; number of air traffic controllers, according to Barry Krasner, president of the National Air Traffic Controllers Association.</p>
<p>&quot;The number of controllers is lagging far behind the growth in air traffic volume ... the FAA must modernise the ancient air traffic control infrastructure,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Krasner said surveillance radar, computers and other navigational aids regularly failed and that the system was at least 10 years behind in technology and procedures. Representative Peter King, R-N.Y., added that some of the equipment was so outdated IBM no longer made replacement parts.</p>
<p>Current forecasts estimated a 5 percent annual increase in air traffic for the next 10 to 15 years, Krasner said, adding that without significant improvements the sytem would simply be unable to cope.</p>
<p>&quot;There is serious concern about the number of controllers that will be required to support current demands, let alone future growth,&quot; he told the panel.</p>
<p>FAA Acting Deputy Administrator Monte Belger acknowledged &quot;operational errors&quot; were up in the New York area, that the FAA was concerned about maintaining adequate staffing there and had already begun hiring 100 new employees for the region's five air traffic control facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;However, past studies have shown that there is no statistical significance between staffing and operational errors,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>That brought howls of protest from lawmakers who accused the agency of trying to write off the problems as &quot;statistical aberrations.&quot;</p>
<p>D'Amato charged the FAA with &quot;putting out drivel&quot; in an effort to appease Congress, while Republican Representative Susan Molinari of New York called the FAA response &quot;puzzling, if not blatantly incorrect.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
