<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656757" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US rail intermodal freight up strongly from yr ago.</title>
<headline>US rail intermodal freight up strongly from yr ago.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. rail intermodal freight was up strongly in the week ended June 7 compared with the year-ago week, the Association of American Railroads said Thursday.</p>
<p>AAR said intermodal freight, which does not include carloads, rose 8.2 percent to 172,059 trailers and containers last week compared with 159,048 in the year-ago week.</p>
<p>AAR said a strong economy and decreasing motor carriers capacity has attributed to the rise in intermodal freight, which has steadily climbed since April with a record volume expected this year.  </p>
<p>AAR said carloads fell 1.7 percent in the week to 347,312 from 353,241 in the year-ago week, while ton-miles were unchanged from a year ago at 26.5 billion. The ton-mile, a measure of freight transportation, is one ton of freight hauled one mile.</p>
<p>AAR said decreases in loadings of metallic ores, grain and coal led to the decline in carloads. Metallic ores loadings stood at 20,028, down 13.4 percent from 23,122 last year, while grain carloads fell 9.3 percent to 19,988 from 22,048.  </p>
<p>Coal carloads were 131,251 in the week, down 3.1 percent from 135,505 in the year-ago week. AAR also said primary forest products fell 3.4 percent to 7,206 carloads from 7,463 a year ago. Loadings of crushed stone, sand and gravel declined 4.4 percent and coke was off 5.5 percent from last year.</p>
<p>But carloads of grain mill products rose 2.5 percnet to 9,694 in the June 7 week from 9,457 in the same week last year, while metals and related products increased 8.2 percent to 13,076 from 12,084.  </p>
<p>Petroleum products loadings stood at 5,905, up 2.5 percent from 5,759, while motor vehicles and equipment increased 1.6 percent to 23,369 carloads from 23,011, AAR said.</p>
<p>AAR reported that the two Canadian-based U.S. railroads had 53,695 carloads in the June 7 week, up 6.2 percent from the year-ago week, and 25,526 trailers and containers, up 19.8 percent from last year.</p>
<p>In the first 23 weeks of 1997, AAR said carloads increased 1.6 percent to 7.80 million from 7.67 million in the same 1996 period. Trailers and containers rose 6.6 percent to 3.72 million from 3.48 million, while ton-miles increased 2.2 percent in the period to 608.6 billion from 595.6 billion.  </p>
<p>For the same period, AAR reported 1.22 million carloads on the two Canadian-based U.S. railroads, up 1.5 percent from the year-ago period, and 558,158 trailers and containers, up 11.2 percent from last year, AAR said.</p>
<p>Combined total volume in the United States and Canada for the first 23 weeks was 9.01 million carloads, up 1.6 percent from the same 1996 period, while intermodal traffic totaled 4.27 million trailers and containers, up 7.2 percent from last year, AAR said.</p>
<p>AAR also said that 57,877 new freight cars were installed on the nation's railroads during 1996, the second highest number for any year since 1980. It said 60,853 cars were added in 1995.</p>
<p>AAR also said that the nation's freight car fleet as of January 1, 1997 -- 1.24 million cars -- was at its highest level since 1.29 million in January 1988. It was also up from the 1.22 million at the beginning of 1996.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
