<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656753" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fifteen brokers suspended at H.J. Meyers &amp; Co.</title>
<headline>Fifteen brokers suspended at H.J. Meyers &amp; Co.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fifteen brokers working for H.J. Meyers were suspended and fined up to $10,000 for allegedly overcharging customers, regulators said Thursday.</p>
<p>The brokers, who neither denied nor admitted the allegations, were fined between $2,500 and $10,000 and were suspended for three days to four months as part of their settlement with NASD Regulation Inc, the regulatory body of the National Association of Securities Dealers.</p>
<p>The brokers were censured for allegedly charging retail customers unfair prices or for failing to prevent such activities, NASD Regulation said.  </p>
<p>All of the alleged violations occurred while the brokers were employed at Thomas James Associates Inc, a brokerage firm that was later acquired by H.J. Meyers and now operates under that name.</p>
<p>&quot;NASD Regulation found that the salesmen were responsible for their customers being overcharged,&quot; NASD Regulation said in a statement.  It added that in every case the brokers allegedly received gross commissions in excess of 10 percent for the sale of the common stock and warrants of Xerographic Laser Images Corp and Integrated Security Systems Inc.</p>
<p>In a similar action in July 1996, 22 H.J. Meyers managers were sanctioned and the firm was ordered to pay more than $1 million in restitution to 3,000 customers who were allegedly unfairly charged, NASD Regulation said.</p>
<p>The latest action brings to 37 the number of brokers sanctioned in the investigation of H.J. Meyers conducted jointly by NASD Regulation and the District 8 Office in Cleveland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
