<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656723" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Police probe illegal arsenal for ties to bombings.</title>
<headline>Police probe illegal arsenal for ties to bombings.</headline>
<dateline>MARIETTA, Ga. 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police looked Thursday for possible links between a series of bombings in Atlanta and an illegal weapons arsenal seized from a suburban ranch home this week, officials said.</p>
<p>SWAT team members and agents of the U.S. Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (ATF) raided the home of 31-year-old Christopher Novak late Wednesday, confiscating automatic weapons, grenade shells, explosive powder and a quantity of the drug methamphetamine.</p>
<p>Novak was lured into making an illegal weapons sale to undercover police after a man arrested on gun charges in a neighbouring town fingered him as a seller of automatic weapons.</p>
<p>Authorities said Novak was wearing combat fatigues and a bullet-proof vest when he was taken into custody and charged with four felony counts. Investigators later swarmed his home outside Marietta, located about 12 miles north of Atlanta.</p>
<p>Police and federal agents tried to determine whether bomb components seized in the raid could be linked to three bombings which have rocked the Atlanta area since last July, including one at the Olympic Games.</p>
<p>But an FBI spokesman said the case had not attracted the attention of a special bomb task force.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no reason for us to believe there's any connection with the Atlanta bombings,&quot; Cobb County Police spokesman Dana Pierce said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still very early in the investigative procedure and the process,&quot; he said. &quot;We cannot eliminate it nor can we say that it's connected with any other events in the Atlanta metro area.&quot;</p>
<p>Novak was jailed without bond on charges of possessing a controlled substance, unlawful firearms, unlawful firearms by a convicted felon and possession of firearms during the commission of a felony.</p>
<p>Police said he also could face a raft of federal weapons charges.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARIETTA, Ga."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
