<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656867" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: OECD sees three percent 1997 growth, jobless woes.</title>
<headline>OECD sees three percent 1997 growth, jobless woes.</headline>
<byline>Brian Love</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Economic growth should reach three percent in the 29-country OECD this year, its strongest level in nearly a decade, but Germany and other European Union states run the risk of a &quot;jobless recovery,&quot; an OECD report said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The twice-yearly report by the Paris-based Organisation for Economic Co-Operation and Development predicted non-inflationary growth of 3.0 percent in 1997 and a slightly slower 2.7 percent rise in gross domestic product (GDP) in 1998.</p>
<p>The OECD, which has expanded from a grouping of established industrial nations to embrace Mexico, former Soviet bloc countries and South Korea, said over half of its member countries could expect growth on this scale at national level, with the United States and Canada doing relatively better.</p>
<p>But the outlook for Japan and major EU countries, including Germany, France, Italy and some smaller EU nations, was less buoyant due to public spending restraints or other austerity measures and fragile consumer demand, the report said.</p>
<p>Unemployment across the 29 countries was expected to fall by about a million to 35.2 million by 1998, with the jobless rate easing to 7.1 from 7.5 percent in 1996, but it remained a serious problem in Europe, especially in big continental states.</p>
<p>&quot;The weakness of employment growth in much of the European Union may revive questions of whether a 'jobless recovery' is in prospect in some countries, notably Germany,&quot; the June Economic Outlook report said.</p>
<p>While improving employment often lags an upswing in economic growth, persistent and relatively strong productivity growth in the European Union may be due to high labour costs and intensive capital investment at the expense of labour, it said.</p>
<p>The report said OECD economic growth should be helped by the need to meet rising demand in strongly growing non-OECD regions, above all from China and other Asian countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Expansions appear to be strong and well established, even if they are in some cases now quite mature, in the United States, the United Kingdom, Canada and most smaller EU countries,&quot; its said.</p>
<p>&quot;Output has also been rising in Japan, Germany, France, Italy and several smaller EU countries, but at a more hesitant pace,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the major continental European countries, net exports have been a consistent source of strength, but consumer spending remains weak, while private investment has failed to strengthen much despite lower long-term interest rates.&quot;</p>
<p>The OECD predicted U.S. economic growth of 3.6 percent this year, followed by a slowdown to two percent growth in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy may begin to slow in the second half of 1997 from its rapid first-half pace as the growth rate of domestic private spending tapers off under the weight of tighter monetary conditions, moderating income increases and the exhaustion of favourable stock adjustment effects,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The OECD said it was assuming another rise of a half of one percentage point in the U.S. Federal Funds interest rate &quot;around the middle of 1997,&quot; after a quarter percentage point rise to 5.50 percent in March, the first in more than two years.</p>
<p>It forecast Japanese growth of 2.3 percent this year and 2.9 percent in 1998 but chief economist Stephen Potter told a news conference this was based on an exchange rate of 127 yen per dollar.</p>
<p>At current levels closer to 112 yen per dollar, the OECD forecast would more likely be for GDP growth of around 2.1 percent in 1997 and 2.5 percent in 1998, he said.</p>
<p>In the European Union, the OECD expected the German economy to grow 2.2 percent this year and 2.8 percent in 1998, while it predicted French growth of 2.5 percent this year and 2.8 percent next year.</p>
<p>Both countries, along with Italy, will overshoot the deficit reduction target implied by a strict reading of the Maastricht treaty to qualify for a European single currency. France's new left-wing government wants a more &quot;flexible&quot; reading which is not excluded by the treaty.</p>
<p>The OECD said it expected public deficits in Germany, France and Italy to come in at 3.2 percent of GDP in 1997 -- the test year for European monetary union. It predicts Italy's deficit widening the year after but those of Germany and France falling in line with the strict Maastricht interpratation.</p>
<p>Potter said the decision on who joined a single currency would be a political one. &quot;(But) from an economic point of view, it would seem anomalous to exclude a few countries on the basis of a few decimal points,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OECD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
