<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656896" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Romania, Slovenia fight on despite U.S. NATO move.</title>
<headline>Romania, Slovenia fight on despite U.S. NATO move.</headline>
<byline>Janet McEvoy</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States, pouring cold water on the hopes of Romania and Slovenia, said on Thursday that only Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic should be in NATO's first expansion.</p>
<p>The decision by the alliance's most powerful member was hailed by the Poles, Czechs and Hungarians, for whom NATO membership is the best long-term guarantee of independence after centuries of domination by larger neighbours.</p>
<p>Washington's European allies reacted coolly and disappointed Romania and Slovenia both pledged to battle on and try to change President Bill Clinton's mind.</p>
<p>Their bid to be among the first wave invited to join at next month's NATO summit in Madrid had won support from senior European members such as France, Germany and Italy.</p>
<p>Officially the final decision has to be taken by NATO's 16 members by consensus. But Washington stressed it was not for turning.</p>
<p>&quot;The President (Bill Clinton) is firm on that,&quot; U.S. Defence Secretary William Cohen told a news conference after the first day of a two-day meeting with NATO defence ministers, at which he revealed the White House decision.</p>
<p>Italy, which backs early membership by the two, said the U.S. decision was a mistake and vowed to try and convince Washington to change its mind in the run-up to the summit.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States should get to know the interior policies of these countries before making such statements,&quot; Luxembourg's Prime Minister Jean-Claude Juncker told a business conference in Bonn.</p>
<p>Britain pointedly described the U.S. announcement as &quot;an important contribution to the debate&quot; and stressed that the decision would be taken by all 16 members together.</p>
<p>France has strongly pushed early membership for Romania, with which it has traditionally strong ties. New French Defence Minister Alain Richard raised Romania's case when he met Cohen for the first time on Thursday.</p>
<p>The United States is already embroiled in a row over the alliance's southern flank command structure, which Paris wants transferred to European control.</p>
<p>Cohen justified the U.S. decision to expand just to the three, all of them widely backed by the other NATO states, saying it would preserve the alliance's cohesiveness and create a sound platform for a future enlargement eastwards.</p>
<p>&quot;We wanted to send a clear signal that the door was still open,&quot; he told the news conference.</p>
<p>NATO Secretary-General Javier Solana said that the summit's final statement would stress that the NATO door would remain open, and that the &quot;first wave will not be the last&quot;.</p>
<p>But no official would be drawn about when the next NATO expansion to the east might happen. Twelve countries in all have applied.</p>
<p>France and the supporters of a broader expansion argue that tiny Slovenia and Romania need to be included in order to maintain a balance within NATO between its northern and southern flanks.</p>
<p>&quot;Slovenia enjoys the support of at least nine NATO member nations for its candidature,&quot; Foreign Minister Zoran Thaler said in a statement. &quot;This support is getting stronger and other members are not opposed to our bid.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the final decision will be taken by consensus in Madrid,&quot; Romanian Prime Minister Victor Ciorbea told reporters. &quot;We will continue to play our cards until the end and we won't stop until the summit.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
