<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="657169" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan pleads for peace with India after clash.</title>
<headline>Pakistan pleads for peace with India after clash.</headline>
<byline>Raja Asghar</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif pleaded for peace with India on Wednesday after a border clash between the two arch-rivals in which a Pakistan army major was killed.</p>
<p>In a televised address, Sharif urged his nation to consider what had been gained from 50 years' hostility between the two nations since independence, and suggested it was time to try &quot;other means&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;In the past 50 years we fought wars and our relations have been strained,&quot; he said. &quot;Is there no lesson for the two countries in the 50 years' history?&quot;</p>
<p>Sharif made his conciliatory remarks  hours after a Pakistani military statement said a major in a paramilitary force was killed in an overnight cross-border clash in the eastern Sialkot sector.</p>
<p>It said the Indian Border Security Force (BSF), firing from the Indian-ruled part of the disputed Kashmir region, also suffered casualties but their number was not known.</p>
<p>It was the most serious border clash for several months between the two countries, currently preparing for a second round in recently-resumed peace talks.</p>
<p>Sharif said he had proposed to Indian Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral &quot;why not to try other means&quot; instead of hostility, and that the two sides negotiate on all issues, including their dispute over Kashmir. The two leaders met during a South Asian summit conference in Male, capital of the Maldives, last month.</p>
<p>&quot;The Indian prime minister's response to this was positive, (and) he also agreed with the proposal to follow the path of negotiations,&quot; Sharif said.</p>
<p>India rules two-thirds and Pakistan the rest of Kashmir, over which the two countries have fought two of their three wars since independence from Britain in 1947.</p>
<p>Sharif said India-Pakistan relations could be productive only &quot;when Kashmiris' right to self-determination&quot; was accepted. &quot;This is the basic point, by agreeing on which we can proceed further.&quot;</p>
<p>New Delhi regards the whole of Kashmir as an integral part of India, but Islamabad wants the predominantly Moslem Kashmiris to decide in a U.N.-mandated plebiscite whether to join Islamic Pakistan or Hindu-majority India.</p>
<p>The Pakistani statement earlier said the border clash followed &quot;unprovoked firing&quot; by the Indian BSF on civilians building an embankment on the Pakistani side of what it called the working boundary with the Indian-ruled part of Kashmir.</p>
<p>&quot;Pakistan (paramilitary) Rangers personnel moved in support of the civilians and, during exchange of fire, Major Jamil of Pakistan Rangers embraced Shahadat (martyrdom),&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Pakistan Rangers retaliated, inflicting casualties on the BSF,&quot; the statement said. &quot;However, the number of Indian casualties could not be ascertained.&quot;</p>
<p>Tension has run high between the two sides during more than seven years of a separatist revolt in Indian Kashmir.</p>
<p>Top Indian and Pakistani foreign ministry officials met in New Delhi in March, marking a resumption of the dialogue between the two countries after a three-year deadlock over Kashmir.</p>
<p>Pakistan has proposed the next round in Islamabad be held on June 19-22, but still awaits Indian approval of the dates.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
