<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="65717" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: RESEARCH ALERT - Seamico recommends sell SSI.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Seamico recommends sell SSI.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seamico Research said on Thursday it recommended investors sell shares of hot-rolled coil company Sahaviriya Steel Industries (SSI) because of the poor industry outlook.</p>
<p>Seamico said SSI would continue to register losses in the third quarter. With an estimated spread between the selling price and the price of slab at around US$80-90 a tonne, the company will not make enough to cover all of its fixed costs, Seamico said.  </p>
<p>Seamico said Sahaviriya Steel was also affected by global and domestic hot-rolled coil prices which remain weak.</p>
<p>The current average selling price of the product was at $330 a tonne while the price of slab is $228 per tonne, it said.</p>
<p>However, a short-term rebound in Sahaviriya Steel's share price was possible if the government imposed a 50 percent surcharge on imported hot rolled coil.</p>
<p>Sahaviriya Steel was currently lobbying the government for such a measure. A decision was expected to be reached within one to two months.</p>
<p>Sahaviriya Steel's current gearing remained high with a debt-to-equity ratio at the end of second quarter at 2.7 times, Seamico said, adding that the company was likely to rely on bank loans on bank loans to service its debt obligations.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
