<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="657408" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London SE to list Jiangxi Copper.</title>
<headline>London SE to list Jiangxi Copper.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The London Stock Exchange said it will list shares in Chinese mining group Jiangxi Copper Co Ltd.</p>
<p>The issue, the exchange's second Chinese listing, will be brought to the market by Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>The investment bank has raised 132 million stg through a new issue in Hong Kong and an international placing, the London Stock Exchange said.</p>
<p>Jiangxi Copper is engaged in copper mining, milling, smelting and refining facilities in northeastern Jiangxi province in China.</p>
<p>Tthe listing was made possible by the signing in October 1996, of a memorandum of understanding between the UK and Chinese regulatory authorities, providing Chinese companies with direct access to London markets, the exchange said.</p>
<p>Shares of Jiangxi Copper ended at HK$2.35 on Thursday in Hong Kong on their first day of trading there, against an issue price of HK$2.55. Turnover was 158.04 million shares worth HK$391.26 million, putting it among the 20 most heavily traded stocks by turnover for the day.</p>
<p>&quot;A weak performance had already expected, but the shares falling below the issue price disappointed the market,&quot; said Kinson Au, research manager at Asia Financial Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors, particularly in Hong Kong and other Asian countries, know very little about mining stocks and natural resources-related stocks, and that more or less reduced their interest,&quot; said Raymond Jook, associate director at SocGen Crosby Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;A deep fall in the (local) stock market also dampened interest,&quot; Jook added.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 5106</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
