<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="657498" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INTERVIEW-Johnson Matthey sees pound pinch.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Johnson Matthey sees pound pinch.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>British metals and materials group Johnson Matthey Plc said on Thursday it expected sterling's strength to hurt profits by some 1.5 million stg this year, but added that earnings growth should offset the impact.</p>
<p>The company's pre-tax profits rose 6.0 percent to 108.3 million stg for the year to March 31, with currency translation cutting that number by about 1.5 million stg.</p>
<p>&quot;At current levels, currency translation won't have a huge difference versus last year. It will be slightly negative,&quot; executive director Gordon Thorburn told Reuters in an interview.  </p>
<p>&quot;The outlook is good. We're expecting very strong growth in our Electronic Materials division and a further rise in the Catalytic Systems division, with the other two businesses being broadly flat,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Johnson Matthey's shares rose six percent, gaining 28.5p to 490 by 0900 GMT to rank among the top percentage gainers on the London stock market.</p>
<p>Thorburn said the company's new Plastic Land Grid Array (PLGA) technology would boost its Electronics Materials division this year as its U.S. PLGA plant comes fully onstream.</p>
<p>The company expected to reach full capacity production of about 1.5 million units per month toward the end of its financial year in March.</p>
<p>Thorburn also said the firm's new cross-licensing pact with Japan's Kyocera Corp would be a boon for business.</p>
<p>Under the deal, Johnson Matthey will license to Kyocera its PLGA technology, while the Japanese firm will license its technology for future generations of plastic laminate packages for semiconductors.</p>
<p>&quot;(The agreement) is worth a very great deal, but the commercial details are confidential,&quot; Thorburn said.</p>
<p>Higher prices should help the Precious Metals division, which accounts for about 40 percent of the company's profits, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the end of March, precious metal prices have risen very substantially. That means we will make more money in that business,&quot; Thorburn said.</p>
<p>The division increased its operating profit by 4.0 percent to 44.0 million stg last year, despite weak precious metals prices.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Catalytic Systems profits rose 30 percent to 34.1 million stg, and Electronic Materials division profits grew 21 percent to 30.9 million stg.</p>
<p>But the company said profits fell at its ceramics venture with Cookson Group Plc, hit by low sales prices and weak demand in the European tile market.</p>
<p>Cookson Matthey Ceramics' profits dropped 36 percent to 15.3 million stg. --Jeff Daeschner, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
