<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="657582" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ralph Lauren stock poised for gains.</title>
<headline>Ralph Lauren stock poised for gains.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Westhoven</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polo Ralph Lauren Corp sold shares for $26 each Wednesday in the second largest initial public offering this year, raising roughly $767 million.</p>
<p>Stock in the fashion designer is expected to jump nearly $5 when it begins trading Thursday on the New York Stock Exchange, analysts say.</p>
<p>The offering will make an even richer man out of Ralph Lauren, a former necktie salesman from the Bronx whose original name is Ralph Lifshitz, and is expected to spur other designers to take their fashion houses to Wall Street.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the biggest payday in the history of Seventh Avenue,&quot; said Alan Millstein, editor and publisher of the Fashion Report, referring to the traditional home of the fashion industry.</p>
<p>Despite the enormous size of the offering, even portfolio managers at some of the top U.S. investment banks were not sure if they could get a piece of the red-hot deal.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't even know if I'm getting an allocation,&quot; said Arden Armstrong, portfolio manager at Miller Anderson &amp; Sherrerd LLP, which manages over $41.4 billion of assets.</p>
<p>Polo's strong brand name, its established menswear line, a growing line of womenswear and opportunities to grow around the globe are all drawing Wall Street's eye. Analysts also say its broad product line protects its from &quot;fashion disasters&quot;.</p>
<p>Wall Street has mixed feeling about fashion houses -- Gucci Group more than tripled from its IPO, while Donna Karan International Inc. fell more than 50 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;In fashion, things are quixotic. Success is ephemeral. But Ralph Lauren is not a designer -- he's a businessman first. He doesn't sit around with a sketch pad. That makes him a better bet for the investment community,&quot; said Millstein.</p>
<p>The company has also branched out from traditional apparel to sell products such as towels, sheets, bedspreads and even paint.</p>
<p>Despite Polo's strengths, some analysts have knocked the deal, saying the price was too steep, especially when compared with Tommy Hilfiger Corp..</p>
<p>But Armstrong said she was willing to pay top dollar: &quot;This is an expensive deal, but it's worth it. The P/E (price to earnings) ratio is higher than Tommy, and Tommy's growing faster, but this is a much more mature deal. They have strong cash flow and a stable and mature business.&quot;</p>
<p>Manish Shah, editor of the IPO Maven, expects the stock to follow Gucci upwards. &quot;It's expensive, but fundamentals are good.&quot; He recommends holding the stock until it reaches $35 if it was bought at the $26 IPO price. But on the open market, he only recommends buying below $32. He considers the stock overvalued above $35.</p>
<p>The initial price of the shares exceeded their estimated cost of $22 to $25. Of the total 29.5 million shares, the company itself will sell 9.4 million, raising $244.4 million. But the lion's share will be sold by Lauren and Goldman Sachs, which held a 28 percent stake before the IPO.</p>
<p>&quot;But if the business is so real and its so great, why is Goldman getting out? That always leaves a bad taste in the mouth,&quot; said Manish Shah.</p>
<p>Millstein, of the Fashion Report, said the deal may lure other world class designers to Wall Street.</p>
<p>&quot;This IPO made more money than they could have fantasized. It will cause them to lose sleep. This is an industry inhabited by the most jealous, thin-skinned egotistical people in the world. Polo will absolutely speed up any ideas held by Calvin Klein or Gianni Versace about going public,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Millstein said the designer with the best prospects and the most established empire was Italian designer Giorgio Armani.</p>
<p>&quot;But it would be a long shot. He's a very private person.&quot;</p>
<p>The offering makes this the best week yet for IPOs, raising $1.87 billion so far and beating the $1.67 billion record held by the week of May 23, according to Securities Data Co.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
