<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="657757" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch property funds rebuild investor confidence.</title>
<headline>Dutch property funds rebuild investor confidence.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Kelly</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Although dazzled by double-digit returns on equities in recent years, investors may well have overlooked a long-awaited recovery in Dutch real estate.</p>
<p>After a lean period in the early 1990s when a slump in global property prices forced them to write down the value of their holdings almost every year, Dutch real estate funds bounced back in 1996 and the recovery has continued into 1997.</p>
<p>Research institute IRIS calculates that the eight Dutch property funds it tracks made an average total return -- share price appreciation plus reinvested dividends -- of 30.2 percent in 1996 and 12.4 percent in the first five months of 1997.</p>
<p>Property fund managers are cautiously optimistic about the future, saying the crisis in the sector seems to be over, with physical markets showing signs of durable recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;We are positive about the outlook for this year and the slightly longer term,&quot; said Peter Neervoort of the 2.5 billion guilder Wereldhave fund based in The Hague.</p>
<p>Wereldhave, which sold off its Carnaby Street retail complex in London last year, had to write down the value of its portfolio every year from 1991 to 1995.</p>
<p>But in 1996 it raised the estimated value of its portfolio by 1.5 percent to reflect the recovery in property prices.</p>
<p>Wereldhave's net income -- which is rental income, less costs -- has been rising steadily since 1993 and the company predicts a further increase in net income this year.</p>
<p>Rotterdam-based Rodamco -- the biggest Dutch fund with a portfolio worth some 9.6 billion guilders ($5.4 billion) -- says 1996 was one of the three best years since it was set up in 1979.</p>
<p>Its total return for the year to the end of February 1997 -- calculated on the basis of the increase in net asset value per share plus dividend -- came to 12.8 percent.</p>
<p>Chief financial officer Wim Dijkema said this was more in line with the 10 percent average total return Rodamco achieved in its first 11 years and a far cry from the three years of negative total returns it posted in the early 1990s.</p>
<p>Dijkema believes the recovery will prove stable and that an investment in Rodamco should produce a higher return for investors than Dutch government bonds.</p>
<p>Rodamco has recently cut its holdings in Germany, where it believes property prices have become overstretched, but has stepped up investment in Britain, France and Spain where it sees further upward potential for property values and rents.</p>
<p>Dijkema said investor confidence in the sector -- badly shaken at the start of the decade -- was recovering gradually and had prompted a trebling of average daily turnover in Rodamco shares on the Amsterdam bourse in 1996 compared with 1994.</p>
<p>Analyst Andre Mulder of BZW Nederland said the recovery in real estate had restored an old relationship in which the return to investors lay somewhere between that on bonds and shares.</p>
<p>He said dividend yields for Dutch property funds were still higher than bond yields, unlike Britain and the United States, and that their share prices therefore had the potential to rise a further 15 to 20 percent to close the gap with those markets.</p>
<p>&quot;My favourite would still be Rodamco because of its international exposure...and I'm also turning positive on a specialist fund like VastNed Offices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mulder predicts Dutch property funds will produce total returns of about 15 percent per year over the next few years.</p>
<p>He said Dutch institutional investors, many of whom have been busy building up their equity portfolios, might now be ready to raise their property holdings which he said had sunk to an average seven percent of total assets from 12 in the 1970s.</p>
<p>Jos van Niekerk, general manager of Unilever pensionfund Progress, said he was pleased with the performance of the fund's property investments which accounted for some 16 percent of its total assets of 6.7 billion guilders at the end of 1996.</p>
<p>Progress has earned an average return of 11.8 percent on property over the last five years versus an average return of 11.0 percent on its fixed-income holdings.</p>
<p>Van Niekerk said Progress would continue to keep some 10-20 percent of its assets in property, because it provided a stable income stream and was an effective hedge against inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;If you go back to the 1970s...we saw very clearly that real estate provided a great buffer against inflation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Van Niekerk said Progress had been relatively unscathed by the property crisis of a few years ago, largely because some 50 percent of its portfolio consisted of apartment buildings for whom tenants had signed index-linked rental contracts.</p>
<p>DUTCH REAL ESTATE FUND PERFORMANCE -- TOTAL RETURNS IN PERCENT</p>
<p>		    to 31/5/97  1996  3 yr avg  5 yr avg</p>
<p>Rodamco		 21.6    19.9    6.9     11.4</p>
<p>VIB			 9.9    27.1    3.5	5.0</p>
<p>Wereldhave	    12.7    31.1    9.9	8.0</p>
<p>Rodamco Retail	 5.0    20.6    7.5	---</p>
<p>Vastned Retail	 4.7    30.0    5.6	9.3</p>
<p>Uni-Invest	    12.6    44.6   15.4     14.0</p>
<p>Vastned Off/Ind     17.1    31.5   16.8	9.6</p>
<p>Schroders Int	15.6    36.7   19.1     15.2</p>
<p>Source: IRIS (Rabobank/Robeco). Total return is calculated from share price appreciation plus reinvested dividends.</p>
<p>-- Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000, Fax +31 20 504 5040 ($ = 1.79 Netherland Antilles Guilders)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
