<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="657846" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French minister says 1,000s may be dead in Congo.</title>
<headline>French minister says 1,000s may be dead in Congo.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A French junior minister said on Thursday he had unconfirmed reports that thousands of civilians may have been killed in fighting in the Congolese capital of Brazzaville, although Paris had no way of checking.</p>
<p>Secretary of State for Economic Cooperation Charles Josselin told the newspaper Le Monde that witnesses had spoken of several thousand dead, but French military specialists dismissed talk of such high casualty figures in a week of fighting.  </p>
<p>&quot;We don't have the means to evaluate how many civilians have been killed, but some witnesses speak of thousands,&quot; Josselin said, adding that French troops sent to protect and evacuate foreign residents, would not intervene to separate the warring sides.</p>
<p>A radio report on Wednesday quoted an evacuee as saying French soldiers on the spot had told him there might be 10,000 dead, but military sources in Paris said they had no such figures and were wary of them.</p>
<p>One senior officer told Reuters in Paris: &quot;We don't know how many have been killed. Because much of Brazzaville is made up of shantytowns where people live tightly packed, it is possible some rounds from multiple rockets launchers they are using may have caused heavy casualties in places.</p>
<p>&quot;There could be 200 dead or 1,000 dead in the very worst case scenario but we don't know,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CONGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
