<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="657924" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INTERVIEW-Daily Mail sees strong ad market.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Daily Mail sees strong ad market.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Newspaper publisher Daily Mail &amp; General Trust Plc said on Thursday the advertising market was looking fairly strong in the second half of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;Advertising is looking pretty good, particularly in recruitment advertising,&quot; finance director Peter Williams told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>But Williams said there was obviously a question mark against how long recruitment advertising would remain buoyant as companies filled vacancies.</p>
<p>Williams was speaking after the company announced a 27 percent rise in underlying pre-tax profit to 46.9 million stg in the first half of the year.</p>
<p>That figure was towards the bottom end of analysts' expectations but Williams said most analysts were focusing on the full year number rather than the split between the two halves.</p>
<p>Looking at the newspaper market generally, he noted the Labour government had pledged not to introduce Value Added Tax (VAT) on newspapers.</p>
<p>The company said losses at its Channel One cable television unit had been reduced but Williams would not give an exact figure. The unit has lost 10 million stg in past years.</p>
<p>He said the company remained committed to local cable television but revenues were not growing as the company would like. He said the company was looking at a range of options from cost cutting to selling its programmes more widely.</p>
<p>-- Keith Weir, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8793</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
