<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="658098" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: INSTANT VIEW-Australian May labour force data.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW-Australian May labour force data.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian employment fell by 40,300 in May to produce an unemployment rate of 8.8 percent, the Australian Bureau of Statistics reported.</p>
<p>Economists' forecasts had centred on a 15,000 rise in employment, and ranged from a fall of 5,000 to a rise of 25,000. Unemployment rate forecasts ranged from 8.6 to 8.8 percent. A selection of economists' immediate reactions to the data follow.</p>
<p>DAVID DE GARIS, SENIOR TREASURY ECONOMIST, ANZ BANK:</p>
<p>&quot;(The possibility of a rate cut) ... I think that's the way the market's interpreted it. On the basis of these numbers, we think employment growth will probably be around flat in the June quarter, after the small growth we had in the March quarter. We are now six months from the November/December easings, so it's looking like those easings are yet to really spark a lot of growth in the economy.&quot;  </p>
<p>HANS KUNNEN, CHIEF ECONOMIST, COLONIAL STATE BANK:</p>
<p>&quot;Even if you average out the last two months, you get zero jobs growth. We may see some improvement, but improvement from zero to 10,000 jobs for a month still wouldn't be enough to get the unemployment rate down. So, yes it is a lagging indicator, but this sort of job market is indicative of a fairly stagnant economy and one that may be in need of stimulation -- code for a rate cut.&quot;</p>
<p>SHANE OLIVER, CHIEF ECONOMIST, AMP INVESTMENTS:</p>
<p>&quot;The market's reaction is towards that (a rate cut). Bill rates are already trading below cash rates ... and these figures will only add impetus to that. One can point out the employment figures are traditionally quite volatile and it's quite likely that you'll see quite a solid bounce back in June. But that said, one can't get away from the fact that the trend is very weak, and unemployment, if anything, is drifting up very modestly. You put all that together, you've still got low inflation but an unemployment problem, basically the odds of another easing are actually quite high.&quot;</p>
<p>ANNETTE BEACHER, SENIOR ECONOMIST, CITIBANK AUSTRALIA:</p>
<p>&quot;This is just unambiguously scary. After the brief shining light yesterday with our 12.2 percent rise in housing finance it has just been swamped by a wave of bad news and I think it's time to get off the fence and start thinking that they (the RBA) will cut again. The question now is timing. What I am sure is that they will not be awaiting for AWOTE (average weekly ordinary time earnings) on August 14. Consumer sentiment is down, so the last rate cut hasn't improved propects. It is just very, very bad economic news here.&quot;  </p>
<p>SUSAN CREIGHTON, CHIEF ECONOMIST, ABN-AMRO:</p>
<p>&quot;It certainly increases the prospects of another interest rate cut in the near term because I think everybody's going to be very worried about the employment situation, particularly as the consumer sentiment survey yesterday showed that that's the main factor, outweighing the interest rate cut side of things, for the consumers. It's a bad number, and it really brings out the patchiness of the economy.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
