<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="658064" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Centennial to buy Airly coal deposit.</title>
<headline>Centennial to buy Airly coal deposit.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Centennial Coal Co Ltd said on Thursday that it would pay Rio Tinto Ltd unit Novacoal Australia Pty Ltd about A$2.5 million for the Airly thermal coal deposit near Lithgow, west of Sydney.</p>
<p>The main Lithgow seam of the undeveloped deposit had an indicated resource of about 200 million tonnes while the overall project included a mining lease and development consent.</p>
<p>Airly was located about 30 km north of the Mount Piper and Wallerawang power stations which together consumed about five million tonnes of coal annually. The project would hopefully provide coal to these mines.  </p>
<p>The company said it would also spend a further A$1.5 million over the next financial year to establish a trial mine. The ultimate size of the mine would depend on market conditions, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Airly fulfils a complementary role in Centennial's growth strategy by extending the company's strong presence in the domestic coal supply market. This market currently accounts for approximately 40 percent of Centennial's sales,&quot; the company said.  </p>
<p>Centennial last week said it would acquire half of the export-based coking coal producer Cook Colliery in Queensland for A$5.5 million from Resource Management and Mining Pty Ltd.</p>
<p>The other half share is owned by Swiss-based Glencore International Ag.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I11000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
