<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="658196" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokai Kanko to tie up with Far East Consortium.</title>
<headline>Tokai Kanko to tie up with Far East Consortium.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hotel chain operator Tokai Kanko Co Ltd said on Thursday that it had decided on an equity and business tie-up with Far East Consortium International Ltd of Hong Kong.  </p>
<p>Tokai Kanko also said it would issue 54 million new shares to Far East Global Asia Ltd, making the company the largest shareholder in Tokai Kanko at 51.6 percent.</p>
<p>Far East Global Asia Ltd is wholly owned by David Chiu, who holds the largest stake of 30 percent in Far East Consortium.  </p>
<p>Tokai Kanko said in a statement that the increased frequency of small earthquakes in the Izu resort region west of Tokyo has dealt a considerable blow to its business as Izu is the area where the company operates most of its hotels and inns.</p>
<p>It has decided to seek the capital participation of Far East Global Asia in order to improve its financial condition and to boost profitability.</p>
<p>Part of the funds procured through the third-party allotment of new shares will be used for operations and capital investment in existing Tokai Kanko resorts and restaurants.</p>
<p>The funds will also be used in a housing development project in Southeast Asia undertaken jointly with the Far East group, the statement said.</p>
<p>Earlier in May, a Far East group company acquired the largest stake in Mori Denki Manufacturing Co Ltd, a manufacturer of industrial lighting equipment and electrical engineering materials, through a third-party allocation.</p>
<p>Mori Denki issued 8.9 million new shares to Far East Organization Finance (International) Ltd, a member firm of the Far East group.</p>
<p>Mori Denki, suffering from a slump in its domestic business, said it hoped to invest jointly with the Far East Group in shopping centres in Asia and to manage other real estate projects in the region.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
