<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="658269" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia Ekran rights issue seen chilling listings.</title>
<headline>Malaysia Ekran rights issue seen chilling listings.</headline>
<byline>Christina Toh-Pantin</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A heavily undersubscribed stock rights offering by Malaysia's Ekran Bhd could chill interest in its pending Bakun dam equity listing as well as in other infrastructure projects, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>After weeks of speculation, the main developer of the $6.2 billion Bakun hydro-electric dam confirmed the market's fears about its rights offer of 257.1 million shares. The one-for-one issue was to raise 1.47 billion ringgit ($588 million).</p>
<p>Ekran said the issue was undersubscribed by 62.77 percent, and that its executive chairman Ting Pek Khiing had taken up 150.98 million of the 161.42 million unsubscribed shares, or 93.5 percent of the shunned portion.</p>
<p>The purchase cost Ting 859.8 million ringgit and raised the stake held by him and his wife in Ekran to 55.7 percent from 26.3 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;For future IPCs (infrastructure project companies) including Bakun itself, it doesn't augur very well,&quot; said Lai Tak Heong, research director at Socgen-Crosby.</p>
<p>He noted that Time Engineering Bhd's Time Telecommunications unit, and media and telecommunications firm Binariang Sdn Bhd were also seeking to list their shares.</p>
<p>Time Engineering has said it may delay the initial public offering of its telecommunications unit.</p>
<p>Ekran's rights issue flopped because of a bearish stock market and concerns about the controversial Bakun dam, which is being built in the rainforests of Sarawak state on Borneo island, analysts said.</p>
<p>Environmentalists have questioned the need for, scale and impact of the dam, while some investors are cool to it because of the gestation period of around six years before profits materialise and the higher risks associated with such projects.</p>
<p>A 10 percent foreign tranche for the Bakun dam company stock listing was scrapped due to lukewarm interest, and the firm's debut on the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange has been pushed back from June to early August.</p>
<p>A third of the proceeds from the Ekran rights issue had been earmarked for financing Ekran's 32 percent stake in the Bakun dam company. Ekran is the biggest shareholder.</p>
<p>The 2,400 megawatt capacity dam will clear 69,000 hectares of forests, displace more than 9,000 tribal residents and create a reservoir the size of Singapore.</p>
<p>It is due to be finished by 2003 and preparatory work was started in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;I think you're going to see perhaps fewer issues, issues getting deferred, more innovative offerings and more generously priced offerings,&quot; said Patrick Russell, managing director at W.I. Carr.</p>
<p>He said that with the market's unforgiving mood, companies selling stock may have to add sweeteners such as a portion of convertible debt to their equity offerings.</p>
<p>But several fund managers said they believed Ekran's problems should not be used as a broader indicator.</p>
<p>While the short-term sentiment on Ekran and Bakun may be negative, &quot;I think the Bakun project over the long-term is still a viable project,&quot; said Haizan Johari, manager of investments at KL Mutual Unit Trusts.</p>
<p>&quot;At the end of the day, the IPCs are decently priced and commercial going concerns,&quot; said a foreign fund manager.</p>
<p>He said that the Ekran rights issue may actually have good implications for the Malaysian stock market. It shows &quot;the market is not stupid. That's a sign of maturity.&quot;</p>
<p>($1=2.50 ringgit)</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
