<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="658325" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: In hungry North Korea, famine has only just begun.</title>
<headline>In hungry North Korea, famine has only just begun.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Browne</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Even if food aid eases North Korea's hunger, and peasants can somewhow survive until the September harvest by boiling roots and grasses and grinding tree bark to eat, next year may be just as bad.</p>
<p>And the year after that, too.</p>
<p>Like most famines, this one is largely man-made.</p>
<p>But nothing suggests that the men responsible -- the Stalinist commissars who have subjected their people to the lunacies of collectivised agriculture -- are doing anything fundamental to reverse the catastrophe.</p>
<p>Instead, Pyongyang has turned to panhandling from the international community, and since this produces no more than a few coins in the begging bowl, it has gone in for drug-running and money counterfeiting as well.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, large tracts of the nation's southern breadbasket are a wasteland. Protein deficiencies show up in the orange hair of stunted children.</p>
<p>Hospital beds are emptying because doctors and nurses no longer report for work: they are too busy trying to stay alive themselves.</p>
<p>What is &quot;Great Leader&quot; Kim Jong-il and his Workers' Party comrades doing about it?</p>
<p>&quot;They are taking half-hearted steps at reform,&quot; said a Seoul-based Western diplomat.</p>
<p>Cho Yong-han, a professor at Sogang University and an expert on North Korean agriculture, said that collective farms imposed on the countryside in the 1950s were now breaking down into smaller and somewhat better run units.</p>
<p>Village-based collectives of 100 or so peasants had become clan-sized operations of seven or eight families.</p>
<p>In addition, a Chinese-style &quot;responsibility system&quot; is well in place over much of the country.</p>
<p>Under this incentive system, farmers contract with the state to deliver a set amount of produce, selling any surplus on free markets, which are now tolerated.</p>
<p>&quot;For a country so stubborn, they are showing a willingness to change, however marginal that may be,&quot; said Cho.</p>
<p>It may be too late.</p>
<p>Pyongyang is flat broke. It has no money to improve the exhausted soil by buying fertilisers, pesticides, tractors and other farm machinery.</p>
<p>And because of a policy of farming hillsides, spring rains now sluice down slopes denuded of bushes and trees, producing instant floods.</p>
<p>A repeat of floods similar to those that smothered rice fields in silt and rocks in 1995 and 1996 -- and which were the proximate cause of this year's chronic food shortages -- is almost inevitable.</p>
<p>But even under ideal conditions, North Korea would not be able to feed itself, agricultural scientists say. Arable land is too scarce, and the soil too poor.</p>
<p>Pyongyang's only real hope is to import food using hard currency earned through trading. Yet it has almost nothing to sell to the world.</p>
<p>Last week, it scrapped a breakthrough zinc-for-wheat deal with U.S. grains giant Cargill Inc, opting instead to sell its dwindling stock of the metal into the spot market to take advantage of a sudden price surge.</p>
<p>Quick fixes have become habit-forming. In April, Japanese authorities seized a North Korean ship laden with illegal drugs worth $95 million. Pyongyang's ability to print high-quality U.S. dollar notes has been well documented.</p>
<p>Panhandling has so far secured about 800,000 tonnes of food, now being delivered or in the pipeline. South Korean authorities say that should just suffice.</p>
<p>The World Food Programme insists 1.3 million tonnes is needed to avert &quot;human catastrophe&quot;.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, North Korea continues to stall on joining proposed peace talks with the United States, South Korea and China designed to end an armed truce on the Korean peninsula dating from the end of the 1950-53 Korean War.</p>
<p>This is despite signals from Seoul and Washington that peace talks could produce massive food aid.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
