<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="658470" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU leaders urged to back single market action plan.</title>
<headline>EU leaders urged to back single market action plan.</headline>
<byline>Fredrik Dahl</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leaders at the European Union summit in Amsterdam on June 16-17 will be urged to back plans to &quot;move decisively&quot; towards completing the bloc's single market to coincide with the launch of a single currency.</p>
<p>The European Commission, desperate to create jobs and boost growth, has put together an ambitious action plan to remove remaining barriers in the world's largest internal market by January 1, 1999 -- six years after the original deadline.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential of the internal market for competitiveness, growth and employment is enormous,&quot; Commission President Jacques Santer told the European Parliament this week.</p>
<p>Santer insists that the borderless EU market should be completed before the end of the century.</p>
<p>The summit is expected to welcome the plan, especially since the Commission softened its demand for a fully complete Single Market by January 1999. It is now talking about &quot;maximum possible agreement&quot; by that date.</p>
<p>The EU launched the original Single Market programme in 1985 to create a huge domestic market to help European firms compete on global markets by removing all barriers to the movement of goods, services, capital and people.</p>
<p>According to a Commission survey published last year, it has resulted in 900,000 more jobs, boosted EU income and lowered inflation.</p>
<p>However, there are still a number of obstacles to a truly border-free market, not least because only 65 percent of Single Market legislation is fully in force in all 15 member states.</p>
<p>&quot;The internal market is very important, it is very positive for business, for jobs, for employment in general,&quot; said Keith Richardson, secretary-general of the European Round Table of Industrialists. &quot;But a lot of trouble arises in Europe because the market is still incomplete.&quot;</p>
<p>Also, some of the most controversial and complicated issues -- such as greater tax harmonisation and the abolition of border controls on people -- were left unresolved in the 1985 plan.</p>
<p>The Commission wants to implement its action plan in three phases, given that some of the proposed measures, especially those on tax coordination, may be difficult for member states to agree by 1999.</p>
<p>Avoiding a barrage of new legislation, the plan focuses on the need to apply and enforce existing Single Market rules, like those affecting government contracts which account for 11.5 percent of the EU's Gross Domestic Product.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
