<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="658451" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - June 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - June 12.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Egyptian press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-AHRAM</p>
<p>- Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak and Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi to hold a summit meeting in Libya today. Information Minister Safwat el-Sherif said Mubarak's visit would last two days.</p>
<p>- Mubarak reviews peace-saving efforts and Egypt's contacts to activate the Palestinian track of talks with Israel. The president's political adviser Osama al-Baz will hold two meetings today with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Palestinian President Yasser Arafat. Based on the outcome of the two meetings, a tripartite meeting will be decided.</p>
<p>AL-AKHBAR</p>
<p>- The General Federation of Egypt's Labour Unions condemns the Turkish aggression against northern Iraq.</p>
<p>- Police killed three terrorists in the province of Minya, 240 km  (150 miles) south of Cairo, in a gunbattle early yesterday.</p>
<p>AL-GOMHURIA</p>
<p>- The cabinet decides to increase cash allocations for farmers' wheat deliveries to 700 million pounds ($200 million).</p>
<p>- Interior Minister Hassan el-Alfi said: &quot;The next confrontation of security authorities will be with the (outlawed Moslem) Brotherhood, if it tries, directly or indirectly, to impose itself through crooked means.&quot; Alfi told a gathering of university academics: &quot;The security authorities will not allow the Moslem Brotherhood to run for the next elections at the press and lawyers syndicates.&quot;</p>
<p>- Mubarak to chair the second meeting of the higher council for exports in July.</p>
<p>$1 = 3.395 pounds</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +202 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
