<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="658604" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-PLAY RESUMES; LEHMAN, WOODS AND ELS CHASE MONTGOMERIE.</title>
<headline>GOLF-PLAY RESUMES; LEHMAN, WOODS AND ELS CHASE MONTGOMERIE.</headline>
<byline>Larry Fine</byline>
<dateline>BETHESDA, Maryland 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tom Lehman and Tiger Woods each lost some ground in pursuit of leader Colin Montgomerie Friday as both players were bit by the bogey bug after sitting out a delay of more than two hours at the U.S. Open.</p>
<p>The championship chase was stalled for two hours, 18 minutes due to a threat of lightning in the vicinity of Congressional Country Club.</p>
<p>After play was resumed at 2:10 p.m. (1810 GMT), Masters champion Woods bogeyed the 17th and British Open champion Lehman, playing in the same group, went on to bogey 18.</p>
<p>Lehman finished the round at even-par 70 to remain three under par for the tournament, while the 21-year-old Woods posted a three-under 67 to climb to one over par after starting the championship with a 74 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Montgomerie, who had not yet teed off when play was suspended, later parred the first hole but bogeyed the second to stand at four under par, slipping back into a tie with Hal Sutton, who had yet to begin his second round.</p>
<p>Woods, who began the day four over par, had stormed out to a 31 on the front nine after making four birdies without a blemish. As on Thursday, however, when he went six over par over the last eight holes, the young phenomenon had his troubles on the back nine.</p>
<p>Woods bogeyed the unlucky 13th, birdied the 14th and 15th, then bogeyed the 16th and 17th in his up-and-down inward half.</p>
<p>Ernie Els, the 1994 U.S. Open champion, also fired a four-under score of 31 on the front nine to reach three under par, before posting two bogeys and a birdie coming in. He finished with a round of 67 to stand two under par.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BETHESDA, Maryland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
