<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="658633" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-SUTTON GETS BACK TO BASICS TO CHALLENGE AT U.S. OPEN.</title>
<headline>GOLF-SUTTON GETS BACK TO BASICS TO CHALLENGE AT U.S. OPEN.</headline>
<byline>Larry Fine</byline>
<dateline>BETHESDA, Maryland 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hal Sutton has undergone more makeovers than Dennis Rodman, but the one-time tour sensation believes a return to the basics has gotten him back on track.</p>
<p>Armed with a back-to-roots swing and outlook on golf, Sutton shot an impeccable four-under 66 Thursday to stand just one stroke behind leader Colin Montgomerie of Britain after the first round of the U.S. Open at Congressional Country Club.</p>
<p>Sutton credits his resurgence with a lesson in attitude he received during the Masters from notable teacher Jack Burke, a former Masters and PGA champion.</p>
<p>&quot;What he had to say was a pretty powerful message and it's been hanging with me,&quot; said the 39-year-old from Louisiana.</p>
<p>Sutton began his latest golf rehabilitation last July by making a series of swing changes with his old college coach, Floyd Horgen. But after he started hitting the ball well again, he still felt something was missing.</p>
<p>&quot;Floyd and I kind of talked about it and I said, 'You know, I think I want to go get overhauled with Jackie Burke, mentally.' And Jackie Burke will work you over pretty good.&quot;</p>
<p>Sutton had won seven times, including the 1983 PGA Championship, in his first five years on the tour, but then went into a deep tailspin that left him groping for answers.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been through a lot of makeovers,&quot; said Sutton, who finally ended a nine-year victory drought in 1995.</p>
<p>This time, Burke told him something that stuck.</p>
<p>&quot;Jackie Burke is from the old school, and he believes in playing because of the challenge of the game and playing because you love the game,&quot; said Sutton.</p>
<p>&quot;You know, in today's world it's very easy to get caught up in trying to make X number of dollars. And when you look at contracts, you're looking sometimes at getting the most money instead of getting the best product or whatever.</p>
<p>&quot;And Jackie Burke just asked me one real simple question: He said: 'Do you play golf because you love the game or do you play golf because you're making money?'&quot;</p>
<p>Sutton said he thought Burke was posing a trick question.</p>
<p>&quot;He said, 'It's not a trick, I'm asking you a question. When you get to the last hole and you can't win and there's a par-5 over water, are you thinking about laying up so you can save as many (prize money) dollars as you can, or are you thinking about going for the green because you just love the challenge?'</p>
<p>&quot;And when it came right down to it, I'm laying it up 90 percent of the time,&quot; Sutton admitted.</p>
<p>Sutton suddenly saw the light.</p>
<p>&quot;I got to thinking about it and, you know, when I was an amateur I wasn't playing for money,&quot; said the 1980 U.S. Amateur champion. &quot;I was just playing for trophies. I played because I loved the game.</p>
<p>&quot;When I came out (turned pro), I didn't play for the money because I didn't have any money, I didn't have any debt. I didn't have anything.&quot;</p>
<p>Sutton said his life changed and his attitude changed once the money started rolling in -- and changed some more after it stopped.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that's constant in life. I think that in this game it always seems like you're going uphill, then you're coming back downhill. You're always fixing something.</p>
<p>&quot;But I don't feel like I've been fixing anything for the last two months. I can't remember a time in my life when I had the same playing thought for two months.&quot;</p>
<p>Sutton said he faced a moment of truth right away at a tour stop last month.</p>
<p>&quot;I got tested real quick at the 18th in Atlanta. I got there, I couldn't win the tournament. And I went right for the green across the water. I thought, let's go! I'm playing because I love the game. Here we go.</p>
<p>&quot;I did knock it across, too.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BETHESDA, Maryland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
