<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="658913" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>COTE D'IVOIRE: World chocolate trade to meet Ivorian ministers.</title>
<headline>World chocolate trade to meet Ivorian ministers.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bunce</byline>
<dateline>ABIDJAN 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A world chocolate industry delegation will meet Ivorian ministers on Friday, including farm minister Lambert Kouassi Konan and commodities minister Guy-Alain Gauze, to discuss cocoa quality, supply and the credibility of Ivorian export contracts, a delegate said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are here to discuss, in particular, supply and quality,&quot; he told Reuters before going into a separate meeting with the World Bank.</p>
<p>The talks, under the auspices of the world chocolate organisation OICCC (Office International du Cacao, Chocolat et de la Confiserie), were being held against a background of stricter food legislation worldwide and rising demand for quality chocolate in some consuming countries, delegates said.</p>
<p>&quot;Legislators and consumers are putting pressure on us,&quot; one added. &quot;There are a lot of factories going up in Eastern Europe and Asia and we can't afford any hiccups.&quot;</p>
<p>Ivory Coast's plans to add to its four existing cocoa processing factories and process 50 percent of Ivorian production by 2000 will also be on the agenda for the talks, the government said in a Thursday news release.</p>
<p>Ivory Coast has been reducing the role of its state Caisse de Stabilisation (Caistab) marketing board since 1995 and liberalising cocoa marketing under the terms of a $150 million World Bank loan.</p>
<p>Industry concerns have centred on cocoa quality and on ensuring that bids submitted under Ivory Coast's export contract auction system -- in place since May 1996 -- are not inflated to win contracts.</p>
<p>Industry has raised the problem of non-application of auction penalties against exporters for speculating on world prices by delaying shipments.</p>
<p>The delegation includes Cocoa Association of London president Anthony Ward, a trader for U.S.-based Phibro, which has built up a large position in Ivorian cocoa, and representatives of France's Association Francaise du Commerce du Cacao and the U.S. trade body CMA.</p>
<p>The chairman of CAOBISCO, Europe's chocolate trade body, and European Union officials are also attending, along with representatives of chocolate manufacturers such as U.S.-based Hershey, Britain's Cadbury and Switzerland's Nestle, said a trade delegate.</p>
<p>The delegation, which arrived after holding similar talks in Ghana earlier this week, held private talks with the Caistab and the exporters' forum GEPEX on Thursday before meeting World Bank officials on Friday morning.</p>
<p>The GEPEX has recently been in discussions with the Caistab over the management of Ivory Coast's export contract auction system. Auction prices early this year rose above international futures prices.</p>
<p>--Abidjan newsroom +225 21 90 90</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100144">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABIDJAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COTE D'IVOIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
