<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="658959" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - CZECH REPUBLIC - JUNE 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - CZECH REPUBLIC - JUNE 13.</headline>
<text>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - As part of the proposal for new social laws presented by Labour and Social Affairs Minister Jindrich Vodicka, the cabinet decided yesterday that pensions can increase only if inflation reaches 10 percent. Vodicka also proposed that the number of people receiving social support decrease and that support for unemployment should decrease by 10 percent.</p>
<p>- The central bank did not hold any repo operations yesterday, and experts believe it is beginning to think that decreasing interest rates will not cause the crown to weaken, according to Daniel Heller from Credit Lyonais.</p>
<p>- The cabinet approved conditions for issuing 20-year, 200,000 crown no-interest loans for housing with delayed payment of 10 years. It also agreed on a system for progressively increasing mortgage payments.</p>
<p>- The Czech Army's order from Aero Vodochody for 72 L-159 sub-sonic jet fighters, which was confirmed yesterday, is the most demanding order in the history of the company.</p>
<p>- Skoda Plzen signed a contract in Uzbekistan for the supply of another 40 trolleybuses. Since 1993, it has exported 135 vehicles to Uzbekistan.</p>
<p>- This year, the Export Guarantee Insurance Company (EGAP) insured trade contracts for nearly 20 billion crowns. Most of these contracts were in Turkey.</p>
<p>PRAVO - American President Bill Clinton announced that he wants for three countries to enter NATO in the first wave of expansion: the Czech Republic, Hungary and Poland.</p>
<p>- On Thursday, the Senate approved an increase in concessionary payments for public television and radio. Television payments will increase to 75 crowns and radio to 37 crowns monthly from July 1.</p>
<p>- The union of industry and transport respects the necessity to approve short-term measures to help the economy, but it also calls for long-term programmes, and is prepared to participate in these, according to their position agreed on at meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>LIDOVE NOVINY - Beginning today, the Czech National Bank is allowing banks to obtain Lombard credits. The rate remains unchanged at 50 percent.</p>
<p>- As of yesterday, Foresbank is offering clients seven-day and two-week revolving accounts, with which it wants to prevent long lines at its branches.</p>
<p>- Private operators of petrol stations which are members of the society of petrol stations need to increase prices by at least 60 hellers per litre on average due to the current economic situation. The price of petrol should grow to around 25 crowns per litre.</p>
<p>- A survey from STEM confirmed IVVM's results that the opposition Social Democrats (CSSD) are ahead of the strongest coalition party, the Civic Democratic Party (ODS). STEM placed CSSD at 30.1 percent and ODS at 20.8 percent.</p>
<p>MLADA FRONTA DNES - One of the largest domestic food makers, Vitana, which controls more than 50 percent of the market in soups, will buy the leading manufacturer and trader with spices, Emarko, which will also give it the largest processor of rice, Bask, according to its owner, Norway's Rieber &amp; Son.</p>
<p>- The Finance Ministry revoked the licences of the closed-end fund Vltava and the open-end funds Palcat and Vysehrad, all administered by Investicni Spolecnost Bohemia.</p>
<p>- The top 100 companies according to ING Bank and Resources had total sales last year of more than 875 million crowns, 20 percent of the country's total revenue. The firms employed about 425,000 people, 10 percent of the total workforce.</p>
<p>- The Bureau for Preserving Economic Competition upheld a Finance Ministry verdict that the winner of the tender to build a staff information system for the Czech Army is EDS-Digital. The bureau rejected protests from Unysis and IBM.</p>
<p>- The cabinet decided yesterday that people who do not pay social and health insurance could be punished with three years in prison, and in cases involving large amounts of money, as much as eight years in prison.</p>
<p>- In a cabinet meeting yesterday, Health Minister Jan Strasky took back proposals from his secretary Miroslav Macek because he was not satisfied with them.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 420-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
