<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="659031" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: US firm to start Ukraine depository certificates.</title>
<headline>US firm to start Ukraine depository certificates.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. firm Ladenburg Thalmann International Ltd will begin issuing Ukrainian Depository Certificates (UDC) covering Ukrainian equities in September, the head of the Ukraine branch said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The UDCs will make it easy for large institutional investors to buy shares on the Ukrainian market without having to experience current settlement problems,&quot; said Joseph Kolb, chief executive of Ladenberg Thalmann Ukrainian Securities LLC.</p>
<p>Kolb told Reuters the over-the-counter certificates, modelled on Russian Depository Certificates (RDC) launched by Western investment banks in 1995, would be made available on shares of 15 Ukrainian companies.</p>
<p>Companies which have started trading on Ukraine's embryonic stock market expect development of clearing and settlement centres and a depository within a year.</p>
<p>Kolb said UDCs would eventually be convertible to American Depository Receipts (ADRs), not possible under existing rules.</p>
<p>The firm would begin trading in Ukrainian equities and fixed-income securities next month, and planned to begin an index of the top 50 Ukrainian companies by September, Kolb added.</p>
<p>Bank Societe Generale Ukraine, whose sub-group SGEAN-London recently launched the $50 million Socgen Ladenburg Unveil Ukraine Fund, will serve as custodian for Ukrainian shares against which UDCs will be issued.</p>
<p>--Irene Marushko, Kiev Newsroom +380 44 244-9150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
