<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="65913" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Rolling settlement begins for JGB transactions.</title>
<headline>Rolling settlement begins for JGB transactions.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new rolling settlement system began on Thursday for transactions in Japanese government bonds (JGBs) to reduce risks in settlement, an official at Japan Bond Trading Co said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Beginning with JGBs traded on September 19, deliveries will always take place seven days after the transaction date, rather than eight, nine or even 10 days, which used to be the case,&quot; said Akio Kimura, director at Japan Bond Trading Co, the largest inter-dealer broker in Japan.</p>
<p>JGBs traded on Thursday will be settled on October 1, he said.  </p>
<p>Under the new system, settlement will take place every business day, rather than on fixed dates, as was the practice earlier.</p>
<p>JGB settlement formerly took place on fixed dates -- the 5th, 10th, 15th, 20th, 25th and 30th of each month -- and it took from seven to 11 business days to settle JGB transactions.</p>
<p>The adoption of rolling settlement will lessen risk by reducing the amount of money involved on a particular settlement day and by shortening the time lag between trade and settlement, said Kimura of Japan Bond Trading.  </p>
<p>&quot;Under the old system, there could only be six settlement days in a particular month. The new system may have as many as 20 settlement days each month, so there will be less concentration of funds,&quot; Kimura said.</p>
<p>As for the shortening of the time lag between trade and settlement to reduce risk, the eventual goal is to achieve &quot;T+3,&quot; or settlement on the third day after the transaction.</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal is to achieve T+3 by April of next year,&quot; Kimura said.  In the Eurobond market, transactions are settled three days after a deal and U.S. Treasuries are settled one day after the transaction.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
