<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="65931" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PLDT to seek approval to impose metered rates.</title>
<headline>PLDT to seek approval to impose metered rates.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine Long Distance Telephone Co said on Thursday it will apply to the state National Telecommunications Commission (NTC) in October for permission to introduce metered rates, allowing it to charge for local calls.</p>
<p>&quot;It should have an effect on our bottom line. If people do not change their usage, it will mean incremental revenue for us,&quot; PLDT executive vice-president Edgardo M. Del Fonso told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;If people suppress their calls, circuits will be less tied, the network will be more efficient and there will be less need for additional lines. Either way, it's a plus for us,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>PLDT currently charges subscribers a flat monthly rate for all local calls regardless of their duration or frequency.</p>
<p>Del Fonso said an in-house study showed the metering scheme would lead to a net increase in revenues. He declined to reveal figures.</p>
<p>PLDT shares gained 45 pesos, or 2.68 percent, to a year high of 1,720 pesos in early Manila trade on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are looking forward to the metering scheme to increase PLDT's revenues. Even with the entry of new telecom companies, it will take a lot of time before PLDT's share will be eaten up. These companies do not pose any threat,&quot; said Juanis Barredo, analyst at Citisecurities.</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom 63 2 8418938 fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
