<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="659325" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Vietnam buys diesel for power generation-traders.</title>
<headline>Vietnam buys diesel for power generation-traders.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam has bought three spot diesel cargoes totalling 66,000 tonnes in the face of a possible power shortage, industry sources said on Friday.</p>
<p>Vietnam's state electricity monopoly said earlier this week there could be widespread power outages within weeks unless water levels in hydro-power dams increased.</p>
<p>A senior official of Electricity of Vietnam (EVN) told Reuters that EVN was using diesel generators and other machinery to maintain supplies to most areas of the country.  </p>
<p>On Friday, oil traders said the diesel cargoes purchased by state-owned Vietnam National Petroleum Import-Export Corp (Petrolimex) were for delivery in the second half of June.</p>
<p>They said the diesel was to help cover the power shortages. Vietnam buys most of its diesel through term contracts and it is very unusal for Vietnam to purchase diesel in the spot market, they said.</p>
<p>The 1.0-percent sulphur diesel cargoes were sold at about 70 cents over spot Singapore quotes on a cost-and-freight basis to Ho Chi Minh City.  </p>
<p>Traders said the purchases by Petrolimex could also be partly attributed to a decline in second quarter deliveries of diesel, compared to the first quarter, in its quarterly tenders.</p>
<p>Petrolimex cut purchases to 170,000 tonnes of diesel for delivery in the second quarter from 207,000 tonnes for the first quarter.</p>
<p>Vietnam is expected to issue a tender within the next two weeks to purchase petroleum products for delivery in the third quarter, traders said.  </p>
<p>Petrolimex also has a two-year term contract with Kuwait Petroleum Corp for the purchase of diesel and jet fuel in 1997 and 1998.</p>
<p>The contract is for the import of 700,000 tonnes of diesel and 120,000-130,000 tonnes of jet fuel.</p>
<p>Vietnam plans to produce 19.7 billion kilowatt hours of power in 1997.</p>
<p>The latest government data shows that hydro-power generated 71 percent of power in 1995 and thermal generation, including coal, oil and diesel was a combined 29 percent.</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65-870-3093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
