<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="659316" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Ford hopes to make China catalytic converter.</title>
<headline>Ford hopes to make China catalytic converter.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. auto maker Ford Motor Co is working with Chinese researchers on developing a rare earth catalytic converter, but it will be many years before China requires the devices on its cars, officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>Ford launched the programme to develop the converters to reduce car emissions earlier this year through China's Ministry of Machine-Building Industry, said Ford China spokeswoman Yang Meihong.</p>
<p>The project is being financed by Ford's China Research and Development Fund, which will support the research for three years in the cities of Shanghai, Dalian and Kunming, Yang said in an interview.</p>
<p>Yang said she did not know how much Ford was spending on the converter project, but said the $1.6 million research fund was supporting 16 separate projects in China.</p>
<p>Researchers were studying how to make a catalytic converter based on rare earths -- which China is rich in -- rather than the more pricey metals platinum, palladium and rhodium used in traditional devices, Yang said.</p>
<p>&quot;China is rich in rare earths,&quot; she said. &quot;The rare earths can be a replacement for those expensive metals.&quot;</p>
<p>Chinese officials have said the converters would be produced in small numbers by the year 2000 but Yang said Ford did not yet have a detailed production deal worked out.</p>
<p>&quot;This project will be capable of export to outside markets and China can use them to reduce emissions of its automobiles,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>China made an estimated 1.6 million automobiles last year, including 384,000 passenger cars, none of them with catalytic converters.</p>
<p>China is worried about the environmental impact of large numbers of vehicles on its roads, said an official with U.S. car firm General Motors (GM).</p>
<p>But China would not mandate catalytic converters for many years yet because they required the use of unleaded petrol, which is unavailable in China, said the GM official, who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>China has said it will phase in unleaded petrol in major cities by the year 2000, but GM, which has started work on a $1.57 billion sedan joint venture in Shanghai, would not put converters on its cars even then, the official said.</p>
<p>&quot;You may be able to get unleaded gasoline in Shanghai, but if you drive to (nearby) Anhui province, you won't be able to find it,&quot; said the official, who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>An official of Volkswagen AG, which has car-making joint ventures in Shanghai and northeastern Changchun city, said the German car firm had no plans now to start making catalytic converters, but would be ready when the time came.</p>
<p>&quot;We will make whatever is appropriate on what can be locally sourced,&quot; said Eric Carlson, sales manager for Volkswagen AG's Asia-Pacific operations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
