<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="65943" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Henderson China in low-cost housing - paper.</title>
<headline>Henderson China in low-cost housing - paper.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Henderson China Holdings Ltd has signed a letter of intent to invest US$360 million in developing subsidised housing units in the northern Chinese city of Tianjin, Sing Tao Daily said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Henderson China, a spinoff of Henderson Land Development Co Ltd, will build 20,000 flats comprising two million square metres of housing, the newspaper quoted an official of the Tianjin Low-Cost Housing Working Group, Wei Jianhua, as saying in Tianjin.</p>
<p>Henderson China was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>&quot;If Henderson completes the project within two years they will get a total return of about 17.5 percent,&quot; Wei said.</p>
<p>The municipal government would buy the houses from Henderson at a price 15 percent above the construction cost and would also pay 10 percent annual interest on the financing provided by Henderson, it added.</p>
<p>This would be the first time Henderson China has participated in a Chinese government subsidised housing project.</p>
<p>Henderson China mainly engages in office and retail developments and the building of luxury residential units in Shanghai, Guangzhou and Beijing.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong News Room (852) 2843 6369</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
