<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="659526" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soybeans end up, July rallies on supply.</title>
<headline>CBOT soybeans end up, July rallies on supply.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lingering concerns over low U.S. soybean stocks boosted July soybeans to sharply higher closes Friday, and other months ended with modest gains, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still tight, there's no question about that,&quot; said Sid Love, analyst with Kropf and Love Consulting in Overland Park, Kan. &quot;If the USDA hadn't raised (U.S.) imports, the carryout would have been 115 (million) bushels.&quot;</p>
<p>On Thursday, the U.S. Department of Agriculture raised 1996/97 soybean ending stocks by five million bushels to 130, but supplies are still near 20-year lows.</p>
<p>Around midsession, the tight supplies caused July soybeans to rally to the daily 30-cent trading limit, but the contract's inability to hold that level spurred sales, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;As soon as we failed to lock limit in July, the bulls began liquidating,&quot; said one floor trader.</p>
<p>In early trading, July also punctured several key resistance points, which triggered heavy buy-stop orders and accelerated the pace of gains, traders said.</p>
<p>July soybeans ended up 13 cents at $8.54-1/2, with other months up two to 6-1/4 cents.  </p>
<p>Weekly crushing data from the National Oilseed Processors Association was also viewed as supportive to nearby contracts, traders said.</p>
<p>The NOPA crush of 25.387 million bushels came in near the high end of trade expectations and implied robust near-term demand for soybeans, traders said.</p>
<p>Volatile trade in the July/November spread was also noted.</p>
<p>On the day, Refco bought four million bushels July, Merrill Lynch bought 2.5 million July and 1.5 million November. Term Commodities sold 2.5 million July, pit sources said.</p>
<p>In options trade, Lind-Waldock bought 500 November $6.25 puts and sold 500 September $8.25 calls. Rosenthal bought 1,000 July $9.00 calls and Continental Grain bought 600 August $8.00 calls and sold 600 August $8.75 calls.</p>
<p>Soybean futures volume was estimated by the CBOT at 72,000 contracts, above Thursday's actual volume of 61,952, according to CBOT data.</p>
<p>((Anna Driver 312-408-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
