<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="659508" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Securities group praises House tax cut bill.</title>
<headline>Securities group praises House tax cut bill.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Securities Industry Association on Friday lauded the savings incentives provisions in a sweeping tax reform bill approved by the House Ways and Means Committee.</p>
<p>&quot;The House Ways and Means Committee is to be congratulated for their efforts in approving some significant incentives to help all Americans save more for college, retirement, and other long-term financial goals,&quot; said SIA president Marc Lackritz, referring to the tax plan, which includes $85 billion in tax cuts over the next five years.  </p>
<p>He highlighted provisions in the bill allowing individuals to set up education savings accounts with special tax breaks, the back-ended Individual Retirement Account (IRA), and a cut in capital gains tax rates both for individuals and corporations.</p>
<p>&quot;The Committee also rolled back or eliminated a number of punitive taxes on savings and investment. If enacted, these proposals would have made it more difficult for companies to raise capital,&quot; Lackritz said.</p>
<p>SIA called on the Senate Finance Committee to expand some tax incentives in its tax plan to be considered next week.</p>
<p>&quot;We are working with the Senate Finance Committee members, for example, to expand IRA eligibility so that the spouses of single-wage-earning couples can make a full $2,000 contribution to an IRA regardless of whether the income-earning spouse participates in a pension plan,&quot; Lackritz said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
