<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="659672" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Focus-Mass. moves to take over Middlesex County.</title>
<headline>Focus-Mass. moves to take over Middlesex County.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Massachusetts moved toward assuming even more power by absorbing the employees and duties of beleaguered Middlesex County.</p>
<p>The House on Thursday voted to abolish Middlesex County, wiping out the three-member commission that runs it, absorbing its corrections and record-keeping functions, and taking on the costs of its operations and the pensions of its employees, State House News Service reported.</p>
<p>The county is in default on some of its bonds, with more defaults possible later this month. It has almost $19 million in debt it cannot pay.</p>
<p>Counties in general have needed huge amounts of state help over the past decade, as the rising costs of corrections, the courthouses, and recording outstrip the ancient governments' revenue sources.</p>
<p>The issue has opened a schism between the branches, because the Senate passed budget riders wiping out all 14 counties.</p>
<p>The House has argued that the process should be more deliberative, with a task force to study which counties really need to be wiped out, which should remain and which functions the state should take on. A decision on what the final budget sent to the governor should say about county government is in the hands of a House-Senate conference committee.</p>
<p>Progress was reported this week on Boston Mayor Thomas Menino's top priority, a new convention center in Boston. Both Menino and House Speaker Thomas Finneran said they are moving closer to agreeing on what mix of new taxes and city contributions should be used to finance a $700 million 600,000-square-foot convention hall in South Boston.</p>
<p>After years of disagreement about how to give Boston the facility nearly everyone agrees it needs, it appears the plans finally may be ready to come to fruition.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the State Administration Committee moved toward approving funds for a variety of projects with the same objective as the Boston center: new economic activity in Massachusetts cities.</p>
<p>The committee took testimony on the governor's bill financing improvements to the Basketball Hall of Fame in Springfield; $2.5 million for a National Music Center in the Berkshires; a better convention facility in Worcester; and repairs to an industrial park in Fall River. The bill totaled more than $50 million.</p>
<p>A new tax would be imposed on home sales in Cambridge and the 15 communities in Barnstable County under provisions of a bill approved Wednesday by the Taxation Committee.</p>
<p>With adultery much in the news these days, particularly in Massachusetts, a hearing of the Judiciary Committee Wednesday got extra attention.</p>
<p>Rep.David Cohen (D-Newton) routinely files a bill wiping out the ancient &quot;blue laws&quot; that make adultery, premarital sex and sodomy illegal. This year, the Michael Kennedy, Kelly Flinn, Joseph Ralston and Frank Gifford cases have put &quot;crimes of the flesh&quot; at the top of the news.</p>
<p>Cohen said the commonwealth should not abide unenforced laws. But other lawmakers said there's no reason to send out the message that adultery is okay.</p>
<p>As if the electoral picture for 1998 weren't complex enough already, State Treasurer Joe Malone added another level this week. He said he'll probably run for governor with a woman as his running mate. Malone suggested former Economic Affairs Secretary Gloria Larson would make a good choice.</p>
<p>Huge problem: she suggested that Malone's rival, Lt. Gov. Paul Cellucci, ought to be the next governor, and that if she runs, she wants to run with Cellucci.</p>
<p>((Boston Bureau, 617-367-4106)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
