<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="659756" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Intermountain Power bonds may be called - official.</title>
<headline>Intermountain Power bonds may be called - official.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The proposed restructuring of Utah's Intermountain Power Agency (IPA) could include calling or defeasing billions of dollars of outstanding debt, the agency's senior debt manager said Friday.</p>
<p>Allyn Orme, IPA's capital programs manager, said plans to call or defease the nearly $5 billion of outstanding agency debt were still &quot;very preliminary.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;A reasonable outcome of this (restructuring) is that all of IPA's bonds could be called on normal call dates and/or defeased,&quot; Orme said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Asked if bondholders would be hurt, he said: &quot;There's no risk to bondholders in this transaction. There is no downside. The only impact on the bondholders is on the upside.&quot;</p>
<p>The Intermountain Power Agency -- which operates a 1,640 megawatt coal-fired power station in Delta, Utah -- is negotiating a new ownership structure that would dramatically change the way the power station is governed.  </p>
<p>The proposal has made some analysts and investors nervous.</p>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's Corp. warned Thursday that the changes could result in lower ratings for IPA.</p>
<p>Some traders and fund managers said they fear the agency will call its bonds at or near par, hurting bondholders because IPA debt has been trading at a premium.</p>
<p>As currently structured, IPA is composed of 23 Utah cities that collectively own the assets of the agency. The agency, however, sends its power to six California cities, which provide IPA with the revenues to pay debt service.</p>
<p>Under the proposed restructuring, the six California entities, including the Los Angeles Department of Water and Power, Anaheim and Pasadena, would take over ownership and governance from the Utah cities. In exchange, the Utah cities would give up their liability for the bonds, Orme said.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been no definitive solutions on how to deal with the remaining debt,&quot; Orme told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said, however, that the restructuring could involve the call of bonds on their stated call dates and the defeasance of debt. There is no risk of early calls, he said, adding; &quot;We have no ability to make a premature call.&quot;</p>
<p>Orme said a final restructuring proposal could be put together in the coming months. The plan, however, could take years to implement, he added.</p>
<p>((- Adam Entous, 415-677-2511))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
