<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="659875" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: BoF head happy with low May French inflation.</title>
<headline>BoF head happy with low May French inflation.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Official figures showing weak French inflation won praise on Friday from Bank of France Governor Jean-Claude Trichet who said it was one of the conditions for low interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;Confirmation of a weak rise in prices is...one of the necessary conditions to permit our medium- and long-term rates to be kept at a remarkably low level, the third lowest in the world and the lowest in the European Union, along with Dutch and German rates,&quot; he told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>The preliminary data released on Friday by national statistics institute INSEE showed a month-on-month rise in May of 0.2 percent and a year-on-year rise of 0.9 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;This good result conforms to the objectives of the Monetary Policy Council (of the Bank of France) for 1997,&quot; Trichet said.</p>
<p>Trichet said last December that the central bank's goal was a price increase cap of two percent for 1997 and the medium term. The low inflation &quot;would help preserve the purchasing power of households,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The latest figures meant that, &quot;France today ranks among the three countries in the European Union performing best in terms of inflation,&quot; Trichet said.</p>
<p>He noted that the average year-on-year inflation rate in the European Union in April stood at 1.5 percent.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
