<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="659928" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norway shares rise on Nycomed takeover talk.</title>
<headline>Norway shares rise on Nycomed takeover talk.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Norwegian stock index rose on Friday after shares in drugs group Nycomed ASA jumped on a report that it may be taken over by German chemicals and pharmaceuticals group Altana AG.</p>
<p>Nycomed's A share finished 4.33 percent higher at 109.00 crowns. It was the fourth most traded stock in Oslo at 64 million crowns. The Oslo Bourse Total index closed 0.65 percent higher at 1,183.83 points in trade worth 1.1 billion crowns.</p>
<p>German newsletter Platow Brief reported in its Thursday edition that Altana might be interested in joining forces with Nycomed, triggering Friday's rally.  </p>
<p>The newsletter reported cash-rich Altana was seriously looking for a partner to strengthen its pharmaceutical division and had cast an eye on Nycomed.</p>
<p>Neither Nycomed, nor Altana would comment on the report.</p>
<p>Industrial giant Norsk Hydro, Norway's largest listed company, was another winner in Oslo, rising 0.65 percent to 386 crowns in trade worth 120 million crowns.</p>
<p>--Rolf Soderlind, Oslo newsroom +47 22 42 50 41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
