<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="66003" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German M3 and business confidence grow in August.</title>
<headline>German M3 and business confidence grow in August.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bundesbank said on Thursday that German M3 money supply grew at an annualised rate of 8.7 percent in August, up from 8.6 percent in July.</p>
<p>The growth was stronger than expected.</p>
<p>Most economists had predicted M3 growth would have slowed again in August, following a steady downward trend seen in recent months.</p>
<p>Economists had predicted an annualised rate of eight percent from 8.6 percent in July. Forecasts ranged from 7.9 percent to 8.2 percent. The Bundesbank is aiming for M3 growth between four and seven percent this year.</p>
<p>Separately, the Munich-based ifo economic research institute reported a modest pick-up in business confidence in August, broadly in line with expectations.</p>
<p>The Ifo business climate index for west Germany rose to 94.4 from a revised 94.0 which was previously reported as 94.1, Ifo said in a statement. Most economists had predicted a figure of about 94.5.</p>
<p>German bonds dropped quickly in response to the M3 news on the assumption that it made a further cut in German interest rates less likely. There has been some speculation that a further cut in German rates was possible later this year.</p>
<p>But the subsequent news that business confidence had risen only modestly confirmed that the economic upturn remained fragile, and bonds quickly pared their losses.</p>
<p>Klaus Baader, Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in London told Reuters Financial Television: &quot;The (M3) number is not a major catastrophe, but the process of rapid convergence toward the growth target (four to seven pct) has been interrupted. Reaching the target after this will be an uphill struggle.&quot;</p>
<p>The Bundesbank targets M3 money supply growth as its main monetary policy indicator on the grounds that it provides a guide to future inflation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
