<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="660236" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France, Germany short of final deal on EMU problems.</title>
<headline>France, Germany short of final deal on EMU problems.</headline>
<byline>Brian Love</byline>
<dateline>POITIERS, France 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leaders of France and Germany made progress but failed to reach a final accord on Friday on European Union policy coordination for growth and jobs aimed at keeping the planned euro single currency on track, officials said.</p>
<p>They said German Chancellor Helmut Kohl and French President Jacques Chirac, who met for talks in this western French city, hoped for agreement at a summit in Amsterdam next week on French demands for new EU commitments to promote growth and jobs.</p>
<p>German Finance Minister Theo Waigel said he was &quot;cautiously optimistic&quot; about a reaching a final deal at Amsterdam but that EU finance ministers would meet again on Sunday, the eve of the summit.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope we will be able to find a solution,&quot; he told reporters after the one-day talks.</p>
<p>A French source said Chirac, forced by his centre-right coalition's defeat to share power with a left-wing government, told Kohl the French election campaign had raised expectations which could make it harder to meet Maastricht treaty criteria on a single currency.</p>
<p>&quot;The president presented the new situation in France, where things were said in the campaign and expectations were created that may be an additional complicating factor in achieving the criteria,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>Both sides remained determined to meet the conditions for monetary union and recognised this would involve extra efforts.</p>
<p>Chirac asked Kohl to show understanding for the new French position on the European Union's &quot;stability pact&quot; limiting budget deficits, given both countries' attachment to achieving Economic and Monetary Union.</p>
<p>Socialist Prime Minister Lionel Jospin met Kohl separately later to seek a formula for a resolution on employment and growth that would enable his government to approve the stablity pact at the Amsterdam summit on Monday and Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Jospin government, which took power last week after an upset victory in June 1 elections, stunned Bonn and other European partners by saying it wanted a delay to study the German-driven pact aimed at assuring fiscal discipline after the introduction of the euro.</p>
<p>French Finance Minister Dominique Strauss-Kahn and Waigel met separately to discuss details of the stability pact issue and both said afterwards they had made progress.</p>
<p>The French source quoted Kohl as saying that, while he understood Chirac's position, the pact was absolutely necessary to create the single currency and could not be abandoned.</p>
<p>Jospin's Socialists pledged during the election campaign to redirect European economic policy from austerity towards promoting growth and jobs.</p>
<p>The failure of France's previous centre-right government to keep similar campaign promises was a key reason for its surprise election defeat.</p>
<p>Germany has consistently focused on fiscal discipline and price stability in the run-up to a single currency, but Kohl's reputation was dented when his government proposed revaluing the central bank's gold reserves to qualify for the euro.</p>
<p>European Commission President Jacques Santer said the EU's Dutch presidency had put forward proposals that should pave the way for approval of the stability pact at the Amsterdam summit.</p>
<p>Santer said the proposal would integrate the goal of boosting employment into plans for more coordination of economic policies under monetary union. French officials said there would be no numerical target on jobs.</p>
<p>Santer said that if the European Union managed to &quot;give muscle&quot; to two articles in the Maastricht treaty on monetary union -- articles 102a and 103, which provide for economic policy coordination -- &quot;we will certainly have an agreement&quot;.</p>
<p>German officials said Bonn would not agree to any resolution that gave the European Commission new powers or involved extra spending on employment measures, nor would it accept a link between the stability pact and an EU statement on jobs.</p>
<p>French officials said they wanted the jobs and growth resolution to be appended to the stability pact.</p>
<p>The Poitiers summit was widely seen as a test of the close partnership between Bonn and Paris, seen as the dual engines in the drive for European unity.</p>
<p>Financial markets and some European capitals have shown concern that the controversy could undermine the steady march to the euro's launch on January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>Bowing to the EU's new leftward tilt following the British and French elections, Germany agreed this week to add a jobs chapter to the revised Maastricht treaty on European integration which is to come up for ratification in Amsterdam.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="POITIERS, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
