<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="660256" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EMU CONVERGENCE CRITERIA: GUIDE BY DEUTSCHE BANK.</title>
<headline>EMU CONVERGENCE CRITERIA: GUIDE BY DEUTSCHE BANK.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a table of the key convergence criteria for European Economic and Monetary Union under the Maastricht Treaty detailing where each country stands, compiled by Deutsche Bank Research in Frankfurt. Figures for 1997 and 1998 are forecasts by Deutsche.</p>
<p>Actual latest domestic consumer price inflation year-on-year rates for each country are also listed. All figures given are percentages. Long-term interest rates are the average of the 12 months to July. Notes and definitions to criteria are listed below. All latest inflation figures are compiled by Reuters.</p>
<p>		    Inflation	 Deficit/GDP    Debt/GDP   L-term</p>
<p>									     rates</p>
<p>	     1997  1998  Latest    1997  1998    1997  1998</p>
<p>Germany    1.2   1.4   1.6	 3.0   3.0     62.0  62.5    6.1</p>
<p>France     1.5   1.9   0.9	 3.1   3.0     58.0  58.5    6.0</p>
<p>Italy	2.2   2.3   1.6	 3.1   2.9    124.3 121.5    8.4</p>
<p>Britain    1.8   2.5   2.6	 2.9   1.9     54.2  52.9    7.8</p>
<p>Spain	2.1   2.4   1.5	 3.0   2.9     68.2  67.5    7.8</p>
<p>Nethrlnds  1.7   2.0   2.2	 2.2   2.1     74.1  72.3    6.0</p>
<p>Belgium    1.4   1.8   1.58	2.8   2.7    127.0 123.4    6.2</p>
<p>Sweden     1.7   1.9   0.3	 2.4   1.5     76.7  74.7    7.6</p>
<p>Austria    1.4   1.9   1.5	 3.2   2.9     68.3  68.3    6.1</p>
<p>Denmark    2.1   2.4   1.7	(0.1) (0.1)**  67.8  65.5    6.9</p>
<p>Finland    1.0   1.6   1.0	 1.8   1.0     58.6  57.0    6.6</p>
<p>Portugal   2.1   2.6   1.8	 3.0   2.9     64.4  63.6    7.7</p>
<p>Greece     6.0   5.4   5.4	 5.2   3.8    109.1 105.3  *12.0</p>
<p>Ireland    2.0   2.4   1.5	 1.5   1.5     71.8  67.2    7.0</p>
<p>Luxmbrg    2.2   2.2   1.07     (1.0) (1.0)**   6.6   7.0    6.2</p>
<p>*   Indicates 12-month T-bill rates</p>
<p>**  Indicates surplus, not deficit, as a percentage of GDP</p>
<p>CONVERGENCE CRITERIA</p>
<p>1. The criterion on price stability shall mean that a Member State has a price performance that is sustainable and an average rate of inflation observed over a period of one year before the examination that does not exceed by more than 1-1/2 percentage points that of, at most, the three best performing Member States in terms of price stability. Inflation shall be measured by means of the consumer price index on a comparable basis, taking into account differences in national definitions.</p>
<p>2. The criterion on the sustainability of the government financial position shall mean that the Member States avoid excessive government deficits, in particular a) the ratio of the planned or actual government deficit to gross domestic product shall not exceed three percent, unless either the ratio has declined substantially and continuously and reached a level that comes close to the reference value, or alternatively, the excess over the reference value is only exceptional and temporary and the ratio remains close to the reference value; b) the ratio of government debt to gross domestic product shall not exceed 60 percent, unless the ratio is sufficiently diminishing and approaching the reference value at a satisfactory pace.</p>
<p>3. The criterion on the convergence of interest rates shall mean that, observed over a period of one year before the examination, a Member State has had an average nominal long-term interest rate that does not exceed by more than two percentage points that of, at most, the three best performing Member States in terms of price stability. Interest rates shall be measured on the basis of long-term government bonds or comparable securities, taking into account differences in national definitions.</p>
<p>4. The criterion on participation in the exchange rate mechanism of the European Monetary System shall mean that a Member State has respected the normal fluctuation margins provided for by the exchange rate mechanism of the European Monetary System without severe tensions for at least the last two years before the examination. In particular, the Member State shall not have devalued its currency's bilateral central rate against any other Member State's currency on its own initiative for the same period.</p>
<p>--Reuters London Newsroom +44 171 542 6784</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
