<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="660319" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EU stability pact - extracts from 1996 draft text.</title>
<headline>EU stability pact - extracts from 1996 draft text.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are key extracts from the EU report outlining the Stability and Growth Pact, aimed at enforcing fiscal discipline under EMU. The extracts are taken from the official summary of the conclusions of the Dublin summit held in December 1996.</p>
<p>Ensuring budgetary discipline in Stage 3 of EMU</p>
<p>18. The treaty imposes on member states in Stage 3 of EMU an obligation to avoid excessive deficits. (Reuters note: a footnote to the conclusions says Britain is exempt from this obligation unless it decides to join EMU). Sound government finances...are an essential condition for sustainable and non-inflationary growth and a high level of employment.</p>
<p>19. To that end, the Council (of finance ministers) proposes to adopt regulations on the strengthening of surveillance and budgetary discipline and on speeding up and clarifying the excessive deficit procedure. These regulations, combined with a European Council Resolution, will constitute a stability and growth pact. The resolution would enshrine the solemn political commitment of the Commission, the Council and the member states to the strict and timely application of the pact. The surveillance procedure and the excessive deficit procedure (except, in particular, sanctions) will be common to all member states. Euro area member states will be obliged to submit stability programmes and will be subject to agreed sanctions for failure to act effectively on excesssive deficits. In the surveillance procedure, the other member states will be obliged to submit convergence programmes only. In the excessive deficit procedure, sanctions cannot be applied to them...</p>
<p>21. Each member state will commit itself to aim for a medium term budgetary position of close to balance or in surplus...</p>
<p>22. Member states adopting the euro will be required by secondary legislation to present stability programmes, which will specify their medium term budgetary objectives, together with an adjustment path for the government surplus or deficit ratio and the expected path for the government debt ratio. Furthermore, the programmes will contain the main assumptions about economic developments as well as a sensitivity analysis of the deficit and debt position and explain what is being done to achieve the objective.</p>
<p>23. A separate legislative proposal will be forthcoming from the Commission which will provide for the submission of convergence programmes by the non-euro area member states. The information they will contain, as far as budgetary policy is concerned, will be similar to that of the stability programme.</p>
<p>24. Stability and convergence programmes will be multiannual and will be updated annually...Member states will make their stability and convergence programmes public. Early warning system, monitoring and surveillance</p>
<p>25. The Commission and the Council will study these...programmes and monitor member states budgetary performances...with a view to giving early warning of any significant deterioration which might lead to an excessive deficit. In such cases, the Council will address recommendations to the member state concerned. Excessive deficit procedure</p>
<p>26. Adherence to the objective of sound budgetary positions...will allow a member state to deal with normal cyclical fluctuations while keeping its government deficit within the three percent reference value. Nevertheless, to deter excessive deficits and to ensure that, should they occur, they are promptly eliminated, there is a need for detailed provisions for the implementation of the excessive deficit procedure. A Council Regulation will provide for expediting and clarifying the procedure, in particular by establishing clear definitions and setting deadlines for the various steps. Once it has decided that an excesssive deficit persists, and as long as a member state has failed to comply with a decision under Treaty article 104c(9), the Council will...impose sanctions on a prescribed scale. The European Council Resolution described in paragraph 37 will provide political guidance on how this procedure can be operated efficiently and speedily.</p>
<p>27. An excess of a government deficit over the three percent reference value shall be considered exceptional when resulting from an unusual event outside the control of the relevant member state and which has a major impact on the financial position of general government, or when resulting from a severe economic downturn.</p>
<p>28. The Commision will be invited to commit itself in the European Council Resolution (see paragraph 37) to prepare a report whenever the actual or planned government deficit exceeds the three percent reference value, thereby triggering the procedure under Article 104c(3). The Commission, when preparing such a report, will consider, as a rule, an excess over the reference value resulting from an economic downturn to be exceptional only if there is an annual fall of real GDP of at least two percent.</p>
<p>29. The Economic and Financial Committee will formulate an opinion on the Commission report within two weeks. The Commission, taking fully into account this opinion and if it considers that an excessive deficit exists, will address an opinion and a recommendation to the Council for a decision. In the event that the Commision considers that a deficit is not excessive, the Commission will be invited to commit itself in the European Council Resolution to present in writing to the Council the reasons for its position. This would give the Council the opportunity to discuss the issue taking account of both the Commissions position and the opinion of the Economic and Financial Committee. The Council could decide, by simple majority, to request the Commission under Article 109d to make a recommendation. The Commission will be invited to commit itself in the European Council Resolution to issue, as a rule, such a recommendation, in response to the Council request.</p>
<p>30. The Council when deciding, according to Article 104c (6) on a Commission recommendation, whether an excessive deficit exists, will in its overall assessment take into account any observations made by the member state showing that an annual fall of real GDP of less than two percent is nevertheless exceptional in the light of further supporting evidence, in particular on the abruptness of the downturn or on the accumulated loss of output relative to past trends.</p>
<p>31. Where it decides that an excessive deficit exists, the Council will, at the same time, make recommendations to the Member State concerned with a view to bringing that situation to an end within a given period (Article 104c (7)). These recommendations will accordingly set clear deadlines for 1) the taking of effective action (within four months), and 2) the correction of the excessive deficit, which should be completed in the year following its identification unless special circumstances are given. The Councils initial judgement on whether effective action has been taken will be based on publicly-announced decisions of the Government.</p>
<p>32. If a Member State fails to act in compliance with the successive decisions of the Council under paragraphs seven to nine of Article 104c, the Council will, in accordance with paragraph 11 of that Article, impose sanctions including a non-interest bearing deposit. These sanctions would be imposed within ten months of the reporting of the figures notifying the existence of an excessive deficit. An expedited procedure will be used in the case of a deliberately planned deficit which the Council decides is excessive.</p>
<p>33. The excessive deficit procedure will be held in abeyance if a Member State does in fact adopt, through formal government decision, appropriate action in response to a recommendation under Article 104c (7) or a notice issued under article 104c (9). The Commission and Council will monitor the progress of the Member State continuously until the Council decides under 104c (12) that the excessive deficit has been corrected. If the action is not being implemented, or is proving to be inadequate, the procedure will resume immediately. This would lead to sanctions being imposed in accordance with Article 104c (11) within three months of the procedures resumption.</p>
<p>34. If actual data demonstrate that an excessive deficit has not been corrected within the time limit specified either in the Recommendation under Article 104c (7) or the notice issued under Article 104c (9), the Council will immediately resume the excessive deficit procedure. Structure and scale of sanctions</p>
<p>35. Whenever sanctions are first imposed, a non-interest-bearing deposit should be included. This should be converted into a fine after two years if the deficit of the government concerned continues to be excessive. When the excessive deficit results from non-compliance with the government deficit reference value, the amount of the deposit or fine will be made up of a fixed component equal to 0.2 percent of GDP, and a variable component equal to one tenth of the excess of the deficit over the reference value of three percent of GDP. There will be an upper limit of 0.5 percent of GDP for the annual amount of deposits. The amount of the sanction will be based on outcomes for the year in which the excessive deficit occurred.</p>
<p>36. Further consideration is being given to the disposition of the interest on deposits and the proceeds of the fines on the proviso that there would be no increase in Community spending. European Council Resolution on the Stability and Growth Pact</p>
<p>37. When using the leeway which secondary legislation necessarily must leave to them, the Council and the Commission may receive guidance from the European Council, through, for example, a European Council Resolution. Such a resolution would give strong political guidance to the Commission, the Council and the member states on the implementation of the procedures. The resolution would invite all parties to implement the treaty and the stability and growth pact regulations strictly. The Commission should express a clear commitment to that effect, which would include an undertaking to prepare a report on the budgetary situation in a country whenever there is a risk of an excessive deficit or the planned or actual government deficit exceeds the reference value.</p>
<p>The Council would be invited to take the decisions necessary for carrying the procedure forward as quickly as practicable. If the Council did not act on a Commission recommendation at any stage in the procedure, the resolution would invite the Council always to state in writing the reasons which justify its decision not to act and to make public the votes cast by each member state.The resolution would also cover political agreements on the implementation of the stability and growth pact. In particular, the resolution would invite the Council always to decide to impose sanctions if a participating member state fails to take the necessary steps to bring the excessive deficit situation to an end as recommended by the Council.</p>
<p>The resolution will contain an undertaking by the member states not to invoke the benefit of the provision in paragraph 30 unless they are in severe recession. In evaluating whether the economic downturn is severe, the member states will as a rule take as a reference-point an annual fall in real GDP of at least 0.75 percent.</p>
<p>The recitals of the Council regulation would make an explicit reference to the resolution.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
