<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="660555" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. does not dispute India on missiles.</title>
<headline>U.S. does not dispute India on missiles.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States said on Thursday it did not dispute India's assertion that it has not deployed ballistic missiles along the Pakistan border.</p>
<p>Responding to a comment by Indian Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral, State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns told reporters: &quot;We do not dispute that assertion.&quot;</p>
<p>But he repeated the U.S. view that &quot;deployment or acquisition of ballistic missiles by India or Pakistan would be destabilising and undermine the security of both countries&quot; and urged the two states to keep on with recent peace efforts.</p>
<p>In Pune, India, on Wednesday, Gujral told reporters that media reports that India had deployed its Prithvi missiles on its border with Pakistan were false.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not deployed Prithvi in any part of India and more so on our borders,&quot; Gujral said after inducting the first batch of Russian-built Sukhoi-30 fighter aircraft into the Indian Air Force.</p>
<p>India has tested the 150-mile (250-km) Prithvi missile, and a 90-mile (150-km) variant, and has vowed to press ahead with its missile programme despite opposition from the United States and other countries.</p>
<p>Gujral said it was no secret that India had acquired missile technology but added it was not true that it had deployed missiles on its border with Pakistan.</p>
<p>The Washington Post, quoting U.S. officials, reported on June 3 that India's military forces recently moved a handful of medium-range ballistic missiles to a prospective launch site near the Pakistan border.</p>
<p>In Thursday's editions, the newspaper gave more details, saying U.S. intelligence detected the missiles movement toward the Pakistan border while it was underway and administraiton officials protested to Gujral.</p>
<p>The newspaper said Gujral told Washington Indian army officials orchestrated the movement without his advance knowledge or approval and that he would prevent any further shift of missiles toward the border. Gujral also promised he would keep the missiles from being deployed, the Post said.</p>
<p>Burns, in his comments on Thursday, referred only to the issue of deployment not to any other movement short of that term, which is generally regarded to mean the missiles are operational.</p>
<p>In part because the allegations about missile deployments have infected the atmosphere of promising new talks between India and Pakistan, U.S. officials were reluctant to discuiss the issue at length. But some told Reuters the Indian missiles are not operational or any closer to being useable.</p>
<p>Burns said what is important from the U.S. side is that Secretary of State Madeleine Albright, who is considering a trip to the region later this year, &quot;very much wants to support the recent decisions and moves by India and Pakistan to talk with each other and to try to reduce tensions.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
