<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="660940" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Canadian iron ore producer to take axe to costs.</title>
<headline>Canadian iron ore producer to take axe to costs.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Iron Ore Company of Canada (IOCC), Canada's biggest iron ore producer, said on Friday it aimed to slash costs by a quarter within three to five years.</p>
<p>IOCC chief executive John Le Boutillier said the IOCC board was developing a business plan to attack unit costs and to put the company in the same league as its most efficient rivals.</p>
<p>&quot;We would be looking at least at a 25 percent reduction in costs,&quot; Le Boutillier told Reuters on a visit to Australia, home base for IOCC's new parent company, North Ltd.</p>
<p>IOCC produces about 16 million tonnes of iron ore a year, at cash costs of below US$0.40 per iron tonne unit, with pellets and concentrates at about 65 percent iron content, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying to put the pieces together at senior executive level to come up with a business plan which will have certain specific targets,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have an ambitious programme,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>IOCC is owned 59.3 percent by North, 21.8 percent by Mitsubishi Corp, 12 percent by the Labrador Iron Ore Royalty Income Fund and 6.9 percent by Dofasco Inc.</p>
<p>Le Boutillier said productivity gains would deliver half of the cost reductions, and across-the-board efficiencies the rest.</p>
<p>&quot;About half of it will be volume related and the other half will be efficiencies across the board, and we still have to work this out,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got some ideas and we need to refine this, but it will be across the board: the mine, the concentrator as well as the pellet plant and the railway and the port.&quot;</p>
<p>IOCC operates a mine, concentrator and pellet plant at Carol Lake in Newfoundland.</p>
<p>IOCC plans to shift more of its production toward pellets and, from mid-1998, begin producing direct-reduced pellets which are tailored for the growing electric-arc steel-making market.</p>
<p>IOCC aims to increase its exposure to the pellet markets and hopes within about three years that pellets will account for 80 to 85 percent of its total production base, Le Boutillier said.</p>
<p>The company is considering stepping up total production to around 22 million tonnes a year, with the resurrection of an old pellet plant at the port of Sept-Iles in Quebec province.</p>
<p>The plant, connected to the Carol Lake facilities by a 420-km (261-mile) railway, has been moth-balled since 1981. A feasibility study on re-starting it is underway.</p>
<p>IOCC sits toward the bottom of its industry's efficiency ladder, but aims to reach the top quartile through cost-cutting.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not going to happen overnight. It's a three-year to five-year programme,&quot; Le Boutillier said.</p>
<p>IOCC has a troubled history with its highly unionised 2,245-strong workforce, but Le Boutillier said relations were improving. &quot;We won't correct that overnight,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
