<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="66100" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN says humanitarian crisis acute in Tajikistan.</title>
<headline>UN says humanitarian crisis acute in Tajikistan.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Painting a bleak picture of life in Tajikistan, the United Nations said it intended to send a humanitarian relief mission to the former Soviet republic to increase the current level of assistance.</p>
<p>&quot;The people of Tajikistan are faced with an acute crisis,&quot; said Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali in a report to the Security Council released on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Because of continuing heavy fighting in several areas, he said thousands of civilians have been displaced and many needed aid &quot;to meet their basic survival needs.&quot;</p>
<p>Although the cereal harvest is expected to be larger this year than last, Tajikistan will continue to need foreign help for basic foods. Diarrhoea outbreaks are common and typoid epidemics and  malaria were reported totally out of control.</p>
<p>Since independence in 1992, the central Asian state of 5.7 million people, has suffered a mosaic of clan and regional rivalries, in which tens of thousands of people were killed, 600,000 were displaced and another 300,000 fled the country.</p>
<p>The report described a ceasefire agreement reached in July as a failure. Fighting continued in the central Tavildara area and increased in the the Garm district to the north.</p>
<p>In addition tension was is high on the Tajik-Afghan border and U.N. military observers have been restricted by both sides from inspecting dangerous areas, it said.</p>
<p>Boutros-Ghali called on the government and the rebels to resume direct contacts and said his special representative, Gerd Merrem of Germany, would help set up such a meeting.</p>
<p>The U.N. Mission of Observers in Tajikistan (UNMOT) comprises 94 people, including 44 military observers.</p>
<p>Last month, after weeks of fighting with rebels, government troops took control of the strategically important town of Tavildara, 120 miles (193 km) east of the capital of Dushanbe.</p>
<p>Boutros-Ghali said that in Tavildara itself, about 15 percent of the town haf been completely destroyed and nearly all residents had fled.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TADZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
