<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="661355" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Chinese general in HK border &quot;insult&quot; row -- report.</title>
<headline>Chinese general in HK border &quot;insult&quot; row -- report.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Chinese general clashed with Hong Kong customs and immigration officers when he drove through a restricted border area without a permit, a newspaper said on Friday.</p>
<p>Major-General Zhou Borong, chief of the People's Liberation Army advance unit in Hong Kong, later complained that his force had been insulted by colonial authorities, the South China Morning Post said.</p>
<p>It was the first report of any incident since the general led a vanguard of troops into Hong Kong two months ago in a downbeat, &quot;softly-softly&quot; advance as Britain prepares to withdraw on June 30.</p>
<p>The PLA has an advance party of 196 soldiers in Hong Kong to prepare garrison facilities ahead of Britain's withdrawal, ending 156 years of colonial rule, just 18 days from now.</p>
<p>The daily said a senior customs official was called and the general was allowed to pass despite having no permit to travel through the Lok Ma Chau village, which straddles the Hong Kong-China land border.</p>
<p>The general has said his troops want to improve a tarnished PLA image after the force massacred unarmed pro-democracy protesters in Beijing's Tiananmen Square in 1989.</p>
<p>He said the incident was an insult to the PLA, the newspaper said. It said if the PLA tried to act above the law after the territory comes under Chinese rule on July 1, they would fail to clean up their &quot;butcher image&quot;.</p>
<p>Many in Hong Kong's 6.4 million people view the PLA with alarm because of its role in the 1989 crackdown.</p>
<p>The telephone numbers of Zhou's office are kept secret and he was not available to comment on the report.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
